hey what's going on everybody welcome
welcome welcome to hash Church I myself
am just freshly back from a camping trip
so give me a little bit of time and I'll
get everyone invited in for the link I
hope everyone's having a good Father's
Day happy Father's Day to all the
fathers out there of course and yeah
we're gonna have a nice little episode
today so stick around let's see what we
got to do here we got a copy this there
we go
I'm excited for today's episode looking
forward to often a little with with Tim
Blake and Alec for messy labs todd
mccormick helped to set that up so we're
very happy that he did all right so we
will send the link out I see Todd and
Tim and Etienne have seen it so we could
probably expect them in in the near
future and yeah we got a whole bunch of
people holding down the chat room right
now nice to see you nice to see an
absolutely happy Father's Day and thank
you all for the Father's Day blessings
that you have passed my way I do
appreciate it
well Happy Father's Day how's it going
guys happy Father's Day to you and all
the father's sorry about that Anna had
my thing turned off what was that it I
said happy Father's Day to you and all
the father's yes absolutely here we are
on a beautiful Sunday afternoon well
early before noon actually it's 9:00
a.m. but somewhere it's afternoon
somewhere it's afternoon how you doing
Todd I'm melting melting is it like 107
degrees it's damned forest hit me up
this morning and he was just like dude I
wish I was a little higher north today
I'm with him at that point right now
yeah it's pretty what he said it was 107
or 108 yeah that's that's like hot yoga
you you heat up a room to do hot yoga
it's about a hundred and ten degrees
Fahrenheit it just goes look new it's a
fatty for Father's Day I love it how
Fatty's for Father's Day
it's awesome have a fatty for your
father today this one is in memory of
mine mine passed away this year my
stepfather who was really my father so
this is my first one without him so much
love to Joe family right yeah absolutely
let me see I might need to make a new
message today I don't know if anyone got
those give me a couple I just sent him
an Alex as well I had sent it to them as
well but I think the way it happened
this morning that things did not get
sent the way they should have gotten
sent so it should be conversation today
they're gonna come on we're gonna talk
about the way they're doing their new
test for the the country fair that's
happening in Layton bill in July they've
broken the categories into five
different categories based on terpene
expressions oh yeah you said that that
looks really cool
yeah well this is a that would be a
first of its kind yes leave that up to
the people at the end woke up of course
I think it we have to push you know it's
good to see things pushing in a
different direction at least challenging
the status quo yeah they're defining
cannabis culture in a lot of ways they
are not waiting for permission they are
actually coming out and doing it really
well this new event that they're doing
is based solely on organic horticulture
which i think is really great it's like
the old-timers stepping up and saying
hey we have to be stewards of the
environment we have to pay attention to
what we're doing and I think that's
fantastic
personally well it's nice to see them
changing it up and doing something a
little bit different and you know the
importance of terpenes that we have
learned in the last 20 years
hey welcome Sam hey we have to be
stewards of the farm you have to pay
attention and what we're doing and it's
like deja vu that was such a weird deja
vu I was like I've heard this before the
importance of terpenes that you've
learned hey he stays on I keep repeating
the same [ __ ] I apologize I'm you them
I'll just mute I'm he'll figure it out
the terpenes are where the Terps are
where it's act well they're definitely a
part of it for sure a very important
part that maybe for a long time we
weren't quite as aware of seems like the
community is becoming more and more
aware Tim's here welcome to mr. Salinger
Tim good morning happy Father's Day
hello thank you for joining us happy
Father's Day Sam yeah
we only got you for an hour right yeah
well we'd love to give you the floor
could you please tell us a little bit
about what you're doing up in
Laytonsville and the new country fair
and then we wanted to ask you about the
new competition and how you are breaking
it into terpenes and that you've changed
the categories well can you guys hear me
good very well okay so what's going on
is that I've been calling the Emerald
cup of canvass country fair for 14 years
and of course we do it in the wintertime
where it's not the best weather for a
fair type environment so I've talked
with Jonathan's involvement a few years
back and he held the domain name for me
and a friend of mine wanted to come
along and try to do that last year at
black oak branch and failed kind of
miserably with it and I went back and
said you know what that was my name that
was my that was my show I'd like to do
that and make something good for the
Emerald triangle people in the community
of Mendocino because they're all kind of
disappointed we took the Emerald cup out
of the triangle and down to Santa Rosa
so we thought we'd bring something back
home for everybody up here and do a
weekend event where you can camp out and
actually hang with people you know the
Emerald cup and a lot of these
competitions or shows they're so hectic
you're running your booth you barely
have a chance to even spend five minutes
with anybody I hardly even see anyone
I've got to go back to see you showed up
through all the videos and so I was like
okay let's do a weekend event where
people stay for the weekend we'll make
it a really community-based thing we'll
bring the best of the Emerald triangle
vendors in and we'll do a new type of
competition that we will want to do alex
has been bugging me forever so we
thought we'd do all that and put a great
show together now I'm working with some
new partners they're very quiet and they
they never use their name so
not even supposed to really honor him in
fact if you look at the introduction for
the cannabis Country Fair we really
didn't even introduce them and except
we're very vague it's because they're
quiet they're not ego based I'm working
with a new group of people out of red
light management the guys that
discovered Dave Matthews they have fish
it's the most respected talent agency in
the world for music they also our
partners and many festivals but they
don't put their name on anything they're
not ego based the gentleman who owns the
thing privately never puts his name into
anything so I'm probably gonna get a
little flak for even going into this
much because like I said they're they're
just a very quiet reserved company but
they're very powerful stuart ross who
produced the first 360 Lollapalooza is
helping manage the show and the idea
turn it into like a Lollapalooza and
take it around the country and integrate
alternative lifestyles and the
agricultural techniques and the medicine
and everything that we do and take it
around and you know show it off to
Michigan in the East Coast and down
south in Texas and stuff because that's
what they do we've got Charlie Hernandez
who's out with you two right now usually
produced and production managed I'm
sorry all the Farm Aid shows he's on the
board of directors he was out Neil he's
pretty he's the production manager for
us so we had some issues last year with
the Emerald cup as we all know it got
out of control with so many people
coming in and we extended the contest
accidentally which may gave us a train
wreck with 850 entries the last three
days I was out of control so we really
looked at it and even though we had a
good experience with our partners last
year we had the opportunity to work with
red light and come in and bring them in
and we decided that we wanted to move up
to the next level so that we could be
you know the hold up to that standard is
the best show in the world so we've got
Charlie and Stewart with us for the
cannabis Country Fair and the Emerald
cup we have another partner red light
gym Lully who's helping produce the show
he created a festival back in 80s called
the horn festival he worked with
earthing aids off for ten years he's an
amazing I mean everybody there is
amazing he's an incredible individual
happy Father's Day to all of them
and that's this new team that we're
coming together with the cannabis
country fair so that we can take it on
the road and work with people like you
and everybody else to help showcase who
we are you know ten there's a long
there's not it's a great entry than what
you've done with the country with the
Emerald cup and I'm sure what will
happen with the Country Fair I mean even
though you say it's gotten out of
control it is the most community-based
event in my opinion that you can attend
anywhere in the world mean you go to
places like in Europe everybody comes
from everywhere else but there's just
such a core group community with what
you're doing that I just think is
fantastic yeah well I've got word out of
control maybe that's a little
heavy-handed it was just the elements
when you get that many people we've
learned things and like we had 300 extra
people that tried to get it a Damian
Marley now we've never had a problem in
the past because by the end of the night
there's so many people that are so high
they don't even want to go to the show
so we left the first 3500 in it's never
been a problem because it's just worked
this year about 400 people wanted to see
Damian and they could just see Damian
and it was sad because they couldn't get
in there and the fairgrounds wouldn't
open up and let those extra few hundred
people in and then the contest was kind
of a challenge because so many late
entries you get 850 entries the last
three days I mean how can people judge
that so we've changed the rules for the
Emerald cup we're gonna shorten the
timing we're gonna give the testing a
lot more space we're gonna give the
judges clean medicine and we're going to
rectify everything that wasn't perfect
because you know what it's amazing you
can be an 8-cylinder card if you're
running on seven cylinders it still
won't be a perfect right even though
it's running almost perfect so the
Emerald cup from what everybody saw
really went well but we see the few
things we're going to correct and we're
starting with the cannabis country fair
to get them all in it sounds like you
got the right people on board Tim I mean
wow that's great to see
really no 140 cannabis companies and
they decided they want to work with us
and I'm very proud and honored to have
them with us there it's really still the
Emerald cup presenting a cannabis
country fair but to know that they're
the ones helping with the show the
organisation and whatnot gives me a lot
of cup
we can deal with the other aspects now
that's that's a key aspect that's needed
I actually did the Horde tour myself
many moons ago in a galaxy far far so
yeah I know the professionalism that
goes into it and what's needed and that
was a very well-run gig altogether so
just from the listing of the cadre you
have there it's quite impressive and
it's great because it shows that you're
taking it serious and vendors want to
know that the people that attend don't
really understand what happens around
the you know in the backwoods of what
actually takes Jen transpires I have an
idea of thrown events not of course of
this caliber but it's great Tim thank
you very much for one coming on and then
making us well aware of what's
transpiring and thank you for stepping
up your own game I do have a question
for you Tim this is Nessa Sam here what
I'm interested in is your saying that
there will be five dominant dominant
terpene varieties yes contest me between
picking out the best of these five
different terpene dominant varieties
correct yes and are those going to be
type 1 type 2 or type 3 plants in other
words THC CBD and THC or CBD well we're
not going to do CBD for this this
contest we decided to tighten up and
just go with concentrates and light depo
and do a small contest it was the last
night of show that we put together
there's a lot of other events you got
Dougie chalice down there and so we
thought we'd just start with a small
contest you know stay out of people's
way and and just keep going with it
there's so many different ways you can
throw in the contest dominant variety
you mean also a THC dominant variety
with well that sounds really good
because I was worried that you were
gonna mix up the three type one type two
and type three plants and that would
have been crazy because how can you
compare a CBD variety
see varieties side-by-side just by
terpene content it wouldn't work
you know what I mixed up enough and I
think everybody else is so we don't need
to do any more than we already got if
there's so much for us to learn and be
educated on but that is the future for
sure so the five term is the future
really quickly - Kevin Jodrey and the
golden tarp who basically started this
this direction of course with dominant
core view with the trooper festival and
then you've got Jeremy plume Jesse Dodd
up there with the cultivation classic so
these three groups really spearheaded
the direction of that even though Alec
Dixon has been bugging me for years to
go in this direction they jumped in and
did it and it's really a big shout out
to Kevin Jodrey and the folks at
Wonderland the golden tarp that really
spearheaded that up in Garberville
does that have to be a natural
extraction from plant material or can it
be fabricated with natural terpenes and
THC distillate well we're doing a
separate distillate contest and so you
can do that we'll have a co2 contest and
the and the concentrate contest will all
be natural extraction the distillate
contest we're opening that up we're
recognizing that I mean I tried Toni
Mendocino who's the creator of the
skittles and whatnot and fields they
have an ethanol cartridge that boy I
finally found a cartridge I mean we have
co2 cartridges they're nice but this
ethanol distillate cart was just
stunning I mean it was the first thing
I'd ever tasted which had expansion
actually almost tasted like you were
smoking a joint except with a clean
taste and and it hit well all the way
down so that the futures obviously going
to be ethanol distillates for the
cartridges and so we're bringing that
distillate contest in to recognize that
even though ethanol is still considered
a violent solvent we got to get
realistic here I mean it's not it's it's
an even xane of propane and butane are
gonna be allowed in there bringing them
in their states can allow them in so
under the right conditions these these
are gonna come in and we're going to let
them into the cup we're just waiting for
the legalization to come in well what is
the THC level of ethanol Carter
like this in other words if you looked
at it as THC as a percentage of the of
the weight of volume what is it do you
have any idea you know I don't know
those are the first real ethanol carts
that I've seen come in and there wasn't
any information with them I've been
hitting them for the last couple weeks
and trying them out with everybody that
I know all the hardcore people that
don't want cartridges in their lives and
they're all going you know what I
probably I probably hit this in fact I
would I like this and so I'm like oh my
gosh this is really a project yes okay
yeah because 20 years ago we tried an
ethanol extracted from resin material
and it worked pretty good but I myself
personally I couldn't handle it was
ethanol based but it was nebulized with
ultrasonics well you know leave it to
the brilliant people of this country in
this world to figure out new ways to do
things so you know we've gone from you
know where I come from just you know
puffing on joints to where you've got
the leading scientists in the world
figure out how to do all this it's so
far beyond me I just you know my hats
off to all of them and I just want to
enjoy it can I ask you Tim what was
these five terpenes that you're going
with Turpin allene pioneer limonene
careful Ian and mercy and are those the
five most prominent terpenes and
cannabis well according to Alec Dixon
and Essie labs and what they're doing
you know you've got so many others but I
think that you know talking to Alec he
thought that we could have them all fall
into those ranges and so of course I
defer to them they're going to be the
ones that separate the the entries into
into the categories for our judges and
you know looking at it you know like I
said there's so much to learn I'm old
school we were doing the cup you know
just everything against itself we used
to have a best morning bud contest so
that the blue dreams and stuff would
have a chance this is a very different
structure of how to do it I'm excited to
see how it works I'm hoping that it
works so well that we can bring it right
into the cup it gives a lot more room
for different strains to win I mean
how's the blue dream or a train
we've talked about that in the judging
forever oh this is a stunning blue dream
but I wasn't going to beat up fuel you
know so this gives all those different
strains a chance to compete to get
honored it brings back and you know what
the concentrates going in that direction
so much I mean who wants to just you
know hit a dab of OG you're looking for
cookies you looking for skittles you
look at urban children of ours and so in
the concentrates he's even more
pronounced it's time to really recognize
that what we're looking for are these
terpene profiles and so let's honor them
and give everybody a chance to to win
prizes off of those I would agree with
most of the terpenes you picked but
Carrie ethylene does not potentiate or
modulate THC as far as I know I know I
tried it I couldn't get it to modulate
it huh well that's interesting incorrect
him it's more about the the expressions
that are shown in the test that SC Labs
is doing I think they're seeing
carefully and things like gorilla glue
can Girl Scout cookie sherbert skittles
the stuff that there's the cannabis
Country Fair has a really good page on
this listed under contest and it talks
about the different categories for the
terpenes and Alex is supposed to be
joining us as well today so maybe we can
get more information on em too he's you
know what he is he's brilliant I'll tell
you what Alec and Josh and the guys at
SC it's just amazing what they're doing
and you know they have put it together
well there's a lot of different ways you
can go there's so many different
varieties I mean you could have expanded
this out but then how do you how do you
close down the contest only there's only
so many terpenes with modulation and put
potentiation a lot of the terpenes do
not modulate and do not put 10 she ate
THC for example so you might want to
start with those first oh boy we should
get you on a panel talking about this
it's a salad I I don't I I live in
Europe and I don't think I'll come to
California just to attend there
hopparoo everyone come over yeah because
I think this is how people are going to
be educated and there's a lot of
Education that needs to take place and I
know a lot of people say that carry out
lean is important for medicinal use
because it's it's a cb2 binder but if
you want to get high you don't want to
see be due to binder you want to see b1
binder well that's true well it's like I
said we're all going to go through this
contest together and then go through the
Emerald cup and it's going to be
something that everybody's gonna really
learn a lot about because really as I go
out there and talk to people
there's so little information that
people the people really know and we're
sitting there talking about it but most
people are still in the dark are the
concentrates going to be in the same
categories yes concentrates can be
broken down into terpene profiles which
is they had to convince me to do that
I'm old school so I'm like oh my gosh
this is like you know it's nice we're
doing it the country fair but when you
look at the concentrates look at all the
flavors that are coming in and shooting
profiles that are there so it really
naturally breaks down into those
categories too as far as winners and
what people are looking for I agree with
you Tim it is a natural way to do it
what would be kind of interesting is if
they would also besides a printout of
the terpenes and cannabinoids of the
extract also habit of the original herb
the extract was taken from so that you
could see what has altered in the
extract versus the original herb and I'm
talking about altering the cannabinoid
you're terpene profiles you're
interesting you know that's a very good
suggestion actually well I wish we had
more time before this contest to have
taken a lot of this in Tony's came on we
did this from a wrong start Tony did a
little bit through SC labs with Blue
River where they tested the bud and then
they tested the terpene profile of the
terpenes that were extracted and it was
there were little little minor changes
but fairly accurate it was pretty
interesting it definitely a good idea
depends how rough your extraction is the
sesquiterpene stick around much stronger
than the monoterpenes it'd be really
really gentle the monitor could be all
there and pretty close to the original
profile as in the earth right I think
the ones that I saw there was just a few
that it actually like like one had
disappeared and a new one had shown up
terpene which was kind of interesting
maybe Alec can talk about it when he
gets in from Messi you know the
cultivation classic guys they're Jeremy
and the Philo's people with what they're
doing is really interesting they put all
the cultivation classic and you can see
how it fits and what's where it's going
and how how the genetic you know
background goes and I think you're going
to see more that we're trying to bring
that into the cup this year as an
educational piece and it's exciting to
see this I mean it's so I'll be back in
the woods just will you have a category
for pure terpenes cannabis derived on
adulterant rate no cannabinoids no herb
just terpenes you know we're not doing
at the campus Country Fair what I
believe will do that if there will cup
nice that would that be variable you
know where do we stand that out because
we wanted to make sure we didn't make
one mistake with this contest and it was
a new set of you know parameters it was
like let's just keep it small let's keep
this together and do this because we
went back and forth on how many other
contests people wanted us to add a bunch
of the contests in it was like you know
what let's just work with this we'll
head pickup we'll get it down and we'll
just expand it but that's a really good
suggestion on that when we talked about
it I think it should be in yeah good
idea to build your foundation you know a
little simpler and not too overly
complex because as we know with cannabis
and getting into terpenes especially the
holy smokes you could go deep it can get
complicated
yeah I mean all of this is complicated
this contest is complicated where it's
like I can't keep track of all the
prizes and the contests and what's going
on that's why we're bringing these these
you know heavy weights in here just make
sure it all runs right
well I tip my hat to you sir it's you
know you've been doing a great job
obviously I hear great things about the
Emerald cup it's one of the events that
I cannot believe I haven't been to in
the cannabis community it's hopefully
one day one day Oh we'll get you out you
got an extended VIP tickets for yourself
- that's so cool Tim the Marc's been at
this a while so I can't visit mark
because of my cannabis convictions and
mark can't visit me because they're so
we've both been bumped on the Canadian
border so this is a lot of why I used to
do house Church because it gave me time
to just sit and smoke with mark I know
it sounds funny but it was I can't
other than meeting him in Europe at a
coffee shop I don't get to spend quality
time with my friend or Jamaica I'm in
Hollywood marking to make the yet but on
tennis
well we'll be doing that soon I'll tell
you go ahead Tim oh there's just so much
going on in Canada right now I wish I
could get up there - I've got
convictions and so I can't get I'm
hoping with the unfoldment legalization
they'll open that all up now
we will meet in Jamaica Tim tell
everybody where they get to get
information if they're interested in
going to your event where is it going to
be held what are the dates how do they
find out more information
well the dates are July 21st 22nd 23rd
of this year it's going to be at the
historic black oak branch in Mendocino
County it's 10 miles north of right on
the highway there you can get the
information at cannabis Country Fair
calm you can get tickets at Eventbrite
we're gonna have tickets in the stores
throughout you know Northern California
over the next couple days and it's going
to be a beautiful 80 acre ranch with a
river going through it that people going
to be camping on and it's gonna be a
wonderful outdoor camping event for
people cools down at night so the
weather's not hot we have an amazing
line-up I mean these guys it's red light
I didn't know half these bands you know
I go out and try to get booked are acts
and then people they'll tell us yes or
no but we'll get one-offs red light goes
out and every every available comes to
them
so we got an act that is blowing up
they're number one in the country
alternative rock called Portugal the man
who I don't even know who that was and
he's amazing and then of course we got
Theory Corporation which just did a new
record they were down in Jamaica putting
that together they were doing some tours
and then we got beats antique but then
we've got white denim and Alan stone
Jamestown revival Anders Osbourne who I
didn't even know about who I know that
guy's amazing nominal you know what I
was told by one of my record store
people that take tickets they said you
got to go listen to Anders I sure I've
been so busy a chance to they said you
got to listen to this guy and I went
listen to him I was like oh man the guy
is phenomenal and these guys are all the
headliners and they're all right and
they're all playing you know third
fourth and the lineup oh they hit it out
of the park they they spent more money
than I do on the Emerald cup for the
music and so a great lineup for that
some great speakers coming in great
great topics and really just a
comfortable place to hang out with
people for the weekend it's almost like
we're turning it's like the these
cannabis events are really gonna sort of
take over these what a concert used to
be let's go to a concert and drink a
beer and watch like Roger Waters play
his songs it's like no now there's like
speakers there's an event it's
cannabis-based is a little competition
there's it's just such a better thing to
have these amazing bands play at these
events but make it still you know
focused on that plant that we all love
and the County Fair I mean that's a
natural I used to always go to county
fairs it was very agriculturally
orientated both animals and plants what
can we talk about a little bit this is
an organic based fear I read on your
website you're not even you don't even
want to accept applications from
nutrient companies that don't have
organic lines could you talk a little
bit more about that Tim well we're
really stepping out with that we're not
calling anybody out but we're looking at
what the state's going to demand next
year in terms of testing and we're
looking at the environmental issues and
the patient's issues and we're just
drawing a line and saying that we need
to provide organic medicines for our
patients and for our farms and for our
communities and we just can't stand down
from that so we're
just now going to demand that everybody
coming into Canada's Country Fair and
the Emerald cup we already have all the
all the food organic we have all the
entries organic we've given some people
leeway as far as vendors but we're drawn
a line in the sand and saying look if
you want to be with us and you want us
to represent you then you're gonna have
to be organic because that's what we're
saying we are and then without all these
groups slip in that aren't people people
come to us and they say well we thought
they were organic cuz they were with you
and so we're bowing for these companies
in effect no yeah I think I think that's
fantastic I mean you represent to me the
old-school Mendocino when I first went
up there in 94 and I spent my first
summer up there growing with Richard
Davis you you remember Richard Davis he
had a museum yeah he was a hero it was
different I mean you guys had such a
different consideration for the
environment around you you were not
polluters you would not trash in the
place you were not clear-cutting to put
up greenhouses it was such a different
vibe I mean the guys growing at the
normal meetings and and the activism I
did were the same people I saw at the
earth first stuff that was standing up
and trying to stop the loggers and and
then a whole new generation of people
seem to come in after proposition 215
passed and it took a very different vibe
and it broke my heart and a lot off and
you know I'm not religious but going up
to those trees it's like a spiritual
experience you know Northern California
and I'm just really happy that you have
this voice of reason and that you're
bringing back this consciousness of hey
we have to be stewards of the land we've
got to take care of each other I love
the community element of this so much
Tim and I hope people really hear that
and get that and understand that that's
been a big part of the mo cup for a very
long time thank you very much time
that's a it's a it is true but you know
it's not just the cannabis people it's
across the country we we taken all the
topsoil off all the land we toxified it
so much that boys you know you go on a
San Joaquin Valley and they're growing
six legged frogs and all kinds of stuff
and it's like we need to be leaders and
I need to take that responsibility and
we'll raise that bar and show the rest
of this country how to do it because
they're not doing
in the vineyard industries and the
traditional agriculture industries
they're pretty much toxifying the land
and themselves and us and it's got to
stop and it's you know it's really a
great place for us to be to be able to
leave that way and show everybody how to
do that and that's what the state is
asking us to do and that's what we can
do and you know those people coming back
after all those years ago Todd they were
coming back up here not to make money
but to live a good life with their
families to live organic lives and it
was about growing some cannabis if they
could pay their bills cuz nobody was
getting rich I mean back then if he
could bring a hundred pounds out you
were a huge guy I mean anybody could
that was almost unfathomable because you
were growing out of the trees and let
the shade these little quarter rounds
four quarter pound plants a huge plant
now it's like people are like unless
you're a ten box guy and grown a
thousand pounds the guy showed up at my
house at area 101 he came in he said I
got four acres and humble I'm getting
four more do you think if I have eight
acres I can compete and I said you know
what eight acres we're done we're doomed
I mean there's just no way to support
that there's no there's no way to get it
up people to smoke that and so we're
gonna all have to be reasonable going
into this it's gonna be a big thing
because one of the things I found the
last month we're finding up here is we
have a crisis going on and I want to
start a whole like almost a theater
piece on what happened how did this
happen because we're bringing prop 64 in
we're supposed to be reasonable
everybody's supposed to be down at an
acre or less we're gonna be all playing
fair
Mendocino is playing fair we've got
everybody at the top level doing a
quarter acre that's what we've got
10,000 square feet and I've got
neighborhoods complaining because we're
too big and yet you've got Steve
DeAngelo down there were 27 and half
acres they're predicting 25 million
pounds being grown from Santa Cruz to
San Luis Obispo this year
I mean it's eight times what the
triangle brought out you talked to Eddie
and the guys in Sacramento they're going
to come online with a hundred million
pounds they're building the greenhouses
as fast as they can right now won't
impact us this year but before prop 64
came in you got people on Humboldt about
four to eight acres you got people
always safe to gone around it and how
did our senators our leaders and
everybody allow this nightmare that
happened before it even became legal but
looking
don't don't you think in all factuality
I mean there's been a surge of growers
surge of people buying land because it's
got huge profitability you take the
profitability out and you turn this into
tomato farming there's gonna be a whole
lot less enthusiasm around that tomato
farming because there's not the profits
there and if cannabis goes down to the
price of anywhere near organic Tomatoes
under ten bucks a pound all these guys
are walking out the door I mean you're
you're gonna see a nice quiet Northern
California again because you're gonna
lose a lot of the people that came up
there with the antenna can I could beat
ya and not to say that not to say that
people aren't going to get a decent
dollar for their cannabis in the future
a craft style like that'll always exist
but this three thousand dollar a pound
thing that's based in on people going to
prison for years of their life is just
no longer the reality that we want to be
part of Todd I do disagree with $10 a
pound though and the reason is is
because the anibus is usually sold dry
by the pound and if you sold dried
organically grown tomatoes that were
dried it wouldn't be $10 a pound they'd
be more because who have to drive the
link go through the the hassle to do so
that makes sense
fantastic example so I'll show you look
up my dry organic tomato pound but you
know what I don't think it'll go down to
ten but you get that there's gonna be a
situation where your neighbors are
looking at the cost of production and
they're gonna be realistic about what it
costs to produce that pound of cannabis
they're gonna double their price because
they have investors that want to see a
return this is gonna turn into a regular
business and I think one not happen
everything's that's the trouble is it
already happened it's it's like with
what we found out and the research is
that that we I went to sleep I had some
serious illnesses over the winter and I
woke up doing this canvas Country Fair
thinking we were gonna have like the
total celebration and it's almost it's
not a wake but it's almost like a total
shock and awe thing that's gone on
because what we found is is that that
last year's outdoor right now because of
the millions of pounds of depo is coming
in
it's almost not saleable you're watching
people that have sour DS and and and
cookies and stuff that they begin 12 to
14 they're not getting a thousand now
they're looking at boxes and maybe they
gotta go I've been told seven or eight
and it's because there's so much demo
coming in that they don't even want last
year's anymore there's not even a market
or even back east people don't want it
and so you've got this whole thing where
now you're gonna have these millions and
millions of pounds of temples coming in
from all over the California farmland
and it's going to keep the prices down
and then you're gonna have the long
season come in and I've got people
predicting that you're gonna see long
season crops in Humboldt and Mendocino
going for six to seven hundred dollars
by Halloween and probably 500 on the
front by Thanksgiving I think being
generous to be honest with you Tim from
when I was really really the truth of it
is let's be frank here you can grow a
Christmas tree farm and you sell those
Christmas trees less for for less than a
hundred dollars
some of them take five years to grow you
what do you think you could do with the
crown of us which is an annual crop I
mean of course you could sell it for
$100 a plant each one when you drive
you'll get more than a kilo it's gonna
it's just simple economics of course you
can you know Tim in the 90s they were
growing so much and down in Switzerland
that the way they did harvests work
because they couldn't they couldn't
bring in the labor to harvest everything
in the field so they had picnic tables
set up and people could come to the
fields and literally buy a plant go cut
it down process what they wanted leave
the pile with take what they wanted and
split that's that's gonna be I believe
the future because when you get into the
labor of taking it down trimming it
sharing it and then packaging it you've
tacked on a whole lot of cost true yeah
you know what there's the jincan of
people that they developed Shaw's web
and then they just agreement with the
guys that pushed it out so they formed a
gen can and went to Kentucky and worked
with Mitch McConnell and Rand Paul to
legalize hemp to sell worldwide they
grew a million pounds last year at
twenty dollars a pound
with organic growing farming techniques
with the tobacco farmers and they're
doing crystal Seavey they'd like me to
bring it into my products out you're not
trying to figure out how I'll be viewed
by the people out here I start using
crystallized CBD from Kentucky even
though they're California humble
triangle people that grew it all so I'm
like oh my what does this mean and now
they're coming to California to do you
know THC boost
cannabis and they're talking you know 50
bucks a pound well yeah you know you're
right traditional agriculture when you
get in there I'm looking at it like for
all the people that spent 40 years in
the triangle developing this living this
fighting it going to jail and trying to
put it together I would have liked to
have seen them get an extra year or two
as the transition took place and what
we're seeing is it came in so quick that
it's already here and done and you're
gonna like you said you're gonna see it
it might even go below that this year
and on the one side for the patients
with the amount of products we're going
to get and for the pricing it's going to
be an incredible thing across this
country California's going to become a
forty five billion dollar industry so
it's going to be remarkable that all the
products and the stuff that's going to
come in here but it's going to be a very
difficult transition for the Emerald
triangle folks and for the people up in
the Sierras and stuff that didn't get
their brands or old school didn't get
their permits you didn't do it that way
they thought they'd just stay with it
for the next few years and they're gonna
find that it's it's coming out of faster
they're think about it what other
agricultural products are grown up in
the Emerald triangle they're in little
pairs were a big part you try it and you
got business travelers wonder lumbered
I'm just trying to point out not a true
agricultural center the way many places
in California are no I think that I
think that the price reduction is gonna
weed out Northern California of all the
wannabe cannabis entrepreneurs and leaf
people like that we're there because
they love the place because they cared
about the place because it felt like
home and they weren't there to make
money and I mean and I feel Tim totally
for a lot of the people there's a lot of
20-somethings that were screaming at me
because I was support in 64 and
I don't really have a ton of pity for
them they were eight nine ten years old
when we passed to 15 20 years ago they
don't understand what it was like to get
raided to get locked up to go through
hell and they don't get the fight that
we fought for so long and this hasn't
been overnight this has been [ __ ]
decades of us losing you getting our
asses handed to us our assets taken our
bills lined up our lawyers sucking us
dry so if this hasn't been overnight and
I do feel bad for the people that had
Gardens in the last ten years and has
just watched profits go down but this is
great for the end-users because there's
gonna get to a point I think where it
goes direct to consumer where people
like you can sell on your website like a
winery does and say hey 3,000 cases of
XYZ take it or leave it and and I
believe that it's gonna change the face
of this and if it means that the end
user is going to end up seeing huge
price reductions in the cannabis that
they get I think it's great and I feel
totally bad for people that have been
living off it but I feel way better for
the people that have been drinking wine
or smoking cigarettes or sucking down
pharmaceutical pills because they had no
[ __ ] alternative and couldn't smoke
the $400 an ounce [ __ ] that you and I
burn like trees you know we burn it like
it's nothing but a lot of people don't
get to live that experience and and now
maybe they will
and I think yay I really do think yay
for them cuz it helped me I hope it
helps everyone else you know I love you
Todd I'd like to see the price for a
large plant that can yield one kilo
cleaned and dried but you perm a
Christmas tree type set up a hundred
dollars that way people could afford to
smoke hashish you know and that's what I
like dry snipped together with cannabis
trees missing right [ __ ] Christmas trees
they shouldn't be cutting down pine
trees those should all be wheat you know
it should all be cannabis just think of
the beautiful smell on Christmas morning
in your house if you came down and there
was just this big huge beautiful
cannabis plant in full bloom
yeah the beautiful thing you know what
go ahead get me to talk on that and I
really do agree that I've been telling
people for years that they had to wake
up and so I've spent the last three
years getting my manufacturing in place
getting my branding getting it all and I
told everybody it wasn't gonna go on
we've all said one more year one more
year and I I don't what I the only thing
I am perplexed by was that we talked
about was 64 and what I sold people Todd
was that this was going to be an orderly
rollout we were going to hold back
large-scale farming to like one acre for
just a few years and we were just gonna
let this slowly you know roll down and
it's happened so quick that it's just
steamrolled it and it's basically over
and so what you're seeing up here is
going to be shock and awe and for me
it's like we're coming to the cannabis
country fair it's good for us to have
bending so we can show people and we're
gonna talk about all this at the end of
the day though I fall on your side Todd
and everybody else it's going to be an
incredible boon for patients they're
gonna see cost-effective medicine in the
80s when they started bringing it so
much time I wasn't sure what I do with
all the time Mexicans I was getting
thousands of pounds and it just got
cheaper and cheaper well people just
started smoking more and more it became
like all of a sudden it just went
everywhere well that's what's gonna at
what this campus is going to go from
seven percent to 22 percent to forty
pretty soon half this country is going
to be using cannabis in some form so and
it's gonna be cheap wonderful I've
listened I completely am with you I have
believed everything that I've been
saying with Jack Herer for 25 years I
believe that society will be a better
place if they have cannabis instead of
pharmaceuticals booze tobacco and
everything else I really believe in
cannabis and it's just it I believe that
the price is absolute huge hurdle for a
lot of people to overcome and it's
beautiful to hear that elope that in a
sense low quality cannabis is not
desirable because everybody's like oh
it's a race to the bottom it's raised to
mids
well now mids won't be able to be sold
because everybody wants good stuff so
you're gonna have to learn how to grow
quality at a competitive price and it's
gonna have to be clean because now we
have people like alex at SC that's gonna
be able to see if it's not and
disqualify the people that are
hustle us cuz you know I was blown away
that so many people brought tainted
samples and entered him into the mo cop
because I thought jeez who do that you
know like what wants to get caught and
there's so many people did that and I
think that's this willful ignorance of
what they're doing that leads them down
this path or thinking they can compete
with stuff that you would never smoke
yeah and I also think that they went to
they went to a few other labs that
weren't quite as tough as SC they might
not have tested it they did make some
mistakes but you know we had an
educational process with the cup the
last two years everybody realizing that
because nothing was getting tested and
let's face it the thing of it is is that
most of the OG and these collectives is
not tested it's all indoor and the
dispensaries are turning their head the
other way because they want to sell it
and next year like alex says let the
restrictive nature of the testing it's
going to be nine times harder and most
of the stuffs gonna fail so the one
niche for the high-end cannabis farmers
is going to be growing a really quality
organic product and so if you're the
best of the best you'll have a small
niche the biggest thing Todd is that
with all the Devils coming in so quick
there's no time to store last year's
crop anymore all these people that store
it and think they're gonna keep it nice
and tight and sell it I'm looking at
this our D and this cookies and stuff it
looks great but it's not fresh light
demo and so people are looking at it
like I can buy fresh light up or I can
buy your backpack last years which is
great but now they're B grain we don't
want it and I'm like oh my god in one
year you can hell no longer can sell
last year's outdoor or if you do you're
gonna sell it for seven it's interesting
too though because people are now
experiencing fresh cannabis in abundance
and they get the terpene profiles and
how bright they are and how they look at
stuff that's been sitting around they go
I'd still like it but there's just
there's just not the shine there and
it's it's people are getting wiser to
this and and this is also why when I saw
the ax breaking get down into the
terpenes I thought this is really
fantastic because it's really bringing
more attention to the nuances that have
been attracting us for so long and it's
a great educational tool because you
can't really understand the contest
unless you start learning the names of
terpenes and why they're the one
in the heads of the contest so I thought
it was a fantastic educational tool this
is really why I've loved animal Cup for
so long because I think that bringing
everyone together you influence the
community because everyone else sees
what everyone's doing and there's an
emulation that occurs you know everyone
wants to step up their game and do
better I don't think anyone wants to
bring dirty medicine to the table so
what you're doing is creating the
element or the atmosphere where they can
truly learn and grow and and communicate
with one another and that's probably my
favorite element of both of your events
until doing this analysis of the herb
and the extract made from it to show any
differences in terpene or cannabinoid
contents or ratios you could also do
fresh herb and dried herb because drying
gets rid of three-quarters of the
terpenes already good good input I love
the point where they make your salt
it'll be interested to see what happens
next year cuz on the website I like how
you're talking about how you're doing
things this year and then you're going
to apply them what you learned to the
next year's competition I mean this is
also something that this has been such a
growing experience for everybody that's
watching you do this because it's an
application of ideas and technology all
coming together under one roof well what
was the Emerald cup when I say
technology be in the testing and then
application of ideas being organic and
sustainable farming I think it's I think
it's the only way to go and if someone's
not there to teach these new young bucks
so to speak how to do it right where
they're gonna learn it it's the only
conscious way to go but people buy
Budweiser beer too instead of a a
handcrafted small beer so I mean it's
not the only way to go but it's the
intelligent you know conscious way but
you know the fastest-growing market and
the spirits and alcohol markets is the
high end and it's gonna be the fastest
in the cannabis industry because once
people could go to a collective and get
an OG and not have to be
you dog they all wanted og well now that
they can go get skittles or you know a
six star full melt concentrate they can
see the difference between fresh frozen
bras and rather than low-grade and so
you're going to see those prices come
way down people gonna be able to use
much better medicine because it'll be
much more cost effective and this
contest I thought it I really am proud
of the fact that was stuff that you say
we can take this around the country open
source and teach all these people so
they don't do what we did to the
triangle environmentally they learn the
right way they learn how they're gonna
get a better profile with organic
farming techniques and how they can get
patients to the right medicine and so we
can teach this whole country in this
whole world and we need to do is just
open it up to export all this so that we
can keep growing enough to sell it all
over the world which is what we do as we
do with the rest of California
agriculture we sell it all over the
world well that's gonna be our saving
grace whether they would just get back
and be on the interstate lettuce go
nationwide like they're letting the Jan
kin of folks do with the hemp they sold
a million pounds nation or worldwide
they're gonna do to liam pounds this
year you know and so that's what we need
to do and then we can basically hold our
heritage you know in some ways i think
the opportunities in front of you and
you know with with no disrespect to high
times they brought many of us together i
wouldn't know a lot of my friends if it
wasn't for the events in amsterdam and
but i think that it's a different vibe
and the community really could use the
kind of vibe that you guys are putting
out because i mean again no disrespect
to high times but it's it's more of a
party vibe and not exactly an
environmentally conscious let's you know
save the world vibe and you and mo cop
has definitely been from more of a
coming from the earth perspective and
hey let's be responsible and hey let's
be good stewards and good neighbors and
and i think that's the message more and
more people need to learn as they get
into this community because if they
don't if that if the community doesn't
take on these core values it's just
gonna be a [ __ ] show and you know that's
we don't we don't need to see more
events you know holding their events and
leaving piles of trash so the vote you
know the photos go viral and everybody
thinks you know oh look at those jerks
you know we need people like you guys
that stay until the place is perfectly
clean and you know leave it better than
you found it and i really would love to
see you go national with this if not
international
this because you know from the rumors
I've heard people smoke this stuff
everywhere so the potential is pretty
huge well you know we want to do we want
to take exactly we're doing here this
conversations and take that across this
country so that people can very quickly
not have to take ten years to learn we
can get them up to speed and that's just
a critical important thing for us right
now because you can see this country in
this world it's not inclusive it's not
community it's not I mean it used to be
you grew up in a neighborhood and
everybody in that neighborhood was part
of your hood it didn't matter you were
all the hood and it was across the whole
world
and now look at what we become in the
cannabis world now unfortunately a lot
of dog-eat-dog is starting to happen
because people are starting to be
worried about their their brands their
livelihoods and instead of everybody
being an outlaw where it's us against
them
now it's becoming it's all of us against
everybody because we're trying to fight
for our lives and we got to really stop
that and really hold together as a team
that's why we're trying to teach people
how to manufacture we teach people how
to make 6-4 6-2 are full amount we don't
hold back on anything that we do because
it's got to be open source and it's got
to be a community well one thing you can
see quite obviously from the analysis
the last few years is that varieties
that have high terpene levels are
consistently and in the winning circle
absolutely the theis THC is never won
any of our contests people have come in
several times and told me they got the
is THC and they're gonna win and I tell
them all I'll bet you a hundred bucks
you don't it's the balance of the
cannabinoids and the terpenes in our
case I thought that it'd only be OGS and
fuels that would win and then all of a
sudden you add the green queen a green
crack you had the lemon skunk you had
these different things come in last year
skittles and so for us our judges have
really moved towards those terpene
profiles and that balance and it's been
nice to see so this Merit receptor that
you see that it really is the higher
terpene profiles that a lot of our
judges look for but the real truth the
real truth is that
terpenes on an average used to be one
and a half two percent of
dry weight total now they're moving up
towards 5% and a few individuals have
been created which are 10% 10% terpenes
that's amazing and what do you what do
you think the concentrate on those
terpenes would be if you did an
extraction that's I don't know I haven't
done it and I I did not do this chirping
work but friends of mine did do it and
5% several people I know have fibers but
a few people even have tethers because
it's just interesting it you get a lot
of people talking about the addition of
cannabis derived terpenes and maybe
there's a going to be a number where
it's too high terpenes being
hydrocarbons but maybe we are already
seeing for the lasts you know maybe
decade to two decades that we've been
smoking some fairly high percentages of
terpenes in our extractions well the
best way is when you have a contest like
Tim's at the Emerald cup and the winners
are consistently those that are also
highest intervenes there's there it's
not a coincidence
if that's for sure now I think we should
go back and do some research because the
testing all came in so late you know I
got a midnight I haven't gone back and
looked at that data and we have all the
data from all those concentrates and
we'll bring that into the cannabis
Country Fair because I think that's
really you know a great great suggestion
to to really look at these two European
profiles in the concert right now the
cartridge is pushing 15 bands got stuff
came in over 14 you got really credible
13 levels I don't know how high they go
of where the balance would be let's just
omit that so much research that we have
so much data we almost have to hire
somebody just to start mining all the
data and giving us information and I was
talking about herbal terpene levels of
one or two percent now up to five and a
few individuals have been created which
are 10 the extracts I I don't even know
how how high those numbers would go yeah
I think they'd be pretty high
I'll have that information by the canvas
country fair we're gonna put that up I
wrote it down you got some great notes
that's fantastic to him I can't thank
you enough for coming on with us this
morning I know it's Father's Day and you
got stuff to do
but I'm excited to go to your event and
I hope a lot of people attend again it's
like his Country Fair mm-hmm I I want to
thank you for producing all these
amazing events that I can't come to
maybe one day you'll come up to Canada
or Jamaica and put put it a bit VIP
tickets if you can make it I know you
can't but one day we'll get you there or
we'll get over there Todd and I'll make
it you guys are like I said all invited
come up you can camp backstage with us
to do whatever you want
Todd you've been a great support a great
voice of reason I got you down in LA I'm
up here in the the Triangle and it's
like we're both representing the same
things we want the same things and we're
seeing the same things happen so I can't
imagine what we'll be in five years how
many products how many new industries
how many things we'll have to talk about
it'll be tough for the farmers in the
transition but overall like you said for
the world and for all of us it's just
going to be an amazing new dawn we're
coming into a new world okay I said you
know my upside of this Tim is I've been
growing my own stuff since I was 13 and
if a 13 year old kid can grow it in his
closet without his grandma learning him
let you know finding out he's doing it
for a whole year I didn't get caught for
a year anyone can grow their own
cannabis it may not be worth much
anymore to do it but you're also not
gonna go to jail so you're not gonna
lose your [ __ ] you're not gonna get your
doors kicked in or your dog shot so have
your Gardens I mean to me that's gonna
be a beautiful day so I'm sorry a lot of
people are gonna get flushed out of the
industry but I'm really glad a lot of
people are gonna are gonna really get
introduced to cannabis on an economical
level so that they can use as much of it
as they want and people need to realize
that the worth of cannabis isn't all
monetarily there is an incredible
relationship to be had when you start
using this plant when you start eating
the essential oil rich seeds and oils
when you start consuming the
cannabinoids whether oral
or through vaporization or smoking there
are relationships that are created
through that and that to me has always
been the worth of cannabis and people
have to realize that high prices are
really an artifact of prohibition there
would be no high prices like this I mean
traveling around the world
I bought kilos of Simpson Mia for three
dollars and fifty cents because it was
barely prohibited in that area now look
we didn't come up in the mountains I
didn't come up here all those years ago
to make a bunch of money
I came up because I refused to stop
smoking cannabis and put me in prison
they could do it but I was going to do
what I wanted to and that's just the way
it was and all the rest of the guys did
I can tell you right now that you don't
see the gauntlet in Northern California
anymore there used to be people pulled
over every day two or three as you drove
down to the Bay Area they're gone
those cops know they can't get a
conviction even though it's not even all
the way legal yet it's over there are no
more gauntlet runs throughout Northern
California and hallelujah you know what
they're bringing the cannabis down safe
and easy nobody's going to jail like
Todd said we've all gonna live in a
great world and to me it's nothing but
goodness and so I'm you know I just like
I said the only is I think it happened
very quickly but in some ways child
we've been talking about this for 10 15
years every year it's gonna be hit so I
can go both so you know and I feel I
feel my brothers and sisters growing in
and that I get it I totally understand
the loss of an economic opportunity
opportunity but at the same time it's
another opportunity that's good for
everybody
and you know hey cannabis for all I
think should be our new motto to be
honest yeah thank you for being as well
not by next year thank you for being a
leader at least not only with just your
emerald-cut but also saying you can step
it up a bit and doing with your country
fair so thank you for constantly raising
the bar and I look forward to a great
success for you
thank you guys hope you can join us
y'all got tickets let me know we'd love
to have everybody up here we'll get you
guys anything we can Todd and I'll
continue thanks for everything you do
you guys I respect you very much good
luck with your puke adventures Jim yeah
we're all yours bro we're all we're all
rooting for you
absolutely thanks so much for first
blessing us with your presence on hash
Church and anytime you want to come back
and share what it is you're up to of
course you are welcome no no no sherry
the last going-away thing I lived up
here illegal my family couldn't come up
here because it was all too too
dangerous now I've got 20 different
family members nieces and nephews all
moved up in the last six months two of
my three kids are here I just picked my
grandson up just graduate from high
school he's been growing to plants in
Georgia for the last three years and now
he's working on 10,000 and I got my
whole family coming up because it's safe
for them to come in and not worry about
going to prison and we can all be proud
of it so we're gonna have to have a
Father's Day for the first time with my
whole family in probably 20 years out
here and I'm very happy that this has
happened so that we can do these types
of things so I'm really excited about
where we're going and I look forward to
doing it with all you guys
that's amazing man enjoy your family
have a great Father's Day and thanks for
coming out Tim take care thank you much
love how amazing is that
hey like that you really see the change
now do you think Alma had a lot to do
with that Todd having his family move up
in the last six months well or it's just
the last five years it's it's been it's
been an evolution of change of culture I
mean yet we were all afraid of putting
our families through what I've went
through I mean etn had to clean up the
mess of boy one of the messes of my life
so you know I hate that burden on the
people I love and to experience it with
the people that you're you know your
family your your daughter's your your
sons and to have them it's it's people
just sometimes don't understand or
remember how friggin ugly it really was
for a long time and to me it makes me so
happy to hear that now he can with a
paranoia
invite the people he loves to the place
that he grows and and literally
celebrate life instead of having to
worry about that you know that the man
was common and they're gonna kick down
your still and shoot your dog and
can ruin your life man I mean no way
well now not only that he can attract
now professionals to run that you know
look we all specialize in our own
aspects of what we're very good in and
look I know when I don't have expertise
in something I hire experts who do and
when you when he listed off the cadre
that he has running the show it shows
how serious they were taking and that
they really want to feel that level and
that's what it takes you have to have
production companies you have to have
people running things properly that have
done this before I mean it it helps
greatly look I'm not saying that you
don't do it but it very much helps when
you have all the contacts as you said
when bands come to you as opposed to
going to bands it's a whole different
dynamic all together and let me throw
this out you know again I never wanted
to be in a disrespectful way to high
times because if it wasn't for the
cannabis cups we would not have a lot of
the cannabis consciousness we have so
props to Haggar props the high times
props to stand keeping up the torch lit
and running with it and you know one of
the things that I think is good is that
high times now has new ownership they
have very professional leadership that's
going to come in and be able to execute
the cannabis cup in ways that they've
never been able to in the past so we're
gonna see a whole new face on this and
if they're listening I just say this I
hope that they take on an environmental
and and and a social event of social
responsibility and high ethic and
morality to what they're trying to do
because we need to set a good example
and if they don't who will
I don't you know so well and you'll also
see what Tim does ripple into other
events you know we all know that there's
how many events do you guys have up in
there in Canada John and and bubble man
you guys have you know competitions as
well and we have so many here in the
United States and so they're spread all
over the world but they're looking to
who's what standards are and so this
gives us another standard set to compare
to to say hey this competition is doing
this not only the environmentally sound
but they're also doing it by terpenes
it's it's accelerating the conversation
so people laymen or force to get
terpenes water Turkey
it's gonna elevate the entire
conversation to a point of understanding
that I think that the fringe are well
aware of as because I'd consider us the
fringe because we're the less than 10%
of 10% but it brings an opening to the
rest of the community so that people go
away and then all these magazines
because there's like 20 to 40 different
magazines here in United States now that
will cover that information and make
people aware that oh this is how things
are done at this competition this is how
that's done there and it's gonna cause
people like High Times to go hey maybe
this we should it's gonna force them
economically or through the competition
and realizing how natural people go I've
been to the High Times event up north
and I've been to the Emerald cup and
there is no competition in size that
Emerald cup draws in comparison to High
Times again no offense to high tech I
got married at the High Times Cannabis
Cup God was my best man there I met
bubble man there I met Sam Scott man
there so it's without a doubt they they
have their place in history but at the
same time it's taking it and elevating
it and it's great to see that this
freedom with all mother's freedoms that
are given now with 64 that can push the
allows this type of discussion not only
that competition not only that that labs
are calibrated and up to this point that
we can actually having this conversation
right now as opposed to hoping that one
day so we still have a ways to go with
with testing but at the same time it
shows us how far that we've come and
very much excites me as down this
precipice and is to look over the
horizon to see what's coming no it's
great I think a lot of good things are
happening and you know and you know
props to Steve a girl when the cannabis
cup first started he was bringing in the
whole environmental hemp information
into cannabis and trying to expand the
consciousness of the culture and talk
about a lot more than just you know who
had the best weed he was trying to bring
in spirituality he was trying to bring
environmentalism
he was the guy that put you know at jack
harries book almost in every other issue
of high times for the awesome free free
smooth space
nonprofit groups that were Pro hamper
pro-environment and so he did even
though he thinks I'm a CIA agent uh I
still give him props for what he did oh
dude I got an email I got a message of
you bro that's so huge of you III think
that he's gone a little off the wagon
these days with some of the accusations
you've made and for you to say that is
great at the thing listen threw out
against you I think are brutally wrong
on every level so it's awesome for you
to say that oh yeah
I admire you a little more all the time
sir that rumor is still going on and I
got hit yesterday from some Instagram
telling that same [ __ ] story a Sam's
a CIA agent yeah here at it every it's
just such [ __ ] that I get quite
offended when I get like where I come
from it's really simple if you want to
say that someone has ratted someone out
you produce a document and that is the
only way if you don't have that document
you shut the [ __ ] up and sit down
and that's just where I come from it's a
very very very very dangerous accusation
to make where I come from and you better
have the paper to back it up so yeah
it's [ __ ] yes super [ __ ] anyway
that's my rant let's possible just
defended my mentor you know Frank of 18
shots makes me want to cry that what
that I will do hey welcome D 420k and
Johnny B and marks Cal don't [ __ ] we got
talking there I didn't even welcome you
guys to the room my apologies father
love birthday father lovers yes this
ball grips for you daddy Oh
each of us had a dad hey yeah what's
everybody puffing on I'm puffing on this
nice Kongo haze cuz I love the haze
thank you have recessed racks I'm doing
the first bounce of the many push off
the screens it's just most like water
tasty
melts like water hey and it tastes good
too Sam I'm not gonna lie it's it's it's
nice I'll hit this Justin Trudeau push
bubble hash pardon me for my dirty
camping nails there we go boom a little
bit of grease there
thank you for help for you reminder from
our man camp yesterday and sitting in
the Argo and I was just like I hope you
had an epic time of Finland they were
asking where's Johnny be where's the
Argo we had an awesome time I did my
wake-and-bake for some reason I had a
Wi-Fi sore a signal for my phone that I
could get on to not Wi-Fi but my actual
and I managed to pull it off each day so
it was kind of hilarious good times lots
of dirt bike riding many many many hours
of dirt bike riding I fell off my dirt
bike a couple of really good times thank
God I wear full gear from like head to
toe but man I'll tell you I'm cool
though cool Wow sleeping in the tent was
a bit cold we were at 3,200 feet so you
could see your breath it was probably
one or two degrees above zero I think
that's about thirty degrees Fahrenheit
for the Americans did you bring the
portable hidden like I was hitting this
the whole time I just brought this that
was fun I love taboo 1302 is freezing so
birdy
no freezing okay so then it would be
like 35 38 maybe III don't know under 40
degrees you should have been making some
hash of that there was only a couple
degrees Celsius above zero so dry system
there next time so so dabbers since
bubbleman and Johnny and others here
actually dab what is your preferred
cotton-tipped user there's now a
different manufacturers of course q-tips
is of course the one that's out there
but there's now different manufacturers
or people that are promoting these
different types I was just wondering
what's your favorite item on your cotton
and wood or something instead of any
plastic yuck yep yep
yep that's definitely on it but at the
same time I will say this I also used
mostly I like the big wood ones with the
pointy tips because I was really
thinking you had to scrape but as I
learned to do the low low low temp I
learned that at the end of my rip it's
just a puddle I can just pick it up with
any kind of [ __ ] q-tip and especially
because I use DC glass cleaner I just
put a tiny bit on the q-tip and it just
swoops right up I don't care what kind I
use I think the more important thing for
me is the DC glass cleaner I've taken
people tile 't paper as a glass cleaner
if they can micro encapsulate it have it
stuck on the thing so it doesn't
evaporate I've taken I forgot my patrina
for I had something but it's all good
I'm gonna hit a rip that's a great idea
and somebody's gonna come up with that
there's there's got to be something
where they'll actually have you know
where it stays on the actual tip so you
can actually just swab it to me the DC
glass cleaner is wake more important
than any q-tip because I can make a
q-tip out of anything to clean the DC
glass cleaner up if I can just pour some
into my quartz it's gonna pick
everything up and boil it right out of
the out of the bowl press it I've used
it a it is impressive when I've actually
applied to my quartz it's it's
dumbfounding how fast it actually causes
everything marks Cal don't Sheldon in
his non-chlorinated water karanji oil
processed coconut extract processed kelp
extract and process extract of sugarcane
it's mostly water but the way it the oil
kind of soaks up a little bit they've
made videos of these greasy greasy like
fully reclaimed like burnt black glass
bowls putting it inside of this liquid
boiling and it just literally melts the
resin off and D Chason eights I would
have called it the D Chaz
the ditches Nader nice yeah the DJ fix
all of my balls
Wow no no no let me think
listen you chat you've charged those out
so bad there this is the difference I'm
not talking about the the gray destroyed
smokey cloudy Bowl I'm talking if you
get a little black on your bowl and you
can be smart enough to not burn it with
your torch because that's what we all
want to do it's just like let's just
burn it off I don't want to see it
anymore once you've done that you're
[ __ ] the courts pretty good
from my perspective I it's just my
opinion I'm not not an expert or
anything but yeah become experts on
coals because I the reason why is
because the the mineral components were
left behind i right into that's like a
salt layer that sort of does not come
right and once it starts building up
right infuses and makes like a a mixed
oxide with the glass itself so it sort
of uses with it so it becomes like yeah
if you start scraping it you're actually
scraping the glass yeah but um so let me
just understand I think we've talked
about this cleaner once before right
mark so you you you put this on but you
immediately wipe it up right like it
doesn't leave a residue behind here's
the most important thing for me okay I
have a heightened sense of smell and
taste kind of to the degree of it being
more of a bummer
than a good thing because trust me there
are plenty of shitty tasting things and
tons of bad smelling things like I'm
that guy if I'm talking to someone and
they have bad breath I can't be like
three to four feet within them or I'm
just like dude please go [ __ ] floss
your teeth it's gonna throw up so it's
it's kind of like if there's anything
weird in anything I taste it this has
never left a taste in my bowl it
evaporates out completely like water it
doesn't leave any residue at all and I
just wipe it up with q-tips til it's
till it's dry and then generally the
next time I go to smoke I heat my courts
up so I don't even see smoke come off
the courts when I'm heating it up unless
I've left resin
there'd been a little bit inefficient in
my cleaning but you said it acts like a
soap I got like a soapy kind of action
to it did you say well there yeah that
karanji
oil almost you know if I were to do this
yeah seize it emotion right yeah well
suffice not not not a huge percentage
but there you know like I bet you the
karanji oil content is very low like
probably under 10 percent sure it's
mostly water right most mostly water you
can see the color even is very just off
a little bit but mark if anyone else use
grunt dog I use grunge off and in fact
it's reminiscent of grunge often before
I saw grunge off I'll never forget this
I was in my friends coffee shop in
Amsterdam the amnesia coffee shop and
I'm sitting there with the budtender and
he's like I've got this new bomb cleaner
and I'm like mom like what kind of bomb
cleaner he's like it's not from
chemicals you know it's he's talking
about how it was from an enzyme or
something from a soybean like something
they extracted from a soybean to produce
this very organic you could drink it it
wouldn't get you sick it tasted shitty
but you could clean your bong and it's
basically the next time I saw it and how
I knew it was very much the same thing
was because when I touched it it was
almost impossible to get off your hands
like you had to wash your hands for
[ __ ] five minutes to get this [ __ ] to
come off your hands and grunge off was
was different but identical Richard took
it and created a different property he
marketed it and bottled it and I
supported grunge off for years I still
do it's a great product I just don't
really my glass I cleaned so often with
a little bit of hot water you give it a
shake and dump it out at the end of the
night maybe a shot
tiny little shot of ISO in there just
cuz it's quick and fast but the my
biggest deal nowadays is just cleaning
my quartz I'm it would be interesting to
see if grunge off worked to clean quartz
in a similar way so Martin I squash
question like if you have like a dirty
rig like if you have your rig and you've
poured all your rig water out yeah now
you're ready to put the cleaner in and
there's like globules of reclaim they're
in there well well this stuff
just act to dissolve all those globules
you know like rule shaking and mark
showed it to me it was he boiled water
imported in his bong and Barcelona yeah
that's what you have to do thick stuff
and then used a little bit of ISO and
cleaned it and it came out great and
ever since he did that I have a hot
water tap at my house that's separate
from my faucet so I used the you know
the the really hot water rinse it out
and get all that all what you're
speaking of out of there cuz as soon as
the heat hits it it loosens up and
agitates and then I soak it with runs
off and the stuff comes out mean I
soaked this yesterday for that done your
three entire effect you pour directly
your liquid reclaim down a drain I I
wouldn't because it could gak up your
pee your fight poster what is inside the
cold surface suwanee inside of your
pipes it's going to solidify like a
arterial plaque inside an athlete's
corrosive patient so yeah absolutely
should not pour reclaimed down the sink
hey Sam hey Sam yes would you mind
would you mind enlightening these fellas
too broken more glass pipes and any
other human being on the planet earth
who didn't mean to but I've also clogged
more pipes cleaning my bones
dude you're the reason I don't pour
reclaimed down mice down my sink like
today well you not for several years or
even five or ten years but if you live
in the same place you don't want to do
it didn't you have to remove the pipe
and it was just like full of reclaim yes
like a [ __ ] lilo I don't know how
much it was whether they called like
snakes
you know those pipe snakes yeah and he
says what the hell is this Oh black crap
but it wasn't liquid anymore it dried
and hardened out and it was like Chris
Foley
my god you're alright I can actually
speak to this because I've actually I
dot I don't boil my glass I have done
actually cold soaks where I've just
poured a grunge off directly into old
pipes in fact I did this with a pipe
that I had from the 90s an old pipe that
I have from Oh glass blower that just
had resident I just soaked it and then
I'd pour it back into a separate
container and then rinse it out but when
I'd take that the grunge off if you put
it through a coffee filter it'll
actually go back into its container and
you can reuse it oh yeah yeah IV ivory
used the same bottle of grunge off for
months I actually just went by a couple
swings and all fun if you have them for
six months dude I have mine from years
right and if you can if you have just
making people where if you actually
filter your stuff you can reuse this for
years because it said well it's a great
cleaner you can sit cold because again
I'm fearful of that hot water in glass
just myself because I've seen and people
who do good things and Marcus what's the
new glass cleaner as well that you're
talking about I have that and I have to
say I'm absolutely amazed and somebody
said over here in the chat that Oh
sponsored by I'm like no we're not
sponsored by X by everything that I have
and that stuff's not cheap but it's well
worth it and that's one reason why you
can recycle it and reuse it is because
it is expensive so you know just get
some coffee filters and an actual a
little spigot there to go in and you're
good to go well this stuff is super
cheap it's like eight bucks a bottle if
you buy it buy the case or twenty bucks
on Amazon or something and it's not
reusable
I don't own a shares in the company I'm
not paid by the company but I do give
bottles of it away but Markus if you use
poured a bottle of that down my clogged
pipe do you think it would have worked I
think that if we poured boiling water
down your pipe for quite a while and
then poured it down I think it would
have been quite effective yeah but it
would have come out the top of your sink
yeah well
that is how the pipes got clogged was
with dr. Bronner's yeah dr. Bronner's
and boiling water Marcus is the pee the
dead stuff I'm not sure that it says the
pH on here but I could ask Mick
I'm gonna go throw it in a pH meter yeah
each of that is I'm really curious leave
soaking into a glass is clean yeah so I
haven't even cleaned glass with it I
just use it on my bangers but I'll tell
you I don't want to hit my torch my
banger with a torch if I don't have the
DC glass cleaner if I don't have q-tips
it's okay I can get something straight
break off a little piece of paper or
toilet paper or paper towel and make a
ball and that's like my q-tip that's
unimportant important is that I have
this little bit of liquid to clean the
bowl nicely important to me anyway
greaser I'm thinking that it would you
know like like grease is grease right
well just to clean out pipes and it's a
real big thing in the in the wintertime
when pipes start getting cold and and
and oil becomes difficult to flow and
yeah I mean anything that can you'd be
used to degrease could be having all
kinds of industrial applications yeah
would you like me to send you a bottle
mark can you of course
yeah just send me an email with your
where you want it sent bc bubbleman at
icloud.com
I always used a small amount of ethanol
it absolutely gets things sparkling
clean sure I just love the fact that
this is non-toxic it's just simple it's
like I put it in little I usually have
it in these little vials I'll fill up
like 10 of these and just roll with them
I give them to people too because it's a
nice little thing you get maybe like 10
or 15 cleans out of it and it does the
job it does the job I can hear my little
guy in the other room getting all
excited I was away camping for quite a
few days so we're
have a nice day today for Father's Day
Father's Day what are you doing for dads
day dad's I see three three dads here
yeah dad's lots of dads I honestly get
absolutely nothing for Father's Day that
was different than any other day oh [ __ ]
I've rented a submarine and my family
and I are going to be checking out the
bottom of the ocean near the house sound
I'm joking I like wish he had children
no but that submarine sounds really cool
allons you know recovery vessels but
this whole yacht thing that seems like a
lot of fun but I'll leave the kids
tomorrow well one of the guys I camp
with he'd uh he builds sonars for
submarines it's probably why it was on
my mind and why I made the joke but this
summer for two months he's going off to
New Brunswick and there's this area of
the Atlantic Ocean where like from the
13th 14th century or whatever on there's
been thousands of boats sink in this
area it's just brutal so he's going on
the submarine to go recover a particular
vessel from like the 14th century how
deep is the sub as deep as they go like
he builds he did sonar for the British
Navy and he's been on military subs with
the u.s. like this guy is said he's a
serious sonar genius guy so he's yet he
gets sick on submarines can you imagine
I I get seasick quite easily but imagine
your job was to build sonar systems and
tests he has to go down and the subs to
test it it's like Jesus okay so you
wanted to know the pH solution so yes
kind of curious myself too so I ran up
to the garage ground pH meter it's
sitting out like six one
does it surprise me it's mostly water
move attire is it hitting ten three days
four so it's very much really really hot
out the line this question right and
it's something I can do right quick for
you guys so it's like right move yeah
then six seven so it's really really hot
yes
yeah that's white immediately emulsifies
the oil is way it just bubbles right off
a little bit works it's like a magic
trick
it's like watching yeah I want to be a
chemist when I grow up
dude you should man you know a lot about
chemistry actually it always kind of
surprises me I'm like this [ __ ]
should get a degree oh wait someday I'll
do something I want to be the king of
mainstream cannabis when I grow up
oh dude the chemistry you can be the
king of chemistry our Ian's already the
king of cannabis so you can't be that
but oh you got kraut
I want to be able to do chemistry by
just thinking about it so you don't have
to touch it you just think about it and
it did we even have our franco rip it
seemed like that kind of dissipated did
we all get together and say let's have a
rip for Franco ie we all hit it at the
same time let's get our bongs together
we got a dabber remember doing this
several times but let's do it again
one minute time mr. Franco whatever you
got everybody in the shower everybody
everyone why don't we let Darren lead us
into this one song riff everybody
every lover while you mother loving
father loving people out there happy
father all right that was appropriate
all right P Franco well I think he lived
his life the way he wanted to and how
else that's that that is what to be able
to live your dreams and manifest them
that is the ultimate thing to me to be
honest
did you know personally Sam what is that
do you know him oh absolutely tell us
some stories about him I don't really
know him in-depth but I met him numerous
numerous times and we talked about many
issues and I liked him well whereas his
partner I don't want to say anything if
I can't say something good about
something so I won't talk about what
kind of strange
did you know everybody loved
Franco Franco has been involved in the
European cannabis scene going back 90
obviously loved cannabis yeah we talked
to him about indica he loved his indica
I never deep conversation with Franco
every time I saw him at the tea white
copper when I was in Amsterdam and
whenever I saw him about the see Franco
always got the cups of the events once
here in Vancouver and what he just loved
to talk about the plant and the growing
and and and he was just so in depth with
the way he fashioned and talked I love
talking with Franco and he's definitely
an inspiration and I know he definitely
loved his indica and we talked about I
definitely had seen him bumped into him
in like
half a dozen countries at least from
like all over Europe even in Jamaica the
one of the last times I saw him was with
Tony and they were just standing on the
side of the road at a jerk chicken shack
at like 1:30 or 2:00 in the morning and
we kind of pulled over cuz my soup guy
was right next door across the street
but I always go to the vegetarian soup
guy and we look across the street and
there's like Arion and dusty and Franco
pretty pretty funny too you know the
love of cannabis brings the same people
to the same places you know you can be
in the middle of nowhere in the north of
India you can be like in a ganja field o
world it's a small world it's a small
world getting smaller but when Franco if
you engaged in Franco with a
conversation regarding cannabis a
serious conversation regarding cannabis
you were immediately a brother you were
immediately a sister he just engaged you
with just a love and an appreciation and
yeah his his knowledge institutional
knowledge of cannabis and phenotypes and
just smelling it I would watch him smell
a cannabis and look at it and in the way
that I you know I had learned to but he
just his passion was so infectious and
his love for cannabis was just
undeniably it came through in every
sentence that he spoke and he was very
direct about what he expected one in his
cannabis but his love and appreciation
overall for every person who engaged
with him was humbling and beautiful to
watch because his his knowledge was just
yeah very few people I know have that
type of knowledge in them thank you did
we see chimera come in here at one point
in time yes nice I'm here what's up guys
how's it going dude not bad how you
doing dude I'm missing that pine and
lime
yeah the live in pine the Lyman pine
dude chimera brought this nugget over
here I love you know what I really you
what you did and I and you've talked
about it it sort of showed me a little
bit of
future and you came over here and you
were like you had your little bag of
herb it was like a quarter pound or
something you're like I didn't have any
concentrates so I thought I'd bring some
herb we could squish well I did have
concentrates they were just not
consumable by you right right I ate
exactly yes not knows directed I didn't
I didn't look I didn't want to wave in
your face right right no problem that's
cool but anyway the bud had this
beautiful smile like it was very unique
it has there was a sweet skunk esque
whatever that is I would have thought
that was like terpene Helene what what
what do you think that is chimera it's
probably the pioneer combination with
the lemony also wow yeah just the
combination of the to make this most
unique and Wow was the high every unique
- we made some really nice Roz and I
wished I had photographed it better
because we would have been able to throw
up a picture I like the name instead of
mine pie at pie line well it was like he
hadn't written like lime and pine or
pine in lime on the bag as in the two
dominant terpenes as in he didn't even
know the name of the cultivar I was like
that's the [ __ ] right there I like that
yeah the names aren't important right
it's the chemical profile that's
important yeah and so I'm starting to
rename things based on just based on
that because I think it gives the most
information right what do you think
about Tim's new contest
I've already copyrighted all of the
turkey what do you think of the new
contest broke it down by five different
cannabinoids five different terpenes I
haven't seen it actually um I put a
little something in the chat the links
in it in our chat right there you can
click on it well I didn't come I wasn't
in then so I don't see that here really
it will be the future obviously yeah
it'll be right up your alley for sure
chimera cool so our Alex Jen coming in
alright you're late Tim was here came
here and doing dad stuff
and Alex I don't know what happened Alex
he tends to sleep in I'm guessing he had
a really good good
and some did fine so they back the cop
down by does that oh you cut out there
for a second
your voice is breaking though go again
right that's great well I be you know I
would tell these guys they need to do
this since you know we started doing the
terpene classes because it judge wine
it's the same thing right like yeah it's
it it close the similarity is to wine or
beer to a lesser degree now that's
pretty cool
let's you know it's pretty cool so it's
classified by the dominant terpene and
it's for THC varieties rather than type
2 or type 3 and you're gonna test both
the concentrate in the plant that's the
myth of the rumor yes that'd be cool I
think it's gonna be a Fanta as like that
they're changing things I think it's a
fantastic way to change things based on
science and not speculation and I've
always thought that the that the classes
were stupid you know especially when
mostly everything is is hybrids and
there's no real true Hayes's in the
contest anyway that I would even almost
remotely almost want a mistakenly call
sativa so it's always been this whack
mix of hybrids that they try to identify
as sativa indica and other and I've
always thought it was dumb so this at
least is based on some accurate like a
profile a unknown terpene profile and
then it comes I think varieties that are
similar to each other a better chance of
competing with one another yeah but I
mean I mean when you look at all the
terpene classes there's more to it than
just the dominant terpene for example so
I mean this is a good start and I don't
you know I'm not trying to poopoo their
their new method but it's it's not
example is hiding like you can have
there's multiple different terpene
classes
the tiny superclass right right it's
taking one instrument out of an entire
Orchestra and trying to figure out what
piece to the orchestras playing yeah
exactly so it's like maybe that is the
loudest note but it's kind of and whare
with music because that's what they did
a little genotype to music and it is
it's like who's the loudest horn and and
in a way it but it's a lot better than
you know the made-up names that the
growers were calling it anyway even
though it's too simple it's a start it
is a start no it is a start and it's
it's putting us on the right behalf you
know saying that it's like have you got
a cookies in an ogee like cookies no grr
relatively close
I would I would say that they're you
know they're in the same type right
but typically og is especially what's
grown well it's like limonene dominant
it's not usually Terry awfully dominant
but cookies for example is Kerri awfully
need ominous right so it's like those
are two plants that smell kind of
similar but they're gonna end up in
different classes here well og is a an
OG as a hell of a lot closer to cookies
then for example say Barry White right
so it kind of does chop them up in a way
that's later we we've got to understand
the individual notes before we can
understand the Suites when when there's
a a complex combination of notes you
know that that may be everybody's
favorite in the end but we have to start
someplace
ya know an allergy there's classic music
there's bluegrass music there's jazz
music these are all different classes
that all get awarded Grammys right
there's Grammys awarded in all of those
categories so I think the categorization
that Ryan is referring to something
based on how it actually tastes maybe
there could be more broader categories
on citrus and how the terpene profile
expresses the citrus flavor could be a
limonene dominance
it could be a citral dominance so there
could be all kinds of different other
notes that are right underneath the main
note and the predominant dripping there
to really give the overall flavor in
essence so why don't we just base it on
you know the human how that's yeah okay
when you do like the terpene suite so
imagine you have like you know it's like
saying okay this is a three-piece band
with like a keyboard a drum and a bass
player right and so you compare all
those different types of three-piece
bands that are keyboard bass and and and
a drummer and a percussionist right and
that's gonna have a different sound than
a guy on a guitar you know like a single
guy in the guitar or like a guitar and a
bass and a drummer right like they're
gonna have different sounds so yeah it's
a start it's a start I think it's and
it's you know we're teaching people
right so it's a start but it's also
predicated on very reproducible results
I mean so do all gorilla glues fit a
carry off lean the dominance or just
certain well no that's that's what I'm
saying like environmental effects of
your grow contain your energy your seem
dominant or they can push the limonene
up and then it's limonene dominant but
really it's still beta carry awfully Mir
seen and lemony right over the top 3 and
Ryan isn't it true that carry awfully
and is essentially ubiquitous and all
green plants right I think if you
extract just about any green plant on
earth you'll find carry awfully it's one
of those ubiquitous terpenes that just
everywhere yeah I mean it's really
prevalent it's not ubiquitous though
because you can you can knock out the
sex kotor beings and have varieties that
are just monitoring there that are
almost only mono Terps right it's
prevalent in most essential oils that
i've looked at like mint oils gets in
capital I know it's experiment
peppermint too as well I just assume
that it's just one of those compounds
that if if there are glandular trichomes
it's in there carey awfully just like
one of those basic molecules that
subscribe yeah but it's funny though
because let me when you know when they
pursued corn and they went after the
sweet corn and they start
Bradon for sugar content you know it's
like like you with selections when you
select for one thing you're
unconsciously selecting against
something else right and it turns out
that most modern corn varieties have
actually purged at beta Kari awfully um
which is which is strange because beta
carotene is a compound that's kind of
it's bitter tasting to bugs right or
it's even produced in roots right so
like there's corn variety they have
these corn varieties that are how the
high sugar varieties they get worked
over by you know certain grubs and stuff
in the soil and they're actually now
going back and breeding beta carotene
back into the court Wow I'll find out
let me just give me two seconds I'll
find a paper post oh they're the
shrunken or the SU or the s you Yi or do
you know which version it is that you're
talking about I'll get the paper and put
them up and then you can have a look
okey-dokey wow that's crazy I know that
they were trying to put protein content
now I know this was like high lysine
corns corns that you know are
genetically modified to do all kinds of
stuff but man it's yeah it's they they
have what they call a you know sweet and
super sweet and the super sweets also
have when you get the bits the corn seed
for planting it's it's shrunk up like a
raisin I mean yeah I mean here here in
the mid-atlantic there's something
called Jersey white corn and I guess
it's maybe native to New Jersey it's
small little pearl giblets and they're
just wonderful it's only basically
harvested at this time of year from now
to like maybe you know the end of
harvest but it's it's wonderfully sweet
it's great it's the best corn on the cob
you've ever had you can just eat it
without even cooked
that probably could he is laughing
butter salt over it is too he'll like it
right oh yeah all right so I've slipped
you papers in our chat and for anybody
that's in the the viewers chat
it's called amaze beta Kari awfully nice
in phase implicated in indirect defense
responses against herbivores it's not
expressed in most American mains
varieties that's what it's called that's
the paper yeah all right I'll try to
paste that into the chat room so they
can try to find the link maybe I can
even just paste the link into the chat
room yeah they can just google that and
they'll find it'll come up but and then
just you know if people are looking to
want to find the paper sigh huh I don't
see they weren't looking at the big
picture they were strictly focusing at
the small picture and they were
incredibly successful at creating what
they did do America but remember what
they were doing was looking for corn or
looking for high sugar content oh I know
exactly what them and they were very
very successful but they were only
looking at the picture right in front of
them and not the big picture which is
what you're talking about with this
paper yeah exactly when you go for one
thing I mean there's trade-offs right so
it's like it's like you said they're
looking at that one fine point right yep
and they were quite successful at
looking at about one fine point yeah
absolutely
but down line they realized that it was
a bad sample it was it had other
downstream effects right did you want to
talk a little bit about the effects we
got from that pine in line yeah the
bottom limonene in finding the reason
the variety is so special is that it's a
it's a rare terpene profile it falls
back to kind of the hippie weed of the
seven
you know it's like and it was really
it's like I said it was just up and
focused right yeah they are both
potentiate errs and moderators yeah but
what broccoli should affect right it
basically opens up your Airways and lets
all the other wonderful things from
cannabis in yeah and like la moneda
speeds up your heart rate and you know
that kind of gives you that cut up and
go feeling right yeah it was definitely
nice to dab we dabbed it out of
existence it would be interesting to see
the difference between one that was
slightly Lima leaned dominant or piney
down a minute mark resistancy of the
rosin was a tacky or sticky or what was
it like was it you know it was quite you
know pull and snap kind of sticky but it
looked like very very like temperature
pressure is sure it might even got one
picture on my phone it was really
light-colored yeah Marcus but
temperature and pressure you're pressing
it we press that eighty psi and the Tim
what was the temperature I missed that
oh it was about like 190 to 200 hundred
I knew there was a glassy or buttery it
was kind of in the middle of both of
them it wasn't butter in the sense that
you could pull it and it would like
stretch but it had the color of
something that like looked because the
color does do it yeah yeah but it wasn't
there was uh we did two squishes with
this one well I was I can say is isn't
life wonderful I mean I was really
impressed with that Sasquatch machine I
mean the the lemon pine it's such a low
yielding variety but you know making
extracts by putting it in the column is
not really an efficient way to go I mean
sure he'd make it you wouldn't get very
much why you'd be able to have that
sasquatch and just put in like you know
a couple of grams or whatever it was the
squeeze it out it was I mean that's a
beautiful thing it really was so right
why is that is that is that variety just
that is a low oil producer is that just
a no the amount of biomass that you get
off of a light it's not it's like it's
hard to say oh those three like that
3000 watts of electricity in like 12
weeks or 10 weeks or whatever we were
growing it for the yields such a slow
amount of flowers that some like just
take it all and load him into a column
and economically really economically
viable right so we've been really been
consuming in his flowers but you know
like we took it and put it in the
Sasquatch press with it it coughed out
some beautiful it really was the essence
of the plant I mean it was it was a
really really nice - - was that a fresh
squash or a dried bud squash it was cure
it was cured bud okay yeah it had a nice
moisture content and it wasn't like
powdery snappy but at the same time it
certainly wasn't wet yeah it was just
cure it was well cured bud that's
something that steps is about six or
eight weeks from harvest so it's been in
a bucket but it's did you know it
maintained its proper eight to ten
percent water content so this a squash
yeah it's a great little machine for
sure I'm sure they're gonna make a
smaller one so that people can you know
feel feel a little more like there might
be a little bit much having this giant
thing on at your house I got a kick out
of watching me squash it too I mean it
wasn't me weren't just watch you weren't
just using your eyes you're using your
ears and your nose to like you know kind
of like the resin whisperer
just a second man I'm listening quiet
herb talking to him it was saying
that was cool those I mean really I I'll
come back and squish more cuz it's like
that's the way to consume it those death
so tasty I mean they were just so tasty
even the way it smells like fresh you
know you could just be like oh my god
some of those terpenes they're just very
nice don't write your opinion that
that's something that can be done you
know commercially the squishing you know
to make rosin as a concentrated product
in Canada yeah absolutely this is not a
very active all can up to a process
where you're you know I saw someone
posted a 300 gram shatter pad Pattie
that they had done looks a lot like
that's the type of process that you need
you need to be producing at 300 grams at
a time like producing a gram at a time
isn't gonna cut it in a legalization
world right like that's more of a home
user kind of type of thing oh yeah
even 3,000 you know like 30,000 grams
like who knows how it's crazy to think
that well I guess there is enough
cannabis being grown in the sense but
just not by licensed producers but like
licensed producers if they all got
together now could not they would not
have enough cannabis for even like a
fraction of the people that want to use
it right now it's so it's kind of
laughable that there's even this up this
option of a monopoly like that and they
can't even supply it's not a monopoly I
mean are you talking about supplying
herbally or long times that much so that
they can all make something like this I
would like concentrates myself I think
that the main reason why dispensaries
have a strong position is that they're
still offering concentrates to people
and the LPS are unable to yeah the
government really needs to deal with
that issue
I mean the whole thing is when they're
creating this legal market they need
they need Canadians to buy in right they
need to them accept that that is gonna
be the new the new source for flowers
and if you keep you know if you say
they put the dried with the dried
cannabis at first I said no you can only
consume dry cannabis you can't have oils
right you can't have extract so they
don't have the extracts available of
course the black market is gonna still
persist I know guys that are like MMAR
growers and they produce for
dispensaries and stuff but they've moved
a hundred percent to production for
extracts right that's what they do if
they grow green as we image and let's
not forget this though one major thing
the LPS would have been doing a lot
better had they not maintained the exact
same prohibition based prices for
cannabis what the [ __ ] is that
well this again it's it's typically LPS
are owned by people that are from
outside the cannabis industry I mean it
like it takes ten million dollars to get
a license right so that's not your
average stout or a grower that can come
in and compete in that they can't play
in that pool so it ends up being a bunch
of money guys and with money guys the
first thing is how do they get their
money back yeah of course the same
prohibition based prices so that's what
I mean like I think the black market
would have been more drastically
affected just like anything if all of a
sudden people can buy something it's
good quality and it's not expensive like
make it inexpensive and go for the long
game but let's flip the script I mean
how much would five star go for in in
the new model like five star should
command the highest price right but but
that price will be dependent upon how
much material we can get to grow that
kind of material you know to process
into that product and what was the cost
on doing it it was never as much as have
been based on prohibition
yeah but missions gone then the price
will be supply and demand and what the
real price to produce cost right that's
what I mean it's not there's a little
bit of a gap there in the actual
production cost and I mean they're
making it seem like well the production
costs are high because you know that
some of them are putting 30 40 million
dollars into their facilities so yeah
that is a high production cost but in
the long run it's like a toll bridge
they don't need to charge you $100 each
time because the
assistance II and the growth and the
sheer volume that will move through that
bridge will pay it off like tenfold in
like you know 20 years or something to
think about the Lyman pine again so say
say they're growing like BC grapefruit
for example their produce and two ounces
of square foot or her like you know
they're doing a gram per watt right
well the Lyman pine is gonna produce
like 200 grams for per thousand walk
light it's not going to produce a kilo
so it's it's five tighter therefore the
footprint is five times more expensive
many of your growing a high yielding
variety exactly right so instead of like
four bucks a G it will be twenty bucks
well but you're not thinking about the
rest of the world getting involved in
that same cultivar being grown in
Jamaica or Brazil or India and being
able to express that terpene expression
even better under the Sun under a hue
you know on an acreage and now we're
getting into you know the supply and
demand an agricultural product and the
price is not gonna be as high yeah
that's possible I mean that's
theoretically possible the regular don't
really we don't really go for that yet
they will they they have to once that
once America goes federal all the other
countries are just like they're so
confused by this state thing that's
happening and money that's being made
and Colorado made 200 million like it's
just like constant right all over the
world trust me beautiful governments are
seeing this [ __ ] the future of cannabis
and extract just look look at how many
countries can you buy wine from how many
countries can you buy distilled spirits
problems is the future of cannabis
international trade item and you know
what I think you can't trick go from
state to state but that's gonna change
really fast no I think you're right Sam
and I think that certain places will
uncover certain cultivars that Express
almost you know the highest expression
the the one of the in the I don't know
how to really word it properly but yeah
you know the way I bring it up all the
time French is the France is known for
some of the best lavender because for
whatever reason in that region all the
variables environmental everything adds
up to a beautiful expression of terpenes
yeah absolutely it's the same with white
I mean that's why Australians known for
sure as our Syrah grapes right they grow
really well in that area they make a
really nice product so it's obvious
cannabis will be that way both grown
outdoors in perfect conditions that
allow it to finish bully and also in
greenhouses with without supplemental
lights and darkening and in indoors
under lights if that is required for
some reason whether be legal problems or
weather or maybe medical requirements
yeah I mean we saw it will happen when
you know right now again and remember it
is all growers and they're expecting
these high prices but remember what
happened when Scott and our shanty Baba
and and all those folks were growing
down in Switzerland and they went to the
tomato growers and they said hey you
know if you get a plant we're gonna give
you the clones and if you get the plants
to knee-high they'll be worth this much
and if they get to waist high they'll be
worth this much and you know to the
tomato growers they were making like you
know a dollar two dollars or whatever
was per square foot so when when you
offered them five they were stoked I
mean the growers were so thrilled to
grow cannabis rather than tomatoes
because they made five times as much but
the reality is that to a joke or I mean
they were for the guys that were buying
it from them it was worth like twenty
dollars square foot or $30 a square foot
right so when you get the growers from
other industries involved there they're
gonna that's when the costs are really
gonna drop right because they don't have
the expectations in a cannabis grower
they have the expectation of someone
that's producing they're getting by just
producing like just a couple of dollars
per square foot yeah I will say that I
see well sorry son go ahead in the
Netherlands the margin used to be 25
cents or what could make or break would
be 50 cents of square me
but that was in the street in flower and
vegetable market yeah so when you know
on the laws change enough that all those
guys can actually get into the game
without having to go through these
insane restrictions to become a licensed
producer you know that's when we're
gonna really see the chief cannabis
coming up because it will shift from
those few people that are growing
cannabis now
- like Todd's been saying for so long
it'll be an agricultural crop where any
pot of it prices are gonna crash hey
Ryan did you see this um
PCR tool that Kevin's company released
for rusted mites
I'm putting the link up right now mark I
don't know if you can put that link in
the in the YouTube chat absolutely I
will
but um yeah yeah I was it was powdery
mildew and rusted mites right so it's
the other one yeah I mean PCR is great
method actually detecting unique DNA
sequences right so the every every
species has unique DNA sequences so you
can help are those unique sequences then
you can use them to as a probe to see
they're there I mean yeah I don't
again I don't I don't know sober killer
I'm just trying to say this will be yeah
it's another little tool in the toolbox
what I mean it's only useful is because
it only like I said I'd only detects
that one unique sequence to or that
they've identified in Britain Russert
might so so it useful for both broad my
trusted Knights and using it on little
tiny clones that you were taking if you
were gonna grow them to be a big mother
it might be no nice to know that they
were free of these problems it's so it
can be what is the diagnosis it can only
be used once the infection is taking
place or could it could look at the I
think Kevin told me that it was
effective on a single spider mite yeah
they are there well that's the beauty
thing about how PCR works is that's what
they use and we're in crime
to identify blood samples because you
can take a tiny tiny little piece of DNA
and you amplify it in the process and
you can say oh wow there's this you know
in that little tiny piece of DNA we
found this sequence right and so that
the reason I think it's useful for for
us at mites are for cyclamen mites or
whatever they are is that they're so
small they're hard to identify I can't
see him really
I mean without some handheld device I
can't see them no you see the damage but
you don't yes exactly you know
something's wrong
yeah so that'll help them you know it'll
help people identify but like if you
have an infection in one part of the
plant that's isolated from the rest of
the mass of the plant and you sample
from the rest of the mass will you also
come up with a positive hit even though
were you sampled from isn't necessarily
in fact don't think so no but you have
to have a DNA yeah that's part of the
creature now DNA doesn't deep right
these are the already moving on the
plant right right so there's nothing
systemic about infection in the plant
that now creates some kind of
biomolecule that can be worried there
might be a virus transmitted but that's
not part of the of the might directly
it's a virus but mites do spread viruses
right I mean this is how they test for
e.coli in the food supply I mean it's a
very very sensitive methodology I was
just wondering is it really and I don't
have any other person that I think is
more qualified than Ryan to understand
you know whether or not this is like
overkill or is this something that's
gonna be in every lab like everyone's
gonna have one of these things because
this is just repeat like the bee's knees
when it comes to how to determine
whether and I read ever a headdress it
might I'm not saying you can't but I
think going for forty years I've never
had breasts at mites I've never had
broad mites
yeah I mean in question as to whether
it's the overkill is it's really like do
you have the problem then it's not
overkill exactly but I mean for example
like you don't need it to identify the
two spotted spider mite because the
damage is apparent I mean it's pretty
clear when you see that right me right
know you've got mice you don't need to
code and get a PCR test to say if you
actually get webs and you're really
styling you can really tell yeah but I
mean like I said the cyclamen mites are
so small and the leaked it like it's
it's one of those one of those things
where it's like growers are like there's
something wrong with my plant what the
hell is going on
right you get the sampling symptom but
it's hard because you the mites are so
so tiny you can't see them it's hard to
identify that this is the pest so for
that type of thing sure it would be a
really it would be a cool way to say no
no you've got you've got rust mites you
need to do this right right can't be
with a new material that you were gonna
bring in from outside of leverage if
your greenhouse is quarantined then
you're gonna bring fresh material in to
be able to test it with something like
this might be a half something Andy the
thing the way I feel better than this is
they've got you've got you know there's
there's sample prep and there's
collecting and all that stuff takes time
when you're when you're when you're
doing that right but so to get back like
one piece of information like Mike's
present yes or no or y-chromosome
present yes or no it's like who cares it
when it's like one at a time you're
getting me straight however you can get
them all together in a gene panel or on
a gene Chandni and there's that you know
that needs to bit that to the lab and
you get back information on a hundred
markers or a thousand things right all
the pathogens all the ones that are bad
so so you can do this as I understand
not on just live plants but on on
harvested material and cured material as
well yeah if it's DNA based it doesn't
this as long as you haven't yeah as long
as the DNA is present you can do these
tests right right so basically you can
you
do that test up to the processing of the
material right because I'm sure after
it's it's processed into a concentrator
extract if it was mite infested extract
also have the DNA yeah most likely I
mean definitely especially if it's
coming from stuff like there's no
chemical process like for example if you
were squishing right there's gonna be
DNA in the squish to you huh right so
yeah I would be interesting I mean these
are all experiments that need to be done
it's like where's is such a new science
I'm gonna copy write the name mighty
resin no you're gonna have people lining
up to buy the mighty mighty resin well
yeah no it's it's cool it's it's like I
said it'll be it'll be we're working I
think these single tests are like I kind
of you know I kind of roll my eyes out a
little bit because it's like having
information on one marker is not that
exciting but what is exciting is that
we're on the path to you know Kevin
slowly building his army of his his he's
expanding the toolbox and right now he's
got a cool tool box with a couple of
tools in it but one day it'll be full
with tools and that's when it'll be
really useful to growers and breeders
yes I'm like I you know as much as I I
don't get all excited about ok yeah we
got a marker for Mike tests now I mean
it doesn't that doesn't really excite me
but what excites me is that we're on the
path it also is getting the conversation
going I guess in a sense you know with
some people that might not otherwise be
having it and and having people who are
have that expertise to be able to have
the wherewithal to be able to bring
those products to fruition what we
really need instead of a mildewed test
is a mildew susceptibility test
Strangler thing where we can test the
genome before it was was very tall and
you would determined no this should not
be saved because it's a
credibly susceptible to mildew so like
most of the cultivars on the west coast
I have pretty much come here I just was
looking at some of the approved products
in California and there was one called
regalia that is a natural organic
fungicide and I put a link to it in the
chat that we have and I was just
wondering if you had any information on
that yeah I think it's I think regalia
is a bacteria right it's like one of
those ones that call my leaf surface and
makes it more difficult for the for the
foot for the spores to you know they
caught like I said they call hives a
leaf surface so they kind of occupy the
real estate on the leaf so when the the
spore lands germinates it's it's harder
for it to control if you use that kind
of a control when they test your
cannabis for purity and cleanliness will
that set the desk top depends on the
type of test that they do so if they're
doing might make it float yeah
especially if they're doing like for
example like Kevin MacLaren's test if
they're using a DNA right if you're
probing it for DNA you can find these
like really mine you my new amounts so
they're doing a DNA base force of the
mildew which didn't germinate but
instead landed on this other thing
you're talking about it's just for you
guys it's AM it's a it's an extract from
the plant giant not weed yeah no I
understand exactly what it is and I'm
saying if you sprayed your plant with it
then a spore from mill down landed on it
it might die rather than germinate on
the plant and if you then took a DNA
sample of that leaf you would still get
the B spore from the node ow so it would
maybe test positive or can it tell the
difference between dead and alive now if
it was DNA it just
just is DNA present or not yeah that's
what doesn't that make the DNA test kind
of floored because you know dust you
know is organic and it president in our
atmosphere so if you know certain
particles landed on it you're just
screwed it would be post-processing
everything you did was right you grow
these perfect organic strawberries and
you know XYZ lands on it and then you
flunk the test yeah yeah I mean they
could do what are called calibration
curves right like you test a sample like
we saw this a long time ago but if it's
powdery mildew resistant or powdery
mildew contamination you can detect
between low medium and high levels of
contamination right so but again they
got it they got to do those calibration
curves like yeah best show you have to
have low high and medium levels of
contamination and then be able to say
this is the chemical of the DMA signal
it's coming off that but if you eat have
you look on that little graph that they
post it up on the if you if you scroll
down the first graphed on the graph on
the left you can see they've compared it
to things like actinovate right so
actinovate is a it's again it's a
biocontrol but it's a bacteria that they
swear down the leaf so you know the one
all I'm saying is that DNA signal is
gonna be in the plant or on the lawn the
flower right on the leaf yeah I'm just
wondering what will happen with those
DNA signals will they pass or not pass
when it comes to looking for fungus and
bacteria and everything else
maybe it'll set it off yeah well and
that's you know why it's so important to
choose the test because we're not trying
to detect who cares if there's like the
fact that you can find my DNA on your
flower it doesn't mean that it's
contaminated right because again you're
amplifying these tiny tiny tiny levels
of DNA right so yeah so Sam they're
saying that you can spray at the day of
harvest on strawberries
right well they rock where they watch
strawberries right we can't watch
cannabis you know cannabis I can it's a
different type of planets because that's
so oily right like it's bubble man
washes cannabis great about losing that
resin though is but remember it happened
when people were doing the sulfur -
right like the resin glands people would
say when they're burning the herb but
they couldn't tell that it had sulfur
most people couldn't tell but when you
extract it down
it tasted like [ __ ] burning matches
yeah it was unbelievable and so that was
just a flavor thing but imagine it was a
compound that didn't have flavor but it
had toxicity right so you couldn't taste
it but the resident lands are sucking up
those those chemicals so it's like it's
it's it's all I'm saying is that it's
not the same thing as strawberries it's
not the same it's safe to spray on
strawberries because you can wash
strawberries it's not the same thing
with cannabis doesn't mean that it's
safe to spray on cannabis up til a
little couple days before harvest or
even like at like four weeks or five
weeks because we used to use BT bacteria
thuringiensis a lot and we tried to use
it right up until the plants we're about
to start flowering you know try to do
the use all vegetative and also it is is
a organized by organism it's it's
nothing dangerous but people using
chemicals during flowering is just 'men
think of what to call them well let me
say this - I totally subscribe to it
ryan saying and when you start seeing
flowers form on your plants it like even
week 3 I don't recommend you spent you
spray duck jet anything on those damn
things and then that's partly
responsible to be honest well even no
matter how safe it is like oh it's a
safe biologic it's like okay but safe to
like burn and inhale into your lungs
because that have they done
research because that's generally what's
happening now are cannabis and our
resident know they have it right so
that's gonna change let's go through
some of the chemistry and just how much
change goes on smoking leaves you have
to be careful about what any-anything
lee gets on the leaves if you look in
flowers then what what's on the leaves
probably won't have any effect on you if
you're only smoking resin yeah but it
also depends if using a biological it
you know these things are not
intrinsically gonna harm the resin
whereas some of the chemical sprays I'm
positive but they do poison the resin
itself so the US EPA regulates these are
so called biopesticides they're viewed
as being sort of more you know
environmentally friendly and I think
even neem oil falls into that my cat
mint insect repellent Falls its fat so
they're the biological resource and
think of it is what you're doing is your
automatic the local biome of a plant by
just changing the the natural biology
that's already happening by giving a new
little bio chemical which is really a
biologically derived system so you're
just admitting the biology it's not a
spring chemical but you know those
chemicals again or those you know
enzymes extracts those types of
preparations are usually not as
effective and not quite systemic as the
as the chemicals are but remember that
if the onus is on the the company who
registers those things with the EPA to
get through EPA registration for those
end-use products and so exactly in order
for you to show the efficacy and the
safety of those products you have to
conduct trials with humans which take
institutional review board
okay's and many millions of dollars to
actually get approved and actually do
and so Scott's
miracle-gro click claim this week in the
news to actually start that process with
the EPA on one particular thing they're
registering something for specific use
on cannabis which tells me that they've
done efficacy and they've done some type
of probably bridging to human safety
studies because there's been so much
work done in agrochemicals to assess
their safety and as we've always pointed
out you know vegetables a lot of
vegetables are washed and a lot of those
things are applied and what makes it
agrochemical today is not necessarily
one that kills bugs and fungus and mites
and all that it's one that breaks down
safely by the time that produce gets the
Whole Foods and gets sold through
anything so by the time all that process
happens that thing will have either
photolytic ly degraded hydrolytically
degraded actually in some cases
biologically degraded by other microbes
so the whole point of this is actually
to get human studies to actually show
that you can effectively use these
treatments in the cultivation of
cannabis and here's our efficacy studies
that gives us the label requirements
that helps the farmer understand what I
do have this type of infestation here's
the label use rates and so this is the
use rates that basically they have
established studies for to show that if
you use this product at these use rates
you'll be able to control this
particular pest and most importantly you
won't have any bad effects in the
products that are derived from that
that's what's called a registration that
registration cost 10 maybe a hundred
million dollars once you have that
registration then you can start selling
this product in the cannabis space so
that's the hill that this company has to
climb Todd thanks for bringing this up
because it was really important well
you're gonna see a lot more conversation
about this because California is
starting to release these lists of
approved chemicals for cultivation and
so a lot of people are going to be
bringing up these codes where they might
be
and again they're bridging data without
actually having all of the studies in
place to say what happens when not
supplied to cannabis during flower and
residues to end up in the extracts and
kids are dabbing this on a hot email
those studies I can tell you
categorically have not been done studies
are done and won't have all that safety
information then they can basically have
free not great to sell those kinds of
products but I think the approach that
they're taking right now is to use
biological control these enzymes and
extracts again are viewed more straight
spinosa
is another natural product that again is
actually on one of the hot lists of what
to look for if you get contaminated
stuff in Colorado there's all kinds of
natural products like neem oil they
really are making incredible claims now
that neem oil has some connection to
cannabis related hyperemesis I don't
know I've looked at some of the data I
don't know that that's absolutely true
but neem is supposed to have that effect
so you know God you know is there a
correlation between the two who knows
clinical trials will tell mmm so it's
good that research is happening yeah I
haven't used neem on my plants in two
decades plus yeah well I guess if you're
facing a huge economic loss and you know
you're pressured to do whatever you have
to do to recover that economic loss and
you're forced to buy some kind of
treatment to help you mitigate your pest
I mean wouldn't it be great to have the
knowledge up front like I think Ryan was
pointing to and and to understand the
genetic susceptibility of certain
varieties and certain grow conditions
and certain climates to succumb to
certain pests and maybe what we would do
is hey let's not grow the Sour Diesel
that time of year let's grow the cookies
that time of year
change your cultivation planning and
your cultivation practices based on what
may or may not be more susceptible to
pests
yeah we were just I was just helping a
client lay out a really big grow and
they were using their variety as their
genetics to put in and they wanted to do
all these boxes market varieties but
because of the regulations at their end
they can't they can't spray anything for
powdery mildew they have to you know
essentially what we did is I totally
changed their grow around and put in
only varieties that were resistant to
powdery build it right just because
that's it's kind of like unfortunately
the market dictated that they want you
know the most popular things that was
really quick you know cookies og all
that kind of stuff all the cushions
there they're all there the badness all
the powdery mildew magnets so it's like
filling up your facility with a bunch of
stuff that's going to attract problems
that you have to deal with it's really a
good idea microscopic problems that you
can't see until they're very very much
prevalent everywhere
well that that's just a question for
Kevin is that how infected does your
growl have to be with powdery mildew to
get a positive result on this kind of
one single spore he can test for no wait
as the death seemed out of out of whack
biologically Ryan that's that's the way
the tests work right that's what PCR
does PCR again for those that don't know
you can google it but it's called
polymerase chain reaction and polymerase
chain reaction and a DNN a method for
amplifying specific pieces of DNA right
so if that's the beauty of the text if
you can take my Newt my new little
almost undetectable little I mean that's
what they do in the clue but the cops do
when they go into a murder scene and
they can find they'll they'll tape
they'll take a tiny little dab of blood
that might have been left by the killer
right and then they can amplify the DNA
in it to see and and get a signal out of
that dividing that your sample contains
a little bit of the DNA and so I guess
the the caveat to what Kevin is saying
is if there is a huge grow and there's
one spore in there that's on one plan in
the corner of the room
and you sample over here you're not
gonna find it right I mean no you know
because it happened DNA has to be
example that they're testing I think
it's more likely that he's saying that
it there could be a single spore on the
test sample India yeah I I get that yeah
totally
well you know what it's good that it's
this well I mean for cannabis anyway I'm
sure there's probably other industries
that have been using this for a long
time but it's like chimeras to get a
hundred or 200 of those in your toolbox
that would be an extreme value yeah just
imagine if you could swipe a little
piece of a bud
on a stick and it would you know change
colors if it if it had milled out in
other words that the grower [ __ ] up
they speak English it's mildew he'll do
I'm doing you the European version you
say banana I'll say mildew no doubt you
say tomato I say tomahto
I'm just giving you [ __ ] daddy yeah it's
quite all right I don't mind at all
if you're German root let me guess both
pronunciations copyrighted impounded
right both of them correct not not to
mention the Italian and Portuguese
version yeah i think what i'm just
looking at this county fair thing i
think it's a great first step these are
guys are did going by the dominant
terpene but I think the inevitable
evolution of this is that we're gonna
get like this is what we call terpenes
superclasses right but eventually what's
gonna happen is these terpene classes
will get broken down another step into
and then they'll start well then then it
really will be like will compete against
like like for example like you know the
lime and pine would fit into the pioneer
class but it would be competing against
blue dream which is a totally different
flower
right there really even though they both
are PI D dominant it's really not the
same if you're not comparing you're
comparing apples to oranges right and
the idea that I think is the the real
evolution of these cannabis cups is
where you compete you from air it's like
you know it's like a dog show you
compare Huskies to Huskies and pugs two
pugs and labs two labs right and then
you do the best and show but you know
really like you don't want to be
comparing the Pug to the lab because
they're totally different animals
they're different beasts well I like to
compare the pugs to a Great Dane because
the Great Danes always win they're
obviously a bigger better dog well cross
the two salmon come out with the great
pug yeah it really is an important thing
that you're comparing because they are
such like like I said like let the lime
and pie and it's it's not og you can't
compare to og because they're totally
different types of experiences right so
needs to be listed is the top ten
terpenes and in with some sort of a
display so you can see that terpene the
pining is got the most it's 50% of the
total of terpenes even the top three is
enough to really differentiate yeah it
would be a good start you're right
yeah I mean it's it is enough it's like
Tom if you have a top three it's like
now you're you're actually comparing I
have a slightly different idea and and
again it falls along less long the dog
analogy and more along the music analogy
so out of bluegrass festival they have
competitions and have competitions for
bands but they also have competitions
for individual instrumentalists like
they'll be a bluegrass or a banjo an
upright bass competition a man
in competition and so maybe a way to do
a competition along this analogy is to
do the best in show which is that hey no
matter what terpene you can pack into it
this is just the best [ __ ] and it goes
right best in show but maybe the other
way to characterize these is to say okay
if the root means that we see most
predominant in cannabis or these five or
these ten your strain has to fit a
terpene dominance in that category to
compete in that competition right and so
you use the terpene dominance and again
I think the more you use the rather than
five do the first ten or the first 15
that are all found in cannabis before
you know it you'll have all these
instrumental competitions as well as the
overall band competition which is sort
of what it's all about right I don't
know just an idea
yeah I think that's the way that'll be
all so you're always gonna have best of
show right that's what they are now but
it's like you got to give I think you
got to give props to the best grows in
every class right because they are such
a different assistant to different user
experience like the experience of smoke
in an OG or vers
oak in that lime and pine I mean they're
totally different animals roses are
actually a good example because the
modern Rose is not scented they bred
from a beauty right now I wonder how
much that had to do with you PAH rules
being so based on morphology like yeah
it seems like there could be another
scent another competition that is the
the nicest froze right where does the
rose competitions happen is it only once
a year
I'm sure they happen all over you know I
know they think they do they bloom in
different times of the year right
depending on the country you're in
yep google it there's the Rose today
there's the rose a two-day competition
that seems to be the big one
there's a massive competition well
there's a mango representation every
year where they have representation of
every all 3,000 types of mangoes I need
to go to that so I mean you can see at
some point somebody will you know maybe
they'll just be you know the the green
crack festival or they the haze festival
things become more specific you know
becoming a region because some will
become regional genetics you know yes
it's just the evolution of those
competitions where they become less
competitive and less dick waving and
more just appreciating of the beauty you
know like it's like if you it's like you
believe you win the biggest dog at the
at the County Fair it's like that's not
that big a deal you know and it'd be
nice if it was more about the
cultivation in the cannabis or the or
the extract than it was about the ego
and the bump in sales like a lot of
people or what we were talking about
with forests whoever donates the most to
children whoever right whatever whoever
does the most for the industry you know
who those are the ones a different
measurement though I mean the people who
help out everybody and not just not just
themselves and not just push themselves
forward talking about comparing apples
to apples so to speak you know what I
mean it's just flowers that's again and
you can't really award people like
forests for what they're really doing in
my opinion because we should also be
supporting his work in my opinion we
should all be yes wanting to accomplish
having a competition where rather than
submitting extracts that you could
actually submit extracts rather than
some judge panel to actually patients
who need medicine you know that's what I
said last week when for I told forest
I'm just gonna donate whatever that was
a person writing that I said but at the
same time like forest you know you know
in we were supporting him last week it
was amazing to see everyone donating by
the way you guys donated almost seven
hundred US dollars to the khalad rias
network and that'll go into buying
little jars and lids as stuff for the
the creams to go in for for some of
those kids with the skin diseases so
it's the good work it's a good thing not
trying to say shut down competitions but
definitely I hear what both Todd and
Mark are saying it's like yes continue
to have the competitions but Wow like
you know putting everything all we're
trying to do is figure out ways this
community can put things aside you know
while it's kind of like that I'll put a
couple of plants in the back of the grow
room for a good cause you know so it's
like in this community when we're doing
things if there's an event where we're
gonna drop like 23 thousand dollars to
promote our company cuz we're all about
the patients maybe kick a thousand bucks
down or something down sometimes some
energy some focus something that just
shows that you're also and your time the
most valuable of all commodity
absolutely mine can I toss this out
there to your attention your time and
your attention can be way more valuable
than a dollar donation yeah yeah and one
of my thoughts is also is in line with
what Tim Blake was saying is that you
know they're seeing growers without door
that's really good cannabis having an
impossible time to get rid of it and
what that really means is it's lowering
the price threshold that people need to
meet to be able to get into it and we
are gonna see more and more of that
cannabis going to people that really
need it because now people can afford to
give it away and they can afford to be
more generous because literally the
stuffs not worth that much in the first
place anymore like it used to be so and
I think this is where people like him
could benefit if we could focus our
generosity because I don't want to say
that the little bits of crumbs that go
to the competitions are really what we
should be donating to the kids we should
be giving you know maybe on too much of
a socialist you know what I mean but I
believe we
should be helping our neighbors you know
when I started the san diego compassion
club i was donating the cannabis i had
and i was having a lot of the friends I
worked with read allowing me to
redistribute stuff because once they've
realized you're visiting hospitals
you're actually seeing people that are
sick that have had cancer - I'll give
you pot and it was like we just didn't
know there was anyone doing that to give
pot - and that's really what the bridge
became and I just became the happy
deliverer of other people's generosity
and we all need to do that and when I
was asked about that on the san diego
media my my comment was is that look
when your kid or your relative is sick
it's a question of compassion it's not a
question of capitalism you know so we
really all need to get into this thing
of compassion and you know my mom didn't
sell me weed when I was going through
chemo imagine if that was the situation
you know and this is what I think we can
all do is we can find outlets like guys
like Forrest and we can foster that
generosity and help little kids and old
ladies and people you love that's the
whole point of this you know I'm sure
that if we hooked up even Tim Blake with
Forrest that he would somehow involve
you know it would be a good thing just
to forward the you know along because
people that are doing big things and
making moves always need to you know and
and that's what Tim's whole thing is
community and like doing the right thing
and you know like I bet you he would
have a great relationship with Forrest
is your campus up up in Canada is it
tax-free for patients no but that isn't
a last year they subjected GST they're
trying it because it's weird because
medicine typically isn't right so no
hill and a whole bunch people have been
really lobbying hard to get that removed
right they don't call charge provincial
though right
currently they don't but I bet that'll
change under the new legalization the
obviously the provinces will grab their
piece - yeah I was a test case for
California for the State Board of
Equalization because we went with the
argument that it is medicine and the
State Board of Equalization said we
don't care we're taxing it so that's why
you've we pay an over-the-counter tax
and so I saying well it should be
tax-free these donations well
unfortunately we can't get nonprofit
status for medical cannabis it's illegal
federally so there is no tax write-off
everything that we donate so just we
give free medicine to 250 qualifying
patients and up 2% to Berkeley patients
every single year we do that free you
know that's just the realities of what
it is you know there's no ability for
anyone to actually have an ability to
actually acts right off something like
that something that we're trying to work
on on the state level right now is I
want to continue to be able to donate
and give those patients free cannabis
but with the new laws that are being
passed that becomes much more difficult
so we're actually trying to lobby on
Capitol Hill you know it's tough well
can I point out something that is [ __ ]
up in California you don't pay tax on
your pets medication okay because they
could they have they have considered
that it creates a financial hardship on
the pet owner so that they shouldn't
have to pay taxes on if your dog gets
hurt but if your grandma is going
through chemo and she's need some
medical cannabis taxer and that's that's
it where we got to get into a different
conversation and demand equal we should
at least have equal rights as pets right
well I spent that out I spent six
figures on a lawyer that was the former
head of the State Board of Equalization
and still lost well it's not on you it
doesn't matter no no I understand I just
want a little bump in their road and
they were trying to make a point with
BPG that was a [ __ ] up point but you
know now technically they're now in a
situation where if you do have your
California card you do not totally pay
taxes on that um and the only taxes it
should be collected and I'm not sure if
this is correct going forward will be on
recreational or adult use sales if you
have a California a cannabis card you
will be tax exempt for your your
purchases of medical cannabis and but
that tax is 15% and that tax is 15%
that'll be January 18th or is that
Junior
I mean January 1st 2018 the the tax on
cannabis will be 15% is can I ask you
this on top of the 10% we pay or 9% we
pay a sales tax yes there is to my
knowledge there is no waving of the OTC
tax per County so like in Alameda County
we paid 9.0 percent over the counter tax
so you'll pay that to my knowledge as
well as 15% and then I'm Berkeley I've
done I have as at 2.5% wholesale tax
another 2.5 percent retail tax so you're
talking a tax of 29% but what about this
is it possible that we start selling
this herb as medication for dogs and
cats and then just let our grandmas and
our dads and moms and all these other
people just use it can we get around
this is there a loophole we can fight
well can I throw this out there in all
honesty they're the people that I think
that the whole medical everybody needs a
medical card thing is going to evaporate
when nobody needs a medical card and the
people that are really sick you know are
obviously gonna continue to be really
sick because that's the [ __ ] cards
they were done in life but and and
they're gonna pursue medical cannabis
use because they have to I'm not because
you know they feel like alternating beer
with some cannabis on a Friday night and
now they don't need a damn doctors no so
I think doctors notes are gonna go the
way of you know nowhere because you're
not gonna need it you're just gonna need
to be 21 or over you know who's gonna
need to pay a doctor a hundred bucks for
some freedom papers when you're already
free patients that don't want to pay
those taxes that so you don't have to
pay those taxes legitimate patients will
still be in relationships with their
doctors and you know I don't mean
legitimate like everyone that says they
use cannabis is illegitimate I just mean
like look if you're seeing a doctor all
the time did you [ __ ] you know a step
away from dying that's not gonna change
you know so you're gonna still be there
like hey and if you can save fifteen
twenty nine whatever percent until end
of work on B and people should get their
their California cannabis cards and they
should avert the taxes because it's
their right to do so
crazy you know that said though even
with the taxes I still think stuff's
gonna drop alcohol and tobacco piss got
taxes on it that are ridiculous when I
used to go get my mom cigarettes when I
was a little kid they were under a buck
you know and now they're stupid money I
don't even know how much they're cuz I
never smoked them but they're taxed
incredibly and you know the FT they're
still legal and no one's shooting each
other up over packs of cigarettes
twenty-nine percent it's just like such
a ridiculous that's well the discussion
back in the day is hey we don't care
until it's time let's just pay a tax on
it well this is what happens when you
you know and people are keeping a
diligent eye on this it's just the
reality of you know the potentiality of
these local governments that have passed
these laws in the absence of regulation
or state regulation
you know what the tax on alcohol is not
even close to that you know what it is I
have no idea
not off the top of my head I used to
have that in my head but apparently got
pushed up by other facts and figures
III think I'll get like this though I
mean granted we'll be paying taxes but
it's not even close to the friggin tax
so that we've paid for prohibition and
an ounce of weed shouldn't cost 400
bucks man I don't give a [ __ ] what you
grew up with or how much love you gave
it that is all cut early ridiculous so I
think get cannabis into the hands of the
people and whatever I mean it'll be nice
to see also tested weed that's not you
know basically laden with pesticides and
growth hormones and every other thing we
can't see or smell so it's in many ways
I I'm I look forward to the change yeah
me too
it's coming there's no stopping it
that's for certain acres will be grown
sections well with this also as well you
also have more labs
you know because regional areas will now
have laboratories so that people can
actually sit and get their a cannabis
tested and that's going to elevate
everything because that's when you'll
start to see
oh saying yes this is tested when you
start hearing that that's a whole change
in the gambia there's no discussion on
that level that I know from anybody's
like yeah man I got this [ __ ] tested and
here's why it's this price you know I
know it at the retail and Erised methods
by certified laboratories that have to
hold up to a scrutiny of a third-party
testing every quarter the only way you
have to you know these labs have to be
watched like any other consumer product
absolutely need to be ring tested like
you say affordably or whenever it'll
start to happen though you know when
when the labs themselves are not you
know quasi activists for what they're
doing I mean a lot of these people that
initially started the labs are heroes to
me because they were facing a ridiculous
fine like ten thousand dollars per test
they did and he did it anyway and you
know what this is this is the kind of
Pro activity we need or we're not going
to have an industry you know this stuff
didn't start out and nothing it started
out of people risking their ass and
taking a chance and making what was now
commonplace science it which is
something that wasn't available I mean
20 years ago when I was in the bel-air
place I got arrested I was looking for
all my own equipment because there was
no labs I could take anything - and if I
didn't acquire my own equipment I would
never be able to get cannabinoid tests
of what I was making and that's why I
have three labs and I do read and test
them all the time it's it's more than
quarterly because you know we were kind
of we were pioneers in this so it's kind
of always been one of those things where
always keeping everybody on their toes
but now that they're calibrated once you
have a good calibrated lab and they're
actually calibrating their machines and
cleaning it and doing everything
properly as dr. Sheldon will will admit
you get exact science and that's what we
need and know more that you're seeing
conjecture anymore we get real data
replicatable data that will then spread
into these other states that will then
spread into these local regions so you
know because each agriculture department
in the county are like in Louisiana you
know I grew up in sugar cane country so
there was a reg
there was a certified regional
representative that actually came and
tested and made sure that everybody is
growing proper to the regulatory
standards that's the accepted standards
for you know what is growing and so that
was backed up by actual science they
actually have testers and things that
they can take into the field that are
calibrated to that specific you know you
know agricultural product so it will
become that way in point in time with
the with cannabis where you'll have you
know even because we had a US Department
of Agricultural representative in the
region as well to back up the local
regional data and testers and and
laboratory which will of course employ
lots of people throughout the United
States because you're talking all these
regional oversight and things that these
taxes are gonna go to pay for that are
necessary evils you know people who hate
regulation but at the same time we have
to have somebody out there that's
unitarily making sure everybody is doing
things properly otherwise we're back to
the same point where we were before so
it's it's it's very important steps that
we're making toward and by having
laboratories that are properly testing
and then showing other laboratories
through brain testing how to actually
calibrate their machines and get them up
to standards besides you know becoming
proprietary you know knowledge it now
becomes universal knowledge for everyone
so that everyone has access to their
testing and a reasonable rate because
let me tell you it's expensive testing
and it costs hundreds of thousands of
dollars and I've spent hundreds of
thousands if not millions of dollars on
testing but it's necessary evil to get
to the point that we're testing is real
and we have real data and so that we can
actually take forward knowing that
everything that we have is actually
properly done and tested and now that
everybody else is held to the same
standards it's it's gonna ripple across
the effect because I'm no longer bearing
that personal responsibility which I
have and willfully now it will be spread
across through all these different
regulatory agencies and oversight bodies
that will actually make sure that one
I'm not making sure that my labs are
calibrated they're at standard
that I'm actually making them happen
agricultural centers and on top of that
we'll have hopefully in the future
Organic Standards and certifications so
that you can actually go through the
two-year process to actually become a
certified organic grower so then you can
actually have certified organic cannabis
that's gonna be the next step we still
have to pierce that veil and once that
is actually broken through through these
regulations which we should see here in
California but national certification
may still say that well we're gonna hold
off until it's federally there because
we haven't seen that certification
really pop up in Colorado have you heard
any discussion of organic certification
in Pennsylvania dr. Sheldon no I haven't
even heard of it in Colorado I think I
heard of it in the HAMP side of the
Colorado industry but I'm not familiar
with it on the medicinal or recreational
side but I it happens real fast because
yeah Oh Whole Foods can't sell it until
it's certified organic and Amazon just
bought Whole Foods so of course they'll
force cannabis to be allowed to be
organic also yeah if anything I would
expect Amazon to be the first online
deliverer of cannabis well I didn't say
it I know they're friendly they bottle
foods they bought Whole Foods for 14
billion dollars the other day yeah yeah
that's going shopping for sure that's
just through a whole thing because you
know Walmart and those have had their
you know their super stores and there's
Sam's and their food centers but this is
a huge volley for Amazon they say that
there's about a million existing Amazon
fresh customers this is Amazon's food
fresh food delivery business they
imagined that that number is going to
peak about a hundred million it's gonna
go from 1 million to a hundred million
people buying their groceries through
Amazon
on their phone closing doors down hey
well I was interesting because it's like
everything's been going towards the
Internet in favor of brick-and-mortar
but now one of the biggest companies
essentially what they did is they went
shopping for brick-and-mortar right well
yeah it was on the food market and to
change it they need well and and the
fresh food market really is is is
directly tied to the price of fossil
fuels like it or not as elitist so right
now their distribution network has just
become this huge web of whole food
stores but you'll see them make a deal
with Tesla and they'll all of a sudden
have the first electric vehicles that
are delivering all these things across
the country arc drones right there
flying around dropping food and that's
scary they're gonna have intelligent
drones no they're gonna have driverless
trucks that Tesla and them will create
that are already solar power
you're not already replacing the
supercharged centers with solar so now
they're gonna be solar supercharged
centers on top of that and on top of
that they're gonna be autonomous so oh
you come out in it and be on your front
porch it's already that way with
instacart and Google delivery this is a
huge shoot shout against Google's
delivery as well because I get a Google
delivery where I can order my food and
all my non perishables and they come in
boxes to my house and I order my
instacart and I can have all my fresh
fruits and vegetables delivered to my
house as is right now I do this all the
time I don't even go into stores anymore
because the convenience is acceptable
there so it's already drones are a
concept but they're already doing this
all the spread of the stores miss you
the stores miss you the stores want you
back eight yeah but some people will
always love to choose their produce yeah
I think it's great
IIIi look we found we found that with
delivery of cannabis when when we were
shut down by the government for a
temporary I went to delivery exclusively
and what we found out from deliver
exclusives exactly that is a majority of
people especially Californians
highly educated on cannabis and they
want to see their cannabis they don't
want to be like here's what you have
choice of this one thing good day they
want to be able to to like at the store
they get whenever somebody asked for a
genetic we pull out three to four
different one of that same kind so they
can pick between those and they'll be
like ooh this looks better than this and
that's what their should their choices
to just show up with the delivery and
just be told exactly that's a something
that the market does not necessarily
want for cannabis how do you find that
like with your avocados and your
tomatoes and your produce that gets
delivered directly to your house I mean
I like to go to the store and pick out
my cantaloupe I like to feel it and
smell it and I don't want someone else
picking out my cantaloupe for me how do
you like that procedure I mean is nine
times out of ten they nail it you know
as the thing is is you know it's listed
as what it is if is you want organic
cantaloupe they will pick up an organic
cantaloupe it you can select know that
if there isn't that organic cantaloupe
then cancel it or select something else
so they can have a choice where you can
select either another organic cantaloupe
or a conventional so you can have that
selection in the menus currently on if
that that organic cantaloupe isn't there
now could I pick something right myself
better than somebody most likely but as
I said nine times out of ten they get it
right and for me the convenience is
better than actually going down I prefer
to go down to a farmers market to a
local farmers market which I tend to do
but even they're doing that now they're
going to local farmers markets so even
that takes a hell of a lot of the
guessing games out so instacart not only
goes to local my local market but on
certain weekdays that go to local
farmers market so you can actually
select that as well and you know you're
getting organic local and locally
supporting and that's where your dollars
are going you're just not having to deal
with the driving around the parking and
all those really is my wife would grow
up Amish farm on the other side of the
hill and by all armistice all throughout
this time of the year so we have our I
like some Amish farmer you know 20 yard
or Woody's wife Laura had a company in
Los Angeles called yoga niché's
and they home-delivered organic fruits
and vegetables and you they gave you a
list of all the ones that were available
the week and you would check them all
off the ones you wanted and they would
prioritize those in your box and you
would get other stuff but you know we
were pretty open-minded to other organic
fruits and vegetables but every week we
used to get a couple boxes we were on we
would get the fruit and we get the
vegetables and I thought it was
fantastic because it also it really
helped the farmers in a lot of ways to
get to their customer but it also gave
you recipes as well so that was also so
you got recipes if something was
regional or seasonal it gave you
seasonal recipes so it also broadens
your recipe base so that you if you've
already had something in mind for the
fruits and vegetables that were coming
to you great but if you didn't because
we do something or did something for our
hospice patients where it was farm-fresh
to you it's a local organic farm and
they do the same thing they would
deliver organic vegetables we realized
when we were dealing with hospice
patients that cannabis is is it's an
essential tool but it is a tool you need
to take care of your health eating
properly is one thing so I highly
recommend supporting these types of
local box organic vegetable delivery
services because you're supporting the
farmers and even if it's not ripe
you know as you know dr. Sheldon you
just leave it on the shelf a couple of
days and it can it will ripen in time
you know it's it's I've never gotten
past right things from that type of
delivery I've usually gotten things that
are you know pre ripe yeah I think they
pick them pre right because they know
it's gonna ripen on the on the delivery
service but yeah how good it's packaged
because certain vegetables will bruise
quite a bit when they're when they're
shipped and so you last thing you know
you want to get is a apple that's all
bruised up or avocado or a pear to chop
bruised up
you know dr. Sheila I [ __ ] you not
because I worked in Pennsylvania on a
horse farm and I used to go to the the
Amish or a mesh and depending on I want
to try Amish grown pot I bet you they're
organic cannabis if [ __ ] dick in the
dirt amazeballs
I mean yeah
do the Amish grow tobacco I don't yes
they do yes thank you really yes they do
yeah if there's a market for it and it's
agriculture the Amish grow it the Amish
will grow anything they don't smoke do
they watch TV or not that are mint
tobacco oh um I don't think so I don't
think they're alive really not even a
pilot oh maybe maybe they are I I don't
know I I know they're not allowed to
consume alcohol I mean the strict Amish
folks I mean they don't they don't use
electricity
they don't use shoes they're always in
bare feet they're they have dirt floors
in their homes
the Pennsylvania men and I it's they
have like motorised tractors and
vehicles and [ __ ] like that
but you'll see him at an Amish guy out
there with a team of horses plowing a
field like his great-great-great
grandfather's did you know it's crazy
that they're still farming in this very
very you know it make they control when
I when I went to the the the mills the
sawmills cuz I got the the sawdust for
the animal bedding and they controlled
it so every time I went down there I
would actually have to wear long sleeves
so my tattoos wouldn't show otherwise it
wouldn't deal with me you know a they're
that strict still back in the 90s you
know they're they're socially about what
they are but it also depends there's
different sects there's do I you know
that they are there can be as strict and
by-the-book or as close to Mennonite is
even possible you know so you have the
whole gamut but for the most part
they're very strict and I can't say I've
ever seen an Amish smoked smoked tobacco
myself but I know that they grow it they
grow everything great they don't [ __ ]
around when it comes to farming them in
barns you want an Amish barn yeah they
do lots of barn raisings but you know
the one thing about the Amish is again
they know that
you of what they they bring in terms of
marketing you know like there's I've
said this story before probably not on
has to church but we went in one time to
buy our our Turkey and there was a line
again Range Rovers and BMWs parked at
the Amish place where there's horses and
buggies lined up and then you basically
have these people who buy their Amish
turkeys well this girl behind the
counter was probably like about I don't
know 14 or 15 years old and she was
rifling through a stack of 20s like a
Vegas dealer I'll be right with you sir
and just as very stark image a very
simple lifestyle but just huge in
understanding the business is what they
do and there was this line of people out
the door who wanted their Amish this and
their Amish that and so they know the
value of a buck that's for sure awesome
well I think that is the high note of
hashed Church and we should probably end
it on the high note an Amish story above
turkeys and Range Rover no no that's
okay I honestly I said I was gonna end
it at 12 and it's 12
it was awesome having Tim Blake come in
thank you for that Todd good to see what
he's up to and I'm sure we'll hear more
from him as the time goes by or at least
maybe get to see
well maybe Tony will go on filming or
something and we'll get to see more
about how that event went and I guess
thanks chimera for coming in as always
the panelists Todd McCormack at TF on 10
skunkman Sam March Sheldon Johnny B and
Darin Massey who have split and anyone
that I'm forgetting I sure don't mean to
skunk man Sam everybody everybody yeah I
think I said it thanks everybody for
watching hashed Church this week I think
brothers and happy Father's Day you know
what I will end it with a picture of my
father Chief Gary Richardson of the fire
department r.i.p dad love you for all
those who have fathers who have passed
on like yours Marcus exactly r.i.p to
the father's and for those that haven't
have a great day with your
families and friends peace out everybody
Oh your dad much love everyone