computer I have never gone live on
Facebook so this is a
first I
guess that lots of people use Facebook
you know like all the mass murderers
when they're going out killing people at
uh shopping centers and
stuff all right well I want to say
welcome to everyone this is a strange
hash church this is the first one I've
ever gone live on Facebook because
YouTube just wasn't working for us so
welcome everyone to Hash Church uh 3.0
episode 6 really just going to be a hash
talk today um hopefully I'm not sure how
to share this uh but it would be very
good um oh here we go I would be very
good to go into the YouTube chat really
quick uh where everyone's legitimately
waiting for us to go live right now and
I should do that um otherwise welcome
guys let's uh let's start the discussion
you guys can start uh the chat maybe uh
uh while I'm doing this so go ahead do
your thing talk
guys hey
guys there you go Colin you're picking
up the slack that's what I'm talking
picking up the slack guys um welcome
welcome um hey guys a question for you
Colin yes what was the first electronic
instrument oh the first electronic
instrument I'm not sure I think uh wait
hold on um
it's not the theramin there's something
before the
theramin I don't remember I don't I
don't know I keep going back to the
thein I I don't know I think it is I
think it is the therin but I'm not sure
that's what I asked I think it is the
theramin U that's a creation that's a
collaboration actually between bog Moog
uh American designer and engineer and I
believe a European friend of his I don't
we should should look this up uh it's a
very
important very important point in uh in
creation of of music musical instruments
it it really set the tone for uh 20 the
20th and 21st century and where we're at
it happened shortly after a pretty
intense mushroom Journey most
likely um just
like what's that Josh Frozen up just
like everything else good in the world
exactly it is the thein actually it we
were correct I I was not surprised one
of my favorite movies Is The Day the
Earth Stood Still and I am completely
wrong it is not Bob moo it is Leon
Therman that's there you go go figure so
very cool the way to do it that makes a
lot of sense i'mna question for you Sam
what was your first variety that you
grew that inspired you to make an
outcross to make a what to make a what
make an outcross or or a new hybrid out
of it oh a new hybrid well to be honest
the first
de I grew I really grew land races and
the first one I planted was Mexican but
somebody stole it before it flowered so
I didn't get so far with it but I tried
uh the first hybrid that I I created was
uh skunk number
one that's amazing so that was your
first thing and then that went on to
touch and I think this is important for
the the audience because I I've been
really the last few years I guess I've
been really diving into the genomic
aspect and the genomic tagging if you
will and better understanding what we
have in our hands that variety has
touched pretty much every modern day
cannabis variety that I've seen there's
very few that it has
um well not only that but I I added some
DNA to it so it it actually says SK
number one in the DNA and uh anybody who
has SK DNA sk1 DNA uh I actually own
your variety you should start sending me
royalties no back in the day Sam I
remember you telling me that there was a
tarine profile that was spiked on the G
or the GLC that you would recognize
varieties that had skunk in it is that
is that
accurate you there well no but here's
what it was when when I made hybrids
with skunk number one and say a tie or a
afan or whatever and then I did the GC
analysis tpine
analysis of of the mother skunk the
mother atam the mother Thai and simple
F1 hybrids between them I could
recognize it just by the uh GC print out
that which ones were related to the skug
or the tie or the appam just by the
tpine content when I first discovered
this uh 25 30 years ago I was blown away
that it was that easy to recogn canvas
by just it tured
profile incredible well I certainly
remember my first trip to Amsterdam in
1995 and uh wow was skunk number one in
every coffee shop it was
unbelievable everyone had their version
of
[Music]
it yeah what incredible variety I know a
lot of the stuff I made as a younger
self I mean having it sequenced by by
Kevin mccaran really shed a lot of light
into actually how much of your variety
Sam have infiltrated all of the work
that I've actually done unbeknownst to
myself like I thought I I wasn't even
working with it and it was it was all in
there so well in the beginning mine was
the most consistent stable multi-hybrid
and
it was easy to grow it was easy to use
and uh when you cross it with something
else it usually made it better so
everybody was using it for everything
and what year was that what year was
that Crea well I I released it in uh I
think 76 or 77 but I had worked on it
for a year or two before
that and how much did that have an
effect on modern day hash making
that cultivar and how it got into
soar it's easy to make hash from it with
dry sifting which is what I did so uh on
that that level it but it's hybrids
don't always make cash easy so yeah
because I remember my two easiest ones
to make cash with
was was uh skunk number one and and uh
the variety from DNA s stack what was
it SLE stack absolutely correct but the
hybrid
between the hash did like it does with
SLE stack number one I tried it was
incredible that SLE stack cross with
skunk number one I was there for all of
that and that was good times that [ __ ]
rained resin and it cleaned really
really nice yeah no the SLE stack was as
easyest skunk to to make a really really
clean hash with dry C and uh it yeah it
was truly amazing I say we start a p
petition and get DNA to bring back the
SLE stack where's the SLE stack
at well one thing I've asked DNA over
and over and over is did they analyze
the Turing profile of and the canono of
stack because it was really unusual both
me and Rob found that as long as we
smoke SLE stack resin we didn't sleep so
normally I go to sleep at 10 o'clock at
night at the latest and when I would
smoke SLE stack I'd stay up till 3
o'clock and I
finally smoke some uh you know a real
couch lock weed to knock me
out yeah I fell in the go G train and
Hayes the same way just you know smoking
that at night is not the best idea if
you actually want to go to sleep at any
at any point in time but uh it is what
it is when it's that good you have to
sacrifice a little bit of
sleep hey I wanted to welcome Dave
Sullivan to the room he's never I never
smoked it for days sorry sorry Sam I
wanted to welcome problem at all you
know me I will interrupt everybody
because have to say it's so
important D don't ever stop please I
love you in every way and uh it's just
such a blessing to have you here and
hear your voice and I I definitely miss
you being able to come and hang out with
you and puff bowls and spend time SP uh
it definitely sucks not being able to do
that but uh church and do you have it
working in YouTube now Marcus is working
YouTube I went live on Facebook so we've
got I've shared the faceb
link uh in the YouTube chat a bunch of
times and I don't know there's got to be
maybe a hundred people or something
Facebook okay
I so back to welcoming Dave suan into
the room his first hash Church episode I
met
daveon
Josh I'm gonna beting some mics oh it
was Colin look at that it's always like
the music guy like the guy who does like
is obsessed with perfect sound
you for whatever reason your mic is like
Johnny B's mic it just creates the
craziest feedback when it's not muted
mine's muted I just unmuted myself no I
muted you oh weird yes trust me now
you're muted again um but once again
three times charm Dave I want to welcome
Dave Sullivan to the room he's uh he's
an interesting fellow I liked what he
had to say on the on the demm pure um
videos that they've been doing do for
the last uh couple of months and so I
wanted to introduce you dude and and
tell the hash Church audience a little
bit about yourself and how you came to
find yourself uh here on the
panel well um yeah my name is Dave I
live in Oregon and we have
a certified organic vegetable farm here
we do a bunch of acreage of uh Market
crops for you know farmers markets and
restaurants CSA and all that kind of
stuff and we also
um have a wck
farm so we we've been growing cannabis
and uh vegetables for you know
approaching 25 years and uh yeah that's
what we
do that's awesome and you're obviously
growing jot herbs as well amongst your
food y yep yeah we've uh yeah we we we
we've kind of got a unique system where
where we've sort of incorporate uh G
into our crop rotation and uh that works
really well for us and so obviously with
both growing food and growing uh
cannabis resin you're going and doing it
organically and regeneratively and
whatnot I'm suspecting that you have
long understood the
relationship of the way food and
cannabis is produced and the way it
tastes and smells in an organic living
soil environment
versus one that is more scrubbed of
terroir maybe it's an indoor grow now
and it's got artificial lights and it
has a a soiless medium and it's being
fed fed salt nutrients you you guys must
be well aware of of the intensity of the
differences of of those two
relationships yeah I mean it it's it's
obviously it goes without saying but I
think one of the
um one one of the real tangible ways you
can see that around us is all the you
know we're in a pretty thriving farming
Community here so there's a lot of uh
monoculture around us like uh Ry grass
and hazelnuts and sugar beet seeds and
things like that so you can you just
even seeing the difference between you
know our neighbors and our soils that
are that were managed like organically
and building up soil over the years
versus the conventional guys that are
just blasting herbicides and spraying
24d you can just the soil just looks has
like a dead look to it and um you know
I'm not you know I'm definitely not in
the like uh making hashes and in my
wheelhouse and I'm clearly not an expert
like you guys but uh I do know that we
we have collaborations with uh some of
the you know who I think are the best
hash makers in the state of Oregon and
they uh it's it's it's not even
questionable to them that you know
living soil sungrown herb is uh they get
the best turps off the hash and
and I would say uh you are making hash
by growing it because if we as hash
makers have nothing to wash yeah you
know hash makers uh sometimes take a lot
of credit but we shouldn't you know we
do we do a job but you what the job that
you do is uh there's a lot more time
that passes and there's a lot more
variable that you're exposed to uh than
than a hash maker there's no doubt about
that what are some of the loudest
strains that you have right now Dave
going on in your greenhouse because I
saw that you're getting towards your uh
one of your first steps and
everything well the joke these days is
if it's not named after a a dessert or a
fruit then no one's really growing it
but uh but I'll seriousness um what we
have a a really good sour Tangi cut from
I think got Crockett breadit and um
that's super loud and then we have a lot
of um a lot my my friend crispy down in
California he he uh he's got a sour
diesel headband that everything he
crosses into it is just it's a thorough
bread and um one of the I think one of
the ones that we're hearing is really
good for hash is um it's called this is
the [ __ ] or tits which is kind of a
terrible name and Oregon doesn't like
the name so we we renamed it Grandpa's
finest after the breed who BR it he's
he's an Oldtimer from uh from uh K
Valley in California but that's sour
band onto an ogkb and U it just has that
really just greasy kind of Himalayan
structure to it you those are probably
some what other have you grown our Tangi
in Northern California and in in in the
W Valley or what are some differences
that you've seen from say Bol to the
wamit valley well for us we we didn't
get the S sour Tangi cut until after we
weren't really growing down there
anymore I've given it somebody's down
there but
um in southern humble um in particular
I'm sure there's you know there's
obviously good micro pockets and regions
all over the world but that being you
know the the the famous Emerald Triangle
the not even all of Humble County
obviously killer herb comes out of all
of Humble County but that particular
Zone uh where the the the Kings range
the Lost Coast it's about 28 miles that
that it was just too uh the terrain was
just too uh Steep and drastic to
actually it's the only as you guys
probably all know it's the only part of
the California coast where the 101
doesn't go through there's about I think
28 or so miles of and it's literally
just like a 4,000 foot cliff to the
ocean the the King's Peak so once you
start getting east of the 101 get into
you know Eastern humble and um you grow
really big weed you know like it gets
like Sequoia weed like where it just
gets gigantic but it's really hot and
once you're obviously in the in the fog
line on the coast you kind of deal with
all the muck coming off the ocean but
the reason that particular microc climb
is so sweet is because you literally
have this 4,000 foot cliff blocking all
the muck off the ocean but you still
have that Coastal pattern so um I mean
you almost once you have like a decent
green thumb and fews behind your back
you almost have to try to not grow good
weed there to not be able to pull it off
good and Oregon where we are here is um
you know Southern Oregon you know a lot
a lot of good herb comes out of there
but the wamit valley where we at it's a
little wet here so so um what we have
kind of developed our style around is if
if you like kickstarting it so you know
we're pulling plastic Late July early
August so that late September um after
the Equinox you can finish under the
natural a without having to man
manipulate the schedule anymore and we
have found that the climate here in
September is almost identical to uh
Southern humble in October so
to kind of trick your plant into
thinking that that it's October
California they don't realize they're in
Oregon we we grow really good herb that
style and uh with some Canadians in the
house actually we kind of learned that
style I'd say back in the mid 90s we had
some buddies up in
um qualcom is that the name of Zone up
in up near uh Vancouver Island yeah not
Vancouver Island um it's it's
it's like like no no it's it's near
Whistler it's a there's like a bunch of
lakes up there pton and and Qualicom no
not qual qual on the on the coast but
these guys there they were just kind of
terracing and um the name of it will
come to me but it was like a really cool
uh tucked away like way remote yakum
Valley what what is it yakum Valley
that's it that's it yeah you got to
drive through louette to get there and
I've dirt biked all over those mountains
man yeah that's it's such a sweet spot
like wild land Carpenter
Lake yeah yeah like and um that's what
my blades did there they would just kind
of Terrace the hillsides and just sort
of gorilla Style with shade cloth but
they would just tarp their whole Gardens
to get stuff to finish there because the
season was so short that's really close
to goldbridge and bror which is a really
super cool like very unique little town
that used to be for the gold minds but
now it's like used by professional
skiers and snowboarders photographers
and sleders all through the winter
you've seen any Canadian filmed you know
Teton movies and whatnot Bray Lauren is
always representing super steep gnarly
mountains and uh incredible beautiful
snow uh and I've got quite a few friends
for a town of you know 46 people or
whatever I probably know 20 of them
right right yeah it was a really cool
Zone it definitely let me impression on
me and we we kind of we kind of I mean
when we you know I've been in Oregon the
whole time I've been on the west coast
but we we had a property in in Humble
that we were managing while we were
farming up here and we kind of bit their
Style on that in our early years down
there just to not have all the Harvest
come in at the same time with a small
crew you can kind of stagger it but um
but here in Oregon that
that to grow like the longer kind of
really greasy strains um you kind of
have to Kickstart them to to get him to
finish here not have all so they were
light depping up there in northern BC in
the mid 90s yeah
yeah it's pretty cool hey um talk about
big plants uh Paul hail in the house is
uh from sub school and vert verness
Farms is well known to grow 20 pound
plants am I right Paul oh yes sir well
we were lucky enough to do two of
them tell us about yourself we got it
twice well been growing herb a long time
I started off uh back in Virginia and
indoors in the 90s and um and the early
2000s went out to Amsterdam got really
motivated to start getting into hash and
uh but was working with all indoor
material when uh things progressed and
we started got into a farm and started
getting experienced with outdoor started
utilizing some of the same things we had
learned indoors outdoor and one of those
things was root space was a really
really big deal for yield uh along with
a long veg time and you know of course
with some good fertile soil as well but
when we did that Outdoors after you know
getting some advice from up from some
other friends who were saying things
along those lines the yield started
exploding and uh you know we we were
able to have plants that were framed you
know 10 feet tall that were in smart
pots maybe 400 gallon smart pots and
then the exact same frame with the
unlimited root
space grown you know literally side by
side the whole time and the plants would
end up about the same size overall but
our yield would be 10 12 13 pounds on
the big hole and it would be four or
five pounds on the little smart pot so
you know after that happened we just
kind of ran with it and dug 12 by 12
holes got them highly amended uh the
years that we got the two 20 Pounders we
both had them in the ground at the very
end of April under some supplemental
lighting keep them from flowering but uh
it was really it's really magical when
it happens it's uh it makes an amazing
season that's sounds awesome I uh I'll
never forget my friend uh from overgrow
the mullum bimy madman who I used to
talk he was one of my first Australian
customers that bought bubble bags and I
guess his his father had you know been
involved in just really crossing the
[ __ ] out of this cultivar for years that
ended up being the mullum bimby madness
and so this this dude would just be like
no you got to try it you got to try it
and like trying to send me nugs and
stuff and I'd be like no no don't do
that don't do that like this is like the
'90s right and so in the end I I ended
up getting some beautiful seeds from it
that I still have to this day but he
sent me photos and this this is this
this goes to show you how far back it
was they were like actual photos not you
know there was no digital sending
pictures so he sent me these photos of
uh this Mullen bimby plant that ended up
being I guess it was about 10 to 12 feet
tall tall but it was 18 feet wide uh he
ended up just getting this enormous
amount of cannabis off of it was it was
like close to 20 pounds uh and just
beautiful exotic sativa the Mullen bimby
Madness I mean I'm sure skunkman Sam
probably knows more than I do about the
strain but it was slapped with
everything it was just kind of like the
way the Hayes brothers did it Sam you
know where it was like the just taking
different things that came in and and
throwing it in
you know the first time I ever saw the
largest plant on overgrow Marcus is that
that guy posted those for the first time
and it just let it literally lit the I
mean our small community on fire we just
all kind of I'd never seen
20 no it was yeah we've gotten really
close both seasons we had the big ones
uh we had a bunch of 18 and 19 pounds
that that year we had 32 plant pounds or
I'm sorry 32 plants and we got a little
over 440 pounds so that it was truly a
blessed season and just eye opening what
what I wanted to say though is that on
the biggest plants we've grown they've
also been the healthiest and they come
amazing you know there always been
question to people thinking oh these
these older plants they've been through
a lot they're not going to really put
out and you know have the same THC
content but they absolutely do if
anything the bigger plants were better
than our smaller plants were at the end
of the day and so so the year you grew
those cers tell tell me about that
harvest
party oh my gosh I were they clones or
were they
seeds they were seeds they were from
both both times that we had the big all
from bod seed uh it was a
snow the snow was the first one that we
did it and then the triple goddess was
the second one that did it and the uh
the snow we have a picture on Instagram
I believe 11 people all holding hands
with their arms spread out was about
what we measured the circumference on
picture yeah yeah that was that was
super fun and how big were the
St oh ridiculous like like my around the
stock yeah the the when the w we
actually had a bunch of rain and heavy
winds come through right like a couple
days before we were harvesting and uh we
had the support for that we had three
steel cages to hold it in place and the
wind hit it and she crushed all the
three steel cages we had to use a come
along and put uh toost we nailed all the
way down into the ground to stand her
back up to limp her through the the last
few days to harvest but the the weight
of that plant like wet could you
unbelievable it
was a treat could you get if you had if
you took your two hands could you get
your fingers around the bottom of the
stem B
no you couldn't get them around no no
way
actually yeah that's that's the way I
judge them they're they're either a tree
or they ain't a
tree we made a lot of really fun videos
where we'd have people inside the tree
you know dabbing and smoking and then
walk out you know and kind of give
perspective of how big those things get
uh but it's you know it's definitely was
a I don't know it's kind of like you get
the Gold Fever now I've got the giant
fever it's just it's so fun when they
get that big it's it's truly magical
it's it's a different dimension and then
to be able to to to show people what's
happening they've never seen that before
is just it's electric it's really fun I
had two friends in southern orian that
grow really big like that which is the
Snodgrass family and they had yeah
they've got some some plants and the
Williams Wonder was one plant from down
in southern Oregon that got really
really big and another friend named Jim
down there who would grow some some
really big plants uh as well and I know
that they would Harvest sort of the
outside of the plant at first and let
the inside kind of grow out within a
week or two and then they would get you
know say two to three harvests off off
these particular varietals and they did
come from seed as well so um yeah we did
that as well even with the snow and the
20 pounds we took was only the first
harvest only the buds we pulled down off
there I never even posted or talked
about the second and then the third
Harvest because if we're going to put
that weight together it's just Sil at
that point it's just silly the uh and
and the the reality is all of that stuff
went to Hash you know everything that
was smaller went to hash and it worked
out fantastic it just kept it just kept
giving sorry about that that's awesome I
like the way the camera even flipped
right when you went back the timing was
perfect it it in it it really showed
that there was a good quality and a good
amount of hash oh right
on and that's in the Sierra St up the
camera we're in the Sierra we're located
at well on the farm that we did the 20
pounds now we were at 1,800 feet the
farm that we're on now is at 2600 so
we're a little bit higher but we get
amazing both spots get full sun all the
way from the beginning of the day to the
end um but we're located between Tahoe
and plaster bille kind of in the middle
right there what uh one thing we've had
going on really difficult is at the end
last year a deputy was killed on a Grove
about 10 it was a Grove that was run by
Cartel and the sheriff has fully
initiated uh raids without warrants and
all the legal anybody even with just
plants is getting chopped down so we
have a we have a whole lot of drama on
around us but what it's made us do is
it's made us kind of regroup the plan
for our farm and what what we're going
to get into for this next season The
Following Season here and what that's
going to entail is a big project
we have four rows 12et wide that we grow
right now each plant gets about 12 by
12 what we're going to do is we're going
to fill Center the center walkway
between the two rows to make a 30 foot
wide row then we're going to put six
plants in green houses in those rows and
try to get them into the ground around
February March at the latest and see
what this plant's really capable of
doing we're going to cover it and then
the greenhouse is going to become part
the structure that's going to hold it in
place but uh it's a perfect opportunity
kind of back down on our plant numbers
but it also gives us a chance to really
see how big we can grow them so I'm
really fired up for it we're getting
planning right now and yeah it's gonna
be fun to see I've never grown anything
more than about 25 feet
tall more than 25 feet yeah about 25
feet tall the biggest
tallest wow that's huge I think that
bookie was our tallest and I want to say
she was about 17 feet um the triple
goddess was really unbelievable because
I didn't I didn't take many pictures of
her but she was only six or seven feet
tall but she was so big around and the
key with that one was these big long
branches and the triple goddess I think
it was the OG that was in it just made
all these popcorn nugs from the middle
of the stalk all the way out so when I
looked at that plant I mean I didn't
even I wasn't even really that excited
about it it it I looked at it was big
figuring maybe 15 pounds 16 pounds it's
beautiful but ah it's it's just not that
big when it hit the scale though again
just shocking holy cow very little flar
and that one we harvested all the way to
the Bone we didn't leave anything for
the second third Harvest on anything
more than 10 or 12 pounds is a [ __ ]
tree
yeah it it is a
tree that's awesome I'm sure uh what a
beautiful thing to just be able to tour
one day where you're just like oh let's
go visit the you know oh it's the giant
redwoods it's like oh look honey it's
the giant cannabis plants we should
probably pull in for a little tour with
the
kids you know what what was fun I
remember saying to my wife that well
which one are we gonna smoke in today
hun it's kind of like getting in a
treehouse no doubt well and I'm sure it
made a a whole hell of a lot of hash
that's uh it's nice to know with
cannabis especially when the
government's all sort of like you're
allowed to have four plants and that's
it it's like okay like sounds good you
know it it's it's kind of crazy our
count been really good to us for a lot
of years but with what happened with the
deputy last year I I just feel that
they're uh they're going Full Throttle
with eradication no matter what the the
levels are so I it's an up and down ride
we'll play with six plants next year and
have a blast doing it so it's all
good totally well I have a 98 plant
license here that I can grow for my
medical license or if I wanted to grow
on the other side of things
recreationally I guess we're just
allowed for better than nothing for sure
but at the same time I'm kind of looking
forward to the day where we don't treat
cannabis like plutonium and feel that
you have to protect the whole world from
it and that really you have to limit it
in in any way shape or form it's uh they
don't they don't do that with
strawberries don't do it
with be
legal I I look forward to when in
California you can grow it like
Christmas trees and allow people to come
and pick their own mature plants you
know you grow a 100,000 on your your
field and then you uh let people come
and pick their own one or two kilo or
three
kilo plant and sell to them for a 100
bucks wrapping them up in the
plas dude how about you ask them do want
me to drill a hole in the bottom of it
for
you Sam on the East Coast uh some people
do that on their hemp Farms they allow
people to come and they uh they'll weigh
it out for them after they've walked
through the through the
field starting
to the first place go ahead Brian yeah
uh sheep I think it's Sheep Scott farms
in Maine does that they grow acreage for
hemp and really high quality I actually
grew the same strains like last year you
know sub Hayes um Hawaiian lifter all
these really pretty good strains and
they were did a free pick your own and
uh they
also if it's hemp got below 3% THC
yes sort of yeah how do they value it
what's the cost that they Char per wet
weight I don't know Brian maybe he has
some insight
you
know I would I wouldn't know I I'm
actually not sure myself in terms of wet
waiter yeah I mean there's such a
processing you know energy to it and
space provided that I think it's almost
a little bit of it's kind of like a good
luck in a way with it and hopefully they
know what they're doing I'll tell you
people getting it in Switzerland in
2001 when I was driving from uh Val
husen in the north down to Lugano in the
South uh we would pass these upic and
Switzerland has these things all over
there's like flower ones where you just
drop some Swiss Franks in the little
mailbox thing and you can pick a big
bouquet of flowers well they started
planting cannabis amongst those upic and
you could legitimately not that I needed
to I was hanging out with breeder Steve
and he had tunnels full of dank weed
like it was definitely some of the nicer
weed in Switzerland that I saw um so I
didn't really you know do it but I
thought wow that is the coolest thing in
the world like you can just go snip some
branches off that bad boy and like you
know go go home and and make a tinure or
do do whatever it is you want with it I
just it was still just fresh out of the
90s cannabis was still very illegal
everywhere and then here was Switzerland
where in val husen it was like football
fields giant huge
grows um most of the people in
Switzerland grew so much those years
that it all rotted they had no they
didn't understand the how the space that
cannabis took to dry and the environment
that was required and so all sorts of
cannabis rotted uh on the stem and also
in in the barns but what an incredible
site to see uh back then I'm sure you
used to go quite a bit too back then hey
Sam a absolutely I I saw thousands and
thousands of plants not only that but my
friends were using mobile darkening
units so they were like hoop CES that
could be
moved and they had a few hundred of
these hoop CES so they would uh because
I was there for seed production not weed
production and what we would do is
darken the plants off for uh two three
four weeks at the most pollinate it and
then move the darkening system to the
next group of plants and the seeds would
finish mature it would rev and uh not
have any mold problems because in
Switzerland if you varieties it could be
a lot of problems with uh mold and
everything else but uh this this worked
out really good the plants never even
finished flowering but they still had
pretty good seed yields and uh it was
totally easy to
do interesting and that was in
Switzerland was that in the North or
no that was near
Zur
sorry I missed that it was near Zurich
oh Zur Zur Zurich zik
yes excellent good to know I haven't
been to Switzerland in a very long time
um I used to really quite enjoy going
there it's very beautiful it's very much
similar at least in parts to British
Columbia with the big mountains and
forests and you know epicness that's
there hey welcome uh Logan in the house
is that Logan in the
house yo respect everybody Welcome dude
early morning in Hawaii I I I didn't
realize how much earlier Hawaii was than
than BC it's like our it's just like us
for the East Coast exactly man y yeah
that's right um yeah the alarm clock
didn't go off but yeah I'm here man give
thanks for the invite nice well happy to
have you man so yeah we uh we met I met
Logan on one of the dragonfly Earth
medicine uh shows and really just loved
his transparency and his truth and his
uh commitment to his mission and I just
uh uh resonated with him pun
intended I want Logan are you drinking
mate um this morning I I I recently quit
the the coffee thing the con of coffee's
big over here you know so I recently did
that for health reasons but um I'm
tonight today in spirit of dragonfly
Earth medicine I made some
cacao okay it because it looks like a
mate cup yeah yeah my my brother
actually gifted me these because we do
uh do the mate quite
often nice have you guys ever taken mate
and ran it through your bubble bags no
it does it have a uh a glandular resin
gland it does indeed wow interesting
yeah I saw you I saw you getting down
with a few different things yeah back in
the day you know I just was like I was
kind of like Well there must be
something to this and then I I went on I
would you know there I didn't understand
the language a lot I didn't know a lot
of the terms and so it was difficult to
do research on something that you didn't
really know the terms for but eventually
I found an article from a BRI uh from a
university on glandular tricomes of of
mint and then I bought some mint and I
went home and I made some mint hash ran
it in my bubble bags made this little
Gummy mint hash you know dried it out
was kind of like what should I do with
this so I was like I'm gonna have a bong
rip of it of course so I slapped the
mint hash in the bong and I took a big
bong rip and I blew it out it was just
like it was so smooth and and just
Pleasant that I was like you know that
that was kind of crazy and when I say a
bong R like because I was now trained in
the art of full melt um first of course
by you know the Maestro skunkman Sam in
in 95 via not from but via a friend of
his I saw the First full melt if it
don't bubble it ain't worth the trouble
um and that really sort of uh opened my
eyes to it so I would waft the match or
the beine it was a match back then over
the over the hash to kind to allow it to
melt and stuff not really burn it harsh
so that's why it was just this beautiful
pleasant experience I'd really vaporized
the mint so then I was like well I got
to do this with cannabis like maybe
maybe it'll soothe the bong rip and I I
you know I put a bunch of full melt hash
in and and some mint hash and I took a a
rip of that through the tube and was
like just blown away how I didn't wow
the mint so I go and I do this I go onto
the internet and I'm like mint suppress
cough and it's like r J Reynolds $322
million study to come up with
mentholated cigarettes I'm like whoa $32
million I used a set of bubble bags and
some
mint and a bong you know it just blew me
away it reminded me of the uh the
Americans spending all that money for
the the pen that would would write in
space and then the Russians just used a
pencil I was like that's crazy well
that's that's what you know in uh in
their system the dumbest idea ideas rise
to the top and then they get funded with
all the money so you know nothing but I
think it was uh I think it was a
straight concentrates is actually who
I've been been uh following recently
they've been doing a bunch of glandular
extractions I think they did hops
recently yeah and and I think he was
working on something else too recently
but yeah real interesting to realize
that you know that those glands are
really just the protection mechanism not
just but are function has a highly you
know evolved protection mechanism for
these different plants in this uh
wonderful plant kingdom and for our
Consciousness talk about a protective
mechanism wow there go it's okay Marcus
if we call you a mint head uh you know
what I didn't get hard into the mint I
got to admit Sam that was the last batch
I'm just joking because in La back in
the70s mint heads they would put PC p on
mint and smoke it and everybody call
them mint heads bro then you can
definitely call me a mint head that's
like my regular
ritual I got it in a salt and pepper
shaker but it's called the PCP Shaker
instead of wake and bake you wake and
Fry oh my God that puts a new meaning to
to the name thin M listen I'll be honest
I am not a fan of disassociative drugs
like PCP and like belladon and like uh
you know just I don't like drugs pamine
is the same K listen any drug that you
have forgotten that you've taken a drug
while you're super lit and frying hard
not interested in yeah
Salvia it's the same stuff yeah Salvia
was uh I've seen too many bad
experiences in Lugano with that Salvia
stuff it always would start well breeder
Steve used to think was funny as hell I
know trust me it was part of what made
it even
worse yep I I told him if he ever does
that to me it'd be the last thing he
[ __ ] did well I'll never forget when
he did it to horge sentes because I was
sitting there with him and it was just
us and he said to horge hey do you want
to get higher than you've ever been with
a bong and passed him like the you know
the lighter and the bong and hor was
like sure I've never horg doesn't even
smoke a lot he hit this bowl like
nobody's business uh finished it right
off and then literally proceeded like
I've never seen anything like it like he
just you could see the moment where he
was like realized he was in this
full-blown Terror trip and he just like
grabbed the side of his face and
screamed this terrible scream inside the
warehouse at Steve's place in Lugano and
uh it was not a good vibe I remember it
actually upset Annie reiken quite a bit
she she got really upset with
it don't do that to people you know I
like to follow Tim L's two Commandments
of never giving people a psychedelic
without their knowledge uh and never
trying to keep people from taking
psychedelics those are the the two
psychedelic Commandments that I can get
behind
personally I think all police officers
should probably do a healthy dose of
LSD I think uh we should take their guns
away
first hey on that subject uh what's it
all like with the Canadian police
compared to American police police
because we got all these police that
just love to beat people up and kill
people how you Canadian police just got
called to a uh what's it called now a
it's like a checkup you know but really
what it is is it's abuse of power and
it's usually a jilted spouse is like oh
she has a she has a history of M illness
can you go check up on her so they
rolled up on this native
woman and killed her in her home this
happened like two weeks ago maybe Nova
can Canadian please carry
guns uh tasers and guns absolutely you
know we don't have the level of it
obviously we don't have the amount of
people that are down in the US but that
should happen two weeks ago no one can
deny it you know like checking up on her
and end up uh killing her two people got
killed out in I think it was New
Brunswick or maybe it was Nova Scotia
but it was I think it was New Brunswick
and uh another man got uh indigenous man
got killed out there and then other
people saw the the chief that got
attacked that was in March terrible I
would say the biggest issue with police
up here that's super alarming and even
not with police but it's the missing and
and murdered indigenous women is is a
massive massive problem up here in
Canada and there's highways up here that
are not associated with the police um
that are associated with truckers and
different people on on the road that you
know there's a lot of killing of of
indigenous women and so that that's
alarming British Colombian cops don't
have to have cameras on their body
either so I think that's another push
here in in British Colombia is to have
cops you know have that accountability
of of having um body cam
and I mean Vancouver is a well-known
like there's some really really bad
spots in Vancouver as beautiful as it is
and and it is a spectacular City to to
visit and everything but there's some
heavy duty homeless spots and hardcore
spots in Vancouver I mean Canada is
known as as a wonderful country and and
generally a lot of the people are super
super awesome but there there is a
definite undertone of of racism I mean I
think Vancouver is the largest seik
population outside of
India um and it's not funny but you know
Vancouver is known as hongcouver maybe
it's funny but anyway there's a lot of
people Toronto
also um anyway so that's that's some of
the stuff happening up here yeah and the
there's the biker element too and they
they really hush up the police on a lot
of stuff the bikers
do yeah I was just curious it seems like
some intelligent people could really
figure this stuff out really quickly and
and for some reason they choose not to
but and not to harp on that subject for
too long you know I keep it positive
around here well the police in America
are protected by the police unions what
you need to do is declare the police
unions domestic terrorist groups and get
the [ __ ] rid of them yeah they need to
demilitarize the police for certain
because that was the start of the end
right there like just don't we don't
need these guys like in fully armored
vehicles with grenades and machine guns
and you know huge bulletproof everything
like that's dude police is just like you
need to like you're there to help people
not not murder
them deescalation and human rights you
know like Health you know like
humanistic intervention you know people
would be nice to go around with the cups
I mean there's a lot of mental illness
out there and I mean I don't even know
how you legitimately create a police
force that's perfect so I I understand
the difficulty in that but I think the
dialog important I dialogue is important
and it's you know for me I haven't been
involved in the dialogue too much I've
really been just watching and reading
and listening and it's funny because
I've been called out by a few people
like hey you're not backing us up and
I'm like oh yeah I'm doing I'm gonna do
something and so what I planed to do
I've contacted my partner Claude from
Jamaica and I thought you know is there
a way to get this is mainly about black
lives matter and and sort of you know
the discussion that's going on right now
with the police murdering black men in
this accelerated way and this whole
white privilege and I thought well gez
like how can I use my platform to
involve that conversation so I called my
buddy Claude And I said hey would like
Richie Spice and some other artists be
interested and maybe we could get knife
this amazing Rastafarian PhD that I've
had on hash Church before he's just
brilliant and he on both sides of the
fence from the Rastafarian sort of deep
knowledge Elder Knowledge but also from
the schooled and educated um side of
things you know maybe get John nine
who's a female artist from Jamaica and
sort of offer them the platform to speak
about white privilege to speak about
rasa Fara and livid and the music and
and and cannabis and ganja and all of
these things and so he he was kind of
excited when I when I offered that to
him so that's a I'm going to try and get
uh going on hash church here in the very
near future while this conversation is
fresh and so that's uh you know
something that we can do to use the
platform to you know give more exposure
to a very important
conversation nice man on just on Friday
we held an event uh we have a record
shop and a smoke shop in town and it's a
roots and culture shop AR rasa shop here
in Kona town and we had a end police
brutality equal rights and justice for
ra um uh peaceful protest which was
actually just a a musical um dance hul
and we uh sered free food free itol food
for the community and handed that out
and people were just loving life man
because of all this Corona BS and
everything everyone came out and you
could just see the people and The
Awakening that's happening around the
world because of these serious serious
issues com to the Forefront of people's
minds and everyone have to kind of
re-evaluate what their position on the
earth is and and really what's going on
you know and what is what is life and
what is health and you know all these
kind of questions that are coming to the
Forefront it's very true there's no
denying it you know just just even with
you know whatever covid-19 is the one
thing that I've seen that's come out of
it that I was really quite excited about
was the interest that people had to
produce their own food and the interest
that they had to plant a garden and to
start having a discussion about how do
you plant a garden where do you get
seeds what do you plant your garden in
what kind of soil do you use how often
do you water it and all of a sudden
these you know they weren't talking
about what was on Seinfeld last week
they were talking about those
conversations and although I have a lot
of friends that are involved in those
conversations already I started hearing
people who have never been involved in
those conversations starting to say
these things and having these
conversations with their kids because
their kids aren't at school anymore
they're at home not on stop and it's
like hey what can we do it's like well
you can only watch so much Seinfeld
let's plant a garden let's plant some
seeds let's grow some food let's check
out the relationship that we have with
the Earth that produces the substances
that we need to energize our bodies to
continue on in this thing called life it
was I it's it was a pretty nice little
Revelation that I had and then dragonfly
Earth medicine starting these shows
right at the time also showed me that
they were seeing it as well that they
were tuning into that as well that the
choir is always there to preach to but
that there was this new group that was
willing to listen now and what timing
for for their educational uh soil Health
series props to that Josh and
Kelly yeah thanks appreciate that that's
the true Revolution keep going Colin
sorry yeah I was just gonna kind of kind
of work off of what you were you're
touching on Marcus is what you know
we're we're in a an Awakening right now
and that Awakening is um is pouring over
into social injustice it's it's
highlighting and put a microscope on the
things that should have had a microscope
on them a long time ago and we you know
we're we're we've you know we have to
bring everyone's voice together to fight
for the justice that needs to happen and
we can be better for it and we can all
be more aware of ourselves the
surroundings that we put ourselves in
and
ultimately the future that we hold in
you know in front of us and that's
that's the most important thing and I
think you know I'm doing my best as a
privileged person in all this to listen
to learn to try to understand all the
different facets of of all of this and
to support um and be a support system in
any way I can um but it's you know that
that's Marcus doing that show would be
great you know and and putting some
sponsors together you know that people
can can donate to for a good cause would
be really helpful and you know if
anyone's out there listening now I think
it's important to um pick a great
organization to support and to um you
know make sure that the whatever you're
giving to that organization is going to
the cause that you're you're mostly
profoundly um you know getting behind so
you all have a lot more faith in
humanity than I do well we've been
around less than you dude you've seen
way more harshit than us ganja Farmers
the ganja Farmers remember recent
demonstration during the recent
demonstrations at Berkeley when they
looted a bunch of
dispensaries that was a
bummer yeah that's I feel like that's a
lot of organized crime taking advantage
of the broken system um and
unfortunately a lot of there's a lot of
good outfits that did get hit I know
Magnolia got hit I know that berly
patience groups got got hit three
times W yeah I I heard harbor side was
just completely it just wiped everything
out so I I feel for all of those
businesses and it is a shame it's it's
not okay um you know it's that's a tough
one when you see things like that going
on I I think it's the ones we need to
reach the most the ones we need to reach
the most are the organized criminals
they're the ones whose Minds have to be
turned around you got to remember that
the Brotherhood of eternal love were a
bunch of
biker criminals before they turned
on
yeah it's interesting
perspective Surfers I have a quick
question for everyone what is everyone
puffing on because I'm puffing on this
uh concentrated X DNA gentics banana
strawberry banana bubble
has baby I'm puffing on this variety uh
that I had made actually Sam called
Square I called it Square wave and it's
a Hindu Kush times skunk one times
taii so it's it's a dumper has makes the
most 90u out of any variety that I've
ran to date is that that I've been
collecting yeah this is this is press
but this is from uh from from oh [ __ ]
he's pulling out the
jars dude some nice things on the screen
right
now yeah um also have a solventless cart
of uh Rosetta Stone that I made U that
I'm trying I'm testing right now which
is really quite delicious Ros Rosetta
Stone has a more of a Jack Jack herrer
kind of vibe to
it little lenon
oh [ __ ] strawberry
Angela damn this is some strawberry
Angela low temp flower
rosin what
temp strawberry
angel we're starting to we're starting
to get more requests for people that
want to supress
hemp and make cash out of it there's
someone out on the East Coast that's
like oh yeah we need a bunch of hemp I
was like oh yeah give my friend Dave a
call but yeah I know there's a have you
guys been hearing about that or what's
up yeah I've been I've been pressing
some hemp uh I think there's a big push
for people trying to get solventless
products on the market from hemp I think
you know it's a real viscous material I
don't know if anybody's been pressing
any of it or watched any uh hemp before
but uh it's mainly like a 45 25 kind of
grit to it real
I heard friends don't let friends press
h that's what I
heard that's number one and number two
you press hemp that's 3%
th resin or the rosin will be way way
illegal that's true
yeah it's real visous too because of the
lack of of canono it's really
interesting so most of the people up in
Canada have to grow good hemp under
a
um Regular like recreational license
because if you get a hemp license in
Canada you're basically locked into
their varietals which are not
representative of high CBD cannabinoids
so you know you have to kind of have a
regular recreational license in order to
even bring you know be able to bring in
varietals into your scene but then again
you have to do it when you start your
license because you can't bring it in
afterwards it's kind of messed
up well that's you can you can bring
varieties in
afterwards I I ship seeds to
uh I I shipped uh a kilo a week ago with
a Canadian import license and with u uh
all the legal certificates required and
uh there's no
restrictions all right well there's some
type of restriction for some I don't
know I was just talking to David Peron
on the uh from the green organic
Dutchman and there's there's you know
for some they can't just bring in
varials they have to create them after
they have them you I don't again there's
a lot of logistics to it but I know that
definely that way for are starting I
think a lot of it has to do with people
all have different levels of knowledge
and because I I'll tell you I had a
friend of mine tell me that absolutely
no way can you bring seeds in Canada and
I was like okay like I know people doing
it but you know that's neither here nor
there Le i' I've supplied 20 of the LPS
in
Canada well and I can tell you I was in
an LP in Canada staring at these
beautiful skunk Haze plants in um in a
greenhouse and I was like man like I was
like where did you get the first I said
what are these and he said they're skunk
Hayes and I was like where did you get
these and uh he didn't really know but I
knew I knew right away where they came
from and they were beautiful man they
were like seven eight feet tall huge big
rows of them and just really healthy and
resinous and had my mouth
watering hey I got a quick uh quick in
put onto the squishing hemp not to
change back to an old subject but just
real quick um you know I was always I
was always a little skeptical of the CBD
push when it first came out I own a
smoke shop and you know we sold a little
bit of CBD and my friends Matt rise
who's one of the first pushers of CBD
and you know I took the pills and I
smoked some of the early flowers and
some of the early hash and you know it
it it was cool and everything but really
when I got a nice an ounce of some
really high-grade hemp flowers from
organs that my buddy grew all you know
Korean natural farming style and I took
it home and I actually squished it on my
Rosen press and for the first time I
took a really fat nice you know like a
really good dab using you know the same
technique I would with some you know
really good fresh Frozen and The
Experience from smoking that hash
convinced me about CBD and I actually
got enough concentrated form to actually
be able to testify to the powers of CBD
and it was only in the form of rosin
from those really highgrade flowers that
I was able to come up with that
testimony and now I can actually tell
patients what it's all about if if
you're making rosin out of uh a high CBD
variety then the THC level is going to
be a couple of
% true it's notc which is what makes it
good right
true well I would go one step further
and say that with no CBD it's even
better maybe it's time to change your
name from hemp guy to THC
guy I concur Sam I think that uh most
most varieties I've seen from test
results um on a wide variety of of of uh
different cultivars they're really
anywhere from like four and up in terms
of percentages um very rarely is it
actually at the legal limit in which
they're asking everyone to be at so it's
um
it's it's almost impossible to produce
High CBD varieties that fall within the
legal limit because the CBD synthesis
reduces THC at a ratio of about 20 to1
which means that if you've got 20% THC I
mean 20%
CBD your CBD level is going to be like
you know more than 1% right THC exactly
yeah and that's that's before you squash
it right exactly and that's that's the
that's the beauty of it all right now is
that there's there is very much a gray
area and I think you know if we keep
working and working these lines I think
eventually you know as the farm bill
caught up in the in the states I think
you know hopefully I think the the laws
will catch up and everything will be
worked out to reflect the plant's you
know ability to produce those
cannabinoids and those those major and
minor
cannabinoids does anybody know how um
how transparent these testing companies
are and actually how accurate these
testings are and all that because I know
just a lot can be manipulated with
Statistics and testing and maybe even
pay off a company or these kind of
things has anyone really looked into
that or are we just kind of trusting
science at that point I have my own lab
for the last 30 years like your own lab
as in you do the the the
ACTC uh uh uh gas chromatography we had
our own lab set up a decade before Steve
pill
that's amazing Sam so what I'm seeing um
just from my own experience is that it
depends um what instrumentation the lab
has and the investment they' put into
that said instrumentation so let's say
one lab Lab a will have gas
chromatography hplc and the lab B will
have liquid chromatography and while
they're both maybe right for those said
Labs they're both going to give
different and results and we trust those
end results to then go to market with so
that's the the difficult aspect of where
the debacle I guess of labs right now is
that there's no standardization for
anything so we're really left with
trusting their processes once we give
them our material um so that's where I
see the biggest there are public there's
there are
publish
methodologies which you can follow and
you will get the same results with the
same Machinery with the same
materials yeah so okay I hear what
you're saying so but what I'm what I'm
illustrating is the fact that no two no
no two labs are the same where in my
experience where most of them have their
own set of Sops and instrumentation and
one one might not have instrumentation
that the other might have so right
that's the biggest differentiation when
I send a test result out like banic I
don't want to name n but there's certain
certain companies give me higher test
results and I I see it from just the way
that they test stuff so I think there is
a disconnect in terms of that there's a
H
Farm there's a H Farm out here a hemp
Farm out here in Hawaii just real quick
a hemp Farm out here in Hawaii that I
know personally and um he sent in three
samples of the same exact plant and
labeled them differently just to test
the test lab yeah and he got three
different
results how different were they couple
points or like significant uh not not
super significant no but but enough to
where maybe hey I can't sell that batch
you know what I mean like that kind of
you know that that would matter you know
you mean in terms of the pesticide
screening or the heavy metal screen or
more more like the percentage like all
of a sudden you have much THC and now
you can't sell that batch legally or
something yeah exactly that's I see I
see it from Lab to lab um and and
there's definitely I don't know Sam if
you've seen this but I I've I've been
told there's a 30% variance um based on
the the testing methods that that are
used um and that's a huge variant
identical Machinery identical
protocol you get identical results I'm
telling you I I when I set our lab up we
had a lot of trouble getting standards
we finally did obtain proper standards
we tested them
and we knew they
were uh they were claimed to be 98% THC
when in truth it was 86% THC and I also
sent a sample to Dr Bren Eisen in
Switzerland and Dr El in Mississippi
they confirmed my results we had
identical results to them because the
three of us were doing it
correctly yeah it seems we need you to
open the lab there's serious scientific
labs and then there's these business
Labs that open up that you know you know
maybe they're given higher numbers maybe
they're you know not as good at their
jobs maybe they're not able to follow
the standards and the Sops as well but
there's definitely I mean if you want to
see how accurate labs are really the
only way would be to develop your own
system where you knew each and every
time like Sam was getting accurate
results that were like verified by two
outside Labs the Eli lab in Mississippi
and the one in Switzerland those are
like big named labs and then you send
that same material out to two or the two
they were the
two I'm
say what I'm saying
SOB Labs I mean it's expensive but if I
want to know the accuracy like I'll
definitely send it to more than one lab
and uh you know see what kind of VAR
ations I
get I wanted to send our weed to Prague
and get the 100
canid
bio that's that's that's kind of the Big
Goal you know get Beyond 12 canabo if
there's books and everything written on
all these canabo then why are we fooling
around with 12 canabo like is it 2020
yet I'm just
wondering and yeah hey Bri I was
wondering go ahead just wondering just
wondering about Bri you were doing a
bunch of work on your farm and how's the
best friend Farms development going
how's Maine feeling what's the weather
like and you've been talking to ancient
green and everyone out there and I'm
just wondering how's the vibe out there
yeah it's uh we're having great weather
here sorry about that just got a little
distracted but um yeah it's been
beautiful beautiful day days we're today
even pushing I think the 80s here on the
farm and I've back and forth with
ancient green gonna go see them next
week actually and finally get over to
their farm and I've just been going
crazy on the vegetable tip and
ornamentals even and seeing a lot of
volunteers come up on the land this year
so um yeah just really connecting to the
plants as well the same the same tip I
think that most people are feeling and
kind of digging deep into thoughts and
exploration just through planting of of
local Terre and
even um I guess uh the the ground we
walk on the air we breathe you know the
water that falls here and trying to be
healed by the medicine and fed by the
food that comes from that so working at
everything every way we can trying to
bring in birds with bird houses and um
you know introduce worm hopefully have
some fish soon and yeah and love you
guys thanks for everything for all the
knowledge dragonfly it's been
definitely um a lot of learning through
you guys in a in a short time
already that's that's awesome it's been
super fun watching you develop the farm
and everything and you know see it rage
and dogs and everything going on out
there and stuff looks pretty
sweet yeah all the way in everything
mind B Body Soul all the way Spirit even
included here and my lady's been helping
me with all the gardening her thumbs are
like fluorescent green John Deere Green
and it's
just so we've been kind of having a nice
fun
what oh excuse me I'm
sorry what
is the canono you're looking for drag
Light Farms what canabo are you looking
for I mean you know I'm looking for the
one that keeps the politicians alive
through all sicknesses I don't know I'm
look I I I'll tell you when I find it
you know it's not like I have a desired
thing I just am in recognition that
there's over a hundred cannaboids in the
plant and we are why don't you tell me
what I'm looking for since you've
studied you know the plant in and out
basically you're talking to the wrong
guy I'm a recreational guy THC is where
it's at all the other conides do not get
you
high well CBM it you know and and I love
that you love getting high um it's just
it just happens to be that there's other
ailments out there that the ganja helps
and so it's super useful well that's why
I what you want hey that's why I'm
asking asking you what do you want
because I know what I want you want th
in the right
tures what I'm looking for we're after
THC the fra we after
THC
sorry go ahead my
go I I I don't have much more to say
other than just I like the fractal of
possibilities I like that it's fractal
medicine you know I'm not going to just
like throw in the towel because we found
th you know what I mean like I'm out
there like believing there's something
more to it also you know I mean I think
DHC is awesome I'm smoking weed right
now you know what I mean but uh you know
I like the herbalist aspect of it so you
know I mean there's there's more to the
ganja than even just the resin you know
I mean there's the roots hold you know
tremendous uh potential in healing
medicine so when we make our medicine
you know we're making whole plant
medicine and and I think there's value
to the Lea
you know I think there's value to the
seed and to the stem and and and it's a
fact so you know mat you know I I would
love to hear more about endo fidic and
and uh bacteria and fungi which comes
from the soil you know those are those
are unknown medicinal compounds I mean
they're just beginning to to study those
so do I believe there's more to the
Cannabis than just THC hell
yeah maybe THC just get you high I'm not
trying to say there's not nothing more
I'm saying it won't get you high that's
all I'm saying of course there's there's
all these other con I I developed the
world's first High CBD variety we did
the same thing with CBC cpg
thcv and uh another half dozen
cannaboids but they were strictly for
medical use they weren't for
recreational use a recreation what what
is getting high what is getting high
what does that
mean uh it's different for a lot of
people but uh some people get high quite
literally just to get [ __ ] up not
because they need it or want if they
want it but I mean you can get high off
of breath you can get high off of breath
work so I mean to say that
only I I say that's fine but it's not
what I I like smoking
THC you've gotten high off breath work
listen I want to make a comment about
the breath work one because it's funny
Terrence McKenna had a hilarious quote
on breath work because some because some
you know he was talking about
psychedelics and someone was like well
you don't need to take those drugs you
can do that with your breath and Terren
answered him well that's all good and
fine but when I take a psychedelic and
I'm tripping balls I like to know I've
taken a
psychedelic I thought that was pretty
funny it's a old esam Institute uh um
also too I've never done breath work to
the point where I did not exist there
was no
me I I've never been that high with
breor never right but you did take like
a hundred hits of acid so that's
like that's also true but uh there was
no I I guarantee
it I guarantee
it well really you have to understand
with Sam like he may sound abrasive and
like he's coming off in a certain way
but he really isn't he really just
wanted to know what canabo Josh was
looking for because for him it's if you
know him well he's very big promoter of
THC he always promoted even when people
were using medical as a shield when most
of them weren't medical at all Sam was
like I like to get high I will fight for
people who want to get high as hard as
people are fighting for medical right
now like why is either one less
important than the other they both
should be allowed and it one reason why
said one reason why it's important to
acknowledge the medical aspect of it is
because that's why we're having this
conversation right now we didn't get
into this conversation because everyone
wanted to get high we got into this
conversation because it gave medical
relief to people that were in chronic
illness right but check this out how did
we find that out how did we find that
out we found that out by getting high
that's how we found that out I'm I'm in
I'm in acknowledgement of getting high I
love get all day it led us to that the
medicine component of the plant so I'm
not saying either one is more important
than the other I'm just saying they
should always both be respected and
acknowledged oh I absolutely agree me
important for the people who need it I
don't I get
high question I still don't know the
definition of high what's the definition
of
high I don't think there is one if if
you need to ask then I'm not sure it
could be explained to you I know when
I'm high I will say this Logan I've
smoked a lot of hash and a lot of
cannabis in my
lifetime and remember hearing our friend
Rob tell me about oh God I was so high
the other day I just couldn't even and I
was like that's like come on like I've
never been that high like what's that
what is that like I I would smoke as
much as I could get to the brink and
still not be high enough that's just who
I am but when I went and visited Sam for
the first time I had a couple of pieces
of humble pie now he didn't completely
destroy me I didn't pass out or [ __ ]
myself like I thought for sure I was
going going to because I was just so
high and if you want to know what high
is it's like lit
like like a rocket ship flying through
space it was unbelievable this man put a
little bit of hash in the bowl and I
smoked it and it turned into water and
glistened and bubbled and melted and
before I had exhaled it I was so [ __ ]
high I wanted to run out of my body I
was and I'm sitting and I'm trying to
like not lose my [ __ ] this is like
someone I look up to I've been invited
into his very very very tiny circle of
people that he allows in and I'm not
trying to [ __ ] that up but man oh man
and then we smoked I don't know 20 more
of those he smoked for sure 60 more I
smoked probably 20 more and when I left
like my two sides of my body were like
unplugged I was walking like a weird
mon remember when we were at Legends
in Amsterdam here and Wally duck came
and tried our a really high quality
drives it he passed out cold and fell
backwards yeah oh yeah he then after we
picked him up and brought him over the
table passed out and set his hair on
fire from a candle on the
table that was no joke so those Legends
of hash parties you know that there's a
perfect example ex Le what is getting
high Legends of hash if you don't know
about it um it was a party that Sam and
I
started 15 16 17 years ago I don't even
know and it was really it was during the
High Times cannabis cop and of course
Sam had been there since the beginning
and I showed up around 95 like six years
later and I would go every year and we
would kind of realize like oh this is
kind of this commercial swaggy event but
it's all we've got but there's these
amazing people here and everyone's just
promoting themselves and flyers and this
[ __ ] and that [ __ ] and we were
all kind of sucked into it and so we
thought what if we started in a little
party that we we hand chose 50 people
based on their hash not based on who
they are based on their hash and that's
what the party was about and you
couldn't bring cameras and you couldn't
be on your phone you couldn't um promote
yourself in any way and give away
business cards and talk business it was
like let's just spend a night where we
eat a beautiful meal we drink some
amazing juices and eat some beautiful
fruit and we smoke an insane amount of
hash and and uh Sid would bring his
beautiful Afghan pipe some of which were
a hundred plus years old and we would
smoke these Hubbly bubblies with like
with Sam's insane like 60 to 70% pure
dry sift the [ __ ] that sent me off on a
rocket ship he's pouring a gram in the
in the no sometimes I put and grams in
it that's what I'm saying it was
ridiculous like I've never seen anything
like it and it was really truly a night
for people I would tell people who would
be like Oh I'm trying to get a ticket to
Legends I'd be like you know what like
if you don't want to smoke until you're
uncomfortably high like you don't want
to come to Legends because that's really
what that party was designed for and to
do and that would be my explanation of
what is getting high what is getting
high getting high is going to a Legends
of H hash dinner anyone that's ever been
can attest you will be high and you
won't have to question what it
was I would say the dragonfly Earth
medicine parties are pretty good too I
believe it we get
together marus I remember I remember
meeting you you in uh in in uh I guess
what was 2010 at the High Times canons
cup Marcus and I remember leaving one
night like him hanging out with you and
your your buds and and I walked around
the circle I think like Dam Square like
so many times that I ran back into your
friends when they were leaving like
three hours later they're like what are
you doing I'm like I don't
know I don't know I'm walking
man yeah I definitely am a big proponent
of medical it was it is what finally
took away prohibition getting high was
never going to take away prohibition um
but medical definitely was the you know
and
particularly you know sick children that
was like the last leg of prohibition
even the biggest douchebag
prohibitionists couldn't really stand
behind like taking medication away from
like little Charlotte Fiji or whatever
you know like how how you gonna how you
g to do that and that really that
cracked the door um that was never to be
closed I mean that was that was the
impossible happening and and here we are
today still not where we want to be but
but getting closer and closer oh yeah
look at that that's an Afghan Hubbly
Bubbly right there he's puffing tough
let me tell you those Afghani dudes puff
tough that is not uh if you think
smoking chillums in India or Nepal is
like heavy duty smoking and don't get me
wrong it is these are are more intense
than that it's like putting the Chillum
into a into a water pipe that has you
know gallon of water in it so it it
pulls quite a chub
chubble anyway so on uh speaking of
Afghani it made me think of something
Marcus um do you guys is that a texed
Time Warp gone for yester year up there
is is the time warp still around oh no
it's still around man it's still on Tex
island with some of the more old
schooler dudes there's all sorts of
crosses of it out there but the original
Tech of time War which is just a super
stretchy crazy you know tie cross um
that thing is that thing definitely
exists it's uh it's around and and and
it's not as hard to find as you'd think
uh if you've got knowledge you go to you
just go to Tex Island it won't be long
before you meet someone and you say
words and they hear those words and then
you'll be at like some old school dude
we can help you yeah exactly just be
like at Rainbow's house or whatever and
be like dude I met rainbow like I was in
his Greenhouse where he gave me a cut he
gave me a cut in a golden pot like look
at
this that's that's good to know that was
one of my favorite strains back in the
day I thought it was an Afghani because
I got I had a friend from Southern
humble and she had a pile of old Afghani
seeds and um and and um once in a while
you get you get some some of the plants
were really similar to what I remember
time where being
like but what what year did you smoke it
um I'd say all through the 90s like
maybe 90 mid 90s to around 2000 and then
uh then I just it it just seemed like it
um
obviously well early 90s I think uh I
grew I was growing up on Vancouver
Island and we were growing T mostly Time
Warp and uh and that was just a rocking
strain I mean where on Vancouver Island
were you I was in in
Suk yeah it was like probably the worst
place in North America to learn how to
grow outdoor
weed it's like right off the off the
muck coming off the ocean oh yeah in the
first year we had really in summer
beginners luck and then I think the
second year
um uh I remember I didn't from October 1
and until on I don't think I saw the
color blue in the sky till the following
spring
yeah it was it was rough but that that
was a pretty resistant strain I'd love
to grow it down here because I know
would do well here in
Oregon well you got Josh offering right
there nice that's good to know he can
hook you up we'll see if we can get back
into the US and back into Canada again
because that's the current issue at the
moment yeah I guess the Border still
closed
huh yeah I mean we could go to the US no
problem but we can't can't come back
into Canada without contact tracing and
a two week quarantine and I just don't
want to you know I don't want to do any
of that it just doesn't doesn't sound
right and I don't need that kind of
scrutiny and all that I just stay out in
the woods out here far away growing all
these insane varietals and everything I
mean our Greenhouse the plants are about
six or seven nodes high right now I
don't know about three two to three feet
all from seed and we have the
fattest stocks on all the plants right
now and some of the most like crazy
leaves we're not haven't used any te's
yet this year and uh it's just we're
just going on the incredible soil
building we've been doing over the last
few years and uh the health is just
amazing right now and it's just we're
we're starting to get some incredible
branching coming off the plants right
now so I'd say in a couple weeks we're
probably going to start our first light
dep but it's cold here right now it's
still in the SI Mid
60s um you know or 70s like we're in
this like super cold front right now we
had an early hail um yesterday and cold
here too and rainy I feel like it's my
fault I went and got my boat out of
storage that's how you make it rain in
uh in your neighborhood for those of you
that don't
know right get the boat out yeah go put
that [ __ ] back away
hey Colin you know on another show I
remember you talking about growing
clones in an indoor setting and then
seeing by the nutrient um inputs or by
the soil that you were getting more
waxes on your hash or less waxes and and
and you were noticing that the you know
the tricomes were different and I was
wondering what were some of the things
maybe that you that you that you found
that that changed that and what were
your what were your goals in the end
yeah yeah so that's great question um
it's like three we'll we'll unpack that
one um so it's uh so yeah so basically
what I went through was trying to better
understand the resin and how it was
growing in environmental changes that
affected it um
so essentially I started looking at
basically
your you know the vapor density and the
room the you know the avd so um so that
informed a lot of my decisions on like
keeping the the humidity a little bit
higher during veg and then understanding
that if you dried things out the wax
membranes on the on the leaves would dry
out and that would leave the plant
vulnerable to disease and to fungi and
to all these different uh topical things
that could happen betus that forms in
the flower itself which then can can
actually now we know it can actually
become sustain
um so and that's actually been confirmed
which is interesting um for all you home
Growers out there if you do get Petri
test on your beloved plant just be
careful and know that that is going to
most likely be with it there's qpcr
tests that you can get out there that
are fairly cheap you can test all your
plants and get U really accurate results
very quickly for all of you guys out
there that are um trying to do trying to
better understand your environment and
the Clones that you might might have so
that's the other thing is is
understanding how healthy your plants
are actually you know that was another
thing that I started to get into so it's
really about understanding the
environment so I went from uh very humid
70s 8s and then dropping that humidity
and understanding where to drop the
humidity for certain varietal or certain
cultivars if you will um and what I saw
is that during the more humid
environments all the way through flour I
had much better resin that was more
tacky and a lot stronger and under the
loop the it was a lot more uniform and
under drier conditions I had more a lot
more stacked Trion you could see it was
all kind of like jumbling up and when
you touched it they' all kind of hit hit
each other um so that was the biggest
thing that I learned through doing those
those those trials um and then medium
itself affected all of that as well
where I felt like soil
honestly um was a lot more uh conducive
to a higher res count itself it it felt
and this is you know all based off of
Photography and anecdotal for all of you
people out there I don't want to sound
you know pretend like there's there's
there's a University study behind this
but um what I found was um you know
growing in Coco produced a lot larger
biomass but it didn't follow suit with
my resin and where soil produced a lot
of biomass not as much maybe as the as
my uh you know my cocoa medium did but
it still It produced a lot more
desirable um resin on the actual flour
itself that I could then actually
Harvest so you know that was really what
you know I learned from doing that and
um I I personally think that it depends
on your application in which you're
growing in and I understand the hurdles
in which you're growing
50,000 square feet versus 400 square
feet and everything in between that and
then also um are you is your environment
you are you are you having to create an
artificial environment and then how does
that refect your medium choice so I'm a
big fan of going directly in the ground
I think there's a lot of value to that
the connection to the to the soil is a
big deal and amendments and
understanding how to play Within the
natural ecosystem is a as you know
you're an expert in that
um you know something that is really
what the plant desires I think at the
end of the day um and it's a lot easier
to uh grow at scale in my opinion when
uh those environmental factors are
working in your favor and you're not
having to tune them uh and then an HVAC
system may break but it all depends on
what your application is you know so
indoor can be great outdoor can be great
um but it you know you've got to have
the the understanding of your of your
environment um your cultivars that
you're putting in that set environment
are also very important and then your
inputs for that set environment and the
turine levels so turpine levels
um you know they honestly I think for me
tpping levels are higher on in a in a
greenhouse setting than they are in
indoor setting for me um however but
medium to medium I see very little
difference unless like from Coco to from
soil to Coco but if I go to rock wool
for some reason it's it feels a bit left
Less in terms of the the lab results
basically the lab results tell that
story so and I really let that stuff
Drive I don't try to have too much of an
opinion other than um trying to search
for the answer if that if you if that
makes
sense yeah that's super that's super
awesome good thanks for that
yeah what do you think about shade grown
anyone considering shade grown cannabis
even um for the aspect of hash even or
tpine influence on the hash where I mean
seemingly like the worms are more alive
the compost Deadfall from the trees and
stack up for humus is more active
underneath uh shade line tree layer
especially exposing itself to the right
exposure from east to west facing south
and bleed in of sunlight perhaps like
very location based shade grown for
production I think you can grow really
high quality in shade but your yields
will be significantly
less yeah I agree with that yeah we side
by side depos last year and shade tarp
one and we didn't shade tarp the one
right next to it and both of them had
tropical Truffle in it and the yield was
less not significant though um it was
within a couple pounds in the big
picture but the tpine was far better in
the shade tarp far better it it was it
was notably different you could
literally put two buds from each on a
table and see the difference too in the
color um it was a little bit less speed
up went you know and the way that they
hashed out they they both they both bled
about the same um for yield as far as
that went but the uh the turpine was
higher in the shade tart
yeah that's been our experience too
going to uh Farms you know at different
places is that if you have like Paul in
your area you know where it gets
scorching hot southern Oregon you know
110 all summer long it feels like
there's a lot of um automatic green
houses that have shade cloths that come
for even two to three hours in the
middle of the afternoon you know that's
in an automatic setting and stuff so you
know I I personally I would never use
any shade cloth up here because I barely
have any sun it feels like you know so
I'm going to take all the sun I can get
but I think it really matters on your
environment I wonder in Maine you know
how exposed you are to where you would
necessarily really need that but if what
Paul's saying you know I mean I would go
for the shade cloth in an exposed area
if it gave me better tping because
ultimately we do it for the
turps as well as the medicinal qualities
it' be nice to see that experiment that
Paul did in some different regions
that's for
sure yeah Central America even hot dry
where we're you know6
107 for multiple weeks so you know I I
know cooling it down they definitely
looked happier in that
environment definitely preserved tpin it
sounds like so that's that's great so
many I
think go ahead I think it probably helps
blocks the soil too you know keeps the
soil
more moist and more active I would
imagine the roots are a lot happier too
and hey Paul you you've been doing a lot
of more natural farming um practices on
the farm and really adding even more
attention to your to your beds and and
doing a lot of that work and I was
wondering are you noticing a difference
in in your vegetative growth this year
and um yeah just go ahead no I'm sorry
absolutely it's it's exciting um not
only the stocks thicker and everything
that we've got but the uh the smell of
the dirt has really changed and uh you
know Everywhere You Dig in we've got
earthworms we've life we got activity uh
you know really doing a lot with playing
with the imos uh you know this beginning
of the season end last season and I
can't believe how quickly things have
been making making a difference it's
exciting it's fun to
watch um hey I have a question um
so what is anyone you is there any
inputs that that anyone's been using in
terms of uh cover crop that um that
they're finding that are uh they're
exciting that they haven't used before
this year is there anyone that's uh is
you know maybe Josh you can speak on
some of this but uh you know I I'm I use
the same things over and over is there
is there anything new that that anyone's
been been explain you know exploring or
kind of playing around with in terms of
uh cover crop and uh
you know I think it really depends I
could let you know Logan and Dave answer
as well you know my our two senses is up
in this Northern Area the winter Ry has
been an amazing friend to us this year
and I know the Sudanese sorghum grass is
an incredible um biomass and and it also
you know in an indoor setting you know
the cover crop does a little different
things but on in a in a greenhouse or an
environment Outdoors where you don't
have ganja growing the cover crop can
keep micro risal fungi growing and Sudan
sorghum grass is one of the best you
know hosts for micro risal fungi so part
of the cover crops you know thing is the
stomata eats the air and Farms the air
you know puts it putting it into the
roots and then the other thing is uh the
fact that it's you know the green manure
so I I feel like having Clover it can be
really good but it at times it can also
get the the powdery m can come in on it
so I think it it matters so I I we mulch
is life for us so right now we just got
done putting all of our winter ride down
and it's incredible how much it's in our
case this winter Ry grows up to be
incredible grass and it's just so easy
to pull up and when you see the roots on
it they're just white and supple they
just looks so incredible and you just
realize oh W you don't really need to
bring anything in when you have a really
healthy cover crop but you can't really
do heavy Mulch and cover crop so well
sometimes you just fold the the the
cover crop over and it Reves so right
now I I just feel like more than
anything it's it's covered the dirt and
the mulch is is the magic it's the mulch
love and really diversity you know
buckwheat is is an amazing thing um it's
very Supple and really nice um to to
roll over
um those are those are some that that
come to mind Dave Oran anyone else have
any thoughts on
that straw local Straw from
the we we I'm sorry you go on wait to
done hello can you guys hear me I can
hear you I oh you man okay cool yeah go
for we've been um you know for our field
crops like for vegetables um
we're a big fan of like aye and a few
legumes we usually do like a field pee
and a vetch and fava and like Josh was
saying the the grasses you know kind of
help build up the organic matter and the
but they they really work well together
and then you know we kind of try to
knock them in the ground about you know
a good five weeks before we want to uh
plant so they have plenty time to break
down and
decompose um or you know anything that
we're going to plant later season we
like them to go the distance and we just
try to knock them down before the uh the
seed becomes viable so you're not
creating more weed problems but in ganja
in particular we've been a really big
fan of um of a New Zealand Clover it's a
white clover and uh really similar to
Dutch clover but the reason we like it
that Variety in particular is it
generally only grows to be about a foot
tall you know and it and it can handle
foot traffic traffic and it's drought
tolerant so to get it into your aisles
like because you know we're just growing
in hoop houses in native soil but the
plantet into your aisles after your
plants are established it kind of
creates a natural mat so you know your
but your buds don't get all dusty and
and uh and dirt on them but then it also
creates a lot of habitat for beneficials
and stuff and we find that if you let it
you know we usually plan it on our
second round like our July rounds um
after the plants are bigger big enough
to uh not get choked out but if you let
the white clover in particular go to
flowers before you before you uh turn in
The Following season um the the the
spike in nitrogen is is RoR it's like
it's really impressive how much how much
nitrogen you get off of that just a
little low line of of the white clover
so that that's been you let it go to
flour we well we let it go to FL yeah it
as as as as much as we can we let it go
to flower you know but some sometimes if
if we have to get into a hoop house and
plant before it flowers so be it but
generally that's that's the goal so you
know it'll it'll okay you know we'll
Harvest late October and then uh the
following April May is when it starts to
flower okay cool thank you it's a good
tip right there I would say that it's
really good to have growing cover crop
during the veget cycle and into the
beginning part of the flower cycle and
then it's really good to
drop that
vegetation into a mulch towards the end
of the flower cycle so that it's really
kind of capping off the top of the soil
and keeping the moisture in and it's not
creating any stagnant air and then right
be right as you're harvesting maybe a
week or a few days before you harvest
you could reapply more cover crop seed
to where it's growing just starting to
grow as you're harvesting and then that
would kind of get you right back into
your vegetative cycle so if you're
indoors or if you're in a FL dep or
you're in a place where you could like
kind of put another thing in there then
you'd have the the cover crop growing uh
which would keep the micro isal fungi
and everything in there the risos spere
happening and then the new plants would
go in and eat the old
roots are are you using beans to fix
nitrogen in your cover
crops uh we we use fava beans is one of
the as one of the beans we grow for for
for nitrogen
yep yeah yeah it just cuts down your
fertilizer cost yeah I mean we we we um
we definitely see our our organic matter
levels rise from year to year and where
we um are on top of our game with cover
cropping the the nitrogen levels will
will increase from from year to year we
are in uh in um you know we're in we got
a ton of rain here in Oregon so a lot of
that washes out but in in the hoop
houses in particular we really the the
nitrogen levels get they build every
year because you don't get that can
takes a huge amount of canabus cannabis
will absolutely deplete nitrogen from
soil if you gr enough in the
I mean nitrogen is the easiest thing in
the world to create I mean anything
that's green just melt it in water and
throw it over your I mean it's just same
how much so I for me nitrogen is like
simple you know it's it's to create the
carbon and to create the organic matter
which holds the fungi which holds all
the nutrients that's where the work is
like that's where the attention for me
that's where the attention goes too and
then um using the aisles for us is like
the frontier like everything that we
walk on is just fat organic matter and
over mulch the system you know and and
and if you have big beds on the edge of
the beds and on the sides of the bed
just a a large amount of of mulch for
decom decomposing and we're seeing a
good 8 to 12 inches of of of new soil
that we're folding onto our beds each
year right now and those aisles are just
all of our our new soil for our beds
each year and I recognize indoors that's
different and everything however if you
make your beds right um on the edge of
the beds where it comes up you can get a
lot of mulch in there or or even you
could dig out holes in your indoor beds
and pack those holes with food
scraps and and different kinds of straw
for for m isn't necessarily the best
because it doesn't have a lot of
nutrients in it so stra straws is fine
you know because it's carbon but you
know with with mulch you're really kind
of looking for nutrients that's where
like if if you're mulching with
comfrey and nettles and grasses and tree
leaves and all that then you have this
crazy diversity with all the trace
minerals in it and that's where the the
real magic comes from Logan I'll jump in
and share something about Hawaii real
quick cuz we're in a in like a
continuous Farm loop with the Cannabis
in particular where it's it's a year
round farming so we don't really get a
season off or anything like that so your
soil's always eating and always
decomposing and um like what Offa Josh
was just saying a lot of you know more
green material is what I've been been
going for and just real quickly I drew
this diagram real quick just to show
like a living soil bed with your
cannabis planted in it and what I've
been doing is planting my edges with the
with ComFree lemongrass and terara and
so what I'll do is that the comfrey
grows so fast I'll just come through it
when it starts to flour and you let some
of it flour for the bees and everything
but chop and drop that onto the beds
just constantly year round and then the
lemongrass I'm adding on there year
round and it's just always growing and I
got onsite green waste to add to my uh
to my beds all the time and then on top
of that I'm using lots of uh just
diverse cover crops obviously your
nitrogen fixers that are in there which
would be my imported seed but I'm trying
to wean off of the imported seed a lot
and I'm going more with seeds that are
more prolific in my area which one of
them is like this uh this edible
amarinth the kalalo from Jamaica and
that one just keeps growing prolifically
and I can just keep chopping and
dropping it and reeding it um to add to
that one thing I do like to uh use is
daon um if you can keep daon in your
beds all and for some reason it grows
great with cannabis they they're like
really there's something going on with
the um exit dates or something but these
daon I'll come back through and pull
them out after they've been in there uh
maybe I'll harvest my cannabis and I'll
see some of them that that survived and
you know you come back through and pull
them out and they're a couple feet long
of 12 to 24 inches long and some of them
are decomposing and if you look through
the middle of the daon route it's like a
tunnel like a like the outside's like a
shell and The Middle's like this rotting
tunnel of like just microbial life and
that's from the top of the soil you know
that's going straight in so that's like
an air tunnel in a microbial power you
know super highway and it's just adding
life deep down into that middle and Su
layer of your of your living soil so I
really love daon and the same with the
comrey if you pull up a free root to
replant it somewhere else you see that
rotting outside kind of decomposing root
has this channel going deep into the
soil of a brown rot kind of uh Decay
which which you can just see is like
this bacterial Super Highway and and uh
like Josh said that nitrogen is just
heavily abundant if you're using that
one more thing about uh the choice of
covering your
soil um wood chips i i notic in cannabis
a lot of people it's kind of stray away
from wood chips more than than uh maybe
they should and I just started using a
lot more wood chips recently with great
results and uh mixing actually like a
hard wood with more of like a green wood
we have I live on a coffee farm so we uh
chip the coffee boughs and in just in
one day of leaving these a pile of
coffee chips you'll see this white
mycelium running through it within 24 to
48 eight hours it's just you can go back
and open up the the pile of of this
because it's a soft green wood and um
you know so it's just this living Mulch
and and that mixed with the native ohia
wood chips which are more of a
hardwood um have created this whole
another layer of life that I've haven't
seen on my living soil beds that are
like 10 years old at this point you know
so some of those uh those kind of tips
and tricks would definitely implore the
daon some of these deep drilling root
vegetables maybe or deep drilling things
like um like your uh your clovers and
your your you know your comf and having
it nearby because Rudolph Steiner said
Rudolph Steiner said only a sick Farm
needs outside inputs so is your farm
sick is your farm sick or is your farm
healthy and I'm not speaking for a farm
that's just starting of course you might
need to bring something in from the
outside but if you're living on an
established farm and you're planning on
being there for a long time only a sick
Farm needs outside inut that's what my
quote that's Rudolph Steiner so I
remember
that nice well said good uh good tips
and tricks there for sure that's uh
that's good information you want to be
knowing these these things from people
who have actually done it one thing I
would say about the wood chips too at
least here in in in Pacific Northwest
cess and mushrooms just love wood chips
they really really love wood chips so
here in West Vancouver close to where I
live they just wood chipped every um
Boulevard and then put grass over top of
the wood chip but all of our boulevards
are basically wood chips so you see cyan
and mushrooms generally around October
November just popping out all over the
place you can find them even driving in
your car by looking for a much larger
honey mushroom that if you spot those
out of the corner of your eye you can
pull over and like I've literally
searched for cyan and mushrooms in my
vehicle like how ridiculous is that
every every other time I've had to and
you can see them in Vancouver as well
but they're simil inata liberty caps if
you go towards the Vancouver airport on
the right there's this big field of
grass during those months in particular
you'll see people walking with golf
clubs uh they're not golfing they are
picking psychedelic mushrooms and uh
good on them for doing that so
yeah that was a big issue in Oly from
Olympia up to through Seattle was like
Evergreen State College was is was they
mowed all the trees down and chopped all
and chipped all the trees and then put
grass over it and then built the college
so everywhere around the college when
Paul stamus was going to college there
and everything like can Essence were
just part of the campus yeah and then
they started using like you said wood
chips all over Seattle um in landscaping
and and it was just basically like put
wood chips out and they will come so and
and then sadly they started using a lot
of fungicides in the uh the
municipal uh uh wood chip areas to stop
like the spread of the Psychedelic fungi
and everything but it is really good for
people to to when they find a a big fat
patches they could grab a little bit of
that mycelium and bring it back to their
land along with fresh wood chips and
grow growing that on their land it's
good for the forest and it's good to
have that um you know growing on your
property little wild patches G gently
you know we had a we had a house that we
were growing in years ago and my partner
called me up in a in a flurry and he's
like he's like there's this Drey guy and
and he's picking something out of our
out of our front driveway and I'm like
what like you know we're we're paranoid
at this time you're not really allowed
to be growing it's pretty illegal and
we're just like is this Drey guy like a
like like an undercover agent or
something you know that's the mentality
you're thinking when it's super illegal
and you can get in mad trouble turns out
he's picking all the mushrooms that are
growing on Art we have this like insane
flush of mushrooms like buddy took a
giant bag of of cyan Essence out of
there uh and then we used it for years
and one year I was I was I went to go
there um to pick just a few
mushrooms and my ex partner was there
literally digging up the the entire
Mycelia bed with a shovel to take it
away I was just like dude like talk
about a faux paww pick a little but
don't take a lot when it comes to the
Mycelia when it comes to the mushroom
take a lot don't take a little you
shouldn't be able to see where you took
it from afterwards let's just put it
that way you could take a handful and
make it Grow from there if you can't
make it work with a handful you
shouldn't be taking it there's two
vibrations in this world fear and
scarcity and love and abundance and
people have a hard time they get trapped
in the fear and scarcity and it
definitely does make them do strange
insecure things that you would just
think like you know there's enough for
everybody like you don't don't don't
forget the biggest Mantra of mankind
greed greed is for
real I don't know maybe just a little
humility I like weed
instead of
greed yeah I uh I hear what he's saying
though you know the human race
definitely has a problem with greed
probably because the whole system is
based on fear and scarcity and the whole
design is just very inaccurate and
insanely wasteful and definitely not
sustainable probably why we're in some
sort of you know I don't
know strange Matrix like complex that's
that's uh just you know we're just in
some strain don't they say that fish in
the oceans have been reduced by
75% that we've reduced fish by
75% man did well the one that Disturbed
me the most was that and it was a freaky
one it was
like it was about the
Maman Mass on planet Earth it was from
David aten bro the the guy that did the
Earth series you know David um he he
said something oh it was to the tune of
it was like
77% of all bird life on Earth are
chickens in like commercialized chickens
77% of the birds in the whole world and
then it was a more it was even a more
disturbing world word for for the
mamalian mass it was like cows and pigs
and they made up this like they made up
like 96% of mamalian mass along with
with humans uh and then like zebras and
giraffes and lions and [ __ ] that was
like
4% of what was don't don't forget rats
that's probably a
few yeah exactly they probably make up
half the percent of all the the
4% it was kind of
depressing uh in a way of thinking about
it I thought well we could probably do
better than that like I I I'm pretty
sure we can do better than that we just
need to uh let go of some of these old
systems systems and come up with some
very new ones when you hear a statistic
like that it it should just ring a bell
think about what you eat and what you
consume and what you participate in
every day you know for sure that's big
time that's very accurate in fact very
accurate what are the systems that you
are supporting knowingly those are the
first ones you try to work through and
nobody's saying it's easy and you know
as long as you're working through
getting you know those cut down to
eliminated eventually then this then the
unconscious ones are there which are the
really frightening ones because that's
how the whole system works it it avoids
even conscious human beings and gets you
in some way or another it's uh it's
quite quite a shitome as Peter Tosh
would always call it I always thought
that was a very perfect perfect term for
the entire for the entire thing once
more cannabis and psychedelics have
helped me see through these things in a
way that I honestly don't think I ever
would have had I not uh had those those
in my life feel blessed for that
everyone else was abusing alcohol when
they were younger in my age and uh oh a
dab fell out
Kobe right into the bowl looks sweet
dude very buttery that like some rosin
that you pressed some hash out of or
what yeah
you talking to me that's whole plant
fresh Frozen
um some papaya whole plant fresh frozen
Rosen papaya that Papaya's nice I was in
Jamaica and my friend was telling me
about the emerald cup and he was like oh
straight Organics won the solvent list
with his papaya or whatever it was so
beautiful and I'm like oh man like don't
be telling me about hash that I can't
have and then he's like what do you mean
I have it right here this is the winning
one from straight Organics cracks it
gives me a big dab I was just like dude
that is the most amazing flavor that
whatever papaya cut he has tastes so
good papaya is so good it's like one of
my favorite
fruity
perfumey gassy honey so good man I don't
know it's just Top Rank and it's in a
different category it is honey seeds
makes that so you can I think you can
find your keeper out of the out of his
varieties that you know I think he's a
good breeder and really good Tropicana
cook uses another good one from
him um
beautiful real papayas in
Hawaii yeah we grow many varieties of
papayas we got do a lot trouble with you
have much trouble with fruit flies when
we were growing them in Kawaii we had to
uh keep them inside of screen green
houses uh because papaya the the fruit
flies hit every single papaya if they
weren't
protected no no no not the papayas and
the fruit flies aren't an issue it's
this ring spot virus that's out here
that's floating around on the island
it's uh some kind of I don't know I bet
it's man-made you know what I mean but
uh
what spreads r do you know the insect
Vector I don't know the vector myself no
but that's the reason why they created
the GMO papaya which is like the main
one they grow on the east side of% 90%
of what they grow in Hawaii is GMO
papayas corre right right that's true
and that's due to the Rings spot virus
um you know so yeah you got to really
question what's going on with your
farming practices if you're dealing with
some kind of you know islandwide virus
uh you know what what happened there
what what we do
virus so they yeah so they say yeah yeah
that's what they call it anyway DN
Mexican fruit flies made it really
hard until finally we just grew the
papayas inside of a netted shade crop uh
and that that stopped M cold that's
interesting because we don't have that
issue at all with with the with anything
tropical but if we try to grow like a
European vegetable like something like a
squash or a melon or uh anything that's
like some kind of more like a northern
European type thing then you
gota yeah this was in the North Shore of
kawaii okay okay interesting maybe it
just at a lower elevation or at a
certain a certain uh humid area or
something like that but even been the
time you know when
yeah but yeah the the papayas are so uh
resilient you know they're a tropical
fruit so anything tropical the bananas
the papayas the teros the sugar cane you
know the sweet
potato anything tropical like you don't
spray it you don't you don't put
anything on it you know you just kind of
like maybe just help build the soil and
mulch things and plant them you know
what I mean anything that's that's
conducive to the environment just grows
and that's when we talked about food
sovereignty and the last dragonfly Earth
medicine talk it was all about just you
know using food and things that grow
properly in your environment so a lot of
that netting and stuff like that
definitely comes with the European
vegetables that are susceptible to that
fruit fly that fruit fly will sting the
fruit and they'll put their larae in
there and then the thing is done you
know Papas did really good in Hawaii
until the Mexican
interesting I wonder if that was even
maybe just like a scor or something a
certain time of time of uh of in history
that maybe we had like a scorge of them
as far as I know they're still there
interesting yeah no problems with fruit
flies on the
papayas they grow great we do a we do
different varieties red thae papaya we
got this Filipino pink papaya um
strawberry papayas uh solo papaya
you know we got a good variety
of have you grown the ones from Thailand
that are
orange yeah that yeah well we got one
called the red tie and it's got a really
really orange kind of pinkish flesh in
there you know and and that's that's one
of our better ones for sure a ripe or
even green and a papaya salad you know
wo any pineapples down there well that's
what actually my my main fruit is uh or
actually my main thing I bring to Market
would be my white pineapples and we do
anywhere from 2 to 5,000 pounds a year
we're looking probably this year we'll
probably get more like three two to
three th000 pounds but um yeah the white
pineapple man it's this string called
Sugarloaf and the thing is so turpy and
tasty and sweet and um yeah we're kind
of known for that and you know we love
it it's like the crown fruit the king's
fruit and you grow any pineapple ganja
spral out there so I have one that I
call the white
pineapple in spirit of the white
pineapples on the farm and um and it's
one of my one of my really good hash
strains as well to tell you the truth
and it puts off this really um you know
floral uh
fruity turpy hat that uh that is really
sought after too is it pretty obvious
that you're using your white pineapple
fruit juice on your white pineapple
ganja
varieties I definitely do a few um a few
ferment and fpjsangprobinsyano
to nothing nowadays man doing the
natural farming for so long man you just
learned that that soil really can eat a
lot unless you're just really blowing it
you know what I mean the if you got a
nice living soil that's just really
respirating and really just vibing out
you can't really do too much wrong to it
unless you're buying a bunch of imported
weird things or something but you know
that's the dry side of the island we're
over here on the Kona side so luckily
we're on the dry side even though we've
gotten uh what is it now I think 30 days
of rain straight but we're coming onto
the Rain Street season so um the
Cannabis definitely is not loving that
at all at all so it's the tropics and
it's rainy so it's kind of like that
double do you almost have to grow you
almost have to grow the tropical land
racy varieties during the wet season
that's what I wanted to get into when
you guys were talking about I think
Colin was talking about um just the
different uh you know climates and how
they are affecting the turpins and the
waxiness of the hash that got me
thinking well you guys were talking was
what has anybody ever thought of this or
done these experiments where it would be
like you take an Afghan hash strain and
and you grow it in a in a I mean if you
had a controlled Greenhouse you dry you
know you make it a dry desert
environment and you try to mimic that
Afghan kind of high mountain desert
climate or if you had a tropical land
RAC strain you try to up the humidity
and try to kind of mimic the nature
because in natural farming what we're
doing like the main teaching is mimic
nature and bring nature into your system
so what if you actually went down to the
genetics of where your plant came from
on the planet and mimic that nature in
um a controlled environment I mean I
don't do that I'm I grow in green houses
outdoor and I love it but uh maybe you
grew an Afghan hash drain in a high
desert mountain climate
mimicked in your system what do you guys
think about that I think that goes back
to the the whole idea of terar and
Appalachia I think Sam has the most
experience in all of us in all this I'd
love to hear your uh your thoughts
Sam well the one thing I could say is
that widely varities from Afghanistan
Pakistan and the surrounding area uh
which were developed for
uh they they have no natural resistance
to uh petritis and mildew and and these
kinds of problems so it can be a real
problem to grow them in a wet humid
environment like in the North Shore of
Kawai or any place else where it's it's
it's really they just don't have
resistance whereas varieties from uh
Thailand or Colombia or those places
those are from hot moist tropical
environments and if they didn't have
resistance they wouldn't exist anymore
they'd be
gone right I guess my question is more
just for you guys that have a a way to
control your environment uh and just for
the the purpose of talking hash
production in general would it would you
be able to to uh to tease your climate
to better match the genetics you know
that's kind of where I'm going with I
think Colin understood what I was saying
yeah of you can do that of course but uh
there's a couple problems is number one
most WID Leaf varieties indicas or what
people call them uh they
uh they don't really have the tpes they
got lots of THC I I can't criticize them
for that they got lots of resin but they
don't have the tping the way that ganja
smokers have uh conserved and preserved
and uh created varieties like Thailand
Colombia etc etc that are are really I
mean no matter how much THC you have
without the right
tpes it doesn't cut it you you
need the tpes
that's all I'm
saying yeah I I agree with Sam 100% um
and to to answer the question of of the
environmental stuff I for the hybrids
that I grow absolutely everything's kind
of catered to that for resin production
um when I'm growing a variety it's all
about how I'm catering to that variety
or group of varieties and I try to group
things together that are kind of related
to one another based on region and I do
look at where those varieties come from
from a progeny standpoint standpoint to
make sure that if I'm putting motor
breath 15 in there with sour d and chem
dog D they're all going to play nice
with my feeding and I don't have to do
too much work so I try to keep keep
things um you know I try to think like
that in terms of what my end goal is
because it's all about hash for what I'm
I'm
producing right I I understand exactly I
can give you a good example I had a
greenhouse where I was doing triing of
imported seeds from Afghanistan year
after year after year and so one year I
had a couple thousand of them growing in
there but I had also grown a few uh
original Haze plants in the middle of
the of the greenhouse in between the
roads of Afghan plants 90% of the Afghan
plants got
uh uh mdeo uh I mean it was this one
year it was really really bad both the
environmental conditions and the seed
variety itself but I
had uh Haze growing in the middle of
these I had a darkening system so they
were flowering along with the Afghans
the Afghans were more flowered along
but the haze didn't have one spot of
mildew on it none of them
whereas the some of the
Afghan were quite literally dripping mil
do white crap off their [ __ ] leaves I
mean it's you you can't fight mother
nature and if if you want to use Afghan
varieties then you better breed it in
such a way that none of those
nonresistant varieties uh genes uh for
petritis and Milo are are in them
because uh it's it's it's you're just
fighting Mother Nature what you should
do instead is grow things like Haze or
or other tropical narrow Leaf varieties
which uh have no trouble growing mildew
and petritis spre in uh even if your
Greenhouse is a bit hot or
humid I agree
uh I have a question for you what what
varieties are you growing up there that
are uh dealing with all all that we have
to deal with on the on the East Coast um
you know when hurricane season starts to
kick up and the storms start to
come well I'm I'm kind of following what
uh Sam is saying for a while now with uh
selecting the right cultivars that do
well according to the climate here but
when I was even in Northern California I
didn't have the greatest exposure so I
had to deal with mold and betrus and
mildew and I've had some genetics carry
over like I mentioned last time some
strawberry fields which is a strawberry
banana Tang from Crockett uh that I
crossed to my angel food cake which is
kind of a deep poly strain uh very poly
hybrid strain I made and then I've
carried over to here with that one
that's done very well I've made
variations from strawberry angel food
now into strawberry Angela which is a
strawberry angel food by tester Roa so
I'm having great results outside with
that that cross into the testarosa um
it's a skittles magnumopus
Skittles so what I'm seeing and even uh
sensing in the tpine profile on the
strawberry angel food particular cross
um to testos I call Strawberry Angela
that feno is a is a reminder of the
grapy royal Kush kind of magnumopus
thing but I'm just getting great health
results with that type um 24 Karat I
have one outside right now that's a
beast and super healthy I actually find
that sat the sativa equatorial sativa
input just is what we kind of need here
even in main so it's interesting but it
has to be absolutely the right phenotype
that's been selected and that just
basically takes letting it run like even
out here I'm year three of selecting and
I've got about oh
three chosen types that I go back to
after three years a sour banana sherbet
you know that's just amazing comes off
early into late uh September on its own
full sun and yeah otherwise I'm light
deps we just flipped a week ago on the
first session and I'm Greenhouse grow
but I I do both and it's about the
cultivar about finding that one and I
agree and that will Shine for You indoor
Greenhouse outside even from into
different regions I
believe got to put in the
work eador on the East Coast has really
been successful for me over the years in
the last you
know however long it's it's something
that I recommend anyone on the east
coast to take a look at that's growing
outside I definitely share Brian's
sentiment would you guys all agree that
sometimes your best genetic that grows
for flower production and health and is
that most vibrant kind of like you were
just saying how how you get you find
that one that shines and everything but
for some reason Huck come that one's not
really the hash
producer you guys find that yeah I
agree yeah my strawberry angel food
drips my strawberry angel food drips TPS
I got the juiciest flower Ros and I've
been hitting low time flower Ross and
getting this just buttery cream and it
it really drips even into the cross out
with the tester Roa is still I'm getting
at the same temperature white chalk
flower rosin that dumps pretty good but
it's just not that turpine influence and
then I don't get the best bubble hash
off it either like the pineapple
fields yeah come out as much yeah yeah I
find that
too strawberry really great varieties
that gave lousy yield of dry sift
because I'm always after dryp I know the
The Cutting Edge is rosin but I'm old
school dude your dry sift is Untouchable
bro forget about old school new school
whatever school that [ __ ] is the Holy
Grail enough
said you know one thing that um to kind
of circle back to what Logan was talking
about um and some of you guys might do
this as well but we don't um we don't
try to create a a uh I guess what you
were asking about specifically is any of
us uh try to create an environment for
specific uh you know uh cultivars from
that that that kind of mimics their
natural environment where they're where
they're naed to we don't do that but one
thing that we do
is you know we we have a pretty good
climate for it stays like in the 80s
most of the summer might might spike in
the low 90s but then inevitably we'll
get one or two spikes here usually June
July August um for you know anywhere
from three days to five days where we
get a heat spell of 100 degree plus days
and um the ganja doesn't like that you
know it grows a lot during I think you
know during like the three hours of
super hot weather you know maybe from
like 1 to 6:00 p.m. it's kind of just
like hanging in there but the rest the
other 20 hours of the day it's Trucking
along and and and growing a lot but what
we do we we don't have like high-tech
like bells and whistles climate control
green houses but we do have um you know
rollup sides and a lot of ventilation
and we've been bringing augs uh big fans
and shade cloth everything to
for those heat spells like anything
that's like you know three weeks or less
from from
finishing um we definitely see that the
um you know they'll kind of do like that
starfishing and and the Le the leaves
will taco and the resin count is not as
good with that super heat so the shade
cloth really you know we try to have a
lot enough sha cloth on hand so so that
um that we can have you know sort of
beat the heat with all those houses and
cool it down a good 15 20 degrees in the
house from outside but one Technique we
we do here that that works really good
because we have almost three and a half
acres in hoop houses between our ganja
and our vegetable crops and since you
only need that shade cloth for maybe
once or twice a year it's a pretty big
investment in more more materials and
stuff uh one thing we like doing here we
call it the poor man shade cloth where
you get a heat spell and you know either
your Tomatoes or your ganas like in that
in that crunch time where it's G to be
suffering a bit um we just take buckets
of mud and toss it over the green houses
and uh that works that works great it
cools it down just the same as shade
cloth and then you know some sometimes
we'll be lazy about it and let the rain
wash it off otherwise we'll uh we'll
just you know get up on a tractor and
wash it off after the heat spell goes
through but you know between the
sidewalls and the end walls and fans and
shade cloth um just just with a elbow
grease you know that's kind of like our
our our low Tech climate control that
really that really
helps what I used in the Netherlands was
uh an organic uh white Co chalk like
material that you sprayed on the outside
of the glass house because I I had a
greenhouse that was about 20 feet tall
and it uh uh was about an acre under
glass and uh every May
or early may I would spray it and uh it
was the kind that after a couple of
really good hard rains it would start to
wash off and so by the uh end of the
year it was uh pretty much gone and I'd
spray it every year and uh that would
knock the temperature internal
temperature down at least 10 degrees and
uh I I never saw any negative effects in
yield quality in fact uh I find Cannabis
like all of you agree uh if it's grown
too
hot veg maybe it can take it but
flowering it is not good for flowering
cannabis excess heat Sam I have a
question then how the
hell did that bubble that was made in
Jamaica back in the day when we were
there together that was just beautiful
big clear domes remember the doctor he
grew oh I remember dude how because I
was always thinking about that I'm like
it was so insanely hot up on the top of
that little mountain where he was
growing that [ __ ] and it was like like
the sun it was just always like melting
the resin glands off of it I just
thought I was like I don't know how you
could have like how the hell does he
have that many do everybody else hear
him I what's
that oh no I you broke up and the
connection went bad for a minute sorry
about that I just wondered how you could
grow such great Herb in Jamaica in the
in the insanely intense heat like
nonstop from morning noon till night and
and produce well what what you're not
comparing it to Marcus is what would the
same canvas have been grown if it was uh
10 degrees cooler like why I grew in why
I grew in Santa Cruz we always had ocean
fogs in the morning and stuff it it was
so much cooler than Central California
over the hills and and I tell you the
Cannabis liked it well here's what I'm
thinking though at that point in time I
don't think I'd ever seen you smoke
anything from anyone ever you just only
smoked your own but you smoked that and
I thought wow this has to be really good
hash for him to be like I'm going to
smoke
that it was great I was I was running
out of the house I had with
me it was still pretty big that ball was
still pretty big it was abolutely
excellent and we would probably had some
if not the best some of the best smoke
in Jamaica on the whole [ __ ] Island
oh I would go without a shadow of a
doubt and say that was accurate man
because still to this day when I go back
there and I make full melt bubble from
Jamaican cultivars and then I go around
mostly to the Steamers you know I love
the Chalice
Steamers I've got a couple of friends
that own steamer companies Caleb uh is
on one side of the island and then Kevin
has steam team Jamaica and uh those
things with the coals burning in the
kochie and you know the first time I
tried to put something on top they were
kind of like whoa no man we just steam
I'm like no no you're going to steam
this but it's going to steam a little
differently and just dropping big de ABS
on the coals while hitting like a really
exotic sativa underneath while at a
reggae show like in Jamaica I'm just
like this is this is it for me like this
is the Pinnacle of my life's experience
this is just good if you haven't done it
I implore you all to do it in fact we
should all do it together let's go to
Jamaica enjoy some good reggae and good
food and great people and amazing
culture and the best place to listen to
music in Jamaica of course is a yard
concert I mean that's it for real in
fact the best yard in my opinion I was
brought there by ksai and it was Earl
Chen Smith's yard he is the most musical
dude on the planet and the people who
gravitate to to uh Chen's place is uh
really like seriously an
unbelievable experience you just see man
bubble bubble man you get you get the
treatment over there I'm going with you
next time bu yeah dude you go we'll go
we'll go to the yard I guess so man I'm
going to chinis yard what are you
talking about or the in of the yard in
of the yard is another really good one
there's a couple of amazing yards in
Kingston that are uh that are just uh
Next Level and doesn't matter where you
are if you're with kis eye like he is
just the most incredible awesome
individual hilarious I could listen to
him tell stories all day long if you
haven't heard of him Google him and
learned some of his music go on Bubble
man's world you can there's Jamaican
episodes where he plays a you know
graduation from Zion check out the tune
graduation from Zion kid asai legendary
tune legendary artist big up kid as I
yeah for real I've got I was dabbing at
a a stepping High Festival put on by
carlen and and uh and uh oh what is it
DJ oh I don't want to get his name wrong
anyway great people they put on stepping
High Festival in in Negril it's been
going on for like 14 or 15 years and one
year I showed up and had a booth and uh
I I got the judg it and I was with ktis
the whole time and I was sort of filming
as well and at one point he was at the
booth and he's like he's just look he's
just always looked so cool and he just
kind of leans over and takes a dab out
of the Fab Ed you know he's just like 78
years old or something he's just
like hits this huge dab has a huge joint
in his finger while he's hitting the dab
and then someone's like ktis you're next
you're next and he's like okay and I
film I'm filming him take a dab then
this guy says You're Next and so he's
like he's like I gotta go perform and he
sort of w starts to walk away and he
walks through the crowd and it's very
dark and there's lights in the
background from the stage and he's just
walking through the smoke passes the
police everyone's like kis kis yelling
to him it's straight out of a movie you
should try and find it I think it's
called ganja baby because then I follow
him he walks super slow all the way to
the end backstage up the stairs the band
quits playing he grabs the mic and
starts performing and like niab bingi
drummers are in the front with a bunch
of cannabis plants right all in the
front of the stage it was so good I just
uh it was one of my all-time most
favorite moments in Jamaica was the F my
favorite thing I've ever filmed on my
channel and it's got like two or three
thousand hits like it's
absolutely go hit that [ __ ] up and find
it because it's worth checking
out big up kid is you know something I
wanted to add into about the uh you were
talking about the uh the bubble hash and
that heat you know or that that plant
growing in the heat up there I've grown
you know a lot of years I went and grew
in different climates in NorCal but I've
growing here my whole life in Hawaii as
well and there's just something there's
something going on with with the the
equatorial region that you're growing in
and what I mean by that is you know
obviously the tropics and the dry desert
and all that or the northern climates or
whatever but there's something about the
that Tropic
equatorial um it's something about the
way the sun shines the Angles and the
degrees that you're getting and you're
getting this you know it's you know the
diff obviously like uh like hemp guy was
talking about the the different you know
turpine profiles of the tropics you're
getting way more this fruity floral
thing going on and then you know in
those drier regions but anyway you know
I've just noticed that growing in Hawaii
in particular every every cult ofar that
I've grown here and that I've grown in
California the ones in Hawaii express
way more Turpin way more of a of a you
know and not to say anything's better or
worse than anything it's just a
beautiful plant in general but something
about the tropics you know and that
might be the answer to your question I
think Bubble Man word look at what I
found this kid is taking that there it
is at my table while he's smoking a
joint he's smoking a joint he's like
okay yeah let me take my joint out of my
mouth I'll smoke the mothership real
quick
here there's no sound but you can go
check it out it's ganja baby kesai and
the inard drummers and yeah it's got
like 2,000 views man I can't believe
this video should have so many more oh
he's hitting the Taurus too not the egg
my bad this was years ago 2015 five
years
ago ktis
Champion strongest man most amazing
individual definitely a key person to
bump into if you go to uh
Jamaica and and everyone everyone knows
him
there's no doubt about that I have it
muted not for really any reason I guess
I
could I'm walking backstage with ktis
with me are you going backstage yeah I
haven't that
ton Ton's at that table still can you go
get him and bring him
backstage so you're going back
Tony's Right Where I Was we'll fast
forward to a few seconds of the
performance because it's just so
ridiculously
[Music]
good gja baby
ch
[Music]
all right I'm not going to play the
whole thing but I wanted you guys to
check it out and I got I got sucked into
it there but it's awesome and I needed
to share it because that's the world
today you can see some talk about
something and then be like well I can
share a few minutes of that right now
Jamaica is my all-time favorite place in
the whole world to travel and hopefully
when this whole covid-19 thing is up
we'll be able to head out there again
spend some time on the
Rock hey Josh hey Josh do healthy plants
get
viruses you know it's really really hard
for a healthy plant to get
viruses that's one thing I will say
that's the truth right definitely
definitely I think we should all take a
lesson from the uh plant kingdom that's
I just wanted to add that quick I think
that was one of the best things to add
right at the end here we've been going
for three hours uh I think 9 10 11 12
yeah three hours so I wanted to thank uh
you know the folks that have never been
here before Dave uh Sullivan and Logan
and Paul hail um always good to see best
friend farms and Colin from vessel and
dragonfly Earth medison to help set all
this up because they invited uh some of
the newer folks um yeah I I appreciate
everyone showing up I'll put it up on
the podcast and send the link out to
everyone and uh yeah hopefully we can do
this again sooner than later I like the
idea of the dialogue you guys are all
really know your [ __ ] and seem to uh
always impress and inspire me so thank
you for that uh and thank you for doing
the very things that you're talking
about not talking about the things that
you want to be doing it's uh makes a big
difference thanks a lot everybody thank
you church thank you so much Sam I could
never forget you you're my
favorite peace thank you guys respect
respect
love thanks
everybody be a part of it you thank
thanks Josh for inviting me and Marcus
for putting all together big healing
Dave big healing love to Chelsea love to
the family love to Leandra Paul everyone
everyone's other halves and everything
BL love to the family sh the whole
world worldwide love worldwide love and
healing blessing that's the