all right all right let's uh get this
show on the road I just got to do a
little copy and some quick over there
then I'm going to let some folks in like
eten who's been waiting in the room for
a few
minutes
and here we
go good day
friend good day sir and a happy
wonderful New Year to you too sir well
and and to you as well I'm not sure why
my
um airpods aren't working but I'm going
to go in and try and fix that right now
it's nice to see you brother it's been
far too
long uh when was our last hash Church by
the way just out of curiosity you know
I'm not even sure probably the last well
maybe not the last one I think you had a
you weren't able to make it or
something yeah I think I did miss that
last one yep you're right
well I'm trying desperately to get my
headphones to work they are not working
let's hope that I don't have too much of
a problem today with uh feedback and
whatnot none here but you know no issues
so far so
smoothly I think I got to do it
inside here actually real quick and then
I'll go on and uh we can fix this oh
here we go
audio yes speaker Marcus's airpod Pro
say something at
say something
ATN you're in my ears a here
candy hey let's let Mark in Mark is the
breeder who created that hash Church
cultivar oh nice yeah so we're gonna let
him in we're gonna let Wade in happy
hashy New Year
everybody yes yes Hashi of New
Years I love it let's see if these guys
come in without a problem with their
audio or their technical
I see Mark I I see Wade I see them both
as well is your phone is your audio
working
gentlemen hey guys how's it going hey
Mark's working Happy New Year's fellas
happy New Year's to you brother and
welcome to Hash church I got to
introduce you real I gotta introduce you
real quick so Mark is a guy that hit me
up
and he said I got this
cultivar and I want I want to name it
hash church and I was kind of like I
want to name it hash Church like whoa
whoa whoa whoa whoa let's uh let's talk
about this we can't just be naming
anything hash church this is like a long
running show and I started talking to
Mark and very humble guy very kind guy
quite obviously a very Canadian guy
actually and uh he's yeah he starts
hitting me up he sends me he sends me a
little flower first he's like I want you
to see this flower I can say that
because it's totally legal in Canada to
send someone some cannabis flowers isn't
that amazing that [ __ ] wasn't happening
in 2019 but here in
2021 Mark could send me some flow so he
sends me this okay he sends me this
flower so look at this
flower little Frosty little nud nug just
covered bro like covered to the point of
like even right away when I posted it
people like oh is that hooked tricomes
are they real tricomes cuz it just looks
so ridiculous ulous like it's so furry
and and frosty so Mark was like look
I'll he sent me a cut I I completely
[ __ ] the bed on the cut and was was
unable to take care of it but I was able
to share it with a friend so we still
have it growing and we're still going to
see it Bloom Mark didn't want to wait he
was like I'll send you some flour run
some bubble which I did I got the bubble
and pizza boxes over there it's very
lovely melty bubble blonde tasty
flavorful bubble reminds me of some old
school Dutch Treat that used to grow
back in the day that was also very very
coded in resin so we're we've invited
Mark in we're going to end up talking
about that this hash Church cultivar uh
throughout the day here and uh I wanted
to make him a part of the show um just
sort of kind of you know share my thanks
with him and also kind of apologize
because I've been so busy and here we
are during a global pandemic you know
things are going rough with for Mark and
his family like it's not just smooth
sailing they're they're really trying to
hold it together and rock and roll and
make things work out and now they're
sitting on this cultivar and the minute
I posted it I'm certain the guy could
have probably sold 50,000 seeds people
just hitting him up left right and
center and he's like look I'm not going
to sell any of this I just want to make
sure you're good with it that it's the
hash church cultivar that it's real I'm
not trying to build fake hype and all
this sort of stuff so that's kind of the
story behind Mark just seemed uh like a
good dude with a nice cultivar and uh I
thought yeah it's a beautiful cultivar I
you know me allowing him to name it hash
church is nothing more than me saying
sure you can name it hash Church we're
not partnering up I'm not going into the
seed business to make money off
cultivars that's none of what I'm
interested in but I love the idea of
helping good folks and the bubble did
come out very very nicely I also pressed
a little bit of Ros and it had a really
nice kind of unique almost an old school
high if that makes any sense and uh
welcome to Hash Church
Mark how's that for a a buildup thanks
brother I appreciate it yeah it was uh
it's been a long little journey with
this little plant for
sure very
interesting yeah mysterious uh some
mysterious things have come up with it
uh throughout its little journey too
which
is yeah it's very cool thanks brother
yeah absolutely welcome and welcome to
you Mr House of harleyquinn Wade it's
been a while since I saw your smiley
beautiful face as well so we want to
welcome you to the room and thank you
welcome your welcome your energy yes yes
it's good to see you andan and always
fun to hear about new Cult of ours um
yeah having a good year already uh and
really looking forward to hearing how
everyone else is doing and what you're
doing and uh yeah like that I got some
news at some point to
share beautiful I love it I love the
sounds of kind of everyone doing that
sharing some news talking about the old
year talking about the new year I did
come to the conclusion the other day
that
2021 can be spelled out
2020 one w n but we won't have that
because 2021 is is is a new year and
we're gonna we're going to bust it out
and uh we've got the be
oh oh snap
we're in 2020 for a couple more years is
that what you're
saying it's almost like a sequel going
on 2021 22 23 who knows no I feel like
things are going to get
better and hello
fan hello Wade much love and respect
good to see you're well and doing what
you do so
well having a good time having a good
time that's what we're looking for Happy
Times well we shout shout out to uh
Chimera he just sent me an email saying
he's not going to be able to make it
today as he has no heat and he's trying
to sort that out so welcome to Canada
welcome to uh I'm not even sure where
Chimera is these days to be honest but
he's usually kind of in a wooded area so
it makes sense yesterday was wicked
wicked windy and uh I'm surprised I have
power right now actually it's kind of a
blessing that we're able to do this
first of the hash Church we're going to
talk about that Mr Bingle Lombardi we're
going to get into it in a little bit
don't worry about that I'm just going to
let Allison in I invited a ton of
awesome people into hash church today
friends and and fam that I haven't seen
in a long time that we haven't been able
to kind of connect some of you I connect
with the odd time on Zoom chats like Mr
Colin Palmer welcome Colin I see him
every once in a while but I don't get to
see all of you and I will apologize to
the entire hash Church community because
I do feel like I've dropped the ball a
little bit I guess we got to the point
where hash Church felt secure enough of
a show that even if I didn't do it for
months and months all I had to do is
text you guys we get back together and
we have a show and and that's kind of
how it started to play out but I have a
lot of people we have to understand that
there's a group of people hundreds of
them that look forward to gathering on
Sundays while we Yammer on about
whatever it is we Yammer on and they're
in the chat room right now um there is
about three 260 people in the chat room
right now
and these are the guys and gals that
look forward to uh whatever it is we're
discussing and I saw one of them today
say man I wish we uh I wish we could do
more hash churches you know I miss I
miss gathering with all of you guys and
I sometimes forget that we're the keyh
holders in that Gathering you know if we
make the point on showing up everyone
gets to gather everyone gets to uh enjoy
themselves so I do thank all of you for
taking some time out on a Sunday
morning I appreciate it I really do and
Johnny Be is in the house too I think I
saw him sneak in we got Johnny B in the
house over there yeah there he is he's
got his whole headset on looks like he's
about to take off on a plane I was
trying with the headset but not work so
I'll plug in the Yeti microphone all
right check right now oh that's much
better dude right there is that's that's
that's it sure I came in clear for 2021
because I'm clearheaded and we're ready
to start growing I'm so excited for this
year of being the grow year of
2021 everybody's just got to start
popping seeds popping those genetics and
let's get the grow on that's what I'm
grow grow your plants like Johnny Be is
growing his hair that's what's up said I
wasn't GNA cut the hair I said you know
what I had my haircut last year in
January when I went for the lift
conference and then after that then all
of this pandemic stuff came up and I'm
like I'm not going to cut my hair well
guess
what I'm gonna start going to the mosh
pits with all your broken bones and
broken spine you're gonna go to the mosh
pits I wouldn't even be you got the
motion you got to move the whole body
now I would not even be surprised if I
was in a Slayer mosh pit and I looked
over and saw you oh he seen me there
slip not all there I'll be right in
there but uh you know you know I've been
kind of striving I couldn't find a
screen for my Hash Pipe all morning so I
pulled off some nice Congo dabs just to
kind of bring in the 2020 one and I
think we should be doing a a nice big
dab let's do well I I like it let's show
everyone let's show the cameras what we
got everybody I'm going to go to gallery
view so everyone can see what we're
holding up I've got a little strawberry
banana from concentrated X looking oh so
greasy nice I got some
9110 and this here guys is the LA Kush
cake and this is some fire bubble this
is some of the best that I've
managed to get my hands on I'm really
happy with this beautiful I see Wade
held up some nice big chunks of hash and
Colin had some jars of goodness
there yeah got some lemon cake some
Square wav job is Stash from Bodie big
shout out to
Bodie really enjoy his
work and I've still got my amalgam that
goes back to
2012 Everlasting Gob stopper that I keep
adding to so still
going I should bring a plant in today
you know show it off in House
Church what's that Johnny this is medy
Kush and um what's the nose on medy
how's that how is the the turpine
profile on that what's the the turpy
profile yeah what does it smell like
gas gassy um I've been on you know I've
it's one of those strains um it it's gas
it's it's it's an original cush I used
should call it like a pure cush it's
it's it's it's like Carmel would say
it's like a pre 93 Bubba like uh he
really liked it too
nice how old is she pardon me how old is
she um I've been running the same strain
since 2005 15 years from
seed way to be
yeah it it's definitely one of long
haulers myself that I've kept how many
weeks is she in flower currently this is
day
56 and by scoping it last night I got
Amber triones all milky no clear at all
so it's pretty much it's at that stage
that it's going to get washed probably
today or
tomorrow beautiful hey I want to welcome
Allison into the room look at that
welcome Allison thanks it's been a long
time it's been forever how the heck have
you been um I have been amazing um I
have metamorphis from doing the Edibles
to actually accepting my doctorate um I
actually had a doctorate the whole time
I was in cannabis and I just never used
it and um Dr seil Agarwal um approached
me um when there was a when there was a
flux a change between medical and
recreational and um he started a
cannabis and psychedelic uh Integrative
Medicine practice up here in Seattle so
now that's what I'm doing I'm practicing
Psychotherapy with cannabis and
psychedelics and it's um really amazing
it's uh probably some of the best work
I've ever done well that's what's up and
it doesn't even surprise me in the least
because the mushroom has been boring its
little way back into my life like so
crazy I can't even like tell you all how
hardcore the mushroom and now just to
give everyone a little idea you know
I've had a relationship with the
mushroom for a very long time since the
late 80s early 90s when my roommate
Jason ordered spores from siy company
that was owned by cat and Terrence
McKenna we ordered the SZ siy strain
which is the parental stock of the penis
envy mushroom nowadays siy is of course
the mushroom that Dennis McKenna and
Terrence McKenna collected in the Amazon
during the 70s prior to writing their
book uh the mushroom Growers guide which
was one of the first times uh people
were able to gather information on
cultivating mushrooms indoors they took
it a step further I guess there was a
priest down in the Amazon who had
cleared some trees to raise some cattle
the cattle started [ __ ] the [ __ ]
started spawning the mushrooms started
speaking and the McKenna started
listening and that sort of brought the
mushroom to Hawaii which we shipped it
in a Spore print over to Winnipeg
Manitoba an absolute incubator of
alcoholism where we thought let's see if
we can get less people to drink alcohol
and trip out on these wonderful
mushrooms that were growing in my closet
at the time in Grain prior to the PF
Tech so we didn't have the old distilled
spores in water that we could just
inject we actually were forced to use
transfer Chambers where you had to you
know take the old gloves and build them
into a box and do everything inside that
which was a little bit you know A Step
Above uh growing cannabis which we
thought was pretty amazing at the time
but all of a sudden and ulating mycelium
into agar transferring agar into grain
casing grain and growing and fruiting
mushrooms this was a whole other
incredible experience and I cannot tell
you how blessed I am to have had that
experience to have had the mushroom in
my life I'll never forget stumping Paul
stamitz at the Psychedelic gathering in
Whistler one year where I got to meet
the entire psychedelic family from Ralph
mner to Jonathan a to Paul stamitz to
Finn McKenna was there at the time his
father uh Terren had just passed away um
but it was really quite an incredible
time and Paul stamus walked by my my
booth that I had and I was selling
bubble bags and I had a macro photograph
from yuk Dumas in Amsterdam and I said
to Paul I said can you identify this
mushroom and he stood there for three or
four minutes with this totally stumped
look on his face and uh I finally said
you know listen it's actually a
glandular Tricom just busting your balls
and uh it was pretty funny I do look
forward to seeing him again one day and
bringing that up because I guarantee you
he won't forget being stumped on a
mushroom identification photo that
indeed was not a mushroom so awesome to
hear that you're doing all of that Dr
Allison Dron I love it we're actually uh
Dennis McKenna and Paul stamitz are
currently um working with our Clinic
because uh we've had a hard time with d
Crim in Washington state of psychedelics
we're not as um fantastic as Oregon and
so we're trying to come at it from
another perspective with the right to
try
psilocybin and so we're
currently um we have submitted
documentation to the DEA to do
psilocybin for end of life um and so a
couple of my patients are part of the
study to be able to use it uh terminal
cancer patients so we are we work with
McKenna and stamas as well because
stamus is helping us procure the
psilocybin for our project well I'm
going to put up a cyanin mushroom cap
that I photographed with my macro camera
I've never photographed psilocybin
mushrooms with my macro photograph but
as we're talking about the mushroom I
should I feel and this is another sort
of trippy thing that the mushroom pulled
me forward I I discovered cyan Essence
mushrooms growing on a grow that I had
back 20 plus years ago we seen some
dreadlocked kid picking mushrooms like
it was going out of style in our front
yard and we're just trying to you know
grow cannabis illegally at the time not
not let anyone know and we see this kid
and I buy Paul's book and I start to
discover that this is one of the single
largest patches of sin Essence that I
have ever seen in my life this kid must
have gotten 8 to 10 pounds before we
finally caught him and said please stop
picking the mushrooms on our property
and heating us out we have an illegal
grow over there we didn't say that but
we were definitely feeling it and uh so
recently 20 plus years later 22 years
later I was uh pulled in by the mushroom
again this year I don't know if any of
you saw some of the mushroom photos I've
been posting but we found some massive
sciessent flushes here in Vancouver
really like I'm talking me and my friend
were rolling around on the ground uh
giggling like school girls we were so
giddy uh it was just the most exciting
amazing thing to see the mushroom come
back full circle into my life I've been
uh doing macro do uh micro doses uh to
the macro does I did for so many years
when we first started growing terrance's
mushrooms we were pretty much of the
belief system that if we didn't eat five
grams in a dark room that there was no
purpose or point in in eating these
mushrooms so we're I see Wade tilting
his head back and laughing like oh young
people like my God because we were like
teenagers in in our just young 20s and I
really laughing at having done that
myself absolutely and it was the most
amazing thing and I you know so many
people that have asked me over the years
have you go to university like where did
you go to university and I I really take
a quote once again out of Paul stam's
book when I saw him speak in Vancouver
and I believe it was
1995 the first year that I actually met
do uh uh Dave uh skunkman Sam he was at
this event as well it was kind of like a
hemp and psychedelic event and Jonathan
art was thanking the people at Harvard
and you know everyone was H thanking
Yale University and all of these like
you know super brilliant men that went
to these incredible institutions and
then and then Paul stamitz gets up and
he's kind of got a disheveled shirt on
he says oh wow you know I I learned
everything I learned from the mushroom
and standing ovation like right away
already's like just Tak all the
universities and push them off to the
side and he's like I just want to give
props where props are due not that
Harvard and Yale and all those amazing
people aren't great but the mushroom
taught me everything and I would uh I
would really say the same thing so it's
really wonderful to see of course
cannabis is an accelerator of course
cannabis once it breaks through and gets
to you know breaks through uh into
legalization into breaking out of
prohibition can uh psychedelic uh plants
are going to be a close followup it
makes sense as you open your mind to
stopping believing in the propaganda
that has been so strong over the last
several you know hundred plus years and
I if for people that want to get into
this there's an incredible book out
there called The Immortal key and it
really shows the history of when
psychedelics took a left turn and
Christianity took a right turn and you
ended up with this really divisive split
between the Greek way of thinking that
scientific sort of proof versus the
paleo-christian way of thinking which is
really that faithful way they took the
the Rapture out of the experience they
removed all of the Psychedelic
sacraments they replaced it with the
blood of Christ of course which we all
know how well that did for indigenous
people around the world and uh here we
are today so that's kind of my rant I
want to welcome the Turners because they
just showed up and somehow Colton became
a man since last time he was here I
don't know what's going on but Colton's
a man now and here we are in
2021 welcome
Turners hey what's up guys how's
everybody hey you got something on your
lip right up here and on his chin look
at his chin look at this oh [ __ ] taggy
going on our little boy is growing up I
love it
I love it yeah he's going to actually be
21 this year holy
smokes yeah okay that threw me for a
congratulations team Turner getting to
21 I know I was so excited when I first
got diagnosed they didn't think I'd live
to be 15 here I am going on 21 yep
exactly so if that doesn't show you that
cannabis works yeah that illegally alive
thing really worked out for you yeah
yeah unfortunately he still has to be
illegally alive like many others in in
the United States which kind of sucks
but um I'm so glad to see your little
Spore behind you we're really excited
about uh mushrooms and psilocybon and
and all the crazy stuff that's going on
with that and the decrim that happened
in in h Oregon and California and or did
it happen in
California well some some of the states
down here so we're really excited for
that we're we're hoping that um will be
able to try mushrooms for his headaches
one one of these days awesome it's
coming there's no doubt about it there's
no stopping it Pandora's box once you
open her up she's super hard to close
back up that's what the story says
anyway so it's it's exciting to see I
hope so yeah absolutely well and you
know what the Psychedelic mushrooms are
really just the tip of the iceberg
because with what you know Paul's got
going on and a lot of people in the
community right now that have going on
dragonfly Earth medicine who I hope to
see here later on I've been taking their
capsules I take Paul's capsules Lion's M
but I also take the chaga and the turkey
tail and uh all Corps and a whole
variety of other mushrooms that
dragonfly Earth medicine put into their
capsules so I'm I'm always enjoying both
of those capsules and uh I just can't
say enough about all of these medicinal
mushrooms and the the new tropics and
how they offer you know this
regeneration to your brain and this
elasticity you grow older for memory and
it's just I can't say enough about it I
don't know the most about it so I won't
say too too much but there's some very
interesting
conversations uh to be had uh around
this fungus for sure and I thought you
know what getting the macro camera out
and starting to shoot it and see it in a
way that I've never seen it before also
just like cannabis really opened my mind
to learning more about the mushroom um
and yeah I just uh I can't say enough
about uh about the mushrooms I'm really
excited about the I'm I'm really excited
about the future of mushrooms um we we
don't know anything about it it just
we're kind of going into to mushrooms
like we did cannabis you know
completely just like new and fresh and
it's a mushroom that's all we know um we
know that people call it psilocybin and
now we know that there's a little
nickname called silly and and that's all
we know about it but the the some of the
things that I've seen and heard is is
it's our it's the same path that we were
taking with cannabis so when they say
that cannabis is a gateway drug it
really is because it's opened our mind
and opened our opportunities to so many
different things and and mushrooms
hopefully can be one of these uh we're
hoping to be able to give them to Colton
because he has migraine headaches and
we've heard so many good stories about
it um our friend Dr Sue sisily is doing
a lot of research on on a psilocybon and
she really believes that if Colton could
access that then then he she thinks that
it would really break through his
migraine headaches and he wouldn't have
to take you know Summa triptan and nor
trolene and Gaba Penton and things like
that that they're wanting to prescribe
him for for migraine headaches um so you
know we're really excited for for that
legislation to come through and we're
hoping that eventually we'll be able to
get involved in that and and understand
a little bit more about psilocybin and
mushrooms and stuff like that so well I
can tell you that the mushroom the
mushroom is actually excited about the
Turners becoming proponents of the
mushroom because the mushroom has seen
what you've done for the cannabis plants
and I guarantee you it won't be too
different for the mushroom when you say
you jumped in like newbies I was going
to say you did like a triple backflip
off the high high diving board isn't
that usually how the Turners enter a
community we we physically can do that I
mean we are gymnasts so I do
own right that's awesome well I look
forward to sharing the journey with you
guys I love this whole psychedelic
Renaissance that we're in the middle of
that I can't help but think that
cannabis had an incredible you know
impact on the cracking of the core of
the social fabric that allowed this to
start taking place and to start rooting
and it's been a long long long journey
when you think of so many years back our
Gordon wson stepping into Maria samina's
little little little Hut to take the
psilocybin mushrooms for the first time
that really started it out if you guys
want to learn about psilocybin mushrooms
and how they kind of ended up into the
Western Society check out our Gordon
wson and he wrote a really great article
is anyone going to remember the name of
the article he wrote In Time or Life
Magazine on the mushroom the silly the
the the the simple mushroom or the
anyway there's if you if you Google it
you'll come up with it pretty quick
definitely a good spot to start and uh
that's where a lot of people kind of I'm
gonna pop in here there's a a really
great book that a primer that I
recommend for all of my clients who are
interested in exploring psychedelics to
change their mind um and it's Michael
pollins how to change your mind
um it's just a really great basic book
um and and I have to say like you know
what everything that you're talking
about Marcus like psychedelics are the
best tool in my toolbox and I've
actually been a psychologist for almost
30 years um it's the easiest Pathway to
explore your mind and to to let go of
the old ghosts whether how do you how do
you spell pollen how do you spell his
last name l l l a n a n it's a book it's
a great all all of his books are
great out of Oregon and you can get it
on Audible as well okay great is he he's
not at Berkeley
anymore um he's not teaching there
anymore I remember he was teaching for a
while he he might be the last I heard
from folks in my office was that he was
down in Oregon and it could just be he
was working with the Oregan Sil Theon
crew he's amazing he jumps in Full
Throttle to whatever he's doing and he
jumped into psychedelics and took some
pretty heavy trips as an older gentleman
and to me my hats off and I gave him
respect for jumping in and doing it the
right way and of course he's an
absolutely impeccable writer that's what
he specializes in writing and if you
haven't read the omnivores dilemma or um
the the botony of Desire these are all
spectacular books that uh that he has
written R Gordon Watson's article was
called seeking the magic mushroom it was
published in May of 1957 in Life
magazine and you guys can check that out
as well and she's right that is
absolutely the place to start is how to
change your mind I listened to it a
couple months back on Audible it was
awesome I mean I mean getting through
this whole pandemic craziness um almost
every one of my clients is currently
micro doing in some fashion um with a
macro do thrown in there for good
measure um because it's um it's we have
no control over craziness that's going
on in our world so it's um it's a
perfect time to really in investigate
your psyche and uh come to some form of
Happiness from within well you you just
called it because listen life isn't
about figuring out how to stop suffering
life is suffering you're going to suffer
throughout the whole thing it's how you
react to your suffering this is the
great trick this is what thick nanot
says in his wonderful book The Art of
Living
if you haven't listened to that book or
read that book this is another amazing
book that will bring you solace in
Western Society we tend to have
foundational belief systems that set us
up for anguish and pain okay this we
become attached we become attached to
our little dog when our little dog dies
we're shattered we we become attached to
our parents when our parents die we're
shattered well these are there's
different ways of having your belief
systems switch so that you once you
don't believe that death is final that
belief system well it opens up a whole
other you know opportunity to to to
remove some of that suffering that or at
least some of that reactionary suffering
that you know how we react to our
suffering so that's the big trick in
life and I think I said it recently when
someone asked me what do you think about
this mushroom thing is it just going to
be a big corporate takeover and blah
blah blah blah blah and I said you know
yes and no I mean what I really think
about it is is that it's probably the
most important thing in regards to
psychology and Psych Psy Psychiatry
being able to remove ourselves from the
pharmaceutical drugs that people are
currently taking messing with brain
chemistries when you have access to
fungi and plants that do it but on a
very different level in a very more
personal sort of Soul seeking level um
you know already with people who are
terminally ill they're finding a single
dose of psilocybin uh done and taken the
right way with the right person can give
them instantaneous relief of death
because here's the thing when you
realize that death is actually just a
transition just like you're
transitioning your suffering into
happiness just like you transitioned
your fetus into birth uh there's no
death and once you have that revelation
of course you're going to be less
stressed out about death when you have a
complete and total understanding that
death is a complete and total illusion
and it's not really real it's just
another transformation so these are
things I think the world desperately
needs right now maybe a little bit more
than another four hours of CNN um
but we are but Michael's book also spoke
to the reconnecting that psychedelic
mushrooms do and especially in older
patients and people who are suffering
trauma it
reconnects nerves and Pathways neural
Pathways in the brain that I think is
exponential to human healing especially
during this most trouble time of covid
but especially is going to be needed for
these uh Healthcare work ERS Who as a
combat V I can see the thousand yard
stare in these poor workers my sister's
a nurse and others that are just dealing
with death day in and day out uh they're
going to need this therapy as well and
the older patients and those that
survive the damage that's done they're
going to need it for healing especially
mentally yeah it's good that you're
bringing that up Aon it's it's that's
something I was gonna going to chime in
on is you know they to me it's like
being in the pocket when you're playing
music with other other instrumentation
you know happening around you you're
you're in the pocket and that opens up
doorways and Pathways to go anywhere you
want and do things musically that you
could otherwise wouldn't be doing
because you're getting yourself and your
mind out of the way and you're allowing
yourself to exist and get in touch with
yourself and the pathways that allow you
to to be so in tune with the things that
you're doing and and things Colin you
you just described a part of this new
movie from Pixar called soul and I don't
know if any of you guys have seen this
movie but it's heavy really heavy
there's the guy he's a piano jazz player
and when he goes into the pocket in his
improvisation he disappears and he goes
to a place where the new souls are born
and they call it the pocket he's like
floating in a purple energy just like
improvising yeah in in musical terms
like tragus said me playing Black to my
face I'm constantly trying to get out of
my own way I it's just I'm I'm that's
that's what that's my dream is to just
just get myself out of my way so I'm
just channeling these this energy and
these things and it's all about
dexterity and just being in touch with
your your body and that's that's music
in in a sense it's it's it's and it's
also canabo and it's also psilocybin
it's it's it's all these things and and
how that all works um you know is g to
be individual for everyone you know but
it but the general ideology of a pocket
um we as musicians speaking in musical
terms we we always talk about this and
it's really really we all talking about
this with with these you know chemicals
because it's true it's so true you you
really can't get past yourself if you're
thinking about it you're you're never
gonna get it if that's H we using it as
the analogy well when you say I need to
get out of my own way what you're really
saying is I really need to get my ego
off the couch out of the steering wheel
out of the driver's seat and that ego
disillusion people enforce this that
they are their egos and that's where
you're also setting yourself up for some
massive massive pain and anguish because
you aren't it's just a it's just a
mental construct that you created
throughout your life based on your
experiences I I wouldn't say that it's
nothing because I truly believe the ego
is sort of
the controller it's the value of this
experience if we come from the
everything we come here we're split
we're divided we're we're we're we're
we're fractured we be get to become this
single eye and then we go back to the
source so this this experience really
probably some of the most valuable
experiences that we have on Earth is
that relationship with building our ego
and designing our ego and using our ego
to navigate this three-dimensional
reality that we're currently in
because souls or whatever you want to
call that life energy they don't have
that ability like this is the valuable
Universal all the souls are lining up
with their quarters to get a turn at
Earth this is the game that's got the
lineup in the arcade and here we all are
and uh what a joy that we found things
like cannabis we found things like the
psychedelic mushroom thank God for the
people and the proponents who now are
the people here here on this very panel
but when we were growing up we all had
different shoulders of giants while I
mean you know weight and and and Sam
were still there back when we were all
barely a blink in our Daddy's eye but
you know it's a neat thing to have been
able to stand on the shoulders of giants
and to pass on this information and as
fast as information is passing it's
still very very very slow and uh
nothing's quicker than in my opinion
eating the Flesh of that mushroom
smoking the resin of that cannabis plant
and that is where I really start to
gather information and learn and put
things together so thank thank you each
and every one of you for taking this
journey and sharing it with everyone
because uh we're all learning from it
there's no doubt just think you know
Colton was what Colton was 13 when we
started our cannabis
journey and now he's going to be 21 this
year we're looking at seven years of
just cannabis reform and it's still not
even there you know we still have in in
in the United States we still have like
19 states that haven't legalized
anything and so now we're starting a
whole new Journey with with psilocybin
trying to get it legalized and I'm like
why is it taking so long when we can get
a vaccine for covid within eight months
you know it just doesn't make any sense
to me and I don't understand why we have
these beautiful plant um
and this this ability to heal
ourselves and we are making it illegal
and people are keeping it illegal for
what reason I just I can't wrap my my
head around to to let us know just how
important they are that's the reason and
that's the reason we do what we do yeah
it's the only reason it's like they
could they're literally shining a
spotlight on all the most most important
things things in the universe basically
and we're just over here looking like
hey what what about this over here like
we should be allowed to have this and
welcome to the dragonfly Earth
medicine exactly I just don't understand
it it's impossible to understand but
thank goodness we have people in the
world like you Wendy who just are they
see right through it and they're like
you know what I've got there's bigger
things for me than to swallow a bunch of
[ __ ] that's being fed to me by a a
news person or a news anchor I've got
this real thing here my 13-year-old son
who basically just about died in a lake
and almost drowned and now something
else isn't right so I don't really have
time for all this [ __ ] over here and
that's how you tear through all of that
crap in a very quick uh manner now to me
I was just as blown away when you know
people I think it was Chris Christie
that like the dad like approached Chris
Christie and was like my kid will die
without this medicine my kid has
epilepsy and will die without this
medicine and he was just like yeah no
sorry you can't we can't like right to
the guy's face even I was just like wow
like it was almost like when Donald
Trump made fun of the guy with the arm
the reporter that was also like a sign
like oh of course this is going to take
forever because if he could maintain a
presidency after doing that well then
anything's game it's like of course like
oh what children in America are dying
because don't have access to cannabis
we'll get some synthetic stuff your way
as soon as we can we just got to wrap up
these patents make sure that the profit
margins are approved got to be FDA
approved you know it's going to take
seven years unless it's a vaccine for
covid we'll Hammer that out in nine
months the same thing let's send
millions of dollars to other countries
but each American can only get
$600 we but we did the same thing when
um we we were lobbying in DC one year
and we went to our representative in
Colorado Springs and his name is Doug
Lamborn And that son of a [ __ ] I'm
telling you he looked straight at at my
face and said if it's not FDA approved
then there's nothing I can do about it
and I said can we FastTrack it and he
said well yeah of course we'll we'll
sign a bill to FastTrack it and I said
we will be the face of that bill I said
we will do anything that it takes to get
that bill FastTrack and FDA approved and
I said but what are we supposed to do in
the
meantime and and he said there's nothing
I can do about it and I said well my kid
will die without this medicine you know
he he can't take the regular westernized
medications he's G he's not going to
survive that and he looked at me and he
said that's not my problem oo oh my God
and I went off I was so freaking mad and
I'm like yes it is your problem it
absolutely is your problem and I'm like
so you're going to tell me that it's
okay for me that I'm just supposed to
let Colton die because this is not an
FDA approved
medicine God and I was just I was
appalled I could not believe it and then
to to see the the same things happening
all over the United States you know and
even in other countries I just I just
don't understand how people can't be
more compassion compassionate about the
life of a of an individual know even
with this Co stuff you know there was so
many people that said it well if you
can't survive it then you're not
supposed to survive it I'm like but you
know it just stay in your house and I'm
like but you know Colton makes a
difference in the world you know he
tries to make a difference in the world
it's it's what we do and you're telling
me that his difference that he's made in
the world isn't worth it anymore that he
needs to just stay home and not so you
can't wear mask so Colton can actually
go out and do the things that he does to
make your life better but it's the
compassion and the and and just the the
Simplicity of of all of this that just
boggles my mind and I'm just I'm so glad
to be able to move into a a journey in
my life where I'm more more woke I wish
that I was even more woke but I used to
be that D mom and
now I you know since cannabis saved
Colton's life I'm looking at other
things thinking oh my gosh what more is
there out there greatest Dar mom
transition ever by the way I just want
to throw that out there I appreciate it
I appreciate
it the most epic I've ever
seen walk in hey everyone how's it going
can hear y'all Ste Warrior Mike U was
diagnosed with with different couns
quite a story and same thing Colton he
grabbed bball he started using cannabis
I mean um just quite an amazing story
both of you guys it's it's great he just
walked in Mike's coming in and work in
the garden but uh I thought you know
what jump in here and say hi Mike
because uh yeah happy New Year Mike it's
good to see you and it's really nice to
see that you have absolutely kicked
Cancer's ass because I know it had a
deep grasp on you you were you weren't
the stage one guy you were deep in
it well I don't know what stage it would
call it was it was a crucial tumor that
needed to be removed and it was
tenacious because it kept coming back
and due to its Rarity it's well that's
why we were tackling it with Canabis
because uh they couldn't figure it out
they thought cutting it out would be
good enough but no it's just not they
removed a rib they removed tumors you've
had over 26 surgeries M's got quite an
amazing story and cannabis has since
changed his life completely and uh
you're on uh RSO daily he makes his own
uh he gets he went and got his own
what's the machine he has the extract um
mind blank now mind blank which is
awesome but um I mean all these little
things exact extract and and and I've
even talking with Mike about mushrooms
and stuff and I was going to mention
that Turner I mean for me um I was
having bad migrain and cluster headaches
from my 28t fall and in 2007 I took a
micro dose of mushrooms at
420 and my headaches never came back I
used to I couldn't handle my tension
headaches and stuff like that I mean
I've been previously using mushrooms in
the past but I really became medicinal
when I was going through that time with
my injuries and mushrooms was that that
that next step of me being able to move
forward with what had happened to me so
definitely go down that pathway micro
doing is huge when it comes to dealing
with headaches and migraines for me
myself and I know lots of testimonials
that people do the same thing and it's a
great reward so um enjoy your journey
just a little bit of the time that's it
that's it guys that's it you know right
before you uh he came in and introduced
Mike I was kind of thinking as Wendy was
talking and a few people in the in the
room were talking about what what it is
this is you know you just can't imagine
you're like this is my child like what
are you evil and you start thinking and
I'm sure they're just probably the wrong
terms to think of it as they're just
these opposing forces whether it's
Darkness and Light or good and evil try
to get out of that mentality cuz they're
really both Wings on the same bird but
it really is this like opposing energy
that's built into all of life you know
all of life entropies all of life dies
and so you got to just think that
without that opposing energy there
couldn't be the other side to the
opposing energy and it's this sort of
Journey that we take and you just want
to you know you want everyone to just
come on all let's get everyone on side
and it seems to be an impossible factor
it's it's that there always has to be
both sides to the coin or the coin
itself can't exist it seems to be a very
important part of the illusion that
certainly on four or five grams of dried
psilocybin mushrooms you can break
through and experience something far far
beyond that uh or maybe some LSD I
remember Sam telling us one time he took
I don't know if it was a 100 or 200 or
however many hits he took back in the
60s and blacked out there's there are
ways to experience to remove your
Consciousness from this 5ense prison
that it's currently locked into to you
know if you think of psychedelics as a
pro a prosthetic that can take that
Consciousness out of this five sense
prison and move it beyond that into this
you know more wider I I would say view
but really the language isn't there
because it's beyond our senses but
anyone that's experienced these
substances in Fairly large doses uh will
be up and Downing their head right now
with a somewhat pale look on their face
and a bit of fright uh in their soul
because uh yeah the ego uh my favorite
teren McKenna quote these compounds do
not bathe the ego in a cloud of
certitude that's one of my favorites
right there from psilocybin in the sands
of time if you guys want to check out a
great talk Go YouTube sasy and in the
Sands of talk that [ __ ] will blow the
back of your head off and it was like
1986 at The esam Institute when he did
it so it's worth checking
out what's going on dragonfly Earth
medicine
smiley
faces hey everybody happy New Year
really nice to see everybody
today Allison really beautiful to see
you
onday thank you so much for your work
thanks to the Ames Institute I have so
much deep gratitude for the work that
you all are doing we're following it all
the time and um yeah so appreciative and
everybody else out there so so beautiful
to see you and um I just I think it's a
beautiful representation of the fact
that you know we can't necessarily
always uh rely on our government or
medical industry for things and I'm
really thankful that at least we do have
an alternative community of people that
are turned on and that will go the extra
mile no matter what because karmically
and their hearts they're right and I'm
thankful to this community of people on
and people that are listening because
obviously there's amazing amounts of
people listening too that are equally as
powerful so big love and respect to that
community that keeps this world a better
place and keeps it taken and I just
think that you know as the Cannabis
culture and having been a part of it for
um the past 30 years pretty much was
sounds incredible wow time is totally
rolling that you know being a part of
the traditional Market made us not look
towards you know the government made us
not look
towards whatever uh politics lobbying
anything because just wasn't allowing us
to be able to get the job done and it
seems like more and more people are
coming on board and places and things
are becoming legalized you know and and
and decriminalized and it's all because
the medicine is really doing the work
sure there's people behind it there's us
cultivating it there's people getting it
out there totally illegally Against All
Odds but it's the medicine that that
changes the people when people people
ingest it that that they feel those
transitional changes even even
politicians now so we're becoming more
intelligent because the food and the
medicine that we're taking is of higher
intelligence so it brings our
possibilities up and that's what they
don't want they the them they don't want
that intelligence to thrive and places
like ases is like a you know Ames
Institute I don't know if you've talked
about it yet but I mean it's it's like a
a ground zero spot for
you know normalization and and and maybe
you could tell us more about and the
bridge The Bridge from from the work
that we've been doing in the in the in
the black market and the traditional
market and now Ames is really taking it
Forward Alison I'd love to hear about
what what you've been up to and what
what you've been doing lately um I
mentioned earlier that we're currently
um well we do all kinds of psychedelics
right now um Dr sis is working on um
using iasa uh for cancer patients um she
has also put forth um her first
documentation to get approval from the
DEA to utilize iasa she is also working
with the mckenas um there she's a
steward to their property in Hawaii and
so we will be using iasa from that um
that that community and um as I
mentioned earlier we are currently
working on a study for psilocybin end of
life um we are trying to bypass a DCM
and and using the right to try rule um
and uh getting uh attorneys involved to
basically Sue on behalf of several of
our clients to be able to use psilocybin
for end of life um we currently do in
office ketamine assisted Psychotherapy
sessions we do cannabis assisted
Psychotherapy sessions um it's uh I I
can't I can't tell you guys enough the
power of the work it's like cannabis was
amazing or is amazing but when you take
these people who are hurt and just have
tried every medication and then you give
them some psychedelics and you see the
change and it's like Marcus is saying
that ego dissolution your ego gets in
the way of whether you know it's um
seeing love or whether it's letting go
of hurt or loss and um with the ego gone
it really allows someone to um see
another side of life and uh and and I'm
really lucky and so honored every time I
sit with someone on a psychedelic
session or I support someone and either
teaching them how to micro dose um or to
do macro doing um it's it's an honor and
a privilege to me um it just just it's
it's kind of like helping like you were
saying Marcus take their soul to a to
like a cleaner lighter um space where
that um the constructs of everyday life
don't have to
apply and that's that's that's kind of
what we're doing at as I mean every day
is is different um you know we deal with
with with all different kinds of clients
that are looking for support um I like I
said I do ketamine in the office and
then I support micro and macro dosing of
other psychedelics that are not yet
legal and um our goal is to be able to
do psilocybin we are um we have we have
gone through the MDMA training through
maps and now we're awaiting the DEA to
approve um our site we've gotten all the
requirements of the refrigerators and
everything that MDMA is supposed to be
kept in but unfortunately under Trump's
presidency um a lot of those DEA
approvals have um kind of stalled
so we are hoping that with the new
presidential Administration that we will
have more our site will be approved for
MDMA as
well awesome that's amazing that puts a
big smile on my face for
sure and we work with the Canadian we
work with salame salame has come down um
from the Canadian psychedelic
Association love her she's awesome um
she's come down and we're kind of doing
work hand
inand um
awesome yeah we've been doing work with
salame as well she's part of our
community up here in British colia and
Seattle and in the US and Hawaii and the
Iowa Vines of the Big Island um but yeah
we did a really amazing talk with h sish
and um Sunil uh and it was really
beautiful online if anyone hasn't seen
it I'm not sure exactly where to find it
right this second just to say it but
yeah it was an incredible panel with
maps just on uh Canabis and cancer and
other plant medicine and and cancer and
just it was just blew my mind to to sit
with those folks and and just have a
discussion so I feel like wow you know
as much as 2020 has been just so
incredibly you know whatever it is it's
all of the words I don't even want to
say one word because it's all of the
words still the mushrooms are getting
through the melium is grow gr you know
the seeds are sprouting the plant
medicine is making its way into almost
regular conversation regular dinner
tables and regular Suburbia like all
over the world and I just think that
this incredible you know time for plant
medicine and totally we're we're getting
such empowering messages and and it's
really giving us a lot of the answers
that we've been searching for that you
know maybe science and this idealization
of a continually isolating things to
give us the answers of the great magic
of the unknown of why we're here and why
we exist and where we're going to and
where we came from and it just seems
like the plant medicine is doing much
better than um you know past science
it's definitely reaching the masses I'm
always surprised when I get like an
80-year-old Grandma come in with like a
Michael pollen book all Doge eared and
she's like help me do this take you know
these little old ladies more so than I
ever saw in cannabis because these are
these are old ladies that are not
necessarily sick but they just want to
know like they want to find peace in
death they want to find peace with with
their past um and it's um and they're
willing they've never some of them have
never done psychedelics before and they
just want to like find out what is this
magic that goes on with looking inside
the mind and it's really cool it's
really really cool and and I definitely
see psychedelics touching the masses a
lot more um since since the acceptance
of
cannabis yeah that's that's for sure go
ahead an it's a great healing too uh one
that a lot of our veterans are finding
exponentially uh I've started uh kind of
a a group with loose affiliation with
various uh veterans from all over the
United States and now we have ones from
Canada who are joining us uh because
we're finding not just cannabis is
helpful but especially working through
our post-traumatic stress to arrive at
our post-traumatic growth one of the
things we find is definitely
psychedelics of various ones help kill
that ego so that they can get past uh uh
their trauma so that they can finally
arrive at their healing um it it
definitely is a clear of the pathways
and the blockages for many people I
can't say for all but at the same time
uh these are things that we realize that
cannabis has its place but so does Iain
so does iasa so do all the other
naturopathic plant medicinein so uh I
want to give a shout out to my veterans
Action Council brothers and sisters
there uh for our continued work because
that's one of the things we're working
towards in the new year is continuing uh
opening up access especially for
veterans because we're just a small
encapsulation of society but such a
concentration of society it's reflection
reflects back so uh we just want to uh
lend our hands and our ears and our
minds as well I think one of the
important things we're going to find in
the next 10 years as well as we do with
everything we we scrub all the culture
out of it right we do everything in a
very sort of clean style room and I
think that the set and setting and the
importance of learning that and everyone
learns that when they have their first
maybe took too much whatever at the
wrong spot it was kind of like wow that
was that was certainly not the same as
it usually is and that was kind of a bad
experience like I guess taking acid and
going to the bar and playing pool wasn't
as good of an idea as we thought it was
and so you can see how the set and
setting and I wonder where that will
take us this set and setting because
will it be in a room with walls and and
ceilings and or will it be outside will
it be more like you know because we have
these two things we have these aashka
ceremonies that are happening in in
South America and in Central America and
they definitely happen in different
types of Huts they have these
traditional settings that have been in
place for many many many decades and
then you have sort of the western
society's version which we do with
everything even the way we grow cannabis
we've scrubbed the entire Terre right
out of the entire cannabis Growing
Experience which could you imagine ever
suggesting that to the wine folk like
hey we should scrub the terroir out of
grapes and grow them indoors with like
lights and white poly walls and like
what do you think of that idea you know
like so I hope we don't scrub out that
terar culture from the Psychedelic
experience if that makes sense one of
the things we are working towards right
now in the veterans Action Council is
Sops we started reaching out to Shaman
and others and realizing that there's a
lot of unfortunate sexual abuse that can
happen in uh these situations Maps has
put out a situation so we're actually
working on a white paper and Dr Dron I
would love to have your input and look
over because we're reaching out to the
Native American Shaman Community the the
traditional uh Shaman Community as well
as reaching out to Ms because we realize
that a lot of people want to IDE and
want to go there but at the same time
they don't know how to prep themselves
where need to be who needs to be there
um you know because people think that a
couple is there but we got wi that a
particular couple will abuse people
while they're under these psychedelics
so um we want to work on educating
people so that they can have the
experience that they desire and not the
one that they get you know tan I I
usually recommend people so for what I
do like you know there's some um you
might hear some clinics that do just in
fusions like whe whether it be ketamine
um um or or underground therapists that
do their individual work um but for what
we do at our Clinic it's absolutely
imperative to develop a
relationship um over a period of time
with the person that you're going to be
going on this journey with um I work
with um highly traumatized individuals
who've had years firefighter police
officers people who've been uh raped
multiple times um and those type of
individuals really require uh trust and
I know Maps um does the two people um in
our office it's just one therapist but
what we do is that we develop a
therapeutic relationship over a period
of time prior to giving that person
psychedelics um and sitting with them um
and that
seems that seems for me to help a client
develop that trust but I'm absolutely
open to to reading your paper and um
giving some feedback because I think
that this is in order for anyone to let
go of their ego in an environment they
really need to trust the people that are
going to be the holder of their
bodies agreed I put my email in the chat
there so uh if you could reach out I to
uh make contact for that because we just
want to create a safety document so that
when people have or want to experience
this this just becomes sort of a go-to
document so they can understand that
this is the way that it should be done
so appreciate your input and thoughts
and there's an energy behind the
medicine that's being taken to and the
way that it's cultivated and we've
learned through cannabis about conscious
cannabis cultivation and how its effects
from regenerative cannabis into the body
is more it's easier to assimilate and
when with psychedelic mushrooms I mean
they could be grown in a super
chemically Laden situation and really
that's not positive for our body nor is
it positive for the people growing it or
the trip that we're GNA have you the use
of isopropyl in the production of of of
psychedelic mushrooms is extremely
harmful to our microbiome and and you
wouldn't want the cultivators to get
sick in the in in
in the uh you know process of creating a
cure so there's conscious ways of
creating psychedelics you can do it like
Marcus has been showing wavy caps and
cyan Essence in the background those are
uh Woody mushrooms people can create
Woody patches on their land and create a
lot of medicine in those areas and I you
know we talk about the the epigenetics
of the trip it's it's so important where
are
we doing
hear is she breaking up for you guys as
well to be able to go in yeah the
correct area in the
care sorry maybe I'll come back to it
well we lost you just for yeah we you're
we can hear you coming at the end now
but yeah we were you were chipping out
there and I really wanted to hear that I
was going to add to what you were saying
is is that I am I have I've never in my
life heard of so many people growing
mushrooms these little little ladies
coming in to visit me at the office
they're growing mushrooms uh every Tom
Dick and Harry is growing mushrooms at
this point I live in the Pacific
Northwest so it's very easy or creating
new strains this was what I was gonna
dragonfly I was going to touch on is
that what's seeming to happen now is
that people are putting two different
types of mushrooms in a tub and then how
would you describe it is that then they
just choose the spores of the big fatty
ones and then they continue to propagate
the big fatty ones but that doesn't
necessarily mean that the traits of that
particular mushroom are the best just
because it looks big it's it's okay I
know it's this constant need for bigger
better quads you're going to look for
quads in in
mushrooms
quads guys doesn't matter it doesn't
matter but star mushrooms listen I
listen I will even add it's it's more
important than that because anyone
that's ever grown mushrooms knows that
when you take a trip of the little
aborts the little mushrooms that don't
make it the Caps that don't open up
they're tiny little babies well listen
primordial heads listen those things I
swear to God I don't know if this is a
fact but this is what it seems like when
you eat them it seems as though they've
produced all of their psilocybin and
psilocin when they're this big and then
you eat a gram of those and it's
literally like eating five grams of like
big huge giant you know three foot
mushrooms or whatever because especially
if they're fresh the stem but is the
most my partner is agreeing with what
you're saying yeah me too my psychedelic
Journeys have agreed with what I'm
saying in the Pacific Northwest there's
a lot of foraging that goes on here you
know in addition to the Sans we also
have spring and fall ovoids um which is
another type of psychedelic mushroom and
then of course on the coast we have the
azer resence um so we're in like the
mecca here in the Pacific Northwest for
mushrooms and so Seattle has gone on the
attack to kill the mushrooms because
they used to have wood chips all over
the city and psychedelic mushrooms grew
all over the city that's West
Vancouver over
they still all of West Vancouver certain
cities are adding fungicides to their
wood chips so that they do not grow the
mushroom but that's most that's mostly
up in Bellingham we're hearing
Bellingham fungicide in the mushro in
the in the chips but but here in Seattle
it hasn't really the fungicide hasn't
really taken over it's still really good
my partner is a master forager um and so
he spends his fall and spring um out in
the wood chips well he's invited up to
Vancouver to come spend it with us this
next fall because we're doing the very
same thing we're we're pulling morals
we're pulling yellow foots which you see
behind me all varieties of gold
shantells Lobster mushrooms cauliflower
mushrooms uh bow lights um a whole
variety of wonderful edible mushrooms I
ate my fair share of edible mushrooms
this fall it was insane we would just go
every single weekend Shout to Shawn
Michaels uh the very same Shawn Michaels
that did the pointilism work on my
bubble man uh guy that sits on the
tricomes he's uh been forging also for
the last 20 years here uh fungi and
plant medicine so it's uh it's a huge
bonus but you guys should come up and we
should uh we should share some pick and
stories and some experiences someone
someone needs to come to Illinois and
help us we have tons of mushrooms here I
mean Illinois has medicinal polypores on
your trees in Illinois
oh my gosh and we have no I mean we have
70 Acres of just Woods um that my family
owns and you know we we're looking we're
doing we mushroom hunt um but mushroom
hunting morels which go for like $500 a
pound around here because everyone loves
them so much but there's we we look at
all these other little mushrooms that
are around and we're like which ones can
we eat which ones can we not um it's
just it's incredible there's and we live
um the area that we live in is the where
the Three Rivers come together so it's
really moist here and there's a lot of
humidity um so someone needs to come and
show this area get yourself some spores
and uh Spore some of your hardwood bark
what about a special show on mushrooms
both edible and psychedelic Where We
Gather some of the great minds and we
educate ourselves like that yeah and
that would be awesome I mean I don't
know how many times that I've gotten on
to to Hash church and I've been like I
don't know enough about cannabis and you
guys all blow my mind um simplify it for
us you know we're just now getting into
this we need to know which mushrooms are
good which mushrooms are bad where to
find them you know and and just just
simplify it just for the the the Layman
so we can get more good good if you're a
human bad if you're a bug anyone okay
and not found in Illinois either
and I was wanting to say that you know
the
incredible um uh positive reactions that
we've gotten from compounding cannabis
with medicinal mushrooms so adding that
in there the incredible importance of
these adaptogens going together and and
creating medicine together yet there's
some Moc canic caps that was really fun
you
knowy turkey tail Lion's man all of
those U my partner just said it's
actually illegal to possess legal it's
legal it is legal to possess spores in
Illinois oh so you canful than the
fruiting body so that's a good thing to
know very powerful is it is it true that
scores are are legal in all 50 states to
hold no they're illegal in California
they're illegal in California is it true
that spores are the only other living
creature to leave Earth aside from
humans and float in space trapped in
Cosmic radiation pressure just putting
it out there uh water bears as well oh
water oh right what do they called it
again TR Tru they have a weird name they
just took those things to the Moon
recently uh the the hard the strongest
living organism those weird little
creatures that have the snout mouths
they're like microscopic TR
traga no
nobody when we which
one yes
exactly
at [ __ ] so it's a small group it's a
small group six-legged creatures that
can survive in space but yeah it' be
great to know about uh if if actually
scores do actually travel through space
because you know how long have they been
traveling yeah and where did they come
from we need all these questions
answered and also can you imagine space
nice I I want some space mushrooms as
well for all we know we have them
already we are space mushrooms let's be
real like we're pretending right now
that we're not ATN have you ever tried
this the the uh cyano
franciscans the the Psychedelic
mushrooms that are found in Oakland I'm
pretty sure it's like in a Jack In The
Box parking lot or something like that
like there a newer variety of of
psychedelics that's been discovered in
the last maybe 10 years now and I'm sure
and there wasn't a clinical name for
them because they were new but we've you
know taken them and and had some uh
chance to try and grow them but it
wasn't Su have you heard do you know
about the
Oakland I have heard of it I have not
tried it and if anybody who sees me who
knows me and wants to and has access to
I would love to try them and I'm pretty
sure if someone's watching the chat from
what I I've been told on the on the
street you know it's called the cyano
franciscans but it probably should be
called the cyano they're mushrooms that
you don't they actually try they try you
that's the way it usually goes for sure
I mean and with psychedelics there's
there's there's manure loving uh cubus
and a lot of them are manure loving and
those are a lot of the ones that are
grown indoors or you can cultivate them
in greenh houses yeah the the produc how
would you uh rate the the high of that
mushroom was it a solid ego kill which
mushroom
the Oakland Francis Francis uh it was
very uh visually pleasing very visually
pleasing and uh had a you know super
silly note to it it was kind of like a
little bit reminiscent to the to the
cyan Essence to the very very sparkly
more sparkly than I'd had mushrooms in a
long time lots of like really activated
colors and sparkles have you guys have
you guys tried Bens cuz those often
produce the visuals with Bist and nor
Bist those are blue bells and grow also
in and around like Maple Ridge and stuff
in British
Columbia yeah I've tried those before
they were really nice um one of the good
ones we had recently was the albino
penis
envy the ape the ape I mean those are
amazing you know really incredible I me
wow medicinal they look insane you know
and the the trip was so much fun you
just eat on them like you
know I feel like I should be welcoming
both skunkman Sam and best friend Farms
into the room I feel like I kind of [ __ ]
the bed on welcoming those two guys to
the room and I apologize I got sucked
into the mushroom talk can you hear me I
can hear you you you're like the guy on
the cell phone commercial can you hear
me
now he patented all the mushrooms wanted
to say one thing and that is we've been
through a lot of this before the psychic
psychedelic revolution in the 60s and I
think our big mistake then was okay we
took psych does we did kill our ego that
served a purpose to let us understand
ourselves better but uh the trouble was
uh back then lar used to preach turn on
tune in and drop out we don't want to
drop out we want to turn in turn on
excuse me tune in and take
over really that's the goal is to take
over because if we don't we have the
morons in [ __ ] power and uh we we're
stupid enough we don't need even
stupider people telling us what to
do ain't that so I just want to tell you
go ahead kill your ego turn on t in but
take
over and overgrow don't forget to spread
the
overgrow my ciate the
system yeah let let let the mushrooms
and the plant medicine take over and we
just stewarded it into the melium we
like to spread melium everywhere well
said hey I want to throw in a thought
here I I love the conversation about
killing the ego um and yes that was my
experience with psychedelics uh earlier
in my life but I came to realize that
actually it's not so much about killing
the ego it's about coming to understand
that the ego doesn't have to be in
charge uh ego does serve a function in
certain ways it's but to me psychedelics
took the illusion away that all of this
physical plain reality is what's really
important um and I it's been years since
I've used any psychedelics um I I get
really high on love these days uh love
of my life love of nature I I'm
fortunate enough to shelter in place on
a farm where I can walk the land and
really drink deeply of how beautiful it
is when it rains finally in
California um and I get really high that
way because psychedelics early in my
life helped me recognized that all of
the stress and the fear and the anger
that I could find in my life was an
illusion and it was based on attachment
as as Marcus alluded to earlier so I I
really want to encourage people to yes
use use psychedelics to help you see the
illusion that that seems so real that we
call life because yes life is suffering
and uh but what's true is within each of
us there's this place that psychedelics
helps you experience where you can carry
it forward in your life dayt day moment
to moment without the need to constantly
micro do or to macro do and I highly
encourage anyone that hasn't tried the
Psychedelic experience to do so but also
to recognize that it's helping you see
truth as versus is truth itself
sorry for the rant I just had to pitch
that in
there I appreciate everything you just
said Wade and I also appreciate the tone
in which you said it it was very calming
and just enjoyable so I appreciate you
sharing blessings thank
you so I have to throw something out
there that um I've been holding on to
for a little while now um I want to talk
about her ratio a little bit today
Marcus I uh I got a a piece of jewelry
um that he and his wife created before
he
died um and I just want to make sure we
talk a little bit about ratio
today absolutely let's uh yeah we had a
whole show for Horatio rest in peace
I've heard a few of them today as well
he was definitely a brilliant mind and
uh really an incredible energy that is
definitely missed here in uh in our
community he's surrounded in this
building he is all over here um I have a
lot of htio memory and Allison I have
something here for you
and I have these special little um
aluminum balls that are steel balls at
Horatio this was part of his leing
extraction so certain people in this
group if you please send me an email I
will ship you one of these
um Alison you're one of them um I was
paying ET and anybody here who was
involved with ratio and was part of that
family I save these and I talk with Mary
quite a bit I just talked her on New
Year's Day and uh these are in memory of
a great mind and a great soul and a
great person so I don't even think I've
had a chance to give you one Mark I
haven't been out because of Co and I me
staying home but I can put these in the
mail to the people um that are are
abroad um I'll ship them to Amsterdam
Europe SP wherever I don't really care
it's not about anything it's about
having that memory of someone who was so
great so there's there's people in and
we've talked about it so um please reach
out to me um if you don't have my email
it's uh quite easy you can just send it
to medtainer Canada gmail.com um to
certain people out there but please
contact me and I'll send you a
little little piece of someone who is
great this is a big part of what he did
and it's pretty uh they smell like lean
mean too so it's kind of cool
I found some of my old lemon um hash oil
that I had been hoarding and I and it of
course it doesn't look the same but it
still was like just to smell it you
could still smell light Trace like very
light traces of
lemon um but he um he was he was an
interesting an interesting fellow and he
um really um was a historical piece of
the
Cannabis movement um a quiet one other
than hased her she was really
quiet uh and kind of kept himself and
you know lived in his little house in
the woods with his family and um I also
too have been in touch with Marne you
know I got a few pieces of his jewelry
and and some stickers and stuff that was
from um from some of his containers and
um just broke my heart that he left us
way too
soon way too
soon I sit here and look at the trione
of the microscope and just go down there
research path of what we all do and what
he did and how we all inspired one
another here that was a big part of of
all of us in hash church is the
inspiration we all gave one another and
hertia was one of those ones that
inspired us to move forward like we all
kind of do here every day it's pretty
awesome to take a look at the journey
that uh has happened with has church and
the surrounding people and the community
have just keep pushing forward to just
see this plant grow and grow and it's
awesome I love being a part of it
yeah so thanks I just wanted to just to
bring him up a little because you know
he is was a special part of hash
Church oh yeah he was definitely a fan
favorite lots of people always loved uh
listening to what uh hereso had to share
and a thinker innovator you know
definitely was playing around where you
know we got people going off about tech
in the in the chat right now upset that
certain texts haven't been shared but
Horatio's texts you know were unable to
shared because of the danger they they
posed to to people playing around with
them and he didn't want to be giving
Tech to people and then having them hurt
themselves and so you know you can see
that it's not just black and white you
know people want Tech and so they feel
that complaining about it is how they
can get it but it's not it's not always
it doesn't always work out that way so
you know I I remember talking to him
about you know when I went and filmed
Horatio's inner sanctum and how
controlling he was in that aspect and he
really wanted to make sure that I didn't
share anything um that you know maybe
people would get a hold of and and and
hurt themselves doing so you know that
that that was some chemistry that he was
playing around with there and uh I kind
of respected it that he that he wanted
to do it that way you know I personally
was very honored to be able to go into
his lab because I know very very few
people ever got invited in there and to
be able to film as well with him um puts
that that that puts that out there that
I'll never take that video down you know
that'll be available to people to go in
and to to to watch and check out and and
visit with Horatio so to speak it's uh
yeah that we went to Marcus um was it
called cannabis economy and it was up in
Vancouver and you and Horatio introduced
the turp
champagne yeah that was
awesome that was so amazing I mean like
there were people who in that setting
that had no idea about tpin and you guys
just champ to all those
folks
fromo let's do it for I pulled out 90
year here man I'll
never take a dab all right everyone in
chat whatever it is you're doing pick up
your pipes your joints we're having a
dab a dab
stre Colton's gonna go get his Vape
because he doesn't dab but um just to
remind everyone his GoFundMe is still up
and you can donate to Horatio's GoFundMe
still so everyone out there who has been
touched by htio please go to goof fundme
and and give a few
dollars I purchased a they she did an
auction and so um some of the jewelry
that they make um I um I I purchased
some jewelry as a way of supporting the
family um and so she still she still has
those pieces not all of them went for
auction um but uh and story behind that
and the jewelry that was made was
actually was pretty cool because it was
a new form of attack that he had
actually came up with by fusing two
compounds together to make the jewelry
that no one had done before so it's a
completely new as you know how ratio was
he came up with something so amazingly
and Innovative he was able to fume these
together I saw the material I saw what
was going on with it I seen the molds
and everything um this Julie is
something special and it's be great for
the family to move on because she'll be
something that Mar will be working on
and his daughter maybe in the future but
it's something to fuel that family and
keep that that Vision going in that kind
of uh it's pretty cool Julia guys yeah
definitely check it out just go to his
uh his Instagram page and you'll see
some of it and stuff yeah it's really
cool
stuff DK where's the DK let's do it
let's do it I got 600 just under 600
Fahrenheit I'm ready for a dabby bless
you bless you my goodness no I'm
coughing well bless you're
coughing I'm smoking a
TR I'm dabbing
got some Johnny B action going on there
it's pretty impressive I like
it I took some uh caps this morning uh
the the 240s and I took two of them so
about 15 minutes into hash church I was
getting a little jittery and I was
getting a little anxiety out and I sat
there and started smoking a little bit
of hash went for a walk came back and
had to relax a little bit so it's kind
of like gu I I think I went to my Peak
limit this morning I uh I ate some M
caps from dragonfly Earth medicine and
I'm also rocking some host defense some
Lion Man great for memory and nerve
support those are my uh those are my
daily medicines right there boom
shank some mushroom going hard been
going hard on the uh the mushrooms
lately probably taking up to three
heaping tablespoons of lion M Lion's man
three heaping tablespoons of uh turkey
tail and and um just started a a 12-day
water cleanse and I'm just going to go
hard with the mushrooms and the Miso and
just do water mushrooms and miso for 12
days and try to get reset I feel like
coming into my 50th year I felt like it
was really important to well having
passed my 50th year felt like it was
probably a good thing to uh do some
cleansing and and and some sometimes
when it's quiet it's it's a good time to
go within and realize that food and
drinking and and external and all these
things that we take into our lives
really take up a lot of time and energy
and when we sort of pull back from that
and and do things that you know are good
for our body I think that we learn more
about ourselves and we learn more about
what's going on um you know in the world
today so coming into 2021 I feel like um
you know and probably end it with a
really beautiful intentional Journey
some type of plant medicine
Journey so loving those mushrooms also
thanks uh Marcus I've been taking so
much oil it's been awesome it's it's
it's just so healing on so many levels
to mix the medicinal mushrooms with the
Cannabis I feel like they were made for
each other and and a lot of those
mushrooms in there are foraged from our
for
and we live on the edge of a Wilderness
so it's like eating longevity
enzymes you know with
longevity longevity enzymes you know the
poly like who gets artist con and amadu
and fobes and the red belted conch and
and slices we slice them up and make
make oil out of them I mean the oil of
the mushrooms itself is
just yeah just that there it is red
belted polypore slice it up and just
stuff the pots and I'll P I'll pull a
polypore off like that slice it with a a
knife to a little thing and chew on it
while I'm and then if you put the slices
together overnight in a basket they will
melate on top of each other they just
continue to grow it's insane so if you
took that and you sliced it it's like
you could make a thousand of them from
that they just want to continue to grow
and they seem to be everywhere and it's
good to have some of the bark still on
the mushroom because the bark is healing
as well and the cambium layer I mean the
mushroom is is a fruit of the cambium
layer of the tree yeah that mycelium is
where it's attached to the lifeblood of
the tree so all the intelligence of the
tree and all of the history of the tree
and all the everything that the tree is
uptaken is in
that that Marcus is holding that then we
can absorb because we can't absorb the
tree but we can absorb the mushroom so
it's a brid and uh that dried mushroom
that Marcus had is uh still has a a lot
of the medicine in it so it does store
in they're dry but it's really hard it's
nearly impossible possible to cut you
could probably burn that
Marcus I mean I don't know whether you
want to burn that one or not but those
uh those mushrooms when uh when dried
also burn so like this is and also the
the smelling the smoke from a polypore
like chaga and amadu the Tinder conch
smelling the smoke is healing to the
body and a lot of native peoples used
that as an incense in their uh in their
smoke and so you can smoke this polypore
if you take a little slice of it and put
it in a vitam mix and kind of uh make it
it goes furry when you try and blend it
it doesn't like chip up you can mix it
with cannabis and smoke it in a
doobie and it's really really good for
you it's a fantastic you know fungicide
it's really helpful for damp lung issues
people with consumption and and a lot of
the native people had it you know like
Josh was saying in their medicine bag
because it helps rid pathogenic fungi so
we always burn it through our green
houses we burn them in our basements we
really you know take advantage of of
this cleansing uh here's another really
awesome example same thing that Marcus
was showing and this is off of birch and
it I mean uh the the red belted conch is
the phomopsis pinac cola which is
generally off a pine tree but this is
from a birch tree
so this would have different compounds
because the Birch has betulinic acid in
it so we we really are stoked when we
find mushrooms off a birch tree it's our
goal to we eat the Birch we eat the the
bark of the Birch we drink the birch
bark because you can't eat
it I mean you can do a lot of things but
this is on Birch this chagga
beautiful today really became a mushroom
church I'm going to have to do like a
I'm going to have to start a mushroom
show where we share mushroom information
and do maybe not every week by any means
but be good to do a mushroom maybe I
could ask all of you to help collect
some names and contact information for
the people that would want would should
be in you know invited such a discussion
yeah I think that between the people
just on the panel here right now we
could probably put together another 50
to 100 names pretty easily and we could
encourage the growing of mushrooms
together with cannabis especially for
the backyard and homeg grower because a
lot of medicinal mushrooms like myi
lions
M uh what's Rishi those three are just
ones that come off the head that they
can grow they grow off wood so you can
if if people are clearing their Forest
blah blah their fire you know whatever
you can plug trees and put them in the
dirt underneath your cannabis so the
trees will fruit these medicinal
mushrooms underneath your cannabis and
they'll breathe together right because
the mushrooms are breathing in oxygen
and exhaling carbon dioxide with the
plant which is taking it in it's a
beautiful C cyclical and then if you
plant your mushrooms with uh micro isal
fungi then you just have this completely
living unbelievable medicine that will
it'll transform your life that this is
what we should do is try and challenge
each other to and it wouldn't fruit
maybe this year so that's a real thing
you know when you when you plug a tree
may or may not fruit but it might fruit
in the fall if we do it proper in the
spring you know and we've done that
before and why not take on a a higher
intelligence like I think that what we
continue to do is this circle game
almost like a durable inside of a cage
that we continue to look towards
government and individuals and humans
for better information like humans
evolve together we are all on this
incredible Collective Consciousness we
need to look towards other beings such
as plant medicines for us to evolve to
that next level we can't be looking
towards other humans we need to be you
know
evolving with the medicine that that are
here for us and I just love it that uh
you know the mycelium continues to pop
up in all little cities all over the
place and become decriminalized and and
and she's making her way you know the
Cannabis sort of opened the door uh for
all the rest of the plant medicines to
to walk through it and some cannabis
Farms are transforming just to
psilocybin production true in Oregon I
know this and also you can grow
mushrooms
do in a greenhouse right next to a
cannabis greenhouse and you can exchange
the air between the two greenh houses
you know and then you would have you
know and and science May someone's gonna
try and tell you it's bad but it's good
because SP go onto the tricomes someone
will prove that this is good and those
spores be on the tricomes as we consume
them and so it'll be more it'll be third
instead of secondary metabolize it'll be
like what's the third tertiary yeah that
tertiary
metabolites just and then it will go
into quads which goes back to what we
were originally talking about which is
really the go you know which which
is well the conversation take one
there's uh there's also the aspect I
have actually people send me stuff all
the time like samples and stuff of
things that they do and some of the most
interesting samples I have are people
who are micro doing decarbox cannabis
and mushrooms and
caps for for like a daily you know
booster um and uh yeah that's that's
that's what we do Allison so we've been
compounding mushrooms and cannabis oils
both THC CBD
CBG you know doing isolates full
spectrum all of it and you know for a
very long time you know realized that
you know the isolates were not helping
we already knew that as far as the the
the studies go but you you put it onto
patients no full spectrum full full soak
oil uh we do a a coconut olive oil and
like 17 different mushrooms and it seems
to just help people with everything why
not throw it out there we always give
people the recipes we tell people do it
yourself
here's these amazing plants that that
are showing themselves and and we're
becoming more educated from them so
let's let's make them in our own
kitchens let's let's heal each other so
possible yeah yeah I love it that you've
got somebody who's doing that as well
the more people who are compounding
these incredible intelligent uh plants
together and mushrooms are just going to
be helping us all out it just it just
helps raise us all up
it's pretty
cool pretty pretty
cool yeah I think a lot of people are
starting to take you know into account
the the power of what you know specific
tpin can do um in specific uh varietal
tpine um you know uh that you you know
you can really blend two different types
of experiences that um are quite
complimentary to one another and quite
really really beneficial to your every
day you know and it's really it's it's
interesting because we really are
starting to touch on a very large pallet
and it starts to get into this idea of
of biohacking and and better
understanding what you can do um for
yourself and being more self-sufficient
and better understanding your own body
um and then the energy that you can
connect to um by understanding these
compound BS together and that's
something that um it's really beautiful
to see you know everyone around us kind
of learning and wanting to learn um and
as you kind of Illustrated before Kelly
it's
it's it's so it's you know we have
abundance around us fine yeah they small
right it's really important that um you
know we we connect with these medicines
in a really responsible and really um
you know
a really a way that allows us to really
get in touch with with what's around
us come on your researchers on these CHP
Frontiers we need you yeah I mean I
think in terms of tpin there's a lot of
work that's being done I know you know
there's there's there's quite a few
people that are that are on the verge of
releasing a lot of different products
that incorporate I know teren mckennon's
been working on some stuff that that
incorporates terpenes um I think a lot
of people are really working on this you
know it's just a matter of time right
now and better understanding how we can
scale a lot of this stuff so it's it
it's available for everyone um cultivar
specific tpin are very hard to scale um
it's a it's you know the process in
which you need to go through to isolate
them you know your returns are just not
there yet um however you know there
there are the ways we can achieve what
we're trying to do and and the turpins
that are involved in in mushrooms you
know the the the TR Turpin and the tpin
S and the sesa tpin I always love to say
just just for fun because I came to this
on on a journey is that is you know when
if you take all the crayons and you melt
them all together they're always Brown I
always feel like
oh no broke up mushrooms breaking
up really think about that oh
no we're
uh sorry it's okay just said all the
Crayons yes all the Crayons Together
made Brown and yeah so when you and then
you you take all the Crayons you melt
them they make brown and then if you
take all the Tarpin in the world and you
melt them all together smells like
mushrooms so I feel like there's really
some awesome
um uh Horizons to expand on in tpine h
production uh in mushrooms I just sent
Marcus a h um article called TR uh
traversing the fungal
Tome I got it the tome
the
terpenome one of them their government
SS the fungal terpenome I want to
Traverse the fungal tome in fact that is
100% the name of the show by the way
traversing the fungal terpenome you just
named the show okay so that's the name
of it that's not even a joke that's
happening for
sure wow I just can't believe how great
that is it rolls off the tongue so
[Laughter]
eloquently [ __ ] I love you guys great we
got a lot of people in the chat room
listening and chatting away I don't know
how many of you guys are visiting the
chat room but uh there's a solid 400
plus people in there chatting away got a
couple of good conversations going on
it's a lot of the old
hardcores OG's go ahead when we Ally
with with
Fi we're we're creating a bridge we're
helping our own fungi and bacterial
microbiome have
communication uh back to our very DNA
how we are able to uptake these things
like I love the quote that we're
99.9% identical as far as our DNA and 99
.9% different as far as our
microbiome and I was reading last night
that we have
380 trillion viruses or pathogens living
in our body at all times it's called The
Vi the the vome just look up
vome online on the W on you know on then
you'll find
out yeah so so the the more that we can
Ally with these incredibly intelligent
beneficial
microbiology spores fungi it's going to
help us rise up and help create a higher
Consciousness like I was saying before
because because they're so easily
available for us to uptake they're just
right there and and and they communicate
with our interior microbiome so so
easily and our brain you know they say
you know trust your gut because your gut
maybe is more like your brain than your
brain because there's so many more
organisms and microorganisms and
thinking you know thinking and with your
receptors and your neurology so your
microbiome is and your nutrition and
your connection to soil is equally as
important as micro doing and as taking
cannabis to treat your ailment so
without the full picture of of nutrition
and Earth connection and schans
resonance and without these things that
connect us to the longevity of the earth
the earth is always going to be here we
in our smartness you know we may go away
very easy we always say we're trying to
save the Earth it's so funny like we're
trying to save ourselves people the
Earth is trying to save us and we really
need to listen because the Earth has the
answers the only
on and Detour really quickly that we're
talking about our own microbiome we also
need to talk about these cultivated
plant medicines microbiome the
endophytic system within the Cannabis
also the endophytic system within the
mushrooms the endic system within all of
the vines that we're taking and making
medicine out of we need these medicines
to be incredibly intelligent so we can
gather that information you know people
have bad trips on mushrooms not just
because they are um thought it a good
idea to go to the movies or you know had
a bad epigenetic situation but also they
took bad mushrooms the same as cannabis
we all know what it's like to take a
really big hit of some chemi weed it
just spins you it's horrible so it's not
just any mushroom is good for you or
any is good for you we need to really
your source and know your farmer ask
your farmer to rise above and create
intelligent medicine rise above yeah
rise up
Hi Rise
Up ca why
not yeah actually so go ahead into my
regimen actually it's it makes perfect
sense the conversation for even into the
organic
indoor uh I was taught how to make
melium Flats out west from soilscape
Solutions
friends and I've been using that for
yeah Sam and Natalie and I've been using
that method for probably seven plus
years in a row and I get great fungal
flat results on a pretty good Rhythm and
it really without being scientific about
it it opens up my tpin and my oils I get
great fraction on the test back we've
done and it seems like even back from
the extra actor friends like ancient
green for instance those friends that
were seeing better high quality results
out of it and full tarping profile and
just amazing results from the mushrooms
into the soil life for regenerative so
on r on repeat for
us that's what's
up that is what's up got to shout out my
six-year-old who I'm taking care of
today as my wife is off having a little
rest and relaxation he's been incredible
and has not bothered me a single time
just taking taking care of himself shut
I have the new Co Mouse for 2021 for all
you smokers so you got you got a hole
here so you can smoke your joint and
when you're finished I had these custom
made and uh there you
go this is the co M for
2021 was actually um
girlfriend's mother who came up with the
idea and um got to be safe out there for
2021 right you got still be able to puff
so this way you don't have to take off
your mask your
fatty or just go to a restaurant just go
to a restaurant because it doesn't
matter how many people are in the
restaurant you're just allowed to take
your mask off when you go in there there
you go but it was it was just the I had
42 delivered to the door so some people
are getting these in the mail as be your
20 21 present
nice yes that is hilarious DK trades
says that's hilarious John you make them
in big mouths for people like me well
actually the prototypes we can only put
pinners in there I'm like I need to be
able to put a joint in there so I should
what I said a big pen just give me a
like enough so I could put like a big
big pen in there and she laughed but
that's the size that you need take a
smokey fatty right oh my God that looks
like a sharpie yeah that's what that's
what worked
so because my first ones I had had
stains in the front because I was
smoking with it so she was laughing so
she came up with the idea of making us
yeah and there's different prototypes
but uh you know be inventive for 2021
whatever you're going to do and and
spread the word about cannabis and this
is I have a full bandana that I can go
into the bank with that has the whole
thing all right I have to ask Sam why is
your guy backwards is he okay is is Cat
in the Hat
okay now he's gone oh [ __ ] now I've done
it now you've done it
at no more oh oh he's got his mask on
he's got his mask on Oh my he he doesn't
want to get a computer
virus oh remember boys and girls it's
not a dad joke until it's full grown
so what's uh going on in Amsterdam there
Sam is the uh is covid ripping through
your friends and family or is it really
not that you don't see it too
much uh I I I saw it around and uh uh
but I think Amsterdam itself must be
getting worse because all the
restaurants are closed all the schools
are closed so yeah it's not doing so
right I I have a question about Spectrum
it it's always like the holy gray full
spectrum but uh I mean I always thought
that for smoking anyway what you want is
THC you don't really want the other
conoids you may want particular Turpin
that you enjoy whether it's a mirene for
Punch or loline for up but uh I I I
always always hear about full spectrum
like it's the Holy Grail but it's I I
just don't see it for for recreational
use I really don't see it well because
your Holy Grail is
THC with lots of turps so the thing
about cannabis is that everyone has a
different Holy Grail and I also will say
that when I heard that I also thought I
always think this when I hear people say
oh you know iets are no good I think
okay just a second time out um what
about uh you know someone like Haley
Rose who has this you know neurological
disorder super sensitive they created
the Haley's Comet for high CBD had
certain ratios I'm sure John could go on
for hours about it because he has a
close relationship with them but what
happened was it worked it worked it
worked it didn't work it didn't work
anymore like whatever happened something
happened in the terar something happened
in the grow something happened in the
genetics where things just changed a
little bit
produced different things and now all of
a sudden it wasn't working anymore so I
always thought that a value would be
like listen obviously want we want to
take the whole plant apart so we we can
actually decipher through our own
bioassays what it is that's happening is
this you know this full spectrum versus
microns of hash versus certain ones put
together with other tpin from different
just let's do it all let's dive into
this as deep as we possibly can and
uncover all these complexities so that
we can a which we always all at least
claim that the patients are the most
important we can send that data over to
patients and be like look if you're
someone like Haley and you require a
company to monomolecular eyesee and
isolate every compound so they can build
it back to something that they' are
copying from a full spectrum state of
perspective like a of a of a plant
they've done the full lab test now
they're going to take all their monom
moleculars and tpine fractions and
they're going to put that back together
the best that they can to the point
where it never changes so that someone
with a neurological disorder or maybe
even someone like Colton who has super
sensitivities in in the intestinal
region any little amount of anything
that's off he's going to feel that like
strong so there value of monomolecular
there's the and there's also the value
that we can take it all apart do I mean
the first time Sam put a bowl of pure
THC in my bullshire I thought it was
neat I smoked it but then you know was
all ready to be excited about it and he
was like well how was it how was it how
was it right just right in your face
super excited like well I guess in a
sense it was a little one-dimensional
and then hitting it with that one single
tpine that wasn't even cannabis derived
just to experience that sort of whoa
this is different to me it's all
valuable we should never get caught up
in our divisions of course the Holy
Grail is everything it's all whatever
perspective you're going down that can
be your Holy Grail and all facilitate
you getting as far down that road as
possible but let's not [ __ ] on all the
other roads because there's so many of
them so Sam we know what your road is we
appreciate your road many of us have
traveled your road thanks to you
pioneering and breaking ground and
putting that road in for many of us so
huge thanks for that but also thanks to
people like Colton who are discovering
New Roads for for for different people
uh in different times in different
experiences so that's how we have we
have discovered that roads is definitely
the best uh analogy to go there because
we always say that you know a person's
canab endocannabinoid system is like a
road and every road has potholes in it
so you have to figure out you know what
you need to fill those potholes make
sure that you don't you know if you add
too much then it gets the row gets bumpy
you don't get enough you don't fill
those potholes uh but we discovered that
you know there are you know can there
are canabo that I can't have so there's
this cannabinoid called
thcv uh which is an appetite suppressant
so first off Whoever thought of weed
that didn't give you the munchies uh
that that you know when we first figured
that out that blew my mind uh but it's
an appetite suppressant so for people
with diabetes who just want to lose
weight and I also hear that it's working
really well for people with uh
post-traumatic stress disorder uh
they're using it with great success but
it's an heti suppressant so someone like
me who has a wasting syndrome uh I can't
have thcb so there are you know
cannabinoids that people you know should
be looking at and analyzing and deciding
you know is this what's best for me uh
because there are you know some canapino
that people either can't handle or can't
have and we need to know that
information as patients because if we're
taking this as a medicine we need to
know what everything that we're putting
into our bodies is doing to our bodies
we need that information we need to know
that I absolutely agree with you and uh
I I it would I want to empower you to
the most degree to get the combination
or turpine or or cannaboid that benefits
you and none of the ones that
don't exactly right and I and I think
that that that's what our trial and
error has been through this whole
journey is that you know we we were the
full spectrum family we we got into
cannabis and everybody was say full
spectrum full spectrum full spectrum and
we love that um you know CBG has done a
lot of good for a lot of people in CBN
and we we understand that situation but
we also understand it as a medicine too
and that specific combinations or
specific turpins or specific canabo um
do have do set harm to other people um
and we we discovered that on accident um
by colson's um medicine and you know
getting a strain to to for for him that
had a lot of thcv in it which cannabis
doesn't have a lot of thtv in it but
this is this this was one strain and I
and I can't remember what it was um
African it might have been I have no
idea I mean we what happened
it may have been it we we just know that
whatever what the difference in the
medicine that he was taking was
thcv and that was it and we we noticed
that when we gave him Vapes that had
thcv in it that he would start losing
weight and he lost it rapidly um and
that was one of the scariest things for
me is because trying to get him to 100
pounds is difficult uh trying to
maintain that is even worse well it was
difficult now I'm 115 yeah um because we
figured that kind of stuff out um and we
we've tried to avoid thcv at all costs
um because for like for him it doesn't
work now like he said for people with
diabetes it's excellent um I would love
for somebody to just make a pill that
was thcv for weight loss I mean that
whoever does that is going to be a
billionaire um they're working on it
good good good send me some send me
some but you
know I think the Frankenstein I think
frankensteining it sometimes we we have
to understand that um it's okay to do
because we do have to we have certain
patients that need certain things and
then we also want to have other canono
involved in and tping involved um and
flavonoids we we want everything but we
want specific too um so I think that
there is a a place for
everyone and if you're taking the I if
you're taking the
FL you'll get if if you're smoking the
flavonoids you're de you're deactivating
them a short note that's all excuse
me I just wanted to say that I think all
of these points are really important and
what's happen happening is we're missing
an incredible
bridge and that's allowing the plant and
the cultivator to have those
conversations for the greater people we
we I I feel like when science continues
to and this is just like a side of it
you know we we we have all different
things and I respect everybody in the
conversation for sure but I got to stick
up for the plant here in that she has
these capabili when we talk about full
spectrum we're talking about that full
plant what that full plant has to offer
and we've learned and you all have
learned that thcv is not good for Colton
well that's really easy to get a
varietal that doesn't have thcv it's
really easy to get a varietal that
doesn't have the CBG it's easy to get a
varietal that does that has exactly the
tpine ratios everything that you're
looking for and and and then we have the
plant grow it and by saying that we
synthesize it and take this tpine and
that tpine and we mix it together and
we're humans and we're scientists and
we're going to do it better than the
plant can I just really feel like we're
missing something very important here
that of course we need science to say
yeah this chirine is good this canaban
oid was helpful this wasn't but let's
allow the plant to create create the
medicine for the people rather than
science Laboratories creating it let's
get that beautiful connection to the
Growers and to the the strains that you
need colon that can be grown
regeneratively that can be done well
it's the problem is is that you're in
Illinois and there's still all this sort
of you know heavy duty oppression on the
plant that needs to be lifted we need to
allow the plant to do what she does and
stop outsmarting her and ourselves and
thinking that we're going to do a better
job that's all I'm saying and I'm
sticking up for the plant in in in that
way so when we talk about full spectrum
we're talking about the fullness of that
particular plant we're using that whole
plant that whole
varietal and we agree with that uh and
we we think that a whole plant a whole
spectrum is is very beneficial for so
many people um but we also see the other
side of it you know we if we could find
a plant that would be great for Colton
um and we we wouldn't have to take it
apart and we wouldn't have to figure out
what chirpin or what uh Cano work and
what they what don't in his body um and
that's the only thing that that we grew
for his medicine uh for people with
crohn's disease then that would be so
amazing but there but like you said
everybody's different everybody is
different um and they have their own
potholes and you know we have to learn
how to film uh cannabis I I I I've taken
cannabis a million times and I don't see
the benefits in me that I see in him
because it just doesn't work as well for
me for whatever I mean I'm I'm a pretty
healthy person so I don't really have a
whole lot going on um but you know we
everybody is so different and I wish
that we could just figure
out like you know like Tylenol I mean
and I and I know that this is like
insane but you take 500 milligrams of
Tylenol and your headache goes away um
for most people but with this plant it's
just not that way and it there's just so
many varieties and so many things that
you can do with it and it's just there's
we're we're just at the cusp of of
learning everything that this plant can
do and and what is in it you know we
still probably have not discovered
cannaboids that that is in this plant
and what they what their powers are well
you just you're you're mentioning how
important the human element is in all of
this that the plant's not going to do
everything for us that we are a major
factor even in growing it because if
we're growing it with salts and we're
not putting in that energy yeah there's
there's a way to think that as a human
you can do better and you start growing
organically and regeneratively and
that's actually better and that was the
human factor So when you say oh humans
think they're going to take this plant
and do better well that's actually what
we're all kind of doing with it at all
times so who's to draw the line where
that should stop you know all I know is
the plants aren't all available at this
point in time and I hate when I see
small children with neurological
disorders where cannabis help them one
grow and then then two grows down the
line it's not helping them the same
cultivar anymore because something
changed something the room got too hot
something happen so you know I do see a
value in all of it I certainly wouldn't
pick one over the other I just think
that we're so divided by as humans we
constantly have to put up a fence and
say no the grass is greener over here or
you know no it's actually Greener Over
Here I just rip that fence down stand on
the edge and just say look let's be
accepting of all of these different
potential
as long as they're based in love and
based in trying to help and based in
positivity and great you know a greater
you know outcome for the human race
where I'm not talking about becoming
some evil corporate entity that uh holds
these Powers over the rest of the world
gets rid of all plant medicines grow you
know and I wasn't also even talking
about you know synthesizing as much as
isolating and then re and then
restructuring that's really kind of what
I was
mentioning but I do appreciate your
passion and uh did very much hear what
you had to say one thing I thought what
was interesting is is uh Kelly brought
up the idea of of a term we use you like
like we use broadspectrum and tfree and
and these terms that are so um full
spectrum what what does full spectrum
mean what types of tpes what types of
cannabinoids are there you know I do
think that it needs to be further
divided defined and further explored and
we need to better understand uh our
varietals and and how they're grown and
what regions they're grown in um it it's
going to really help us better
understand what the chemicals that the
plant's producing are um you know what
it consistently can produce and what
those anomalies are um you know I've
seen in different conditions spikes in
thca that in Delta 9 that that are
abnormal um you know and it when it gets
to cooler temperatures and different
feeding schedules you see lower overall
Tack and all this stuff really
attributes to not only the environmental
factors but also the feeding what you're
giving the RIS of spere what type of
inoculant are available what type of
cover crop is even there to even
sequester what you're trying to
sequester and then providing the
environment for it to actually sequester
because that's a whole other topic in
itself and you know it really is
important for us to have this this
dialogue and I do appreciate that point
of view and it's it's uh it's something
we need to talk more about because full
spectrum is varietal specific it's why
we name these things we humanize it we
get closer to trying to grab onto it
with our human hands and and better
understand it by naming them and using
naming notes and glimmers and things
like that but yeah it's it's it's super
important because the dialogue is all we
have um and it allows us to kind of
expand upon one another's thought
processes and and processes as well um
how you do everything I
agree there is no ra rather than
seeing sorry go ahead Sam oh I was just
going to say there is no true full
spectrum in the sense that there is no
one variety of cannabis that has all 150
of the tpin and all uh 120 or whatever
it is of the cannaboids it just doesn't
get in the way words just get in the way
because as soon as you start as soon as
you start using the word you start going
all over the place with with with the
word I think it should be full spectrum
like the whole plant you're using that
whole plant most of the leading
herbalists that use herbs and things
with patients on The Daily for
Generations both believe that not
cannabis is not the only answer towards
full health and transformation cannabis
is one thing that a person would use to
transform their health and often
compounding cannabis with other herbs is
the actual you know healing that's
needed so then you're just now your full
spectrum is including other plants so I
think the idea is that diversity is is
what we're missing and and if you look
at a person who's really sick a lot of
times if you dissect their microbiome
they have less living organisms in their
gut enabling them to transform their
nutrients and Medicine sure it's pretty
easy so you just got to say oh I need to
up my diversity how do I do that any
person has their own reality and their
own world and their own things that are
available to them it's just a goal when
you learn things and that's what science
is good for they teach us some things
and then you just learn through
intuition to go further so diversity is
the key to our survival and Longevity
and also oh you go ahead go ahead go
ahead well and you were saying that you
know we have different sides of things I
don't know if it's really different
sides as much as it is it's holistic
what we need is we need more
conversations more of holistic views
we're always taught that there's this
side or there's that side or that this
thing needs to be an opposition with
this thing I think that now that we've
noticed so much diversity and
divisiveness not diversity as far as
like diverse but you know being diverse
and divisive and being separated I think
that we need to realize that there's all
these beautiful conversations that bring
in a wholeistic value it's good this is
just good conversation and to accept all
all the different values and realize
that they're all there because we're all
invited this is our table we're bringing
everything and putting it to the table
hi perspectives perspectives would be
the term more than size they're all
perspect perspectives this convers learn
a little bit warm
fuzzies nice love you Alice to to see
you yeah and I love I love everyone's uh
dialogue that they bring to it it's so
um expansive in everyone's front
everyone has a very unique understanding
of their disciplines that they've been
studying respectively and that's that's
um that's the beauty in of of it all
it's just
it's it's just soaking in you
know y straight up cannabis Community
that's why we love it so much
right it's a growing Community now it's
a changing Community for a long time we
sort of you know almost held the keys to
the gate and that those Gates have been
blown off and the Community has expanded
and it's over here and over there and
it's it's you know it's been some years
of the Cannabis core Community getting
used to you know okay well look we want
it to be included we want it to be
included we want it to be included then
all of a sudden they included us and
everyone started criticizing everything
about how it you know which is natural
you know you're kind of trying to steer
this thing or feel that you're steering
a thing but I really do welcome the rest
of the world I welcome so many people to
cannabis and how how they are all
finding like we mentioned with Colton
earlier like different Pathways
different roadways and more importantly
sharing those ways with us so that we
can see all the incredible uh beneficial
ways that um that you can use this plant
and there's 50,000 commercial purposes
this plant can be used for there's you
know plexiglass and metals there's you
know essential amino acid Rich seed oils
and it's really quite something when you
when you start to break it down I'm
certain if it was discovered tomorrow
for the first time in the history of
mankind it would be one of the greatest
discoveries ever
made I know you're welcoming everyone
but I can't hear you a oh can you hear
me
now y can't hear you now yes yes I can
hear you you guys hear him you okay then
it's me yeah I was about to say uh now
that you're welcoming everybody in just
beware there's a lot of [ __ ] sharks
everywhere so watch out there's a lot of
sharks [ __ ] teeth and they bite and
they take a lot of Flesh so uh be
careful out
there yes a lot of people are in the
industry for all the wrong reasons but a
lot of the people that most people I
know are in it for all the right reasons
and those are the people that people are
listening to and paying attention to so
you don't see um the [ __ ] with all
the followers or all the people getting
involved we have we have a job in a
sense and we have a journey and I think
it's a journey we all follow which is
just spreading the knowledge and
education on how
cannabis it's it's it's saved my life
it's it's I love preaching about it and
talking about it every day wherever I go
it's kind of like have you done a bong
rip what's wrong like it's important to
just keep sharing that knowledge and how
it helps you my battery is
low yeah and it's really
my bad uh it's it's really important to
make sure that patients are protected
and that you know uh because this whole
industry is centered around the patient
the patients are really the ones that
need to be taken care of the most almost
you know as much if not more than the
plant itself uh you know there are
plenty of patients out there who I'm
sure are getting taking taken advantage
because the people that they're getting
their medicine from basically have a
monopoly on their life because you know
say you go to one grower and it's the
only for one reason or the other it's
the only cannabis that works for you
then you're stuck going to that one one
grower or that one company or wherever
it is you're going to and they can
basically dictate however it is they
want to give you your medicine or
whatever they want to do with their
medicine they will so a lot of patients
right so you know a lot of patients need
to have protections like that you know
to make sure that their medicine isn't
going to be you know tampered with that
it's going to be coming in consistently
effectively and safely that we know
everything that's going into this
medicine because and that's the Gap
medicine's a human right that's the Gap
that we're having we're having even you
as a patient having direct contact with
the plant you know you being able to
have this this incredible relationship
with the plant because nobody can make
medicine for you better than you I think
anyone who's a cultivator anyone who
understands this plant understands that
anyone you know and and that's the
problem it's all this politics and all
this this oppression on this plant
that's getting in the way from us to be
able to have this direct good connection
with the plant and I I love it that you
said that Colton because you're
absolutely right the plant is here for
the patient number one the plant's
number one goal is to heal humanity and
so that's what that's what she wants to
do is is to have that direct connection
with patients and and it continues to
get in the way and these conversations
that we're having that are very holistic
in nature allows that energy to go out
so that the plant can can make its way
into regular Society so that everybody
can have that direct relationship and it
is why we created the pure certification
to Ally and bring Farms together for the
betterment of humanity to create safe
medicine that's alive and living along
with our own bodies and biomes and
patients can have direct contact with
with uh cultivators and these medicine
makers have been like having to survive
so they're creating medicine that
survives too so now we're all adapting
and adapted genic medicine you know for
the masses we hope that you can get what
you need and there's so many cultivators
that want nothing more than to be
cultivating medicine directly for
patients that's their number one goal in
focus and they feel incredibly
frustrated just like you that they can't
get it to you that's their number one
the biggest problem that's me over here
access ATN number one he's been he's
been you
know walking his talk for forever is
whole adult life of patient access how
do we get the plant to the people and
the people to the plant and this is this
is what we're all trying to break down
those barriers go and that all that red
tape is just it it's just strangling us
as patients and and we we don't want
that we would love to be able to grow um
but one of the things one of the reasons
why we don't grow and somebody on this
panel needs to get this done is that we
we do want testing we want to make sure
that what what we're growing isn't full
of of Miracle Grow here in Illinois I
mean we're monsan Haven um but we we
need that so we we always depend on a
cultivator and a grower of of with a
company because at least we're getting
tested medicine um home testing is is
very very difficult um and but but we
need to know how many canono Colton is
getting in his body how many flavonoids
are not not really flavenoids but tpin
and and if there's any microbials and is
there mold in it because you you trust
me to grow his medicine and it's gonna
get [ __ ] I mean it he it's it's bad um
but I I think that we need to have those
types of small little entities that that
help the the novice grower Empower
themselves to grow their own medicine um
and with without that without those
little home testing kits that we can
test you know we we get afraid that
we're not getting the right canabo in
his into his system um so there's just
there's just so many aspects of of Home
grow and and Commercial grow and and
everything and all the red tape that
just strangles us as patients and it's
just it's disheartening it's so sad
we're we're all I think it's the the
term is we're all
learning we're all learning every
State's learning every state is learning
from each other every bill is different
and they're all reminiscent of some Bill
that they heard about once and you know
that's that's that becomes the problem
but it also becomes the path forward and
how we shape that and and it's you know
it's something that is important to to
know is that someone like myself that's
in a regulated State I work really hard
to make sure that I have induction seals
and things that keep this stuff fresh
because I know how long it takes to even
get to a patient and it just Bo that
alone boggles my mind because coming
from the traditional sense it was
immediate it just you didn't have these
you never had these hurdles before so
it's you know the responsibility is is
massive and then the
testing you know that that's super
important like you said you can't you
can't be ingesting mold you're create
you're you're trying to solve from one
problem and creating a new one and
that's just you know it's important to
have access to Labs even for yourself
and I think yeah hom grower should have
access to all this stuff I you know it
just gives us better insight as to what
we're doing and how we can do it um you
know and it's it would you know it just
helps us further along what we're
actually after which is better
understanding the things that we just
don't understand and I'm going to chime
in here it requires due diligence
right now in Utah they're trying to pull
PTSD off of a conditions for medical
marijuana so uh as forward as we are
moving there are still people trying to
pull things back so remember interal
vigilance is the price of Liberty ladies
and gentlemen and your brothers and
sisters in Utah need your help so you
know find a local organizations National
organizations chime in but you know it's
a new year but the struggle it's the
same unfortunately for some people and
um what you were also talking about uh
Wendy is you know growing cannabis can
be easy but growing medical grade
cannabis consistently is an art and
that's a challenge and that's a thing
that uh one of the things when I was a
buyer that I used to do is you know a
plant can tell you exactly if you've
grown it enough times you can look at a
plant and tell exactly what's gone on
and really freak out the grower it's
really kind of fun um because they're
like how the hell did you get in my
growroom but the plant tells you
everything so uh having educated people
who can give you good information around
cannabis is always challenging because
every grower I know grows
different everyone I know you know
everybody here is nodding because you
know everybody thinks they know how to
grow it or this way etc etc so it's also
challenging to educate people how to
grow properly when every everybody grows
in different ways and paths and
pathologies so depending if it's
Hydroponics if it's inso if it's indoor
if it's outdoors you've got different
functions and different religions to
each specific ones depending on what you
have and have access to so it's also
what you can afford what you have access
to and yes there needs to be Regional
players who could come in and educate or
there be Regional places where people
could go and learn how to grow and
educate themselves like what positronics
used to do you know they would propagate
clones that'd be mothers there so you
could come in and then grow your plant
if you need to in a communal environment
so you could learn and teach at the same
time but of course that was decades ago
and Amsterdam and a galaxy far far away
but it's still applicable today is
community growing so that you can learn
proper techniques so you can arrive at
the techniques that will most benefit
you so that
Colton can get a better quality of
cannabis from you than you had
previously green thumbs aren't natural
they're learned oh yeah I do not have a
green thumb and one of the things that
we are learning is that you know we we
moved from Illinois to Colorado um for
access to cannabis and the legislative
system there was you know they they
tried and tried and tried to to to pull
it back but then we moved back from from
Colorado to Illinois and
the
ecosystem here is different uh so when
you have blue dream in Colorado it's
it's a different it's a different style
than it is here in Illinois because
there's different growing techniques and
and situations it's very it's very humid
here it's very dry in Colorado so when
you have a Colorado grower to come in
and grow your medicine in Illinois
they're they're running into a lot of
situations that that they don't
understand because they've never grown
in Illinois we have rich soil here here
um we have a lot of moisture in our air
um so the it it's just it's been so
every region is so different um so
making sure that we have medicine across
the the United States uh anywhere Colton
decides to go that is consistent has
been very very difficult to
find yes no one has pulled the ray Croc
model where you get your same big Big
Mac here
as you get in St Louis that's still
always been a frustration and our 21
years of providing genetics is you know
people want what we had last year or the
year before they didn't keep or
maintain um and that's also challenging
because you know people grow differently
and you know you can get a different uh
yield in the lower areas of the Bay Area
than you can in certain other bay areas
of the Bay Area because there's so many
microclimates there's literally more
microclimates here in the Bay Area than
some places in the world so it becomes
challenging just here in an area in a
region as well it becomes challenging
for consistency and maintaining or
getting consistent access from my
patients perspective is a frustration
because also having stability of access
to the genetics so that when somebody
says this is a blue dream it is actually
a blue dream but not something else
masquerading as a Blue Dream which is I
think one of the bigger frustration a
lot of us have found especially having
to forge in the traditional Market much
less even in the legal Market because
consistency of genetics to have the same
Big Mac every single day I still can't
do after 21 years right and I think that
the only way that we can actually help
that progression along is interstate
commerce you know if we can have you
grow the same exact medicine for Colton
and be able to send it across the state
lines then then we wouldn't have this
issue um so that's one of the big things
that we will be pushing this year um is
interstate commerce um because like you
said there's so many different regions
and you know the way you grow may be
completely different the the way you
grow grow blue dream may be completely
different than what's being the way you
grow blue dream in Illinois um but yet
the blue dream that you grow in in your
area is what we like the best um so we
should definitely be pushing interstate
commerce um and reciprocity and you know
just making sure that it's it it's
available and accessible across state
lines and and across country lines I
mean we have a ton of people you know
here in Canada
and we we want to be able to access
Canadian medicines you know because
we're the United States and our our
infrastructure kind of sucks um but you
know if you grow the best I want the
best for my kid and I want to be able to
access it without having to move where
you are right and I love the idea of
expanding that even greater bring it to
you across the world the globe you know
imagine crying sorry
sorry sorry sorry go Marcus go Marcus
please um I was just saying that it
would be neat to do that on a world
scale like have international Commerce
where you know people who grow cannabis
and extracts in different parts of the
world all over every country being able
to move those to different countries and
to find certain things and have
discoveries as to you know we speak
about the importance of Terr well if
Terr is important then it's likely with
cannabis that certain things will
Express themselves you know more
uniquely or whatever terminology you
want to use you you'll see some unique
expressions from Cannabis depending on
where you grow it and at what time of
year that you grow it and I love the
idea of Interstate travel with for
cannabis and being able to do Commerce
but I really love the idea of being able
to send stuff from like Colombia to you
know Illinois or to be for you guys to
be able to access stuff from everywhere
in the world and we would love to have
things from Colombia or or Venezuela or
wherever I mean just think of the
ability to try different areas and
different regions of the world um that's
more realistic now more than ever great
to be able to give you this nearly clear
rosin it's ridiculous the Reas i' love
to have your nearly clear rosin uh
Michael krowitz and the group uh down at
the un
unfortunately changed international law
over the holidays they actually got uh
cannabis pulled out of schedule four so
actually medical marijuana now exists in
the [ __ ] world for the first time the
DEA is still not responded to it in
December but this now opens up Things N
uh uh internationally on top of that hey
Georgia we're looking at you if the
state of Georgia passes and gets both
these Democrats elected then you're
going to see a more act and you will see
interstate commerce open up within uh
the year here in the United States but
if it doesn't then it's going to be
fought all the way through but a lot of
changes a lot of places you can plug in
to make a lot of change happening not
only internationally because of medical
marijuana now being internationally
recognized by the UN and the World
Health
Organization I want to be able to import
Canadian cannabis and we want to be able
to export our California Cannabis as
well uh so we could have genetics
exchange all that fun stuff so I think
2021 and in the future it's a lot of
stuff's opening up but definitely
interstate commerce domestically could
potentially happen soon awesome and
hopefully we'll continue to push that
that education forward and that
conversation forward because just like
you all are looking for for the right
medicine we as cultivators want nothing
more than to find the right patients so
when CBD is opened up and we we are
doing our m canic
I have direct contact with all of my
patients you know or you know I'm able
to talk to them on a human level what's
going on what's happening it's all freed
up it's direct it's from the grower the
manufacturer the maker directly to the
patients so we can have these
conversations so in my garden I could
have okay these three plants I'm growing
for Colton not only am I growing them
for the the varietal that he wants but
I'm thinking about him as I'm growing
them and I'm growing enough for him to
have for an entire year that he's not
going to run out that he's not
continually looking for something so I
want to continue pushing that
conversation forward too that the
cultivators are having direct com
conversation and communication and
education with the patients worldwide I
I would just like to also say like often
cannabis is fumigated when you bring it
from another country which
completely is goes counterintuitive to
everything that you've done to put into
the medicine so let's keep cannabis from
being
fumigated and keep it medicine let's
keep cannabis sacred and keep cannabis
as medicine so as we're fighting for
this
International you know Marketplace let's
like be aware that a lot of herbs and
Foods get fumigated with chemicals when
they enter the
of a new country and Alice probably has
something to say about International and
Alice it's nice to see you what's going
on girlfriend nice to see you all too I
said to Marcus sorry I came in late but
my cat dropped all my transplant so I
had to fix
it and um I was actually wanting to
bring up something too because um every
time I come here most of the people that
are here are either North Americans
right are either from United States or
from Canada and I love to come here and
listen to all the conversation
and but I feel that you are all so many
steps ahead than we are in Brazil even
though I live in California now that I
just love to come here learn everything
sometimes I even take notes so I can
just like rethink on how this could be
applied South American perspective and a
few things that you brought up today
that I really loved is this that you
were talking about the education and the
fact that the person that grows can also
have a connection with the with the
patient and now in Brazil they're trying
to pass a b that only the government and
importations would be ready to would be
um possible to produce cannabis somehow
or like deliver cannabis to patients and
no hom growing at all so no one can have
the connection with the medicine itself
or grow from their for for themselves
and I see how this is how this just
takes the full on power autonomy of the
patient I I talk like I mean I'm a
cannabis patient too but I I balance in
between being a patient because of my
chronic pain and also being someone that
uses like that likes dab that likes high
THC content things different tping
profiles and trying to balance that
thing and it's just so hard when we
think of it for someone from South
America in a reality like this and uh I
just love to come here and just learn
everything and uh try to try to engage
and uh translate this knowledge for the
people down there with the possibilities
there are you know the possibilities
that I offer down there so thank you so
much for all the for for all the I'm
just listening today I'm just like
almost taking notes
Here well we're happy to have you Alice
I was kind of sad when I didn't see a
few key folks Dr Mark never made it
today we hope and wish him a happy New
Year and that everything's okay with him
because I know he had planned on making
it but uh he had a birthday too is that
what yeah he did didn't he he just had a
birthday an earth strong for Dr Mark yes
hashy believe Mark also lives in an area
that used to be the mushroom capital of
the of the world and I want I was hoping
he would be in today so we could talk a
little bit about Kenneth Square and see
if that has any
Roots uh in the world uh at large uh you
know what's happening it'll have to wait
till next week I
suppose can I bring up one subject since
I I arrived here late and I said like
last but it's just that now I'm stoned
and tripping and uh I just uh something
crossed my mind which is H uh we were
talking about education and cannabis
right and we recognize cannabis as this
moderate plant and this very medical
plan too but a lot of people and I think
that all of us are aware of that do not
use the plant medically they create
different patterns they create uh
different relationships with the plant
that sometimes their be their actions
their uh their daily tests their
behavior Behavior towards the plant does
not create a healthy setting or a
healthy environment for the people and
uh that's something that I almost don't
hear about here in United States I feel
like in Brazil when we're engaging
content about cannabis and things like
this we always try to bring up this
perspective to which is almost harm
reduction right coming with the good
things and the bad things and how to
balance them and I would like to hear
all from all of you something that it's
hard for us to hear I would like for you
all to tell me something negative ative
about cannabis and because I think that
that's a thing that engages in the
education you know in balancing harms
and risks and I wanted to talk about
this with you all because uh two months
ago we made a post on girls in green and
a Content based on the that we have to
talk about the negative effects of
cannabis and it was the thing that most
engaged lately because that's something
that few people were talking about and I
just wanted to bring it up here for a
discussion too if it possible I have a
great idea
go ahead Wendy um so I I was the DAR mom
you know we we established that earlier
um
but there when it came to Colton being
um being a patient of Crohn's and on
pharmaceutical medicines I saw more harm
on Pharmaceuticals than I have on
cannabis H not to say that there isn't
any type of harm but I haven't found any
and I I
just I think it's a mindset I think that
because we
have villainized this plant for so long
that people push off a lot of negativity
towards a person that does use cannabis
um there's there's a Facebook group it's
called parents opposed to pot and they
are just they just push the negativity
so bad when as a parent with a kid that
was 13 when he started using cannabis
which I never thought in a million years
that I would do um I just don't see a
whole lot of negative other
than the mentality of other people that
are against it still so if we can if we
can educate every one about the benefits
of it I think that you would see less
harm um
than than using the plant um I think
that that's I think the negative you
know stigma of it is is really what
makes it worse and I think that you know
with everybody who has tried cannabis
you know there hasn't really been
anybody that had a you know a bad effect
from it as far as you know somebody you
know getting sick from it as in you know
not gonna get cancer you're not gonna
get cancer or anything from it obviously
there are some canabo that have some
effects that you don't want to have like
I can't have thcv it's an appetite
suppressant you know I would lose a lot
of weight that you know not good for
someone with a wasting syndrome but it's
not to say that thcv is bad it's not bad
it's doing exactly what it's designed to
do which is to suppress your appetite
but there are obviously you know some
people that should back off from that
conoid go to other cannaboids instead
and I think everybody can have a bad
trip and and like like dragonfly was
saying earlier they they you you have to
have good medicine you can't have all of
these chemicals you can't have all of
these things and I think that with
education and good growing habits and
less Monopoly when it comes to these
huge companies that want to just take
over and make billions and billions of
dollars I think that that's where we
need to start is making sure that people
are Ed at understand that yeah you know
if you have a bad trip it could have
been because they're using monsano
pesticides and in your in your medicine
um and that it wasn't just a it could
have just been a fluke that we have an
endoc canab cannabinoid system and that
we need to nourish it and we need to
keep it saturated um but I think that it
is it is all encompassing of Education I
think so too and I just wanted to bring
up one thing that it's a different
perspective to you coling to like when
you're in South America or in Brazil no
one knows which cannaboid they're
consuming they're buying bre and that's
something that I like to bring up here
because it's such a different
perspective when I when I asked about
the negative effects of cannabis is the
negative effects of cannabis and
prohibitionist itself too that in a non-
legalized uh setting we have all these
other layers that doesn't have a market
there no no testings at all you brought
the testing so much today how this is
important for a medical patient and over
there people medicate themselves with
whatever weed they can find because they
recognize weed as something medical so
they are doing uh can of butter out of
brick weed with a lot of like chemicals
on it and they're giving the cookies to
their trying to give the cookies to
their grandma and sometimes it's not
exactly positive for them so I believe
in you with the education right it's
that it's the tool for so people can
balance if it's good or bad for them uh
I I I would add that and I wouldn't say
it's necessarily bad but I would say
that for certain mental health
afflictions here in North America at
least I've seen cannabis not be helpful
and what I mean with by that is like how
we even deal with mental health in the
first place and how it's so just swept
under the rug and no one it's fine if
you have a big tumor growing on your
neck people will feel bad for you and
they'll care for you but if you have
something twisting in your mind that
you're having difficulties with people
don't really have as much patience for
that stuff they get scared for their own
well-being with certain mental health
afflictions and it's really you know
it's that is the major problem that
we're not you know this missing
psychedelic component for taking care of
people and and care you know like I
think it was
um you know it was one of the guys that
dragonfly Earth medicine had on who I
guess he takes people through
psychedelic Journeys and he was really
interesting he was talking about the
importance of bringing people back to
their moments of trauma holding them you
know in in your arms while they're in
that moment of whatever their trauma is
you could be a little baby that was
getting left in the room because some
book said it was a good idea to make
your baby sleep away from you for the
first like f the first night of its life
it's like what a crazy crazy thing to
convince mothers of but it it happens
and so you know there's all of these
different things with mental health that
we've got these major problems and I
think if we can take care of that with
the missing component that is
psychedelic plant medicines and fungi
that we'll see maybe less of it but I
have seen some people who have used
cannabis almost in an addictive way
smoking it like crazy amounts throughout
the day and just and and you can see
that it it it wasn't being helpful I had
a roommate who actually had to stop
eventually because it was it was really
just it was too much for him especially
the way he was uh using it and I felt
that from that relationship I've learned
that because I use it in such I am an
anomaly to a lot of people that in the
amounts that I use it maybe not to you
people here on this particular panel but
to a lot of people they'll get together
with me and I'll always say listen like
you don't have to keep up this isn't a
keeping up thing like I don't want you
to uh you know to feel that every time I
have a little dab that you also should
have a little dab and uh you know that
relationship with my old roommate really
taught me that that you know be aware
that everyone's going through different
things and that uh you know everyone has
different capabilities so that's what I
would say about that
Alice uh I I will speak on two one I
will speak directly to what you spoke
toward Marcus because there studies that
have shown that people who do have
multiple personality disorders or
schizophrenia it does allow using of
cannabis allows them to slip more
lucidly in between uh their
personalities I've seen VA studies
regarding this
specific and a newer more interesting
one that is somewhat controversial which
is cannaboid
hyperemesis syndrome which causes
chronic nausea uh I had a friend of mine
uh daughter uh she was 16 and using
cannabis she got there on the islands in
Hawaii and just
became chronically nauseous
every time she became she smoked
cannabis to the point where she had to
go to the uh hospital um so uh people
are finding that um and a small
percentage of the community are finding
that you know cannabis does not work for
them some people are allergic and this
most recent one um I would ask Dr Dron
are you familiar with the uh canono
hyperemisis syndrome yeah I am it's
interesting though it seems at least at
least in some of the patients that I
work with it seems to be
THC that causes it more so than CBD and
so some of our oncology patients will
switch them when they have these re the
kind of uh type of reactions to
cannabis we will switch them to like a
CBD and they don't seem to have the same
kind of like nausea uh physical pain
that the hyper mesis um seems to bring
with high
THC I've also read a a study that it had
a lot some of it could have had to do
with neem oil and I don't I don't know
about that um but there I've heard I've
heard that theory come up I've heard
that theory too but no confirmation just
to science to back that up it's all hear
saiying conjecture at this time if
there's a study that backs it up I'll be
happy to cite it Alice you have well
I've been doing a a bunch of study you
know research and and looking up on
hyper mesis syndrome and and what we're
also finding is that it's sort of
becoming um an overlay maybe like a a
whitewash if you will sort of like
fibromyalgia you know you come in with
with pain and and doctors are really
they need to have a diagnosis it's part
of the medical industry to give you a
diagnosis so they have to give you
something so hyper Mesi Syndrome has
been coming up a lot they'll ask people
do you smoke they're having a lot of of
of puking we're also finding that within
those people if we ask further questions
can you please test the enzy the enzymes
um of the stool and of the blood for
gallbladder a lot of these people are
having gallbladder issues
simultaneously and is the endoc canabo
system sparking something also
thca isn't seemingly reacting in the
same way so you know I just wanted to
further what you're saying Allison thcs
has been very active with whatever this
syndrome or reaction is thca has not
been so much like CBD also so there's a
lot of um information out there that we
just don't know enough about as well as
chirpings you know I know Colin you
would probably have a lot to say about
this there's people who are reacting
directly to tpine consumption and when
we re uh you know h uh grow plants that
are very very low in tpin those people
who have these symptoms and symptomatic
effects from certain high aromatics of
of of of cultivars when we reduce those
aromatics they do much better so there's
a lot of
unknowns this anecdotal evidence that
we've seen in family that have H have
had hyper mesis really bad will smoke it
come back from a weekend of of smoking
other
herb that's wherever at an event and
then have some of our herb that we grew
and not have any effects of it at all so
it's definitely common to find Cannabis
with chemicals so one of the harms with
cannabis might be that it's a dynamic
accumulator and one of the harms is it
uptakes bad attitudes right and int and
chemicals and those bad attitudes and
chemicals re
act in our body it's also wisdom weed so
sometimes it brings out the ailments
that we need to pay attention to so
sometimes if you smoke weed and you get
an adverse ailment it might be a window
towards something else that might be
happening and so also one other thing is
another harm to cannabis would be maybe
to say that it's the one thing that can
heal you so one thing that's harmful is
it's not the only thing that can heal
you it's one of the things that you use
along with health well-being exercise
Community connectivity diversity and
love and food
juicing those things definitely I mean
and music your life those things are
definitely yes um those things are
definitely um something that we learned
coming into you know we're newbies at
cannabis still I mean we've been in in
involved in this situation for seven
years Colton decided now to not just
have Crohn's disease but have massive
migraine headaches and cannabis isn't
touching them so it is the
all-encompassing it's your whole
wellbeing it it is music it is love it
is psychedelics it is conventional
medicines it is cannabis it's everything
and you just have to find what that is
um and and and enjoy it and and be in
the in the moment with it it's it's not
an all for All or Nothing system you
know there are people that use you know
cannabis alongside their pharmaceutical
uh regimens and they're having great
success with it uh so it's really it's
always about what you as an individual
need for your body it's never about you
know oh well everybody is doing this so
I'll do it that way too uh even though
you know a lot of people may be taking
the same medicine that you are it
doesn't mean that you have to be taking
it the same way or you have to be taking
the same amount you know your body
requires different things so don't be
afraid of only using one thing to meet
those qualifications or using multiple
things to meet those qualifications
because that's the journey that we're
going to be heading on you know with his
migraines is is trying to find to to see
if psilocybon would be beneficial for
Colton's migraines um cannabis doesn't
so it's obviously not the the perfect
solution for for his body
when it comes to his me his migraines
but it is a great solution for his
Crohn's disease um so I think using
everything in Your Arsenal and your in
in in the world that you can get your
hands on is is definitely
beneficial and with no Stigma right
that's the thing no stigmas no stigmas I
think that's a really big thing um
changes thei that the person's GNA have
like if you're in a prohibitionist
setting there's a way more of a
possibility
that if you take a psychedelic you're
going to go into a difficult trip
doesn't have to be a bad trip right but
a difficult time because you're going to
uh you're going to go through that it's
prohibited okay my mom doesn't know I'm
here I'm taking something that no one
knows I don't know what the [ __ ] this is
because I don't know what's in there and
I mean if you know so there's a lot of
things that uh connect to that and
there's it's definitely your mental ill
you know that's that's your mental
capacity and your mental state is
definitely something that that would
react
to negatively towards your your trip if
if you were in like oh my gosh you know
am I going to get caught you know that's
one of the reasons why we thought okay
moving to Colorado where we're safe
where we have access where mentally
we're
relaxed that it's going to make his his
opportunity to for health better I think
mental stigma is a huge thing most
dangerous thing about cannabis is
getting caught with it yeah
it's true and there's one thing that
Marcus shared about like mental health
that uh well I graduated in Psychology
before I changed my life for the to grow
weed
but I some some two subjects that I I
see cannabis as as a tool to help out
but also if it's used improperly as a
tool to make you go deeper even deeper
in the hole is anxiety and depression
too and it all depends on what uh what
you were all saying especially damn pure
that brings this holistic experience
that it's not only the Cannabis itself
right it's everything that comes with it
all your daily habits and things like
this but with people that have like a
severe anxiety consuming high THC higher
THC profiles can help them can even be a
factor that help them like have one more
of an anxiety crisis but different
cannabinoids with different ways of
consuming it can help out settle down
and to calm down too so it's very crazy
that just the knowledge and the
education towards the plant can change
the whole experience you can get with it
and I just wanted to shine a light on
this too because mental illness and uh
and every every every medicine it
doesn't it doesn't matter if it's
cannabis or if it's an anti-depressive
medicine it's uh like a tra from the
traditional you know like uh sorry my
English is kind of is kind of kind of
sucks sometimes but from from like this
medical traditional medical environment
uh every person it's subjective and
every person is going to create an
experience towards that so uh with
cannabis it's the same thing and he has
to be taken care of and seen and taken
care of by a community not only by a
psychiatrist not only by a doctor that
only sees the symptom and I think that
cannabis at this point I wanted to bring
up the subject about the good and the
bad parts of cannabis because I think
that that creates a setting while
someone has the autonomy to balance
everything and make a choice like oh
okay in Colorado so I can make these
choices or I'm in Brazil so I can make
exactly the choices I wanted but I have
to go with the flow of what I have here
and I just wanted to bring this up and
uh bring this bring the subject
up I'd like to I appreciate it go ahead
Wade yeah uh I love the question great
one Alice
um I've seen two potential problems if
you will with using cannabis uh one of
them uh is overdose cannabis has a
really strong biphasic effect where you
get certain effects and experience at
low doses but when you increase the dose
particularly if you and you use the
example of somebody who takes brick weed
and makes cookies and gives it to their
grandmother and grandmother gets like
150 milligrams of THC and she never
wants to talk about cannabis again and
she's lost the opportunity to experience
some of the healing effects that
cannabis can offer
and I think that's a problem and that's
about education which has come up a
number of times today the other place
that I've seen
cannabis potentially be a problem is at
the right dose and the right chemistry
cannabis has really remarkable
properties to relieve
pain and pain is actually a message from
your body to stop doing what's causing
the pain and I know from personal
experience that you can use cannabis to
the point where you can hurt yourself
and that's a problem and again that's an
education thing it's helping people
understand how cannabis interacts with
our uh OC canono system and how it can
help our bodies not just heal Trauma
from injury or overuse but really help
our bodies find the condition we call
Wellness or
health and and I'm really excited about
something I've been doing a lot and I
want to throw this in here I've created
an education program for a local
dispensary here and uh part of that
program is to help the consumer who
doesn't know much at all about cannabis
other than well if you smoke a joint you
get high help a consumer to understand
how cannabis Wellness might work in
their life and also a pro part of the
other part of the program is for the
wellness Associates the people who are
doing the transactions in the dispensary
helping them to understand what does
cannabis as a wellness product not just
as a medicine but as a wellness product
is helping people find this
wholeness uh that we call Health and it
is possible to have that and mental
health particularly with the covid and
so many people being forced into
isolation mental health I think is a
huge issue and I think the conversation
today has been really fruitful in this
way um I'm looking forward to uh more
people having access to the uh
educational thing that I've been putting
together because I'm really excited
about it I've realized I'm trying to
address a perceived need where people
don't really understand what we talk
about when we speak of cannabis as
medicine and uh I wanted to touch on one
other thing that was said earlier in the
conversation about isolates and
concentrates and I'm a big fan of the
canono but really when because we're
talking about patients and patient
well-being
every person's ECS is different and
every person responds differently to
cannabis preparations so it's really
important for opportunity to be
available to people for seeds to get out
to as many people as possible and let
them start trying to find the plant
that's going to work for them because
this plant will uh assert itself herself
in knowing you and providing the
medicine the chemistry that is uh again
this the genetics of this plant like you
mentioned Blue Dream part pardon my rant
I know I'm taking up a lot of time right
at the end of the show but uh I'm really
excited about it uh Blue Dream you
know does really well in certain parts
of California I can imagine in Illinois
where the environmental conditions are
very different the genetics of that
plant would give you a completely
different result and yeah analytical
testing is really an essential thing so
on that note happy New Year everyone and
much love and much respect to each of
you and I'll stop renting now thank you
thank you Wade I didn't think of that as
a rant at all but it was a great way to
kind of end out the show sort of Polish
it off my little son is anxious for me
to go spend the afternoon with him and
I'm actually very anxious to go spend
the afternoon with him so I want to
thank everyone if you are into it uh we
can continue this next Sunday and have
more discussion about everything that we
just talked about I am going to figure
out a kind of behind the scenes separate
show for the mushroom um the uh
traversing the fungal terpenome as uh
Josh hooked us up with earlier that'll
be the new mushroom show the first of
its kind on Bubble man's world what's
that Alice I said I want to come I want
to come because I started the mushroom
too because of anxiety and things like
this I started the micro dozing and oh
okay I've I've been feeling very great
with that it's being very good and
always The Damp your hoco too together
with it with the micro do but it's been
great I I I can talk of it as a psych U
psychedelic uh how do you say it I but
the person that goes through the
experience you know like not the grow
the cultivator but someone that has been
going through it's been great wonderful
well listen I'll let you guys all say
goodbye I will invite you all back next
week so we can continue this
conversation and for sure I want to uh
invite mark back next week because we
didn't talk about the hash Church
cultivar we're like just just kind of
easing into it slow so you're going to
come back next week we're going to start
with that and talk about that uh
cultivar you can give us the breakdown
on how it came to be and it's parental
stock and all of that goodness I'll
share some macro photographs and some
mind information in regards to uh
working with it pressing R and sifting
it bubbling it um definitely want to to
talk with you more uh Dr Al Alison it
was great to uh reconnect with you and
uh everyone all of you it was amazing to
uh spend 2021 January 3rd Sunday morning
with all of you it was wonderful now
we've taken it right into the afternoon
so I'll just let you in whatever order
you want share how to get in touch with
you you know your Instagram and whatnot
where people can check you out and uh
we'll finish it off like that I'm BC
bubble man on Instagram this is
bubbleman's world uh thank you all for
watching I'm going to let the panelists
tell you how to to how to find them I'll
jump in ATN Fontan ATN 420 at uh
yahoo.com or definitely for sure on
socials ATN
420 I'm Dr House
Harin sorry go right ahead um I'm Dr
Allison D on Instagram um one L I'm als
O A Raisin at am institute. net um ww.
am institute. net to find out more about
what we do in our Seattle
Clinic House of harlequin.com
um just got created uh and there's more
content coming to it and uh Instagram is
House of
harleyquinn uh spell ha us but uh we'll
probably change that one of these days
as well anyway much love and much
respect thank
you Colin Paul thanks for having guys
from vessel life
science um as always Marcus amazing
everyone Brian House of Harley Quinn
ATN Josh and Kelly always awesome to
hear your perspectives and all your
knowledge skunkman as always thank you
so much for being who you are and uh get
in touch everyone see you guys
soon uh thank you again so much for
having us it really is a blast every
time we're on here uh you can get a hold
of us and check out uh my journey uh on
Facebook or on Instagram at Colton's
Crew That's Colton with a Y and crew
like mle crew uh be sure to get a hold
of us there if you have any questions
and uh thank you so much again we also
have the Colton Turner Foundation that's
the www.c Colton the Colson Turner
foundation.org
um and if you want to get a hold of you
know people that are doing research we
would love to
to attach everyone together to to do
that so thank you so much hash church
thank you Marcus thank you everyone it's
always incredible to be listening and
and and part of your conversations it's
I love this thank
you give thanks family everyone oh go
best friend and we need to talk soon
anyway off on on a different realm but
say goodbye
yeah okay well thank you um thanks for
the time love listening to everybody you
guys always teach me so much for sure so
thanks for everything and yeah happy to
share again soon hope to do it again um
take care happy New Year best friend
farms uh at excuse me at gmail.com and
then Instagram is bestfriend Farms
I'm G to jump in here everybody know
it's on 420 Weed Master Instagram um
just grow for 2021 in so many different
ways if you can't grow your PL grow your
mind grow your life grow your journey um
Mike wants jump in here he's going to
probably say a little few words well
happy happy happy happy new year happy
New Year everyone enjoy have a great day
and success and everything that you do
and hey grow in good health thanks guys
peace
see you all I'm Alice and I have this
educational project that you can all
find at at Girling green 710 or the
website www.g Girling green.com or Ellis
on Instagram with six eyes I know it's
weird but go follow girls in green thank
you so much thank you so much Marcus
Josh and Kelly it was great to see you
happy new year for everyone happy hashy
year for everyone much love thank you
and big love to the work sauce Winery in
the background making it happen in the
kitchen what's up with my man Flynn just
got here actually at home brought from
the farmers market so yeah had to get
the mushrooms you can only get them once
a week at Farm Market you had to get
them so thank you so much everyone who
who is here um we appreciate you all you
can find us at dragonfly Earth medison
on Instagram or on YouTube or online or
demure farms.com to learn more about the
demm pure certified Community or follow
the hashtag deure and I just wanted to
take a second
just
heart every one of you Marcus for
continually putting this
on I have so much respect and love for
all the different
perspectives all the that we all get you
know to this medicine what an incredible
together from all different facets of
life and I'm I'm so thankful Happy New
Year to
everybody happy New Year
guys uh thanks this the first time on
the show so been super cool to be on the
other side mad respect to you all for
sure um you can find me at uh TR
Chrome
farmer.
lb have a good day guys Happy New Year
thank you everyone for spending time I'm
going to go hang out with this guy and
uh much love to everybody thanks a lot
talk to you soon peace man