hey what's going on everybody welcome
welcome to hash Church 2.0 episode 17 we
had a nice little very chill session the
other day and I thought I don't want to
repeat it so let me get the quick
hangout sent I'll send that off and we
will send this off and we'll see if we
can't get some folks in here and hello
to everyone in the chatroom who's been
hanging out with got 133 people there
were only about 50 hardcore OGIS in
there earlier but I see since we've gone
live that we're up over 130 right now so
thank you all of you in the chat room I
grew some bud rich slothy heads John
Maddox 70s mama and bingo heads Lombardi
of course hash Ketchum smoke face Red
River organics Johnny B Johnny B Johnny
B so I sent out the link we'll see if it
gets back to me here yeah just got a
couple hours today don't have a ton of
time to talk hey welcome buddy welcome
welcome gentlemen's call in what's going
on dude what up brother just uh skinned
settled here chillin man [ __ ] on this
great Sunday morning oh honey stripping
bubs burnin burnin bubs oh yeah so I
sent out the invitation to a bunch of
people this morning well yeah that's
just too loud the whole coughing and
everything I don't have a bong ripp
thing we'll just mute I just ends up
being really loud in the headphones so
I'll turn it down a little bit there we
go what's going on skunk man Sam would
be reverberation I'll kill that I
already with your circle incarnations
trying to fix this it's always nice to
do well you know what the bonus for you
is that it's like what is it six o'clock
at night right now
it's not 9:00 in the morning for you oh
it's five five okay right of course they
like savings time maturing but not my
end ah so it goes there's a time where
it's an only eight hour difference
between Canada and Holland interesting
interesting so how we do it in here
today gentlemen's everyone you know
everyone have a good weekend yeah really
good weekend
it's just been shelling when working
hard that was everybody else uh much the
same although I did have a little day at
Whistler yesterday which was quite nice
got a couple runs and got to watch my
four-year-old do some skiing down the
mountain which is always that's pretty
precious always beautiful yeah that's
awesome Anna you guys have been having
an amazing season so that's that's super
special yeah it's pretty it's pretty
good up there generally you know it's
just one of those spots that I'm sure
every year we get between forty and
fifty five feet of snow that falls up
there so it's it just keeps coming right
it's constant I'm sure we'll get March
storms for sure nice nice well I was at
the Calgary have cannabis Expo this
weekend for industry day and the event
went on over the weekend I didn't make
it today of course I went to fly out but
quite a good event going on Calgary
about education and what's going on in
Canada and a lot of the new I guess
license stores that were there and
what's going on with the industry like a
good talker what people are foreseeing
for the future in cannabis and cannabis
is pretty cool that is really cool
yeah checking it out I was just starting
Calgary it was cold it's like minus 25
or something when I was there yeah last
weekend it was minus 35 in Edmonton
tonight I knew it was gonna be at least
10 degrees colder than what it was in
Calgary when I said that it's just so
cold out there
oh my god uh well hopefully we you know
come to a nice lovely conversation here
at one point in time a little bit slow
to start I just it's daylight savings
we've from Fox in ours so we're kind of
it's really a two o'clock in the more
right now and I've landed at one o'clock
this morning oh and are you going to
Barcelona
um no I got some ICBC stuff to take care
of with my own personal stuff next week
I'm going to the ICBC Oh different kind
of ICBC mines company where does
Colombia bullsháá I ran into Remo
yesterday in Calgary and he was blazing
fat he's headed to Amsterdam so he's a
mate to Barcelona
we're gonna be the last one before hard
times screws up the whole political part
of it Paris already happened Wow well
you never know I mean I know they bought
it I've got you know I mean the Marley
family day me and Marley bought a big
chunk about High Times yeah yeah I think
it's you I P Oh Oh have you but what do
I know you don't know [ __ ] dude everyone
knows that you don't know [ __ ] fake news
fake news here on hash Church skunk man
Sam doesn't know [ __ ] hey what's going
on wait I didn't see you sneak in there
oh it's lovely
and yes daylight savings time beautiful
no 8 o'clock in the morning it is 8
o'clock in the morning but you know what
we've been up for hours let's be honest
here I still can't believe Amsterdam
doesn't do daylight savings that's so
trippy like they do they just don't end
at the same time um of course of course
or start at the same time it's a little
bit different I love it crazy well we
got 346 people watching they're hoping a
good conversation it Rupp's here out of
hash Church I figured you know what
not a huge plan but I did send out a
little email message yesterday saying
hey if people want to join let's do it
we'll hang out I'll have a good little
time and
dabbe tools and how little screwdrivers
work really well forgetting the format
drives just out of the container
yes I like that'll screw up what gets it
whenever it it'll just screw it right up
what was I about to go look for I'm not
good alright what else do we got
where's mark shall dome where are you
dr. mark I know he said he was in I will
be right back I'm gonna go grab some
some hash I guess the big the biggest
thing really coming up is spannabis and
international cannabis business
conference with Damian Marley for the
after party I'm looking forward to that
I split in a couple of days I see that
Flav is now in Amsterdam today hanging
out with Rick delici I saw them earlier
puffin what's up go to spam Abids are
you going to share pipes or are you
gonna wear gloves in faces dude I went
last year and did not really share pipes
I I just can't I have to I got so sick
that time well you know cuz your wife
got even sicker and it just that was
like the plague
that was like five Mike's got you know
oh yeah it seemed like if there was ever
a conspiracy there there was like some
crazy virus that got dropped on
spannabis I suspect it was just some
random dude traveling from like India
Africa just brought the brought the
plague with them every time I go to the
yeah they found common hatch and then
those germs on the pipe that passed it
around yeah that's basically what
happens they just get it all get it all
viral and pass it over I got it I got to
avoid it it's also all the cigarettes
they still smoke mad cigarettes in Spain
and so that really just lowers my immune
system after about four or five days of
like every breath I take even outside
like you go outside in the fresh air
there's just some
banished you smoking like five
cigarettes he's just like right beside
you people used to get sick at 90 times
and it was because of sharing pipes
because it was very little tobacco use
there actually it was just you know well
that and the other thing Amsterdam was
everybody was smoking weed that hasn't
been cured dry yeah that's true too you
get that that that cough that nasty
[ __ ] your weed hasn't been now well
you know it's now that's like that's the
Instagram resident of today that's like
hey we shouldn't cure this we should
just like to cut this let's just just
extract it while it's still growing on
the plant
we'll get all the most caustic terpenes
and then we'll take giant dabs of them
what do you have to say about that dr.
mark sorrows on me um hey everybody I
don't know yeah pasta doesn't sound good
at all right it definitely doesn't but I
do love the Jerry shirt oh thank you yes
totally yes right which finger I think
the middle finger right I think it was
the middle finger and what was it like
did he how did he lose that [ __ ] did he
get brother yeah yeah Sam bought the
finger and uses the fingerprint to get
into his iPhone yeah yeah I'm sure he's
got it right the actual fingering so
that's one Jerry thing I never saw on
sale on tour
fun fact he had to relearn how to play
the guitar after that happened
fun fact he was able to play the guitar
quite [ __ ] awesomely after one day
that was before he played the guitar I
think it happened to him as a young
child so I think it was way before he
started playing anything but yeah I mean
it was not on his on this finger or on
this hand it was on this hand right his
pick not picking
oh dude he was a 1 he was 4 years old
right there you go wow that was before
he started playing stringed instruments
but damn I let less than a year later he
watched his father drown in a river
during a fishing accident I had no idea
about that yeah that's really heavy
Jerome damn that's like he was 5 years
old yeah yeah yeah that forever changed
his life but I am wrong that's ok
drop it faked today's title is fake news
a man big this Jerry blanket actually
drowned when I was 3 years old but
somebody pulled me out of the bottom of
the pool gave me artificial respiration
I'm still there I have a similar story
Sam I literally almost died it - I took
my water wings off jumped in a pool and
my brother pulled me out gave me CPR it
literally was the bottom of the pool I
can remember I bet you want some of my
oldest memories I can remember going
down and seen the bubbles going up above
me
does it didn't make me afraid of water
at all damn well that's that's how
Colton got it got his Crohn's right like
drowning in the lake damn near dying
it's crazy
it's full-blown insanity so what about
you dr. mark are you gonna head to
spannabis you never come to these things
do you you're more like a I'm not going
this year I got my hands tied up in so
many different projects right now I've
never been busier which is great Marcus
as you know I mean in this industry you
have to you know sort of go where the
where the work is and I'm fully
committed on several different projects
both in the hemp and cannabis space and
Ben never been busier and but it's great
what it says you know just are different
and all the clients are different but
you know as you know like when you're
consulted the space
you're sort of you know the expert at
the table that's making you know people
feel good about you know buying
equipment or dedicating you know entire
production - you know methods that you
know we're recommending and so we have
to you know do the best job we possibly
can to make sure that we got our eye on
the target of where this thing is going
to be in the future you know and not
necessarily sort of like where it is now
so you know the great thing is like all
these projects like the one in Jamaica
is just like the unlimited potential
that exists you know like like we can
see it like when you and I go there and
when other people you know go to these
places but um it's just unbelievable
because again you know that we can bring
there concentrate level and to make it
to a whole new level that it doesn't
exist today which which is really cool
because you know just given the whole
culture and attitude and everything that
goes on down there so just you know
these projects where there's unlimited
potential is just you know like just
great I mean it's why we do it right
more like what you said way up when you
say hemp CBD yeah yeah yeah just when
Americans say hemp when Americans say
hem they're talking about CBD when
Canadians say ham we're actually talking
about all the rest of the plant we're
not allowed it's just the way it's just
the way it is they all the hemp growing
in America is for CBD extraction and
Mart right are you growing in Jamaica
we're growing there's projects I'm
working on all over I mean right now
Jamaica does offer a tremendous
opportunity to grow em we're not growing
up per se right now but I've been the
trip that I made down there that you
know I threw some pictures that we
posted on it was a potential project
with a group called sativa
and university is a West Indies and yeah
ultimately there is hemp production in
the scope of that project I'm absolutely
certain of it well one of the parts of
the temperate climate you know that they
have down there to be able to grow all
the time you know no but the problem
with hemp is all of the varieties are
registered low THC varieties worldwide
require northern climates but you're not
about or near the equator or near the
tropical there are no tropical have
slightly behind plants well cool well
let's make them time to get busy I tell
you I'm just gonna make the oil though
grow that the plants do it exactly the
beautiful thing about extracting and I
tell this to people all the time is that
we can pick and choose who can actually
grow good enough herb rather than try to
like everyone in Canada is all about
this like I'm gonna build my grow and
then I'm gonna build my facility and
then I'm gonna just process what I grow
in my facility and it's uh
you know it seems limiting to me
compared to I will just Pro like even
even Jamaica for instance I had my
project going on and Jamaica they're
sort of I wouldn't say it's falling
apart but I don't talk to my business
partners at all anymore like period and
so I kind of feel like you know I could
just process if I want so I've been also
a few companies have reached out to me
and I've just sort of like okay well
well suss this out it's easy you don't
have to start a whole company you can
literally just go there and just do what
needs to get done because the bottom
line is they don't have people who know
how to do that well especially working
with the university because the
university is just chock-full of people
who have minds that are absorbing you
know higher levels of you know academic
information it's a quality University
like when you go to
it's one of that you can't even believe
you're in Kingston I mean Yui is on
point I mean they have who proton NMR is
in that building yeah I I saw yeah isn't
that crazy though they just got two of
them opportunity to not only you know
produce but also to train people for the
industry is just it's really cool the
folks who down there who are working in
it everyone's got a smile you know in
the grow everyone's happy to be there
yeah they're happy to be employed yep
100% and with herb
I mean how [ __ ] beautiful is that
there is one way to grow hemp in Jamaica
outdoors I'm talking about which is what
you're talking about
and that is you put lights above the
property then like you say you can just
turn off the lights and flowers no right
under what time here it is well yeah and
Marcus I'll say that like one thing
that's going on here in Pennsylvania is
they they uncapped or yeah I'm capped
the acreage limit was at a hundred acres
and now you can grow as much time do you
have land for so in Pennsylvania there's
been a number of different companies
that have announced putting in
facilities one is using that so-called
hemp train which is just a big you know
you know auger type of you know excluder
that just you put the plant material
into a conveyor belt that just feeds it
into the system and it separates out the
fiber from the from the herd from the
what they call green microfiber which is
what you extract for CVE and if you
check it out it's called hemp train the
hemp train it's like you know 1.5
million dollars worth of investment but
if you put this on the front end of an
extraction plant certainly you could do
just something like ethanol extraction
there is a you know value proposition
that's pretty compelling for building
processing plants for places that
again are just gonna be farming you know
that point three percent or less
THC you know a variety of have no doubt
in terms of Pennsylvania that's a great
actually a great climate for growing
outdoors depending on turns your how the
hurricane season really shapes out down
in down in Africa how those storms come
off of there really determine your your
just what your September looks like but
you can absolutely dial it in in in that
in that climate there it's beautiful
sure is and at that scale it certainly
does make sense to you know separate out
the various components of what you can
get in terms of value if you can you
know recover you know value by
extracting the fiber and you know I
don't know what varieties they're
talking about Sam most of them were just
pretty you know I don't know I mean I
guess I need to learn more about so that
the varieties that that I'm seeing in
the state Sam are predominantly coming
from Oregon a lot of desert those are
not hemp right there hit up growth
hydrants absolutely but they are they
you can't grow them the most compete
because they are not registered low THC
varieties well some of them are Sam that
a lot of people I'm talking to you are
absolutely getting certified seed I'm
not quite sure the intricacies okay
super international registration is and
you can register should or Canadian
registration those are all different
than what you're talking about
certified seed so could you expand on
that Sam so you could explain everybody
with what the intricacies of those the
international laws are and how that kind
of plays a role and how it get how a new
cultivar gets on to the registry that's
a yeah I think that would be a great
conversation well I'm not sure I have
enough current because in a little bit
I've got to disappear and I'm going to
with my family I think it would take you
know maybe 15-20 minutes to explain it I
just don't write that much in Canada
it's fairly simple we have a seed
registry for the hemp cultivars yeah
they they grow them they require three
years of growth whether that's in
another country they want you to have
grown it and test it if you do you want
to sit do you want to say it's Amer do
you want me to because I think they just
want to be answered right cuz I'm down I
don't mind I just know that how that's
how it works in Canada you have to get
the seeds into the registry it takes
three years I actually talked to the guy
recently at the hemp conference in
Manitoba who was in charge of adding
seeds to the registry see when seeds are
in the registry and they've been tested
enough times they don't require testing
anymore so there's a bunch of cultivars
in Canada that they don't even test for
the THC levels because they absolutely
know that those THC levels like Zola
tanoshii are so much there they're below
the point three percent they're closer
to point zero three percent which is
literally ten times lower than the than
the amount that makes it hemp in the
first place but that's how it works for
Canada so that's why we're in a bit of a
quandary we don't have these high CBD
cultivars so we need to get ourselves
into a situation where we get these
cultivars into the registry and
everyone's kind of you know there's not
really a clear and precise concise way
of getting that done it just seems a
little bit convoluted but I'm sure a
couple of years will go by and we'll
have all of those cultivars Marcus five
years ago there was no new registered
varieties in Canada there was only
imported ones from Europe yeah Canadian
ones awesome yeah yeah exactly
so welcome my quest I like the way you
looked when you came in you had the hat
on and the glasses and it looked like
you were like just ready to go take eat
some psychedelics and enjoy the day put
a smile on my face really I'm not gonna
lie yeah and obviously the the state of
Colorado state of Oregon are working on
their seeds certification programs those
programs are designed for their States
there's a couple of groups in Colorado
and through two or three that I know of
an or
that are working on that certification
process but ultimately like like Scott
man said he's obviously in Colorado
they've had industrial Henson 2014 that
gives them four years they've been
developing cultivars testing them but
what we've seen some of the cultivars
that were developed in Colorado and
Oregon when you bring them to two places
with more blue light spectrum there's an
upregulation in the THC synthase and
down-regulation in the CBD 8da synthase
so we've actually seen some results
where cultivars that are certified
certified in Oregon's safety grow in
Oregon or Colorado being brought to more
equatorial climates and they end up
testing hot so what you'll likely end up
seeing is in the u.s. at least you know
States certifying seeds those certified
seeds being state specific and tell
federal law changes and then on a as
federal law changed allowing US
companies to certify those cultivars
internationally then you'll actually a
lot be allowed to start seeing that
exportation of seed cultivars
unfortunately federal law being what it
is we have to operate state-by-state so
many times we have to do research in
states that allow that research and
avoiding research in other states so
good example Washington state doesn't
allow any CBD extraction but they do
allow industrial hemp research so we did
some research at Washington State
University looking at industrial hemp
fiber processing into biomaterials
whereas the University of Colorado
Colorado State University Oregon State
University are all researching CBD and
cannabis and offering actually
researching courses in cannabis so
you'll end up seeing that kind of
develop unfortunately that's going to
hinder Canada's CBD production for the
next couple years until we have CBD
cultivars certified in the in the
country of Canada but there's actually a
really long history of industrial hemp
you know my family when they migrated
from
the Catholic persecution of the Moors in
the sixteen 1500s to North America they
settled in New Haven Connecticut and
they were hemp farmers they the Spanish
the French the English all brought hemp
to the colonies but that was before a
lot of the THC testing so what we know
of as some of the Central American
cultivars are actually imported hemp
cultivars from Europe that have become
feral or essentially landraces and then
through the domestic propagation have
become what we know of as the the
Colombians the mohawk ins the Panama
Reds those are all Spanish strains that
were brought to the new world by the
conquistadors so I think now it shows
that they're more likely from India or
Asia you know absolutely third they're
Indian Asian cannabis varieties that you
know were brought through the Silk Road
to southern Europe and then during the
colonial periods were brought from
southern Europe to the new world now
obviously there's been trade throughout
the Mediterranean for beyond 10,000
years but a lot of that trade you know
we did wouldn't have had transoceanic
trade without industrial hemp because
papyrus breaks down in salt water hemp
is one of the few that they can use for
their rigging the sails that wouldn't
degrade in salt water so it ended up
being quintessentially necessary for
transoceanic trade to have hemp
cultivars wherever they were building
their ships man who got to figure that
out the first time when their ship
disintegrated in the middle of the ocean
hey I don't think we can use this stuff
anymore guys the way it worked Marcus
first ships used to go along the coast
for hundreds of years finally they got
brave enough to cross the oceans sure of
course
Braden it was probably those bloody
there's the Egyptians on the nine
I was across the ocean yeah so the
Egyptians would be we're able to use
papyrus Reed boats bundling reeds into a
giant bundles that were more buoyant
than water so they would actually be
able to travel up and down the Nile but
once they would hit Alexandria and you
know obviously the Mediterranean ocean
that papyrus would would only last for
about a month and a half so they were
able to actually I guess circumnavigate
along the coast but they weren't
actually able to do any transoceanic
crossings so the there is some in
reading the Rob Clarke's
Annabeth's evolution ethnobotany book
there is some suggestion that new hemp
was as as the Egyptians brought per
pyres to the coast and then started
traversing around the edge of the
Mediterranean to places we now know of
as Israel Palestine Lebanon Turkey
that's when they started identifying
seeing the use of hemp and wooden boats
more so than the papyrus boats so is
this John the part --lens work is this
what we saw John do in Leiden a couple
of months back or if Jesus been a year
now actually is that is this kind of
what John was talking about Sam in
regards to what wasn't it all based on
Pollan where he was finding how cannabis
had traveled and where it was located in
its most ancient forms I guess sounds
yes yeah so using pollen samples you
know there's a if you actually go when
you guys are in Spain when you guys are
in France you can actually get in the
late summer that you can get pollen
reports for the cannabis or the hemp
pollen that's flowing over the Straits
of Gibraltar from Morocco so obviously
you know the wind same wind that brings
sand from the Sahara to the Amazon basin
brings hemp pollen from North Africa
into Europe so one of the things that
they were able to do is look at the
sedimentary layers of different parts of
Europe and you know hemp pollens unique
you can actually look at its structure
compared to other other wind pollinated
annuals and you can actually identify
where different parts in the strata
different parts in the historical record
have fallen pops up and that's gonna
tell you approximately within you know
five hundred miles you hey that at this
strata we start to see hemp pollen
appearing in these areas therefore
within 500 miles and X amount of time of
where we find these pollen we can assume
that industrial hemp was being pulled to
be or you know in that case it was all
cannabis back then because it's all
prior to the testing at THC because we
have to we have to understand that you
know prior to the singles treaty and you
know essentially creating that
definition of em for being below 0.3
percent THC you when Rafael Missoula
originally elucidated the chemical
structure of THC they didn't have lab
tests to be able to show they didn't
have proton NMR to show the structure so
they elucidated the form oh yeah they
had proton NMR that's how he figured it
out just had it was just right at the
beginning of the use of it
60 megahertz proton NMR and that's how
he you know did the structure
elucidation so we're meeting reports the
NMR data so it was NMR that you know he
used to basically fully do that and
prior to the 70s they they didn't have
60s yeah sixties yeah so the early
sixties they didn't they didn't have it
yeah until then it was just
yeah the structures that Adams said and
Todd and others had had proposed which
were close but not quite
yes definitely go ahead Mike so prior to
all that analytical testing being able
to identify the active compounds in
cannabinoids there there was no
difference in industrial Hampton and
cannabis yeah we when Linnaeus described
it he described it based on its
characteristics but not on its chemical
profiles so it's the whole
differentiation between industrial hemp
and cannabis is really only
evolved over the last 50 to 100 years
prior to that what we know of as the
Central American cannabis varieties were
essentially industrial hemp varietals
fiber for idols prior to 50 hundred
years ago well I'll tell you it was it
great it was a great presentation by
John McFarlane in Leiden Holland at the
International cannabis Research Society
when he did that it usually it starts
the first day I guess is a little bit
more plant-based in cannabis base before
it gets just it goes so deep into
science all of a sudden we're you know
torturing animals to figure out how the
mechanisms in their brains work and that
both Ian and I from Saginaw right we
just we just we were just like you know
what let's go rent bikes and drive
around Amsterdam like this is I could
listen to the plant part but now they're
torturing rats and monkeys and all sorts
of things to figure out these mechanisms
and I'm sure they're it has its place
but it's hard for my brain to wrap
itself around one one problem I had with
it in particular was when the guy was
like when they give a rat or a mouse
like a normal amount of cannabis like
for their size of body they can never
tell that it's high basically because
it's just like a person you don't you
can't really tell it's not alcohol we
don't get all [ __ ] up and so what they
do for these experiments is they give
them so much it's like the equivalent of
you smoking like six pounds in a in a
sitting so they basically start to
finally look like you know they've got
brain damage or something and that's
when they decide okay now it's high we
can do the experiment it's like that's
really good because they're really
testing people like you and me oh man
I'll tell you what about you Sam were
you digging those but that part are you
into the deep science I are much much
more but what I do is I ask Johnny
Parkland you know what's the good stuff
and I go around they looked at all of
the posters
posters I checked those out but it
doesn't sound like I'm going to be
interested and the speeches I I do not
listen to him anymore something that
really stood out to me and what Mike was
talking about was pollen drift the
observation that in North Africa
cannabis growing there and I assume
among other places you're talking about
like Gotama for example in Morocco where
big fields of cannabis are happening and
have been for a while that pollen
manages to get down out of the mountains
across the coastal plain across the
Strait of Gibraltar and to hemp fields
in southern Europe and pollen drift is a
real issue in California with because
California now has a hemp bill and a
cannabis regulated marketplace and one
of the real issues in local
jurisdictions is about the difference
between hemp and cannabis and all the
rules of involved with it and the
cannabis people are rightfully saying
hey pollen drift is a real issue for us
seeded cannabis doesn't wait well one
difference is yes Paulette makes it
across nobody has ever shown it's viable
nobody has ever proven that you know
pollen that can still germinate crosses
the Baltics right there yeah and when
they look at when you look at I know in
Canada in talking to and reaffirming up
there they in Canada certified seed
program put a four mile buffer so in
order to be a producer with of certified
seed in Canada what's called pedigreed
seed you actually have to have your seed
production with greater than four miles
from any other potential pollen
contamination so they in Canada they put
a four mile buffer Washington they also
put a four mile buffer you can't
cultivate industrial hemp within four
miles of any I 502 recreational farm the
research papers I was reading was
showing that UV light from sunlight
assuming that you have a standard sun
irradiation is going to sterilize the
pollen somewhere between half a mile and
two miles so by the time it gets about
traveling the pollen traveling about
four miles it's going to be sterilized
now there's still a huge issue I'm
seeing it a ton in the Willamette Valley
of organ and go heading down into
Southern Oregon so you know Oregon's
having some tough issues with the prices
of the recreational cannabis the
recreational cannabis farmers are
actually switching from THC cannabis to
CBD hemp and that's actually causing
cross-pollination issues where you know
they're growing industrial hemp in land
that's great cultivation land great soil
but they it's too close to the other TAC
producers so you are seeing some of that
cross-pollination that cross pollination
you when you have hundreds of acres of
CBD and that pollinates you know a acre
of THC you have potential litigation
that could happen between you know the
THC guys are pissed because they just
you know lost their entire outdoor
harvest of THC but the same could also
happen I've seen in Colorado actually
some CBD cultivars test hot because they
were accidentally pollinated by THC and
then all of it we tested we tested how
far campus the both in hungry on
industrial hemp and drug varieties and
in strong linked conditions they can go
10 miles usually four miles would be
safe and it's still viral after then
yeah because sometimes when it's windy
it's also cloudy
yeah windy and dark that's that's kind
of my nightmare situation avoiding
places where it's windy and then because
if it's windy it also most yeah right
isn't it ironic that if you're growing
hemp you can a crop insurance for crop
failure but if you're but doing cannabis
you can't buy crop insurance yeah
yeah that'll change as federal law
changes its its son it's an unfortunate
part of the industry but ultimately what
what I'm seeing in organs specifically
the if I'm gonna cultivate five hundred
or a thousand acres of CBD hemp and try
and sell it at a price that is
competitive in the price depending on
how how heavily extracted it has to get
to whether it has to be distillate or
isolate TC free nonetheless I want to
excuse myself but I've got to leave for
my dinner so bye-bye everybody
take care Sam have a great dinner bye
Sam yeah have a good dinner Sam thanks
for stopping in it's just a short one
today I got to go at 11:00 myself so we
got another hour in 20 minutes to shoot
the proverbial cannabis [ __ ] and then
we'll have to all go our separate ways
but I have a feeling it won't be very
hard to burn through another hour with
you guys here I'm burning right here
right now just keep going beautiful so
see Mike in the state of Massachusetts
what we're up against with happy valleys
we can't even if I wanted to plant 100
acres and extract that CBD at all and
put it on my shelves I have to have that
come from a drug cultivar per the rules
so it's it's you know it's kind of a
backwards way to look at it but I think
that they're trying to do is prevent
people from doing what you know the
large big boys are doing which are just
coming in the state setting up running
the CBD game as a monomolecular
extraction and then that you know that's
it so you know as an ingredient I'm to
say that again can you source CBD as an
ingredient I cannot I have to grow it
from the drug cultivars that I select
now I have plenty of them which is great
but you know as I investigate into into
doing this the way that I see it being
most beneficial it's just you hit a wall
you know you literally or there's no
there's a gas station you can buy CBD
tankers and lollipops absolutely it's
totally weirdest third
dogmatic man it drives me crazy so I'm
like thinking to myself like wow really
guys but it's just the way it is you
know and I'm sure it'll change over time
you know all this is a great experiment
as I like to say and you know each we're
all trying to learn from each other but
no one's got it right well what one new
development I mean if you read the farm
bill it says nothing about this but the
guy who made the response the
irresponsible comments from the FDA Scot
Gottlieb he retired or all sudden step
down and you got to think that you know
trout is only to put a pro cvd person in
there at the top of the FDA to sort of
resolve this issue because yeah there's
a lot of you know things hanging into
balance because this is really it's an
interpretation of what's the law and not
necessarily what one bureaucrat who's
here today gone tomorrow says right
Malang garage of cannabinoids is more
efficacious than individual isolates so
cannabis guys start doing that breeding
breed for one to ones breed for computer
ones seek out those rare cannabinoids
and you'll end up producing better
products because as much as I enjoyed
creating CBD isolates for medical
purposes it's you know the entourage
effect is real ya know natural selection
is really I mean that's part of what I'm
doing with Happy Valley is we have
15,000 square feet for just exploration
and R&amp;D of breeding and natural format
for natural selection now it's not a
huge amount of space but I can get a lot
of real work done in there and to have
that many rooms to be able to isolate is
you know really fortunate you know so
hopefully we get a lot of real work done
in the next few years coming you know I
want to welcome Peter
mr. soil balance has entered the room
what's going on dude it's been a while
Marcus yeah it's good to see you brother
really good to see you
it's good to see you too man you've been
hard at it working working in this
wonderful industry that we're all trying
to push forward yeah
yep it's been it's been the I'll tell
you the the hemp industry this [ __ ]
right now is so thick in the United
States out there with the
with them brokering and the [ __ ]
it's nice to come together with some
with some good heart of dudes and and
talk about the science for a little bit
so yeah good to see all you guys man
really good to see you
yeah man you too I'm glad I'm glad you
came and shared some time with us today
I haven't done many of these hash
searches lately it's a life got really
busy it's kind of like it's like we all
had so much time we're just doing all
these hashed churches and then suddenly
we all got really busy you know like I'm
really busy right yeah so I'm sure
you're in the same boat as the rest of
us but it's it's been great it's nice
and it's nice too it's like Mark said
you know when when the works there you
got a you got to pump it out and do it
so that's what we're all doing
yeah that's time and the the the the
starting gun went off and it's time to
start working and you know so I've been
doing some soil consulting so getting
these these United States hemp growers
conducive on their soil physics their
soil microbiology their soil chemistry
you know really trying to circumvent
those plans from going hot because
that's that's one of the biggest
problems that happened in in like North
Carolina and different states in hemp
production was that they they weren't
addressing the biology of the soil and
the plants were going hot they were
getting stressed out there Delta 9 was
getting stress induced and and they were
having a low CBD output and this is a
very unique plant because it doesn't
really show signs like you know like a
like a tomato plant or a cucumber plant
with its with its stress it's it's it's
a weed you know it's a little bit
stronger and it's got more vitality and
so you don't see the same signs as you
would with like plant parasitic
nematodes or Pythium or Rhizoctonia
Meuse area I'm a lot of the things that
can really tax this plant and you know
get you those those low CBD numbers on
genetics that should have hit you know
maybe 15
percent just poor expressions Duds
basically I saw the article white
buffalo seeds on instagrams been posting
some great soil stuff lately
and he wrote he posted a cannabis now
article that says dark heart nursery
identifies major virus behind dug
cannabis plants they've identified the
HPL VD virus said to infect up to 30% of
crops causes cannabis plants to grow
poorly so there you go that's it there
and a lot of guys that are like buying
these high high in genetics spending a
shitload of money I mean they're
mortgaging their [ __ ] houses and
they're buying this seed they put it in
there and you know with this particular
plant I would say the biology is is even
more important than the fertilizer for
this plant I mean again we're not
growing tomatoes or cucumbers were
growing [ __ ] oil and and the the
producers that you guys all know in
Canada in the United States they learned
a long time ago that the living soil was
like the key to get more frost right and
so to be able to do that on an
industrial scale with hemp for oil
production is it's a new science that
that everybody is embarking on and
trying to learn yeah and they're not
they're not really addressing the the
macro micronutrients of the soil for
this particular plants needs on that
industrial scale they're more worried
about the sea they're more worried about
the drip tape about the [ __ ] laws you
know they're not focused in on what's so
important in actually cultivating this
plant that we all know so the consulting
business is going crazy the the the the
the the new growers who would like to
get into the industry are holding back
right now so there's a lot of big money
that wants to come in but everybody's
scared because nobody knows how to grow
this plant they're not yeah they're not
connected with the plant they don't know
it yeah so yeah that's really all really
great points and and for you to your
point and in terms of the seed that
everyone's buying is is unfortunately we
don't know enough in terms of breeding
practices specifically for cannabis to
eradicate them and to identify those
types of pathogens so when you
have someone breeding with great lines
that may have good expressions there
could be some there could be pathogens
in those seeds you know and those things
get carried on in large numbers and
people don't understand quite yet and
neither do all of us quite yet how to
get rid of that's that right now in in
terms of what pathogens are there right
so those that's really exciting in terms
of what what the next ten years will
really look like in terms of breeding
and in seed and verification is another
thing you know understanding what you
actually have versus what you're told
you have that's a big big deal you know
yeah I've heard some nightmare stories
that people buying huge amounts of these
CBD cultivars in seed planting out acres
of it and being like oh yeah
I've seen it in Kentucky I mean she is
it it's brutal so even like to your
point you know we've these younger
growers that just don't understand the
plan itself and the species so they're
trying to adapt other practices from
other species to this species and it's
just sometimes doesn't translate so you
really have to spend time with it to
truly understand the intricacies of it
so that's you know that's a very fair
point you know what you're talking about
before yeah so it's some topical
discussion I know we're in the first
week of March
generally speaking it's a little bit too
cold to start putting plants outside but
there is a ton of things you can start
to do working in your garden to start
getting your soil beds composted adding
adding cover crops and amendments what
do you what do you guys bulls for this
month to get the gardens ready for this
summer next couple of months I mean you
know the whole no-till thing really took
a cue from from crop rotation and
large-scale farming or at least organic
farming so there's a lot to take from
both sides of what's happening in Doran
and and traditional farming and
agriculture so it really depends on your
end goal and what your
you're doing but no dancer room you know
I think there's a there's a plethora of
things you can do it just depends on
what you're trying to do all right and
so it's bowhead or a genius right
exactly absolutely what we're doing to
kind of help these guys prepare is is
we're doing a bioavailable nutrient
analysis of the soil so again before our
guys actually go in and move forward
with some of these larger acreage
production operations what we're really
trying to do is is understand what that
plant is going to be able to absorb with
regards to the macro micronutrients
before they even plant so that way we
know if they're gonna have a good crop
or they're gonna get you know in trouble
throughout the year because you know if
you're for instance you're you're way
too alkaline or if you're cation
exchange isn't good or if you don't have
the appropriate cal to mag what's
happening right now in the states is
these these growers are going to the
universities and looking at total plan
moocher or total nutrients in the soil
they're not looking what's actually
plant available and so their mineral and
federal fertilizer recommendations are
way off you know putting in way too much
maybe nitrogen or me it really too much
phosphorus when that plant can have a
problem especially with a lot of these
guys trying to grow organic for the
first time those sustainable cultivation
methodologies are not really being
addressed much less than biology and so
what we do is we go in like I had a
grower in Arizona that wanted to grow a
thousand acres of hemp and we tested his
soils and he was like at 8.9 pH you know
his his they and because of that they
had put in sulfur into the soil to try
and regulate it you know but they did a
bad job so now you had sold for toxicity
he had magnesium toxicity this guy was
gonna put two million dollar was two
million dollars of his own money in to
grow hemp you know he's trying to find
the genetics and all this stuff and I
told him I was like you're gonna have an
uphill battle on this soil man you know
and so I think for most growers out
there that are considering getting into
hemp the first thing that you really
need to do is is get that co2 extraction
done of the soil nutrients you
looking at how much phosphorous how much
potassium how much nitrogen your plants
are actually going to be able to absorb
versus how much is in there so there's a
different type of extraction method that
we do that that looks at bioavailable
nutrients and then you know to further
assist these guys they need to do leaf
tissue and SAP analysis throughout the
season to actually see you know again
we're talking commercial or industrial
scale yeah they should I would recommend
orange photonics I know it's not perfect
but in the field it's it's very helpful
to give you a really great understanding
of where you're falling and just every
week just get in there and start taking
samples I'd recommend that to every
large scale hemp farmer out there it's
really important to understand where
you're falling along the season and then
it gives you those data points to make
better informative choices for your next
season or even the cultivars that you're
running right what those choices are
that's the thing that not right people
know like how much magnesium do I need
in the vegetative state absolutely not
to your point with the nitrogen and
those are the types of things that that
throw your heavy-metal testing off you
know you that the metals go up into the
heads and they stay there once it once
they're there it's locked in it's locked
and loaded they're never coming out
unless you blast it out so it's you know
it's it's something you have to take
into consideration in terms of yeah you
know and then go ahead sorry so then
there's the whole you know layers to
this so then you you want to take into
account the energetics that this plan
necessitates right like paramagnetism or
you know bio dynamics or some of the
other layers that are so conducive but
again going back to the life in that
soil the biggest caveat that I'm seeing
right now are the biggest hardship that
a lot of these growers are gonna undergo
unknowingly in Canada as well as the
United States for high oil production
all falls back into that that that
biological system because there are
microorganisms that are signaling that
plant to increase the CBD synthase
if they're not indigenous within that
soil you know that's that's not giving
that plant it's it's familiar microbial
partners that it co-evolved with in
nature right and so yes all of the
terpenes many of the terpenes many of
the precursors to the cannabinoids
are actually bioessence synthesized in
the soil microbiome wanna right the
bacteria the endo ecto bacteria which
are the bacteria lived inside outside as
well as the fungi will actually mind the
soil for minerals
- soil for the nitrifying bacteria will
actually fix nitrogen into nitrates and
nitrates and actually bring it up to the
Canberra plant and exchange it for sugar
because most of those soil bacteria
don't produce sugar they're not
photosynthetic so what they they form a
symbiotic relationship with the cannabis
plant or the canvas provides the sugar
in the in exchange the symbiotic micro
flora in the soil will end up providing
all the precursors but the Animas plant
means so being able to set your soil up
and really nice by a biodynamic soil
before you even get your plants in the
soil is a great way to start I love that
you're talking about this because last
week I just did a transplant and I
transplanted all of my plants into this
product soil conditioner by dr. Mary
Jane so I actually just have it on my
screen right here I'm just going to show
you I'm using this stuff right here I
was gonna ask you about it and you were
just talking about this because I was
just actually really considering what
I'm doing in my soils and adding some
extras to it and then I was looking at
you soils cold little bags sitting there
and I tried this mama - Mary Jane's for
the first time so I'm just kind of know
this is more like the home grower it's
one little package into like a five
gallon pot and I let it sit for 24 hours
I did my transplant and I split my room
in half again and I can already see a
difference within a week of the plants
that are immense these group product oil
conditions I'm like damn she like the
whole room like you could definitely see
a different word wrong and I always
recommend you
gardening for a lot of indoor growers
they're trying to amend I think their
products are great they they have a lot
of the micros is really nice it's good
for transplanting and it's easy and
fairly quick it's easy and this was the
whole thing for me I've always gone back
and tried getting into doing these
living soils and stuff but it's it's
difficult you know thinking about doing
that on an industrial scale job yeah I
mean yeah you're talking about this it's
a great conversation for people who
really understand on the industrial on
what you're talking about but then
either on grower and getting into those
soils because I've noticed my difference
in my growth everybody sees it I have
these different well coats and stuff
like that and really taking a really
good look at the soils and using these
group harmonics and stuff like that is
is key yeah yeah man that's a job guys
thanks John yeah yeah it's I it's just
been it's just been interesting you know
all these all our brothers and our
friends and our family like in the
Humboldt County man growing like the
best cannabis in the world or whatever
the best cannabis is growing I mean
Canada has got some of the best grass in
the world but but most of those growers
have gone to a place point where they
understand that that it's that living
soil that's gonna give you that frost
right and why why is that and so to be
able to replicate that on an industrial
scale to get CBD levels to like 18
percent so you know with the CBD sent a
sends on it goes back to what you were
talking about with regards to the
nutrient absorption the foundation as
well as the the enzymatic communication
of those microbes with the plant to
create more oil and we found a huge
correlation with bricks so to further
quantify your hypothesis on the the
nutrient absorption leading to that that
foundation that's right on the money
dude because the more glucose you know
or the bricks reading that we're finding
is is is again it's it's right now we're
we're seeing this connection we haven't
proven it but but those bricks or - all
glucose is the precursor to all oils
exactly Matt so so what is your
summation yeah we'll set thank you
that's exactly what I wanted to disclose
is that that Brix level when you go out
and test that leaf and if your sugar
content is higher in one versus the
other you know you've got glucose which
is gonna actually
cellularly transformed into the CBD
synthase enzyme as well as of the full
cannabinoid spectrum so that sugar in
the plant that glucose is everything you
know that's good [ __ ] right there
pastor gems it turns into [ __ ] imagine
I'm gonna put a shout-out to the science
of regenerative cannabis soil farming
they had a conference up the PC mark and
I were able to attend and I think
they've been having a couple there's one
more that they're gonna be
live-streaming mark is that last one in
Michigan I want to say you know I'm not
sure why don't I just invite Joshua in
and maybe he can cool greys there was
one in Maine that just happened good
work happening there yeah very good work
it was great listen Mike and I were in
Vancouver for the lift conference while
simultaneously the regenerative
conference was happening and we spoke at
that on a panel along with my partner
Daniel from Whistler technologies and it
was great it was like it was like our
people in that room you know really
conscious really the work that Joshua
was doing by putting all those people
together is definitely really good got
to meet Kevin jawed free and got to meet
kaya from the infamous Caius coffee
which I'm actually puffin on right now
and just some really great folk some of
my friends came up from Ontario it was
definitely a very good very good
conference and I met I met Tara Lee
Tara Lee was there she's in the chat
room right now she's one of our old G's
in the hash Church chatroom and yeah I
don't know if Joshua was gonna get that
in time but I hit him up with it
nonetheless like I tried to send him the
email but it would not I don't I guess I
don't know Joshua was emailed because
when I sent out the the thing yesterday
I meant to send it to him I think I even
might have mentioned if some of that
check if anybody is in and around I
think it's in Michigan is this last one
but they're if they're if you're near
the Midwest last one is
coming up in the next week or two and if
you if you're not in the Midwest they're
gonna be live-streaming it so oh great
they can actually record it and make it
available to have buddy who's doesn't
want to drive to the Midwest so check
them out if many of the viewers want to
I guess watch some awesome speakers
learn about buildings building soil is
more than anything I mean it's very much
like a hash Church in that sense you'll
just have some really great people
dropping some serious knowledge and it
goes on for hours and then you can talk
with them afterwards so it's I would
definitely suggest if you're in and
around the neighborhood I would drive
ours personally to go to go see that
just I'm sure they'll have great people
I think the Dragonfly earth medicine
crew is back from Bali literally the
next day they fly to Michigan so they're
gonna be there as well
yes yes good stuff Peter I really
enjoyed all of that that's that's key
information getting down this rabbit
hole a little deeper and just
understanding you know like what do we
want to be feeding this plant and how
did the variables change what we want to
be feeding the plant like what are the
ratios and how do they change when
suddenly we're growing in a different
altitude or we're growing in a different
environment completely with all
different variables and that's why this
plant just seems to offer us an
endlessly complex rabbit hole to dive
down into with all these other little
mini rabbit holes that go off the side
it's it's why so many of us have so many
different interests in this plant and
still can sit around and talk for hours
whether you're you know focused on the
science of it or you focused on the
biology or you're focused on the botany
or you're focused on whatever it is it's
it's pretty cool it's pretty cool it's
off
I'd say it's awesome yeah and there's we
got five hundred people watching from
around the world right now chatting
about and listening and I'm still
talking Joe and I explain how it breaks
breaks meter works yeah so it's it's
like a $6 tool
you can get it really easy it's like a
it's like a little metal thing about
this big and it's got a refractometer so
basically all you do is you grind up
like a leaf of a cannabis plant you have
to get like you know like a really good
grinder to get the juices out of the
leaf the SAP and then you take that
liquid and you just rub it on the the
the refractometer and then you look
through a little scope in light and and
then it shows you the number of of your
bricks reading and that that really
determines like the sugar level there's
a very small portion of that that's
actually the nutrients I think it's like
one or two percent of that bricks is
actually like your calcium your
magnesium your phosphorus all your
different things that are in that plant
but the higher the bricks reading you
know usually what we're seeing is the
more CBD oil that our hemp producers are
getting it's just like every time we
test non-treated treated bricks it's
like the the the the more oil the higher
the bricks reading and and and that
really goes back to your your soil macro
of your soil balancing so again on an
industrial scale to be able to come in
and actually quantify heterogeneous
soils and if they're conducive to the
hemp plant or not really takes a lot of
reverse engineering to get to a place
point where you can actually understand
the the soil physics the soil chemistry
in the soil microbiology comprehensively
to be able to gauge what you're going to
see at the end game and that's the
biggest thing that that is going to
hopefully lead us back man to more
sustainable regenerative cultivation
methodologies because you know it's it's
it's the route essentially of the core
the end quality is that soil right so so
man the the soil is so impactful in this
crop and it's the the most under you
know under discussed portion just that
that that whole system yeah you're tired
oh go ahead earth man you know
it's a secret it's the secrets that the
suits won't understand most of the suits
are just looking at trying to build
indoor crows they don't understand suits
and the roots and the roots welcome
Joshua we were just talking about your
conference Mike was giving you a shout
out
Peter was dropping mad soil knowledge
and I thought [ __ ] Joshua why should be
here dropping this knowledge with us
how's it going man good I love I love
that you're like working you're like out
harken I'm picks and pants and I just
saw that cooks down and saw the text
exactly so you got one more conference
going on in Michigan yeah we can
beautiful super excited yeah Shangri
loss is coming out excited to hang with
him okay and it's kind of it's kind of
nice to hold because Josh and Kelly will
be back in town they've been traveling
abroad they have they've missed the two
middle kind of conferences and so it
feels like we'll have the band you know
all back together
beautiful beautiful yeah that's awesome
yeah well it's funny too because Mike
was just asking hey what are you guys
all doing to get your your Gardens ready
for for the spring and then you're like
I'll and this and I'm doing that and I'm
like [ __ ] right
yeah actually just hey what's up brother
yeah thanks for the seeds have sprouted
already yeah this Wade laughter hey
thanks yeah yeah I was actually just
going through seeds uh
pulling out packs I got a lot of
generous gifts on my travels I couldn't
get it I didn't expect it to be honest
so I'm I'm gonna start some seats this
morning a bunch of cool stuff from
freeborn selections I got a couple packs
of his sky Cutler cush I'm super excited
about I got two you know I've heard a
lot of people talk about his stuff and I
got to smoke some down at Humboldt and
yeah anyways I'm just super excited
about that yeah how was the Kalle
conference the regenerative conference
down there it was awesome and it was
blew us away I mean the last two just
blew us away we had to actually change
locations at the last minute because we
had so many last-minute signups so we
had about 250 people there yes
rooms that's great news man really cool
because it's it's it's you know the
measurement is really to dig into the
science of how to do organic
regenerative cultivation and it's it's
still that's what we're doing and
teaching but it's also I've got an
aspect of community support that's
really come together you know I'm both
starting in Vancouver when we were up
there you know just seeing that the
clash between the suits and the roots
you know and it's big and it's it's
really cool how the you know the dragon
fires medicine cooperative has been kind
of forming and we're figuring out how to
establish ourselves what we want to be
but the power of small farmers coming
together is has really been a theme you
know that's gone throughout the
conversation well I'll tell you one
thing at that Vancouver lift conference
versus the regenerative soil and they
had tens of thousands of people versus
the 50 to 100 but all the best urban
hash was definitely at that regenerative
like conference I did not see anything
worth anything at lift it was just like
it was as my good friend Hillary said
this is just a bag of dicks I was like
it really is it's true man and it's you
know that's the one thing that's been
Matt been missing you know I know you
guys are talking about it but all these
big grows keep popping up and they can't
produce the high quality you know they
just thought the scenario for but as
small farmers have been doing it and
yeah it's it's just cool to see like the
people being able to rally together
instead of trying to come in
you know I'm my brand and here's my
t-shirt and you know everything we're
all just trying to survive in so we'd
you know but together I think you know
just like we used to move it around a
few friends at a time we'll have a good
market share you know and can put some
good quality herb on the table yeah
absolutely I don't think we're going
anywhere that's for sure especially I
mean from my perspective as a processor
I felt like we would have much more
success with the roomful of people that
you put together then we would with the
people that lift put together and not to
bash on left I I always have a good time
at lift
just saying it was very noticeable to me
when I left left and went to your
conference and was like okay so and I'm
pretty sure I even said it when I when I
spoke on the panel I was like these are
my people you know these are the roots
and over there are the suits and it's
just a different vibe yeah and we need
both to be honest to really get course
out in the whole world you know we're
talking about a different scene you know
we're gonna be most of the stuffs gonna
be going for oral you know we got to be
all inclusive to the people who have
you're just getting into the industry
the people who are just Church it's just
starting their businesses as well as the
a lot of us as well as the viewers or
people who range in experience that have
just are didn't growing their first
plant all the way up to been growing for
decades
oh yeah totally and exactly the roots
gotta educate the fruits and you know
what we're gonna want to talk about on
high level science is not gonna be what
the new people want to learn about but
you gotta start somewhere so conferences
as well I'm excited about the new people
personally because you know I always
said it when the industry was kind of
pre industry when it was just
prohibition and everyone kind of out for
themselves and they were just in there
little grows and they were just paying
their mortgage in their car payments and
it it was what it was but I would just
say that it wasn't the best of the best
there was some incredible people in
there but some really great people were
kept from entering into the industry
because of fear of losing their safety
in their livelihood and their families
and all of these other things that some
of us were just like [ __ ] it I'm just
gonna I'm doing this I don't care I'm
[ __ ] doing this whereas the others
we're kind of like now with the ability
to come in safely
first of all right off the bat what
we're seeing which is wonderful is a
huge influx of women into our industry
another and not because they're women
because that's [ __ ] you don't give
someone something just because of their
genitalia
but I see great women coming in not
because they're women but because
they're now ready to be a part of this
they're right they're like you know what
I've got something to offer and there
are a ton of them coming into the
industry and so that's let's put it
that's put a big smile on my face
because you know generally women are
naturally better at things like
nurturing and caring and you know people
it's time to show nurturing and
compassion to our soils man you're
absolutely right that's a great point
that yin and yang man it's nice the good
balance I I was just saying that the
other day it's that's funny industry day
panel and lift in Edmonton Calgary and
I'd say over 50% of the people on the
panel were women and just amazing
education coming out and have to say
over the holiday events I've done over
the years these last ones were all new
people but all professionals all coming
out of Harvard
coming out of colleges like really
really have been waiting for their
chance to come into this industry and it
was really actually rewarding to hear
the doctors and the specialists of
scientists and even these new testing
machine I was looking at yesterday that
works off a light I actually have it on
my phone it was
it's called [ __ ] sorry biz
no it's yeah complete test like this
little machine is the new complete test
they're testing all these new little
like I'm going to say industry gain
changes are coming to play right now so
these little machines are gonna be game
changers for these micro growers so they
can actually have these machines sitting
in their facilities where they belong on
the different TAC ttat you know CBD
getting into the heavy metals into
pesticide testing and stuff yeah HPLC
machines if you're saying yeah but this
is not gonna replace it I was really
cool it's called complete test and it's
actually by floral tuck and I actually
got a chance to look at this machine
yesterday behind closed doors with Remo
and they actually did some testing I was
pretty impressed it's not replacing an
HPLC or GC but it's able to allow some
you don't have to have any status to
calibrate this machine which is pretty
pretty amazing actually my mind I'm like
what about this for me is just a
difference in night and day but this is
what's coming to the industry right now
and I'm just I was like so excited to
even kind of look at this thing it it's
gonna be coming out we're hear more
about it in the future but even to
little little grinding machines that
testing humidity levels that test the
different cannabinoid levels for
patients so this was another machine I
saw and it collects the data onto an app
where actually they start seeing how
much they're using every day how much
you know what what's strange they're
using so they can actually patients can
start actually tracking you'll see
what's helping them and stuff like that
so all these new little things this is
coming out of Israel I learned about
this over the weekend looks like it's
exciting to see what's actually
happening we're actually getting this
you know this research we've actually
been all wanting for years for me it's
just like wow yeah there's there's
younger minds coming in like you to your
point for me being and now I mean we're
in Mass Massachusetts now we have
Harvard we have Tufts we have all these
gosh I have guys coming from UConn
cannabis you know called cultivation
program coming to us and it's really
amazing to see the the excitement and
and some of the skill level in terms of
Plant Sciences is pretty inspiring
because if you can they have the passion
you know it's it's a potent it's a
potent combo you know it's really nice
it's it's a beautiful thing we need air
to save on rep right now where is he
[Laughter]
that's a pretty big fatty you got going
on there Joshua yeah Partners gotta rip
the big ones yeah they do I agree
farmers gotta rip the big ones that's a
shirt it should be yeah I've just got
accustomed to doing the two or three
grammars a couple times a day rather
than stopping and hitting are these
small ones which is gonna how is to roll
but keep it going yeah right before I
stop smoking joints completely I was
smoking three to four grams and I was
smoking I was smoking a good five or six
of them a day it was it was a little out
of hand I was definitely living in a
cloud of
and one of the first things my wife
noticed when I started smoking hash she
was like wow like holy [ __ ] we were
living in a house fire buddy like I had
like I had three pounds of roaches when
I stopped smoking weed three pounds okay
I got garbage bags I feel like in my
freezer I just gave him away going
downtown little ziplock baggies of
roaches too you know people what was it
locks I only put privileges in glass
jars I'm not even joking
that's the pathetic thing I used to love
my roaches in my favorite thing but then
they just started building up and he's
kind of like started I I got a good road
story so I'm going through a you know
it's like it's late I probably shouldn't
have gone and eaten mushrooms and picked
up cannabis on this particular day but I
was pretty high on mushrooms and had
some cannabis with me and ended up
getting into a into a roadblock and got
into some trouble it was my it was my
case actually with the compassion club
got caught was 16 and a half pounds and
some cash and ended up in jail for the
night so I went to jail and I was all
bummed out I was like [ __ ] they took all
that beautiful organic weed I'll tell
you that jail smelled amazing every time
a new cop walked in they'd be like holy
[ __ ] Barry what's going on in here
like it was so stinky because they
opened it all and weighed it and so I
got I got out the next morning at about
10:30 1040a you know they gave me all my
stuff back and put me in my car and as I
was driving home this is when I still
smoke joints I was like hey I wonder I
was driving my wife's Jetta and I opened
the ashtray and it's just packed full of
roaches so I grabbed the biggest fattest
one I can find and I light that up and
I'll never forget driving up the sea to
sky highway I lit it up and I exhaled it
and I thought it's the haze it was like
the silver lining of the cloud you know
like it was just like it's the haze like
I just got all my weed and cash taken
away from me and thrown in
jail for the night and it's like I'm I'm
enjoying this haze joint right now like
I felt like it was a gift from the
police
like they just were like we'll just
leave him as roaches he's gonna need
that anyway that's a true true roach
story
one of the last roaches I ever smoked
actually but it was the haze there was
man it was the haze I even said it I was
like it's the haze so for those of you
that don't know I love the haze it is
actually my son's middle name I have a
big fondness for nice was there a
tipping point where you're just like
[ __ ] it no more joints well there was a
tipping point because what happened was
in 1998 I tried water hash bags for the
first time and I had tried them a couple
of times and I was like this is bunk
this is just [ __ ] there's nothing good
about this and then breeder Steve was
like hey try some of this shish-kebab I
just cut down its really beautiful trim
and so I ran the trim through these bags
that I had they were isolator bags and I
actually got something of like eye I got
a glimpse of it I was like whoa and so
within months I had my own bags bubble
bags existed and I started running all
these different peoples material while
when I started running Renee and it was
like all of the terpenes were preserved
from start to finish the tiny little
piece of the hash smelt like a bag of
weed it was just so over like just
flavorful to the max and I thought
that's really what destroyed joints for
me because I started smoking it like not
even realizing I wasn't rolling joints
anymore and I was smoking and smoking it
and smoking it well after about two
years of smoking at every single day
because I was blessed a friend of mine
had a hundred like bro and he would just
give me the trim every couple months
he'd just give me these huge giant bags
of Renee trim and it was it was a lot
and so when I went back to burn a joint
you know when I was finally like oh I
should just try a joint like what's up
what's up with me it smelt like smoking
well if it felt like smoking wood it was
just Burt I just tasted burnt it was not
a good experience and in fact I I kind
of was bummed out I won't
be honest I definitely didn't think like
I'm better than joints I kind of felt
like whoa like I ruined joints for
myself like [ __ ] and just can't do it
just even when I smell them in the air
I'm like that does not smell good to me
compared to like some full melt like I
just want full melt of all the varieties
that's what I prefer we all prefer
different things joints will always have
their place some people will always love
solvent extract and some people will
love their isolates some people will
like their distillate some people are
gonna like their traditional hashes
regardless of how they were made I would
never have it any other way thank God
that we all love things a little bit
differently about this plant and that
we're all not just the same robotic like
this is what's the best everyone agrees
there is no agreeance when it comes to
what's the best with cannabis that's why
the term the best is so ridiculous when
it comes to cannabis subjective way too
subjective yeah come on no this is the
best man this is the best I feel the
same way that Marcus like I still do
burn herb it's just not only if someone
has it around you know I really it's
just dude not even when Remo passes me a
giant fatty on camera and I know when I
say no 10,000 people are gonna troll me
or be like we're [ __ ] bubble man
thinks he's better than Remo just smoke
that [ __ ] joint you little douche bag
just like all these wonderful YouTube
comments I get and then poor Remo he's
like oh dude I'm so sorry I always
forget I'm like yeah dude it's all good
like you should never apologize for
someone else being a douchebag on the
internet you should always offer me the
joint and trust me when I sit with Remo
when he smokes a single joint he'll
offer to me like 19 times oh sorry dude
I'm sorry I do you want this no head
said Morpheus wants to say hi he's
sitting on my lighter and my hash and
yeah yeah so I gotta go feed him
something you guys alright there we go
what else what else more more on soil we
got Joshua popping in what were the big
highlights of your you know like what
what's
the real like allows people to break in
because I kind of feel like this
regenerative organic no-till like it the
rabbit-hole goes really deep with this
one and it's like it's complicated yet
it seems to be somewhat simple if you
just sort of learn the right things and
pay attention to the right things
what would you say at the last one in
Humboldt there was the real sort of the
the gem of the I think altogether it's
really learn how to use the microscope
and you know because everyone that's
coming to these conferences are tenured
growers and they all have like like you
said the best weed they've got their
practices and you know I always I kind
of use the analogy of cooking and baking
you know or how a lot of people say
thank you I can cook wonderfully but I
can't bake you know coz and it's because
when they open up the recipe they don't
adjust for their environment or their
oven or the humidity and stuff and so
some good growers good growers usually
have figured that out they just kinda
they have that sense and they you know
understand humidity and temperature and
control and how that affects soil and
but the real tried-and-true way is to
use a microscope so when you're you know
making compost teas and then pop buying
company making compost you're you're
assessing which guys are in there and
not just kind of guessing and and that's
you know we're all guilty of it I'm
guilty of it you know we get these
recipes we do these things we see
results and then we want to make it like
this this recipe thing in it just
doesn't always work that way so I really
it's interesting that you would bring it
to the microscope because that's
literally I feel how I was able to learn
so much about cannabis resin and hashes
and also share so much of it because the
microscope getting into those close-up
images where you're like oh what is that
exactly and there's something about I
mean we have these senses they're
obviously you know the things that allow
us to discover and to learn in this
world and seeing sometimes is such a big
one you can read about it you can learn
about it and then suddenly you see that
thing that you've been learning about
and something I mean with my photography
it was a guarantee I watched it happen
with people something just went click
before you know I released
Photography there was only a couple of
people you really had to go like to
Amsterdam and meet like you Dumas who
took these most beautiful unbelievable
trichome photos that he was taking in
the 80s with an electron scan microscope
I had never seen anything like it but
prior to that before I started doing my
own photography there really wasn't a
lot of people like almost none taking
up-close photographs of cannabis resin
glands and sistah with hairs and the
different types of bugs and so I was
using a camera not a microscope but a
macro lens that works very much like a
microscope so it's interesting that you
would say that no it's I mean it's just
what you need you start to get serious
about stuff you gotta really find out
especially these bugs you know we're
relying on bugs the whole system and
what bugs are there and how do they work
it you know same thing when you're
looking when you're assessing hash you
know I've said you know I've had sent
out material to folks that you know
here's a good mistake I made I pulled
tarp over a a OOP and I didn't have it
the dust blocking it so there was
getting despots onto the onto the head
so you know every time and so they
messed around and they sent me
microscope shots they're like look dude
there's dust in here what the [ __ ] you
know and there's all this agar in it was
for me and we figured it out and it was
you know it was pretty awesome you know
they were able to show me just like that
instead of being like nah man something
not right here
that doesn't help anybody the the
microscope and the rhizosphere like what
would a world for pictures if you could
actually visualize it so it's one of the
things that people don't really you know
think about a lot because they can't see
it Marcus and you're absolutely right
you know putting putting a visual for
for for us as a species to learn is so
much more comprehensive than something
that we can't see so so when you think
about the colors and the images and the
world that is what's happening on that
plants rhizosphere
which is what he's saying is almost the
foundation of sustainable regenerative
agricultural practices it's bringing in
that microscope and to actually see just
just as a weird example like what plant
parasitic mite nematodes are like
you know like like those are little
worms that not a lot of cannabis growers
know about and they're so prevalent in
sandy soils with with high moisture and
so to get a microscope and to see like
the beak or the still it of a plant
parasitic nematode like Malloy de chine
that's eating your fine root hairs which
are where all that cannabis trichome and
resin production really stems from that
nutrient dense base and you see the the
world right you guys are studying the
above ground with the trichomes but but
you get that plant in the other part of
it and and those those those fine root
hairs are what absorbing a lot of your
macronutrients and so the nematodes eat
those guys they eat them in abundance
yeah oh it's fine root hairs are just
gobbled up and then the nematodes will
actually go inside the root and that's
where like the disease can go in and and
again with this plant you don't see some
of those signs you just see low THC
production you see low CBD production
the plant isn't as big in biomass
because those those those that world in
there is out of balance and it's and
it's restoring it back to that balance
which is what I think this gentleman's
talking about with the regenerative
sustainable cultivation methodologies to
actually restore that with with his
compost he's and and getting that
microscope out and saying hey man a good
organic farmer uses three to five years
worth of heavy amendments and composting
and in teas and and humic acids and and
you know all these different natural
blends of nutrients that this plant
needs to to out balance the beneficial
microorganisms on that soil so that the
pathogens don't necessarily have the
competency to take over the community
what about host plants for beneficials
do you guys want to talk a little bit
about that I do I just want to hear what
Josh who I was gonna say cuz he looked
like
really I was gonna happen I can hop it
on both those but I was gonna say on
that good example so you have root
feeding nematodes and you discover you
looking at microscopy oh I got these
root feeding them a toads and so what
are you gonna do you're gonna buy
beneficial nematodes predatory nematodes
that are gonna eat those and then you're
gonna apply them right so now you've
applied them in here to your root zone
and now you want to go back and check to
see if it's effective and well you know
one guy that's actually super boredom
scuttle or granola I think he's been on
here before he's um been able to do some
you know look at some larger canopy
spaces where guys are doing this and
they're not applying evenly right there
at the beneficial nematodes so the whole
crop you know they'll have patches of
areas it will be successful and patches
of areas that aren't in there if you
didn't get in there with the microscope
and assess all the different areas you
wouldn't be able to confidently say that
you've dealt with the problem you know
you'd be kind of guessing and that's
what a lot of people do they they have
information they're like it's it's
partial information but until you
actually go in there and do the checks
and balances the befores and afters you
really are kind of shooting in the dark
and then you know about the beneficial
or banker plants that's more for for the
leaf surface you know for beneficial
insects that are eating you know the
pathogenic insects we were talking about
root zone stuff but yeah so there's you
know one of the things I learned in the
Lord at the roots trilogy as Jeff flume
feels likes to call it fungal hyphae
will actually develop loops that that
can ensnare the plant path in and genic
nematodes
but the beneficial nematodes are too
small so the beneficial nematodes don't
actually get killed by some of the root
fungal hyphae so if you do see that
those in your soil you can you know do a
cover from mulch and in that mulch throw
in some you know cover cover crops like
crimson clover that's going to provide
nitrogen but also doing things like
creeping time creeping rosemary mints is
all kind of be plants that naturally
exude terpenes both in there's leaf
surface but also in the roots
and the fungal hyphae will actually move
those mono-cyclic and bicycling
terpenoids around in the soil to your
cannabis plants it's actually you're
right on its nose right have those in
play you know a lot of people don't
understand and using mouth cries I fungi
which is what he's talking about is the
relationship is moronic Maya cries that
connection where the fungus is actually
harvesting nutrients and bringing it to
the plants and the plants are calling
for the nutrients they need at different
times and then they go out and get it
but the point I was going to make is it
takes 90 days to inoculate a root zone
with Mal quasi fungi a lot of people
don't understand that so if you're a
synthetic based grower and you're adding
mycorrhizae every time it actually makes
no sense whatsoever at all and and if
you're a living soil regenerative grower
you really need to have cover crops to
hold those those my friends I in place
where they can live while you're doing
you know your changeover and you always
want to leave your stalks and stems from
before and then you put your new plants
in next to it so they can just kind of
heart can kind of move over and you get
that benefit otherwise it's it's kind of
a waste of money yeah so if you guys if
you know the viewers are watching or
planting in planting crops into new land
you you got to realize it's gonna if
it's gonna take two three months to get
a stat a cover crops and mycorrhizae
fungi the network's established and
you're planning on planting in June
we're in March April May June you got
three months so now you know March in
April are great months to you know hit
your any new planting sites with cover
crops probably hitting them with a a
compost first you know or leaf mulch
that you can inoculate with a with a
fungal tea or bacterial tea and then
incorporating cover crops into that leaf
mulch so that it can start growing the
cover crop so that when you actually
start planting in May in June then we'll
actually already have some of that
beneficial bacteria Network already
built into your new net new soil beds
yeah I was actually gonna shout out so
there's one of the guys we've had work
with us is dr. Ephraim desire his are as
I was messin Flast name
he's at my co roots calm but what he
does is he just assesses my cries that
fungi that's his specialty and that's
what he's done for his whole career and
everyone knows him you know Jeff blowing
bells nose and Mullane nose and they all
send their stuff to him to get tested
and so I got introduced to him and and
he explained all this to me and
explained you know that most of the
stuff that's on the market has very
little mal Karzai in there at all you
know and you have to use a special scope
to see it and so what what we were
recommending is are legit that you go
and just have a sec when we were
recommending it at the conference is
that you know before you go and spend a
bunch of money on crack because you only
need to inoculate once you send it to
Efren to get tested and he would you
know test the viability of it and then
you know you then you go and spend you
know the kind of money anyway it's just
- just a plug in because he just did
send me it back he's got a him and his
son developed their own thing after like
he's been doing this for like 40 50
years a long time so mycorrhizae has
been around yeah microwaves has been
around since the Egyptian times right
they've they've quantified the the
efficacy of it through sporulation you
know it's it's one of those strains that
can take two to three months to really
gain a lot of traction so when you're
mono cropping unless you've established
a lot of that that mycorrhizae in there
which is in the air actually a lot of
times what we see as micro azide
populations increasing just with soil
porosity being increased and you know
the the bulk density being reduced in
that soil the the if there's a living
soil the respiration will actually
facilitate more mycorrhizae from the air
and actually colonize the rhizosphere
just you know we have Micro Z in our
lungs so it's one of those older strains
but you know as far as a simplistic way
to kind of blow more distance [ __ ]
mind or just a thought that I had so so
think about like an earth womb right so
I was at a bonfire last night with these
really cool guys man we started talking
about and
earth where you could actually in your
farm you could have like an earthing you
know type of experience where you lay
down and you just kind of skin touching
the earth right and allowing that
biology to reconnect with your skin you
know and then it kind of brings you to a
lot of is that biology touching my skin
gonna be conducive to my health how does
it make up my human microbiome you know
should I touch a lot of different soils
like farmers are usually pretty healthy
they're touching the soil a lot it's
it's it's that that soil microorganisms
touching the skin now what are the
correct microorganisms for that plant
that we've decided to put in there that
wasn't naturally supposed to be in this
soil so if we think that maybe our
microbes in our microbiome are coming
from our food they're coming from
touching the earth they're coming from
the air like mycorrhizae does so we're
constantly you know regenerating and
renewing depending on where we're going
depending on what we're touching the
actual microbes in our own bodies much
less what's conducive to the plant so
excuse me when we start talking a lot
about what strains are conducive like
mycorrhizae which again has been around
so's bacillus subtilis we have to start
looking at some of the different types
of acting oh my seed strains that are in
the soil that are conducive to to oil
production the raizou bacteria that are
gonna actually colonize and sustain and
regenerate on that root because here's
the thing compost has approximately 500
colony forming units per gallon of
compost tea so if you create anaerobic
houmous compost that's got clay
aggregates it's insoluble it's it's got
very high nitrate levels and it's
aerobic we produced and you make a
compost tea it's gonna have potentially
500 million colony forming units per
gallon okay so you you you can put a
million gallons of that in and Nan this
certainly give that plant the strains
that are gonna regenerate on its in the
rhizosphere because think about what
compost is its its crop residue it's its
animal [ __ ] and so you're getting
strains that are coming there they're
not raizou bacteria they're not strains
that are reproducing on that root to
really increase that nutrient absorption
for high bricks for high oil production
okay and so to do to replicate that on
an industrial scale it's very difficult
you know and it's in a small grow
operation you get these guys that you
know like this gentleman you know we're
focusing on the smaller grower we're
trying to put that quality into into our
soil but how are we doing that by
increasing the food sources for the
microbes by by adding the correct
amendments and the correct you know crab
meal or you know kelp or whatever you
decide to put into to to get that
biology going again on a large scale
especially in hemp production like in
Canada where these guys are doing
strains that are two or three percent
CBD what if those guys can get 6% CBD or
7% CBD in industrial strains and that's
possible if we correctly address the
biology on an industrial scale which is
which is what we've done with soil
balance so that's that's one of the
things that were really focused on is is
the population so taking strains that
have naturally co-evolved with the
cannabis plants in nature or and that
are in any soils that are conducive to
plant growth but there's soil
microorganisms and I really feel like
those those soil microorganisms when
people are starting to talk about
earthing or actually connecting their
skin to the earth and sleeping there at
night and feeling healed by the soil and
they're you know it's it's this it's
this thing that people are talking about
but but what are those microbes in those
footing they call it ground grounding
earthing or grounding right - yes that's
right and you know what that is I don't
know everything about it tell me about
it man well I don't know what ton about
it either but I read
article in this old dude and he got into
it and he literally like he couldn't
sleep I think it was like an insomnia
thing and then he got it in his head he
learned about grounding and walking
around in his bare feet and then he
grounded his bed he literally grounded
his bed to the earth and started
sleeping and so there's I'd have to look
it up but it was the first couple of
articles I read were about this
particular guy who was like he just
couldn't say enough about it how
important it was to have your bare foot
touching the earth at least biology man
like what we're [ __ ] hand sanitizing
all day oh my god on tour playing music
that's exactly what we'd all do we take
our shoes off and try to just find grass
and sand and dirt and get reconnected to
the earth because it was just it through
you so far off michael franti style he
just doesn't even put on shoes yeah yeah
if I could walk a mile in your shoes if
you could walk a mile in my bare feet
that's going to his lines can I jump in
here for a second I want a story we're
talking about grounding back when I was
learning how to grow cannabis I was
having to do it indoors and went through
a long steep learning curve about
everything from how to keep specific
genetics alive and viable over a period
of time to how to grow without having to
go to the store and buy a bunch of stuff
and I felt like I sorted everything out
pretty thoroughly and was getting pretty
good results already starting to do some
consulting in the Bay Area for folk who
were trying to grow indoors and produce
quality of medicine but I could tell you
were you asked us to think about our
relationship with the cannabis plant
Marcus and I could tell something was
missing in the flowering room when I was
in there I could just tell that they
weren't happy and so I was eight
and was sitting in there with with the
ladies and before going into meditation
I asked him just point-blank I what I
ran down the whole list of all the needs
everything from lighting to the right
kind of water to the right kind of soil
nutrients and microbiology and
everything else that I knew of to make
it all happy but I could still tell it
was missing something was missing and
and after a few moments I got it I got a
simple statement we are lonely and I
said what the hell what does that mean
what do you mean lonely and then I
realized that plants evolved in the
earth they're grounded they're hooked up
to the mother the earth has a natural
frequency of its own seven cycles per
second it's called ground you'll find it
in every at home that's wired to code
the vibration of life it's the vibration
of life and these plants were sitting on
tables in in bags totally disconnected
from the earth and so I did an
experiment I ran a length of romex wire
which is four strands of copper and
hooked four of them up to a water pipe
that was I knew was good to ground and
put the other end of each of those four
wires into force plants four separate
plants just stripped the length of bare
wire and stuck it right into the root
zone and had three other plants that
were the same exact plant same exact
conditions same everything I could do to
make a verifiable control for the
experiment and within a week just like
somebody was saying earlier they put
some microbiology in their room and saw
a difference in a week I saw a
difference in a week the plants were
half again bigger than their sisters
after a week and just to take the story
to the end right around the time they
were finishing a a crew from High Times
was visiting the room and
they commented on what the heck's up
with these four plants that stick out so
much from the rest of them in the room
and I pointed out the grounding thing
and all of that long story short what
was really beautiful about it is and
part of why I have to tell the story is
those four plants were the reason that
this the cultivar known as Harlequin got
its name because those four plants were
all kinds of different colors in a sea
of green plants that the seven plants
that eventually became known as
Harlequin were bigger than the other
eighty some plants that were in the room
but four of those seven had this insane
array of colors and that's where the
name Harlequin came to be and grounding
we are talking about grounding people
grounding plants that's part of why I
think the regenerative agriculture thing
is so beautiful
as I try and practice what Joshua's
workshop is about is finding that
microbiology and on your soil they on
your land where you are because where
nature is flourishing where you live
that's where that microbiology is
flourishing on soil that you have where
you live and so and a lot of that what I
love about this whole line of thought is
that is the idea that can--it the
cannabis plant if we will listen and if
we will look it will tell us how to take
care of the earth that we live upon and
maybe eventually when farmers start
seeing so much success with these
practices traditional agriculture will
start exploring what might be available
there because one of the things that
kind of rocked my boat a little bit is
glyphosate I saw a study was done
checking alcohol alcoholic beverages
that are available for sale they did
like 15 different beers and six
different wines
and all but one of them and several of
these were organic quote unquote wines
and beers all but one of them had
significant levels of glyphosate in them
so and cannabis you can't sell cannabis
in the California market place it's got
glyphosate in it so maybe cannabis is
going to lead us all towards a cleaner
life and a cleaner planet right and a
healing a healing yeah I'm so glad it
also talked to you about that in here
and hear that story thank you so much
for sharing that with us and with
regards to the the connection the
energetic connection that you put with
that copper wiring right which is so so
important when you're looking at the
different layers of true you know
sustainable regenerative AG to
understand not only the the energetic
layers but the the physical layers that
were working with those dynamics and so
just as a paradigm shift that's that's
happening right now there's so much
thought and an avulsion on the
energetics behind the cultivation right
and and that is is really what what
people you know geomagnetic flux lines
the dipoles the way that the the earth
energy works with all the different
dimensions but then but then going back
to the actual vitality of that plant you
know part of it is is is that energetic
but but but the vitality in humans also
is our microbiome you know when we look
at the the the different enzymes and
hormones and acids and chemicals that
our own microbiome is producing in our
body to keep us healthy to keep us
mentally intact to increase our own
alkalinity pH right to order higher
function cells in a human body
then there are human cells more microbes
right that's right yeah there's more
microbes but in the human is actually a
super organism that's you know
essentially an ecosystem of hundreds of
different types of organisms and so a
lot of what we're seeing
getting caused by current medical
tradition is you know over prescription
of antibiotics would wipe out you know a
broad spectrum of beneficial bacteria as
well as the bad bacteria which obviously
we want to get rid of the bad bacteria
but we'd prefer to out-compete the bad
bacteria so anytime people take
antibiotics they don't have to follow
that up with a rien oculi ssin of
probiotics that are going to be able to
re-establish that beneficial symbiosis
semiotic relationship within the human
body yeah you're sure the same things
happens with humans same thing happens
with plants and the better better that
we can treat that as a biodynamic
ecosystem the better you'll end up
saying you know not only your cannabis
plants flourish but you know eating your
berries diff you have berries on your
farm or fruits or trees growing them
organically symbiotically with cannabis
and cannabis will the cannabis terpenes
as they evaporate off the cannabis will
provide anti insecticidal properties to
the crops around it and there's a
symbiotic relationship in an exchange so
I think it's going to I hope and I'm
seeing it a bit I'm seeing new ops
farmers and apple farmers and even wheat
farmers rotating into their crops
because they think they they can get
more money growing industrial hemp than
they can't growing wheat or corn and if
they can grow it without having to use
the pesticide just in even in a rotation
where they can do a cover crop and then
hemp for high value and then follow it
up with the lower value crop and you can
get multiple years and then instead of
having to apply pesticides and
fungicides and nutrients doing cover
crops and and inoculating the cover
crops with bacteria so it's hopefully we
will see some positive change and I
think that that's that's going to be the
way that we can we can certainly
integrate into the existing systems of
Agriculture but be able to be the seed
be the tree
within the rock of the foundation of
capitalism that allows it to grow into
something better we want to we want us
our companies to go public and go into
international markets but at the same
time we want to do that sustainably
otherwise other people will do it more
efficiently so being able promote
sustainable agriculture and swell is
sustainable production efficient
production and then zero zero waste
production where every part of the plant
gets used is gonna really be able to
provide not only the farmers more more
economic means than they're seeing in
traditional or current agricultural
markets but a way more benefit to the
soil to the ecosystem and hopefully to
the consumers well sad men really well
said awesome thank you guys so much for
making the time and being passionate and
intelligent and being able to articulate
I I really enjoyed today's show it was
only a couple hours but it was good it
got I love the soil information I love
the microbiology I love the conversation
in general it's just an important
conversation and I don't think I
realized how important the conversations
that we had on here were when I was so
in it I was just trying to make it
happen but as I stepped back and I
looked at it and I watched it and I
didn't engage in it and I just let it
kind of dissipate I realized that this
is a missed conversation these
conversations although they are
happening pasturage is a really really
good way to hit seven to 10,000 people
every week those are good numbers that's
a good amount of people for us to share
this conversation with and obviously
what Josh was doing with the
conference's is super important to face
to face and the seed swaps and all of
that is super key but we're a part of it
too here on hash church so I want to
thank all of you just first for taking
the time you know and and showing up
every Sunday when it happens and and
being a part of the conversation so I
unfortunately have to bounce here for
11:00 so if you guys all
say your good-byes we got four minutes
for that thanks everyone's gonna say
thanks markets for calling me in and
thanks for the platform dude it's you
know I've been watching hashed Church
for a long time and you know super
appreciate the time you put into just
having the ongoing conversation beyond
dash into cannabis production and
regenerative and so thank you dude and
um yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna say goodbye
as well but uh thanks for having me on
don't do some greenhouse in yeah all
those drops for sure on soil match up
I'm sure everybody's gonna watch this
episode over and over again like I will
when I get off of it thanks guys all
right everyone I'm gonna call it a day
Colin and Wade and Johnny B and dr. mark
my heater all thanks so much guys
pleasure hiring we're looking to hire
hash makers Oh
where did they send it you could
probably reach out to me just on social
media or just on the chat room here or
whatever we're in several different
positions over the next of the next year
is probably I would say about six to ten
people being hired good make likewise
man I think it's like I'm gonna I'm
gonna piggyback you on that I'm looking
for Co two people to run Co to where
we've got our solving the slabs all
covered but you never know if someone's
out there that's looking to go to
Massachusetts and process with us we're
looking for talented individuals I'd
love to have you on the team and I'm
just looking for people out there to be
happy and to be successful and to be
healthy and to be loving and to be
empathetic and to be compassionate and
if you can do that while finding
yourself a great job in the cannabis
industry then win-win for everyone peace
out everybody PC next week