button okay so there's a few things I'm
GNA have to do I'm gonna have to turn
the volume down real quick on this new
one do a quick copy and paste over to
this old
one get them all organized into the chat
and then we'll start this uh episode
thanks for your patience everybody let's
see if I can fit that in there all alone
today usually there's a few people that
have come into the room by now but
that's okay cuz we certainly know that I
can talk and talk and talk if need be so
I will say welcome everybody to Hash
Church 3.0 episode
23 uh let's see how we do here Johnny
bees texted me which is perfectly on
time all right we'll just wait for the
friends I did send out the link
yesterday fairly late so I don't exactly
know
um who is going to um be involved looks
like things are a little okay yeah yeah
yeah we're good what's up magma seeds
hermano Jason S Boulder the Underhill
yes everyone was in the wrong room as I
for whatever reason I'm not quite sure
how to set it up so when I go when I
create the YouTube live video that it
goes live with the actual Zoom video it
creates a new YouTube video but uh
welcome Wade how are you doing this
morning morning uh I'm good
Marcus hear you great week so far how
about you I need to put these on
probably have see if I can't get these
on does everyone here wait or is it just
me I'm going to go real quick here
now we're good waade I I bet you I can
hear you now I had my speaker set up as
my
microphone ah yes I was GNA say I
couldn't hear you but I can hear you
great now thank
you I had a uh great time at the
Patients Out of Time conference this
past week and Colton Turner was one of
the
presenters remember Colton yeah
yeah how was that tell me more um it was
excellent it was uh Thursday through
Saturday Thursday was on regulations and
uh obstacles to research sat Friday was
uh the latest research some pretty
amazing papers were presented and then
Saturday was the
clinicians and one of the case
presentations was done by Colton about
himself
that's so awesome it was it was great
especially at the end they had this Q&amp;A
thing for the faculty that presented and
you got all of these distinguished
clinicians many of whom I know on the
zoom call and then there's Colton who
was just really far out man I think
he'll probably be in that crew one of
these days good morning
Mark yes hey guys how are you good Mark
it was really weird when I just joined
there was this automated recording that
came on saying that this is being
recorded did you hear that two way okay
well the reason that is is because
usually yeah I I usually you guys have
been showing up lately and then I go
live on YouTube and go recording but I I
went live and I started recording
earlier I guess that's a legal message
to let you know that hey if you don't
want to be recorded don't come into the
chat
room yeah the last little window before
you go live says do you consent to be
recorded or something like that
okay see welcome to the big time
Mark yeah well it's like you know it
could be intimidating for people like
Sam right maybe that's why he's not here
yet ah he's like [ __ ] that I'm not gonna
be recorded I had even thought of that
wow
yeah how are you guys
doing doing really well I'm still
farting around with my um I just want to
make make sure that I sound better
they're all bummed out they're saying
it's uh grainy this I'm listening to
chat room yeah I just changed my
microphone from these ones
to to my actual microphone so that
should be better it won't be quite as
bad hopefully the connection comes in
I'm actually trying out a new internet
service today I just TR uh set up my
star length yesterday on the roof there
so it's brand new it's in beta so I'm
just I do have another internet to back
it up in case I have problems but uh for
now this is uh this is what we're doing
and no this is not a recording this is
um yeah this is live live with Dr Mark
and uh with Wade laughter we're here in
hash church I set the link out really
late last night as I've been putting my
son to bed for the last month um trying
to give my wife a little bit of a break
of every single night having to do the
same thing and you know sometimes when
you work all day the you know your wife
is like oh I feel bad you worked all day
well so did you you also worked all day
with kids which is even harder than
working all day at a job so for the last
23 days I've been putting my son to bed
and I generally fall asleep with him at
around 9 o'clock I I can't stay awake
when I put him to bed so uh yeah if it
was a little bit of uh but that gets you
up at like 4 in the morning right well
we definitely get up pretty early I'm
not going to lie I've been up for hours
right now not quite 4 but probably you
know a little bit just a little bit
after 6:00
a.m. so that's once the birds start
singing especially here in the
springtime it it becomes difficult
because um it just it's such a great
thing to hear birds in the morning I
mean I love it yeah
I'm with uh with some people who sleep
with their windows open it's just it's
so loud that there's no way you can get
back it's true uh both both in the
morning and at dusk the birds are so
loud here at dusk it's incredible
they're flying around from tree to tree
I'm really right smack in a in a in a
forest so it's uh no shortage of
incredible birds in fact my son found a
bird yesterday a little baby had fallen
out of his nest in one of our Hedges and
uh yeah
he found him saved him helped Birds
aren't real they Birds AR I've heard
I've heard of this birds are some kind
of alien robots that fly around well
this
one yeah right it looked real though I'm
telling you I know they're not real and
all I don't want to be uh laughed at or
whatnot but where did that come from how
did we get into that how did it I I've
understand all these wild conspiracies
but when did we like who who was like
birds aren't real like where did that
one come
from not an ornithologist for sure
on Josh hey guys how's it
going Josh can you hear me I can hear
you it's just uh we got double Josh
there for a quick second ah nice double
Josh Rutherford
nonetheless all right well we got Josh
Rutherford and then we got dragonfly
Earth medicin Oh I thought there's the
other one coming too so we got three
joshes oh snap you guys are the
uh minorities here in the in the in the
room how's it going man how are you guys
doing couple of live living soil guys in
the
house um doing really really good the
Farm's looking amazing we're about ready
to get a week of rain and all the
plants now that we're in a waxing moon
phase are there's enough Heat at night
and enough you know warmth during the
day that the plants are kind of doing
their Fibonacci doubling process so
we're getting a lot of growth right now
and it's a lot of fun to watch yeah I
you know John brought me these monster
plants just just a couple of them you
know two or three of them the other day
and uh they've only been on my deck for
a couple of days but I'm saying I'm
thinking they've grown about a foot to a
foot and a half these bushes they were
just big round bushes and now they've
got these you know these piece these
giant just coming all off the top and
it's I haven't grown in so long you know
I'm so I I envy what you guys do and I
love growing and I love getting my
fingers dirty and I love the whole
concept and idea I just personally have
not had a lot of time to do it so um
good old Johnny B shows up with some
plants and I'm back in the game and uh
it's fun right there's like this the
nervousness of wanting the plants to be
healthy and happy and give them
everything they need while just being
like Oh my God I got to give these
plants attention and love and focus and
even three monsters I'm uh I really have
to make time for because they you know
they drink 15 to 20 gallons of of water
every day they're
thirsty just like your son they have
needs they have needs they have needs
and their needs must come before my
needs sometimes you fall asleep with
them don't
you absolutely absolutely I was on my
roof yesterday and I was happy to see
them poking up above the the second roof
I could see them you know they're
they've got got to be over 10t tall
right now so only Johnny B would just
bring me three 10 foot tall plants in
the back of his truck and I'm in the
meantime I'm like please tell me you
didn't put those into the truck yourself
because he's he's got a disc thing going
on right now he's got some pretty major
pain he was in and out of the hospital
and I just the last thing I want Jon to
do is uh destroy himself through
kindness so luckily he got his neighbors
Mike and Hy to put the plants in the um
in the back of the truck and I got got
my 17-year-old son heos as we call him
uh to uh to lift out the uh to lift out
these plants you know Johnny B style he
didn't wait for them to get like dry he
he moved them like fully fully like 80
plus pounds per per
plant uh but that's what's great about
having a 17-year-old son for any of you
whose son has not reached that age yet
man you can't you can't imagine how
amazing it is when your son just can
lift and carry everything no wonder
people back in the day on farms just put
their kids to work I mean it's funny
that we got all into this thing like oh
they're making kids make shoes and it's
like child labor it's like have you ever
grown up on a farm because child labor
is how that [ __ ]
operates and in some cases in Ontario I
I've heard this story many times there's
like you know women who have 20 kids I'm
sure you've heard that Marcus oh yeah oh
yeah 20 and 23 children on the farm and
stuff and it's just it's a true
mindblower definitely it's your crew
right it's your crew I can definitely
say Sky's 24 now and he's a complete and
total force of Nature and we we joke
around about being um strong because
we're really into being strong but then
we have this inner Sasquatch strength
that you can like tap into when you
really need to go farther than your
actual strength
we we
we you amazing and and now hit with his
with Sierra on the farm you know and and
Kendall and we have this amazing you
know early 20 we have amazing you know
small crew that really is uh amazing the
work they can do so yeah it's it's
amazingly
valuable that's awesome I don't doubt
that whatsoever that uh sky is a force
to be reckoned with 24 years old now too
hey that's uh unbelievable my daughter
just turned 20 and my son will turn 18
in September and my other son will turn
seven in August so that's so
awesome yeah it's it's it's amazing and
um you know just feel really blessed I
just feel really blessed to have have
them around and have them be so charged
up about our lifestyle and everything
that we're doing and you know it's it's
obviously their calling in life as well
um yeah so one thing I just wanted to
bring up on the show today which is not
about cannabis but it is about
environments is I'd love to bring
attention to the fery Creek Watershed
and the forestry that's going on over
there um there's uh only 2%
you know old growth left in British
Colombia virgin old growth forest left
at all
and it's on occupied lands First Nations
lands Ferry Creek Watershed outside of
Port Renfro on Vancouver Island the
local government here and NBC is the NDP
and they are
uh raising the The Cutting of by 43% of
old growth forests and there's only two
2.3% old growth even left in BC so
they're they're they're basically out to
attack and and murder the rest of our
intact environment in in America in the
United States most all of the old growth
is already in protected forests there's
really
no that's not already in National Park
so there's tree sitters they're first
tree Sitters of people that are sitting
in trees for over 30 years there's
there's activist people sitting in trees
trying to stop loggers are laughing at
them they're stealing their stuff
they're they're they're T they're taking
down their camps the RCMP are basically
private mercenaries for this for this
land occupation and for this type of big
business they're out cutting, 1500 year
old trees right next to people sitting
in trees they're taking chainsaws to I
don't know if anyone's ever smelt a
yellow cedar but a yellow cedar doesn't
actually doesn't grow in in in Oregon it
doesn't grow in California or Washington
it's like a Alaska and British Columbia
thing that the smell the incense like
that that the odor that there's
something totally otherworldly about the
yellow
cedar and um I just really want to
activate people to make phone calls to
John Horgan's office and to krine
Conroy and to the BC
RCMP and to all other people that they
find in their own network the teal Jones
group who's doing the cutting and and
let that the people know that we're not
okay with losing our last intact
environments once these trees are locked
they'll never be replaced the these
environments will never be replaced
they're 14 and 18 feet across which are
really really big for Cedar where Craig
is down in the in in in the Redwoods and
over in the Sierra Nevadas with the
Seas there's trees up here that rival
those redwoods there there's 300 foot
tall
ceders in this Forest that's being ready
to to get cut which are among the
tallest trees in the world like the
Redwoods
so it's all I can think about right now
I I
feel extremely passionate as well as my
family it it right now in British
Columbia Wood prices are through the
roof so everywhere you go in the forest
right now you're hearing chainsaws and
trees falling it's like a
genocide on cedar trees the cedar trees
are so valuable right now that private
land owners are just raking down their
land private logging companies are
raking down their land and it's and and
raw log exports is another thing for
people to be aware of raw log exports
there's something like
cubic three 230 million cubic feet of
raw log exports a year coming out of
British Columbia
we're talking about massive ships with
just raw logs thrown on them so am I
talking about no logging no that's not
what I'm talking about I understand that
there's a place for logging and and
sustainable harvesting and I and I know
that and I understand living in wooden
houses and I get that what we're talking
about is logging an intact environment
that'll never be replaced when you when
you talk about beautiful when you talk
about British Columbia it's beautiful
British Columbia or Supernatural British
col but the government is sanctioning
the destruction of our environment and
it's not okay with us and I just really
want to encourage people to to step up
and to call look at our story and make
phone calls if you can if if you feel
like you have time to make those phone
calls to let the the people know that
our voices have been
heard thank you so much for letting me
say that um it's really important to me
and I appreciate hash church I
appreciate the family part of our
activism is cannabis part of our
activism is in psychedelics and another
part of our activism is in saving our
lands because without our lands there's
no health and and just one more time the
RCMP are targeting indigenous people on
their
lands it it's it's the the word it's
everything that you read in your history
books happening right now in the forest
it's not history it's present day
occupation thank you so
much thanks for sharing that Josh
definitely pretty [ __ ] up to be
thinking about these trees just uh that
take hundreds of years to be produced to
grow into the the the
Magnificent beings that they are and
then to just have like chainsaws you
know the just I'm a I'm a I've lived on
my property for 11 years and I've never
cut a tree I live in a neighborhood
where people are obsessed with cutting
trees because they want to have a
view and I like trees in my view I
wonder if these people when they're done
with getting rid of all the trees in
their view if we'll also drain the ocean
so we can see the bottom better I don't
know I hope not uh but it does seem a
little bit mental in my neighborhood
today and I'm happy to say I only
noticed this a couple Sundays ago and
it's really not probably that big of a
deal but every Sunday I hear chainsaws
in my neighborhood every single Sunday
so I guess you know some lady got on to
the Lion's Bay board and she passed a
little ordinance and now it's Sundays
are quiet Sundays so you can't go like
Leaf blow and turn on your CH you can't
turn on your chainsaw the noise was the
least of my worry it was and for any of
you that have ever watched my videos and
I have over a thousand of them on
YouTube you'll remember random chainsaw
guy that I used to always mention
because any anytime I went out onto my
deck to make a video any time of day or
night some [ __ ] would have a
chainsaw going like two seconds I turned
the camera on i' be like hey
everybody like what the
Yeah we missed that but it was kind of
perfect I think yeah perfect yeah I I'll
just you know some of these native women
like these Elders that are getting
arrested right now like uh
have are are were
were they've had to deal with laws where
only no more than four indigenous people
could gather
together what these native Elders have
lived through laws where they could not
gather we're not talking about Co no
we're talking about you can't be more
than four native people at once or
you're against the law what has and and
and also residential schools
you know where they're taken out of
their lands and and to maid speak
English and to disconnect them from the
land these are the people getting
arrested today and yesterday for
protecting the last remaining old growth
in British
Columbia yeah it's pretty [ __ ] up we
should uh welcome uh Colin and Craig
from alpen glow into the room they just
showed up how are you guys
doing doing really well man thanks for
uh thanks for having us and uh thanks
for sharing that Josh it's uh always
important to you know
voice as much as we can uh to all
communities so they can uh you know join
and be a larger voice together um nice
to see you Craig always a big fan of
your work out
there thanks for being on with us
yes good morning and thank you Josh for
Rolling that out I've been following
along in the stories and doing uh a
small share of reposting and just trying
to bring some awareness and this is so
real and it happens here in our our
community as well um those of you that
have driven the 101 through the uh
humble Mendo State Line like we're
battling
calr there because they want to widen
the road so trucks could go bigger
trucks and could travel through there
and faster and right now it's like we
call it the Redwood curtain because they
have to a certain length of semi need to
unhook and get put on by a little
tractor uh semi to pull it through there
but it also slows everyone down to 40
miles an hour and and it's like it's
almost like going to church for a minute
like we go 65 forever and then it's like
just slow down
and and appreciate what we have um but
yeah Josh you you brought up a lot of
valid points like you're seeing I live
in a wooden house and these fur beams in
my house came from my land and I cut
those down um we have our land
personally was was pretty hammered by
the loggers and grew up all at one time
um there's a couple seed trees left here
or there so we are taking the chainsaws
out and doing a bunch of man agement
because what's grown back has grown back
as as Mother Nature didn't really
plan and in time it would correct itself
you know it's it's choking out some of
the smaller species and they're falling
and and we have this dead and dying
thing happening and you know uh bringing
back the carbon sequest sequestered
carbon back into its own ecosystem but
with the fire danger we have right now
we can't wait for mother nature so we do
have to step in do some of our own
management practices um just in our
little footprint here um but we are
doing we're chipping it and we're we're
using that to build soil and so forth
but I think those of you that are
listening that are hearing the talk
about trees I think you really have to
have critical thinking and I so much of
that critical thinking is gone out the
window these days it's it's with Corona
and all these other things folks have
just thrown the critical thinking out
and it's it's platforms like this that
help us bring these Minds together and
and share our thoughts and thank you
Marcus time and time again for holding
space for all this community and
everyone here um we appreciate you um
for what you're doing thank
you appreciate the kind words very nice
to uh start it off with some realness
this morning you know like uh I
personally absolutely love visiting old
growth forests I have a cedar Forest a
standing Cedar Forest that's just up the
road uh just up past Whistler we have an
ancient Cedar forest and they're pretty
big trees 20 to 25 feet in diameter
they're impressive they take your breath
away of course toino MIRS Island um some
really beautiful trees out that way as
well and it's just such a shame to to to
see them be cut down and even for people
that were here you know back in the day
when logging was happening in the 50s
and the 60s it was really just one tree
that would hit the that would hit the
truck at a time now you see these
logging trucks yeah like one tree for
multiple trucks even um oh look at that
nice little treats Sharon oh yeah you
know I hope Brian shows up from best
friend Farms because he's been doing
these incredible like cookies and like
donuts and like just kind of like they
look really like a treat that you would
would eat and uh I meant to mention it
last week but we got sucked so far down
the rabbit hole of sensory science uh
that it he by the time I went to go see
if he was in the room he had bounced he
had some problems with his um with his
internet so hopefully he comes back in
I'm about to Puff A little dab of some
120 Micron strawberry banana this
[ __ ] this is definitely what dreams are
made of right here let me tell you if
this right here this is literally how we
could stop these [ __ ] from
cutting down trees because I'm telling
you a couple of heroic dabs of this and
there's just no way that those people
are going to decide that yeah this is in
my best interest and wow as humans we
get caught up like you could you could
just feel the polarity the tension
between a logger and an activist you can
you can just the way we just have these
different mentalities and I can't help
but feel that the compelling of speech
speech is getting us into a very
dangerous position here in life as we
start to compel speech there are certain
things we can talk about and there are
certain things we cannot talk about and
if we talk about those things we will
ostracized we will be ridiculed and we
will be punished and I'm not necessarily
talking about any one particular thing I
just you know for a long time this
Jordan Peterson guy was like listen this
isn't about these issues it's about
compelling speech
and controlling speech and we are now
getting into a level of compelling of
compelled speech that maybe we've never
seen before in the history of our
species and um I hope one day that it
doesn't become you know insane to talk
about saving trees I hope one day that
they don't decide to ostracize us and
make us look like uh conspiracy freaks
because we think that trees produce
oxygen and that we want some of them to
be alive because I see a lot of things
getting cast into that sort of well we
can just disregard that because we have
this argument against that plus we've
compelled speech so they're not really
allowed to talk about that anymore
anyway freaks me out a little bit in the
meantime I'm G to have a little
dab Marcus I uh I kind of resemble that
remark that you just made about if we
had a few more light depths of
strawberry
banana just planted one I don't know if
you guys can see it up there on my big
flat yeah right on we planted it into
native soils um I've I've been starting
to utilize this technique of uh
trenching with a a a trencher making
just a little cut because we have where
we have Clay and Shale it is so
compacted like it's ridiculous um from
some of these logging sites so I've I've
tried this technique where I'm trenching
down and then putting the wood chip and
uh inocular ated straw and building
soils that way and then putting putting
a little bit of locally sourced Nursery
stock soil just around the the plant
itself so it can go out and give it
itself a minute um and uh it's it's
coming along nicely and I I'm excited to
see how this one comes out it's the
first time I've done it as a light dep
I've done it as fullterm where you have
more time for those roots to get
established and tap into the biology
light up is a interesting one to uh do
in Native oils um as some of you know it
it takes just an extra minute you have
to be a little more patient but once it
kicks in it's it's
phenomenal
cheers uh does your trench drain water
or does it hold water when you make it
Craig yeah so uh Josh you've been here
and down at our Huckleberry flat place
the lower place that we actually sold
that was more of a Shale finger of the
of the mountain and there it actually
functioned really nicely and that's
where we went a bit deeper and we put a
lot of wood chip in the bottom of that
one so it would be a sponge and capture
the water before it just drained down
through the shell in this one I had a
problem even with a
trencher getting through the the hard
pan clay like it was just like bouncing
um so this one I really feel it's going
to hold water and we are being super so
it's the opposite now so instead of
trying to create a sponge at the bottom
and hold water that was passing through
this one will be using just minute water
and then a bunch of this wood chip that
we've we've recently made we've put in
the pathways and and along the edges and
actually part of the technique is
prepping the flat before we even operate
the trencher so um sometimes if we have
the time we would um put down a loose
fill straw kind of the Ruth Stout method
so loose fill straw and then two inches
or so of uh raw manure let that sit over
the winter then trench and then you're
bringing the native over it like a
lasagna layer and you know I'm not one
for using
mechanized uh tools but sometimes when
you're on the mountain you don't have a
choice and you bring them in one time
and then you're good but the tailings of
the trencher are really nice it's really
nice structure to it and it it it makes
a really nice lasagna layer now up here
um we didn't have the time so we did the
we did the straw wood chips and then we
let the chickens out on it for two weeks
and the chickens went through and got
all the hay seeds out and you know uh
inoculated with their with their manure
um and then we trench and then when we
bring that native soil on top it keeps
that clay tailing from becoming Anor
robic um and that's also really
important with the the manures as well
so now we have that um on top and then
we will come through and probably put a
really light layer of wood chip um and
then I also picked up some spawn blocks
from mushroom Mike um and I'll be
inoculating that the pathways first and
then with a pathway being like that
thick with uh wood chip we will uh
inoculate that and then we'll come in
with um some compost te and just dump it
and dump it and dump it and let that be
the biology spread out in
on there you can spread that on your
aisles you know little seed of some
biology from different places and over
the year your aisle is creating the
indigenous microorganisms because when
you use rice to create indigenous
microorganisms you're going to get a lot
of trichoderma you know the green molds
that come on under heavy and and
trichoderma and and no one's actually
testing the species on the rice so when
you use more locally sourced raw
materials to build your indigenous
microorganisms then you're going to get
more diverse biology from your region
because rice doesn't grow in your region
so how is biology going to have the
intelligence to propagate itself only
certain things will propagate itself so
really by using wild brasses and leaves
and your indigenous soils coming up
manures mushroom blocks these are all
things that grow in the region and have
a more complex carbohydrate a more
complex carbon for biodiversity which is
really what we're looking for so I
really love that you know you're taking
on the aisle Tech and that that's not a
word but it maybe it is now but you know
the Isles are there's so much Earth that
can come from there for the next year
and and I love you Melanie
congratulations you are amazing thank
you for your passion and you know and
your uh your completion of your uh
education that's really a really big
deal we all love you so much and you
know that well thank you Josh I
appreciate it it's quite an
accomplishment and it feels amazing um
to be done and um it amazing it's
amazing just to want to keep going too
right it's going to be uh really neat to
see what you know what the future holds
for all of us and thank you to my
husband for the support oh thank you
have a good time
and of course the two beautiful girls of
course yeah you know one one thing that
Melanie is going to be going on and and
teaching is public speaking and all of
us realize what an important tool that
is you know we can have these
regenerative tools we can have these
political views we can have this
activism but without being able to speak
and deliver it properly and accurately
um' be lost so I sure appreciate her and
and more so just
um to find what's inside of ourselves
and be able to express that
authentically in our way so me me
expressing myself the way that Melanie
does is different than the way that you
would or that Josh would or you know
it's it's just encouraging people to
trust who they are and trust that they
can express themselves in a way that
that is like
them original thought is um lacking
these days so that's why it's important
to turn off your electronics every once
in a while and go experience yourself go
experience your surroundings go
experience your cannabis go touch your
soil go be in tune with intuition
because intuition and and and feelings
it it's it's it's learned it's it's a
it's a muscle it's it's something that
you that you get you have to you have to
teach yourself I mean people that are
remote viewers or people that are
intuitives they they work on it you know
so you know let's work on using our
voice let's work on our original thought
what's authentic to us it's important to
be part of a group too because Community
is part of our our our importance but
you know bringing original thought to it
is extremely important Johnny be's in
the
house have time Johnny be in the house I
would say what Josh was just saying is
to spend time with the
sublime because the sublime is humbling
and you
will we'll all be a little bit
the way I put it the other day to a
friend is you know what we'll be a lot
less dicks if we're just we'll be a lot
nicer if we can just share time with
this humility and that is to stare the
sublime in the face go jump off a
mountain go snowboard down a mountain go
spend time in a garden go out in the
middle of the ocean and feel how
insignificant you are because um yeah
it's it's okay to be humbled the world
could use more of
it good morning morning
everybody we're growing hemp right now
from Daryl Hudson and in planta
[Music]
and you know the
valov does everyone know who Nikolai vov
is uh just curious but anyway in in the
1920s Nikolai vov travel World
collecting cannabis seeds and also other
and created The vov
Institute now he was one of the fourth
foremost genetic seed collectors of the
world at the time but over the course of
the years he became ostracized by the
community and eventually jailed and then
eventually starved to death in jail now
The vavilov Institute still exists and
has lots of seeds um also uh you know
that combined with the historical hemp
of China um we're we're we're we're
looking at at hemp in a different way
right now because yeah High CBD is super
important it's an obvious medicine um
but food and fiber coming out of hemp is
going to be what saves us from the
forest industry or potentially Bill
Gates uh you know whole meat thing or
whatever to save the the Earth and stuff
like these seeds are the largest seeds
I've ever seen and they grow up to 18
feet tall and have giant stocks and they
can outproduce the forest industry in
cellulos and fiber by I don't know the
number four to five times you know they
way outproduce Timber sales when it
comes to biomass and when it comes to
say pellet fuel or C creats and stuff
so we are putting our best foot forward
to continue these genetics outside of
CBD outside of medicinal and and
continuing the work of food and fiber
hemp you know because this this is part
of what makes cannabis the master plant
that it is you know you don't become a
master plant in evolution without having
you know thousands of uses and uh that's
what this plan offers and and we know
that um so I feel really blessed right
now to be able to stand in the presence
of thousands of years and hundreds I
think every cannabis plan is is a is a
thousand- year old you know
multi-generational creation whether it's
a hybrid or from an ancient stock but
being able to reinvigorate that ancient
stock is pretty phenomenal and I'm want
to go grab the seeds real quick so you
can see the size of them I did do a post
of them and some people saw them but
I like that check that out I love that
that's that's what that plant can I feel
like I feel like Sam showed me the
biggest and the smallest seeds I've ever
seen in my life and he did it like all
within the same like 30 second span of
time and and the smallest
ones I uh got from cashmere and the
biggest ones from Yan but I did work
with a Vala for five six years and uh
I had access to every seed they
had but did they have access to every
seed you had did you have access to
seeds let's see that look let me get
this in my
hand are these the Walnut
seeds
yeah let me see if I can
should I get a
scale yeah I'm
curious biggest I ever biggest I ever
had with 12 to one
gr I love that Sam has a reference
point like just think just think of that
for one second okay he's going to weigh
these monster seeds and Sam says to him
oh the biggest ones I ever had had were
12 to 1 gram who [ __ ] knows
that you know I I don't I don't know how
many how much my seeds weigh
particularly but I know how many fit on
a teaspoon of my legacy genetic you know
so I know I can take a teaspoon and
that's about a
100 and you're like you're that's like a
lid that's an alpen glow lid is that
what you're saying yeah yeah a
spoon that's awesome very cool I can't
wait to see how much these seeds weigh I
want to see how many he gets in a gram
the ones Sam put in my hand literally
were like small walnuts I I remember G
laughing when I first saw them I was
like this is ridiculous and those were
not the most insane seeds Sam ever put
in my hand because the most insane seeds
he ever put in my hand were like from
some burial from like 2,000 plus years
ago he's like check these out and I was
kind of like what what are these like
they look really
old this is from the 100th anniversary
of the Balo
Institute oh nice how old were those
seeds that you had from like the burial
uh oh those are uh I think 1700 years
old almost 2,000 years
old those seeds were the seeds that was
the only cannabis thing I ever held in
my hand that I really like the hair
stood up on the back of my neck when I
realized what they were and of course
you know Sam just throws them at me like
they're nothing just like what
valof institute folks took me over to
the Hermitage Museum where the seeds
were from the uh
uh it was from the roseno burial tomb
where he roseno is the one who dug it up
and they found uh these you know uh 1700
2,000 year old seeds and they gave me
eight of them that they found in a
little little Leather Pouch buried uh
under the ground with all kinds of other
cool Treasures from the
cynthian did you try and germinate them
Sam oh yeah so I've got him going right
now in my
backyard no they they were completely
dried out and uh you know there was no
oil in them
at all anymore they they were bit though
may maybe they were okay when they dug
him up because it was in the whole tomb
was buried in ice for all this time but
what happened was uh they started the
museum for you is 20 30 years before
they came to
meet and they were almost 2,000 years
old
so I want to see these seeds Josh are
you weighing those seeds over there I
think we just realized Josh still lives
in the days of paranoia and his scale is
out in an olive Barrel like in the back
40 I gotta go dig it up it's funny back
within the hour
Triple Beam it was pretty
funny if these Hills could talk yeah man
that's
awesome so Dr Mark what's going on man
how did the uh how did the test go with
the uh I believe you you were telling me
you had thcv and uh or cbdv I I can't
remember what can what novel cannaboid
you you're you you got a new line on
that you're trying to to work
with what what what company was that and
what what canabo no so it was a company
that was selling uh thcv
isolate and um uh the
company um is called Snapdragon CBD and
they're at of Tennessee and they were on
the Adam dun show and Adam or Adam's guy
called me up and had me come on the show
real quickly a couple Fridays ago and
they just happened to be on and they're
like hey we got thcv isolate I was like
w really wow let's get some of that see
what that's like so yeah I
ordered yeah so it it it it it is pretty
pure but it's totally Delta 8 configured
right so it's it's not Delta 9 thcv it's
it's Delta 8 so makes me think that
they're just converting it from from
cbdv so cbdv like CBD makes an isolate
and you could uh convert that isolate
over to the THC form and if you start
with cbdv you make T8 CV so obviously
yeah this is like what people are doing
out in the marketplace now people have a
lot of access to like large amounts of
cbdv I guess so I mean I yeah I well
maybe
not large amounts Markus but they're
able to make isolate from from
distillate um I I guess I mean where
else does it come from I mean the other
thing is that um I don't know if you
guys are on future
4200 but there's this fella ion trap
there who's uh actually testing a lot of
Delta 8 products and finding all whole
soup of really nasty chemicals in there
not only the starting materials and what
happens when they so what they do is
they they take CBD and they treat it
with acid and that converts it over to
THC um but um it also unzips the
molecule and and rips the the turpine
portion of CBD off the ring and makes
this compound called olivetol and you'll
know lolic acid is the the the precursor
to all the canono in the plant and aitl
is not something that you want to be
consuming and um and so this guy is out
buying samples of
and if they're less pure you'd think
that you know they would just throw that
away but they end up in things like
gummies where you know yeah the consumer
is going to be tasting the gummy but
they're not knowing that the crap that's
in there is only like about 50 or 60%
pure meaning that there's 40% other crap
in there and he's finding things like
phades in one sample he actually found
dioxins and dioxins is a real really uh
toxic class of of molecules and to make
dioxins my gosh they must have just a
toxic soup of of stuff in there and
these folks are just hemp processors
they're not um they're not chemists like
me and they they don't understand that
what they're making is they're making a
chemical mixture and then thinking that
it's okay to put into uh and safe to put
into products clearly not their focus
their focus is to find an exploit in the
system and to be able to make money
where they thought they previously
couldn't and it's been the it's been the
name of the game since the beginning of
hemp being grown in the US because you
guys it it it it could be done clean and
pure that there's ways that you can
action course of course but that's not
your when that's not your focus when
your focus is just to find the exploit
to make money these are the
repercussions
right and you see that they banned it in
Colorado and I think one of the reasons
why they banned it in Colorado is
because the Delta n Lobby is so strong
in Colorado and certainly the Colorado
is one of the leading states of you know
regulating the industry here in the US
but I guess the real disappointing thing
is that like when you go to these Delta
8 markets they're in all the Cannabis
unfriendly States like Mississippi and
Tennessee and Alabama
and none of those states have cannabis
programs because they sell Delta 8
cartridges down at the gas station so
why do they need cannabis right and and
again Marcus when you look at so the guy
who's on um future 4200 if the Watchers
or the hash church people need to know
there's a guy named uh iron trap that's
the guy you want to look for and there's
a couple threads in there that talks
about him analyzing commercial products
and he's actually looking for producers
to say hey if you guys think you have a
clean product send it to me I'll test it
for you tell you what's in there and I
guess some people again that's where the
interaction goes bad he'll tell them you
got all this crap in there you better
change and they're just like [ __ ] you
you know and that's where it ends so so
listen you should invite him on to
pastur if you get a chance I it well you
you know the way 4200 Works no one
really knows who the guy is now I can
tell you come on like Sam though yeah he
he he's kind of like Sam so Sam you
probably know this guy he says he's been
working in give you his phone number and
address so
everybody he says he's been working in
can canabo science for 30 or 40 years
and when you look at the content of his
posts you realize this guy is is no joke
right Colin he is no joke he totally
knows he knows stuff there's a lot of
haters on 4200 so it's a very
interesting Forum but um sence like the
art community though there's tons of
haters you
know fut2 through the weight of unknown
you know it's called future 4200 it's a
website and you can go there and look
and just look at like I think the thread
that I'm thinking of is something like
there's a Sav compliant way to make
Delta 8 and I think most of this chatter
happened back in March and after that
there was a lot of edicts that came out
about delta8 including this ban in
Colorado so who knows if again him going
out and testing some of these products
that are in this unregulated
Marketplace help the FDA and DEA
actually sort out okay well what are we
going to do here you know and I think
very clearly it seems like there's like
about more than what two dozen states
now Colin that have banned Del that was
that's kind of my next question and like
all right so because of this chemistry
and this toxicologist that's really you
know looking into this the the you know
do you believe that's kind of uh you
know the reason behind the the the
regulation of delta8 and do you believe
that this is going to continue and and
do you believe it should continue more
important well he's he's really getting
down on on producers that don't have
inhouse analytics to basically put some
type of quality control mechanism on
what they're
making Hammer you could use a hammer to
knock in a little tack or you could use
a big freaking Sledgehammer so I think a
lot of these people are using a big
freaking sledgehammer and they're
busting the molecule apart back into a
liol and some other degradation species
I think paracine comes out of that and
there's a few other things but it's
interesting because again he's just
looking for stuff that's in the
marketplace and and all the producers
are like scared of this guy because he's
got the sophistication and the
analytical
instrumentation and Sam I bet you a
dollar to a donut that you know who this
dude is he's totally Anonymous in this
forum but um he's been in canono science
for a real long time and I can tell you
that everything that he posts I read it
almost it took me about two days worth
of reading just to get through March
21st of that single post because there
like anybody who sends me
9.95
995 I'll send you his address his phone
number Social Security number his bank
account number yeah well the other
thing the other thing that made him
quite unpopular is he said that he's
putting a binder together and going to
send it to the DEA and the feds and you
know that just oh instant hot button you
know with a lot of people this guy's a
douche he's a snitch you know [ __ ] this
obvious if he could find things that are
wrong with the substances being sold to
Consumer a whistle needs to be blown
period yes and he's he's the guy that's
doing it and he says he's doing it
because a his friends are being poisoned
people like that he knows are being
bringing things to him and saying hey
can you look at this he looks at it and
says there's poison in here so that's
one thing and the other thing is he
claims that there's a a safe and
efficient process to make this and you
need internal analytics to um to tell
the quality of your products look Marcus
I ask you all the time Marcus will show
a nice piece of hash like that hash
meteor showed last week and I'll say hey
what's the what's the cannaboid numbers
on that how do you know what it is
you're making if you can't test what it
is you're making so I think it calls for
in-house analytics but it also calls for
a higher level of Competency than just a
bunch of cowboys down south making this
stuff in their freaking also too Mark to
be honest Warehouse I think one of the
main empathist behind Banning it in many
states is the fact that it
is it's like what [ __ ] what textbook
did you read go read Paul malberg go
read the people who actually figured out
can abinoid biosynthesis it ends at
Delta a THC okay or I'm sorry I'm sorry
Delta
it doesn't go to Delta 8 right so yeah I
mean there's a lot of people on record
who say that Delta 8 is is found in
Trace Amounts in the plant and I laugh
at that I think that's
funny I've never seen it not true hey I
wanted to cut to Josh I wanted to cut to
Josh because I saw he had 13 seeds to a
gram but then he went off camera and he
found some bigger ones and came back 12
per gram
it it's a tie are those from
Yan well it's it's a combination It's a
combination of the vaval and the
Chinese yeah it is I think it is from
un which has the most biod the most
biodiversity in all been everywhere
around the world looking at cannabis
seeds youan were the biggest I
found look it 12 seeds what 102 come on
now I'll find more I'll make
it I
am I am in Canada so you'd have to ask
about that you know you'd have to ask
yeah look to see if there's pine because
British is famous for
okay now my small seeds were 800 plus to
the
gram wow that's insane what was that
from was that
tropical I collected it
well those seeds I think are the answer
to saving the forest I I believe you
know so that's what I'm excited about I
know that for Sav the
forest
one that's what's for saving the forest
the big ones or the small
ones the big
ones what what I'm saying is the big
ones are because in this case and maybe
the small ones make giant trees too I
just don't know I just know that these
particular seeds are very large and they
also produce some of the largest hemp
plants ever you know that you'll see
they're
large stock they
really it's not a big flower place it's
a fiber and food seed thing so I believe
that's going to be saving the forest
industry because when you
walk in an old gr Forest you're walking
on four to five
feet of trees that have been down for a
thousand years there's no man-made
Forest that'll ever ever make it to that
especially in a fire zone I mean if you
wanted to create a nice forest and a
fire zone you would have to cut the
trees
down which I don't agree with but you'd
have to cut them down then you'd have to
Buck them up and then you'd have to cut
them slice them in half and then put
them on the forest floor otherwise
you're just stealing
soil so like when you walk in an old
growth forest the purpose of the trees
growing really close to themselves is so
they
fall and if you want to speed up that
process and you have to fall them put
them on the ground and not take them out
otherwise you'll NE there'll never be
another large Forest there there's only
so much dirt there's only so many
needles that can fall so that's what's
really important when you walk in a
thousand- year old Forest you're walking
on four to five feet of moss and humus
and that's what makes us a humus being
you know we're humus beings when we're
from the earth when we believe in
natural immunity that's of dead trees
right thank you yes that's what makes us
carbon based microbial humus beings
and responsible what what what what
makes that really happen Josh it's fungi
right it's the wood Decay fungi that
decay to the stuff called White rot and
brown rot and when it hits white rot it
leaves brown behind and when it hits
Brown rot it leaves white behind but
yeah those fungi have figured out ways
to completely
mineralize content of the rotten
wood start it starts with bacteria
bacteria lead the way but then fungi com
in after that and all those rotten trees
that you find are yeah just the tops of
what you're talking about that layer of
humus that goes back for centuries of of
of Fallen wood that and that fungi is
here to save Humanity when I go to
Oregon Washington or California it's
very difficult to find
polypores it's very difficult to find
polypores because there's no trees
rotting everything's managed there's no
Branch to rot you've robbed the forest
of
fungi and you've robbed the humanity of
the
fungi amazingly so it takes those dead
and dying forests those nasty fire
[Music]
forests are what saves our life it might
be that they want to cut down the old
growth forest because when someone walks
in an old growth forest their life has
changed forever they oh my God what's oh
my God the resonance oh my God
everything's intact oh my God owls did
you hear honey Ravens what's going on
what's happening I've never seen life
like this yeah we're losing diversity so
it's very important that we put branches
on the ground and let them rot it makes
Greenery it makes Greenery you you take
the branches away you lose the greenery
I've seen Forest Green in the summer you
know it's possible the only way it's
possible is mulch love you got to over
mulch the system and that's three
branches so I think that's mulch
love yeah Josh and one thing I want to
add to what he was talking about when
we're when we're cutting our firewood
for the for the season we'll leave
behind a little stack as an offering
back along the roadways or along
wherever in the forest we were were
cutting and then now when we do our
walks back through the forest that's
busting turkey tails and and all sorts
of mushrooms on either end and lizards
are coming out of the middle and you
know we'll sometimes roll it back as
like a you know just a little view into
the Earth and um you see all that and I
was talking earlier about uh selling off
part of our farm and uh we sold it this
amazing amazing humus beings and um he
was walking in the road and you said
hey leave one so when you stack the next
ones on it you can keep that cycle going
and then Harvest some for Hogle beds or
whatever you might do but I just what
you were saying Josh yeah another really
good idea is like if you if a person
lives near forests the unbelievable
amount of of Slash that they burn in the
clear Cuts is it's
mind-blowing there's so much material
left over so much raw material left over
by the loggers and all they're going to
do is put it in the air so really like
if you have a truck and a trailer like
an incredible amount of of raw materials
can be gathered out of
clearcuts and you should do it because
you're not stealing future soil from the
clearcut because all they're going to do
is stack it up and burn it which is just
mindblowing and then they try and
replant a forest
with yeah it's so frustrating but yeah
so yeah you you know like like you said
Craig there's this balance you know like
we're taking some we're leaving some but
we and the mindset of I think we need to
Rew environments I think we need to Rew
our cannabis garden I think we need to
Rew our Genie ology I to have viruses
because without viruses our our immune
system cannot evolve by stopping
ourselves from getting sick we're
stopping our body another muscle the
immune system from working
properly before we do any of this to be
honest we need to lower the world
population because the world cannot
support the amount of people we have if
we had one tenth of the amount of people
we have maybe the world could be okay
but in a substainable way we got too
many and it's only going to be more well
we live in a scarcity environment so
yeah based off the style of life that we
live as eight billion people on the
planet based off that style based off
what's been handed to us we live in
scarcity it's not necessary we can live
in abundance if everyone participated in
the concept that we're all trying to
better ourselves and make more food if
everyone grew a little bit in their yard
on their roof on their Terrace somewhere
something it's possible for us to live
in abundance even with eight billion
people on the
Earth yeah we have we have an abundance
of scarcity and it is driving the market
literally they make us feel a shortage
and then it just drives and drives and
drives and without regenerative
agriculture and regenerative soils you
can talk about
soil science all day long you can talk
about Tarpin you can talk about sensory
stuff but 95% of the beers out there are
coated in glyphosate you know most of
the wine is so great you've got all the
sensory down but the base of the sensory
is is tarnished it's it's toxic so
really like the first thing is how do we
put Health back into the system how do
we put Health back in now we can talk
about tpin now we can talk about sensory
and what the but if we're analyzing
sensory while we're getting poisoned by
glyphosate then it's it's it's just not
a system that that recognizable it's
it's a broken system so I I constantly
will
continuously
promote regenerative lifestyle and and
soils and regenerative style cultivation
and polyculture and permaculture because
I want to survive I want to be one of
those people that
survive Marcus I have a question for you
did you hear from Max monrose about the
other type of Turing he
discovered I mean the other uh tricomes
excuse
me no I didn't I only sent my message
late last night so I didn't hear back
from him but yeah he did say that he was
going to come back and share that with
us as well as I think there was
something else too I forget he he said
he grafted Hops and cannabis together
and had oh that's right no he didn't
graft it he bred it he crossed it okay
right right I I was quite IAL but if
somebody did it I want to see it well
you're the doubting Thomas and that's
why you got to touch the incorporeal
body of
Christ well uh I'm very interested also
if he thinks he has a different kind of
a triome uh I'm I'm very
interested well there have been quite a
few posts and even Ed Rosenthal picked
on up on this recently there is a guy
who posts and I don't know know if
they're just mutants but he posted a
picture of a triome the other day that
had like six little heads on top of it I
wish I could remember his name because
he's posting all sorts of very very high
level is that in a variety as uh I have
no idea I have no idea I just know that
it's
canis it could be a one of it could be a
mutant it could be a variety I just
don't know enough about it but um it's
definitely um unique and I wish I wish I
could kind of find one to share but the
only one person I know really is Ed that
posted it and he whoever's running his
account po oh yeah here we go this this
is it right
here oddly it looks like Opium poppy
yeah yeah funny enough the hold it up
and say something hold it up and say
something so your screen is yeah thank
you okay yeah yeah so um six heads
although those heads all six of them
look smaller than the head that would
normally be on a stock of that size nice
anthocyanin sort of coursing through the
center there I wish um Let me let me
shout this guy out his name is zoom unor
Gardens um go check him out on Instagram
he's uh here I'll punch it into the chat
too so it's
zooms score Gardens doing some great
workers great to see best friend in the
house lots of love to you out in Maine
hey I gotta take off family and get some
stuff done preparing for the rain that's
coming this week and everything so
Joshua
Craig Sam Johnny Colin Mark Bubble Man
many blessings to you lots of love
thanks for coming in brother Josh keep
growing those seeds bigger and bigger
Josh
looks
beautiful Sam good job nice to
see or wait that's Joshua's plants yeah
sorry I've been I've been watering all
all morning so I thought I'd just pop on
and I always think I can hop on with a
joint and a coffee and water and talk
and that is just not
possible I'm like what am I doing I'm
trying to talk with people here so I
finally finished my
watering it look follow my Instagram at
all you saw
how
this but I lost the whole top 12 six to
inches and um had lot of work big
mistake and I'm just so impressed with
these plants um
big thanks to Josh and Kelly I used uh
the Lush roots and the Gaia green to
kind of help push through some of
this but I'm just really impressed man
look at these tops I'm GNA have a
beautiful yield look at all these
tops I I messed up my dep this morning I
was I just put this dep on a couple
weeks ago and I was kind of working on
timing it and I I broke my shear pin so
I got to run to the hard hardware
store and get a new shear pin so that's
why I've got my dep on on half of
it look at this one this is a one I'm I
I selected out of 800 this summer The
Black W [ __ ] gold look at these
tops just my little [ __ ] Up's gonna give
me a nice yield I'm excited that plant
looks like straight up like a [ __ ]
canopy yeah dude look look at this big
one back here this uh can you see that
big girl I'll walk over on one of these
planks oh I see her back there in the
shade yeah in the shade this big uh
Black liim from Kevin
JRE so I'm this is six feet right
here she's seven eight feet tall we just
started flower about three days ago
she's GNA get way up there up lights you
use light meters to figure out what kind
of light your plants are getting there
because Johnny B came over here the
other day with this like utterly
ridiculous multi th000 light meter um
maybe he can tell tell us a little bit
about that later but do you do you use
anything like that Josh just to I don't
I can't afford one but um kind of the
way so in the green houses we build the
light system to be a supplement not to
be a
fullon these lights on there's a ton of
them I'm only putting in about 20% of
what the the plants need 20
30% um if I had like the depth on I
wouldn't be able to grow a good crop
with just these lights are you in BC I'm
just below I'm I'm On the Border um in
bla bir Bay damn maybe I can meet you I
could just pass the meter across yeah
toss sitting on the corner know and you
can pick it up and leave it in there and
we'll meet the next day this one's the
Congo though from up there the Roberts
Creek oh [ __ ] Congo B seeing the shade
and I'm looking at I've been doing this
around my own yard by putting plants and
Solo cups at different parts of
different spectrums underneath the trees
and looking at different Reds and stuff
so I'm having a lot of fun with this
right now um just ahe in two minutes
it's going to be 420 and Cate Rue so I
have a 420 clock right beside me so I'm
kind of like but we'll just keep going
here sorry I was just uh on the light
kick um so I'm putting on this dep and
and I built this greenhouse oriented e
east to west right not north to south
because you know my my version of
regenerative is that I grow year round
and I only support people within 100
miles of me and that that's kind of how
I i' I've Quantified this whole thing so
I built this whole system to be a year
round greenhouse and producing the cold
part of the year um and I had another
another local flower guy come over and
he's like what's up with that big tube
if you can look up here I have a big I
call it the the light the dong of
Life uh but it's a big 36 inch tube that
just distributes the air from the top of
the greenhouse into the whole system and
then I and I and I just like no man I'm
not it's never been a problem I've been
running this dong for five years and and
I start talking to him real confidently
about uh the understory and and where PL
cannabis is in succession and how it's
kind of an understory plant and and the
diffusion and I start talking about
rattle and all this stuff and you know
just to describe it better I have a two
layers of poly here and when you blow
them up it creates a light diffusion and
it reduces the brightness in the
greenhouse but it also spreads it out
and you can see it on the plant canopy
if you go you know if I walk from one
Greenhouse with the double layer poly
into another one with a single layer
poly you can totally and in then outside
you can totally see the sharp light you
can see how it affects the foliage um
and I've also kind of [ __ ] around with
putting some plants in the edge of my
forest and and kind of watched in stages
and watched the ones that maybe were a
little bit farther back how they did and
I'm fully convinced that that the plants
do like a little bit less light a little
little bit more diffus use light um but
then I got this this uh dep on here and
it creat some serious shadows and so now
I'm like oh man what have I
done um I kind of just say a that just
to bring up the topic about about
lighting and and diffusion and since you
were talking about it you know I don't
know what what anybody else has dug in
there in you know working in the
diffused and less bright world you know
indoors is it's much different idea
you're kind of just trying to hit a
specific Target you know and maintain
that for an amount of time
I've SE I just had some uh I had some
results with some indoor back of the
room changes with a strain my gas mask
excuse me actually seem to have done
better kind of even mossier stinkier
even little bigger on the flowers in the
back end of the room
I like the light depths even being able
to drop the tarp if you got a hot time
during planting you can drop down
halfway and kind of use it for your own
like shade transitional shading at the
peak key to the day and it's because
it's been kind of hot in Maine even the
last week over 80 so
yeah I have a question I I'll ask
um the uh you the farmers here uh do you
guys think or suspect that there's um
anything to do with uh climate change
that has
impacted the atmosphere which has caused
lighting to be different for us growing
cannabis now in this time period versus
what the cannabis
plant might have been typically um used
to uh working with on on Earth prior to
humanity doing what we've done up until
this
point I well quick the first thing came
on my head was the fires you know two
weeks in August with with h no sun when
I'm when you're making flowers through
you know into September that's a big
deal um that's a real crucial transition
time and and the West Coast folks feel
that pretty hard um the other thing I
was I was thinking on the back end was
the almost the positive effect if you
look at it from a a
greedy humanistic perspective that that
we're able to to cultivate in places
where we weren't able to cultivate
before
um it's a really big interesting
question on my mind I I've I've had the
hard go of it here on my farm in large
part with my neighbor some neighbor
conflicts that have made it really
miserable where many of times I've been
wanting to give up and and and dreamt
about moving away to another place and
and and thought where would I do it and
then I start kind of looking into what
the future looks like like in different
places and I'm like God damn I'm in a
one of the best spots to really be going
forward
um I don't know just kind of the
thoughts that I have when I'm thinking
about how these things things are going
to be in the future and water is a big
fear for me even though I I'm in an
abundant Water Place um I I think that
that the whole thing is going to be a
real real big issue coming going forward
with what companies getting are getting
into charging and Etc sorry I cut
someone else off all that whoever else
was going to pop in
go all good I was just kind of agreeing
with you I'm definitely seeing some
changes and I'm seeing hotter Sun back
into Maine here than I thought I would
see coming from the west coast and I got
a big openup property here so I'm full
spread of Sunrise to sunet mostly here
you know but uh seeing bigger yields and
the and the Earth seems drier this year
here really dry compared it's not fire
dry like the West Coast but it's kicking
up dust my pwns are dropping like a foot
and a half already and it's been a hot
May uh one of the big things I've seen
that's kind of like driving the dogs
nuts driving us nuts the bugs have
kicked up the black flies early
mosquitoes uh luckily the dragon flies
came in about a month earlier because
and I you know the the change in climate
and I don't know if that's just a
two-year blip that we're seeing but here
as an outdoor farmer in Maine is
definitely hotter drier kind of drought
conditions coming in and I'm seeing a
kick up of bugs that seem to bring in
the insect environment pretty hard you
know they haven't been plaguing us but
there's definitely waves of of bugs
we've gotten a bunch of the corn borers
in the last few years that seem to have
come in and you know anyway that's what
I'm seeing some stuff
here yeah I would lean in and uh offer
this thought uh to your question Max uh
I don't think the cannabis plant itself
is going to have any trouble with what
we're doing to the environment uh
because it's dealt with all kinds of
crazy [ __ ]
[Music]
in is what's going to be the effect on
humans and the Cannabis industry if you
will the opportunity for folks to work
with this plant create product and uh
live a life that we all enjoy uh and I
think that's a really different question
um and I think that Josh and Kelly with
the dragonfly Earth medicine Concepts
around regenerative practices certainly
point to one of many different things
that we as humans are going to have to
do in order to preserve something like
the life we currently enjoy uh going
forward over the next few generations of
humans I have grandchildren and I think
this is the real issue of our time I
I've been a a fervent cannabis advocate
for many years I still am but I really
think what we're doing to the
environment that we live in that we all
share as humans is the real question of
our time and uh so circling all the way
back to your question Max yeah I think
it's going to be a real issue going
forward not just for cannabis but for
growing
food for growing food is going to be an
issue for us going forward and that's my
thought I think the Cannabis plan will
be fine thank you I'm con concerned
about the air quality too um you know
for for for growing just to tag onto
that that food thought you
know that that the quality of the air
that you were going to be prod we're
have to you know grow to grow healthy
food we're going to have to possibly
grow in green houses and filter the air
and have cleaned air you know places to
grow our healthy food and our medicines
is is a fear that I
have yeah and I I'll just throw one last
thing and I know that some of the
farmers that are in this group here as
well as listening on the to the hash
Church
broadcast uh may have come to recognize
that it's actually more of a challenge
to grow food than it is to grow cannabis
especially if you're trying to grow at
scale um that's been my experience at
least uh just talk about germinating
seeds of food crops uh as compared to
germinating cannabis seeds and I'll
leave it there thank
you same with producing seeds uh celery
and other seeds take two years to
produce a crop of so it's you know it's
more work for
sure yeah one by the way I here's
one another one I got from Russia it's
Master breeder
congratulations Sam you are known all
over the
world master breeder that's what
everyone calls themselves at LPS now
they've turned that into a bad a bad
word well Master Growers sometimes I
think it should be Master baders but uh
that's really
cool um I guess here's another good
question uh on the lighting perspective
um for a room of intelligent Growers is
um I've heard some people say before
that uh there are varieties that have
spent so much time growing
indoors that they are indoor varieties
meaning transferring them
Outdoors they either don't do as well or
can't handle the intensity of the
outdoor environment um because they've
more or less
evolved uh you know over a 10year period
to be in the in the environment of a of
an indoor space do you guys think
there's any amount of Truth to that um
do you think that there are some plants
that after spending too much time
indoors um H has a change uh in in the
plant's life and cycle that's noticeable
when you were to to put it outside so um
not not from single year of selection
but if you grew a big crop and selected
the most leaning towards indoor
performance and you did that for 10
Generations in a row then you would have
made one small step in that
direction I kind of see
Craig how's that there we go um yeah I I
resonate with what um was saying and
I've witnessed it um when I've been
giving been given some indoor seeds
specifically from from that uh side of
things
and more Airy or more bushy than my
liking and the plant Canabis plant
specifically I feel is a really quick
learner one one season of reading the
next year Boom the the structure has
changed it can support itself and then
you know what Sam was saying we do that
a couple years in a row and the
phenotypic knowledge starts being passed
down and um it it it learned so quickly
and and that's a really good uh thing to
talk about I witnessed it probably five
years
ago um I forget what the cultivar was
but you know folks that would even tour
my garden would would go what is that it
smells
amazing but it didn't have the structure
to stand where where it uh was in the
garden it needed to be inside and um it
took one season to learn unlearn that or
to learn the new
process this
winter excuse go
ahead Max what is the new type of Tricom
and the uh you do you have photos of the
of the hot pie bread with uh
cannabis I I do um I do have photos of
that stuff
um I didn't prepare them because I
didn't know that that's what we were
doing so um I guess I could uh see if I
could quickly open a few files also
don't know how much I uh I should share
before my new book comes out
um what about the new triome can you
give it its name yeah I can well I can
tell you what I want to name it um and
apparently I I have the opportunity to
name it
um the uh what I'm not going to do is
I'm not going to name it after
myself um what I thought would be
appropriate from a naming perspective
though was something in alignment um
that at uh
mulam uh where he came up with
anandamide um the Sanskrit word for
Bliss um which also has some Hebrew
translations and iterations and has some
biblical Essence in in nature um in some
senses um uh I am Jewish and I also
study uh the esoteric world I love uh
cabala
all that kind of stuff and so um with
that thought process I asked what would
the seventh be or mean in a Hebrew word
or Essence um and in a in a meaningful
way because this would be the seventh
type of triome found um we have two
types of non- glandular tricomes
unicellular and
cystolithic we have uh bulbus simp Le
and bulbus complex you have cile and you
have capitate stocked um and so that's
six and so this would be the seven and
uh so this from a name perspective in
Hebrew there's uh the name in Hebrew
that means seven and seven from a
miracle perspective is
nessia and this triome is also capitate
stocked it has a very long stock and it
has a a a head but instead of a mushroom
shaped head it's an upside down teardrop
shaped head and all of those
tricomes they're a teardrop shaped head
so it's it's got a really interesting uh
roundness to it with kind of like a a
point and a do drop that comes off of it
and then the stock itself is a third of
the width of a capitate stocked
Tricom um so there're these really thin
long stocks with these do drop shaped
heads off the end of them um and so I
would name it capitate stocks
nessia um the seventh the seventh triome
and to me it's a miracle that no one
else has scientifically you know put the
put a white paper on this yet and and
Max did you find it in all varieties of
cannabis or just particular lean towards
a particular
uh wide Leafs skinny Leaf equatorial
Northern so um I'm not sure of the the
origin of the geography of the plants at
all um we I can confirm that I found
them in both H types and marijuana
types um
and
um the
I can show you a picture if you want
I'll I'll find a picture of one I'll
show it to you right now since I'm
talking about it the the the thing is is
they are very very very very rare you
just rarely see them um and so if you
have Instagram and follow these
incredible um artists that do incredible
triome photography you see hundreds if
not
thousands of microscopic shots of of
tricomes um on a weekly or monthly basis
and at least I do and when you look at
these tricomes and very very up close
these images are just
incredible um I'm always hunting for
these special tricomes that pop up
rarely and um when I do find
one uh and then I have an opportunity to
acquire the flower and I'm able to
really look at it myself you do find
those other Tricom within it and it's
extremely exciting um and then uh apart
from that
um I have found multiple new types of
tricomes uh some of which are tricomes
that are non- glandular that are four to
five times longer than most of the other
Tricom so these very long curly q
tricomes that are they're just kind of
outrageous um and then I've also found
Tricom where the glandular head is in
the center of the stock so instead of
the head being on the end of the stock
there's a stock then there's a gland
crazy tricomes Max is finding are
actually novel tricomes like who's the
judge over here when it comes to this
kind of stuff um and that would be a
good question to ask um if you know the
work of Paul mulberg he's a scientist
that has done cannabis cannabinoid and
triome research for the United States
federal government for over 30 years and
um his young younger lab texts and lab
assistants one of which is
um and so bringing them in a live uh um
plant with these tricomes will give them
the opportunity to dissect the tricomes
microscopically for their anatomy and so
you have to actually pull the anatomy
out of the tricomes and lay them these
microscopic uh glands out um almost like
you're doing a um it's not a
biop when you uh take apart a dead
B what are you doing thank you
Mark love how like whenever I'm like
this close to like looking like I know
what I'm talking about Mark always steps
in he's like let let me help you out
here well yeah Ma Max we we've talked
about Paul malberg before I think
actually um uh Sam don't you know Dr Kim
or I I know I've met Dr Kim I know Dr
malberg I financed their lab for five
years of work with cannabis with Carl
hilling there you go so your comment
your comments Max your comments are just
right on though and centered on you know
the wonderful research that he did and
the Legacy that like through Dr Kim and
I'm sorry for cutting you
off well we stand on the shoulders of
giants including Sam so you know where
we are today and what we can do with the
plant and cannaboid Science in general
are really due to a handful of
individuals that walk the face of the
Earth one of them who Graces our panel
today but others like Paul malberg and
Raphael michul and Roger Adams and um
and those guys Canada Ernie
small yeah I I I always think of those
those Brits who first made distillate
back in the
1890s and called it called it yeah no
this was way before Adams This was um
easterwood East easterfield Spivy and
wood wood Spivy and easterfield the
first people to isolate
THC so um yeah man I mean we stand on
the shoulders of all these people Max
and it's just like when you read and and
through Open Access you could read most
of malbergs research in fact there's a
website that actually has a list of all
Paul malbergs papers and there's like 30
of them I mean it's it's amazing
go
um thank you and uh I was just going to
ask bubble man if you can grace me with
the ability to share my screen I can
show some of these tricomes I'm talking
about wow that's amazing it is showing
your screen that's not my
screen whose photos are those that's
that's Zoom Gardens and I'll share them
afterwards he has the most incredible
insane mutant macro photographs of
cannabis so while Max was talking about
this I was going I mean that last one I
just showed was like a Tricom that
literally had stocks all inside the
stock but they're also tricomes growing
off the stock so I just figured it
suited the conversation but I will
figure out going in right now and
gracing you with the ability to share
the screen I don't know why it sets it
up so only the host can share but you
you should be good to go now Max all
right so
um this is in my book book interpreting
um and if you look on the upper right
hand screen um this was the
first time I actually ever saw the
seventh Tricom type um was when I was
sifting through triome photography from
my buddy uh schale he used to live in
Denver um and I was actually at his
house uh just going through his pictures
because I was going to purchase some for
company for our website and uh for stuff
like my book
and um it wasn't until after I actually
uh bought this photograph from him and I
brought it home and I was looking at it
again and I saw the it was really the
stock that stood out to me more than
anything else um and you can't see the
its little unicorn horn that kind of
pulls off the end as well on this photo
but um this was the first image that I
ever had of these and I have uh many
more images of them um and you know we
used to we were the contract for dope
magazine when we judged all of their uh
cannabis competitions and I mean my team
of seven sifting through hundreds of
types of cannabis microscopically at
competitions for years on end in
multiple different states uh we found
one of these uh while we were judging
and it was cool to have a a team of us
guys who know this stuff real well all
be able to look through a microscope and
turn a flower around and continue to see
this this one rare Tricom that very
rarely sticks its head out um show up
and and we could all definitely see it
with our own eyes a verify that it was
there take pictures of it um but do you
think this do you think this is
genetically or environmentally
controlled do you have any idea of why
it has a different shape is the waxy
cuticle emitted different or you
understand what I'm getting at yeah and
this that's this that's the you're
that's the area that I need a lot of
help with right because I'm not a um a
scientist at this level well it it would
be interesting max if you could find a a
particular clone or variety where most
of the tricomes were this bulbous type
or I forget the name you gave it I I but
I'll just call it you know not round not
oval but uh tear shaped upside
down yeah um I think you know this you
know I to me science is a that would
show it was genetic Al
controlled I you know science to me is a
community effort and my my role in this
has been to be the one to observe it and
spend five years trying to find it and
getting my hands on the genetic that
consistently produces this
triome um and and and then growing it
out bringing that to a scientist uh a
team of scientists at a university
and then letting them officially
officiate the fact that this is a new
novel triome and then from there when I
have a genetic and I've got the Clones
I've got the mothers and I've got a
white paper and this is something novel
and important um I would definitely be
willing to give this plant to someone
who would be able to do the type of
research that you were just mention well
the the head shape is important but it's
the St
that is really really unique to be
honest yeah well and and the canono
content I mean let's face it if these
things are being grown for for cannaboid
Content what is the impact on on on
cannaboid profile and yield from these I
mean when I see the more bulbous Tricom
I always think conventionally like you
know and from Reading malbergs work
where they actually micr catheterized
these things to actually suck the juice
out of these tricomes I mean that the
more bulb is the triome the more oil
that's there the higher the yield would
be the more mature the Cannabis profile
would be and the
oil does it have a different number of
cells inside the resin head that are
emitting the cannaboids and Turpin that
would be I'm quite curious right like
the tpine kind so are we refer ing to
the to the like the lower left hand side
uh the one where it just looks like it
has a head that shriv shriveled up
no upper right hand side yeah the upper
right hand the top side unfortunately
the in this Photograph the Tricom that's
centered is the the middle Tricom which
is a beautiful image of a what I would
consider a a perfect capitate stock
Tricom if if we were judging tricomes
forther right uh but if you go to the
the farthest triome on the very right
the stock of the tear drop I see now my
my zoom speaker panel was covering that
Max I could see it now well welcome to
the party mark check no I can see it so
it come it comes to a point at the very
end okay I see I see and the stem is uh
uh a quarter the thickness of the big
fat stems of the other tricomes yeah so
would wouldn't you worry that that would
make these tricomes brittle
and okay so that'd be a real drag if
you're try to make cash and the Tricom
stems were brittle and the resin fell
off really easy when you wanted it to
real bummer well you know what I was
hearing and I've heard this now twice in
like as many weeks Sam is that these
high CBG varieties especially the white
there's a variety called the white
that's a very high Variety in CBG it's
it's um grown here in North America and
it's like anywhere between 13 to
18% CBG hardly any THC at all and they
said that's what they said the issue
with that is that you know harvesting
and getting the material to the lab is
is very very crucial because the
tricomes are so brittle you get a lot of
loss in just handling a plant material
hey Mark this is some CBG right here
that I'm holding up if you can see that
that's uh some some
sift made um yeah perent what percentage
CBT analyze for so it's uh on the the
flower was uh I think a 12 to 15%
depending on the batch and then the hash
came in around um or the the sift I
should say come came around in you know
anywhere from 60 to
70 really
70% CBG yep I'm surprised it was green
CB didn't it there he is I was waiting
Mark
cbga so yeah Sam this is uh this is your
sh um it's quite nice actually I like
the effects from CBG it's really
interesting very
uplifting and the tur profile and those
isolates are pretty I mean it's it's
nice it's like a good product right it's
okay I mean it just depends on what
you're looking for if you're looking for
a more hempy uh profile then it's right
up your alley if you're looking for a
drug cultivar really
turpy you know it's not really that um
but
I don't know the the background on the
white to be honest um I came in from
Switzerland those guys brought those
those genetics in from Switzerland I saw
it
happen like two years over a period of
like two years Sam they had this this
variety over in Europe last year then
the next thing I know those guys those
guys all formed
llc's in Oregon and the next year I
guess my question is where did the Swiss
get it from from the Italians and the
Italians I know where they got it from
from the
ukrainians you know what I I want to add
something in real quick the picture he
has up there now I have seen I have
pictures of these for sure Max that I
can uh go through and send you I always
thought it was a cyith hair that a tri
because I'd seen tricomes break off and
land on other components that weren't
necessarily growing there they hello bye
Marcus what's that so have I seen what
you've seen But heads can fly around and
be stuck on things that didn't produce
them yeah I always thought of this as
like but then again it is such a light
like it's too hot long of a of a hair
it's too straight it's just too
different but I I have photos like this
for
sure from like 2008 to 2012
another head or it's sticking to a stock
so therefore the head is sticking on the
side of the
stock like totally I'm 100 like you know
you're talking to someone who's who
Geeks out on triom I started the ma
that's why peer rbie science is
beautiful when when you when you allow
others to examine it and try to poke hes
in it then if it stands you've got it
exactly and I want people people to to
to look into this I want University
scientists to say I want them to be the
ones to say this is scientifically real
and novel because um I'm the
passionate uh you know cannabis
Enthusiast interpreter expert um I'm I'm
just the one who says I think this is
novel and I'll bring this to you and so
that that's what I've but it's also
taken me five years to find the variety
and confirm that it is what it is and
then get seed from it um and uh it's
it's it's been you could write a novel
on uh how crazy this has been um these
tricomes here you know
there's it's it's also really
interesting how mushroom like tricomes
appear um and and what's really
interesting is um the fruiting body of
LSD is also extremely phallic in
mushroom like I don't know if you guys
have ever seen um the Fring body of irot
fungus uh that produces asilis clus yeah
I have it that tattooed to my kneecap um
but it looks just so mushroomy and so
yeah you see this cluster of mushroom
looking tricomes here um and it appears
like that almost maybe that brittle
Factor where you said the Tricom heads
might have fallen off those two tricomes
right here it's either this has a very
tiny head with a point coming out of it
um and the one behind it looks like its
head fell off um but these are the
tricomes that have a stem that is a
third the width of a typical capitate
stocked
triome uh with you can see the capitate
stocked triome uh down to the lower
right right there and um yeah this is
that bizarre uh bulbous shaped head
which is not your classic capitate stock
shaped head and then the rest of the
Tricom continuing off from that head
that is not a mutation I don't think and
I also don't think that's you know a
triome that broke off and fell somewhere
else I really do believe that between uh
this image and the other images that you
have we're seeing varieties of of this
type of Tricom um ex well that's that
that was my first question Max um you
know I'm not an expert on plant tricomes
I do know a couple though um but
factor or some other anomaly that's
producing that well um the what I
there's one
variety that when I found it had this
triome on it we said okay it's this
variety and I secured some of that
variety that was grown in in um the East
Coast I secured some that was grown in
the midwest I secured some that was
grown up north and I'm growing it right
now in
Colorado and so different environments
in different
geographies are seemingly to produce the
same Tricom based off of the genetic
that it
is and so I don't think it's an
environmental stress factor that's
causing these tricomes to abruptly
change their shape I think this is a
type of cannabis plant that is growing a
new type of triome that is a needle in a
hay
stack I think that's what it
is and that's why I've been dedicated to
securing the genetic growing it out
making a relationship with with
University scientists to confirm that
right so I'm not but just to be clear
the Cannabis that you're finding these
uh different tricomes it's not
exclusively those that you're finding
those intermingled with regular looking
tricomes and tricomes that we've always
seen yes so so these are just sort of
like a a minor you know type of triome
that you're finding the more you're
looking at these uh uh closeup images of
tricomes do we know if they've been
there all along Sam and maybe you know
Max's Discovery here is just any
anything is possible but what I'd like
to say is that if you can find a variety
where the majority of the tricomes are
of this phenotype or genotype whatever
they are then uh it's probably
genetically controlled if you can find
one out of a thousand or one out of a
million and you can only find it on some
plants and not other plants then uh yeah
uh maybe the environment should be
looked at more I I really don't know if
it's if it could be environmental or or
but uh if if it's real we want to know
and we want to track down and if it's
genetically controlled you can create a
variety that all of the resin heads are
like that or 99% of them that's what I
was going to say have you can have you
tried to breed with any of it and and
make those observation I mean I know
it's it's early and it would take a ton
of what you need to do is self it to
find individuals that have more uh a
higher
incident here's some jar rot tricomes
for
you I think this was the white I was I
was looking for when you uh one of yeah
this is the white I'm pretty sure um
because the white produces just the the
most bizarre tricomes that there are
they are capitate stocked tricomes are
are these the high CBG varieties Max yes
yes yes they are and you know they call
the plant the white here it is this is
the white they call it the white
it's a different kind of white
than uh ripe tricomes when they emanate
um fullness when their when their
glandular heads are full of chemistry
and they're at a ripening Point prior to
degradation it's different because that
type of white is almost this creamy
white this mother of pearl white um and
what this High CBG variety produces is
tricomes that are
glowing bright white okay so let's just
say that there's like you know in the
paint store there's a difference between
like eggshell white and bright white
that is almost like offensive it's
blinding you know there's there's a
difference in brightness this this High
CBG grows these tricomes that are
glowing bright white in all of the
glandular heads are white and the stocks
of the heads are white too and that's
what makes this variety striking it
really it's
striking um and so how does that work
why is that happening how come the the
why is the white producing tricomes that
are
just this this unique well you stopped
the cannaboid biosynthetic pathway at at
not its end point at at its penultimate
end point right but um I I I I don't
know if the physiological
Char and not making thca or CB cbda or
or or the other
miners have you seen the chemal
if you rub these white resin well from a
fresh plant like that looks like that
and uh is it just as sticky as a a
normal THC High
plant I from a from an aroma perspective
no no rub your fingers on the resin is
it as sticky and oily as a THC bar
so unfortunately I have not had the
pleasure to uh grow this plant out
myself yeah I I can answer the question
yes
Sam oh okay well I'm just trying to get
to a reason that makes logical sense why
it's white I I I took one of I took a
couple tops off of a uh a plants that a
farmer Amish farmer had down in Maryland
down the road took it back to my lab did
an alcohol extraction and got like a
90 pure
CBG he had about one or two% THC so
there's a lot of timing uh that needs to
go into harvesting if you're harvesting
for
CBG and Mark maybe you can talk about
this as well but this variety the the
PE you can go to the grocery store and
buy a watermelon that is just natural
and it comes packed full of seed and
then you can buy a genetically modified
watermelon that is just seedless or
grapes that are seedless or apples that
are
seedless this variety I think if you go
online and possibly by Oregon seed um
they um you can buy this plant and grow
a field of it but if you wanted to grow
a field of it again um I guess if you
I'm sure you can clone it but um I just
found it really interesting that
stuff in a variety of different ways and
every time I've come in contact with it
uh just to answer Sam's question uh from
my perspective is the plant was
extraordinarily dehydrated it had no
Aroma profile whatsoever it had no
stickiness whatsoever it was a very dry
texture and smell Aroma experience
experience and it almost was
disappointing like it didn't have a lot
to offer other than the fact that it
looked nutty with its crazy white
tricomes and it's pretty crazy to find a
plant with this much biomass with that
amount of
cannabigerol that late in the flowering
cycle uh because I'm I'm pretty sure we
all know that CBG is the mother canabo
that starts building the others and that
that process happens really early on in
flour and that's why you don't typically
find a lot of CBG when you harvest your
plant at the end of the cycle the fact
that this plant is being harvested at
the end of its cycle and it the damn
thing is packed full of CVG it's crazy
but uh from us like marijuana lovers um
it's not a ooey gooey sticky funky
skunky herb it's just not uh at least
what I came in cont with and then I was
sifting through pounds of this stuff
looking for a seed
desperately and you just not even the
remnants of a seed not even a a a a
hollow Brack casing that would hold a
seed no seed whatsoever this is a
seedless
variety from the producers who produce
it of course I'm sure you can find this
variety that does produce seed I'm just
saying in the marketplace currently in
the largest amount this is a seedless
variety hey hey Max um could you show us
the pinkleberry
photo yeah you know who I uh who I got
these from
Jesse no no certified dank yeah yeah I
think I'm gonna use one of these in my
new book if I can squeeze it in I think
this is the one and I just posted this
on the triome
Institute uh Instagram page but I'm I'm
just always in awe when you see style
stigma that is just that striking it's
just when you talk about weed porn that
is just
unreal yeah it's beautiful we're we're
actually growing the pinkleberry by
coffee Kai's coffee uh this year it's a
it's a collaboration those guys did so
we're super excited to have it here in
southern humble and see how it looks and
does right
on I I've seen Afghan plants that would
produce th those colors of hairs for gwz
the first ones I saw was in the
70s yeah I'll never forget the first
time I photographed pink hairs under the
macro and it just I mean even just one
or two of them were so so striking and
so incredible that uh I remember
giggling you know as I shot that
plant yeah Coyote Blue um does that as
well and every once in a while you can
uh dry it cure it and revisit it and you
can still see some of that color that
doesn't always happen it's it's a very
special special thing when you when you
go revisit it and you you see the color
variations it's beautiful hey Craig does
that coffee that you're working with
um does it have a a distinct and
noticeable coffee Aroma to it or is it
just called coffee
Danny I was actually just texting with
uh Ka himself just now um yeah so it's
it's an AF out of Afghan stock that he
made and it and and it definitely has
a I I've only had it a couple times so
I'm going off memory but it's almost
reminiscent of of Gorilla Glue but but
different you know where Gorilla Glue to
me is more
chocolate I I was was at Justin
calvino's place in
mesino and um he was showing me this
coffee and I was just doing backflips I
was over the moon excited because coffee
is my second favorite drug and I love
coffee and cannabis together I have mugs
that have coffee and cannabis together I
mean they just it's just I just love it
but the and and cannabis is just
I mean what other thing in the world
smells like blueberry or catpiss smells
like skunk or like lemonade punch smells
like tangerines or dog [ __ ] smells
exactly like coffee I mean this
plant can mimic The Identical Aroma
profiles of beverages food and uh feal
matter uh like like a pro and you you
you just think that like coffee would be
like oh this guy is stoned and just
imagines this this smells like coffee
it's like no smell it this smells like
coffee this cannabis plant smells like
coffee and I got so excited and calvina
was like yeah I just rescued this one
little clone and it like looked like sad
and sickly on the side and he's like
there's no more of this anywhere left
he's like this is the last the coffee
and I was terrified that we were GNA
lose this like amazing plant and I've
always wanted to do a pairing um at a uh
with a coffee cuppers I don't know if
you guys know that like a wine somaler
somaler cannabis interponer and
turpening um you know you're a beer
cicerone you're a cheese Monger uh
you're um and if you guys haven't seen
the experts of which is actually shown
in California where these crazy
Californians are growing coffee um as a
Vine horizontally instead of letting the
tree grow up vertically I think you can
find that on uh Vice I think it's called
something like coffee land to Mecca
Coffee Land Mecca but if you look that
up you will see these people that are
just so enthralled with um uh with c but
I I'm sorry for that rant I just got
excited that you have this variety Craig
so um I would love to um I would love to
do a do something with that a coffee
parent with
coffee they also do it with tea with
cigars I mean cheese it's just on and on
and
on and only in Japan are you considered
a tea master
well I think China produces more tea and
uh some really fancy
ones from a product perspective I'm sure
China does but from a h Hospitality
perspective I don't think anybody serves
tea the way that a Japanese formal tea
party is is done it's it's it's a pretty
elaborate ceremony if you
will indeed it is I've
gotta I've got to uh say good day to
everybody um temperature's getting hot
and we've got lots and lots of Nursery
stock out there that need to be up
potted and implanted and cared for so I
want to thank everyone
um today for this time and space I
appreciate
y'all good to see you buddy thanks for
coming in
Craig good luck on the F Craig never at
the farmers for more than a couple hours
if you're take care Joshua got to work
on
Plants say I I have some
micology uh projects today I need to get
to and
um a couple hundred cacti I need to move
um max are you showing the the uh hops
cannabis or are you saving that till
next week yeah thanks for getting on
what a what a than you're getting on
that I want to hear about that man I'm I
my top three are hops or are beer coffee
and cannabis so when you're talking
about coffee I light up and then I I
totally spaced on that but
I
okay you
guys you pull all my uh all these
secrets out of me cuz trying to like you
know do the science on these tricomes
before other people do I'm trying I
would never you know go on something as
big as hash church with as many you've
got some of the world's experts in Korea
let me tell you yeah well and you know
what and that's why I appreciate when
you guys uh confirm that what I think
I've discovered um might actually
be uh something worth worth sharing
uh these are all canvas and hops
hybrids and so this this is a vine that
is producing hop
cones and the hot right and the Hop cone
will grow downward kind of like a little
uh right it's a little hop it's a hop
cone these hop cones are covered
glandular tricomes that are producing
177% THC 8%
CBD and so you can grow a wall of these
hops up the side of your house uh in
Vine like ways and and pull the mature
cones off of the plants um is that based
on dried way to plant material those
percentages yes so can you repeat that
again Max yeah so you're looking right
now you're actually looking at at
microscopic Tricom
pictures of this hybrid of humulus and
cannabis and you can these are the
glandular tricomes that are producing
anywhere
between
um uh I think 12 to 17% THC and upwards
of 5 to 8%
CBD and the the cones are um smokable
this is a great of the plant uh you can
definitely tell that this is not
anything like uh duck foot or any of the
other webbed foot varieties because of
the rest of the shape of the leaf notice
how there's no uh ridges in the leaf
right like if this was duck foot you
would see leaf ridging and look at the
triome matter coming out of this hot
plant um I mean that is really uh uh
quite
uh quite cannabis
indicative um this is uh the plant this
is a cannabis hot plant and this one is
growing this one took on more of the
form of the cannabis plant and less hop
Vine so this is really like a bushy kind
of cannabis plant um but it is not 100%
cannabis this one is another great
example but this one does have the leaf
uh ridging and the reason why
is because um uh this is not the same
genetic as the last one um what what I
can tell you about this genetic is this
was actually
ruderalis that was cross spread with um
the type of hot plant that receives uh
the cannabis genetics as a cross Max is
he producing corn corns like from what a
a hop root is or is it producing
seeds it is producing seeds uh the hot
plant and cannabis both produce
seed what's the tpping profile like
hasn't been tested
yet does it also have
romes reproduce that
way yeah that that's what I was
referring to by cors I don't know the
proper term I
um I am not growing this plant and the
gentleman who created the the the first
variety that actually took and turned
into an F7 uh humulus cannabis is in
Europe um this is a a friend of mine who
got a hold of the genetic in the United
States and crossed it with um some
marijuana types that he he was
hybridizing um indoors in his basement
and so this is a cannabis
leaf that took on the shape of that hop
plant I was showing you that has the uh
duck foot but without the leaf ridging
and so here you have a cannabis leaf
that actually took on the smooth Leaf
Edge instead of the rided edging um and
that's carried down from that hop line
and that hop genetic and so these
genetics are their brand spanking new in
in the world
of
species um this is a new species I mean
that's what we're talking about we're
talking about a new species and and then
what's interesting is a little of this
spe genetic profile can go back into
cannabis and put some of its genome back
into more uh um you know cannabis
genetics and I think that's what you're
seeing here with other cannabis Farmers
breeding into the genetic or breeding
the genetic into cannabis and really
this just produces a thousand more
questions than it does answers right
what is this what's the turpine profile
what's the tricomes look like I I think
these are passionate farmers and
breeders doing what they do best which
is just growing the stuff out and seeing
what they get but these guys aren't
putting this stuff under
microscopes um nor are they bringing
this stuff to universities to study um
uh the genome profile with uh in that
way and so I I hope to just assist these
passionate
breeders um and uh by by helping them
bring some of these genetics to
universities and other places to produce
some white papers on this stuff because
without question
this is new stuff this is brand new
stuff um in cannabis for
sure it's no longer cannabis it's no
longer cannabis exactly yeah now we're
we're getting into new
territory well very trippy dude thanks
for sharing that was uh that yeah
totally thank you you're welcome I mean
it's an honor right like this is how
well be interesting to like dab those
concentrates like what would it
concentrate from those right I mean
I I I go right to that
right it would be uh yeah of course you
go right to Citra Kush Citra kush man
all day well if it's got THC in it and
CBD in it why why wouldn't they get you
high I guess that's the question it does
get you high yeah and so this is like
how cool is it like we're now grow and
like and you know um I uh because I'm
writing about this stuff in the new
interpreting book I I did get the
breeder of this hop um cannabis hybrid
on the phone and I did
about this I got the whole backstory all
the different genetics went down where
it went down how it happened um so I'm
writing about all of that my new book um
are you gonna drop uh his name yeah yeah
in locations and all those things so you
the
book so uh um but he confirmed that the
purpose of this right like he wasn't
trying to produce a new species of plant
you know to get on the cover of National
Geographic but I think that could be uh
that could this could be uh that could
be one of those things his goal was to
try to do something similar uh to the
ABC genetic right can can you produce a
cannabis plant um that produces cannabis
in cognito so that Becky next St and the
sheriff across the street don't notice
that you've got ganja GR growing in your
yard right that that's kind of and that
was his goal right what could I produce
hops that could grow as a hops plant
that just so happened to be cannaboid
rich in in in a way in which I could
smoke it so could I just grow a big hop
vine on the side of my house and just
not have to deal with plant counts or if
it's medical is it legal do I have a
license for it it's like [ __ ] it [ __ ]
everything I'm just going to grow Vine
up the side of my house and if it gets
me high well then you can come over for
my backyard barbecue and try SL my
hops Vine so that's I've confirmed that
that was the do they also function like
hops like can you make beer from them
you know what I I have no idea why you
wouldn't be able to and
um I need to get my hands on this
genetic and work with it because I I
need to explore a lot of these things um
but it there it's weird I my
understanding of it
is you know the
uh um the plant that produces Jin
Juniper Jesus you know that Juniper is
either a tree or a
bush and like when you're out in the
mountains of Colorado you see Juniper
bushes and then you also see juniper
tree
it's really interesting um I think half
of these hybrids are more hop like and
they grow more vines that produce cones
that that have tricomes on them that are
cannaboid rich and I think the others
produce bushes that are more like
cannabis plants that grow more Bud um
and so the the ones that are more like
hot plants that grow more like Vines I
would have to imagine you could Brew
um as as
canibu which is a name that I federally
trademarked in 2009 when I thought I was
GNA produce cannabis beer instead of
starting a cannabis education company
which sometimes I still
wonder which I should have
done that's cool man very very cool I
like it I'm uh I'll be checking out the
book when it comes out and we'll see uh
go deeper into this I'm sure Nick zegler
would have been very interested to hear
this today I'll have to send him the
link later um I did want to share a
couple of uh your shots best friend
farmer and maybe you could tell us a
little bit about these shots dude
because I've really been enjoying these
shots uh you're making these like
dessert like shots that you're taking on
your Instagram what's what's what's
going on
here oh that one I can look at it that's
a 120 Micron gas mask uh indoor air
dried hash rosin cake on that one with a
beehive stamp dude it's just lovely this
one also I was just like thank
you yeah I like that one a lot that's
kind of like I was on this comfort food
kind of tip you know where I was even
going back to the foods that my mom made
growing up with it's kind of eerie
almost how closely connected in person
all the hashes to me and those type of
foods which I don't really eat anymore
but I'm gluten-free for five years so i'
I'd have to go GF but um that one is
actually apparently Colin likes this
too it looks like an apple cider
donut yeah Colin actually I think was
the one that said it looked like an
apple cider donnut with a maple glazing
on
it even that one is uh
on the outside what's that rosin all
along the outside it's all just so well
done yeah very thank you you know
I I did that by just personal sorry go
ahead I just I had fun with that one
right there man that was like all of
these I actually did by hand a couple of
them on a Sunday even and just kind of
like escape from all the industry stuff
which is so involving and I you know to
kind of go back to some Artistic Touch
on it stuff I like to do and I just kind
of had fun with the smear and and the
yeah I remember doing it kind of just
like drawing almost and and just had fun
with it and I I have it with me here I
can show you the actual scale size yeah
yeah show us the actual scale size but
also like what do you got you got like a
rosin splotch along the bottom and then
you got like a bubble donut with some
like diamonds and sauce Port over it or
something like what oh man so so that's
a 90 uh Micron air dried whole plant
cured flow indoor bubble hash for the
the actual doughnut and then that's a 90
Micron air dried whole plant fresh
frozen that's some air dried fresh
frozen I get a lot of the the tannin
richness on my air drrive but it's just
as Saucy it'll never go stable it's just
sauce and then it's all it's all in line
gas mask all three and then I got a 120
Micron again air dried hole plant cured
flower crumble on the seeve portion so
that's just like some chunk that we
didn't Z didn't press and kind of the
cool thing is with air dried is we're
seeing some different texture and tan
and richness uh differences that you
don't really get when you have just
fresh frozen or freeze-dried so kind of
fun we're actually applying some of the
darker tan and stuff and it's none of
it's BS though it's all melty I'd I'd
like to melt the whole doughnut sometime
try to share the video the size of
it all right I got it right
here the dut's actually pretty
small pulls out a
bunt look at this
thing sorry for my dirty farmer hands I
definitely have my dirty
F so
bad imagine I'm going to do it right now
that is absolutely awesome I want to do
just the this is
the that's my cookie though guys that's
a one oer right there oh I haven't uh
I'm just about to hit your cookie right
now so let's look at it on the screen
what the hell like how come you're not
my neighbor I just actually added you my
Instagram I can't even believe what
about this one before
Jesus that's the whoopy pie that's like
some comfort food from home from
Mom the scale I got to dig it up it's
tiny I did a couple micros kind of like
making micro models type thing you know
too it's fun like art fun and then this
guy's
fun oh
wow I just have to say
okay if you talk you talk then it'll go
on you but it'll it was on me first and
then it went on to John so show that
again but also
talk talk all right so this one here
oops I'm having a hard time showing it
I'm trying there it
is that's your guy it's been kind of
pressed up in the parchment I just tried
to preserve them I might auction them
off at a local dispensary friend
shop um for benefit or something I'm
make
more looks like
theie yeah I don't know you what they
call them down there but that's what we
call them up here a Whoopi pie Whoopi
pie
yeah yeah that one is actually gas mask
in the middle for a rosin I think that's
a 120 Micron a dried indoor and then
those were some hacap which was Sunday
is Sunday brunch by great pie on some
broadspectrum air dried stuff you know
kind of wider broadspectrum and that's
the cookie that's the scale and I can
show you guys
again the cookie amazed me how much it
looks like an unbaked cookie it's kind
of
crazy there's that that guy what are the
chocolate chips made out
of ch chocolate chips are a broad
spectrum also kind of like a wider uh
broad spectrum from trim hash bubble
hash all Air dried and kind of long air
dry on that stuff maybe even up to like
three weeks so it's got the tannin
richness to it and then I'll just check
myself real quick to make sure because
it's been a
minute um so the chips are two grams
they're quarter gram each and it's gas
mask actually broads Spectrum air dried
from the trim in the littles and then
the cookie was a 26 gram gas Mass 90
Micron air dried and it was just this
bubble hash that on the gas mask
cultivar is one of those that speaks to
the real blonde creamy greasy hash and
I've talked about it before it's just
one of those special hash plants and it
kind of retains its creaminess and and
greasy feel even later on it still has
the the cookie still has it right now
so it sounded like
when you were like describing what these
different things were I was just
laughing because it just sounded like
such just I don't know I love it that
was great it's fun yeah I've had a lot
of fun true
artist yeah I really appreciate
it someone many ways someone should do a
book on like hash that looks like
desserts and foods and your pictures
could be highlighted in that because
when I saw them last week I wanted to
kind of go over them but then you were
having internet problems or whatever you
had to go and I didn't bring it up soon
enough yeah by the time I did bring it
up here
no I'm really happy the farming didn't
take over so much that I could come in
today and actually get the technology
right to because I'm very analog so this
is cool and um I'd love to share show
more of them for sure that's one from
way back and I was going to bring that
up to mention that one of the things
that motivated me besides the Comfort
Food Connection art thing and love for
hash was that people just kept dropping
bombs for comments on the Instagram when
it came to these type of hash things
from the air drive that we were doing
that we make and it kind of just really
struck me to where why not make these
food items specifically in design
towards you know looking like that that
food and hash connection there's
definitely something there just like
with the with the tarpine talk that
we're doing
I was eating some chocolate and as I
grabbed up a piece of I thought was
chocolate was hash I started eating it
and I realized it wow so when you're
saying that it looked like the chocolate
kep like I got it chocolate
chip
awesome I've almost eaten a few of the
pieces they just look
tasty well they are you can just like
break off a little like chocolate that
looks like creme
brulee that's what I've heard before on
that that's some bubble cream right
there a recent gas mask
again these are uh concentrate
Confections it's wild
it's wild the connection it just seems
to be there
already that's some good classic kind of
broad spectrum stuff right there too I
think gentlemen I've got some uh
micology to attend to I'm gonna go bake
some horeshit in my oven before the
fiance gets home it's your favorite good
call good call but you guys rock thanks
so much for having me back I appreciate
it yeah thanks Max always a pleasure man
enjoy your Sunday afternoon see you guys
see you Max thanks for the learning Yeah
by yeah that was mad fun I uh I should
get going here soon as well I really did
enjoy the hash
confu um quarterly that we just did
Let's uh let's Inspire more of you to
take a book out of a page out of best
friend Farm's book and produce some
really really cool dessert looking
hashes I'm telling you like I don't do
books but there's I'm down do yeah
someone do a book man I want that book
like and and the photos need to be high
quality so you can put them on a on a
very nice size very high quality paper
you know coffee table book hash dabbing
book oh man I'm way down hit me up on it
I'm gonna make more hash food in the
meanwhile still sweets but I got a few
ideas also make nice postcard cards and
you don't say what they really are you
just give them
some food
name
totally yeah it's true it's all true
well listen everybody thanks for coming
out for hash Church episode 23 today I
superly appreciate each and every one of
you uh let's try and do it again next
week I'll try to give people more for
warning than uh a couple of hours so
thanks everybody peace out thank you
thank you Mark