hey welcome everybody to bubble man's
world and welcome to hash Church episode
153 that is correct we're three episodes
away from three years of hash Church I
think that's pretty pretty awesome I'm
just gonna send a link out here real
quick to our friends let me see 1 &amp; 2
and finally but not least last but not
least we'll hit there that way we can
get Etienne in the room who let's be
honest he's always first thank God for
ED ta well 141 people have beat him into
the room sorry 160 people have beat him
into the room I hope you guys all had a
wonderful weekend I did I was doing wake
and bakes the whole week long but we are
at Sunday and I've invited a pretty good
crew in today let's hope that we get
some we get some friends in here sooner
than later maybe we'll just start it out
with a rip like right away shall we
everyone ready got your rigs
I know Sam's got his you ready Sam Sam I
can't hear anyone at 10 no can't hear
you I wonder if they can hear me I
they can hear me I cannot hear you say
how about you Sam have you tried talking
yet Sammy Sam you're on mute so try to
unclick yourself if you okay good I can
be heard perfect well I can hear you
perfect yes at 10:00 is having the same
problem as last time it was throwing me
off cuz no one was making no one was
making sounds
well welcome guys I think Etienne will
be back in a few minutes and good after
what good evening for you Sam good
afternoon that what we say well
regardless of what we say I'm having a
bond wrap all puff to myself I don't
need anyone else to talk to me in the
room I'm good to go let's do this hash
Church 153 all right let's puff it up
yes Sam slides in first ahead of Etienne
don't see that very often now but I'm a
pretty slippery guy when you want to be
yes when you want to be beautiful day
today
quite nice that's what I heard you say
that that's always sweet when it's a
beautiful day in Amsterdam because we
get a lot about sunshine in the form of
condensed rain in a sense we also get a
good amount of rain we we call it liquid
Sun chart yes welcome back and welcome
marks shall Doane dr. mark how you doing
bud how was your uh your kind of
vacation it was really good yeah my dad
was in town last week so we were out to
brunch and never really made it back in
time to get back on but
before then we were yeah checked out for
like three weekends for the baker's
dozen that's all it was yeah it was
great so they're about to rip it up in
Dixon Colorado that'll always be fun
fish loves dicks but it'll always be a
good show out there so hide all the
people going up to Colorado
oh is that tan trying to talk again oh
my goodness he's still not I really
dislike technical difficulties not not
at ten having them but like myself when
I'm having them like I feel for Etienne
when you just want to be heard and you
cannot be heard I'm sure he'll figure it
out
he and figure eight that was when when
my computer laptop gets hot then my
microphone start breaking off oh yeah
yeah well yeah
gotta get try to get the Logitech's
gotta get the good the Carl Zeiss lens I
remember trying to buy a good a good
video webcam for a computer is not as
easy as it would I thought there would
be way better versions of them and
they're just kind of they kind of tap
out at around a hundred and a bit and
just not that great all right well
what's in the world of cannabis this
week what have we been hanging in the
world of cannabis this week hey so what
was that with discussion about hash
versus oil where did that come from
was that know what that was really I saw
Addison had made a post yeah you know
I'm sick of arguing with hash makers and
I just the minute I saw it I was like
he's not arguing with hash makers he's
arguing with oil makers and I guess
maybe it's semantics maybe it's just me
because most people weren't in agreement
at all but I also think most people who
are oil smokers want their oil to be
hash but hash smokers never call their
hash oil
so it's this very strange thing now for
me I have nothing against oil we're
selling turb oil in the bubble man pen
it's literally designed for oil you know
you have to make oil out of the hash
before you can get it in there type of
thing but not only that but you're
taking the dry sift and making rosin out
of it which is practically bucket oil
well it is oil to me I mean oil to me is
just dissolved heads that have been
extracted to me and I've always just you
know from the book hashish is from I've
always considered it's my sister she's
not gonna stop shell foaming like 25
more times it'll be fine I've always
thought that oil and hash are different
thus the wording I guess these people
have decided that oil and hash are not
different and that's cool we can
disagree it's not really the end of the
world by any means but in my opinion and
that's maybe all it is there's a reason
why we call oil oil and why we call
hashish hashish and they are different
and that's just my opinion maybe it's
not a fact for everyone but I couldn't
believe the conversation mark I was just
shaking my head completely I mean yeah
yeah I think that's what it became a
personal attack but it's always kind of
like I think yeah it's semantics in a
way but I remember growing up that there
were there was hash and then there was a
hash oil so there were two different
there were two different categories and
but there was also eat oil right right
but it didn't matter that it came from
the same you know plant or that you know
basically if it's the oil you know from
the secretory gland itself and you're
somehow milking the oil out in an
extraction process or whatever process
you have a way of basically making a
liquid extract which I guess is oil so
to me oil or as a chemist you would
think that oil has got to be a liquid
right like what was that one comet if it
doesn't bounce it's not
that was this guy Sam Wayne Smith he's
like if he doesn't bounce in 72 degrees
but they completely counter contradicted
himself and oppose prior to that well he
also said something about extracting
cellulose and we all know that these
these cells the the secretory cells and
the dis cells from the great work of
palma berg is all lipid based those are
lipid structures and those are not
cellulosic structures at all and so to
bring cellulose into the game is just I
don't understand that but yeah the whole
bouncing thing I mean yeah it depends up
what temperature because you could make
oil bounce at a really low temperature
for me it wasn't about bouncing it's
super simple if you have dissolved the
heads and they are now liquefied it's
right and if they are micro encapsulated
resin glands resin heads this is hashish
so I mean as a chemist do you consider
hash and yeah to be the center no no III
understand your distinction which is
sort of like one is mechanically removed
in place micro encapsulated and the
other is just completely dissolved and
scrambled into this mixture of c1
putting one above the other I think when
people say hash is not oil it's because
they it's funny I see the oil community
want oil to be hashed so badly they're
making it so they're just saying it's
all it's hash and I'm saying hash has
always been something you know you can
yeah what's your opinion on this because
let's be honest I guess in the end it's
all really just opinions
Wow did it ever turn into a total
personal attack on me because I said in
my opinion hash is not I agree with you
Marcus except for rosin is kind of I
mean is it really an oil or because not
all rosin is totally some rosin is not
oily so right some is buttery etc uh I
can I call it hash oil I mean because
we're just looking for a designation for
where the concentrate therein lies the
closest we can come to his hash we
haven't separated it
into his own separate category of
extraction or extraction methodology as
much as we're just kind of all lumped
everything into what the concentrate is
so we we refer to him as concentrates I
mean in all reality but I mean first
things we came up with when we can't
when it came out was what do we call
this stuff because it looked really
weird so we started call it earwax
because that's the closest it looked to
it color and consistency etc so it's
more of nomenclature that's come across
the board then anybody sit there sitting
there dictating this is you know hash
this isn't hash and I agree with you I
hear you in principle but I still refer
to it as hash oil because of back in the
90s when I originally started to see it
through through extraction methods there
was this one cat here in the Bay Area he
used to wear a Cat in the Hat hat all
the time and he was an old cat and he
came around with hash oil originally
that I had seen in very small vials and
back then it was like a thousand dollars
or something vile he was talking about
and I tried it once and it knocked me on
my ass it was the highest I'd ever
gotten and it was I want to say it was
93 93 94 it was dark
but it was closer to golden than it was
a black oil and that's the first time he
had ever seen a kind of a golden oil but
this guy would only show up at rallies
and he was very kind of much a dick and
exclusionary he passed away I do believe
in the 90s as well and I didn't see
anything close to that until we started
to see what we called honey bud and
that's because early on there was no way
for us to deal or nobody was really sure
how to handle this wax substance so they
basically liquefied it and sprayed it on
to lower to mid grade buds so the buds
were saturated and so that way we could
put it into a bong and smoke it because
again you have to understand kids there
was none of this dabbing technology this
all kind of really creeped out in the
and right so it was hot knifing or in
our case we would use the old coals
where you'd have to wait with the
Gunpowder in the coal and you'd have to
wait for all the Gunpowder to burn off
first and then scrape away right the
smelly room take we would take a dot of
it and put it on aluminum foil then hold
a lighter underneath the aluminum foil
and chase the dragon these differences
one of the things I said in that thread
was that you know I said I grew up in
the 70s in the 80s and we had weed oil
and we had hash oil and hash oil was
simply hash oil that was made from hash
weed oil was boiled it was made from
herb and then some guy came in and he
laughed at me and he said oh so you're
gonna say that you know it's different
from this from that I'm like well it was
I it just was it was back then it was
different like hash oil was much thicker
and stronger and heavier then the same
oil made from herb this is well not to
mention it was Messier stickier and you
didn't have any tools or any way to
figure out there's no way if you had
both of them there was no way you
couldn't see the strong differences so
for me you know I also would say that
making why I think hash and oil are so
different is because extracting with a
polar or a non-polar solvent is
extracting different things than when
extracting with mechanical screen
separation you're not extracting the
same things exactly yes
by nature different and may get attacked
by a lot of people that think they know
what they're [ __ ] talking about in
that thread I wish I could invite them
all in to sort of speak their piece
because well it's a Val it's a valid
discussion because it's one that needs
an Amber casein from where we are
because existed you know common
knowledge is a type of hash oil we
listed under concentrates so for me I
think it is a concentrate yeah we think
that's a property evident clay Chur more
than just hash sort of qualifying like
what a material is it's more hash to me
anyway says more about how it's made
right it's more about the process by
which it's made and not in this is
so the end product you'd say the rep
what represents the end product how it's
made right right oh yeah because you
can't you can't reincorporate after
you've dissolved stuff right well and
you've got its difference between co2 as
well as what you're extracting from pH
oh you know we're isolating particular
particular gland heads by micron size
and oil is mouth dissolving every single
gland head bulbous but you can I can see
why the connotation or the understanding
is that way because it's still a form of
to them they're only a nomenclature that
they know is hash or a type of hash
because that is a cannabis resin
concentrate you know so I understand the
nomenclature I just don't think we have
you know you know what you need to do
then you know we need to put out white
papers you know a proper discussion
breakdown and put a circle eight
something like that and discuss it
because it's a it's a valid point of
breakdown of nomenclature which I do
believe needs to be you know dealt with
a certain level so that you know you can
deal with you know the water extraction
versus you know butane extraction versus
you know rosin because rosin is a
different you know beast altogether then
either BHO or pho or you know co2 itself
so each extraction I don't know does it
then justify its own name nomenclature I
think at a certain resolve this
discussion is bringing that division up
so that we can have an understanding
because the consumer doesn't have an
understanding as much as what they have
access to or read or hear about again
when I first I went back to West
Virginia in 2013 friends would tell me
have you heard about this stuff called
earwax it's everywhere now and I went
down to the local bomb shop there and
they've got full rigs and stuff going on
so the how its spread was pretty quick
but the the hash itself spread faster
than the understanding of the process or
a breakdown of what the concentrate is
what do you think about that Sam do you
think there's
the individual named classifications per
process in the near future I will be
releasing my new patented parties which
have resin heads the size of grapes so
you just squeeze it and people won't be
doing extractions anymore there won't be
any need though just be picking grapes
off and having fun can we make sure
those grapes are seedless god I hope so
that'd be horrible I just don't think
it's really a big deal that they're
different I just think that it's funny
that oil seems to the oil community
wants oil to be hashish so desperately
and it's just from from where I just
don't see it as being a sheet they want
to be included I get why they want to be
included it's just they could they can
separate themselves properly by actually
saying you know we are different we're
this and then back what that is but
they're confused to a certain resolve
because happy with being stronger than
almost all commercially produced in
imported a sheesh so the extracts can
easily you know beat them in the dust
with both terpene and that's why my
medicine is predominantly that nowadays
because of that you know it works for me
it doesn't work for everybody but i
still call it hash you know because
that's as close as people can understand
it marcus i'm not necessarily trying to
say or undermine the discussion it's
just people for the most part less than
1% of us are aware of this you know as
it is we know we're kind of at that that
spearhead again and we could affect
change that ripples through if we you
know we take the discussion seriously so
that they can realize you know I am a
particular process that is that stands
out and so therefore we should move this
but I understand why they're lumping
themselves into hash because that's as
close to a denomination as they can get
nomenclature wise
I believe in the consumer knowing what
it especially anything to do with health
and safety if there's any compromise
whatsoever for any reason then the
consumer should be aware of it but well
here's what I'm I'm having a discussion
Sam what Sam I we're having a discussion
currently if it is a worthy discussion
to gather the fertilizer grown of that
particular flower listed along with the
other information such as potency grower
might be fairly important if you're a
chemical grower then I'm not sure how
important it is if it's a chemical NPK
then that's what it is well some
patients were asking you know well what
was this originally grown with and it
started me to think that well this was
an older consumer I would say she was
probably in her mid to late 50s and she
asked a very legitimate question
well what fertilizer was grown with this
and it as I was behind the counter doing
my own transaction on the side I started
to think about you know that's a very
valid point of notification because it's
not something that we've ever considered
or had much less the base of testing and
technology but is the consumer as you're
watching are you the consumer are you
concerned about the fertilizer that's
grown II you just care about the end
product you know care how it's you know
what it's produced with versus what it
there's a growing number of consumers
that care how their cannabis or tomatoes
and food in general is grown that said
the vast majority of Americans don't
seem to give a flying [ __ ] I mean the
GMO corn and they chemically fertilized
corn and that's where the universe works
the first time it's the first time in
the history of the world that poor
people are obese check that out
that's a Creole America America believes
in that
food stamps and TV and high fructose
corn syrup apparently that's what you
can buy with them mm-hmm yeah I've
always considered it well like when I
smoked hash and I when I smoked oil and
I only smoked rosin that's the only oil
I smoked but I can tell you that they're
different 100 that's okay they are not
the same in my opinion from even the
highs that they give from the same
material hitting an oil from something
and even hitting different micron gland
heads from the same cultivar can produce
you know slightly different you can get
a different high from the resin from the
vho from just the resin heads themselves
I think that's why we make it
differently okay and why do people have
preferences so and I think also one of
the major problems I had with Addison's
comment was that he's a founder in steep
hill a lab a lab for cannabis and I just
felt like shouldn't we use like the like
the proper sort of like when we're
speaking about these things like you are
a person that's going to be informing
the majority of people you're testing
cannabis you're testing hash well you
know we just need scientists and peer
review I mean it's the same way that
we're still having difficult with you
know Rob Clark pointed out a few years
ago now that in to consider or not what
we thought they were so now we have to
change or start their spark this
discussion you know that actually
changes you know this constant the
definition of these concentrate
nomenclatures you know because they are
different you know and I love Addison
I've worked with Addison originally way
back in the day in dealing with testing
so but at the same time there's no
different scientific classification or
that has been presented to say otherwise
so I can see why he would say currently
it is is but I understand what you're
saying and I think it's a valid
discussion because
as concentrates are a whole other level
of discussion than they were 10 15 years
ago
not only that thanks to you by having
your bubble bags and things like that I
have 8 to 10 varieties of bubble hash as
well as 8 to 10 varieties of rosin and
etc so I have the full spectrum you know
and so it's now it's left to the
consumer to the side however you know
you're the scientists you're the people
who can break down information properly
and dissin ate it in white papers so
that you can get peer review so that you
can then change the discussion as
opposed to I mean are like eventually ed
Chen the old lady that came in and asked
about what the fertilizer was that per
budget for an extract and that was for
buds but I mean actually she she's gonna
be doing it for extracts to do right and
so that's why I was thinking and I
started discussed with my you know my
purchasers is you know should we do this
how would we gather this information how
does it make it to where it needs to go
as well as you know is it valid or
worthy information to have is it just a
waste of time currently or is this
another way that we can set trend by you
know now posting the type of growth
methodologies that goes along with it
yeah one thing you can do is start
collecting the information voluntarily
from from the growers and get feedback
from the people who buy it and see are
their preferences towards particular
fertilization regimes and that's that's
a you know it's gonna take time but I'm
good I've already started gathering that
information so that we could learn you
know because you know part of our work
good and it's because when the consumers
are now asking for and since I am you
know a pioneering dispensary first I
don't you know I think of new ways to
disseminate or gather information for
the consumer because it makes a
difference for me when I go to a Whole
Foods or any you know store do I buy
conventional organic I tend to go
organic you know if I have that option
or I can afford that
option that's not always the case but if
I can you know I do think about that and
I forget for organic as long as the
organic every single time because to say
it's not organic means that chemicals
were sprayed on the earth and go
affecting animals inspecting everyone
and then at the same how are we getting
away with something they're just curious
slight oh we save some money so we're
good but nothing else is so I agree with
you but I or to Utley eat for taste so
if something tastes better i as as it's
not dangerous than I would prefer it but
yeah I agree dress if it's been great
with what you're saying but I'm addicted
to taste well you're in luck because
organic food a hundred times you know I
always taste better so you're pretty
much good to go on that there's two
different types of taste
there's the organic delicious sustaining
life and there's the toxic chemical
Monsanto which convinces your brain it's
delicious while simultaneously poisoning
your body and those around you so this
is what we have to deal with this is the
position we're in in every decision we
make every time we open our mouth it's
interesting to hear from the connoisseur
perspective like and then have forests
come in and you realize no you don't
understand like these chemicals will
absolutely affect these children these
sensitive sensitive being I didn't mean
chemicals as much as chemical
fertilizers because in a lot of
countries they will use one particular
of PK because their soils deficient in
it and without it it really super poor
yields mmm which plant material and bio
maps can help a lot better than chemical
fertilizers listen I wait a minute I bet
a biodynamic farmer I was taught by Alan
Chadwick I understand you don't need to
preach to me I'm
converted I don't feel like I'm
preaching I'm just talking its hashed
Church it is I do want to clarify is
that I've had some wonderful organic
fruit that tasted like [ __ ] before so it
doesn't make it everything absolutely
taste good I've had bad tasting stuff
before too but for the most part I agree
is that it does like like if you do
something properly and it brings out the
flavor noise it brings out that you know
everything that you want you know and I
prefer somebody's homegrown something
that's opposed to a mass-produced
absolutely agree with you in general
it's true I know I wouldn't mind talking
really quickly about how like amendments
and fertilizers do affect medicine and
for us to just look at it as a
connoisseur
you know aspect makes it really
difficult because there's a whole
growing process that goes into it and
all of the nutrients and inputs that
goes into it are really all part of the
factor so we get tons of people that
want to know how medicine has grown and
it's really really important to them and
when they find out that wow this
medicine tastes really good and it was
grown in a way that was eka logically
supporting nature and the environment
they're all over it they don't want to
have anything to do as chemicals
generally speaking most of the time and
we're finding that to be a really really
important part of the selling point for
farms because they get to tell their
story they get to show how they're
supporting bee populations and in the
end I know a lot of farmers we work at
the tone of farmers and they have maybe
worked synthetically or in chemical
regiments before and then turned over
towards organics or towards even plant
material or Korean natural farming
methods and they're getting higher
cannabinoid counts and higher terpene
levels through those methods so I think
that there's a lot of reasons why it's
really important about what we put into
the medicine and if it can create a
high-grade product in the end it's a
huge selling point because people really
are behind it so what what do you guys
think about that
well I think that I wanted to a welcome
you to the room
and also welcome wave in to the room
from house of Harlequin and also welcome
be 420k
into the room from the house of nar and
[ __ ] welcome forest into the room i
hope i hope you're all doing well I
didn't miss anyone did I know those were
the newbies I had DS been in the room
for like an hour and I just or a half an
hour and I just welcomed him now so yeah
I couldn't keep interrupt you guys's
conversation I was pretty deep stuff man
I could even fit in a ball rip in there
I just did one that's it we're just
trying to get into the conversation I
love one forest and wade coming to the
conversation because it really you know
and something that you said joschwa in
regards to we have to take it beyond the
connoisseur sort of level and I totally
get that yet at the same time it really
has been some of the most OCD
connoisseurs who have maintained and
stewarded this this plant this medicine
to a point where the people who are like
oh this is the most special thing right
here it's like I've been I've been it's
for my head it's for you know we've been
sharing it for 20 it seems that there's
a really interesting transition from
those the same way that particular plant
makes someone feel incredible through
their recreational feelings or adult use
that it translates over to some very
powerful medicine versus you know buying
some XE sweg off the street or whatnot
as Sam knows the biodynamic collects do
bring out amazing qualities in in
cannabis and food and that's why it's
still around how many years have you
been growing cannabis biodynamically
since I have been up here for and 19
years I mean you know biodynamic so how
about this you know I've been doing it
twice as long so so I I believe in it
it's the way I personally do it but I
also know that most farms are not
biodynamic or be they vegetables fruits
or cannabis and I think it would be
better at more were but yeah it's it's
hard to convince somebody
well the proof is in the puffing
whatever you were doing back in the day
Sam when I first met you whatever you
were growing I can honestly say to this
day that was grown biodynamic no one's
ever put anything it like that is really
seriously medicine that is like medicine
that frightened my soul like I've never
been high like that in my life like that
is that you could probably eat enough of
that and operate on a person like you
would knock them unconscious for 36
hours if you ate how did you ever get
knocked out by eating that resin Sam as
in well what happened to me a few times
when I made no big cookies I would make
them with a half a gram or a gram of THC
so each one would have one gram or even
two grams of the dry cept that was 50
percent THC by weight
so having emulsifier in those cookies to
break it down yeah they were putting
ghee and also to activate them they were
double boiled biggie right butter and
then powdered sugar and powdered cocoa
okay that sounds like a trip ticket to
another dimension quite strong yeah a
few people who ate a few of those also
when you took a bite out of them it was
like the strongest by deenis peppery
taste from the from the rest that you've
ever tasted I mean they were really
really rich of herpes because it's not
THC that has that bitter bite it's a
it's a terpenes isn't it strange that
this plant gets made illegal so long ago
it's got these incredible properties but
it seems that people who want to get
high are the people who are the stewards
for all of these years while they're
trying to eradicate it and get rid of it
and it's just this really I keep going
back to that transition of you know the
hashish eaters getting their teeth
wrenched out in the 14th century in the
Cairo
square-like compared to now where it's
just opening up and it's it's just so
much bigger than a dolt use now as as as
we're all seeing and learning over the
who would have ever thought twenty years
ago that you know cannabis would be
resetting credit for all of the things
that it's that it's now being credited
for its pretty spectacular I wanted to I
think I honestly did believe in all of
these medical applications even ones
that we hadn't heard of yet I expected
them to be bound with each different
cannabinoid with each different terpene
combination you know it's going to
modify it for other medical indications
so I expect I was more of the school of
like I thought it was burning out my
brain cells when I was like 14 15 puffs
and joints I just figured that's what it
was doing and as I you know learned as I
met people like Hillary black and
yourself and many others I realized that
wow this is this is unbelievable
just how actually helpfully people it's
true that in the 1800's and a lot of the
apothecaries and then the Victorian era
cannabis was a base of tons of medicine
so it's almost like we had to force
teach ourselves that it wasn't good and
they had to force it down our throats
that kills brain cells and and monkey
brain cells and all that for us to
totally forget about it in math so that
we could totally rediscover it and find
out wow it's amazing it's a medicine and
it is an incredible awakening and with
all the labs even though some of the
labs are talking controversial stuff you
know they have helped us get to a lot of
really good information and it's really
exciting ya know for sure nobody would
have CBD varieties hmm there you go and
everybody loves their CBD varieties big
deal almost everybody
so forest we were having a discussion
right before you came on regarding a
question I don't know if you heard
in our discussion prior I had a patient
come in and she was wondering what
fertilizers were used on the product and
how they were groaning so we were
starting the we've started the
discussion to the point where we're
actually gathering or doing our best to
gather from the farmers as they come in
is what you know what they actually grew
up with and just having the discussion
do you think it's beneficial and of
course I know with you it's probably a
no-brainer but I'd like to hear from you
well I mean I think it's absolutely
beneficial I mean knowledge is its power
right and if we're doing things that are
there's a lot of fertilizers that can be
relatively harmless but whatever you put
into the ground it's gonna be in the
plant I mean that's what's amazing about
cannabis and that's what you have to be
responsible about it as well it's a bio
accumulator it's going to take what's in
that soil and make it part of its itself
so a lot of times it's just a lot of
folks want it to be kind of black and
white good and bad right and wrong evil
there are fertilizers that can be really
beneficial and healthy for the plant
that the plant needs for a healthy soil
there's a lot of but a lot of that
fertilizer doesn't necessarily mean
medical like Miracle Grow right or some
sort of manmade compound even you know
building living soil can be done without
a lot of toxic things so I think a
survey for growers coming in especially
as an establishment that is you know
working with patients is a great
practice to say here's what it is and
then how is the medicine made if you're
using certain fertilizers you have
certain practices there's a big
difference on if you're making a
medicine from the flower or just selling
flowers they're making extract from
flowers versus if you're making that
extract through roots and stalks and
stems and calling it whole plant so your
risk goes up higher there because that's
where the plant stores a lot of
compounds that could potentially be
risky you know as we learn more about
and we've talked about this here before
but we learn more about certain metals
or toxins that can be stored in a plant
so you know right now it's hard to be
back and white as far as what's good
what's stored where how is it
transferred with the exception of you
know systemic pesticides that we see
coming in even second and third
generations with plants but the reality
is I think if you as a business owner
are do being responsible enough to say
well here's the information at least
giving the consumer the ability to look
at it and make a decision for you
themselves then that's as much as we can
do at this point you know because we are
still learning about how much is
transferred where and what is how it
affects the people so a more working
with children who are as young as six
months old you know we have a
zero-tolerance policy because certain
pesticides of compounds we know we're
toxic and then others well the science
is still out we're looking at it so we
play on the safe side either way you
know but I think with a lot of medicine
right now a lot of people just don't
understand it what is missing is just
the information there for the consumer
to make the decision that is best for
them not necessarily having to have
everything on some sort of standard that
is you know the standard that I would
expect with with children because not
everyone needs if I were going to get a
product you know and this is where I
think the future of cannabis especially
when it comes to pricing and economics
is a grading type of scale you know I
know I don't mean is a full-grown adult
and I'm not treating health conditions
if I want to go get some flowers what
would be safe for me it's a completely
different grading scale than what would
be safe for for maybe some other people
with immunocompromised systems and
things like that so you know I'm I'm on
the on the side of just the information
should be there so that people who know
what they're using it for can get
medicine that is appropriate for them
right I have a question I can absolutely
agree with you and I'll be happy to grow
it for you
outdoors where the birds might poop on
it a little tiny bit I have a question
for you Forrest have you noticed any
differences I'm sure a lot of parents
notice the differences in the Kanab
and terpene profiles and how those can
change and help and maybe not help but
have you ever noticed differences in how
the medicine was extracted whether it
was an oil whether it was made with a
screen separations do you notice
differences in those yeah yeah
absolutely this is why you know and I'll
tell everyone here we as a clatters
Network we use we're doing ethanol
extraction organic ethanol extraction
which a lot of people might shake oh
that's not the the best way to do it and
well for one we have our fortunate to
have a lot of lab testing so we make
sure you have no solvents and things
like that but the reason we settled on
that as opposed to like even co2 right
now is because of an efficacy difference
that we've seen and you know without
going into that ethanol extraction isn't
just one thing a lot of people hear that
and they say well I do that too but you
know I'd like to use the example of we
can give everybody you can give me the
ingredients for a beef wellington and
you can give Gordon Ramsay the
ingredients for a beef wellington just
because we have the same thing the same
equipment doesn't mean we're going to
get the same product at the end so how
we spent years you know really trying to
refine our methods so that we can get a
really whole plant representation of the
oils and the flavonoids enterpreneurs in
it that I feel like I've missed and we
didn't see the same advocacy with some
of those other processes that are really
good at stripping out a lot of the plan
you know you get these beautiful golden
transparent Amber's but when we went to
use some of the medicines we just didn't
see some of the efficacy and we just
made the determination that well with
our limited resources and our need for
whatever was missing out of these two we
settled on this this other extraction
method specifically although we saw a
more pure in pretty-looking product with
some of the co2 you know closed-loop
systems the efficacy wasn't anywhere
near as good and so my logic would
me that something was taken out during
that process that was having medical
benefit and forest for your information
if use an ultrasonic shaker with a an
ethanol bath and you put whatever you
want extracted that for about 30 seconds
while you're shaking it the oil will
come out light yellow you only get about
80 percent yield you lose about 20
percent but you can then extract that
with ethanol in the way you've been
doing it but we you'll get all that is
so pretty that you won't believe them
yeah I mean we have oil that is and I
could run and grab some of those
probably wouldn't look you wouldn't be
able to tell over the webcam but it's um
it's beautiful amber it's not you know
it's not that sludgy chlorophyll filled
sort of you soak it and the higher the
temperature of the ethanol the darker
and greener it gets right right so we do
very short soaks and those sort of
things but but anyway yeah so it's a
long answer to a short question but all
that led through seeing differences in
an efficacy that I think have to do with
what is and isn't filtered out of the
plant and how you administering the
extract is this in the sub lingual
tanner
yeah for the most part so well for the
most part it's considered internal
because sublingual you know beholding
under the tongue and a lot of kids
aren't cooperative so even though
internal dosing is probably the least
efficient and you know the liver removes
a lot of it before it even becomes
really effective in the system with with
kids and and people who have
developmental delays you know you don't
always have the most understanding or
cooperative patient so we give it in
them however we can but yeah sublingual
and internally now you know what is the
analyzed for in terms of cannabinoid
content and say that again a broken
what is the extract analyzed for in
terms of navitor content hmm
well I mean we do a full cannabinoid
profile and then
besides microbio residual solvents you
know those sort of things so isn't like
60% or 70% cannabinoids or I would say
the average between we are just come out
between like 65 and 75 yeah in that
window the reason I was asking about the
different types of medicine my friend
Cheryl Rose her daughter Hayley who's
ICI also has LGS I guess got diagnosed
when she was quite young like seven or
eight years old and they they found this
Halley's Comet this high CBD cultivar
that worked for her they named it after
her Halley's Comet and she was getting
quite relief from this and it was just
something interesting I've never really
talked about it much you know I I didn't
want to sound like like I was trying to
promote my company but I had given her
bags so that she could make different
medicines for me and I guess in the end
she started giving her this bubble in
capsules instead of the oil she was
making and it was the first time Haley
had ever gone I think it was a hundred
or two hundred days without a seizure
mistimed yeah yeah cause if you know the
oil and stuff cut her seizures down by
like 90% or something but it didn't
completely eliminate them it was only
until she started making bubble hash and
putting all the different micron hashes
inside the capsules that that she got
this incredible you know like I'm pretty
sure it was over a hundred days which I
don't think Haley had had it had ever
gone a hundred days in her entire life
since she was diagnosed what's their
cannabinoid profile ratio that strain
let me look it up real quick for you
it's been amazing I only ask because it
is I used to hesitate saying things like
this but you know like everybody else
the more families you work with the more
confident you get seeing patterns and
it's amazing to me how many more kids
respond to a two to one between one to
two and two to one in that range ratio
medicine more so than the twenty to one
I see V D this is raised one to one yeah
yeah
so especially the LGS and what I talk to
parents because a lot of people come or
people were treating we just CNN really
helped to boost this and a lot of that
was not that they did anything they
brought a lot of good attention to the
subject but some of the negatives that
came along with that was the the CBD
felt good and safe to talk about for
ideological reasons so not necessarily
because that was what would they had
discovered was the best medicine for
these conditions you know it just felt
safe to say well this one doesn't get
you high so we're gonna max out this and
give it an CBD has some benefits in that
way but the benefits are really when you
start adding THC to it the benefits are
more than doubled them then when there
are isolated THC or CBD and we've seen
that with a lot of kids they'll have
some reduction with Charlotte's Web or
you know some of those high cv ac/dc or
high CBD strains but when you start to
get closer to a more balanced profile
you start to see some of those dramatic
results and that's what I experienced
that with my own son you know with
having he never had a single day without
a seizure on high CBD meds but that's
what we started with is that's what we
had heard you know six years ago as
parents and almost gave up because we
thought well I guess the CBD you know
it's what's what they say it's good for
kids and but it's not working for us so
we're not lucky and you know through
doing research and what's more words
right are you using your alcohol extract
to make distillate or using the alcohol
extract in the in the capsule or in the
in the formulation itself try and see if
I have any here I can run again no it's
it's like full extract eco what we call
it will extract cannabis oil it is okay
so not you're not when your eyes and
distilling or anything like that's just
thick you know so we measure let me test
that we measure it out and then yeah
there's some way to us and that's made
by our group right there okay turn it
sit still terpene rich oh yeah you open
that the lid on that thing and it smells
like a fruit basket it's got this
beautiful
terpenes besides the THC
might also be contributing to the debt
law for the CBD yeah and I'm a big I am
sold you know I know there's still some
debate in the scientific community about
the entourage effect but there's no
debate and our my experience because
we've just seen it too many times where
we've recreated the exact same base
cannabinoid profile right your CBD your
THC or CBD as much as you can and how
that translates or you know you guys
understand et cetera we've we've had
strange shift to say been forced because
we've run out but we've with lab testing
been able to recreate those profiles and
seemed absolutely night and day into the
spectrum as far as efficacy with kids
where at times you could actually even
see adverse effects where when we went
back to the strain that was originally
there same cannabinoid profile you then
see the same positive benefits come back
and the reason I was mentioning this was
because a lot of these 22 one CBD to THC
ratios varieties have quite consistently
different terpene flavors and aromas
than varieties that are higher in THC
and have been selected for terpenes yeah
yeah if I've noticed that as well I mean
you see you know I know that a lot of
the our force and Charlotte's Web
lineage have a lot underlining pining
sort of smells to them when they're
growing then you don't see with some
other strains not as much as those the
carry awfully black pepper sort of funk
that you get with with other balanced
ratios but like I said it's it's I think
the answer is in a combination of both
and the answer also is whatever helps
the patient yeah and that's it you know
that's exactly it you know so saying
that saying okay we've seen better
results with the more balanced
cannabinoid ratio but
I can give you an example ten kids where
that's not the case you know some kids
they're people you know I work with kids
and adults but some mostly kids respond
poorly to THC and you know you get the
same diagnosis and they need exact
opposite medicines and the way I try to
help people visualize this is just
understanding the concept that when you
see a you know so we'll just stick on
this thing because that's that's forest
theme but it's a good one to visualize
if you just stick with a seizure when
you see a seizure happening you're
seeing the consequence of something
broken in the system right so you might
have two people with seizures and the
doctor observes those symptoms and
you're gonna get a similar diagnosis
let's say Linux gets toe syndrome ma'am
you get that diagnosis that diagnosis
doesn't correlate with what might have
broken down in the system to manifest
those consequences those seizures in
different parts of just to oversimplify
it a bit let's just stick with the
endocannabinoid system different parts
of that system can go wrong and manifest
the same problem we could not be
producing as you guys know an animai and
two AG you could have a down regulation
issue with the cb1 receptor you could
not have the enzyme that is necessary to
break down and cause the reaction when a
nano minor THC bond to the cb1 receptor
so there's just three different real
quick examples of things three different
things that could be going wrong in the
system that are going to manifest the
same seizure when the end of cannabinoid
system is not able to regulate
neurotransmitter function so we know
these different cannabinoids profiles
and terpene profiles interact with these
receptors differently in cost different
reactions some cause and and amide to
build up in the system some interact
with the receptors in different ways and
I think this is really the key logic
would tell me that this is really why we
see some people with the same symptoms
but need different approaches because
although we can see the symptom we can't
see what's going wrong in the body so
teaching people how to take you know
efficient
approach to aim what works for them is
is really the trick you know and that
goes back to you know dispensaries and
what do they tell patients when they
come in looking for things you know some
of it is feeling comfortable telling
patients well it could be a lot of
different things that you need how can
we teach you how to most efficiently
find what your body needs as opposed to
tell them no you need this and if this
doesn't work then you're s out of luck
right and it gives them the wrong
impression of what might help them and
they could walk away prematurely when
there's still an answer there for them
somewhere what fish song comes to mind I
was at a big fish free at last night
don't get me started
yeah just one more thing about
concentrations and you talked about that
oh extract being somewhere between 65 to
70% cannabinoids so then you take that
and you cut that with like another oil
vehicle like coconut oil or something
like that what's your ratio when you
when you make the oil that actually is
going in so that helps us understand
again the level of cannabinoids that
you're getting in these doses and
whether or not the effort efficacy is
always going to be a function of how
much they're getting so how is it like a
ten to one delusion that that's
oh he got muted sorry for isn't you did
you I thought you were talking to
someone else you got to unmute yourself
no I got just reaching behind me in my
bag of tricks here so much that's the
benefit of having dinner I look at it
the more I've worked with this the less
I look at strain names and I look at the
test results and say okay we have a
pallet of cannabinoids terpenoids
flavonoids that we can work with and
from there you know mark we're able to
really dial in what that individual
person needs so when you have your your
extract right so this is some nice
pineapple jack
THC extract labeled and tested ready to
go measured out we know exactly well
exactly within testing range we all know
that analytical testing various a little
bit so we're able to take that and I can
say okay well I have the amount of THC
and a particular terpene profile with
that but maybe this person is showing
that they are also responding to acidic
compounds so I can take some rosin that
we've had pressed here it is also acidic
triangle if you can see that oh it's
bubbly goodness there we can work with
then adding in specific THC and CBD a
and THC VA and some of these other
compounds it basically then build a
customized medicine for that person and
when we get into you know I work really
with rare
you know neurological conditions a lot
so it isn't sup being very
individualized so you're able to take
that medicine yeah I use typically MCT
oil unless they have a sensitivity to it
not uncommon most people are doing that
these days - good good choice and and
there's actually studies that show it's
a preferred vehicle for getting quick
onset of activity in the oral mucosa so
yeah that's a real good choice right so
yeah what's your that you use how what
would and we're like if people are
listening and they want to again create
their own products or how would you I
always thought that the best way to do
is to like dose until you actually feel
nabbed or
the patient's so when you know that you
can titrate them up to the level where
you're agonizing cb1 maybe you want to
dial back from that so would you start a
patient especially a child patient and
say like a 20 milligram per day dose or
is 10 milligrams or 5 milligram what's
the right place to start to sort of look
to titrate up to that level of where you
know you're getting cannabinoids in
there but you're not doing it in a way
that completely incapacitates the child
or the patient to where they have to you
know get dizzy or just their patients
what I find is that they don't want to
take the medicine anymore because they
don't like the way it feels and so I
think it's really important to titrate
their body up to that level because that
tells you that you're getting
cannabinoids into their system but maybe
dial back the daily dose so they can
still be functional and not be dizzy and
not feel disoriented so what advice
would you give them especially parents
dr. michele m and israel find that
really young children like you know 2 3
4 or 5
don't get high when they're given Katie
yeah I've seen I've seen children take
doses that have blown my mind I'm gonna
meet with this parent because I want to
really double-check and make sure
they're looking at the tests accurately
who is 70 maybe no she's like 45 pounds
she's 8 years old and is somewhere
around 1,800 milligrams a day dosing so
that would be an extreme nobody starts
at that level baseless so when we're
talking about starting I started one you
know I started we started you know it
would be one of those slow we check for
we check for all sorts of things no I
think that's the only way you can use
the physiological response as any
indicator to whether or not they're
feeling again I I guess again my feeling
is I was trying to work with an older
patient who feels very distal
and when she takes like a a hundred
milligram candy so what we're trying to
do is start with her low and slow
I think is the way to go and I think
especially for children patients
wouldn't you recommend the same well
this is why we use drops you know it's
not it's not just for you know looks or
because people are used to getting it in
droppers one of the main advantages is
that you can control the dose relatively
you know approximately down to the
milligram so we start with like a
milligram or a drop depending on how
concentrated the droppers are and that's
another great reason when you're going
from concentrate you can make that
teacher is concentrated or is diluted as
you think is appropriate but yeah I
leaned on the side of you start down at
minimum but you don't also need to dilly
dally with titration for months on it
right so we start with a dose we make
sure there's no adverse reactions no
rare allergies nothing that could be
throw us a curveball and then we just
start to titrate up with times of day so
we keep the dose so very small might be
a milligram and then we start we add in
the bedtime dose and in the noon dose
because we want to see every four to six
hours because our goal is to keep a
sustained level in the system not spikes
and waves right so we have you know
neurological type conditions so that's
that's sort of our approach and then
when we get the four or three doses
whatever they feel is appropriate a day
then we start titrating up those doses
like a milligram or two at a time and
doing it that way we've I I can't
actually remember the last time I had
someone even complained about being high
because you will see efficacy usually
before that happens for most
endocannabinoids regulatory issues which
a lot of these conditions fall under and
once you do start to feel something
because you're taking such a methodical
slow approach it
then it's not big jumps in your dose
it's never at the point where this is
uncomfortable like yeah okay I made me
feel a little relaxed here on the sets
the low threshold of intoxication or
psycho activity that it's never a
negative it's never been a negative
experience and you're a hundred percent
right about children and how they
process it because I like I said and
then I've heard dr. Russo and other
doctors say this as well
I've noticed that kids just process it
differently so if we take that low and
slow approach like you said or low and
not too slow but a methodical approach
you know we don't I don't see a real
problem with intoxication ever and the
kids who do end up getting they titrate
up the doses that I know would knock me
on my butt and they've never seen even
you know a blurred eye or giggly
attitude out of them there's no sign of
any sort of intoxication whatsoever and
I think you know each individual
endocannabinoids system has something to
do with that if they're already
deficient and the receptors aren't being
saturated or by an and oh my into AG I
think you're going to be able to
tolerate more stimulation through THC so
all those things have something to do
with it but I don't think the other
thing that does heroic doses do is you
got to remember that the metabolites are
stored in in fatty tissues in fatty
organs and stuff it's protecting those
organs from free radical damage and
oxidative damage but it also on the
burning of adipose tissue basically
releases all that you know systemically
so I mean humans were evolved to hold on
to these cannabinoids for as long as we
possibly can and they're fat soluble so
like most antioxidants like vitamin C
are water-soluble the cannabinoids are
our fat soluble which protects fatty
tissues from oxidative damage oh my god
that I say I already said that I feel
like a mana no I myself as they go off
of certain medications there's
medications that cause you to gain
weight right we've all seen that or
experience
and I've seen big-time not just the
removal of the medication influence
significantly the cannabinoid supplement
dose but as they lose that fat you know
right so the Oedipus tissue is no longer
making those stores I've seen the
interactions with the cannabinoid
medicines change and have to really make
some adjustments because of that as well
so that is a really good point well and
the other thing that's different about
about your product which I'm very
intrigued is is that in this full plant
extract you're not winterizing so you're
not removing any of the other components
such that so if your stuff is analyzing
for let's say a neighborhood you know
seventy percent there's thirty percent
other components in there of terpenes
are a sizable fraction well there's
still a pretty sizable fraction of other
extractables that are coming along with
the plant that certainly you may not
want in stay like add a beable
concentrated Abbeville product because
those things are gonna close in and and
degrade but certainly in this product
format where you're looking to you know
try to deliver the whole plant goodness
by extracting everything that the plant
has to extract again there's fatty acids
in there there's lipids in there like
you point out there's flavonoids in
there all the other minor components
that are non cannabinoids might be
helping the overall entourage effect of
everything and that's good for people to
hear that again you don't necessarily
have to go through making distillate now
making distillate I think is a
completely valid opportunity again to
make medicine from the plant but I think
in this particular case what you're
looking for is again it could possibly
provide so you know for those including
the groups including the roots for those
who used to watch Star Trek this is like
fire all weapons you know phasers you
know photon torpedoes you hit them with
everything because if the plant offers
this and again the plant is a source of
vital nutrition for humans why not take
it in the extract
why would you want it separated out from
something that again can provide medical
efficacy and I think that's part of what
you're seeing in the boost of efficacy
yeah you know we go back and forth on
certain parts of the plant and how to
best use it you know how what
chlorophylls impact is in those sort of
things but you know I agree there's a
lot to the plant you know when I I don't
have data to back it up that is an
anecdotal this is where we get into
anecdotal data but you know when I have
a tincture and I'd be happy to send you
guys something to check out that you
open the lid and it just bursts in the
room with with all the things that the
plant wants to communicate and that's
what those turns are is its way of
communicating with the world around it I
just like with the evidence that's come
out with some of the entourage studies
that are being done and across the board
the studies have shown that single
isolate cannabinoid therapies are not as
effective as therapies that are when you
include and reintroduce you know THC to
a CBD therapy or vice versa and then you
start to talk about the terpenes that
research is being done it's pretty
conclusive that's each study has shown
the efficacy is increased with the
addition of the whole plant cannabinoids
and enterpreneurs as opposed to
isolating you know to me it's just
that's the direction we're going to go
until we have something that points us
otherwise and yeah there's some there
are some turbulent terpenoids
that are only in the roots you know dr.
Russo's work right now is just
mind-blowing but I take it with a little
bit of caution and this is where we get
back to where we started where it's just
I don't want to say what's right and
wrong because Who am I we're all on this
journey of researching and doing what we
think is best so I think that there's
some caution personally with the kids we
were working with if we were starting to
integrate and distill and concentrate
medicines that were made from roots and
stems and things like that just strictly
because of cannabis his ability to suck
things out of the soil and store it in
its roots and stems but that doesn't
mean there's not medically beneficial
things in there that does
mean that if your soil is good and your
soils clean and your environments clean
that that can't be done safely so this
gets back to just making sure that the
customer knows what they're by you know
so that they can say yeah this could be
great for me as a full-grown adult if
I'm trying to work with my you know six
month old with neuroblastoma I might
avoid some of these just because there
might be something I feel it's something
that be cautious about no stems no seeds
that you don't need Acapulco gold is far
out weed nervous about this bulk CBD
coming in you know there's people now
that you can get Gowan CBD oils and it's
all just it's essentially medical or
non-medical it's industrial waste you
know it's from Asia and Eastern Europe
where they're doing big hemp you know
for manufacturing reasons they're making
him products ropes and clothes or
whatever wallets cedra but they just
bundle all this stuff into a big hopper
at the end of it and just dose it with
things and you get CBD at the end and
they're able to distill that down and
run it through a purifier and the heimo
sell you these gallons of purified CBD
oil and that that to me without having
that information of you know where it
comes from how it's made what's in it is
it organic that stuff just makes me
nervous
nekkid just butyl being overcautious but
it's not not for me it should make you
nervous yeah man I think people realize
that's what that is that it's a waste
product of the hemp industry in Asia
grown for that purpose China fell grown
biodynamically for sure human poop well
there's definite so there's definitely a
need for monomolecular for the isolation
of the molecules because then people
like forests can come along and find the
recipes and add the terpenes and produce
those very specifically accurate
cannabinoid and terpene profiles that
stay accurate every single time all the
way down the line whereas plants with
variables they can have these
bits of changes and whatnot so I see the
value I also see the snake oil salesman
aspect for a long time I couldn't figure
out how is everyone shipping this stuff
when it's not legal to ship and then I
realized oh okay they're shipping hemp
oil that's been cold-pressed and because
it's a low THC you know there couldn't
be CBD cultivar in the cultivar that it
it basically small amounts of it press
into the oil and they're calling that
CBD oil when really it's hemp oil with
CBD contaminant in like super super
small amounts
I ran the bottle it's a hundred and
eighty nine dollars for a bottle of
marketed their kids and families every
day
Plus hemp oil and we took it to the labs
and tested it and there was nothing in
it not a terpene not a fraction that the
machines couldn't even pick up CBD you
know and so it's essentially you know
it's $189 if you know I'm assuming him
seed oil could be olive oil for all I
know you know just the way we know
nothing in it beneficial well I didn't
hear that mark said I surprised so bean
oil just because it's the cheapest yeah
so that is absolutely happening though
are you decarboxylated this ethanol
extract or you're putting it in there
not decarboxylated aur be carboxylates
but because of the the distiller it's
really good at temperature control but
it mostly D carbs as well it's not
really good with making acidic compounds
which is where we've started renting out
rosin you know price it starting to do
it that way but yeah we're D carbon we
do classes for families up here really
try to we're doing another one here
pretty soon if you're in the Northern
California area where we actually teach
families how to how to do this so just
try to give them some independence you
know but yeah it's it's D carved it can
all be done at home I'm a big advocate
of not letting people convince people
that they can't take control of their
medicine and do it safely uh it's not
easy and it's not right for
everybody especially if they're
full-time caregivers to be able to do
that but that's different from it being
impossible to do so we do a lot of
classes teaching families you know how
to do it if they wanted to or at least
watching them be able to know exactly
how the things that we're providing are
made and how it's done safely how to
read test results how to then use that
to make them accurately dose medicines
etc yeah that's really important to
empower families how to do it themselves
sorry for interrupting you there but I
have a question for you guys and I'm
wondering about are you working or doing
any test studies in utero with pregnant
women that because we're learning about
this as a basic a nutrient and I've also
noticed that in children that are that
we're also treating with the oils that
we're making which is a whole plant
extract as well we're noticing that the
children who have had THC or CBD from
the beginning you know mothers that have
ingested cannabis from the beginning
have different kind of tolerances then
children who you know have never had it
before it's actually quite significant
so talking about like a basic nutrient
from the beginning you know in a zygote
form I think that's just a really
interesting conversation and I'm
wondering do you work with women in
pregnancy you know it's funny that you
bring that up
I mean it's known that endocannabinoids
signaling is a huge part of neurological
development pre and postnatal I mean but
it's funny I'm going to jump to another
story real quick because I do a lot of
consultations with families from all
over the world Indonesia the UK India
you know the United States of course
Canada and I had the mom who I was
speaking with this week who has a very
young child I think seven months old
and infantile spasms right so this is
not a good sign when your child starts
having infantile spasms of that age it
can quickly be diagnosed as wess
syndrome which then leads into these
more unfortunate epilepsies but
she was in Texas and the access in Texas
is horrific inhumane would be the word I
would use and but if you have access to
what they can order online which is
although not necessarily legal but the
lack of enforcement allows us to get
some CBD real CBD products at times and
she was using those CBD products and not
having any luck with her daughter's
seizures she was still having these
spasms every single day and a friend of
hers gave her THC and like a lot of
parents like I don't know I don't know
if THC is safe you know I'm not sure I
should use it and she read the and she
was gonna see if it was safe and her I
don't know what she was thinking as far
as seeing if it was safe but she's gonna
try it herself and see if it was you
know poison or not okay she read the
label wrong and just totally Doster
stealth-like with a 40 or 50 milligram
dose which is not something she does
because she's not a cannabis user was
knocked out on the couch for the day and
she's like man was experience and kind
of everything go now I'm nervous to give
this to my baby it was such a intense
experience
but then she called and said that she's
breastfeeding her child and after she
dosed herself with that THC her daughter
with four days without a seizure and she
hadn't gone four days without a seizure
in months and months and months
something that really excites me I think
that it's incredibly important we
definitely work with small children and
especially work with small children and
women and children with all different
types of autoimmune disorders whether
it's seizures whether it's some
emotional disorders and we're noticing
that you know really dosing the mothers
with large doses of THC along with the
CBD is immediate response you know with
with the baby and breastfeeding and I
think that you know it's an important
conversation to have even you know with
our alternative culture because they're
going to be more receptive to it but I
do think that it's important to be
introducing to mothers you know from the
beginning of pregnancy or even before
they want to get pregnant to start and
Jess
in cannabis in doses you know that make
them feel good which in turn is going to
help their baby in the long run and then
I think when we see these children who
have had cannabinoids since the
beginning you know they are able to
receive the cannabinoids much easier
something that's very familiar to their
system allows their immune system to you
know avoid autoimmune disorders yeah and
just an important key that you know we
haven't had enough research out there
but we are doing it like you said you
know working with a lot of children and
I definitely am noticing that those
children that have had the seeit TB C
THC and the CBD from the very beginning
are just doing so much better with the
medicine right off the get-go it's not a
week it's the first dosage that they get
it because their body is reminded of it
and they know it well that was kind of
where that story was leading to because
of that experience she was like well
maybe it is THC that is benefiting she
was not a little bit more comfortable
within slowly adding some milligrams of
THC into the trounce dose and we saw the
seizures dramatically decrease you know
so there's a lot you know it's a lot we
don't know about neonatal impacts and in
utero impact of high-level cannabis use
so that I think these people who might
be watching this get nervous and go oh
my gosh are they advocating for that I
mean there's a big difference between
sitting around and taking dabs all day
right and using certain cannabinoids as
a supplement in the body and when you
look at the research have been you
turrible use with children writer or
parents who are using cannabis at the
children who then came through the
pregnancy when they remove comorbidity
right things like alcohol use and
smoking and in other factors there's
really nothing that shows any harm and
that's still even with that that's not
saying we're advocating or recommending
parents abused cannabis and high levels
there's it's just we learn to
differentiate there's more than one way
we can use cannabis now and it's a night
and day difference in some of these
supplements if the parents are having
issues that are
possibly more beneficial and less
harmful then say you know a SSRI
inhibitor right some of those things
that we know can cause problems in in
utero but if the mom say is dealing with
depression
I wouldn't say jump and just start you
using cannabis but if you have the
choices between some of these drugs that
we know can cause in utero problems and
a low-dose cannabinoid supplement that
can deal with what might be causing a
regulatory issue that can cause some
depression or some of those things that
can happen in pregnancy it's just about
looking at what is safe and best for the
mother and child and we're at the point
now where if you get over that fear that
cannabis is not this evil dangerous drug
and there's really no science to back it
up and you compare it to what would be
offered at the pharmacy it's just about
you know what is the least impactful
with the most chance of a positive
benefit and I think cannabis posing way
before a lot of these other drugs that
are given to women in pregnancy and I
think that it's important note um that
you know women are also utilizing
cannabis in their pregnancy for you know
things that they have that's an ailment
that's going on with them you know
they're utilizing it as their medicine
as well um one thing I'd like to note
you know saying that I don't advocate in
the same way that you do in large doses
and I certainly don't advocate for women
to be smoking during their pregnancy you
know hot smoke cuts off the vaso
movement in the placental from the
mother to the baby so it's very
important that if they are utilizing
cannabis you know smoking it in large
doses I don't recommend at all yeah I
think it's unfortunately you have to
just mention that because that's what a
lot of people visualize right away you
know so they had to keep putting that
qualifier on there to realize that
there's different types of relationships
that you can have and some can be very
beneficial and safe you know I wanted to
throw something out here I think it was
Russo who presented the idea of what
he's calling cannabinoid deficiency
syndromes and it's a plural and the idea
is that
there's all these conditions that we've
found that humans are subject to that
seem to respond to cannabis therapies
and most of them are ingested cannabis
again where we see the really dramatic
results and it's reus I believe it was
Rousseau do you remember forest was it
Rousseau
yeah and economic efficiency syndrome is
yeah baby could never know a deficiency
syndrome and and yeah what blew my mind
about this was the idea that all these
conditions from epilepsy to autism to
certain cancers etc etc all these things
that respond to cannabinoids are
happening in the human population
because the human population due to
prohibition is suffering from a
collective cannabinoid deficiency and as
we start adding the cannabinoids to our
bodies
I think of CBD as the molecule that
helps your body find the state that we
call health
it's a homeostatic regulator it helps
the body find the condition we call
health and it's adapted genic among
other things yes exactly it helps the
body find health yeah I just had a and I
I did an episode with of my podcast with
dr. Jeffery hergenrother and he went
into cannabis as an adaptogen in that
conversation that we could do a whole
show on that I'm really interested and
talking more about that but I want to do
the show so I can learn more about it
I'm not ready to speak a bunch about it
but yeah really really interesting
conversation is and how it pertained to
some of maybe the misunderstandings
about cannabis about what cannabis does
what but without taking into account
that cannabis can do different things
that during different times because of
the body's ability to use it in
different ways was really fascinating we
really resonate with using poly pores
and medicinal mushrooms in this equation
too and I would love to see our
community get more involved in that and
being able to take different compounds
for medicinal mushrooms and put it it's
magic which you know
a perfect fusion to the human body as
well and other adaptogenic Chinese herbs
you know that really share different
terpenes that cannabis has as well as
cannabinoids that cannabis has as well
it's just really interesting to look at
what other sources that we can get it
from so that we can get a more holistic
more rounded you know view of it as well
as a medicine it's an opportunity to
bring all you know modalities together
and bring the cannabis and with Chinese
herbs and in with poly poisons that we
get from our florist and you know we
have amazing quality pours in our
forests and we're finding incredible
results by bringing it together with
cannabinoid Paul statements work of
course doing tremendous amounts of work
with poly pores and mixing to Nabin a
cannabis methodical and we read as much
Japanese and Russian stuff as possible
but you know it's PDF files are there
it's pretty mundane and they'd work
together with medical industry as well
oh yeah I see my psyllium running can I
say cannot wait to just put you on your
shirt there I'm quite a fan of it so far
this morning yes we're missing the
mushrooms right now drinking mushrooms
yes now I think that part of what we're
speaking to is that my experience of
cannabis it is a one of the healing
plants and there's I think there's
reasons that humans have been interested
in all these different herbs mushrooms
and I'm pretty convinced that science
can do a lot for us about helping to
understand some of the modalities some
of the things that happen to make nature
what it is but I'm also pretty confident
that science has a very limited view of
the totality of things that are going on
and there's a wisdom in
[Music]
herbal ism there's something going on
with those plants and how our bodies
relate to them and I think what we're
doing here today in the church is
exploring how cannabis is one of those
healing plants that we are all drawn to
very strongly but I think there's other
things going on and really part of what
I'm here for it's a sense of well-being
and happiness and health that cannabis
helps me experience but I use other
herbs as well as well as mushrooms I
really view mushrooms as a really great
sign in the garden when mushrooms are
happening in the garden everybody's
happy in the garden Stamets is research
on bees and the benefits that they're
finding from honeybees who are an
essential friend in all of our lives
yeah yeah and I know I think that it's
really important to when we start
talking about blending different plants
you know and looking for different
compounds and medicinal compounds and
these ancient Chinese herbs that have
been studied you know forever that you
know talk about evidence and yeah Aria
thetic Chinese herbs you know we do know
so much about it but maybe modern
science hasn't stepped into the picture
so all of a sudden oh we don't know
anything about it but there is a
tremendous amount of research and I'm
really interested in taking all of that
research of herbs and then feeding it to
those master plants so trying to create
more terpenes with terpenes you know
going to those master plants that have
been looked at for ever and ever and
ever collecting them from the woods in
the forest and then feeding them to
themselves or creating different
compounds making teas out of those and
building the soil microbes because the
soil microbes are the actual true key to
the medicine we can talk all day about
what we're gonna do with all of our
secondary metabolites when we get them
but you know to be able to get the most
complex intricate cannabinoid systems or
terpene profiles starts with soil and a
diverse soil and if we can get into
herbalism forties and herbalism for
soils and herbalism for soy
all rise us here you really raised our
tree all the sudden everything's
vibrating you know the the soil is
vibrating the medicines vibrating we're
vibrating and it's it's it's beautiful
and there is a difference it's not just
like folklore it's it really comes out
in the labs it comes out in people's
reaction to wanting to buy the medicine
and and everything it's a really natural
feel so you know medicine is something
that we can test in science but medicine
is also something that we can test when
we ingest it and if we're giving the
medicine everything that we can a full
spectrum from other plants and other
medicinal plants then we're also
familiarizing our own immune system our
own DNA with those medicinal plants that
you know as far as our DNA goes and our
structure from the very beginning we've
been utilizing these plants you know
from the beginning respectful evolution
kind of a step back for a second
in one of the things that I understand
about traditional Chinese medicine was
the original agreement in a village
between the healer and the folk who
lived in the village was that the people
who wanted this healers help would offer
whatever they had some portion of it to
them to help them maintain a sense of
health well-being and as long as you
were healthy you kept paying the healer
but if you got sick they treated you at
no cost our Western medicine our medical
system today is set up that no one gets
paid until somebody's sick and there's a
problem there there's it's not in the
interests of our medical system if you
will to show us and teach us how to
maintain health and then in the
traditional Chinese culture it was about
maintaining health so these herbs that
they I've had good experience with
acupuncture getting way off subject
but I'm really talking about health at
the moment and the sense of well-being
and I really think that science is
helping us to understand why we don't
feel healthy but I don't think science
has the full answer on how to get
healthy I think nature we evolved with
nature and all these plants and I think
that is where we can find wellbeing this
in nature and how nature can work
together with us and it involves finding
all of these things that you we're
speaking of but yeah the sense of health
the sense of well-being of being in your
body and feeling good in it I call it I
think everyone wants what's that I call
it happy huh so unless people go looking
for it they'll look for it everywhere
they just can't find it they're like
where the hell is it we catch little
glimpses of it they're like I was
feeling it for a few seconds there did
you notice I was happy happiness is
health it's balanced it's well-rounded
missus it's definitely a lot more than
using cannabis as a medicine I'll tell
you about much I see a lot of people in
the industry who just need to get a
healthier diet be a little more active
exercise you know because cannabis is
one part of the puzzle for sure but I
think it will bring happiness alone well
happiness is the proper balance of those
chemical soup that your body is it's
just you know depression versus you know
manic joy is all which neurotransmitters
flowing on what level and it's funny
that when we look at tying in cannabis
to this when we look at ways to
influence your endocannabinoids system
whose sole job is to keep the body in
balance in homeostasis to provide that
optimal setup for your body the way the
best ways to influence that system that
have nothing to do with cannabis are
diet and exercise when you're exercising
when your diet is good you influence the
way your endocannabinoids system
functions so yeah when you when you are
doing those things and we've been note
we've known that for years and years and
years what we didn't know is
how much that effort was really
benefiting the endocannabinoid system
and supporting its ability to keep the
body healthy and imbalance so you know
yeah exercise sorry I didn't mean to
it's hard coming in on the mute thing I
think that exercise is really important
and it's you know also healthy microbes
happy microbes happy beneficial bacteria
and ice inside of our body makes us
happy and I think that you know when we
are doing healthy things for ourselves
and we're treating our soils with good
things then we're getting healthy
microbiology and I think that you know
they have the higher intelligence
there's way more of them than there is
us and I think that if we are able to
you know ally with them in a way that
you know is more open to our culture you
know we're just starting to get into
bifidus and lactobacillus and all the
prebiotics and the probiotics and now
it's starting to become sort of a
regular term you know I see it on TV you
know in just regular commercials so
hopefully we can you know start gaining
more and more intelligence from those
microbes as as a culture to help us out
and along the way to create a higher
intelligence just like you have to
oxygenate your teas you have to
oxygenate your blood and oxygenate you
know through cardiovascular movement
that's part of why gardening is health
is because you're ingesting soil
microbes and your fingers and you're
utilizing your body you're stretching
your doing like garden yoga and you're
getting weeds and and you're and you
have to oxygenate your soils too you
have to have like aeration in your soil
so more and more research is being done
you know on a medical scientific study
that people who are having a lot of
ailments you know autoimmune disorders
seizures people that are having IBS
people that are even having cancer all
we're doing you know they're doing is
looking into the microbiome inside of
the intestine and realizing that you
know they're totally devoid of a lot of
different microbiology that they should
have in order to be healthy so I think
that this is sort of all wrapped up into
into one thing and
cannabinoid system microbiome it's
interesting you said there's more of
them than us but I guess when it comes
to bacteria they are us yeah just what I
was thinking me conversations today
we've busted out some pretty deep so far
I like it and the mitochondria is a
whole other aspect that's really
fascinating in the whole mitochondrial
DNA has its own DNA that surrounds all
of our cells is a whole other entity
with inside of our body that's just so
unbelievable yeah that's totally a
living being as well so that's digesting
and thinking and breathing for us as
well it's really really interesting
wormhole that we can go down for sure
but having a healthy immune system
creates a healthy immune response and
this is where cannabis is a great
catalyst in our thinking towards that
which is awesome a lot of us are
thinking about it when we're utilizing
cannabis you know but you do have to go
further but like you said Marcus you
know it's not just about just utilizing
cannabis by cannabis like gives us the
mindset to sit back and connect and
think about all these amazing things and
then go out and put it to use in
practice and then having this community
to share it with and because we can't
all do everything and once we have it
all to share with and I think that we
have the most amazing benefits and
recently in the last few years they've
been some pretty and things that have
happened within growing and cultivating
and also within medicine and all the
extracts I mean it's like never ending
really fun things it's almost like
exciting to wake up every day to find
out like what new thing we get to learn
about and so thank you everybody yeah
yeah I'm in the same boat I feel like I
just I can only imagine 20 years from
now what we'll know about these
relationships these compounds and how
they interact with not just sick people
but healthy people people you know as
preventive the whole it's really gonna
there's gonna be this eventual we're
such humans we always we just divide
divide divide you divide everything we
cut it all up we categorize it and then
eventually we come around and it seems
though for me what I'm
around 2:00 is the quiver you know for
earlier having the conversation about
the difference between oil and hash I
was by no means saying that one is
better than the other for me I have a
preference but other there's always
going to be different preferences for
different reasons and that's why
monomolecular Madison will have its
place and that's why you know fee Co
will have its place and that's why all
the different types of extracts ones
that we don't even know about right now
will have their place because it's
unique it's different and it changes
small things when we leave that
footprint behind when we change those
volatile terpenes that we know modulate
the effects of the cannabinoids then we
know that by changing the way we make
the medicine we're changing the medicine
yeah so speaking of volatile terpenes of
forest how do you decarboxylate but
still maintain your terpene profile I
mean that seems to be a trick in the
industry a lot of people are removing
terpenes and reincorporating after any
kind of thermal treatment whatsoever
because the most delicate of terpenes
which is the most delicate part of the
fragrance will thermally rearrange or
decompose and give you off flavors from
what you've extracted so are there any
secrets on that yes well yeah I've got
nothing really fancy to offer me we are
we're at home town sort of folks but we
definitely don't just decarboxylate in
and of and and let everything get lost
out of the wall so your oven so we keep
everything contains when we're
decarboxylated and when we're doing our
ethanol rinses we rinse the containers
that we decarboxylated and you can
actually see them build up on the
surface of those things to integrate
them back into the medicine that sounds
kind of country doing it but we through
test results and through experience
we've seen it makes a real difference
that you can actually capture those
terpenes in the decarboxylation process
and then we rinsed the the containers
and bags with the
alcohol to strip any terpenes that have
collected during that process otherwise
they just sort of all on the outside of
your your oven wall or something like
that whatever your d curving it so do
you recover your ethanol and then how
many times do you use it before you you
know don't use it anymore you keep on
using it no no it definitely loses
something as you know I'm sure but what
we do is we kind of reconstitute it by
adding in fresh as you go right and
keeping it's like a cycle that goes
through it it allows it to stay pretty
fresh and then you're losing enough in
the soap and the rinse where you're not
getting all of your alcohol back so
you're constantly having to add fresh
into it so we're constantly adding fresh
alcohol into it so say we reclaim eighty
percent then the next batch has twenty
percent that is fresh and so on and we
haven't seen it once what is it that's
extracted that fouls the ethanol right I
mean it's not a turkey that's a sugar or
something like that or what makes the
ethanol no good anymore and at that
point is it actually worth it to
actually just buy a still and distill
that ethanol recovered because that's
not you know could be damn expensive
because it's controlled dangerous
substance and you have to have a license
for it and a lot of people have to get
paid to even this bio ethanol is a pain
in the ass their supply chain you know
people that have their pockets open that
want to make a lot of money here but the
question I'm asking you is that so when
you recover your ethanol you'll use it
like maybe once twice or how many times
can you use it to where no longer has
good extraction rates organic you know
we gave it two hundred proof you have to
drive a long way to get it but I guess
we don't we're not throwing it out
because we're constantly making batches
that it's just recycled through it so
you know it's we're not seeing that lot
so it's when we don't constantly add
fresh in every single time that it goes
bad and I would you know that's a I wish
I had the answer I gotta plead ignorance
there as to why
brain around it I was hoping maybe you
guys could let me know as to what
changes because it's still high-octane
alcohol and ethanol when it comes out
but it it's just we've all experienced
it it's just it doesn't work and pull
the same after a while
so yeah we don't have that problem much
because we constantly add fresh hints
we're not necessarily dumping any out
what we lose in the wash and in the soap
it's enough volume is when we replace it
with a clean fresh alcohol every time
that we don't have the same problem you
said you'd lost about 20 percent each
run well I mean I'm generalizing but you
know my medicine makers might be
watching this to enforce you got your
numbers all wrong and shaking their
heads with me you know simplifying we
lose you note in the made say 10% 20%
each time and then we reconstitute
very material dependent in general right
I mean yeah it's how many how dry was it
which that's a huge step as well then we
could do a whole apps on our med making
process which I'd be happy to do but you
know a lot of times when people are
distilling or making doing ethanol
washes they don't dry out the material
enough I mean it's got to be well to the
point where you think it's ruined right
you would never do it for cannabis that
you were smoking like crumbling in your
hands dry because it's the water that is
gonna cause problems in there so you
know when you do that it's also doing
then absorb a lot of alcohol so you
definitely lose that's where you lose
the majority of her alcoholism that step
where did we always we always used to
cater beep with Animus before we put it
in with the alcohol I was gonna say you
could you can freeze dry that some
product and you'd be surprised how it
turned out indeed well it's all quite
interesting isn't it ways to make
medicine or to acquire medicine that's
already there let's be honest we're not
making anything we're just sort of well
I look at it it's the same as you know
we can grow
cannabis and we can all grow the same
cannabis and there's a certain petition
certain amount of people who ruin it
during that period and dry in process
right so it's like how do we you know
how do we just get the best the best
process we can we can't all gonna end up
with something at the end of it but just
like everything how can we help the
plant maintain its full potential you
know you don't see it very often at
least I don't and I do see a lot of
cannabis I saw some yesterday that I
felt like wow this is some of the first
cannabis in awhile that has expressed
itself to its maximum potential it was
just really covered in this beautiful
beautiful coating of trichomes it smelt
impeccable it felt like velour and it
was just nice to see someone grow bud
that is actually attuned to the infamous
local BC brokerage term quads oh geez
everyone's selling mid-grade schwag as
quads this is the problem people are
using and throwing around words that
aren't accurate and I like to be a bit
of a stickler and I'm I apologize for
come across as a dick because I do that
that's all I was doing with saying that
hash and oil are different otherwise
they wouldn't have different names you
know they're different processes they're
different and products they're great
words matter I think so I think so what
our quads yeah but gabble well this is
the way it happened in the 90s when I
was involved in the game it didn't go as
high it didn't go hot as high as quads
it was triples and it was triples were
triple A's a being the highest quality
that you could get and triple-a being
ridiculous quality so it's something
they can just it's the trips you want
the trips and then buddy brings you a 50
pack of mushrooms and you're like no
dude like okay I'll take the mushrooms
but it's the herb I wanted I've always
been a firm supporter of the mushroom
the same way cannabis helped me change
the way I think and look at things
differently I got an incredible amount
of value from psychedelic mushrooms and
I wasn't really like eat a bunch and go
to fish shows although I did enough of
that
it was more like go and with like one or
two people and really like go into the
trip lot learned an incredible amount
about myself and about kind of the world
in the way it works just through these
experiences so I would never I would
never downplay psychedelic mushrooms I
definitely feel that well you see people
now taking what are they taking it for
is it low doses for PTSD and some other
depression that Maps yeah you receive
amazing teachings through through
psychedelics and through journeys that's
why their journeys you can for sure I
mean you can also have like the worst
experience ever depending on your
setting and the people you're doing with
it and your intentions but I always had
I was like Bill Hicks I was like I hate
to tell you I had a lot of fun on drugs
no he does that little sort of I had a
great time on psychedelic mushrooms I I
think of them as definitely you know as
important as as that my views on
cannabis are I I have a strong feeling
that psychedelic mushrooms will and not
just like you Dalek mushrooms but
mushrooms as a whole will come to offer
you know more than we could have ever
possibly imagined even though Paul
Salmons is really blowing the lid off
this [ __ ] right now anyone wants to go
and watch a Paul Stamets video this
particular one how mushrooms can save
the world that this book is based on
which I think originally was one of his
TED talks and it was like I think it was
called six ways mushrooms can save the
world definitely standing ovations type
[ __ ] I would love to have Paul on hash
Church one day it would be amazing if
anyone knew how to reach out to Paul I
could reach out to him he definitely
would be he I mean his time is of the
essence at the moment so his work is
ready he loves you know kite
cannabis and the psychoactive he's
totally that's the beautiful thing about
pollen we've spent days with him and
I've even done the Cortez workshop with
him at hollyhock that is five days a lot
of fun really fun times at the Oregon
Country Fair late night see it down in
the early morning Lucas that book is an
accumulation of all of this work and
everything that he's been doing along
with his crew cuz it's it's Paul Davis
but it's his crew and everyone that
works fungi perspective for perfect
sorry in Olympia and and is why his wife
is partner and they're all just on a
high level and it's really amazing what
they're doing they're all along with
yeah yeah I I got to sort of play a
little trick on Paul at one of the
psychedelic symposiums that were up in
Whistler very small gatherings the
psychedelic family much smaller than the
canvas family but he walked by my booth
and I I had a picture of a trichome like
I think it was from you Dumas the Dutch
photographer that used the micro
electrons microscope microscopy I can't
even pronounce it anyway he had this
incredible still to this day one of the
greatest tricone shots ever taken and I
showed it to Paul and I said can you
identify this mushroom and it just
stopped him in his tracks he was like
looking at it all intently and after
about a minute I said ah you know it's
it's a it's a trichome it's a glandular
trichomes from a cannabis plant and he
was just like man you had me stumped
yeah you're never gonna figure this one
out it's not really what kind of
mushroom is oh my god it's translucent
mushroom what's happening here like it's
lit up I'm like oh yeah it's so it looks
so big - it was a full-page picture of a
full you couldn't really tell it was
small he was probably thinking it was
like you know much bigger than it was
you should've photoshopped it to look
like it was bruised and blue yeah that
would have been it right there yeah I
found these on my property they're about
the size of ants when you eat the entire
world just splits open
and light casts shadow that creates a
language that you've learned
instantaneously upon seeing hey Tony
we're going deep we're talking about
psychedelics what's going on dude
there's also with I was just saying to
invite anyone that knew Paul Stamets to
invite him into hash Church because man
wouldn't we love to have that
conversation and our friends at
dragonfly Madison we know we'll invite
them how are things with you Tony
good man just been some all-nighters
trying to figure out all kinds of little
technical things but I'm good how about
you guys it is today my son's third
birthday so I and the only reason I'm
really not kind of not doing hash Church
is because he's sick right now so he's
just sleeping it's not feeling good he's
got a fever and he's just been sick for
like three days so it's a bummer
you just hate when kids get sick it's no
good usually means you'll get sick sin
I'm not you know what as a parent it's
like whatever I mean I'll take the guy
would take his sickness in the blink of
an eye times 10 yeah but it's how they
build immune systems so you just just
that they're on the right path and that
the fever is doing the good work instead
of the bad work well I can tell you I
made a post about this earlier in the
week this is the cbn this yeah there's
something there actually yes on that
post it looks ridiculous
I should say it's CBN and CBC so but
mostly cbn is this someone you saw the
color-changing happening with is this
that Wow yeah it goes clear I mean it's
pretty clear just in that giant jar it
looked yellow but my first experience I
was gonna load a pen but my first
was on Friday night and I'm gonna make
some some claims here about CBN because
I don't think we've had a lot of
experience
vaporizing full concentrates of CBN but
had a couple people try it interesting
enough I think that you know that kind
of forgetfulness Spacey head kind of
feeling that you get when you smoke a
joint or your smokes an older herb that
kind of couch lock feeling that you you
kind of get we all kind of think of like
CBN but the space enos like when you hit
it it like it kind of I could see why I
would help I could see why I went to
sleep and slept so well on Friday night
but it kind of I don't know it kind of
makes you forget about what you're
thinking about and then you know you
sure I wonder if that's cbn or a lack of
pining I don't know I I mixed this with
Clementine terpenes just to give it some
kind of modulation effect so it could
play in effect but I mean it was like
this I smoked it I didn't COFF and it
kind of like I wouldn't say the
forgetfulness comes from a but like when
you kind of you almost like loss for
words a little bit you're sure it's kind
of like uh it's kind of strange I'm a
little Spacey and then you're like you
know maybe you can't pronounce words or
like anything right away I wouldn't say
it's kind of that drastic but it's it's
like my mind was wound up and I was
talking a whole bunch and I hit that it
definitely silences you do you like I
remember because you were talking to me
yeah okay yeah I was talking to you like
a million miles an hour and then you
were like you were like okay yeah
yeah kind of yeah [ __ ] golf shoes
well and I didn't talk and I didn't and
I was like oh that's strange and it had
and I may be just a delta aid or the CBC
but there was this like delayed effect
it was just kind of like okay kind of
calm me down but then I started to yawn
and I got tired and then I slept for ten
hours so for sure it helps with sleeping
for sure it calms your mind and I could
see like for PTSD and for different
things it helps you forget and that's
not a bad thing no that's not a bad
thing so I do you think you got and how
did you feel the next morning oh I
didn't feel anything in the head I don't
hear anything the next morning no no I
smoked some right now it's not gonna
help but and then I just woke up so
let's see but it's definitely unusual I
definitely think it could go in a pen
with Clementine terpenes or any other
terpenes paired with it it's really nice
it doesn't taste like cherry at all
there's no cherry taste to it there's no
it's very medicinal it's not it doesn't
have like your normal I don't know it
doesn't have any kind of cherry taste it
doesn't and it's absolutely clean on the
nail I mean there's I'll show to you
there's nothing there's absolutely
nothing so I'll show to you let's see
she's clean on the nail
clean clean mine let's show you nice you
had Napa Valley's like Tony's gonna fall
asleep on stream look at look at this
stuff can you see this yes you can see
that right he was doing it just 30 more
minutes it is making me tired
that's like nerd porn for you know
cannabis science junkies right there
I mean it's pretty ridiculous
it was testing
like close to 50% CBN and like I was
quite a bit of CBC in it I have to look
at that again but don't they there's no
thca or THC in it the other 50% the
other 50% is roundup yeah roundup
yeah it's roundup CBN News bubbleman pit
look how much vapor I get no cough and
normally Eickhoff you guys all know that
so I know CBN doesn't work that way
because it's a byproduct of THC but it's
the rest of the components are they
activated in their acidic form with as
clear as it is you know well I think I
posted the test result on on the capsule
the capsule kind of shows you when but
that has CBD in it so I'll post a
regular one so the thing with it and
mark it probably like like this and so
if you take and the first time they
started testing and if you take like the
pure cbn extract and take like you know
a concentrate of it it's off the GC it's
like off the scale so you know diluting
it four times before you test it gives
you a much more accurate reading I'm not
really sure what the rest of it is mark
as it's as clear as can be you could see
it on the side how thick it is but yeah
I don't know it's not like this is build
this was molecularly distilled mm-hmm
yeah so something that's distilled I
mean if if it is about 50% one thing and
50% something else I mean typically a
distillation it was a 90 it was 90% it
was a 90 percent THC with all the THC oh
it was not okay so say say that again I
thought you said it was 50%
you see so check this out you could do
this with rosin or distillate so if you
did it with rosin right and you made it
and we've done this with we've made a
distillation from rosin which you'll
lose about thirty percent of your weight
in terpenes and fats and other [ __ ]
from the hash rosin you could get to
like a ninety percent activated THC you
could do that also from distillate so if
you're molecularly distilling and you if
you start with a 85 or 90 percent THC
you could also start with THC a which is
something I don't know if you guys
talked about today but I definitely
wanted to put the instructions up and
get people on the THC a tip of how to do
that you could start with a couple
different things but ultimate if you
start with THC a you got to convert it
to THC and that's pretty easy to do in a
rosin as well you could you could take a
hash rosin you could double boil that
you can gently and slowly activate it
from THC to THC then you could make a
distillation from it if you had enough
of it once you get to 90% though and
you've cleaned up what's supposed to be
any of the you know contaminants and
stuff left behind then the process that
we do not necessarily mind to share with
but it does it then does not use your
traditional heat and distillation
methods it uses a completely different
method when which does not lose any
weight so we would go from 90 so if
something you start with a kilo of 90
percent THC you end up with 900 and you
know 80 950 grams very little is lost in
the process if any and de COEs it's a
more a little bit more than a 50%
conversion without a volume loss it's
pretty pretty substantially crazy I
didn't really believe it until it's a
50% conversion that means you still have
50 percent THC
nope that goes away well 50% conversion
only 50% of it is converting it well I'm
sorry
you go from 90% then we ended up around
48 to 50 percent CBN with no THC present
left so is it just alright mark well
here you go explain that is that just
the breakdown of the molecule itself
I understand those numbers don't add up
to me so I'm know that's really simple
it means that there was a hundred
percent conversion but the yield was
only 50 percent so okay so I will tell
you this there are okay so if you start
with a kilo that's testing 86 percent or
eight hundred and sixty milligrams and
you end up with 500 milligrams of CBN it
appears that the CBC was a I don't know
if there's a converted by-product but
there was high levels of CBC that were
not there before so that doesn't make
any sense at all to me that's crazy
yeah that's all any sense because you
need you need a synthase to convert to
convert CBC into either CBD or or THC
and that requires there's electrons to
require there so your there's chemistry
going on there that doesn't make sense
to me you shouldn't have seen me see in
there if there wasn't to begin with
actually it really doesn't make sense we
we did a lot of work on CBC varieties
and develop varieties that where the
majority of the cannabinoids in the
plant were CBC oh let me see if CBC was
in the original starting low hon second
I took a picture of the test-score
my piece might be talking out my ass
hold on a second rooster Tony is this
the same process where you saw the
color-changing effects based on
temperature it's just the same this has
nothing like the temperature I thought
the post said it was due to the
temperature it was changing colors oh no
if you just take the if you just take
that oil at the end and warm it up it
goes clear now I thought what you were
doing is you were starting with the tea
see isolate and you were converting it
to CBN to make a something that's 50
percent by weight CBN I thought that's
what he said you were doing yeah no this
is imagine you start with like 1200
grams of hash rosin you end up with a
thousand grams of rosin distillate just
without alcohol you just you fraction a
tin and then this is high THC a high THC
variety yeah I mean the rosin is like
80% as it is and you get it to 90 and
you remove all the terpenes and all the
[ __ ] right and then see what you
find this and then the same way it
doesn't change weight it just converts
all of that THC to from a 90% to 46% CBN
and then there's 56% of nothing so there
are two different molecules with two
different molecular weights and so to go
from THC to CBN you basically have to
move lose two moles of hydrogen right
and that's an ad e hydrogenation process
to caramelize the North ring of THC when
you're looking at the chicken wire north
rate will now look like a benzene ring
because it'll now be fully unsaturated
so in that process you have to lose two
moles of h2 so it's different in
molecular weight I mean just like THC a
and THC are different so what you're
extracting in the rosin process is first
like THC a and that's carboxylated to
make THC and undergoes this d
hydrogenation reaction to make cbn so
that's what's going on and it seems like
you just have a distribution of all
either cannabinoid acids that have been
decarboxylated and now partially
converted over to cbn and then that
partial conversion there could also be
what's called dye hydro you know so you
have tetrahydrocannabinol you have what
I make when I hydrogenate which is
hexahydrate
hydro no double bond at all naturally in
the plant tetra hydro then there's die
hydro which is with two double bonds and
then it's thermodynamically downhill to
lose that last mole of hydrogen to make
CBN so yeah you'll have everything
populated along that profile it probably
depends on if they're using some type of
coax in Anor what type of oxidation
procedures are using no oxygen okay no
gin so this is so no heat or oxygen so
that's the only thing I could do but
because you need something to overcome
the activation energy barrier between
there and there well it's like I said is
not really my process to share it was
co-developed but it's all I can tell you
is that it sounds like it needs
improvement well it's only a 50% yield
what are you talking about so here's
here's okay so here's how I'm current
here here's how I was currently doing it
taking sift farmers grade sift and
putting it into a chamber that has heat
and oxygen for degradation for a week at
a time to get to convert from 250
milligrams of let's say THC a right in a
sip form down to 70 milligrams of CBN
and if I started with a kilo of sift I
end up losing like the weight of the
kief that isn't a thousand grams when I
get it back it's like you know five 600
grams and I also lost the maybe not
maybe not quite that much what I'm
losing like seventy plus percent in the
conversion doing it that way with heat
and oxygen what I'm saying to you now is
when I have a kilo of rosin or
distillate I get the same kilo back and
the conversion rate is extremely well
I'm happy with a 50 percent conversion
rate and no volume no weight loss you
know what I mean right but this is where
I'm having a difficult time following
Tony so if you're only getting 50%
conversion and that means
in in your muscle have you thought any
way to convert it at a better rate from
THC to CBN
no no hold on a second or so there's no
no I'm not trying I'm not trying to make
CBM but I'm just trying to understand
what your what your you're holding up in
the jar so if what you're saying is that
you're only getting 50% conversion and
does that mean the other 50% that's not
converting does that stay is THC you say
that there's no no see so so what's the
other 50%
I'm just true oh yeah no I'm with you
because the other the and the labs also
having kind of a hard time testing so
we've tested this like four different
ways what I can tell you is when I when
we mixed everything and we said okay
here's our final capsule with CBD oil in
it - we were the only thing in it was
CBD CBN Delta a and CBC in the original
oil let me see if I could find it let me
see hold on I'm gonna find it right now
I'll tell you exactly what exactly was
in it did they look for Delta Aid yeah
they look for nothing huh cool no no no
this is SC Labs this is this this went
through a lot of different testing on I
wouldn't put it out there if it didn't
let's see here okay okay was this one
yeah so as a chemist you know again if I
ever realized holy there was 50 percent
completion
I want that reaction to go to a 100
percent completion so that that's what I
mean in terms of the opportunity to take
wait here figure out how to push it the
rest of the 50 percent but go ahead
known okay maybe I'm saying it wrong it
converts all of the THC to CBN but the
rate at which it converts it is about 50
percent of what it started with
so I'll get let me read you what was in
the starting oil okay so that's not
changing some of it's changing into
right but rate when you say the rate
rate is a measure of how fast the
reaction is no I think what attorney
correct me if I'm wrong here you have
essentially the same volume at the end
but instead of it at 90% concentration
the THC was all the THC is gone you have
the same volume but you have a 50
percent concentration assuming it
correct right so what's the other right
that I would love to know so that's why
I'm asking you
so let me tell you what was in it try to
figure it out because it is mind blowing
I've been blown away for about two
months now working on this and so okay
the starting the starting oil this is
all through se labs so this was tested
twice you know just to make sure but
let's say the start the starting oil was
so it was an 82 percent THC no Delta 8
there was 5 there was okay so is eighty
two point four six THC it was point five
seven th cv 1.19 CBC 1.43 CBG 0.57 cbn
0.22 CBD and point two six CBD a when it
came out the only thing it had on a
second
the okay here it is now here when it
came back out it had no more THC no more
THC a no CBD no CBD a it had 400 plus
like 460 milligrams of cbn no CBD v no
CBD VA
no CBG no CBG a no THC v forty to forty
two milligrams of delta eight and
seventy seven milligrams of CBC so it's
over fifty 50 milligrams and of that was
it looks like ten percent of it or 20
percent of it was CBC and ten percent
was Delta eight then I put that into a
capsule to dilute it to get with CBD oil
to try to make our piece
or on and that came out too that had oh
those rolling home that one came out too
I got that one over here okay that one
came out too no THC no THC a which is
fine our CBD that was in there was 44
milligrams
no CBD a then it was 35 milligrams of
CBN no other components except six
milligrams of C Delta 8 and 21
milligrams of CBC now capsules a half a
gram and that lines up with exactly the
oil numbers of the CBN so that actually
all does line up but what I'm saying to
you is CBC was not that much prevalent
so perhaps what I'm I don't know where
all the CBC came from if what you're
saying is that when you convert THC to
see me n the like it wouldn't create see
me see there's what you're saying
something I I don't know it depends the
process you know if you have a against
it sounds like a proprietary
low-temperature rot no template you're
you're doing chemistry I mean you're
taking the components and your rear rate
deckchairs
and I don't know exactly you have to
look at the chemistry and you look at
the reaction manifolds good cbcb form
all the building blocks are there you
know basically you're just rearranging
the same atoms that are that are there
in the molecules and there has to be
sort of thermodynamic driving force for
those rearrangements they don't just
happen on their own through either
initiated by heat or a light or some
type of microbial degradation I mean
there's all kinds of like degraded in
cannabinoids that end up going CBN
because CBN is somewhat of a
thermodynamic dead end
I think else Olli had pointed out that
there's hydroxylated
metabolites I think the eight hydroxy t8
C's and whatnot those are all if you
heat those up they immediately lose
water dehydrate now it makes dihydrate
HC which again goes to CBN almost
instantly so yeah those are all
thermodynamically downhill from where
the molecules of the planar so when you
start heating things or when you treat
them with catalysts or treat them with
any type of stress to put stress on
those most sensitive molecules
especially ones that can equilibrator to
other isomers which is what cbc is right
CBC's and isomers of of THC mm-hmm well
I don't know quite the answer to why or
how I guess but I'm pretty happy with
the conversion I mean if there was a way
I guess what you're saying if yeah the
next step would be if you can convert 86
percent 807 milligrams of THC to 807
milligrams of THC or CBN then yeah that
would be amazing but I I don't think
that's ever gonna be it you would think
in a distillation that you would get a
cleaner cut or that you would actually
if you're doing a short path
distillation here that you'd be able to
take several cuts during that
distillation to look at like can you
actually get rid of the minor
cannabinoid fractions there in an
earlier cut and then later in a
distillation major cut is going to be
just more purified CBN CBN is right and
Sam will correct me on this a white
crystalline compound so if it's pure
like CBD can be purified to essentially
be so yes so the scientists that I was
working with on this I asked them about
like breaking out CBN and I said yeah
you won't be able to do it with terpenes
or anything because of the polarity and
the way that THC a or CBD breaks out is
totally different than cbn I'm curious
to see look because that is the next
step now how do I take this to a ninety
nine percent yeah there's ways that you
could quantitatively can
her THC that's been isolated like the
clear quantitatively converted all over
to CBN and and then if it's not all
converted you can then clean it up in
chromatic chromatography or or
distillation to basically make it an
analytically pure sample but do you have
to but would you use a solvent in that
process depending on you mean the octave
dehydrogenation of THC itself yeah well
it's all the classic yeah you probably
have to do that in a solvent or though
you could be probably creative and
figure out a way to do it without using
a solvent but you know that would
require some some engineering but yeah
most so it's basically it's just a
dehydrogenation reaction right so you
have to this is what you kind of
patented right what's that no I actually
founded the hydrogenation that's adding
hydrogen hydrogen away so the methyl
cyclohexane ring of THC can basically
lose hydrogen and so when you see if
you're doing a distillation and you
typically see white smoke coming from
the distillation that's usually
indicative of cbn formation because what
is happening is that the oxygen in air
is actually being hydrogenated if you
will why the methyl cyclohexane ring to
make air in order to make water and so
that steam that's actually coming up
from from the distillation pot when you
see the white smoke coming from your
distillation pot that's typically
indicative of cbn formation so yeah
it'll happen with just air air is
actually the oxygen and air is strong
enough but you could use other oxidants
to basically promote that to make it go
at less harsh conditions and I know Arno
has camp published a paper and I think
did his his PhD dissertation on a or one
of the parts of his PhD dissertation
involved the quantitative oxidation of
THC to CBN and I think that's go global
and you define his dissertation
Internet I actually saw that once
actually yeah I think
did he use like silver nitrate yes like
a silver kind of stoichiometric which
I'm not sure as is is what you wanted
what you really want to do but I think
one of the things that people always get
hung up on again is that you know you
can convert well this happens to a small
extent just on the nail you know when
you're oxidizing THC in an atmosphere of
oxygen you will get some you know a
conversion to CBN and so you see that
actually as an artefact sometimes in in
dirty G sees and again things happen
where you could actually see the dye
hydro product as well I know that Ryan
has shared that chromatogram well yeah
that's from our no paper if I remember
correctly yeah
so those intermediates can't can be
identified I just wanted to mention that
Tony yeah there's so these guys you know
they worked for Genentech and some other
pretty substantial companies but like
ultimately yeah they were like yeah if
you built this custom this column
machine and spent like eight hundred
thousand dollars they could break out
everything in its pharmaceutical grade
level but I do believe that there is a
little bit of solvent that's using it so
I guess the I guess what it is is you
hit a wall and you say okay if you're
happy with converting th c to c be in
without a solvent this is probably the
best we're gonna be able to do if you
want to take it to the next level and by
all the crazy gear you probably could do
it at a you know at a much more
efficient conversion rate you know yeah
i think what might be key is to remove
the be able to remove the the product in
like a reactive distillation so it
doesn't build up over time because i
think over time they will degrade and i
think that there's other did you use we
did use short path though I'm not saying
we did yeah
and and and and that's great I mean
that's a great way to to do it but I
think you could probably to clean to
ticket rosin out there was some funky
weird [ __ ] that I don't even know if I
want to share like what comes out of
hash but for sure when you try to short
path rosin some weird [ __ ] comes out of
it I test my time you heat stuff up like
if you're heating stuff up to do a high
vacuum yes you should definitely do what
you can to make sure that it's
completely Ben D winterized because you
know this is the point of having fats
and waxes and something that you're
heating up to these temperatures these
things don't distill what they do is
they degrade and when they degrade to
create those off burn rubber flavors
that you don't want in your in your
distillate and so the best way to keep
that stuff out of your distillate is to
make sure that what goes into the pot is
as clean as you possibly can you know
people are using activated carbon and
SIVs and you know what they can to make
sure that by the time you put any
thermal history on that material that
you've done what you can to remove
things that aren't meant to be heated up
to that temperature like those things
are gonna degrade and give your stuff a
really off flavor yeah so one thing I
would note that and I agree with that is
that when you go from a hash rosin the
way it is like the azulene and the
different weird stuff we're pulling out
I actually had it tested and it tested
for all kinds of funky stuff
it had THC in it it was just it like you
said it was like rubbery fishy all these
weird different kind of what I thought
was terpenes of blue terpenes and things
like that but it actually had all kinds
of [ __ ] in it but so consider a little
bit a bad flavor goes a long way yeah
like a drop of some of that stuff oh my
god we blow your entire
I have people again who will take those
low boiling fractions completely
disassemble their unit before taking the
high boil in Terps because you don't
even want to contaminate the path by
which you're gonna collect your
wonderful clean distillate with all that
ass smelling crap that comes over early
and again if I think really if you do
your distillate preparation
appropriately that fraction should
actually be quite flavorful and try to
hold on to it yeah I've seen blue I've
seen yellow purple red all kinds of
different colors well I would tell you
so check it out so then everybody's been
talking about you know the THCA thing
separating THC a withdraws and I don't
I'm sure it's been a pretty big topic I
mean it's been a pretty big topic on the
internet a lot of people making a lot of
claims that they created it and
what-have-you
I can tell you from my experience the
first time I ever saw it was our friend
Matt from Strait concentrated in 2015
when those in Ukiah and we had our hands
on the first press
he pressed hash rosin and then we took
that repress that refolded it up right
in the little twenty five screen repress
that out came super sappy oil and
insider Matt Armstrong whose but yeah
yeah yeah I don't know he watches right
no yeah well no I don't think he's do I
think he's still with him I don't know
there was some something on on his
Instagram it looked like he was starting
a new label or I don't know really but
either way yeah either way we've had our
differences in the past and I wrote on
his Instagram was like listen all I all
I can tell you is in my history in my
experience the first person that I saw
repress rosin was him and we had a white
funky substance I've had I've done that
I never like would create a product or
release it but it was it was always very
interesting we tested that that chip
before I tested some recent huckleberry
og that we did and surprisingly it was
extremely high in THC a it's like a
white little chip doesn't have a lot of
flavor and there is a website out there
that teaches you how to do it it is
Halloween
we got an Tamar of it it looks beautiful
it's it's the absolutely pristine oh
it's beautiful yeah yeah I mean it's it
the signals on the NMR ring like like
there's no tomorrow it just absolutely
pristine beautiful and it's solvent less
so yeah so if you go to low temp -
plates calm there's uh there's a whole
tutorial and actually how to make it and
you can refine this two or three times
so if you pressure rosin and repress it
again at like 130 to 140 you'll get that
nice wide if you could do it again and
you could start pulling out like all
kinds of like crystalline from it I have
been doing that for so you could do that
for you know like a pronto line or
something like that for capsules which
works unbelievable but now I've been
soaking those in you know like how we do
the crystalline crystalline for CBD and
for the stuff that we're doing gold drop
but now I've been doing that same thing
with THC so I'm gonna have a Girl Scout
cookies crystalline grown from soaking
and terpenes instead of you know like
people that are taking like an ethanol
wash and then a hexane wash like on a
CVD and then they're getting crisps or
getting it to break out I'm breaking it
out with cannabis terpenes so hopefully
next week I'll have variations of a
crystalline that I could test that will
be grown from from within that solvent
like so to be I think it's pretty cool
it's a fast way to do that I'm also
working on ways to if you do that with
say CBD and THC oil there's potential of
separating the CBD out from the THC a
because if you have any CBD that's in
your oil so if you notice when you make
that THC a and those little chips that
are left behind all of the oil and the
sauces to the other side that will
contain CBD and other components so
I think that it's a significant
significant movement in the solvent list
world and you know hats off to Matt he
was working on it for a while I've seen
a couple other people out there claiming
that they created it but working on what
like he squished he pressed dress he
pressed it again and inside the bag was
THCA but we didn't know it at the time
no no I know because I mean I got the
same thing at the same time I really dry
sift turning white white being like I
got a puff this and see what's up and
feeling effects from it and being like
what the [ __ ] I brought some to you I
brought some to you recently remember I
was like oh check this out and we smokes
it together yes that Matt gave it that
Matt gave me yep and what I found like
because I've seen him enter and we've
talked after cups and different things
yanno I think he actually filed for it
or something but he hid what I say he's
been working I I think legally he was
working on patenting it if I wasn't
mistaken but regardless he had entered
it a couple times I'd only seen him this
is like for a year he's had it and I
felt bad because it's really strong
that's really good and people weren't
gravitating towards it at all and the
cups that didn't do very good people
probably thought it was wasn't real even
when I got it I was like oh it's a
solvent list and then I remembered like
it just triggered my memory okay I
remember now now because we thought it
was lipids we thought it was like fats
or something everyone that's what
everyone was saying oh yeah I got stuffs
garbage I have since though so what's
interesting though ever since I started
prana when we press like you know CVD or
we press hash we keep all those chips
and that goes into the topical line I
even told that to I've even said that to
force when he came by and he was like oh
and I was like yeah everything gets
reused for us you know we put it under
our high vacuum and into our prana fat
and then used and then heated up to try
to get like a active THC out of it and
there's quite a bit quite a bit in those
chips
we're talking trees we kind of joke
about it with with flower rosin and
things in patch Rus and there's lots of
edible makers that you know it's gold
it's considered like gold now and people
been using that so it's kind of funny
that like at least for the solvent list
world it's it's definitely the next it's
definitely the next push in the next
movement that will come out more and
more and something that you could do
with a hair art and the twenty five
screen you know daily making rosin and
make him making another product
simultaneously yeah and what's cool is
the sauce or like you know you like for
us we walk into the walk-in freezer and
in like 30 seconds you can take it right
off but you know if you're at home and
it's you know you've separated it you're
going to get like a super saucy thing on
your parchment paper so you can fold
that up put it in a double ziploc throw
it in a freezer you know or vacuum seal
it and throw it in a freezer try to get
it as cold as possible but the second
you come out if you're in an 85 degree
or 90 degree area it's just going to be
all over the parchment again so I think
that's the only difficult part but I do
think that you know I do think it's
gonna push the push the industry yet
again I always like when people are
doing things without solvent see where
CEREC see where it could go that would
have been d for twenty K's moment to say
bong rip I like that it was like tony
was talking I lucked out these holes
that a pipe in his mouth well I mean you
gotta admit it's pretty neat huh mark
because as a chemist you do everything
you can to try to find ways of
separating people were laughing and
people have been laughing about rosin
for a long time I believe there's a all
kinds of memes out there that if you
smoke Roz and you turn gay right there's
all kinds of funny
memes out there but oh no it's getting
pretty good hey Tony
yes sir fYI you can take the
highly-educated stems and put it on that
gen1 cap of the oh yeah I uh
we got a longer without burning yourself
because it'll will I've been looking for
that thing for a while bro
every time someone says that I'm like
yeah where the hell is that thing I
actually lost my little titanium gray
260 wire screen cipolla it's a gen 2 HP
with it has the hollow and has the two
holes and allow you to breathe through
it and so it allows you to actually
breathe through the cap no problem okay
so that's called the gen 2 well I think
it is yeah if this thing screws off
you're right Wow little tricks I've
learned wow it's so cool listen dude you
still have to come by I have your
strawberry banana no problem I'll come
by early this week my birthday's
tomorrow so it's been kind of a crazy
week there we go happy birthday man
happy birthday longer up to that I'm
taking one right now for that well I
guess I might as well join you birthday
what are you 40 yeah I wish 48 48 come
on you don't look 48 thanks x credit
cannabis and not drinking you don't have
a single wrinkle on you look closer
[Laughter]
I blame the jeans yeah people say that
to me and you know what I say I'm like
well I don't have any you know I got the
good genes from the cannabis or whatever
than smoking but you know good
complexion here but we both have the
same situation up here so well I would
have hair I just would have it around a
band and my family is I'm like [ __ ] that
just shave it I don't want to look like
some crazy Nutty Professor
I'm not Rick for Rick and Morty what a
little bit dub hey dub a dub dub yeah
but yeah if we were testing so mark
lyrics test the strawberry-banana goose
testing 84 and 85 percent it's over 80
on the THC a and that I have a hundred
grams that I'm this hash frozen from
strawberry banana goo that I'm going to
press just to make the THC a just to
like have have that then I'm going to re
soak it back in terpenes try to grow
that out and then add the sauce back to
it see if I could make something
something crazy nice something for
bubbleman look crazy something something
so I'm soaked in some Franken hash yeah
but um there was a lot of questions
about like I got this week you know I
guess those Trinity pens went out and I
did want to say that they're working on
a way to get terpenes back out to you
guys on a retail level but we'll find
out on Monday it looks like maybe not
three blue river but through up tech
you'll be able to get your you'll be
able to get those kits and you'll be
able to get terpenes as well from him
because you know he's has a long history
with his credit card processors and we
went through the qualification process
and it seems like they were pretty
acceptive of it so it'll be pretty
pretty good to get those out and I sent
you the new vials too you saw those how
mark I did yeah they look pretty cool
I'm always with new vials you show
somebody gene errs well I think it's
important because look I've gone through
this thing these little applicators and
this is why I haven't released stuff
because I want to take time with it and
these little applicators you can see
this had to be changed right and so you
can either do an HD or LD or PTFE type
of plastic straight glass works - that's
what I used straight glass works really
well straight glass yep those are those
I would say you know Gary's working on
trying to get those the okay he's got
one too over there so see the one that
Mark's got all right so that rubber at
over so that little rubber stopper
anything past you know eight percent
terpenes is gonna start to 8 to 10
percent turbines gonna start to eat that
away long-term when you start getting 15
percent terpenes and I'm just sharing
with it like this little plunger wants
to punch out whether the terpenes are
off gassing whatever you want to call it
it definitely creates a little bit of
pressure in there from high volume of
terpenes that's about 70 percent THC a
and 15 percent 12 percent terpenes and
so it's it's there okay they work all
right but I think that at the end of the
day I have a different method than I
think you know eventually we have to
build our own to be honest with you from
scratch but in the meantime it'll it
we've got a different way that I'm going
to do it with the micro glass dropper
and a vial within a vial that will that
I think is pretty neat and it has a PTFE
cap but the way that the file will work
show you right now mark will recognize
these boom
so that little vial is on a kind of like
almost like a spring loaded into the cap
when you open it you can actually have
your terpenes in there with a little
glass dropper or a glass syringe then
you could turn that inside to the vial
mix all of your stuff up you could put
two grams in there which makes four
refill carts so this is for the people
at home that are buying Trinities that
wanna like make turtle make their own
stuff at home you need terpenes to do
that and you need to be able to get it
so that you can get every last drop out
of it instead of it being a square
bottom
needs to be a pointed bottom you need to
be able to get something in there so
this is the solution for that and then
you know pre-mixed refills it I find it
I find this thing to be easy to use I
know mark does I mean they're awesome
because you could do anything with them
you know I find it easy to fill the tank
up like that but you know a little glass
dropper that will go into there and to
put it in the side of the tank would
work as well
it's just that saucy you know it's not
like a distillate so it doesn't
necessarily have to be in something like
this but yeah do you see a turning dark
on exposure to light like when it first
goes in there it's kind of like a
slavery but yeah screaming yep it was
lighter it was creamier yeah yeah I
could see the oil turning dark you know
in those clear glasses or the yeah
Turkey well also besides melting the
rotted stopper in the syringe will melt
any plastic sidewalls also yeah yep it
doesn't necessarily melt it right it
just it basically just plasticizers it
so that's probably it melted I first saw
this 40 years ago in a sealed vacuum
sealed glass mason jar with a rubber
band I accidentally left in it I opened
it up six months later and the rubber
band had melted all in the bud oh yeah
see if I can get a picture and send it
from my phone but that had am spray
bottle that actually House of Harlequin
gave me Wade's organization it was full
of terpenes but it was kind of in a
spritzer so I was been taking home and
and work with it and I it tipped over in
my refrigerator and I found it
I can noticed a day or so later and it
had melted the plastic shelf on my
refrigerator infused the container to it
so in the cold refrigerator
it was corrosive enough to melt the
shelf and I have a picture of it here on
my phone let's see if I can get it to
pull out but that was a lesson learned
the hard way about not only how
corrosive they can be but well check
this out in just Marley I just posted
this in the in the chat you can post it
in the in has the hospital asked group
on Facebook but if you click that little
image I sent you guys in this little
chat you could share that this has a
chart of the LDPE HDPE PTFE PSP PPC and
abs types of things that are out there
and then it has all of the different
solvents and then it gives you a rating
of if it's going to be good or not for
that and so with what you know caustic
effects and things like this
ether ester you know it's got all kinds
of nasty great stuff in there and you
want to look for things like if you look
at the PTFE it's all a is all the way
down except for one category benzene and
then you could see what would be rated
so if you're feeling something with a
hash oil and you're saying okay they're
just using pp at the stopper and you
look at terpenes and you say okay
terpenes with what we know about them
once you start going past you know 8% 5
you know 10% 20% that stuff you're going
to have to use different different
sources and PTFE like we talked about
not something easily biodegradable but
it does work really good all of the new
Blue River degradable at all man no yeah
it's not biodegradable and so but it is
the best if you're looking at the best
source or you know not having any cost
oh yeah and and so again like part of
the issue with some of these things is a
plastic is not just the polymer itself
and people are talking about like
whether it's polypropylene polystyrene
there's polyolefin PLAs
polyester plastics but what makes them
flexible is they add plasticizers to
that and a common plasticizer of the
phthalates that are used that they often
have health concerns about because
they're in plastics like for baby
bottles and baby toys and whatnot and
they can leach out out and I guess in
certain you know toasters Salley
plasticizers can be toxic but like
that's the issue with a lot of these you
know materials whether it's the lid on
your vials or whatever that comes in
contact with extracts that are rich with
with terpenes is that deter pians will
start to leach out the plasticizer now
you have plasticizer in your hash
phthalates and [ __ ] like that so that's
why you never want to use any plastic
containers to have to have anything and
we used to use always use film vials for
like buds and stuff
but I mean like for vials for storing
stuff like this it should be in a glass
vial and not a plastic file and you
shouldn't really be using plastic
syringes and I see in plastic surgeries
use them used quite a bit but I think
the other thing and again Tony this
might have something to do with what
like with these syringes right here they
actually they are stabilized to take
some type of liquid load and and in most
cases like there are no you know if you
look at like the rubbers and all all
those rubbers again will all start
absorbing it's just a matter of rate and
certainly like if you pull the plug off
of some of these syringes you'll find
that the the the rubber itself has
swollen I mean there's like now the
polymer itself is now swollen because
you've actually absorbed a lot of liquid
into the material itself so you can't
kind of fit it in anymore but the point
is is that any material that you come in
contact with that's a synthetic material
like a polymer or plastic a lot of those
are coated or have plasticizers in there
that could essentially leach out with
terpenes so I think that's the more
problematic issue of using anything that
comes in contact with a with a extractor
trait that could extract plasticizers
yeah I agree and ultimate the end of the
day we have only so many choices even
the lids we've got new little lids for
these terpenes and they do so PTFE
underside yep PTFE slip lids there's
then they sell plastic ones and they
sell different [ __ ] that's under there
but ultimately if you want to have the
safest vials for terpenes or the safest
files for high terpene oils kind of have
to go that direction so that's what
we're kind of releasing and then I think
that's how our applicators are going to
be them I mean I think that like if
you're using something like that I don't
think it's if it's a short-term thing
it's pretty good but the whole concept
has to be has to be redesigned so we'll
eventually have our own little custom
push twist glass on glass you know
refill applicator that can work like a
syringe but not look like one but also
work like a controlled you know device
I've seen it you can see what happens
when you have like a paper liner and
it's not a plastic liner oh yeah
that's horrible now the paper starts to
become basically a reservoir for what do
you think that's inside the jar but so
you can't just there's not a paper
solution and I think there are like
coatings that you can put on that are
somewhat more like yeah yeah yeah yeah
this one is all of our new caps are they
don't have that kind of liner like in
Sony let's see that again hold that up
again yeah sure it looks like that so
it's a maybe like a polyethylene liner
it's a pee yeah I forget what it was it
was slightly rated um so I thought it
was pretty good instead of like a I have
to look it up when we when we bought
them it was definitely better than the
liner but nothing that's like anything
that's now anything that's saucy it's
like here's one that I'm not using
anymore this one's okay this is one of
those this is what you normally see that
little [ __ ] that
there yeah I mean you wouldn't want a
whole container made out of that
material but certainly as a lid liner
that would be just fine probably ever
yeah I don't know about the silicone
containers though you know those little
weird rubber ones they seem to those
thing to crack and break down well there
there are victims sometimes you get like
these little tiny holes and the little
pore holes it's not like the material
itself is impervious to most but because
it's thermally cured at a higher
temperature where again polymerizations
happened and so there's a barrier to
keep you know things from being absorbed
but they're only you know as good a
barrier is they are free of little pin
holes or cracks or fissures and that's
where stuff can start getting in you
know yeah how do you feel about LDPE and
HDPE yeah so those are just a Crenn um's
for low density polyethylene and high
density polyethylene they're made from
petroleum I don't know we want to patrol
promote petroleum products
I know they're plastics they're
ubiquitous they're in society I mean
there's really there's not much you can
do you know about it just for everywhere
they're everywhere I did like it do your
limit to you know make sure that any
product packaging that you buy yeah I'm
saying don't you think that's better
than PP polypropylene yeah don't you
think an LD or net HD would be a better
I'll give you a little bit more
protection if you're talking about more
you know high terpene yeah it depends I
mean again I think that those types of
high jerking products should only be
packaged in glass yeah I think I mean
you know occasionally we get a fold that
some kind of you know hash and it's very
very chirpy it was with it a fold so
it's not difficult to deal with and you
wish you had in the glass container
but um I I would think that yet less
plastic is good when it comes to
anything that comes in contact with
something especially something that you
cannot dabby or vaping hey I just wanted
to jump in really quick and show you
guys a new packaged product that we're
having here you know we've got our co2
extract that's in between ten and twenty
six percent terpene content and so it's
really really high and I've been worried
about putting it in these sort of
plastic syringes you know always going
for the best that we can get but plastic
was really the best at the moment so
after working and and looking in China I
found these and so it's all glass on
glass and it's it's very similar to what
you've got there Tony that you've been
using although there's no silicone
plunger and so they they they hold air
you know you can you can pull it up and
then it's a it's it's definitely an air
tight air tight fit there so if
anybody's looking for something to put
their extract in that's a high tree bean
extract definitely look around Ali
Baba's a good resource for this and let
me ask you something there's that
plunger since if you get to 20 or 30%
with terpenes does that plunger stay in
on its own or do you have to hold it in
yeah yeah I know it holds in it holds in
so so I'm just you know yeah just
sticking my finger over it there you can
tell that it's it's airtight
yeah it just bounces right back up so
yeah it's it's glass on glass I would
say that if you get over 20 or 30
percent sure beans you're going to be
losing it like if you put pure terpenes
in here they're going to come out the
backside it's not gonna hold in that
really really liquid Turkey but but yeah
for for anything that's a mixture and
you know we haven't had any issues with
it on the heights European extracts yeah
it's important to talk about because as
everyone gets keeps boosting their
terpene level it's like that changes
that packaging and that's why I didn't
release these little I made like six of
these applicators I've kind of sat on
them I've changed the plungers the LD
you know just done a few different
things I'm like yeah and it's like you
could go
down that path but then ultimately I'm
just doing a little glass on glass
spring-loaded vial with a glass on glass
Mico dropper for at least for the tanks
because I'm not trying I'm not trying to
get like I'm not trying to use it for
dabbing I'm just trying to refill my
friggin tank
maybe those like just like how do I get
my sauce in something where I don't lose
it you know they've got this beautiful
like live rosin sauce and cream and
you're like okay what do I put it in I
can't put it in a regular file because
you won't get it all out you can't put
it in stuff that's gonna have any
plastics because then that'll eat away
so the same thing you probably went
through you're like okay what do we do
and you're like I got to find something
and then you know the glass syringes I
think are great I've you know it's just
like some of the dispensaries and some
of the people are like oh it's a syringe
it's like yeah but like there's only so
many glass on glass things that you can
use you're either gonna use a dropper in
a glass some form of vial or you're
gonna have to use a glass on glass
syringe the one Marcus has and we found
the same thing and you know alibaba's
got really thin
they have really thin ones too that are
just exactly what you were showing
you've had a big Daddy one though you
know you're this is a two milliliter
syringe and and they do sell the one
milliliters that are just like the the
standard one mils
I think Marcus has one up yep those are
the one MLS yep yeah exactly yeah I
really like the form factor of the two
milk because you were able to you know
pull your gram of extract out and you
don't have a whole bunch of space in
there and taking up extra packaging
space so the ten milliliter seemed to
work really well yeah yeah I went in the
other I went in I went in the other door
for for using this I actually poured my
sauce right in the back
let it drip right down and then just
drop the plunger in and build from there
I didn't I didn't actually pull the
sauce up in its actually yeah it's
actually really hard to pull up on these
syringes you know so a better
to go about it is to fill a much larger
syringe and then use a syringe to
syringe connector and then you can
actually fill from the bottom up and
it'll just push the plunger up to
onenote later I like that so then to do
that but then like for the you know the
common folk like you know the best is
for what we went with is the V and the V
insert inside the file that has the
sauce that can you can just grab it with
a micro dropper to fill up your tank
because then it's like more little parts
you know I was like going through this a
lot but you know if you're trying to use
it for an applicator yeah the glass on
glass is the way to go yeah good to see
you Jeff by the way long time no see
brother
yeah good to see you guys like how he
was gone for like eight months and then
he just pops right in he's just like
right into it like as if you were just
like there the whole time yeah I got a
question real quick that's great to see
you man yeah that's awesome
I would left the room I came back I
could hear his voice I was like Oh
sounds like mr. Church is in the room
well thanks for continuing to extend the
invite I you know I have family and so
Sunday's is a sacred day for the family
so it just happens to be that I had a
little bit of time today so it's a
church kind of day yeah yeah okay choice
on church yeah so how the hell have you
been
you get here now you're doing co2 like
you're doing a high terpene co2 yeah
yeah so we've been doing some really
high trip in co2 Rossi Oh - so there's
no winterization that's involved in the
process using really really high quality
material you don't have all of the
lipids that are extracted I mean there's
still lipids don't get me wrong but it's
it's really you know a high terpene
content just really liquid extract that
we're able to put right into a vape cart
and and go with it so you know really
really been blessed with with the
ability to work with puffin farm up here
in Washington State in the legal market
and you know just just been enjoying
I'll be a clean green sir
five material that they're able to
provide so your process is solving less
than because you're not winterizing know
well it's it's a solvent because co2 is
a solvent a lot of people say you know
non solvent because it's a totally
different class but yeah it's it's
definitely solvent extraction using a
you know even Labs extractors which is
what I'm using okay yeah but you know I
mean using co2 you don't test positive
for residuals on anything to you well
I'm not putting any solvents in there
and and two off gases as soon as it gets
to back to the you know regular
atmosphere so there's no co2 residual in
there you know at least not after 24
hours everything is off gassed out of
there but but yeah no secondary solvents
at all so yeah so that's what I always
try to tell people winter so there's a
that fine line when supposed to go to
co2 extractors its solvent listen like
well it only be solvent lists and then I
can under you know we can argue the
definition the solvent but in the end in
the end here ultimately what we're
putting in our lungs doesn't contain any
footprint from a solvent if you're not
winterizing with alcohol we're a lot of
co2 companies winterize with alcohol
grain alcohol then they have to put it
in a rotor vac and they have to distill
it out and there's always like that some
small percentage of alcohol weight so in
my mind what you're doing you know is a
very clean version of the co2 it's a
solvent free I would say that because
solvents left in in the extract
afterwards yeah it's a gas that's turned
into a liquid then back into a gas it's
a the extraction is actually done in a
super critical pressure yeah I'm down
with that
with the cannabinoid concentration in
your extract it varies between the high
40s and the low 60s
so it's suffice to say there is a fair
amount of lipids in there well yeah
there's also a large amount of other
constituents as well like Turkey
like we've gotten up to 26% so that's
taking a huge bite out of what you know
out of that that would be an 86% oil if
you test 60 and 20 see exactly and then
there's the flavonoids the other
constituents that are extractable under
co2 supercritical so then unfortunately
we're not testing or at the moment I
wish that I could get an NMR done on all
of my extracts so that I could really
know what was in there but unfortunately
it's just not not viable at the moment
in our industry I would love to send you
a blank kit for you to try the reusable
Trinity tanks because I think you would
like them oh yes specifically with the
oil that you just described if you put
your address in the little chat not in
the youtube one send me it there I'll
send you one because I texted over to
you I got your number as long as hasn't
changed yeah it texts me over because
I'll just be curious to see what your
what your high chirping co2 raw would be
like in one of these yeah all kinds of
different oil in it you know everybody's
oil just to see yeah I'd better be
spectacular I tried some there were some
holy water like the newer version
obviously like the solvent free holy
water then I had had some distillate
some cold drop distillate in Terps it's
pretty good I find it like it's it's
better suited for a little bit thicker
oil you know it's better suited for what
you're talking about
like it's good for rosin hash rods in
which are peens
it's good for like an oil that's a
little bit thicker it works fine with
the thinner ones but I think you would
find it yeah this co2 is it has like a
thickness that happens when it kind of
coagulates and sits there but the moment
that you move it in the vial or in you
know it just turns right to a liquid
without even any heat so you can
literally drip it out of the syringes
which is yeah that's kind of like what I
noticed exactly the same thing so like
this is this is a once you hit like 15
percent I mean if I took this off I'll
show you same thing it just drips
I mean it literally just like like
dreads
yeah yep exactly that's the same
viscosity is what we're dealing with up
here for sure the tank you're gonna love
the tank that is that is designed for
excellent well I'm glad to glad to try
it out and I'll let you know how it
works out yep I'm getting ready to put a
whole bunch of them and wash them in ice
so I'm gonna try that dark thing you
said Marcus the I'm gonna try one of the
tanks in the dark clear Oh in the DC
yeah why not yeah of course I'm gonna
I'm about to clean some of the near
future here as well my two are just done
so I will be cleaning some and hopefully
making a video I am at the 3-hour point
I promised my family I would go hang out
with my little guy it's his birthday
number three number three birthday so I
would like to say thank you to everyone
for showing up from forests to Etienne
to skunk man Sam - Wade - Jeff church to
the Dragonfly medicine crew - Marcie
aldohn the D&amp;D 420k who came and left
and everyone watching thanks so much for
you know coming and sharing your time
with us we'll be back next week and just
yeah three episodes left til 156 our
three-year anniversary so thanks for
watching everybody peace out
[Music]