yeah okay yeah I guess it went live on
the other page so I'm still learning
welcome everybody a hash Church
5.0 episode
2 just going through the logistics of
trying to get it all to work here we're
live in the other room so people are
starting to come over now oh we got Wade
waiting to get in there we got Wade and
skunkman Sam in the rumor right now
that's awesome couple of
Elders all right I think uh that is all
there we go beautiful welcome Wade
welcome
skunkman here's to another episode of
hash
Church howdy Wade missed you last
week indeede indeede
yeah Sam was uh Sam missed us last week
he was ready but he wasn't ready he was
he just you know sometimes it happens
like that with uh with hash
Church well started 81 seconds ago we
already got 53 people in the room cool
very
cool what's that Sam no that was uh me
playing what you said on
TV I I see I see
well I'd like to watch it on TV because
it's
bigger oh yeah yeah of course for sure I
got a nice pretty big screen there's
Wade got the cover alls on I like
it that is what's up hopefully we're
having a good Sunday today here it was
uh pretty stormy here last night it was
a beautiful day probably like 85 degrees
Fahrenheit all day sunny no clouds and
then last night it was like just wind
and not so much rain but there is a lot
of cleanup to do on the uh on the
property for
sure big time how about you guys pretty
uneventful evening Saturday
night uh not too much
happening I was pretty chill myself I
hung out with my little guy Tanner who's
going to be turning 10 years old in a
few days and uh I'm taking him to his
first concert in two days to Michael
frany and spearhead I love Michael frany
because he does all ages show so it's uh
he's pretty excited about it not going
to
lie oh hey
rackam we will have well Dr Mark just
came in we got skunkman Sam we got Wade
I invited Colin from vessel Life
Sciences he was just visiting his father
in the in the hospital so he'll be here
a little bit late Thomas from
Grandmaster LED will be in about 10
minutes late as well and then uh you
know I I didn't hear from Dr Mark Lewis
or Alec Dixon from SC Labs or Nick
Zigler uh but I also put the invitation
out to those guys I invited Mojave again
if he was able to make it so just kind
of loose whoever's able to make it we'll
have our little
conversation and uh spend a couple hours
together uh for hash Church welcome Dr
Mark Marcus how are you hey Sam missed
you last
week I'm doing
fine yeah you look the
same yeah he still got
his all of us other people are our our
yellow hairs are turning white gray hey
Wade how are
you I'm good Mark nice to see you really
nice to be here
I uh I spent uh yesterday Monica and I
made a big exibition and went down to
the Bay Area for the emerald cup they're
uh still trying to still doing that and
um boy the California Market the
business side of it has FY Bare Bones at
this point um it was lovely to see a
bunch of people that I knew a bunch of
people stopped
by um
but yeah lots and lots of people are
realizing that the California Market as
it's currently structured is a disaster
and are dropping out of it and it's kind
of a shame to see some of the Legacy
operators that I know who are
extraordinary cultivators and uh richly
compassionate medicine makers that
really just there's no way in the
business world to make it in California
right now without L Comm unless you're
willing to stretch the rules or ignore
them and that's a whole different
conversation anyway it was a really
lovely day for me um took a lot out of
me I'm pretty exhausted today but I'm
really looking forward to our
conversation and uh some of the
brilliant people who show up here my
thank you
again yeah well shout out to Tim Blake
for 20 plus years now of the emerald cup
I was thinking about that the other day
he must have started that just right
around when we started uh Legends of
hash Sam because it's been 20 to 21
years of Legends of hash as well so kind
of neat that those two I think the first
year Legends of hash was 2003 is that
correct when we had the
balloons I don't know if it was I don't
know if the balloon was the first year
it's so hard to remember [ __ ] as you get
older but I do definitely remember the
balloon year I wasn't there the balloon
year so I think that was a couple years
later but I think you're right in the
sense that the first one we did was
either an 02 or 03 which would put us
around 21 22 years uh of of doing them I
I saved an extra balloon if you need
one nice yeah I never I never got a
balloon that was a neat kind of way to
get a ticket to just someone's like
let's just put the ticket on the balloon
if you have the balloon you can come in
and if you don't have the balloon well
I'm sure would probably still let you in
but uh yeah crazy
crazy times yeah yeah yeah see what's
going on here just checking out the chat
room we got 132 people watching we had
up to about 220 live last week usually
around 10 o'clock when people are
getting up but we got John Maddox who's
always in the chat room big huge
supporter rackams rosin is in the chat
room right now we got keep it simple 420
for those of you that were wondering
about the German numbers we were
discussing last week uh keep it simple
actually put it in the comment section
in regards to how many members you can
have how much you can grow the sort of
breakdown for that uh German uh model
that they're doing similar to Spain I
guess um so that was nice of him to put
in there got Cody Packer OG brick
420 Al
telescope Uranus geez I don't know about
that but TK Brewers in the house and uh
yeah just a ton of cool people it's
growing as we speak and yeah we'll have
a few more people joining us here in a
little bit in the meantime I think it
might be time for a little rip out of
the
ca loving this little guy unfortunately
my puff Coes oh no actually I wonder if
it started working I think it
did I I was trying to hit my puffco the
other day and it was doing the red light
thing where it wasn't heating up and uh
always nerve-wracking when your little
electric devices stop working but oh
there we go oh wow you got the base and
everything
Sam let's do it let's have a little
rip get the uh dialogue going no uh no
fish for you Dr Mark or don't they have
some huge [ __ ] Festival going on
right now I've been seeing little Clips
on my
Twitter yeah yeah wow yeah they they are
having a Festival down in right
now crazy I saw the secret set and it
looked like it was at the sphere or
something like they really stepped it up
with those visuals I can't but help the
the work they did at the sphere sphere
must have helped Inspire that you think
sure yeah I mean it looked really crazy
it's up on
YouTube so you could see it yeah I saw
saw some clips yeah pretty pretty
amazing pretty amazing for sure I know I
saw the interview with Trey when he was
talking about the sphere shows that they
were going to do and how serious they
were taking it and how they were like no
one is ever going to see anything like
this everything was unique and dead has
dead and Co had a pretty incredible show
it's the same Graphics every night fish
went out on a limb and we're like we're
going to just do new graphics every
minute of every night which is sounds
sounds about right fish yeah I mean it's
pretty it's pretty incredible stuff to
behold even all the dead company stuff
you know
imagery you know they show like
neighborhoods San Francisco and you know
venues where they've
played dude the neb the neighborhood in
San Francisco with the Drone where it
all lifts up and they go up that was
absolutely incredible I of course did
not make it to the sphere for any of the
shows but I've had many of friends go my
friend Allison has been to I even know
how many of the shows so she sends me
little videos and stuff where I get to
live vicariously through her I'm sure
you saw that uh guy who posted his bong
hit that he took on Instagram right and
then uh the
uh the people who run the sphere the
same people who run Madison Square
Garden right the DOL family and um they
use facial recognition software as it
turns out you know so when you go to
Madison Square Garden you go to any of
their venues they'll
actually use facial recognition to say
hey was this guy ever a problem at a
previous event because if so they'll
pull you out of line but uh yeah so he
he originally I think he got banned from
those venues but then there was such a
public outlash of support for
him the bong rip dude yeah you got to
think a lot of bad [ __ ] happens concerts
you know there's some aggressive people
and this that and the other thing but
taking a bong rep at a concert would be
uh especially one like like fish at the
sphere where like bong rips have been
involved in the creation of the entire
the music the visuals probably the
building of the sphere um I would I
think bong rips were present all the way
through and so what a silly thing to
kind of you know what the whole I was
just going to say they have they have a
pretty strict policy just on those
smoking in general I think that's try to
keep tobacco and all that kind of stuff
out but you know people are still
hitting vape pens but I guess the point
of having actually fire and combustion
inside an event where you have some big
glass bong it's kind of like okay you're
already you snuck the bong in you're
smoking you're recording it you're
putting it up to the internet I mean how
are you not going to get in trouble
trouble I still support it civil
disobedience man just like uh Wade was
saying earlier with the disaster that is
the California legal cannabis scene
unless you're willing to stretch Or
Break The Rules which is like wow isn't
that how we got the rules in the first
place I mean I know it is here in Canada
for sure we just like Civil Disobedience
all day long took them to court one
gained this whole scene and now all the
people that are involved in it because
they have like licenses that they're
trying to protect are terrified to step
out of line and do you know practice any
more Civil Disobedience so it's kind of
uh kind of a weird little corner we've
painted ourselves into with these uh
with these with this legal LIC last week
I went to see berning spear at the
Paradiso and uh sure enough you cannot
smoke inside the
building oh my my God no puffing at
Burning Spirit the Paradiso next it'll
be like we really don't want you dancing
like if you could just take your you
know just just don't dance please no
dancing no puffing uh no enjoying
yourself it's a reggae concert actually
we're gonna have to puff and we're gonna
have to dance Bernie spear must be like
close to 80 years old now am I correct
[ __ ] he's [ __ ] old and he's
[ __ ] great I mean he's yeah dude
quite amazing
that's awesome that is so good to hear I
saw the videos uh that your wife put up
some of the video and some of the stuff
and he he looked like he did like 30
years ago he's just super active he's
just like you know he's got that I don't
know what it is but uh another guy
Jamaican that has that is KS ey who's
also got to be approaching 80 now in his
70s I got to hang out with them quite a
bit and I've just I've never seen like a
stronger 70 like just inspir in the
sense of how strong he was and how you
know one night we were walking in
Kingston and in the city and there was
this sort of I don't know like a three
or a four foot ledge and I you know I
was just like I'm going to jump onto
this ledge and we're just walk in me and
ktis and some other people and I I jump
up onto this ledge
and I look behind me and and ktis is
jumping onto the ledge well his foot
slips off the ledge he
[ __ ] Falls so hard smashes himself so
bad like I I was just like oh my God
like he's going to be dead like he's
we're going to be going to the hospital
right now he shook that [ __ ] off came to
the concert with us that we were walking
to hung out and danced and puffed all
night and had like a little bump on his
forehead from where he smacked his head
when he fell but otherwise I was just
like Tony was actually there as well and
even Tony said I would have been in the
hospital for a month if because he was
behind ktis watching him fall and it was
just a it's truly a testament to the
strength of of of the Jamaican people
and how hard they work there's something
to be said for that and how active they
stay uh as they get older because holy
[ __ ] even if he did get all mashed up uh
he could have just uh joined Israel
vibrations oh
that's some low brow humor but you're
right I will be honest the first time
the first time I saw Israel Vibration
and I guess it was Scully and whis who
both had uh polio who have the canes I
believe Apple was the dude that did not
have it um and they came out and were
dancing on these canes it was pretty
inspirational to to see I I really was
blown away at
that oh Colin's just hitting me up like
crazy oh he says he's in the waiting
room that's weird um I don't see anyone
in the waiting
room huh I think he's in the waiting
room of a different room so let's see if
we can figure out sending him the link
to
this oh
goodness too much thinking too much
thinking
um someone else talk while I do some
work
hey Wade what's
up oh probably the most exciting thing
that's going on these days for me Sam is
uh I came across a paper that was
published in a journal called biofactors
I talked about it a little bit last week
specifically um a group of researchers
took three different multiple Myoma cell
lines and tested
the efficacy of minor phyto canono
against those multiple myom cell line
and the fascinating thing is it turns
out that
CBG as in George or Golf and CB in as in
Nancy are both remarkably effective at
suppressing the growth of multiple my at
least these three multiple my cells cell
lmes and um at the right though seems to
trigger cell death and it's always been
fascinating to me how is it I'm dealing
with cancer given the amount of cannabis
that I consume and I realized that at
least for one possibility is I don't
usually consume much cbv or
CBM in my cannabis so it's likely that
I'm missing out on that
opportunity and um I've since secured a
bunch of CBG oil comes in at about 52%
CBG and I'm working on sourcing some CBN
got a little bit of it delivered to me
yesterday at the emerald cup and uh per
Mark Sheldon suggestion last week I'm uh
working on
um finding some manufacturers who are
willing to do a special batch of oil for
me based on your recommendation much of
uh heat oxygen and
time that's all I got for the moment Sam
I'm I'm pretty excited about that I
would love to feel like I
can get on board with personal
experience
of handling and perhaps
even controlling the cancer that is
eating up my bones uh with the use of
cannabis I'm in canab Advocate and a
patient advant for hell going on 20 some
years
and uh yeah I would love to be able to
talk about my own personal example in
this realm anyways that's that's the
news from Nevada County California and
uh much love and really a to see you
toing welcome the
board well uh I wish all the best for I
wish all the best for you
also thank you Sam
that's that means a lot from you I care
a
lot you're welcome Colin thanks man
thanks for having me um great to be here
again with you all lovely to see Mark
and Wade awesome to see you and David
awesome to see cat and hat again and of
course Marcus um you know Wade the the
I've been dealing with a family member
who has Parkinson's and we're going
through the gamut of cannaboid therapy
and we have in the past call a decade um
we've been dealing with around 13 years
now um as a family and um I'm seeing a
lot of success with CBN for pain
management which is actually very
interesting to me um not so much with
sleep to be honest
um C what I found with CBN is it gets
you to sleep but doesn't help you stay
asleep so you need other constituents
and that was part of the work I did um
with tpine formulation to to have other
constituents help you stay asleep um so
I don't know if that's another Avenue
maybe Mark can speak on the chemistry of
that but um there's there's been um you
know I worked with a toxicologist um to
really better understand how our body's
interacting with with tpin and and the
the best way to approach it in terms of
percentage points um so there's a lot
more to be uncovered there but you know
that that was one thing that we I spent
the last call it 18 months just doing
that that type of work so it's um it's
been really eye openening to me I don't
know Mark if you've seen anything
that's you know compelling on your end
in terms of the chemistry of how these
constituents are coming together and and
how they interact with one another or
coexist together but well what what what
what I do know I think since the last
time we've talked about this on hash
Church anyway um is that there's now
published work uh in PE reviewed
journals on a double blind Placebo for
CBN and sleep it was always sort of
anecdotal and sort of suggested and I
think there was a a study a Japanese
study from like I don't want to say the
70s or the 80s where they were looking
at CBN
analoges and they looked in a sleep
model and that was always interpreted as
these things were you know had um
hologen
like chlorine and Florine and bromine
and stuff like that decorating the rings
of the molecules so these weren't
natural compounds at all but they just
looked at like how it it made these mice
behave in a sleep study but it wasn't a
so-called sleep study the the study that
just came out I think it was it came out
earlier this spring and um yeah the data
is pretty compelling I mean even at low
dose and you know I guess there is an
effect on CVN like you said of of CBD
and the other canono are in there and I
think if I remember the efficacy from
the study correctly it was you know that
were um full spectrum oils were were
more effective than the isolates on
their own and they just attribute that
to yeah there's there's just something
else in the mix that's making this stuff
work more effectively we don't really
understand what is but um but yeah it's
good to know that you know what was
always sort
of uh suspected anecdotally um that
there's now
published double
blind evidence to prove what we in the
Cannabis Community knew a long time ago
which is that cbn's good for
sleep yeah yeah it's it's also you know
I think there's more to be uncovered in
terms of the pain management aspect of
that compound I do feel like there's
some something there um based on not
just my own like I have two herniated
discs for instance I have one in my my
neck and then I have a a tear in my
thumb right when I take large amounts of
it my thumb feels
normal and I don't know if that's you
know in Mark you can dispel maybe that's
Placebo or maybe that's you know but I
do I do this is you know thousands of
times high dose of that same molecule
yeah I mean there's an anti-inflammatory
effect that's sort of peripheral yeah it
could just it could just be that kind of
like the way that you know if you feel a
headache coming on and you take some
ibuprofen and all of a sudden it's like
no more
headache um what it what's super
interesting here Colin is that there's a
company called inmed with is actually
taking CBN through I think phase three
clinical trials and I think I want to
say it's for Alzheimer but I don't know
maybe that's maybe that's another study
and it might be a different molecule
because they have a you know proprietary
code but I think it's CBN or a CBN
derivative and um yeah I mean could
these things actually be like the
Pharmaceuticals of the future you know
inspired by the molecules and the plant
that's that's kind of cool and being
able to have access to it like here's
Wade you know I need CBN and I needed
CBG that should just be a formula that
they should already have available for
you specifically for this treatment
dosed at the right level and the
products that you like th this is a
no-brainer I mean we already know that
these molecules are active and more
importantly they're safe right it's not
like you know you're going to die from
taking is a lot of these medications
that they use to treat disease are
themselves deadly and that's what you
end up dying from is the Toxic effect
from all these other things we know that
cannaboids aren't going to do that so
it's like there should actually be at
the pharmacy right now the 3 to one
tincture that Wade needs or whatever I'm
just making three to one up I don't know
what the right ratio is but he should be
able to say look these are both non-thc
canono I'm not taking this to get high
I'm not going to get behind the wheel
and crash my car I'm taking this to stay
alive
okay why is that not available right why
is there not Rel of why is that not Rel
of it's it's it's definitely stunted in
the sense that you would have thought 10
years ago when we were having this
conversation further down the line it
seems like medical was used as a shield
to protect a lot of um recreational
people because and and in their defense
like you're living in a country where
you are a pothead you always want to
have cannabis you love to smoke weed you
love to smoke cash you love to get high
you're going to um you know want to
protect yourself if some way of
protection comes up especially if you're
in a prohibitive country that's like you
could get years in prison or have like
your life destroyed and all you're like
well or you could go get a license yeah
this doctor will get you a license I
think it's like 50 bucks or 150 bucks
and suddenly everyone's got these
licenses it seemed innocent enough
although I will say it always left a
little bit of a bad taste in my mouth
from a patient perspective it's why with
hash church I always loved to Showcase
real patient perspectives and and you
know I always hear Sam's words as well
in the sense that it's all of value you
know someone who wants to get high
someone who wants to use cannabis as a
medicine like everyone should be allowed
to have that totally agreed at the same
time I do believe that patients should
probably take precedence and not line up
behind recreational users and so it is a
little bit hard that um yeah I mean here
in Canada this is exactly what happened
Shoppers Drug Mart all these big
companies got on they were like we're
going to get cannabis we're going to
dispense it because we are the people
who dispense medicine in Canada and
medical was this big thing people were
paying huge for their licenses and
Facilities
and the minute recreational came in the
door I would say 80 to 90% of the
companies just like dropped right out of
the medical
um uh regulated um scene and just popped
right into recreational and it was a lot
and to the point where even Shoppers
Drug Mart I mean that's part of lbls a
55 billion doll company they are not
doing cannabis in Canada anymore they're
just like why would we try and sell
because cannabis just it doesn't fit in
the way they want it to fit in you know
it's like well we want to control it and
sell it as a medicine it's like okay but
like eventually like we were talking
about last week it's probably going to
end up at gas stations you know maybe
it'll be that Delta 8 maybe it'll be
something different but people are
simple in their cannabis in the sense
that they want to get high and they want
it to be inexpensive and they want it to
be convenient and even my own mother who
was buying from Shoppers Drug Mark at
one point was just like this isn't they
they don't have the flavors they don't
have the the options for me and they run
out of what I do need and suddenly she
ended up you know going to you know
another sort of medical platform and
then I think eventually recreational so
it's a bit of a bummer for The Med
patients how the recreational um just
use them as a platform
to get to get to where where it is yeah
I think it's a good point you're
bringing up because you know here in the
States you know medical was applo to get
the recreational to then not have to pay
your doctor that you know let's not
blanket everyone you know pharmacologies
come a long way in terms of
understanding the plant and where things
are at but a lot of these people are
just here for a cash grab and that's
another problem right so I think there's
a dichotomy here that we have where we
have us on Legacy and Enthusiast slash
you know researchers slash you know
activists I I think you you don't you
don't a lot of these things don't get
Broad into the world of you
know of of called the corporate
corporate cannabis or regulations and as
regulations get instilled into these
these markets you know there's not
really a um a bunch of there's not a
group of of experts talking to the
constituents around them to say hey guys
these are the good rules and regs that
are going to allow this to work it's
it's very much they keep trying and
trying and trying I mean New York is a
great example of that um
you know there's there's a lot there's
so many examples of of of this and
medical for some reason is at the back
end of
recreational but that's what got us here
so I think it's it's really interesting
how we're you know I think about what
Sam did when he went to Europe to try to
figure out what his version of of all
this was you know I often think about
that and think about when you started
you and and Rob you know started your
your projects over there and in
Amsterdam we I actually moved over here
because I knew I could not continue in
California and the United States they
just were not g to let it happen it was
too early yeah so I I honestly like I
think it's weird to say this to you as
as we're on on this together but I think
about that a lot when I try to nav as we
navigate here in the states and navigate
even what's considered a mature you know
I don't even even want to call it a
market it's not even mature it's it's
very infant and we really don't no one's
got it right so we all have to come
together to better understand what the
right path is and when we're talking
about medical and Recreation it's often
so heavily weighed towards recreational
and I I start I go back to one thing and
I keep thinking about patient access and
I think that's the only real reason like
you don't have to go to a doctor to pay
him 100 bucks to say hey can I go get an
Aether herb like that's that sounds off
that's that was kind of my comment
earlier about pharmacology and
pharmacology yet yes there s it's it's
very important however those individuals
need to understand the plant and all the
constituents around it and what what
truly matters um and then help push that
forward you know maybe um ask better
questions or or your know problem solve
in new ways because as I look around the
you know where we've been and where
we're going there's just a glaring open
hole of confusion as to what is
Therapeutics you know I think we're
we're constantly talking about pop
culture within medicinal cannabis hand
over fist and it's almost to the point
where that's what runs you know every
single state you know so um I think
that's part of the problem is that we
don't really have constituents that are
fighting for medical they just fall into
this like generalized you know World um
so it's it's really interesting to me
because I you know I I'm you know have
this license in New York state and it's
the wreck license
but most of the individuals that I've
historically serviced have been medical
patients so you know it's really
interesting to me how this is all kind
of shifted um now do now Sam do you
think um when you went to Europe that
you know the idea of medical was the
only modality that was in front of you
or was it was there a glimpse of what
could come I could have worked on IND I
could have worked on Industrial Hemp but
you know there's not as much joy in that
um I I did work a little with Industrial
Hemp but it was always a medical
cannabis that allowed you to explore the
genetics The Inheritance the
cannabinoids the turbines and that was
my real real interest in this so uh yeah
I in America I just plain could not do
it even when I got here they appro
proved me but a lot of people in the
Ministry of Health said cannabis is not
a medicine it is a drug of abuse and uh
I said well at least you have an open
mind on the
subject holy [ __ ] that's frightening
that those you know it's not like it was
just some random sort of a little
ignorance group that was like well we're
afraid of this and then you could sit
down with them and be like no look it's
actually like a really good thing and
then they could be like oh my God look
at that it really is but they're not a
lot of the people on the other side of
this aren't like that here in Canada
Health Canada still does not acknowledge
that cannabis is has medical benefit and
they have like Health Canada that's like
our FDA they a legal medical platform
that Services Canadians and and yet they
all have come out and quoted not all
every single person that works there but
the the higher ups have come up multiple
times in quote
we don't believe there's any medical
value to cannabis we beat them in court
and we force their hands so anyone
that's worried about um Civil
Disobedience yes you can end up in court
but it can be some of the best courts
that you've ever ended up in especially
if the timing is right uh and it was
here in Canada for all of the people and
there's too many to name but obviously
John Conroy sort of leading the uh the
fight with so many wonderful people
behind them that it was uh I went to
some of those court cases and it was
unbelievable to see the unraveling of a
system that had been in play for so long
and then to hear like oh it's going to
descent it's like descent what's that
it's like well you know it goes to the
queen it goes to the royal family and
through this descent process it's like
wow like I'm Canadian I didn't even
realize just how deeply intertwined the
Commonwealth you know Canada is I mean
obviously she's on our m
but uh it's beyond intertwin they make
decisions in in in London for if
something's going to become legal as a
medicine in Canada Canada was just at
the breaking point there was no way
anyone was going to put it back in the
box and now after so many years I see oh
they didn't need to put it in the Box
they had this other plan where they
would just be like well we'll just bring
out recreational and then we'll just uh
you know make sure that they can have
the worst packaging you know like this
these are two totally different products
in the Canadian Market you know this is
the the US version of this is it and so
it's like just a much nicer packaging
and you can't have any packaging here
you can't have any anything that really
makes you look too too different a lot
of it is just so similar and even myself
as a head I'll walk into one of these
shops and I have a hard time like my
brain doesn't want to connect that this
myar bag is gummies and this myar bag is
traditional hash and this myar bag is
you know some bubble hash or whatever
it's just like come on man we could do
this so good if you let
us yeah I think it's it's it's
interesting you say that because there
you know Connecticut was a market that
kind of took that stance in the United
States there's a couple others that did
that Pennsylvania tried to and then it
kind of fell apart New York took took
the stance and then it just exploded but
you know to your point yeah we can do a
lot better you know there's there's not
only from a preservation P perspective
for the for the actual material because
you know chemistry is happening is until
you use it um and you know it it's not
just that but also like these single use
cpgs you know we've fallen into the cpg
world for a product that is just so
heavily guarded like you know I talked
to you even people that can't open the
child say this ripped the package and
it's just trash you know like there's
it's literally you know what I mean so
it's it's really um you know it it's an
opportunity I think for designers and
young designers and young engineer
designers to come and make really
interesting you know artwork and
packaging that other other people can
grab on to and use at scale um you know
sustainability is a big driving force
behind a lot of what I see around what
we need but there's really no perfect um
you know material because plastic so
it's so woven into the world right like
it's oil is just it's just the backbone
so we got to get away from that and then
someone has to engineer a
cpg CR top that that doesn't utilize
plastic you know and that's I think
that's our biggest as a
material um you know what my partners do
Colin and and see here my partners Ted
and Andy they're cpg manufacturers from
China so that's kind of what they do
they build machines and they're they're
really good at it they've been helping
us uh do a bunch of different projects
and uh so they've got this machine and
it's the old it's the old tuna cans but
they have a ceramic but but it's ceramic
on the inside of the can so it's not
even really it's not touching metal but
they have this crazy machine that seals
these cans up and they're all ceramic on
the inside it's pretty wild to witness
this thing going just for me I mean I
don't know how many of you ever saw weed
in the tuna can I thought it was pretty
standard there's always one group that
was doing it in in some Market but here
in BC back in they used to have the the
tuna can and they the the flower was
called the tuna that went into it and so
it was like easy to ship moved around
real good preserved it really nice you
could crack the top and then obviously
you would end up having like a plastic
top after that if you wanted to make it
reusable but kind of a cool concept
probably could do a silicone top at this
point in time but yeah not so easy to
escape plastic these days a lot of
people are wearing it on their bodies
like all of those Lululemon pants and
all of those yoga pants that's all like
forever chemicals leeching into your
body through basically like synthetic
woven
materials yeah no it's well said man
because it's I've been going through it
myself like you know I've been working
on packaging and it's there's just not a
lot of great Solutions you have to
either spend a lot of money on it or to
be willing to get in line and just do
whatever even these like I have these
jars here which are the pop packs right
some blueberry banana in here and
there's just you know this is a plastic
top with a metal piece here sure it
sucks the air out of it and it keeps it
preserved but you know this this at the
heart of everything this is glass with
I'd say 70% of materials that are going
to break down over a long set point so I
think that's a it's an opportunity I
think for everyone around us to to think
about that you know because every single
time someone you know like blast through
these jars like nothing you know boxes
full of empty jars so you know I think
the biggest problem we have is that and
then you know Mark I wanted to ask you
this I've been looking at asilis um
quite a lot and I was starting to look
at tobacco not to change subjects here
too much and I was
wondering there's no evidence whatsoever
in tobacco that those dried leaves have
been tested for
asellus
so in your opinion or anyone's opinion
here has anyone ever looked at this
because I'm starting to look at it
because I'm starting to ask questions
why are we held to such a
flame if things around us this or not
and what are we doing to better
understand it and the actual
constituents that are harmful versus
this blanketed statement that it's all
harmful and what are your thoughts on
that because I I
feel I feel like certain markets are
being suppressed of great material based
on unknowns that aren't
defined in
testing yeah I mean uh so the question
is what like um is tobacco tested for
for asilis and yeah and yeah can it
succumb I I think it can't there's so
there is uh uh fungicides that are
used uh to
treat fungus on on
Tobacco and it's you know again super
interesting to think about you know what
was required for that company to be able
to register products to be able to be
applied to Tobacco right because
supposedly you have to show you know low
environmental impact at the use rates
you have to show you know safety in all
kinds of studies including you know
again just
efficacy safety uh studies on all the
metabolites but it's just really
difficult I guess to think about doing
that for cannabis because they'd have to
show all that
data um on cannabis which is schedule
one right and so how do
you yeah so it's not a Level Playing
Field and tobacco in and of itself so
the the nicotinamides and all those
things those things are potent
insecticides as they are in fact yeah I
mean a
homemade uh you know little recipe to
control flying insects on the farm was
always just take a little bit of chewing
tobacco soak it in water and then use
that to spray down dumpsters and [ __ ]
like that where you have flies in the
summertime but you know at the end of
the day col it's like a whole different
thing because as Marcus will tell you
there's 10 other things in cigarettes
that'll kill you it's like how do you
determine whether or not the the the
application of a fungicide or any kind
of pesticide to the crop has some impact
on human safety when the product itself
is deadly it's right so think I I think
I think it's easy to know that radium
226 is very very dangerous I've been
talking about it for 30 plus years in
the production of
tobacco and just but it goes down really
smooth yeah it goes down really smooth
all right while it's mutating all your
DNA um no it's on health Canada's
website they actually have radium 226
they have the breakdown of polonium 210
and Lead 210 which are kind of two of
the many thousands of different things
that are created when you burn it and
they talk about that they are
radioactive nucleotides and that they
mutate DNA and I I just couldn't believe
that they actually have that on a health
Canada website because for the last 3
year David Malmo LaVine has written
extensive articles on the use of radium
226 uh in the production of tobacco and
how how very very very bad it is you
know just if you were if you had to get
rid of one that would be a good
one yeah that would be a really good one
you know the reason I bring it up Marcus
and and Mark and everyone else is it's
it's really I feel like there's a lot of
um you know terraa is a is a product out
that people have used it's um it's a a
bacteria that that eats the the asilis
appar Apparently and I don't know enough
about it I've never used the product
although we've spoken to four or five uh
Farmers that have sworn by this product
and said that this is what works for
them um I just I'm weary of products you
know I'm weary of the idea of this
product works Tira Vera right it's a
fungus what is it apparent I don't I
think we should do some research before
I blurred out what it is because I don't
exactly know what it's made of but we'
spoken to a bunch of a bunch of Growers
that are in New York and other states
that have been growing outdoors and they
swear by this product um they say that
they're able to pass um they ask
the the labs to Plate their material
rather than just run based you know the
the the the normal way that they run the
the samples so um I'm not
sure you know over I'm not what I'm
after is everyone's opinion on this
product and and
what what do we you know how do we
approach this and as we move forward
because this is not help me understand
for a second so it's like a nutrient
it's not is it a soil or what what
exactly is it it's a spray apparently
you spray on the plant and it's like a
it's a folar spray and you spray it you
know I think it's a you put it a part of
your IPM management and you know as a
hash maker I'm extremely weird of anyone
that tells me that they're like yeah you
know we get in there and put this on our
stuff you know it's going to come out
fantastic the resin's going to be great
because usually the resin is not great
and it's it's contaminated and nasty so
um it's a you know it's something I
think for just the general conversation
to kind of research and look into but I
do think it's a it's an ongoing problem
that is
just everyone I speak to in Oregon is is
dealing with with this everyone I speak
to on the east coast is dealing with
this um and it's not going away um so I
think we just need to problem solve and
start talking to each other about what
the solutions are if there are any is it
genetics do we need to start looking at
certain pools is it this product that
I'm mentioning um or is it something
else um how do we or is it testing do we
need to go back yeah let's let's go
there for a second so like like the way
that they're t now which is for PCR
right they're just basically finding
finding the DNA right and that doesn't
tell you that that the fungus is alive
and well and I remember I think this was
maybe 2019 or maybe 2020 right before
the pandemic we were looking at all of
these failures for aspergilus they were
all hemp crops and all of them were
actually grown uh organically and some
of them on Amish farms in the New York
Pennsylvania Maryland
area and I could tell you the the
material itself looked proper but we
wondered again or like oh look at these
hits for Asis what does actually this
mean you know and it's like yeah it's
after the fact it doesn't actually mean
that aspergillis is alive it just meant
at some point in time during that plant
sample life
Aspirus live there um it's you know I
don't know like how much is that's what
I'm getting at that that you know that
we need to better understand better
understand and Define at what point is
it harmful and is it harmful because
yeah I get on on there's certain
patients or certain consumers that have
you know autoimmune disease so they're
at risk right but have we actually
proven that they are at risk and why are
we taking whole lots of of material and
saying yo this isn't fit for human
consumption based on this small window
of information that we quite frankly
don't understand right and like that's
what I'm kind of asking is like well is
there a better
way I think there has to be a better way
is what I'm getting at I know that
there's got to be some people together
that can figure out the the right rules
and rags and then on top of that the
right protocols and right IPM to man
manage the plants and the the
cultivation aspect because all of it has
to work together you got to remember
that aspergillis is found in the
air right everywhere worldwide and uh so
you know if you're growing Outdoors
you're go if they can't find a sporx
regillus on your plants it's probably
because they haven't looked hard enough
they're Airborne they're everywhere
right so for me it just begs the
question are we going too far on the
parts for million are we because like
all right let's let's bring it real back
outside the industry we've all been
growing before any of the these these
data points right any of this under what
we understood right so I know I've
smoked moldy cannabis in my time I know
all of us have right we we seem to be
okay um sure there's a threshold whether
or not it's you know healthy or not we
understand you're not supposed to do
that but there is a small window and a
possibility that at certain times you're
ingesting it so what if that's the
narrative or the the you know the theme
here in at what
point what is the parts per million you
know because I think about this a lot
because there's huge lots of material
that you just can't work with because
it's just it's failed you know so um and
then it has to go through this
remediation process and then I wonder if
that remediation radiation process which
then goes back into someone's body how
does that you know what I'm saying like
we're we're going through radiation and
then we have dead we have dead material
now sitting on organic
material so I'm just I'm just kind of
drum up the the thought process from
Mark and others that you know we're
we've got we've gotten ourselves into
sort of this weird dichotomy where we're
like well let's kill it but then okay
you can actually smoke it because it's
dead now you know and but we're ruining
the material and the experience for the
consumer and then all of a sudden people
think this is what cannabis is right so
it just it's kind of it's nuts you know
what I mean so I just wanted to bring
that up because it's something we're all
dealing with right now
today and you know we know that's not
what good herb is well we live in a
microbial world and ra actually without
microbes I don't think the plant would
exist as we know it today right because
the plant the plant doesn't fix nitrogen
right but the microbes in the soil do
and it needs nitrogen for amino acids
and proteins and you know those enzymes
all those
syntheses those are made of you know
nitrogen and amino acids but to go back
to something you were saying earlier I
mean it's like kind of like have we gone
too far well um just in terms of like
analytical instrumentation yeah I mean
we have the ability to see down to the
part per trillion level is amazing if
you think about it I mean this is like
Space Age kind of Technology but you
know if you're applying that to to
cannabis or any you know agriculturally
produced product you're going to find
all kinds of [ __ ] in there just because
it's in there doesn't mean it's
dangerous at the level that it's in
there and um yeah like we were looking
uh Richard Rose uh couple weeks ago made
reference to something that was posted
on LinkedIn about a
Japanese um uh referendum that they were
trying to push forward where they were
going to legalize CBD but it had to be
able to be shown to be Point let me get
this right
o one two three four
1% or less
THC so a couple analytical chemists you
know we're like looking at this going my
God so something that's
Point okay let me count one two three 02
would fail or even three or four zeros
0.002 would fail so it's like how are
you GNA
distinguish between something that's you
know just a hair over such a it's like
in the noise of the data it's ridiculous
it's it's it it you basically you can't
do it but you know like in prob bition I
I don't know if it's I don't know Sam
what do you think man like you know even
like like when
michul analytical data like most like
what he was doing is he was looking at
the different compounds that were in the
plant he was able to look down at say
0.01 percent but to be able to get down
to
0.001% is not only an analytical
challenge it's just it's ridiculous to
think that you'd be able to commercially
like test at that level and be able to
determine a winner from a loser Dre
dread dread is in the uh chat right now
he grew for DNA for years and is a
really exceptional indoor grower he's
saying that in Illinois right now the
the cfu limits are
1,000 and so to give you an idea
Michigan is
100,000 for the same test so
everything's failing in Illinois and
then get cooked like radiated or you
know whatever the process is I guess
there's a couple of different processes
for um cleaning out to these
fails it's shocking one really red is a
good
dra um so yo that that's also the
interesting thing I think about the
markets were that we are in in the
states is that you know a lot of us
moved around from Market to Market and
seen the shift in the requirements that
they ask of us and you know like I
learned in mass that it was nearly
impossible to do a certain style of
growing that I wanted to do just based
on the rules and Rigs and then you have
to rejig what you once thought was the
way and you have to adapt and that's
it's really tough to deal with that
because it's not smoke sense makes it
smoke sensense makes a good point in the
chat col and he saying how does the
tobacco industry deal with aspergillis
because that's where the msos are
probably going to look for ways to
mitigate aspergillis
unfortunately pay off the politicians
dude they apply a fungicide they they
apply this stuff called manm and a a few
other Pro there are a few products that
are ETA registered that they can
apply uh to control fungus but I'll tell
you what I don't know if if anyone has
ever been to like a tobacco farm when
they hang that tobacco
in the in the Barns and they hang it in
these barns that actually have wings
that can fold out so like could they
could let air in there my God if you
walk up to the edge of that Barn it is
intoxicating the air that's in there oh
my God like it's if you're a non-tobacco
user non-cigarette smoker you could
seriously you could faint just from the
the effl coming from a tobacco farm it's
toxic so Ryan Ryan craer yeah massed is
weird I've I've actually yet to find
jarble flour in the state that that
smokes with any flavor it's really tough
um it's really insane because you would
think our friend Greg is working for um
for Mass Provisions there aren't they
growing good weed where Greg's at
sometimes I think I think scale is hard
you know even with the best people at
the at scale because it once it leaves
your hands another department takes it
and that department you maybe talk to in
the hallway but you're not running that
team right and then it goes to a trim
team and that trim team does a thing and
then it goes to a bin and then it's like
below the wind it's really hard I think
listen I think no matter where you are
and my just my just talking personal
experience it really it's everyone has
to synergistically be working together
and really want that same goal to have
that make it make sense and it's as I've
gotten in bigger and bigger and bigger
scenarios it just it it falls the black
after certain you know at certain scale
because it's hard to keep everybody you
know chasing the same Dragon you know
like everyone chasing that quality and
like like wanting that the best is you
know it's it's hard man you know I wish
I wish I could say that that it was
easier but but I do think that there
Greg's growing some phenomenal weed over
there I I will I will give him props big
time because he's one of the that's Meg
Sanders who I know from 10 years ago
used to do the mindful which was the um
the grow right across the street from
the Denver Police Station it was always
great to see the Denver Police Station
this huge three-story building with all
these cop cars and it just stunk like
weed there like there was no tomorrow
and their grower there was Philip tiar
Rojo uh who I don't know where he is
these days but uh that's where K bill
and the K Bill crew was first making
live resin yeah about 10 years ago if I
remember
correctly yeah that's Brewer um yeah I
think you know BK Brewer is commenting
on Smash Hits he saying he didn't have a
great experience but I think you know
like I've had I I've had good experience
with his chem 4
um his chem DS1 that he ran over there
was really
good um but I haven't really paid
attention so much but there's some great
growers in the state and I don't I think
again it's just hard to hit every batch
every time um so I commend everyone when
they can do that well you know it's a
tough one but uh but there's some you
know I think there's some amazing
Growers on the East Coast that are um
you know coming back home from the West
Coast you know so it's uh
it's good to see it time in time we'll
see we'll see better and
better so yeah we got
some I think it's coming I think we're
in a big shift right now I think
there's I think there's a big shift
happening I think there's going to be
it's going to take a little time but I
think you
know I'm building a grow right now I
know others are building grows that are
meant to crank out quality herb you know
I think it'll happen it's just it's just
time right now we gotta we got to be
patient um and it's never been easier to
grow your own herb that's the other
thing I say to everybody out here is
it's literally never been easier I mean
I used to be on the forums trying to
trade clones just to get something worth
growing now you could just go buy a pack
of seeds
and within those 10 seeds or even six
seeds you'll find something amazing so I
think that's you know bring it back to
yourself I think that's where I
encourage everyone to go and same with
you know grow it wash it you know learn
about it I think that's the other
narrative that you know everyone's
looking for someone to just like sell
them good herb well it's not that
difficult to grow your own good herb if
you just spend a little time you know
get some good lights like the LED uh
Grandmaster LED you know those guys make
some of the best elights I've ever seen
get one of those get some HPS if you're
a traditionalist
you know dude the the Borg that I have
does the HPS
Spectrum there you go and and it's an
LED light it's pretty wild there's 500
spectrums in it it's actually Beyond too
much many many many many many people
need to get these lights because the
data points are going to come from all
the people who use it totally you know
PK Brewer how can you understand yeah no
I think that's the most important thing
to get across with LEDs right now it's
like most people are like oh LEDs aren't
don't aren't as good well I don't know I
think it's really about you can't just
expect you to change your lighting
spectrum and then not change your
nutrient and your regiments and things
that go along with that and expect it
all to be the same you have to kind of
take a look at you know the the lights
and then there's certain things that you
might need to do differently such as
feeding um or temperatures might need to
be different U or humidity might need to
be different due to the Spectrum so that
that's one of the biggest learning
curves that we went through when we were
switching from HPS to LED and then doing
ultimately running rooms that were both
um one was HPS one was led and just kind
of pitting it against each other for
data points and trying to learn what
varietals responded best to what
spectrums that's that was the whole I
spent three years trying to figure that
out and that's one thing that I
encourage everyone to do is don't just
listen to what everyone says try it for
yourself and see what works for you
because you you might be holding a
varial that for whatever reason might
respond in a way that that what
everything in my stable doesn't you know
so I think it's really important to to
not be so rigid about um what you're
told um go and try it um you know break
stuff and then try again
um so but uh yeah I mean you know New
York someone said in the chat New York
there's a bunch of hemp Growers yeah
they they were a bunch of hemp Growers
but I think you have to understand that
New York if we had just allowed it to
kind of go with just the r yeah it
probably would have had some some
structure there that that uh that would
have you know allowed things to be a bit
bit smoother but I honestly don't
believe that anyone would even have an
opportunity other than them so those
that are in the chat talking about that
just remind yourself that New York is
filled with the big of the biggest
capitalists so you got to got to
understand that it's uh it's only going
to get more and more uh more
crazy but uh but you know keep in mind
we you know it's going to shape up to be
a great a great Market I I was looking
for this this um picture that I think it
was muton muffin mittens or Mitten
muffins I can't remember his name uh he
was growing with the Borg and he just
used different
spectrums and it was the same cut in the
same room with all being fed the same
[ __ ] and this is what they looked
like that's the same
cut in in in different uh different
Spectrum
right yeah in the same room yeah yeah
it's it's exactly this is exactly what
we exactly what I was talking about kind
of blew my mind man like you could play
around and really get the plant to
express itself I mean first of all 500
spectrums I'm not sure what Thomas was
thinking that is so absolutely insane
but it's nice to be able to play around
and have that sort of flexibility in
your own little tent or or grow where
you just I think it's a great idea from
an R&amp;D standpoint even at the most basic
basic like in Canada for instance if you
grow a cultivar that's under
20% um it it you'll have a hard time
selling it so if you had a cultivar that
came out in like 17 or 18% it's very
likely that you could play around with
the Spectrum in an R&amp;D room and bump
that up to like that 20% now that's a
very basic sort of story um but when you
get into the actual volatile organic
compounds and the flavor profiles and
the different ratios of those flavor
profiles then it becomes
like you know incredibly interesting and
a very unique rabbit hole to go down in
the sense of like yeah I'm going to I'm
going to play with these spectrums and
and it's not like you're just going to
grow one spectrum light right like in
the in the early part of your crop
you'll have a lot of blue to keep it
from stretching now if you have say a
part of your crop that maybe it gets
[ __ ] up in some way it gets affected
there's always you know it's great to
have an even canopy but sometimes you
don't have an even canopy and you've got
that little dip and now you can bring in
that 730 far red and just turn it on in
that section and get those plants to
stretch up a little bit and catch up to
the rest of the canopy you could use
that HPS Spectrum throughout the middle
of the grow you could there's just so
many different endless things that you
could do when you have even just 10 or
20 spectrums let alone I mean 500 just
makes it
like an impossible Road for one person
to deal with it's going to be like a 100
thousand people that figure out those
data points yeah we I mean we saw um I
mean I saw a lot of different canono
spikes in terms of just the spread on
testing like high numbers of
thcv um upwards to 6% it was nuts like
you know the LEDs produced we had a run
that was like CBG was like
3.7% with um thcv in the 6.8% range and
then when I made a vape card out of it
it was in the the thcv popped at like
12112 or something like that and it was
just a stacked like the extracts the the
the hash that I made was just stacked
with all these miners that i' had never
seen before um and that was in that was
actually from Rosetta Stone and it made
me think it was the genius that held a
lot of those miners um but you know I
don't know if anybody on here has grown
genius but um genius is one of those
ones that has a lot of minors that are
um just not present a lot of um like
contemporary Cult of ours it's really
interesting yeah the our love of THC
really washed a lot of those miners
right off the board didn't it yeah it's
kind of been our lack of understanding
too yeah and like the different the
different um experiences you have from
all these varietals you know like I a
lot of the stuff I've I've kept in my my
clone stable like like the genius
like I I even when I pop new stuff I
don't see the same spread of
cannabinoids at
all um so I was telling you Marcus I was
starting to pop some of those old those
older varietals that I have even stuff
from Shanti have like the mango Haze
times skunk one and um a bunch of like
Afghan one times skunk one and that's
all the all original Shanti stuff in the
like when you used to um pack them all
in the little straw tubes and then like
seal them you know and put the little
sticker on them so I don't know Sam I
don't Sam I don't know if you remember
this the because you you were you knew
Shanti fairly well um I don't know if
you knew what stocky use but some of
that stuff is um is really viable like
I'm I'm popping like 15 seeds at a time
and all 15 are still
popping so um it's pretty big I've
gotten seeds that I had under
Refrigeration for more than 30 years 96%
germination
yeah that's kind of what I'm seeing
that's
awesome yeah so I'll keep you guys up I
had a Jamaican a Jamaican one actually
Johnny B grew it and he put it in a
frame it's an old Bud now but yeah this
is a Johnny B Bud of the some Jamaican
seed that I had brought back it was like
a lamb's bread you know they were
calling it Lamb's bread meaning it was
um it had that those those sativa
flavors doesn't look sativa at all looks
cushy the way John grew it here in
Canada but uh this was 25 years old this
seed I collected it in 95 when I finally
popped it it was 25 years later and it
was the only one of eight I had about a
7% germination ratio from the seed I
collected but I didn't keep them in a
fridge for at least like 10 years
so yeah if you want to keep them safe
you keep them at uh maybe plus 4 degre
Cade you know I mean that's cool but
it's not freezing yeah no that's the
fridge that's where they've spent that's
where it spent you know 15 years of its
life after kind of being at room
temperature for almost 10 someone asked
me
yesterday Sam what do you think about
refrigerators versus freezers someone
asked me yesterday um do they put it in
a fridge is there if you're going to
keep your seeds for really really long
times yeah freeezing them seems to last
longer if you're going to use them in
your lifetime you can keep them at a
plus 4 degre centigrade in in a dry if
the ultimate container is like a
container which you flush to remove the
oxygen so it's in like Argon gas or or
nitrogen or something like that it that
getting rid of oxygen for long-term
storage of seeds helps them a
lot
so yeah I wonder the the modern packs
that are
sealed have that little bit of air in
there wonder if that's working against
it you
know dread was asking uh about your
thoughts uh Sam in regards to uh the
seeds that Todd McCormick has been
selling the skunks Etc he he got the
mothers and fathers he picked out from
uh uh from me and
uh I have nothing to do with his
business other than uh he seems to be
doing a good job of it and uh keeping
skunk number one available to the masses
that want
it nice that's
awesome you got to keep skunk number one
available the masses that want it I mean
there's a bunch that don't even that
want it so they should probably uh keep
circulating the
globe is Greg mallister the Greg the
Northern Light
mallister yes he is okay hi Greg thanks
for your cont contribution to the GLE my
man it's a it's a beautiful
plant I know a lot of us have grown it
um I'm actually starting to go through
some of the old norn light seeds right
now that I've gotten there a lot of them
are reproductions but I'm curious to see
how they all turn out and how they look
similar or different just started like
cataloging um we're going to populate
probably like 13 different breeders that
have their Northern Lights and one
is Todd has Northern Lights directly old
seeds from Greg so
we just got those from him like a I
think okay a few months ago that was I
think he's got maybe uh
Murphy's from from up in Washington was
like one of the first afghanis on the
west
coast got it and then we have the Afghan
one from
Mel that's a really interesting one it's
it's hard it's got much dark green
leaves
yeah that one I want I'm curious to see
the difference between that varietal and
some of the other Afghans that are out
there to me it's quite similar to some
other Afghans I've
seen
interesting so interesting flavor
profile and it it's
very you know depending
on how you run it but it's got like a
sweet musky skunk to it it's interesting
yeah to me almost smells narcotic but
whatever I like
it a lot of people like the hash from it
makes gray hash go going back to that
Northern Lights the first seeds I bought
in Amsterdam were actually the Northern
Lights number five the closet Queen I
brought those back and grew them in a
little false wall growroom in our house
in Winnipeg
Manitoba the Northern Lights number
number five I'm pretty sure it was
number number five closet
Queen yeah that was my first experience
with no light with number five someone
sent me a a clone named
crippy and it was clearly you know there
Northern you could see when it grew the
leaves are huge man it was like Jurassic
Park it was like the biggest leaves I've
ever seen in my life and yeah it was
really good herb it was like they called
it the
crippy was the crippy
lights you
know good memories man I I do I do miss
the days that like rolling up to
Amsterdam when it was the only game in
town in the world for cannabis people to
just kind of feel a little whether it
was partial ignorance partial whatever
going into the Cannabis Cup right next
to the Pack's party house where the the
Pack's party house right next to the
police station so it's just all cop cars
and cops coming and going in the same
building so they were closer than next
door yeah yeah exactly oh my God what a
time what a time it's awesome though I
mean so Sam like you know when you when
you started going over to Amsterdam you
was Ben donkers like one of the first
people you'd spoken to who was selling
seeds or who was who was one of the well
Ben had just started because when I came
over it was was in
85 and there was one or two sort of
amateur seed companies it was Ben was
not publicly selling seeds yet got it so
who who were the guys like when you
rolled into town like who is like
someone you're like yo that there was uh
the uh the boat down on the on the in
front of the uh Harbor there and
Amsterdam and what were they called the
lowland Seed
Company nice but they didn't have any
truly great varieties and also there was
a
uh uh a gay lady called Dr Weed who used
to sell seeds and here in harand this
was you know before uh they were being
done by Vernard at positronics or and
anybody
else that's what I was going to ask
about Bernard and where where he was at
in that but I guess he came a little
later the the end effect of it
was none of the varieties they were
growing were truly truly outstanding
great cannabis they uh they made THC a
little bit but and uh yeah it it changed
a lot once they got really good seeds
you know that performed really well the
only problem is here in Holland is we
have a fairly early winter with cold and
wet so you got to have a solution for
that so is that where like early girl
and early Pearl and all those like early
varietals kind of that concept of like
well they need to finish
sooner uh yes there was also a bunch of
Dutch varities very early so sometimes
people would cross a skunk or some other
higher THC variety with early Dutch
varieties to try to get something you
know that like some
freezeland yeah because the freezeland
there was that stuff purple pars a bunch
of Dutch varieties actually and uh but
you know their TH levels I I would
presume were below
10% got it interesting
so really I mean when you guys rolled
into town you brought the goods that
kind of allowed everyone to
outcross with better genetics whatever I
I never cared what people did with my
seeds I just wanted to give them a good
product that they could run with if they
wanted to and uh if they made hybrids
you know that's fine and dandy with me
and uh you know
it helped a lot of varieties worldwide
in the early 80s and 90s and then other
varieties started coming up strong and
heavy and you
know but Greg's a good friend of mine
Northern Lights uh yeah his was probably
right up there with skunk and uh maybe
original Haze which a lot of people
really liked he's asking you if it was a
crime what Neville did to Ed Rosen seed
collection Greg is when Neville did what
to Ed
Rosenthal I'm not sure Sam Greg is
saying Sam was it a crime what Neville
did to Ed rosenthal's seed
collection I I don't know what Ed
rosenal seed collection
was yeah I I'm not sure either maybe
he'll hear you say that and he'll be a
little bit more specific on the question
yeah May is he talking about old Ed or
is he talking about uh Ed no no CU he he
said Ed Rosenthal so not old
Ed well I I never knew of Ed roseval
having his serious seed
collection yeah I don't know yeah
neither did I but perhaps we're we don't
know maybe he knows
something I always thought Ed
was I don't know I thought I always
thought he was a writer
that an
educator but all you need to do is ask
Ed yeah true I you can I like that pond
man that was funny um I bought I
actually have some seeds from Ed that he
sent me um I have I got them last year
from him so he is making seeds I guess
but uh I remember years ago he had
cultivars I can't remember like J
something or p41 they were all you know
names like that that was quite a while
ago maybe 25 years or 20 years ago shout
out to rotten skateboards Lobster Farms
what's up
buddy the Durban Poison that I used to
grow starting in the mid 70s in
California before I brought it over here
uh it actually originated at the transy
coffee shop in Amsterdam Ed Rosenthal
was there in maybe 1980 or 81 or
something he got the seeds from uh a
uh package of weed South
African Durban Poison and uh brought him
back and gave him to uh his writing
partner at the
time uh m
Franks and uh Mel Franks shared him with
me and uh when I got him from n every
plant was intersect so it took me three
or four or five years to clean it up and
then uh it was my earliest drug ride
sativa that I had uh up up until the 80s
or 90s
so South African I did get indirectly
from Ed even though I got the seeds
themselves from from
Mel nice to hear those stories right
from your mouth dude because you would
not believe how many reiterations there
are of that
story I was gonna ask about the derin
like so you're saying if I'm just gonna
recap this so it's so you work the line
to make sure it didn't it didn't Herm
and you st
what had happened is uh Mel Frank had
reproduce them or I think he gave some
to a friend who reproduced them before I
got them and uh he said he accidentally
gave me the ones that were interex and
uh because he didn't know and his friend
wasn't very uh you know literate on the
subject so he didn't understand either
but a few years of work I I would have
to grow large numbers out select the
ones that with were least uh intersex
and then uh I did that a few years and
used the progeny that uh had the lowest
incidents and I I almost got rid of it
completely that's it's interesting you
say that I I've actually only had with
true Durban lines I've only I've had
such terrible luck with them like I've
had only when they're outcrossed a
couple times
have they been something I can go all
the way through but yeah well SE a lot
of durans that were different than the
ones that Ed brought back the ones that
I'm talking about are extremely early
like you can Harvest at the end of
August interesting in
California so uh they were very very
early and they had a very strong anosy
licoricey taste and smell but they were
they really resinous because the ones
that I grew were super resinous but they
were just really the ones they they were
fairly resinous yes I I never considered
it super a quality but uh it it was very
good and it was early as [ __ ] I mean I
could pull a skunk plant out of the
ground I mean excuse me a South African
plant when it was done in California in
my little Greenhouse
then I could stick a skunk plant in
there a month or two later it would be
done and then I could stick a haze plant
in so I could use the same hole three
times in a row with just natural Sun
photo period nice that's
cool wellow yeah that's I I've yeah like
I said I've I've been I've over the
years had trouble with durans um low
potency is one of the main themes that
I've gotten but like they look
incredible on the resin looks insane um
and but they're finicky and then they
Herm a lot so we've always kind of
stayed away from them well I I I don't
know if it's the same or somebody else's
because I've seen three or four
different versions of uh of Durban
Poison and none of them were as early as
the the stuff that uh I
was I mean I could grow a crop of 20,000
plants outdoor in the Netherlands it it
was really
early that's pretty cool um so this this
guy in chat is saying that uh it's
purple Hindu that you're talking about
Sam not Durban Poison he says Durban
Poison doesn't have that turpine that
you mentioned he
also a couple other little things he he
can think whatever he wants but uh as
you know I've worked I know my tpes
pretty well we had our own gas cograph
lab with their ID and we could identify
a turpine in a blink of an
eye yeah yeah no I just love to see
people like not realize who you are and
like he's he's still going he's like
land races won't be
early okay well I'm I'm happy for for
his opinion on life but uh my version of
The Facts aren't going to change what
are you guys smoking on well your
versions on the facts are based on
reality and his based on reading and so
there's a
difference well there are a lot of uh
you know land race varieties especially
Ecuador ones that are extremely late
look at Hayes which originated in
Colombia I mean it's late as hell yeah
it's
true it's
true so Sam the Su uh the super to TAA
Club Hayes you'd be the one to ask where
do you believe that came
from because I I've been told so many
different things and they they I don't
know what to believe they were doing
growing and then they shifted into seed
production must have been uh I don't
know in the mid 80s okay so basically
used your stock and others and bl they
used any good stock they could find from
themselves from any friends or uh I was
happy to sell them all my varieties
because yeah didn't reproduce them pure
what they did was they made hybrids with
them so I felt you know he was
responsible for freezin
right I think freezeland might have been
even here before him but you you can
clarify it with him
he's he's still selling organic tab
stuff so uh I noticed his son's
restarted the seed company and I was
just it was it's in Amsterdam someplace
I I've never been there but uh I don't
go out very much and uh yeah I get I get
to see them I get to see them every once
in a while I I bump into I've seen them
in Spain was the last time I saw them
yep that's the last time I saw the dad
but the last time I saw the son was in
Berlin at the Mary Jane uh conference or
Mary Jane whatever they call it Mary
Jane pretty good he's always got great
hats to share he's just happy dude and
he's uh he's definitely like a quality
guy he's got the
quality seemed like a good good group of
people I just was curious the lineage I
don't you know you they they they were
the competition for Neville and his uh
seed
uh yeah his distribution they've been
around as long as him got it that's cool
and did they both get their like some of
their seeds from you abely yeah that's
what I'm trying to get at no of course
that's funny let's both get seeds from
Sam and then we'll like become
competition for one another well I
started my a decade earlier than they
did
yeah
um so interesting yeah I think
um I think the geran sounds legit too SM
smoke shine smoke signs
since since like
S as he's ripping a
dab what's everybody talking on right
now what do you got in your
jars I want to hear it in the chat here
someone said they got
somea press Keef a little GMO yeah their
work isn't very good my man PK Brewer
but um some good stuff out there big
shout out
to all the Growers out there it's been
it be a tough season out there in the
out on the East Coast for those that are
growing
outdoor really I it's a hurricane season
right now oh honey bananas love that
[ __ ] yeah there's like a rainstorm
happening in Ontario and like misses
like a lake throughout the entire city
yeah it's just out so anything
all that asperous we're talking about
starting to starting to sit
in Robert says him and his son have been
watching hash church together since it
began I'm grateful for this he actually
started it with a Jesus I missed the
Jesus we're grateful for
[Music]
you yeah exactly we got 264 people
watching live right now which is a
pretty pretty good number when hash
church was at its PE
I think it was around like 1100 so I
think last week we had maybe
225 nice to see there's this Core group
of people that kind of want to
hear you know specific things and
conversations that we seem to just love
to
have I know that it is the emerald Cup
right now so that's uh that's where
Mojave is right now that's probably
where quite a few people are uh in
regards to that uh poor Thomas from
Grandmaster LED has had a like a pipe of
burst on his property that he's dealing
with frantically right now so we'll wish
him uh a quick and Speedy pipe fix for
that that's uh that can be stressful
when the water's coming out at like I
don't know a thousand gallons an hour or
some
ridiculous gotta get it got to get it
fixed this blueberry banana it's got
these Esters in it that just reminds me
of just older
it's it's it's like a 5050 of like of
blueberry and Oregon kids like BL you
know banana OG it's really really well
done big shout out to Golden State
banana he grew this we washed it oh yeah
golden Ste
banana can I ask Sam what his advice
would be to someone starting their first
indoor grow holy [ __ ] that's uh
I to be honest I'm the wrong person to
ask because that's what I was thinking I
use the Sun or I use the sun through a
greenhouse glass but uh yeah I I I
wouldn't want to give advice because I'm
not current with lights I'm not current
with a a lot of things that uh are
required for and I never really liked
indoor growing because I like putting my
hand in the earth and my head under the
sun yeah makes sense plus you're very
far down the road it's like uh you know
sometimes if you want to ask kind of
like a question like that you'd be like
well let just we don't need to ask an
expert by any means just ask someone who
has like a who's had a small grow or
whatever which I'm sure there's many
people here in the chat room who can
help that gentleman answer his uh his
question how would he go about his first
grow I personally would say get a small
tent you know do some research on lights
figure out if you want HPS or LED feel
free to reach out to me uh and I can
have a discussion with you about lights
BC bubbleman
icloud.com and just uh start slow and
and you know get get some some good
genetics that's kind of the hard part
like I would say like make sure that
what you're going to spend your months
on growing are like really good genetics
not just someone's version of like they
said these were really good genetics
make sure like the reviews are there
make sure the source is correct and that
you're not getting scammed on your seeds
or your clones or however you're going
to get your um genetics and then I would
say as a firsttime grower and if you're
in the US in particular definitely look
at those tarantula Predators from
Grandmaster because that UVC light just
as a preventative for five minutes a day
when the light when the lights are all
off and you're not in there and the
tents all closed up um that's a huge
advantage to a beginner grower you know
when you're a beginner grower if you can
kind of just keep bugs and mildew at Bay
that is going to give you a pretty large
Advantage I know
that what's that grant grant waiter said
LOL grow big bud you know what that
generally made me laugh because I'll be
honest I'll raise my hand here I've
grown big bud literally when I was a
teenager I grew big bud and dude I grew
fat coal is the size of 2 lit bottles
literally it looked like big fat
2 lit bottle colas man so if that's your
first experience growing weed that'll
that'll let your light your world on
fire man because it certainly did to me
it definitely gets you excited I I'll
tell you the I I remember in 99 or 2000
I took Gypsy Nirvana to the Sunshine
Coast to my buddy's place who was
growing the BC hash plants and you know
the the top buds on that plant are
literally like bigger than a 2 L pop
bottle the bottom buds I pictures of
gypsy leaning his head in and the bottom
buds of these plants are about the size
of his head it was like a 10 by 10 room
that the guy pulled out like 23 LBS or
something like it was absolutely insane
weed but that was also the cut if you
ever remembered that this that you could
get in trouble if you weren't supposed
to have it and you started posting it
online that you had it so it was like it
came from a very specific group of
people uh and if you were growing it and
they didn't want you to be then that
could that could bring you the wrong
attention yeah that was it's it's
impossible to spread to stop the spread
of cannabis because it works by the
Cannabis osmosis Theory you know
wherever it's needed it
goes yeah and it seems to be needed
everywhere Hey listen even the first
time I went to Jamaica and I made bubble
hash every I make this hash with this
group I'd be all stoked and then you
know after about five or 10 minutes
they'd be like you can't show anyone
else and I was like oh dude I'm
literally going to show everyone else
and there was a lot of people that asked
me that not to show anyone else in
particular places but Jamaica was like a
high there was a high percentage of
people it's the more difficult time
there's less opportunity you know people
have it rough uh in certain places and I
was showing some people that really did
have it rough uh but I I always said you
know what no don't worry about that I'm
going to show everyone you just hone in
on the best that you can find and grow
and and make the best that you can and
that's how you'll stand out with it and
uh to my word I did keep showing people
and boy I damn near did show everyone
Mar Marcus in the in the mid 80s people
said to me you know just sell me your
skunk number one nobody
El that's I think it's just the fear and
scarcity Vibe we all fall victim to it
sometimes I I'm certainly not judging
people for having the fear and scarcity
it's uh it's a good vibe to to to to
change and and convert or transfer into
love and abundance if you can figure it
out but uh
yeah that's what I'll say about
that don't grow it just me I'm the only
one just just sell me the the the the
skunk number one only no gonna have to
sell it to everyone sorry
everyone and then we all have our
stories like skunk number one that was
like the first weed I bought in a Dutch
coffee shop on the dam Rock like
literally
like got off the out of the train
station walked up turned left bam
sitting down 1995 for me and we went and
bought some skunk number one and we were
just uh just loving it just this fruity
explosion of flavor and smell and just
it was just lovely really really really
lovely especially coming from Winnipeg
Manitoba and kind of growing weed
already where it was like you could
really get in trouble and end up in
prison with like hardened criminals if
you got caught which was uh I mean it
goes to show about that cannabis osmosis
and how it really almost infects the
soul in the way that it's like we're
we're a part of each other now like
willing to like just the the risk at
that time in my life I would not have
taken that risk for anything else the
risk of like getting in trouble and
ending up in in a prison not a jail a
prison with like the most hardened
criminals that you could possibly
imagine we'll get my old Mentor Ron
hickey in here one of these days and get
him to tell some stor of his experience
at the Stony Mountain Penitentiary
because it is absolutely Bonkers that
they put someone who just loves flowers
in a prison like that for 11 years it's
Bonkers and I know that there's worse
stories I know Rick delisi's father was
away for oh God I think it was 37 years
we'll have to get them uh to come on
hash church for sure Rick and uh his his
father uh to tell those stories and I
mean I've heard them from Rick and I've
seen Rick tell them and been in rooms
when he's been interviewed but uh I've
never met his his father so um and I was
definitely like one of the early
adopters of the free delisi promoting it
as much as I could giving it exposure
the best that I could because I just
thought it was one of the most
nightmarish stories you know when he
told me I haven't seen my dad without
plexiglass like since I was 11 years old
like that is if he would have been
sentenced if he would have been
sentenced federally he would have been
released early earlier but because he
was in the State of Florida and uh it
his sentencing was controlled by the
Florida Judicial System uh they were
never going to let him go
until I guess finally they did during
covid yeah I I have a friend I grew up
with that was let out in Co she ran an
incredible she was a I consider her gret
I'll just say gret she was a Visionary
she
we had the whole East Coast unlock it
was just incredible she was a Visionary
and Gretch taught me a lot and you know
she was a Visionary for where we're at
today in terms of logistics and how herb
moved around and who grew it and how it
was grown and respect behind the herb
and how she aggregated it and allowed it
to get to the people it was really
interesting um so I think those are the
people that paved the way for where
certainly I think we all sit today
um in a lot of respect um it's it's how
traditionally we all called our our
buddy to get a get a get a good bag of
herb or in some of us how we
communicated with one another to trade
cuting or to grow herb to get it out to
people and I think that was also a like
the Underground Railroad if if you will
of of our community and I think we all
protected one another in ways that um
allowed us to get you know do what we're
doing today and she was definitely um
someone that I looked at as an
inspiration um and I think the deli is
also in in in that way in that same
light he's he was a Visionary he had a
vision for um what he was doing in a
different way much like Dave you know
David you with your genetics and what
you did in Amsterdam you know very much
Visionary um and how that shaped what
we're doing now you know I'm very my God
thankful for all of it you know it
really helps
me because I get to have you know
something to to look back to and I know
all of us here um share that same common
threat you know like Mich for Mark
scalone you know Dr Mark you know you
you have certainly taken that work and
created your own world and in which you
occupy and continue to push it you know
well my longest goal has been that every
person in every country should be able
to grow for any purpose if they want to
sell it for profit then I it should be
somehow regulated so the consumer is
safe but except for that uh yeah this is
all slowly but surely crumbling in front
of our eyes some some places will take
longer but uh already they can't go back
it's too late you can't put the
toothpast back in the tube yeah and like
in the chat like bear grows it if you've
been growing since 92 then you
understand what I've been through in New
York and you understand what others like
us have been through on the East Coast
especially in and in Vermont and other
space other states you know it's it was
really
tough um and it must be a trip just like
it is for for for me for you to walk
around and see how open it is especially
in New York it's nuts
latest thing that opened in uh Amsterdam
is there's now a Snoop Dog uh coffee
shop I saw that I I did see that the the
prices are at the higher end but uh I
mean Jesus if you want to S smoke sop
snoops weed I guess you gotta pay for
it I guess so man dude I heard the
Olympics paid him 500 Grand a day to
just go and like comment on the Olympics
and hang out and be seen and like the
dude is uh he's he's something else man
he's definitely
like I'm glad to hear he hasn't sold
out oh yeah yeah he's uh certainly not
getting it from the
streams I'll tell you that oh my God
well you know on a side note he is
releasing an album with what with Dr Dre
here very soon I did hear that the other
day they get to
revisit Big Love Bear gr big love to you
man I think the the chat is
um needs a needs a dad that's what I
think my my wife likes listen to some of
Snoop songs uh I've heard a few I like
so I have nothing against him I more
power to him I'm for anybody who can be
successful at cannabis uh I'm happy for
them well he's definitely a spokesman
for it in the sense that he's helping
normalize the mainstream use of
it yeah I think that's that's well well
said I mean let's face it one ad of him
saying I'm not smoke or whatever the ad
was I can't remember but he was talking
about how he going to quit
smoking and then it was an ad for stove
a smokeless that was yeah in the whole
did you see the uh did you see the
custom torch they had them built for to
to to carry the
flame
joint look at that thing man it looks
totally like a
joint it's
legit yeah that's not photoshopped At
All by the way that's uh that's real
100% right there
oh
[ __ ] just being silly saw that had to
laugh Dr Mark what are you smoking over
there
bu uh got this little cuge here but here
I want to shout out
my friend Adam at Menino
grasslands a mutual friend he Dro me off
a little bit of this
nice yeah bit that a little bit of
that yeah Adam and
Ian the whole crew over
there yeah's asking us to Dre Dre's
asking us to talk about our thoughts on
hlvd epidemic but I think we should do
an episode on that and I'll get like Ian
uh from high Labs who used to be over at
segra and some other people maybe we can
get Kevin mccurn in I have been trying
to get him in for a like the last two
weeks I've been sending him messages so
hopefully he sees one of those and we
can get him in and then anyone else that
you guys in the chat or in the panel
think that would be great for a
conversation
hlvd just tell our thoughts on the hlvd
epidemic I mean I've been do I forget
who I forget who did the paper but
recently a paper came out out that uh
showed that uh maybe it was the guy at
gelf University I'm not sure and uh it
showed that it's transmitted by not only
insects and tools and people but it can
be spread by pollen it can be spread by
seeds so you know this is and one of the
biggest warnings is if you're using any
sort of aquaponics thing it can spread
in aquaponics totally easy if one of
them's got it it can spread through
water we didn't real we didn't realize
that before so I I started with Kevin in
20 late 2018 when I got a sample and
that's what started the whole he built
the whole assay off of that one sample
yeah so he collected more samples and
then built more um so I think it would
be great to have him on so you could go
through the data like I actually have
full spreadsheets with the data but I
think it would be better for him to
break it down because there's certain
things I don't understand about the data
um but we we learned a lot I did a hop
um I did a a leaf Hopper study where I
put plants in one Greenhouse that were
closed off and sealed and one that was
open in a plant that was close to that
greenhouse and the leaf Hoppers tested
positive for for hot blade and vroid so
we'll I think Kevin can go through a lot
of the I can I can go through my data
points and explain it all but pretty
much every Vector that you can think of
that is transmittable by
touch is it is possible and then
furthermore water is another carrier
that we didn't at first believe was
real tools W you know Roots soil touch
gloves I mean
I mean any you name it everything it's
nuts it's a virus all of reality you're
gonna die you're gonna VAP R and hldd
you know but no it's not you can't treat
it like that you can't look it's not
doomsday it's just you have to be aware
of your surroundings and just bake it
into your Sops now and just wash your
hands use you know bleach you know um
ISO will not kill the virus you have to
bleach it um test your plants and just
continue to be a good Steward and check
all those boxes for yourself and you
shouldn't have any problems but if you
taking clones from other people you
should have a protocol that that first
goes out to sampling and get that tested
for that and then test for all 12 of the
viroids that we know the Cucumber vroid
there's others besides hopl and vroid um
I have a list of 29 viruses that have
been recorded in cannabis
wow so I recommend just like everything
quarantine everything and and also get
it it tested with
qpcr and and that's the best you're
going to do and just constantly keep the
your stuff
clean um well I think we should try and
get a conversation going in the next
couple of weeks if you want to help me
col and organize some names and stuff I
I obviously Kevin's on there maybe Dr uh
someone wrote in the chat Dr Joe ramahi
and Dr Gupta at IAL genomics as well so
could get a whole crew of some
interesting folks to discuss it I'd like
to learn more about kind of The Cutting
Edge and what's going on right now I'll
look for that recent paper I'm thinking
about and uh I'll I'll include the names
and send them to you
Marcus oh thank you that'd be great yeah
there's a there's a few people that are
really taking this on um with some
really great studies and there's also
some really great existing stuff that's
out there um that that
predates you know all of us so um
there's a lot to dig into I think it
would be great so I'll put together a
list for you guys of names and we'll
it'll be a great conversation because
it's it's such a deep one it's it's kind
of it's fascinating what we're learning
it's just at first we kind of thought
this was like maybe not real and then
all of a sudden it just kind of
snowballed into okay this is real
but what do we do to
I better understand how it's actually
happening because no one R mites were
bad that's another topic I'd love to get
on um actually because to be honest I've
in my whole career of growing I've never
been able to eradicate russed mites I
know people have told me they have but
I've never seen it I've never
experienced it in my career all the best
I've done is walk into a room with a
flamethrower and take everything out and
then shut it down and we just there's no
there's no fighting it um they are
absolutely what you can do is you can
control the economic damage they're
causing enough that uh you can still
Harvest your crop without it being
severely damaged sure but but uh yeah
I've never been able to even completely
eliminate two spotted spidermite from a
large Greenhouse once you get it good
luck
I mean you can control it absolutely you
know with uh Predators but uh yeah you
don't get them on yeah I mean I and
we're really to be honest like
extremely just on top of everything so
it's you know we experienced it three
years ago and I'll never forget it
because it was like it was a burn it was
really it was to the point where I'm
like we just we can't we just have to
take it all down you can't can't do it
um but I do think that um we should
bring I'd love to bring someone on to
talk about IPM and just like it'd be
great a great conversation yeah we we I
have access to a young guy and I can't
remember what his name is but Thomas
brought him up to show him that UVC
light um and he's kind of this you know
IPM genius in the Cannabis World young
kid I met him he was really nice Matt
Gates what's that Matt Gates oh yeah it
was Matt you're right so there you go
perfect so we I'm sure we can get mad on
easy enough and uh some other
folks uba none of that stuff had fully
worked for me I mean I I
under yeah but it sounded like um The
Grandmaster lady setup was a little bit
different than the the setups that I had
used Marcus remember we had that call we
talked about it where we had tried it
and we had Sal sum of success but not to
the point like what grandmas had had um
yeah it's it's been to say the least
yeah I'm uh I think we have homework
though for next week if we can kind of
uh you know put put some list together
for a for a unique discussion I'm
definitely down to stay consistent and
keep gathering on Sundays and invite
more people in and have uh have more
conversations I am going to cut it short
now being 11 we did two hour hours so I
want to thank everyone for coming Wade
as always a pleasure skunkman Sam so
happy to have you back sir uh Dr Mark
it's always great to hear what you have
to to say and share and call and thanks
uh thanks for coming in dude I hope to
see you guys all next week and uh we'll
put together some more people I just
want to be compiling lists of great
people for different discussions that we
can just you know kind of start
scheduling a couple two three weeks
ahead of time and have something to look
forward to so uh as always May the full
Mount bless your bowls sooner than later
and uh want to thank everyone for coming
out today and thank you all in the chat
I guess there's 255 of you hanging out
and we really really appreciate it so uh
thank you so much uh have fun at the
emerald cup everybody uh and shout out
to Tim Blake for just continuing to
crush that event all these years later
peace out everybody
if