got
it all
right okay we are live let us do this
thank you everybody Welcome to Legends
of hash three hash Church 4.0 episode 8
it's been ages since I've done a hash
Church episode just got some folks
coming in right now figuring out their
Logistics with their audio and their
video and whatnot and uh man super
stoked to be here today super stoked to
talk to all the winners from Legends of
hash uh number three in Los Angeles
obviously I think if you got to go to
Legends of hash you actually were a
winner but there was another level of
winning which were the people who really
shined who brought the hashes that
really you know moved people whether it
was through their o Factory through that
numbness of the brain and body all the
beautiful flavors that showed up we had
people come from All Over America and
absolutely
represent Oklahoma [ __ ] represented
let me tell you we'll be talking about
that here in a little bit and uh I'm
just super excited now unfortunately
right now um Addison is not feeling very
well he might not actually make it we
were close to cancelling for a second
time in a row and I just uh I wasn't
having it so uh we're going to continue
on the way we are and I want to just
welcome everyone so far we only have a
few folks into the room but welcome guys
like holy [ __ ] Legends of hash
representing
winners hell yeah what up yeah dudes you
guys you guys [ __ ] crushed it man you
guys want to introduce yourself and tell
us a little bit about uh about your
journey that that brought you to Legends
of hash 3 in Los Angeles to to crush
mode so hard
man uh well I'm Chris this is Dan uh wek
Papa burger that's the papa Burg let's
start off with something proper this
morning hell yeah man I wish I had some
of that right
right that's awesome um yeah so we're
from Oklahoma and uh we are skunk and
we're a legal hash maker here in in the
State on a licensed and uh been doing
this for since 2019 since it started and
uh yeah I mean I I guess we just I don't
know just been a crazy journey man I
don't know I learned a long time
ago
oh think did it did you say 2019 is when
you started uh that's when we started in
Oklahoma yeah as far because that's
pretty much when it uh right after it
went legal like the beginning of 2019 uh
at the time we were living in Colorado
and we we've lived here before and we
have family here and uh so as soon as
they legalized we wanted to be in the
legal market and so we made the jump and
started skunk
yeah started making hash in 20 was it
2019 2018 2018 the end of 2018 is when
we started making hash so what turned
you guys on to making hash like what
were you guys were just like we should
just start making
hash I mean I mean originally it was a
long time ago we learned to make bubble
has then it was like we did we're doing
the B we were dabbling in the BHO for a
while but the BHO I just uh it's it was
like a hard thing to be able to get into
like the legal market and then that's
when we found rosin watched a lot of
your episodes on actually how to make
you know the bubble has and all that
stuff and it's just been it's been crazy
ever since and I mean we used to pretty
much strictly just grow for like flower
but ever like we pretty much have only
switched over to rosin lately like all
of our everything that we do just
strictly goes to rosin right well I mean
listen it's
absolutely topnotch TPS
topnotch rosin I mean it's it's
absolutely beautiful and uh so you guys
took first and second in rosin and then
you also got a a a People's Choice Award
correct it was was it Derby yes sir
sired so you guys got the little dery
cup uh so we don't have it yet uh but
soon it might be at the the po. box I
haven't had a chance to check but if not
there very soon and we can't wait man
we're really excited for that hell yeah
yeah that's awesome man no that's great
to see man I've uh I just it brought a
smile to my face to see that you guys
came so far and you know California
really whether people want to admit it
or not it's it's it's kind of like the
center of the Cannabis Universe you know
like everything if you want to be honest
with yourself and you want to see like
and you go back historically like
obviously I'm talking about our sort of
History you know going back to like the
1960s the 1970s and on obviously
cannabis and hashish has a much deeper
um history I mean even today I'm wearing
my classic shirt of these Lebanese women
doing dry sifting over a table this is
probably a lot longer ago than 1970 so
hashish has a deep and Rich history in
the world it goes back hundreds of years
if not a thousand plus years but for our
history you know for the California part
of things really since like the late 60s
early '70s they seem to be the first
ones to pull the males they seem to be
the first ones to cut the the flowering
period down they seem to be the first
ones to get into oil making and hash
making they beat they just they were the
first ones to really take this so
absolutely serious and have this
infectious love of the plant that I
think a lot of that spread out from Cali
I know it spread right up the Coast to
Vancouver uh we're not too different up
here in regards to our love of cannabis
and our passion of cannabis but you know
I'm sure too all those packs over the
years that got sent out of Cali across
the US that's the inspiration right like
you're literally inhaling California
into your lungs and we get affected by
it and so shout out to California um if
you guys want to hear something
absolutely [ __ ] batshit crazy I have
never been to
California what what I've never I've
never been to California man I I tried a
bunch of times in the 990s I bought a
bunch of Grateful Dead tickets on mail
order and you know tried to go across
the border and they would just deny me I
ended up giving these Grateful Dead
tickets away in the in the forest in
British Columbia because I just couldn't
get over the border and it happened time
and time again I remember when Jerry
died I was pretty upset about it because
uh I wanted to see him play in uh in
California of course you know Mountain
View or something what's up Colin what's
up bro dude just talking to the Oklahoma
boys here Crush mode at the [ __ ]
Legends of hash I'm sure you guys got to
spend time together not really actually
I kind of missed them I I was floating
around a little bit but I was just head
down trying to get through all the
entries to be real man yeah I don't know
everyone else felt but I tried to float
around a little bit but yo to be real it
was like first night I was like I gotta
focus on this and then someone told me
like you got to get in in at 8 a.m. I
was like yo I don't
know that's how we roll that's how we
look at hash look at hash church today
dude there's like four of us it's like
9:00 am people like what time is it at
I'm like dude I sent three emails it's
like 9:00 a.m. bro wake the [ __ ] up what
are you smoking over there and I I'm I'm
late so I apologize for that but uh but
no it was dope because I I ended up
leaving the event around like 10: on the
first night and then just going back to
my spot and just like focused on
everything and just like went through it
all to be honest and everyone was like
you're crazy why you going through
everything I'm like to be honest like I
have to I can't just smell because
things that smell great don't
necessarily taste great and things that
taste great don't necessarily smell
great etc etc and I think it's important
to give every single person that that
same moment that you would if it's your
own work um sure and it was it was cool
man it was good to go through it all it
was a lot of work but um it was
enjoyable it was cool it was good to be
in a focus setting for just my myself
because even having like just the open
air and then everyone else around me it
was tough to like really get into jars
and really appreciate it um the open air
so it was nice to be able to have both
um I definitely went back to jars that I
tried outside or or at the event and
then was like you know maybe I'll give
this a different score so um it was cool
man it was it was it's a unique thing
you know before Legends happened there
was no events like this there's so many
now I can't even count them all but
really when we first started Legends
over 20 years ago you know the idea of
hitting 20 to 30 high-end flavors in
like a two to four hour period was kind
of unheard of it didn't exist you know
and I'll tell you like uh people that I
know that are as hard of smokers as as
you could be were like finding their
levels of of limitations I mean everyone
but skunkman Sam because that guy has no
limitations whatsoever he's just a
Savage Maniac but uh for the rest of us
you know I be I find myself paling out
like out in front of the restaurant just
getting some air with some other Heavies
out out in front of the restaurant just
you know and kind of like looking like
really like are we pushing ourselves
that hard and keep in mind skunkman Sam
was dumping like two grams at a time
into an Afghan Hubbly Bubbly that we
were lighting with flames coming off of
this thing like a foot and a half each
time you lit it so you know you were
getting uh extremely extremely extremely
high had a good question from stinky
farms in the room for the uh for the Oki
group there that he wanted to know what
medium is your flower grown
in so we use a cocoa a highly amended
Coco that's kind we kind of try to like
build a living soil almost out of a
cocoa and then throughout the life cycle
of the plant we continue to add natural
and organic inputs as well as microbes
um to try to keep since Coco doesn't
really hold on to very much of the
nutrients so we like to but we want to
create that rise of sphere and then
continue to add to that throughout the
life cycle dude I like where you're
coming from right now I really do that
micro rizosphere has an intelligence
that humans have not yet acquired this
[ __ ] thing knows exactly what the
plant needs when the plant needs it
where the plant needs it how the plant
needs it and we just have not I mean
don't get me wrong there are some
incredible folks out there that do some
incredible work in regards to their you
know feeding of the plant and and
getting the plant up to that level of
expression where it can be like a winner
of Legends of hash Papa burger it's uh
it's something special for sure I'm not
saying I haven't seen beautiful resin
grown in salts I just I've seen the
nicest resins I've ever seen have been
grown in uh living soil so I love the
idea of building that bridge and being
like well maybe we can't do the fully
fully I mean listen real fully living
soils generally isn't going to be in
pots it's going to be like out in a on a
field like where it's actually connected
to Nature and living but the more we can
bring that in to the scenario and you
know adding those microbes and and
creating that somewhat living soil maybe
we could call it somewhat living soil uh
it certainly shows in your results
because these flavors
are they're just man that's almost
like o almost like some some poooo Kaka
in there there's some like good there's
some goodness in here man little baby
turds oh I think I'm gonna I think I'm
gonna wake and bake with some Papa
burger you know I haven't touched it yet
it's like an
untouched man I don't know how you did
that
ex no I mean just not just being able to
not smoke it well it's because I'm a
macro photographer and what I really
wanted to do was I wanted to um I wanted
to do some nice photos for the you that
I managed to scope but I've just been
crushing them out and uh today I figured
is a great spot to uh to do some Crush
mode so I also want to say hi to Logan
who's uh in the room torching up his
Banger don't worry you don't have to say
hi back right away brother Logan is a
awesome young guy who's just taking it
upon himself to take static sifting to
the next level working along with myself
with sble filtration and the uh the
static sifting machine Logan has some of
the most profound uh static sifting
photos of you know [ __ ] on it like
beautiful resin on his glove and uh so
thank you for keeping sifting alive
Logan uh and I'm sure skunkman Sam
thanks you as well I did invite skunkman
Sam today but it was very last minute so
uh we'll see if he's managing to make it
it is about 6 quarter after 6:00 pm.
where he lives in Amsterdam so hopefully
we'll see him later as well and uh I see
cash is there as well I'm not sure who
that is exactly he's got his camera off
but uh welcome to you as well fine
brother and uh hey how's it going guys
it's good man where are you calling
from I am up in the Northwest right now
all right so in my stomping grounds yeah
you're neck of the woods that's what's
up that's what's up are you just down
across the border from me or I sure am
um um we're right up here like in the
Seven Lakes area of Washington so we're
like
probably an hour away from you yeah oh
man you know back in the day and I don't
know how many of you know this when I
first moved here in like
96 I ended up going a couple years later
I was uh hitchhiking I wasn't
hitchhiking actually sorry I was driving
I hadn't this is the last time I've been
to America by the way 1998 I rented a
brand new car I cut my [ __ ] hair I
was like I'm just gonna I'm gonna look
I'm going to I'm going to get across the
border they had denied me at the border
so many times one time I bought every
single ticket to fish tour summer tour I
bought Miracle tickets to give away and
I got denied at the border it was 37
concert tickets just mine my buddy also
had 37 that all went to [ __ ] because we
bought them on my credit card and I
couldn't even give them away at the box
office to people because they needed my
credit card to pick them up so this was
my last attempt I'm like I'm going to go
see fish at the Gorge and I drive across
the border I make it mainly because fish
had just played in Vancouver and I was
in a [ __ ] circus of freaks who were
crossing the border and I probably
looked the least freaky at the time and
uh I ended up picking up a couple
hitchhikers and it was marble Slinger
and Jason Lee the glass blowers and uh
these guys ended up living in Bellingham
which was really close to Vancouver and
for many many years I had this
incredible connection to all these
amazing glass blowers that were right in
Bellingham and they would come up over
here and you know I saw Slinger the
other day I don't know if you guys know
marble Slinger the glass blower he was
writing on the High Times page shout out
to bubble man he gave me my first oil
dab he gave me my first full Mount
bubble hash dab turned me on to the
melts like it was just neat to see that
history and that was all because I
picked him up as a as a young scraggle
hitchhiker on his way to to fish tour
which was uh very close to probably
where you're at their cach what uh
company did you represent with at
Legends cash you're muted H yeah you
know we knew this was going to happen
the mute mute um I said it uh you called
it um yeah um our
entry um was with h papaya guava and
there was a little bit of a mixup on our
uh the brand name that had appeared so I
think like on the on the media that
Legend of hashish posted I think it said
dsar which is one of our teams and then
um but down in SoCal uh our team is C
and so that's kind of what the entu was
supposed to be under but
yeah we do [ __ ] up every once in a while
we're not going to lie so we're sorry
about that we smoke an enormous amount
of hash and Addison is just also a
Savage Maniac he is a poer this guy
[ __ ] smokes he's not making it up
he's not faking this is legitimately who
he is so uh we'll do better next year
that's all we can say oh it's all good
it was uh it was complicated that's for
sure well shout out to JP Toro for the
Banger here about to uh light up a
little Papa
burger got my got my Banger basket full
and clean with some brand new ISO in
here so that's always nice it gets
pretty yellow it gets pretty
yellow shout out to Mothership I got
this this new this new piece here on the
rig and it's it's just perfect for this
for a sipper like this hell yeah dude
those guys know what they're doing over
there there's no doubt about it I did
invite Scott and JP and Darby as well um
I'm good with this group if no one else
shows up we'll have a nice couple hours
we'll puff some bowls we'll listen to
some stories we'll see where everyone's
going um I'm definitely just loving the
um well I'm loving the excitement that
Legends came off of I mean we had less
than a week of Legends being over before
Lorenzo from tpp's army shout out to
Lorenzo from turps army
uh hit us up and was like why don't we
do a Legends in Barcelona this year for
spannabis and we were like yeah why
don't we like [ __ ] I haven't done a
Legends of hash in Barcelona since
2018 so it sounds like we're going to be
doing a Legends of hash it won't be
obviously as intense as the one that
Addison did first of all I got to give
this guy an absolute massive shout out
um without Addison there would be no
Legends of hash in America uh it had
really only ever been in Vancouver
Amsterdam uh Jamaica
Barcelona I don't go to America so why
would it be in America right Addison hit
me up a couple years ago and was like
listen I want to bring Legends of hash
to America I think that it's time I
think that there's real value here and
the job that he did him and Meredith and
the whole
team building out all those Moroccan
style booths and just you know we lost
our venue 90 days before the event like
the guy was just like oh hey you know
how you put a $10,000 deposit down sorry
man like my landlords of evicting me and
so we were were like what do you like
what
like so we ended up like he had to find
that whole new venue he did so much that
I'll never be able to say enough uh
positive things about Addison and the
team down there um just a huge shout out
to him for everything that he did and it
looked and sounded like it was an
absolutely amazing time imagine the fomo
I had sitting up here in Canada not able
to go to Legends of hash now for the
third time I have applied for a Nexus
car so I sent Homeland Security all my
information exposed myself completely
which is fine cuz I don't uh break the
law or or do any shady [ __ ] and so I'm
hoping that I get this Nexus card by
next year and uh I will absolutely be in
Barcelona but I would also love to be in
Los Angeles next year uh well really
probably the year after because I think
we're doing it instead of December
around January but we'll see we'll see
where that all falls
yes I what about you Logan you want to
tell us a little bit about Logan's
journey and how you ended up now at
the Legends of hash for is this your
third year or second year second year
right Wolverine dabs you crushed it last
year too didn't
you yeah I mean I was the only
competitor so well that's what better
way to but here here's the thing so
here's the thing we can laugh about that
but think about that what you're really
saying was I was the only person with
full melt dry sift so that's that's
something different right when you say I
was the only competitor it kind of takes
away from me whenever I speak in a room
full of heads I always ask people who
here has flour and almost every hand
goes up then I'll ask who here has full
melt bubble and a few hands will go up
hopefully most people will have rosin
which is great that's amazing
but if you ask the room who here has
full melt dry sift it is [ __ ]
crickets and Tumble weeds you guys
probably know about up in Oklahoma
[Laughter]
there so so it's it's it's it's a real
thing to just have dry sift that can
melt into a liquid just to have it is
something to be said so I personally
thank you for showing up and being the
only person that showed up with it
because uh
otherwise no one would have had it and
that's uh that's that's never a good
thing so tell us a little bit about uh
your your journey into the static realm
and into producing uh producing the
fire well so essentially I started
making extracts when I was 17 so around
2012 and I made I I started with like
hydrocarbon and then distillates I moved
on to doing isolates reformulating
reconstructing uh it's actually not
until
2021 that I started doing static um my
buddy Dylan had left me his screens when
he when he moved and he went to go work
for mock
Technologies and left me the screens and
he always told me like dry Si's like the
cream of the crop it's it's it's the
best of the best if you can get it it's
the best experience the best the best
high essentially right so I started
looking into videos on YouTube you know
and I I stumbled across your videos I
stumbled across several other videos so
the very first day I pulled the screens
out I cleaned them completely set up a
table I had YouTube going I had my
screens right there I had my material
and I stood there for 14 hours rubbing a
screen and listening to other people
talk about rubbing a screen and just
listening to the actual like screen
being rubbed so so that sound will
always kind of stick in my brain just i'
I've been around it for thousands of
hours now but it's it's absolutely
incredible um as soon as I started doing
dry sift and and I got it to the Purity
that I was able to achieve which I
consider to be around 98 99% Purity in
tricomb heads um as soon as I started
consuming that I I fell in love and I I
couldn't go back to anything else I
there's it it's it's absolutely perfect
in every way in my opinion simply
because the tpine content is right where
you want it it's sitting around four to
6% which is perfect for human
consumption tpin themselves are
hydrocarbons so anything above 6% can be
harmful for inhalation where did you
come up with that
number what the five to six% well just
that you're safe at four or five but
anything over cuz I'm interested in this
I've always like listen I've been been
smoking 8 to 10%
tpine uh for I I would say a good solid
10 years uh maybe more I still haven't
felt anything but I do believe and
especially after doing Blue River
extracts with Tony for all those years
that we absolutely reached the level
that was too much um we never smoked
that level for a long time I felt that
level personally and I I guess it's just
a subjective opinion I felt that was
above 10 you know around the 11 to 12 it
just stopped being enjoyable for me me
but like five six seven8 like even even
you know I think the hash we made
recently um no that's Pella oh this was
some rosin we made recently at my
facility in uh Canada here and it came
back 9 99.8% tpine
75.7%
thca um but it's it I I wonder where you
got that number very intelligent guy it
so it's pretty much just my opinion but
at the same time when you look at it
tpes are a hydrocarbon absolutely I've
said it a million times it's hard to
make solventless hash when it's loaded
up with hydrocarbons how about that
exactly it's pretty funny it's pretty
funny but I just I I find that my throat
personally reacts at anything above 6% I
just I start coughing and it's my throat
tightens up my chest tightens up I for
me it's the 6% Mark I don't like
consuming things above the 6% Mark so
here's a
question
um if you're using fresh frozen and
getting above 6% versus if you're using
dried and cured and getting above 6%
reducing the percentage of monot Turpin
that are present in the hash which
really for decades we always dried those
out we cured those out of flour because
they were harsh but now
I'll tell you life is so [ __ ] trippy
man here's a trip Colin so my buddy
sends he's like I want to send you some
patella so he sends me this beautiful
little piece of patella dude do you know
what this looks like to me Colin hash it
looks like bubble hash that didn't get
dried properly this was like back in the
original days we you'd get shamed for
this now it's the hottest thing I know
we are so [ __ ] as human beings like
what the [ __ ] that is I I guess it only
happens when you get older where you
start seeing these like 25 years Cycles
where you're like so like the thing that
everyone shamed everyone for and mocked
everyone I'll never forget someone
putting a piece of hash down like this
at Legends one year I think it was Nick
it just he he wasn't able to dry it on
time it was definitely nothing against
him and he put it in front of Rob and
Dave and they literally just like
grabbed it and like was like that one's
wet and like didn't even try it just
threw it to the side and I do understand
it because and and not not to say
patella smokes like it's wet it just
looks like it's wet and the reason I
would say that is because probably the
same thing that's happening with hash
that you leave water in which is that
water sort of makes its way out of the
hash eventually by foaming the hash up
patella because you're sealing it in a
in a turkey bag the tpin are doing the
same thing they have they're under
pressure and they're they're they're
traveling outward and as they travel
outward they foam up the hash and that's
what patella is guaranteed 100% for sure
but it totally looks like buttered wet
hash from the 90s and it did make me
chuckle it does yeah it's funny so I
because I said the same thing to myself
but then I moved on fast from that but
that thought but you know the one thing
I want to go back to what you brought up
about the dry cure versus the fresh
Frozen versus you know chemically what's
there I think it's a good call out
because it's it's also why some people
like you know certain types of herb over
others you know it's it's it has a lot
to do with the chemical profile and the
the you know the chemotype that that has
become over the life cycle of of its of
its time you know that the choices that
that particular grower that processor
made you know that's the relatable
aspect of the actual like the actual
medium you know so when I think about
that I think you're you're calling out a
really important aspect that I think is
yet to really come into Focus for us
like I think these are things I know you
and I and people like as well as Tony
and other a lot of us have had these
conversations together that hey yeah
like these are different products
because by by Design like chemically
like they're just different you know so
I think that's that's really important
it's why I think you know I've worked
with a toxicologist for the past three
years of my time you know doing what
I've been doing with formulation and
dude I've learned you know I'll just be
really candid with everyone I've learned
so much about you know how these CTIC
chemicals harm our bodies um and it's
you know literally cells dying you know
so from that point of view I think Mark
you're you're touching on something real
like the the upper echelon from fresh
frozen there's chemicals there that are
actually protecting our you know our
bodies versus ing them but there's also
not really a clear understanding of what
those are so um I think it's important
that dude I honestly feel like we're all
still in kindergarten it's like man
imagine imagine Sam he's been doing this
for like 40 to 50 years and he also
probably feels like he's in
kindergarten it's just an endless array
of like and then we discover something
like rosin how crazy is rosin or even
bubble hash like water has like how
crazy are those those two
things without those two things the face
of cannabis extracts would look so
different right now they uh they blow my
mind I was happy to be around for both
of them you know to be like right on the
ground floor for both of those things uh
I wasn't the first person to do it by
any means but I'll tell you like it
wasn't far after soil grown press that
bud on Instagram that he was on hash
Church episode 25 talk talking about
well you know we were we were making
flags with our full melt you know like
in the parchment and then you'd you know
zip it with your titanium Dabber and
then pull a flag and it would be a long
flag of hash he was like we were making
flags and I ranan out of hash and he's
like and I don't know why but I was just
like I just put a bud in the parchment
and I hit that with the hair
straightener instead of like doing this
to Hash to melt it he just randomly like
for no reason did it to a flower and
then he's like when I opened it up he
was like there was oil all around it and
it was like I think he was with his dad
or something but they were both tripping
out at the whole concept of this and I
mean my goodness thank thank thank
goodness that uh that it came to be
because
personally I I quite love Rosen I really
do enjoy it but what I like about it the
most is that kids of this generation now
when I say kids like you know 18 to 25
year old guys that are like just
experimenting for the first time they're
no longer blasting cans of butane like
in a very very dangerous environment
that literally could change their lives
forever forever like you have no idea
till you have kids what that means like
I just don't want my kids to tattoo
their face or or burn those are the two
things I'm like do whatever else you
want but just like keep your face your
face don't burn don't you know I grew up
with a father who was a fireman so we
took burning super serious I couldn't
believe how many people were willing to
risk their lives I'd see people posting
on Instagram like a girl in a bikini top
on a on a balcony blasting a can and in
the background you can see something
plugged into the wall outlet outside on
the deck with her and I'm just like oh
my God like that [ __ ] inside the wall is
just sparking like if you could shrink
down and go in the wall you'd see that
they spark continually and so and butane
is heavy so it sinks and it pools right
at the level of this oh my goodness you
know it's one thing to make a mistake
and hurt yourself but when you burn
yourself and now you're burnt for life
that's a real bummer so I love rosin for
that reason alone the fact that dudes
can just go grab a hair straightener and
like have a dab in the afternoon from a
flower that's
amazing big
supporter
100%
100 oh yeah I don't miss the open blast
days no exactly it should just be in a
lab with someone who's really good at it
and they understand all the Sops and
they have the C1 D1 room and like they
have degrees and chemistry like those
are good guys to like yeah yeah you guys
do that over there I'm not against the
thing about myself that I learned
especially after accidentally sort of
stumbling AC AC ac across water hash and
then really focusing and popularizing it
what really blew me away was just the
absolute and
complete different level of high that
you experienced compared to flow cuz I
had taken flour right to the ceiling I
was just on the ceiling just smoking so
much flour that uh I'll be honest I was
coughing [ __ ] up I'd be like I haven't
coughed anything up in like 28 years and
I smoke a lot of
hash you don't cough you don't cough
stuff up when you just smoke
hash yeah I I think for me it's
like having the flavors around me are
more important I mean I do appreciate
the flower I mean I definitely get into
like when I'm feno hunting I definitely
try a lot of the different fos just so I
understand got to love the flow dude the
flow I haven't smoked flour in 28 years
but holy 20 good flower my man 20 crazy
no 24 years 24 years sorry um but I love
flour I just look at it as like it's my
little resin it's like the pizza box you
know it's brought me my pizza it's like
thank you oh pizza box but I don't eat
the pizza box I usually open it up and
take the pizza out so that's what I do I
just wash the resin or bounce the resin
or press the resin you know funny enough
my most watched video on my YouTube
channel is this me pressing a bunch of
where is my bike flower in the p uh
Longs Peak and it was like giving me
like 30% return this flour and uh I
pressed like a half pound it's just
funny that flower rosin is my most
viewed
video you know that's the world right
there like you figure it out eventually
you just figure it out eventually so
yeah props to the almost five million
people who have watched that video
that's uh that trips my mind out you
know the internet is such a trip that
you can be like I'm just going to do
this video and touch five million people
that's a lot oh yeah that is a
ton so what were some of your uh you
know your your likes and dislikes of
Legends I would like to make Legends
better every year so I always like to
hear some criticisms but uh I like to
hear the likes first so that I can feel
a little bit good about it before we get
taken down a couple of
notches I
love yeah you guys go first man go for
it uh we don't we haven't I've never
been to an event like that um we they
don't really we don't really do stuff
like that out here it's more like I
don't know the vendor style popups so I
mean it's I don't know man it's just it
was all about the culture it was
beautiful I mean the way everything was
set up the um yeah man it was just best
event that we've ever been to personally
the way the judging was set up I like
that too yeah you know that everybody
just gotta kind of Judge everybody
else's stuff you couldn't necessarily
like buy judge kits or anything like
that you know what I mean it was just
Community you know what I mean was there
go up to the hash bar and grab some
flavors
yeah awesome that was awesome man the
food was awesome and the people could
experience also the you know the judge
kits but through the hash bar you know
and not so they could experience what we
were experiencing at the same time that
was that's awesome that that's not yeah
that's nothing I've experienced before
so that was really cool yeah you usually
can't try you know the entries that are
sitting there or whatever you you need
to
experience it's the beauty of California
man it's pretty cool was pretty cool it
was a it was definitely a gauntlet
though trying to get through all that
hash man that's for
sure it definitely uh it puts you it
shows you where your boundaries are and
it's an interesting um you know listen
this happened by accident when we
started Legends of hash it had nothing
to do with a competition it was like Sam
sort of was like wanted to turn it into
a competition because for me what I said
was I would sell tickets
to people who showed me a beautiful
piece of hash so I knew that they were
on a level of appreciation of hash that
they actually had one in their pocket I
didn't take any I didn't you know even
smoke any I just look at it feel it
smell it and be like yeah yeah you get
to come to Legends of hash you get to
buy a ticket to Legends of hash because
another thing about Legends was we never
it wasn't about ever comping tickets
everyone paid to be there and it was uh
the original one well
was very very different in the sense
that you couldn't promote your business
you couldn't promote yourself um you
weren't allowed to have a cell phone
present at the event there was no
cameras allowed uh there was really no
talking about it on social media or
anything like that because most of that
[ __ ] didn't exist but um yeah it was
different you know it was uh a lot of
old school hash Smugglers went to the
original ones and they just uh they were
serious dudes and they couldn't be they
they could not be a a photo Tak of them
so we made it very strict that you
couldn't bring cameras and in fact if
you had a cell phone even out in your
hand you you would be removed from the
premises so it was a fairly strict uh
cell phone dash camera rule at Legends
um and and no no promotions whatsoever
so then at that point Sam was like wow
like everyone in this room all 50 people
have nice hash he's like we should do
like a a little contest and then all of
a sudden you know like back then you
have to understand too like skunkman Sam
was like the snuff alpus like people
only really knew about him through
stories they didn't know that he was a
real person or until you know this was
way before hash Church obviously that
exposed a lot of people to him but um he
was low-key and people just didn't know
who he was and this was also after you
know a lot of them were after um 2008
which was when I posted the photo of his
dry sift for the first time which and I
don't know if you guys ever saw that
picture but it was uh it was a game
changer I labeled it
99.99999% pure heads skunkman Sam secret
Tech or whatever on IC M and uh yeah
it's just like pure heads just looks
like caviar it's uh
actually yeah there's one behind me but
you kind of can't see it it's like right
there it's just pure heads pure
beautiful heads and
uh everyone had wanted to smoke when I
first smoked his hash it was the
strongest experience I had ever
experienced in my entire life that [ __ ]
rocked me so
hard it brought all these stories to
life that Rob had been telling me in
previous years about how high he would
leave skunkman Sam's house and I'd be
like well how high could you really be
man and I just didn't know but [ __ ] I I
figured it out at one point I left there
so high I'm quite certain I was walking
like a one-legged
man like it was it was over the top I
haven't been that high actually in in
probably 20 years more than 20 years I
think those are highs that just come
around maybe a couple of times in a
lifetime like when you're in grade eight
and you first hit some
dabs and then apparently when
you're that's how leges was for me that
night man holy I haven't been that high
in so long in so long or ever I don't
know about um I don't I don't know it
was definitely like the first days maybe
never yeah maybe never I mean we were
that's all I'm saying it's a potential
candidate that's enough oh yeah oh yeah
for sure by far some the most out smoke
that's for sure yeah lots of dabs lots
of dab lots of good dabs though yeah
like really good
dabs like absolutely spectacular I think
it's a part of the culture that I'd like
to see grow I'd like to see more people
have access I know that you know and the
one thing about Legends it is very much
professional what I'd also love to see
legends become is to be able to bring
other people to witness the culture
without feeling alienated and being able
to take like micro dabs you know get
served like microscopic dabs without any
shaming and weird ego I take bigger dabs
this [ __ ] guy's dad you know like
that whole vibe and it does exist like
it exists
100% um it would be nice to bring in
other people to witness this part of the
culture um and and just you
know be a part of it but without being
like like frighteningly high you know
like you have to really it would be a
fraction of a pin head just a a little
bit of the flavor you know they're not
even going to blow anything but they're
going to feel a little flavor and they
obviously have to smoke weed I usually
can give a micro dab and make it feel
like you've taken one puff on a joint
you know that's a very small amount of
resin but if they want to feel like they
smoke the whole joint well that's a
little bit more and if you want to feel
like you smoked five joints well here
you go
bam but we got to learn how to do that I
think it's an important part of dabbing
culture I also think that D Nail's new
unit yes is
absolutely going to help change the way
we look at dabbing because the torch is
very sketchy and it's not indoor
friendly uh and it's probably never
going to happen dnails are better you
know the coils and stuff and that new
induction disorderly uh um conducts new
little coil Banger heater but the D but
the denail one that have you guys seen
that thing oh yeah oh my god dude it is
so beads me too I love it the denail
looks like even the next step above that
tsv is so loud yeah I ordered the
XL yeah as soon as I saw it as soon as I
saw it I had to get it I was just like
ah this will make everything I've got
I've got a pre-order list if you guys if
anyone isn't on one I can put you on my
pre-order list because I'm going to be
I'm going to be selling them Brian I've
been working with him for years and uh
he just does such great work he really
Tak this [ __ ] seriously and uh I mean I
love my TPU V I just had I didn't like
the sound of it on all the time it's
annoying and it's a very white noise I
just thought you know and I was just
talking to Brian one day from Dil about
it and I guess he had been working on it
I had no idea but I was like dude if you
could just create a TPU veed style you
know vaporizer and he'd already been
working on it of course like as if I'm
giving this guy advice and uh I swear to
God he showed me this like three days
later later after I mentioned it that's
why I was like how could you how did you
create that in three days he's like dude
I've been working on it for months you
just happened to say something three
days ago I was like oh all right indu
like nice job indux did a good job on
theirs too the bird that's really oh
yeah dude listen that that that's next
level that's something completely
different this is like you could do um
real dab bars like a tool like this
brings dab bars into the equation it's
protected you're less likely to burn
yourself even those outer coils with the
cable are sketch as [ __ ] um this thing
could hit the ground and not be burning
anyone or hurting anyone this is the
future of dab bars um where it's no
sound it's Sleek you just got people
raising and lowering them [ __ ] some will
probably put these little things on a on
a little air pre compressor with a
little pedal on the floor so you can
make them go up and down with your
like I'm I'm a dreamer man I'm a dreamer
I see vapor bars are coming and vapor
bars are not going to have joints smoked
in them they're not going to have
anything burned in them they're going to
be like gummies drinks and vaporization
of flowers and extracts that's it yeah
at least here in Canada I don't know
what's going to happen in the in the US
but definitely the future it'll be the
same way in New York like as we turn
stuff on there I'll tell you it'll
really open up the door for cannabis
people as the cigar culture is like
dying cannabis people come in and buy
those grandfathered cigar shops where
you could invite people to smoke joints
indoors and hang out with one another
like that would also be very popular
[ __ ] private like cannabis
afficionados group where you just go and
burn
Gaggers on on leather furniture with the
boys
that's [ __ ] funny man I need to open
one of
those well you know what the license is
hard to get because in most places now
you can't smoke indoors even with the
big HEPA system or whatever um but the
grandfathered ones in most cities are
the cigar shops there's there's still
clubs where people go and literally
smoke cigars just in the open air around
each other I can't imagine how
unenjoyable that is personally being in
like a room with like 20 dudes all just
chuffing away hard on cigars but I could
I could hang out in the room getting
joint smoked for a little while that
hares my throat out too though I won't
lie yeah that's a whole different kind
of hot box were there a lot of joints
smoked at
Legends no I I had a big shout out to to
Jay happy monkey crew I had Jay there he
uh he was he was one of the few Chief
and down nice you know he was good
though was you know
enjoyed himself repping repping the The
Joint smokers you know there was a
couple couple hash holes the in
inventing room guy gave us a couple hash
holes to try those were delicious oh
yeah yeah Ron our buddy Ron had some
hash holes with him from sensey
mag oh yeah Ron okay yeah yeah oh Ron
that's how we got uh turoa I guess Ron
was the one that told him about us so oh
I'm glad he did yeah
man yeah dude yeah there there's a lot
of good hash out here in Oklahoma I
think you know I know we got our
problems there's a lot of over
production of low quality stuff out here
but there's also a lot of good hash out
here just because of the level of
competition and how easy it was to get
into it in the beginning uh it's just
pushed us all to I mean makes have fire
yeah we're really proud of what Oklahoma
is yeah
we're glad that we got to share that
with people so thank you guys for that
us
too it's all about good hash man we're
yeah that's it man that is absolutely it
it's uh it's just a nice thing to see
the culture of hash continuing and
that's what Legends tries to do it tries
to pay homage to the to the roots to the
old school although I I really you know
I had someone recently who's in
California he's actually in New York too
Colin he's in California he's partnered
up with some pretty well-known people in
the industry and he's doing like an uh
like a traditional hash he's like
there's people that just still love
traditional hash you know the old school
gold seal whatever you want to call it
and um so he's he's talking about this
hash and how he wants to kind of get it
out to the world and promote it and he
was like I was sorry to not see more of
that at Legends cuz he was at Legends
and I said well listen man like Legends
isn't like what we make it it's what you
make it so if you want more uh
traditional hash of course we'd love cuz
what he said was he said it was an
amazing event but he said I felt like it
was just one section that we were
visiting of the event you know the
dabbers that everyone was dabbing he
said he was like it was a bit cracky
there was a lot of blow torches he's
just from a different culture right he's
not he's not torching his so when you
don't Tor blow torch your bangers like
it is to see a whole like 150 people
doing that like
it's hardcore so he was like I'd like to
see a traditional hash I'm like well
then get your friends from different
traditional hash companies to bring in
traditional hash and show us so that we
can of course we'd love to have a
traditional hash section where you could
come and see the hash of old and learn
about how it was made and meet people
from those cultures that are continuing
those um you know those lineages on I I
love the idea of Legends always paying
homage to that but legends is also the
curation of the of the present of what
is at the upper echelons of hash and
oils and all the equipment that goes
behind it from the bangers to the dab
rights to the cardas and the puff
Co which is also I have to give both
those companies a shout out ca and
puffco um focus V for really normalizing
dabbing you know their commercials are
almost so generic in the sense of the
way you just see like the straightest
looking people you know they're painting
this different narrative which will like
for me I want that bridge I love our
culture i and that's not going anywhere
but I also love the idea of building a
bridge so people can come and experience
our culture and see what it is because
it's a pretty cool culture especially if
you love you know smoking hash and
getting high you don't have to get
annihilated you don't have to go to
Legends and smoke you know 27 G but it's
[ __ ] fun if you
do yeah the second day I ran into a guy
who I know is trying to do a traditional
hash brand he said the exact same thing
to me he's like what's up with like
everyone just using blowtorches like I
don't see any like
traditional hash at all and you know I
think that's to your point it's all in
which we make it because you're you're
just offering us a platform to submit
things so if predominantly everyone
starts submitting a traditional hash
maybe that merits a traditional hash
category I don't
know maybe we're we're looking at maybe
we're all trying to group things
together in ways that perhaps it's not
not the right way to look at it I don't
know just asking the question you
know because the things have you know
honestly evolves so much you know like
think about you know we were just talk
touching on the whole fact that like if
someone came with like a
Sheen to the party with you know a brick
Sheen like that we'd be like yeah that's
wet like we're not going to even try
that to now we look for CU visual cues
like that to signify how good it is you
know I know that's super tripped out
dude and it's different though too right
cuz like the thing about it was I guess
what I learned to you know to connect to
the wet hash was that foamy like
expanded so I learned to hate that
because when I'd smoke it when I dab it
it would just be like it would [ __ ] up
the hit so I was like [ __ ] this is not
like being and that was my own fault
like when I first made bubble I just
like finger pressing wet bubble in my
hand showing the whole world how to do
it like that and then it literally took
me like five to 10 years of being like
listen I [ __ ] up stop doing this you
know and people just kept doing it for
years like just rolling up wet bubble
and it it hurt my soul so badly I'm like
wow like one [ __ ] mistake I make
while sharing this information and I got
to pay this karmic debt for the next
five to 10 [ __ ] years and then people
be like hey dude check out my hash crack
this ball of hash under my nose and I'd
just be like oh my God it's like totally
gone bad it's like this [ __ ] guy
rolled up wet hash it's just like it
sells like a like a wet sock in a dirty
to I'm like bro and it was my own like
it was like the universe just like kept
showing it to me and showing it to me
and showing it to me and I was like wow
like when you do educate people you
should be careful that you educate
yourself first I did start a little
early probably should have just done the
process for four or five years and then
started teaching but instead I taught
everyone my mistakes for four or five
years and then I learned them myself
well there he
is but there was I think there was a
time on the forums that you know things
were traveling at at a really fast pace
because I remember when we met on the
forums we were weird just think like
threads happened fast people were trying
stuff I mean and we were mainly washing
in smaller bag systems then um because
our plant counts were so small I mean
just was a totally different time you
know like things moved at such a slow
pace
so like yeah your information that came
out was like it just like happened until
it didn't dude all I know is I was like
the only [ __ ] with f out out of
every single person I always met ever
and then all the people I met after with
full melt were all people that I turned
on made hash with and got you know like
turned them on to the information so it
was what an incredible blessing to be
allowed to be a part of that because I'm
telling you I showed I personally for
sure showed hundreds if not over a
thousand people in person and I'll never
forget pulling that bag you know the
gold bag would be the first bag that
like a a chunk would come out and
people's I called it the eyebrow raise I
just see people like this and then they
go their eyes would go up and it was
like that's right [ __ ] that's
right because before that when you're
pouring the water in the icing into the
bucket no one can wrap their head around
that they're like you [ __ ] idiot like
you're not supposed to do that that is
the stupidest [ __ ] thing you could do
to cured weat welcome Addison by the way
I hope you're feeling better brother
yeah a little better got a I guess I got
like a it's from my diet it's from
eating carnivore and all that stuff all
the time and I guess um you can get like
these pockets in your intestine because
I don't like salad I don't like [ __ ]
grain or any of that stuff so now I got
those guys e you need some Fiber bro yes
so now they're like the the doctor's
just like look some people need to eat
kale and you're one of them so listen I
will say this kale can be delicious when
when prepared properly and it's bitter
when it's not prepared properly you need
to get some like awesome like kale
Caesar salad or something oh yeah no I
got it all figured out it's it's like I
know what it is and I kind of walk that
fine line because I like that diet so
much but this is the first time that I
ever got like a this acute Di
verticulitis which is you know you can
get these like Pockets I guess in your
intestine so but nothing major it's it's
minor it's like a a liquid diet for a
couple days and then so mostly like bone
broth and electrolytes and stuff like
that for like two or three days and then
uh everything's good but yeah nothing
major well we were giving you much
praise earlier brother just talking
about the Legends talking about we
haven't heard from cashier yet he'll
kind of probably tell us his story next
but we've been talking to to the
Oklahoma guys and in great detail of
their journey and how it was uh Rob I
guess from sensey mag that turned you on
to them awesome Ron thank you oh Ron
thank you Ron Kowski or yeah yeah okay
Ron's a good dude Ron was real helpful
with uh when I reached out to him you
know because we wanted to have makers
from more places you know and especially
in places where we feel like they've
established you know they've done a good
enough job in there you know you get in
this little pocket and you're hunt and
you've got the you know the the the the
blessing of the state and you're doing
all this stuff and you know if you're in
your little pocket and you're away from
everybody else there's stuff that just
kind of builds over there and I think
Oklahoma and especially the guys at
skunk are just proof of that that you
know guys are going to get a hold of
genetics they're gonna get a hold of
tech they're they're looking at all the
same stuff and just because they're in a
place you know that's not where you are
which because they're in Oklahoma or
they're somewhere else um doesn't mean
they're not making fire and I think they
proved that so that's uh you know same
with Ace lure I think my my favorite
entry of the entire event was number
three from Ace lure which I think was
like a galato or something um but yeah
it's just you know and asur is from St
Louis Missouri of all places so um yeah
it was cool this year I learned that
from the bags dude every because people
be like where's the best hash and I'm
like wherever I am dude because I carry
these bags with me and I roll and I make
cash wherever I am and of course people
are growing dank weed everywhere you
just have to find those people cuz what
people do is they go somewhere and
they're like yeah I went to so and so
[ __ ] weed sucked and I'll be like
correction your ability to find good
weed sucked and therefore you found bad
weed but um everywhere has great stuff
and uh all you have to do is you know
make the hash press the hash doesn't
matter where you are if you're if you've
got if you got a hold of those
genetics which I mean you can buy them
from seed banks it's not like you need
some special clone or or something
gifted down from the [ __ ] Gods can
pull fenos right out of these bag bags
of seed that you can buy it's it's a
beautiful thing yeah I think you need
knowledge you need the network and you
just need the desire to do it and I
think that's everyone we everyone we met
and everyone we meet has all those
things you know they're not people
always think people always think
knowledge comes from the mentor it's
like no wisdom comes from the mentor
knowledge comes from your
mistakes yep
[ __ ] it up like you were saying earlier
it was so
counterintuitive to take material and
add it with ice and water it was so
counterintuitive it was like what are
you [ __ ] doing and then even the dry
sift methods are kind of
counterintuitive so I think it's you
know when you walk people down that
direction and they see it um it's crazy
now because there just seems to be so
much everywhere and then even for guys
like us which you know we understand the
microns we understand um you know what
they're pulling and as the rosin and the
hash world is getting more and more
mature meaning that you know more
consumers are having access to it you're
watching we're watching consumers get
duped in a way um you know because they
are they are happy to and unknowingly
gonna smoke on some 45u or some 25u or a
mix of those other microns and they're
going to be like hey this is hash and
we're going to be like when we clean the
Banger we're gonna be like what the
hell's going on here so there's that
little learning curve that's kind of
there and I think we watched it here
inali California over the last three
years four years where people were like
well I can get rosin for much cheaper
and you're like oh cool get it for
cheaper and then then they start to get
it from where they're getting it and
then they realize like oh this is this
is like the bottom of the barrel stuff
the stuff that I tried with them with
those guys in that little sesh that
shit's crazy how do I get that and it's
like oh well that's
this yeah you pay for it there's levels
to it for sure there's levels to it for
sure you know and that's the beautiful
thing about ha it's uh it's Dynamic and
there's people who still love their
traditional hashes and pressing it
feeling it and crumbling it up and
smoking it in joints I I got to admit I
don't smoke a lot of it but when I smell
it in the air I'm like oh [ __ ] you're
smoking some of that hash just reminds
me of you know being younger and I did
smoke a lot of hash back in those days
well it's a journey and you see them on
the path and you're like oh you're on
the path [ __ ] cool and then you go
back to your your house and you're like
I got my timer I got my [ __ ] temp
thing I got my dunk dank I got the
slurpers I got this it's like get yeah
but we're sociopaths dude that's we're
trou we're definitely
broken we the hey I want to hear from
cash a so uh how what was Legends like
for you
brother you know uh half our team was
coming straight from MJ biscon which was
uh you know what an absolutely Dynamic
like what so that's like you went to
chadon and then you went to
Legends
yeah completely different experiences
obviously I think you did it in the
right order definitely um we ran through
MJ biscon as fast as you possibly can
and you know met the people that we've
done business with and all that kind of
stuff and um it's wild you know going
through these events for five 10 15
years you run into the same people and
they're like oh you're not with this
company then you used to be with these
guys so like you you know for us we end
up just talking to people that we know
um but it you know so that was cool um
but it was a
challenge uh you know kind of changing
over to Legends of hashish and I think
uh I uh I think we probably
underestimated how uh how many you know
entries we were going to have to uh go
through um and I don't think we uh
prepared adequately for that um yeah but
let me tell you there is no adequate
preparation for that actually it's
psychotic and it just is what it is it's
like having kids where people are like
oh I wish I could have prepared more for
having kids it's like you can't you just
have them and and they're psychotic and
then you just figure it out and and so
is Legends of hash it's that makes no
sense but you know I do want to say um
you know I we've done a lot of events
over the years and um this was a very
very cool a very special kind of
experience um and you know uh you know
we feel super honored to be a part of it
and um I just think there's a lot of
like little details that were really
really cool that you know you just don't
really see at events like you know the
specific giveaway stuff that I really
enjoy like our team has you know all
this Legends of hash stuff that we get
to use over the year and and um yeah
exactly and you know I was able to get
some stuff and bring it home to my wife
so she get to use it to and um so I
think that was really cool like the
stuff that you guys chose to give away
was all like really nice and it was not
just like mids giveaway stuff that you
normally get so I think that was really
cool um you know how the booths were set
up was really cool um uh we you know
we've we've known Scott for a long time
and so that's kind of our you know kind
of inroad into this event and it was
just kind of cool seeing him out in the
wild um you know doing his thing and you
know um I thought that that was really
cool for everyone to like see the man
himself and be able to like thres with
him and like everyone else there I I
thought that was really really cool and
that was kind of like right in the
middle um dude he's kind of like the
skunkman Sam in a sense you know cuz Sam
was always that very same thing at the
early Legends people were just like oh
my God that's him he's right there and
he's just kind of a Crazy Character
right he's just like oh [ __ ] there's
it's just you know and it's also Sam was
like kept to himself he didn't go out a
lot he was like always head down in the
greenhouse kind of thing and so to just
suddenly see him absolutely like a kid
in a [ __ ] candy store just chuffing
hash I suspect Scott was a similar way
since I've seen both I have to admit
that they are very alike in some ways
where like Scott Scott's you know
everyone is just giving him hash and
talking to him so he's kind of like oh
what do you got and oh what's over here
so he's just having so much fun but he
did tell me this year um he's like
listen we need to spread out this
judging because this was too much he's
like this and I'm like if it's too much
for you I'll definitely take your advice
because I know he I've seen him run
gauntlets on like 18 Rigs and just but
you we did have the intention of doing
that it just didn't work out and it
wasn't anything on us it was uh it was
difficult to get the entries on time to
be able to offer them a week early to
everyone and then and I'll explain the
issue so what happened was when I built
the
timeline just like a goofball I didn't
realize that when I was going to be
making that point of contact with all of
the makers it was during harvest season
so what we're going to do now to adjust
is um and I guess we could announce it
here we're going to move Legends to
January um for LA and then that way we
kind of have our own space and when we
timeline it back um everything we're
going to need to do with those makers is
going to going to be in December uh
which is a lot better for us and then
that way we'll be able to get the Ros
and judging done at home um and all
those things that we planned on doing it
was my it was my fault because I
obviously was doing so much I didn't
realize where it fell um but now we'll
be able to do it in January which means
that for Legends
2024 there will not be a Los Angeles
Legends 2024 it'll be in uh January of
2025 so I just want to say one thing
instead of a swag bag I think Legends of
hash gives away 90u bags that's what we
should call our swag bag let's call the
on the 90u bag people like is
interesting those [ __ ] at
Legends don't [ __ ] around and I thought
there was gonna be a 90u from you there
Marcus uh a nice 44 gallon for everyone
dude I'm telling you I got a represent
with bubble bags next year way more 100%
I hope to be there well not next year
but the year after you know what he said
January close to next year the way that
the gift bags work out and because I
have this hair across my ass with gift
bags I don't I go to these events and
they give you this gift bag and you're L
you literally most of the time you just
want to hand it back um it's a it's a
really low ball attempt at marketing
it's it's kind of like a it's kind of
just like a I I look at it as like a
distraction it's like oh here's a weird
bag that you get to carry around with a
bunch of [ __ ] that you probably don't
want and we kept our we kept our
agreement to the companies because we
haphazardly promoted them so with us
it's more of um we really take a long
time to make sure that each company that
we're choosing and selecting and working
with does have a product that's going to
be helpful useful something we haven't
seen before um and then we do our own
stuff like uh like you know Zar was
talking about like we have the we did
the little uh tool stands which came
from which came from like eating dinner
at we were eating dinner at a spot in LA
and then when you leave there you flip
over your little Chopstick stand and it
says I stole this from whatever the name
of the restaurant is and I was like oh
this is a [ __ ] great idea and I I
took it and I used it as a a dab stand
for a while so then I was like this is a
great thing and it kind of puts us on
their on their table they see our logo
um so it just kind of a great idea and
they're they're inexpensive they're not
super costly uh but that we put in the
sonicators we put in the um the magic
carpets which we did with um with some
people from out of country so yeah we're
super stoked man those bags yeah those
bags come together in a really cool way
and then of course the sponsors like 710
labs and davock and chillet and all
these guys that come forward um and and
make sure that we have the products DNA
and and Crockett and you know when
you're getting that much stuff in your
gift bag like I think we we we
deconstructed a gift bag and I think
we're going to release um in some some
we're going to send out some uh some
content we'll put up some content that
will show like what the actual value of
the gift bags is but I think we're going
to now refer to them as the 90u bags
which I think is great
IDE yeah shout out to DNA too um they uh
they were super nice to us and uh uh
we've been running their stuff for a
long time so it was nice to catch up
with them and get some new gear
too yeah that was dope they had some
great genetics too man all the what they
did if you saw what they did they took
honey banana which won the rosin last
year smashed and they just smash
everything with runny banana which
awesome that's gonna be a fun
one some nice things well there's
already some stuff that spun off of it
because the um the guys at Mills Chris
uh Chris and those guys at Mills AB
they've already they had that stuff
early and they were cutting Z into all
that stuff too so now there's a bunch of
these other ones that I saw that a that
AB has that are kind of using some of
those like the the strawberry um the
strawberry and the Honey banana so yeah
I'm looking forward to it I love it man
absolutely hey I got a shout out my
buddy Dan who he's got these 3D printers
and he 3D printed this little dryer that
you like put your Banger into and it
plugs in through a
USB and then it like dries your Banger
after you dunk it in the
alcohol what that's crazy yeah the
little Banger dryer that's that's it
right there little Banger dryer I have
to have these inserts because I've got
little 10 10 mil JPS there but uh what a
cool little product that is that's
beautiful so much Innovation we were
messing around with um when we were
looking at the dab dab tool stands and
some of the other stuff uh we found
these hearing aid
dryers that you that were these little
tiny hearing aid dryers and like you pop
the top open and it was mesh basket
inside and you would drop your heate in
there and close it and it would had a
fan on the bottom that would blow up
through it so we were sourcing these
things but I kept breaking them and I
was like I could not find a good source
for them because I want because a banger
would fit in there with your stuff and
you could close it up and it would just
blow air through it but well that's
basically what this is doing yeah that's
a great looking product so um cash how
was uh did you guys get over to Ego
Clash afterward or we did not
um yeah uh definitely kind of uh for us
it was a little bit under the radar so I
think we're kind of just late to even
finding out about it I mean we're pretty
late to uh Legends as well uh sorry
about that we didn't we we weren't the
ones holding it all up but uh no you
guys killed it yeah you guys it but um
yeah uh you know how it goes I think you
know shout out to all the other
competitors because especially from
excuse me you know from from Oklahoma
and and New York it sounds like uh the
logistics there are uh significantly
more difficult than what we have to deal
with we're La so like uh uh huge
congratulations to you guys because we
we've been through it uh trying to do an
event in you know around the country and
and that that is uh extremely difficult
to do and so you know huge
congratulations Chris and Colin and and
Logan I know it's a little bit easier
for you then there but uh you know that
that is um something to be proud of and
obviously your guys' entries re fire too
so
a lot of heat man a lot of heat
congratulations Colin that was a it was
good to see you up there for sure and
and I just you gave me that jar when I
left and I've I held on to it and I I
actually was looking last night I was
gonna take a dab and I'm like oh [ __ ] I
got the I got the winner right here so I
got to try that so that was really nice
man very smooth thank you so that's
different than what I gave you is
actually different than what I won with
but okay it's still in the same we what
I would consider the G same gas category
but still has some like some
complexities there I don't know like
whenever you try it
like different T at different tents it's
like gassy but also like tropical floral
smooth it's like I don't know it's it's
interesting but um yeah I appreciate it
man in the vent like just kind of going
on that a minute was was amazing for so
many reasons you know from looking at
from last year to this year last year
was great but this year I felt like had
a better layout and the hash bar was
really focused and it just had a really
good flow to it and you know it was good
to see Don and Aaron of course and um I
picked up their the pack that they had
they they hooked me up on that and got
some other other single packs from those
them as well stoked we're really stoked
to put that into the into the green
houses this
summer um but overall I mean it just I
think I thought the judging was much
better this year I felt like it it
really was really honest like it just
you didn't you just had no idea like I
to be honest like completely forgot I
didn't even know what our number was I
had to call my cousin I was like yo like
what number are we um and that was even
after the fact because I didn't even
know um it was good it was good to go
through it and just kind of be
methodical and and really give everybody
the time of a day but I also agree with
Scott um and I understand the
circumstances it was uh I you know I can
you know I love hash so I definitely
will will will definitely go through it
all but it was uh I do use like three
different rigs to be honest I'm glad I
used an e- rig a little bit and then I
went back to my my room um later in the
night and I was I was just using a
regular rig
and yeah but it was there was some
really Dynam DC flavors so everyone out
there man like congrats and you know
skunk you guys crushed it they had
really great entries um really enjoyed
yours I think I remember yours
specifically um when someone asked me I
was talking to Alex I think from hashte
about that um so really good job guys um
solid all around yeah shout out shout
out to Alex too the the just the just
having him there and I think just having
like the energy that he brings with his
team and how they're cutting the video
and like he's really Leading The Way
with like day two we woke up and he had
a video cut from day one that was
running that morning so it's like he's
really on top of it yeah shout out to
those guys man they they do a really
good job and I think you know there are
certain things this year that we tried
to really narrow down on and focus on
one of them was the hash bar the other
was um the layout so it's good to hear
people um recognizing some of that stuff
and it's you know that it's it's not
hard to be prepared and to lay it all
out I think we we spent a little more
this year on production and then the
actual like team of producing the event
so I think that paid off a lot for us
too and it gave us the ability to to put
on an event that we had all the boxes
checked but one of the major components
that made it so great was that we really
didn't have any makers that were late or
that were holding us up or that were you
know causing problems and and you know
that'll happen sometimes because you got
Logistics and you got so many different
moving Parts but for this year it was I
mean didn't have any issues and then
after the event didn't have a single
maker have any issues or complaints um
you know we had one little hiccup where
the judges boxes that we ordered uh
because there was an issue with Printing
and they weren't uh honest about it it
actually didn't arrive on time so we're
shipping those out now but it gives us
like that little Comet Tail to be able
to reach back out and send those to you
guys as well as the uh the new product
uh Carta is launching a brand new
product that they're going to send out
to each one of the judges so gives us a
little touch point after the event and
sometimes you can turn those lemons in
lemonade make it good um so it was uh
but best year yet man even talking to
Meredith even talking to Golden um we
had you know just great sponsors great
makers everything worked out the guests
were amazing everyone you know didn't
have any issues any trouble so um I
think we might have bent the gate a
little bit with h with some mistakes
that we made but you know we'll pay for
that but uh everything else man it was
really uh you know from all the work
that we put into it when it all works
out and when everyone has a blast it's
just a hugest payoff ever so I got to
thank everyone um you know for coming
out and doing it and there's nothing
better than um tormenting your friends
with hash you know there's nothing
better than uh putting the boys through
the gauntlet or the ringer and you know
watch putting the fear of God into
Dey and kind of seeing them are you the
funniest one honestly was
Darby because every time I'd go see
Derby he'd just be like oh man this is
so great you know he's just having so
much fun JP is a monster though that guy
can smoke hash like nothing I've ever
seen in my entire life so um shout out
to those guys too man they all made
Awards um we had the great you know
section of the awards ceremony when they
were giving stuff out and I think every
person that won anything from them was
just blown away with what the actual
prizes were and what they got so nothing
like getting a hand blown you know
trophy from any one of those three guys
so shout out to them and shout out to
the winners for sure yeah that's awesome
for
sure yeah just you know to close out my
thoughts on the event I think it's like
it's I'm excited to see what you guys
are able to do next year and you know
thanks so much for for the invite again
and you know it was steep out there man
there was a lot of good entries so um
and big shout out to Brian from best
friend Farms who uh is going to be
working with us in New York so um oh
nice yeah we're still is that is that
who put in the material for you guys so
we had part of the material we grew
ourselves which we have our own living
soil beds and then Brian contributed
some material that we we grew or he grew
indoor living soil um called gas mask
and gas mask was a part of that we
blended with two other uh really one
other batch that we had it was like like
I'd say it was a a quarter of of the
batch was was the gas mask so it was uh
it adds it's a nice it's a really good
varietal Brian's a super talented grower
it's the material was phenomenal we just
yeah it just was meant to be so and it's
funny because I was telling Marcus like
we did a batch just with Brian that was
meant for it and then when we watched it
I called Brian I was like this just
isn't it like for whatever reason and so
we went back in and uh my cousin and I
kind of kind of came up with this so big
shout out to Z the rest of the team
great work great work man yeah no we
appreciate it man it was uh it was one
of those situations where I think just
putting it all together and at all
working out was perfect and you know
I've talked to a bunch of people
afterward that are um you know some
people want to compare Legends to other
events and or compare other events to
other events and I think it's it's kind
of a slippery slope because why would
you do that when you can attend both
events and have a great time they might
be different speeds they might be at
different places they might have
different formats but um you know you
you get out of it what you put into it
and if you go into it with a good
attitude and you go into it with uh you
know with a desire to meet people and
have fun and and rip some turps and have
a blast they're all awesome you know
it's it's afterward uh or or the people
that I think don't enjoy themselves that
want to criticize and and try to draw
these dividing lines and it's the same
thing in politics right now it's the
same thing you know in wars and other
[ __ ] everyone wants you to kind of
decide and it's like we're not we don't
have that issue we're not politics we're
not any of those things we're hash so
just go and have fun and smoke hash and
have a great time whether it's at ego
whether it's at Legends whether it's at
the hash ball whether it's at a local
thing where you're going to um because
you know the more you do that and have a
good time and have a great attitude and
good energy toward it the better the
event is for everyone um and then the
more fun you [ __ ] have you know you
get Good Hat you have a great time so
I'm not one to compare um I was bummed
that I didn't get to get up to elego
clash actually I enjoy uh those type of
events you know but I just it was my
daughter's birthday um so I wasn't able
to make it up to it but uh I sent the
message to Brandon and and we talked a
little bit so and I know they killed it
you know they had a great event looks
like it was probably one of their
biggest ones they've ever had um so yeah
love you know love to those guys and and
shout out to anyone who doing an event
because I know how much goes into it I
know how much how many things go wrong
and then how you deal with those things
are really going to determine whether or
not you're going to have a successful
event
so I appre apprciate you doing these
events because you know there was a
period of time there for everyone that
you know we're like [ __ ] this will never
happen again you know and so uh you know
big props to you and and everyone else
throwing these events again because you
know the culture you know there was
definitely uh you know a fear that would
really kind of go to the Wayside and
especially um you know in in California
so um yeah stoked that uh these are
happening again yeah or to or that it
goes to like profiteers like people who
are just putting on minimal
infrastructure and you know there's card
T there's card tables and shit's just
kind of more like a sesh which which
still has its place a sesh is a great
place to go and get you know find some
deals and find some great stuff and see
who you like but um we try to provide
something that just had
every corner every turn would impress us
would make us kind of you know say oh
this is nice you know we've stayed in
nice hotels and we've been to Great
events and we've done those things so um
the food is something that I think I
wanted to ask you guys about because I I
I personally get to set the entire menu
um so that's a lot of stuff that I like
and that's probably why I have this uh
this gut issue but um I just wanted to
get some feedback from you guys about
the food what did you think about the
food what did you think about that
stuff uh I'll go uh first I guess um I
think the food was really good however I
don't think there um it could have been
food that okay I'll put it to you like
this if there was like a fire Taco
Stand um I would have been totally down
for that you know um I'm a simple guy so
maybe um some of those flavors were more
than um I wanted to challenge my body
with at that event um but yeah I think
um I think it was good you know bunch of
my team had some um yeah I think if you
if I was to have a a
suggestion um and this is a logistical
nightmare uh before I before I say it is
like you know how can you get maybe one
or two or three food trucks with
different Cuisines so get appeal to like
different people um I think you know if
that's something it logistically that's
a nightmare but um
yeah yeah just personally that's
something I would never do I think the
the food truck kind of creates a A vibe
that's definitely I mean you're standing
there and there's a there's three or
four lines now and there's you know the
food truck can run out of food and you
have less control so it's when you're
delivering that much food to somebody
you have to have you have to understand
all of it and what's going to go out
there so food trucks I think are dope
that's just something that I don't think
we'll ever do but um and there's also a
reason for the menu the reason for the
menu is also Marcus originally did it in
a leevan restaurant so he wanted that's
Mar that's the Marcus half is like to
have Lebanese food and to pick a great
restaurant so Legends started in a
Lebanese restaurant so we want to have
the Lebanese food and then I bring in
from my childhood of skateboarding and
being an [ __ ] in Boston we used to go
to these um we' go to these big brunches
at these huge hotels and there'd be like
20 of us and we'd be all roasted and we
go in there and just like eat and then
take a bunch of croissant with us and
leave and that was kind of part of
that's my addition to it is like well
brunch is the greatest thing ever if
you're high um so that's kind of how the
two menus come together um but Taco I
just got to think about taco trucks
where I've been to too many events and
there's like a hamburger truck and a
taco truck and it just kind of I feel
like uh it's not like a sit down thing
to eat and we want people to have like
sit down and enjoy hash and sit down and
enjoy food um so that's kind of why we
go in that direction but I think we
can we can of course figure out things
that are a little more simple but that's
why we do if you went there's a fruit
bar that has cut fruit the whole time it
has drinks it has tea it has water it's
kind of like a little Oasis that just
has more simple stuff to kind of keep
you um recharged and charged while
you're doing the event so we could
probably add and if you looked over
there there were like a lot of finger
foods and stuff that was going out on
that other side um over by the hash bar
we had like a massive section that we
were serving other food at so I
definitely missed that I don't know how
I mean I was in a in a in a cloud of
smoke roasted yeah well that's where the
definitely didn't see that so the same
spot that we had all the drinks so
there's a massive drink bar that was all
to the left of the hash bar and that
whole entire wall after the gzy art dis
display there was a huge you know spread
there that had all the fruit all the
pastries all the cookies and snacks and
all that stuff was served out there all
day and there was little finger food and
stuff like that that was on that table
as well so yeah I think maybe some user
eror on my on my end a not figuring out
where that was we kind of like did you
drink anything did you drink anything
while you were there uh like uh alcohol
wise no like all the because we had all
the beverages like there a massive
beverage station that was to the left of
the bar I wasn't sure if you were able
to man I don't know how uh I could have
possibly not seen that but I have an
idea of how how you didn't
see so much
drink yeah I
mean after Vegas I don't think I drank
for a week oh man that could be rough
what was uh tell you what oh go ahead
Marcus well no I was just going to say
in regards to your last conversation I
was like you know the way you could
marry uh what you had replied to him
Addison regards to Leia like the whole
food truck uh lineup idea is a bummer
like the food trucks are great the
lineup part is a bummer but imagine that
you had a taco truck or two and you had
them parked out back but no one was
going up to those trucks they were just
hammering out tacos Non-Stop and filling
trays that were then brought into the
place put down just like they would be
any of the other food and people just
grab them that way so there's always
solutions to these things is all I'm
saying and uh I agree with uh both of
what you said I you know yes Legends of
hashish had Lebanese food it was in a
Lebanese restaurant for 13 plus years
that being said it certainly won't have
to be Lebanese food forever we could we
could revisit different menus and
whatnot and uh like Addison said take in
intake people's opinions it would be
great to send out a little questionnaire
about this Addison and see what kind of
numbers we could get in regards to all
all of the things like how did you like
the cereal bar what did you think of the
the you know the little Oasis what did
you think of you know the the the menu
what did you think of the hash bar all
these different things I told them
earlier before you came in I'd love to
hear some positive things that you have
to say about Legends but we'd love to
hear anything that we can help fix it as
well because there's oh yeah you that's
really where the real value is it's nice
to get like oh let's all Pat Addison on
his back because he [ __ ] crushed it
so hard but it's also nice to be like
hey dude if we just do this a little
differently it could even we want to
make it better every year is BAS
basically where I'm coming from and
that's how we did it I mean we what you
saw in year two was us taking the
feedback from year One what you saw here
in year three was us taking feedback
from year two and I think you know we're
already um you know Marcus you and I are
already talking about other stuff I
think we could talk about that at some
point but um I might have accient I
might I might have [ __ ] it up earlier
and said something that's fine you
talked about what about about uh you
know rocking Legends in uh in Barka oh
yeah yeah so that's that's uh that's
actually that's scary for me that's like
I'm I'm excited but at the same time I'm
a little scared because I like that
imagine how it was when I just did it
out of my pocket and just like try like
wasn't from Barcelona I'd have to be
renting venues and chairs and tables and
all this crazy [ __ ] and it was just like
super stressful everything's in Euros so
from a Canadian standpoint it's like oh
how much is it it's just ,000 it's like
oh so like 18 00
Canadian like every every bill every
bill was like double the the
bill of course I'm paying for everything
with no sponsors whatsoever not even my
own company yeah that was we'll crush
this out dude we got the right people on
our side and uh I think it'll be nice
it's not going to be anything like what
you've put together in Los Angeles it's
going to be Barcelona style it's going
to be more intimate it's going to be you
know what it Isen is I spent time with
him at at Legends and I gave him some uh
a couple dabs of some some fresh press
and I think a couple I think some of the
stuff that both Marcus and you
have yeah Lorenzo's awesome top-notch
dude man like I remember when he came on
the scene I remember literally like I
met him quite a few years ago it could
be as as many as 10 years ago at this
point maybe at SAS I'm not sure exactly
where he's just one of those really cool
Italian guys that I clicked with right
away uh and then he just climbed and
climbed and now we had you know he's got
a shop in Amsterdam he's got this
beautiful turps Army in in Barcelona
he's uh he's working it he's got two
shops now man it's awesome killing it
yeah I'm looking forward to working with
those guys and uh figuring out um how to
pull this off it's pretty uh it's
definitely um it's gonna be exciting and
fun so I'm looking forward to it it's
like in three days dude
[Laughter]
yeah yeah we'll see we'll see what
happens I'm definitely uh I like to do
things a little more a little more laid
out and planned but at the same time I
definitely trust uh the rest of but we
have we have good teams we have like
spots for people to meet we're going to
get a great spot the food and the
everything will be really nice and we'll
make sure we get invites out to all the
all the good hash makers that want to
make their
appearance definitely um I've got to
jump off I've got I've got to go um pick
up some medication and deal with some
other stuff but and my stomach is
killing me right now so um but I do
appreciate everybody I I wanted to jump
in I apologize that I've uh oddly I got
this weird issue that kind of came up
out of nowhere but um yeah I got to get
going um not feeling so good so uh I'm
going to jump off but thank you guys all
uh very much and I'm looking forward to
working with Mark and putting some more
stuff together so yeah peace out brother
I hope you're feeling
better we hav't haven't heard from we
haven't heard from Alex Gonzo in the
room here he came in a little while ago
what's up
dude what's up guys how we doing we're
doing good man tell us a little bit
about yourself I I don't know you off
the top of my head yo you're uh you're
good you're good let me just jump on
video here what's up guys Marcus we met
at eag
I'm uh I'm callx we were the packaging
sponsor yeah of course in Barcelona we
yeah yeah
brother [ __ ] hey dude good to see you
through the haze of all the hash yeah
man it's good to see you guys yeah
absolutely so you had a good time with
Legends dude unreal you guys were
talking about what was good uh I think
one of my favorite Parts was the the Cal
bar The Minis the mini aspect like
whoever thought of that
dude uh killed it all time so good it's
good to have little things like that you
know even the little lattes with like
the glob mops and legends like stencils
on top of the lattes that's just so
[ __ ] cool man Addison really went
above and beyond and got some some cool
Concepts and ideas to uh you know you
got to do a lot a lot of those little
things to make it a special evening and
you know nowadays there's just so many
different things things that bombard the
senses that uh you know from the
perspective of Legends it's all about
curating the right products the right
sponsors the right hash makers we're
like curators and we're creating a
living art gallery of hash you know
that's what Legends of hash is and it
happens for a night it's a popup I mean
wouldn't it be an amazing thing one day
to see like Legends of hash just
dispensaries with like the hatch bars
like the whole like little cereal bars
like the whole concept just put in into
a baller dispensary that's like the
legends of hash like you want to feel
like what it was like to be at this
event like go to that dispensary I
wouldn't even call it a dispensary I
would call it like a a hash bar you know
yeah you got to go to the legends of
hash hash bar man that place is crazy
everyone in that City would want their
dabs in that hash bar hash Gallery yeah
that's it man so you had a good Legends
anyway is is what you're saying with the
cereal bar and
no doubt no doubt I think whatever we
can keep doing to curate those like
little uh points of of experience I mean
these hash makers are putting you know
all all everything they can into into
making the best product and um this
whole event like I I I love that that's
that's what we try to do with our
packaging right like the the user
experience and uh making sure that
everybody has a positive interaction and
so uh you killed it like with the
stencil it's like those little things
the little moments that stand out and if
if you can put a bunch of those together
the whole time it's like oh the detail
here and there and and and the effort
put into uh the event man you guys we
yeah crushed it that's what's up dude
that is what's up and we'll continue to
try you know like one of one of my ideas
was uh to always have like at at the end
of Legends I used to go with this guy
Sid and Sid has a h a bubly bubbly
collection of of pipes from Afghanistan
if you open the book hashish there's
pictures in the middle of Rob's book
hashish and in those pictures you'll see
these Hubbly Bubbly pipes these Afghani
pipes that are like you know two three
feet tall big long pipe on them and
you're Big Bowl on this thing like it's
a serious hashm smoker tool like it's a
much bigger rip than a dab even a big
dab even a huge dab and so you know Sid
would bring a one of these down to
Legends and it would be like aund years
old and he'd let us all puff on it for
the night so it was this real honor to
be able to smoke this pipe from
Afghanistan in Amsterdam from Sid's
collection and at the end i' I'd just be
trashed especially because like all the
dead smoke in the original restaurant it
was such a small environment you'd be
rebreathing the Smoky air which was
terrible I'd go up to his house and this
guy would have like 10 or 15 different
types of honey from all around the world
and you'd start you know have a spoonful
of this one and you just I couldn't
believe how well it cleared my throat
and as a hash smoker I always want to
have a honey bar where you can go up and
get a little honey and just have access
to Honey because honey will get your you
you back on the dabs like nobody's
business even if you got a sore wretched
throat a a spoonful of the right honey
from the right environment is so
medicinal you can't even [ __ ] I
couldn't believe it I was like what the
[ __ ] it was Peruvian honey that he
gave me a tiny teaspoon and it went down
my throat and I was just like dude I
feel like I could go do another Legends
now
legitimately so shout out to
honey well I wished uh you know I I knew
it was kind of going to play that out
this way I think my email probably went
to a lot of people's junk mails and I
could have probably done a better job it
would have been nice to have all the
other winners as well as Darby and Scott
and JP and uh maybe we'll do another one
here in the near future I'm good for
another little bit if you guys have
anything else you want to talk about in
regards to your
Brands where where you guys are at with
your Brands what you're
doing you know any of that stuff you're
welcome to mention you're obviously
towards the end we'll tell everyone your
social media so everyone can follow you
we got a couple hundred people watching
in the room and there there should be a
five or 6,000 people that watch this
video so it'll be worth uh getting your
social medias out there
anyone brand action activity
sales where you're at where people can
get your product we can talk about our
launch as a brand we are taking vessel
life science into New York as a brand
and we've got a license there um we're
super stoked to to start it in
2024 we've got uh cultivation um and
Manufacturing extraction
so we're stoked man so it's uh it's been
a long time coming super important for
us and we didn't really intend for
vessel life science to become a brand
but I don't think uh many people intend
many things to happen so we're stoked to
to just be a part of the wave and just
be a vessel for for what we've been
doing awesome dude well congratulations
that's great to hear man
thanks
man Casey bun says we we want to know
more about skunk
KC
CS that's hilarious yeah we just want to
shout out to uh all the patients of
Oklahoma you know without them we
wouldn't be able to operate and we
wouldn't be around so we really
appreciate them first of all you know
foremost for you know really
appreciating good hash it's like it's
crazy the kind of community that's
actually like out here there's a lot of
people who generally and like you know
genuinely care about quality you know
what I mean over quantity so I know like
there's a lot of boof out here too but
there is there's actually quite a good
market for hash and all that you know
Ros and a lot of people out here that
you know take it as a passion so yeah
we're we're real small you know it's
just my brother and I and then we have
um one full-time Helper and then a part
a couple part-time helpers too and uh
yeah I mean we're just going to keep
doing this for Oklahoma as long as we
can and I mean we'll see what happens I
don't know if whatever goes wreck out
here or whatever but um yeah just GNA
keep the slow growth going and keep
making hash well Oklahoma's lucky to
have you guys that's for sure yeah we're
lucky to have
Oklahoma did you guys do that Donnie
Burger
cross the PO yeah yeah so uh yeah that
was the one that won the the first yeah
uh first place and um yeah we you guys
did the cross though or did you get that
no no we got that from it's a it's a
pack from California SE Bank respect at
California SE bank and uh yeah we just
we actually got a couple uh freebies I
think it was like two three pack
freebies and so we just popped all those
at once we feno hunt everything that we
uh grow we don't we've never taken any
Cuts uh I think we were just like
paranoid years ago that you know for
bugs or whatever reason and just you
know Black Market stuff kind of wanting
to stay hidden or whatever um a decade
ago so it's just something and so we
just always like to hunt and that was uh
the initial time the the the first feno
hunt wash so it was like five fenos is a
five penos that's in there so um I think
it adds to like a a quite complex flavor
same with the rainb tan that one um
that's Bloom Seed Co and we've had that
one for I don't know at least a year now
but it's still three fenos and we've
narrowed that one down so a lot of what
we do is like mixed feno of that flavor
we'll keep a couple um just kind of
depending because we want like a nice
wide range of flavors uh give it a
little bit of complexity so I mean
that's just what that's what we love
doing and onto R effect yeah
um yeah we're just gonna keep doing that
I
guess I think you're on the right path
no doubt about
it we're looking forward to the future
that's for sure yes looking forward to
more Legends
things the people next time we gotta
spend some more time I was I was super
overwhelmed with smoking the hash and
making sure we got through all those
like you know like they all said gave
everybody their their due diligence on
that it does become work it does become
work where you're really like holy [ __ ]
like this is actually like going to take
me
hours Yeah by far the most dabs I've
done it was great though it was awesome
this is how we do it out in California
just it's only it's 45 dabs man just get
it [ __ ] done we want to do more of
that kind of stuff for uh for Oklahoma
the the competitions out here man
they're I don't know yeah but as far as
like you know nice events like that
sessiones we we're uh gonna throw one
called blueg grass and hash later this
year or next year I should say uh one of
our buddies so that should be just try
to bring that kind of culture more to
Oklahoma for the people here and what
what I would suggest you do for that is
that um you know we want to do smaller
Legend Styles events in different cities
where we can kind of find the talent
like scouting events so when we can't if
there is events like what you just
mentioned that aligns with our sort of
bottom line we always are down with
finding like the shining stars of these
events and then you know inviting them
into the competition of Legends for the
next year kind of thing so we got to be
able to scout hash makers out there in
the world and that becomes uh you know
the responsibility of the legends of
hash crew yeah well that's awesome man
yeah we'll definitely stay in touch uh
and I think Addison might I think he's
been talking to our buddy Brian that's
actually running it so yeah awesome yeah
he probably has he's he's on the ball
for sure yeah he is
man what about yourself cash
a um yeah um I just you know I think uh
I want to say thank you to you know kind
of all the supporters we have we have a
you know we're blessed to have a decent
amount of people that you know uh [ __ ]
with us and um a big shout out to our
growing team um we're all single source
and so um we do a lot of breeding we do
a lot of um pheno hunting and um all of
that is extremely difficult and takes a
lot of resources and a lot of time and
um yeah I think uh this year we're
getting into uh we're getting like a
culture lab and um fortish culture and
so
um that's really exciting and we have um
you know some guys uh involved that um
are kind of big in the scene and know
what they're doing and so you got that's
the most important thing you could have
said when you said we're going to do a
tissue culture lab I was like w that's
like very specialized but then you said
the next thing which was like we got
some guys who really know what they're
doing from that exact that's the most
necessary component yes you're doing
Meemic tissue
culture um The Cutting of clones The
Cutting of clones basically really small
ones yes and you know the whole you know
uh really clean environment and
separating all that kind of stuff um you
know I am not uh I'm personally not the
breeder of our team so um that's not
like my corner of of what we do but um
the guys we have are on our team are
really you know really good at what they
do and I think when you kind of venture
out to like the next level you
definitely have to find you know a
mentor or somebody who has you know
shown that they've accomplished it and
um I mean we'll see where it goes uh
we've done breeding for a lot of years
just the regular way and um yeah I'm
excited toh kind of make sure our
genetics are um as as good as they can
be you know for a long period of time
cleaning your genetics man never a bad
thing and tissue culture definitely
offers
that yeah awesome man well good luck
with that I love it how about you Logan
thank you
much yeah so uh huge shout out to my lab
partner Jesse great gratefully educated
on Instagram uh we're I'm Wolverine dabs
on
Instagram um we're launching dryft onto
the Washington recreational Market here
in a few months actually with uh dog
star and Western cultur so that's going
to be a lot of
fun I haven't been able to find dry sift
on the market anywhere really like you
know you've got your hash wraps and uh I
haven't been able to just find like you
know full melt dry sift to go buy from a
store anywhere in my area at least so
it's it's going to be in Canada on the
legal Market you can now buy full melt
bubble but still dry sift full melt is
not available anywhere in our country
for sale at a store yeah so it's it's
exciting I'm I'm really excited to
actually be able to go into a store and
purchase it and see it on the shelves
I'm probably going to be one of the
first customers of it so I guarantee you
probably might be the first second and
third even it's like people won't know
what it is at first they'll kind of be
like what the [ __ ] you mean like is this
just some key for
yeah why is it so expensive that's
always the biggest thing yeah why is
this ke so
expensive congrats man it's funny those
Western culture guys are great yeah no
they're amazing so I I love working with
them and we're planning on doing
multiple collabs throughout the next
year so hopefully you know and then
we're going to Branch into Arizona as
the next goal and go from there hell
yeah dude well shout out to you for sure
and shout out to my crew in Arizona
Arizona melts I got a team up there or
down there making making melts and live
hash rosins and they just entered the
Cannabis Cup there and uh yeah they're
doing good work they did some really
nice strawberry melts [ __ ] looked flame
on flame on uh what about yourself Alex
finish you off you let everyone know
where you're at social media and whatnot
I think it's almost 11: so this is a
perfect time to just kind
of mellow it down and uh let everyone go
and have a nice Sunday after afternoon I
know I've got some time to spend with my
young I'm sure some of you guys do as
well yeah no doubt guys appreciate you
having me today and just shout out all
the hash makers who are at Legends are
working on their craft and trying to
make an appearance in in the future I
mean uh you guys are all here because
you're amazing in what you do and we
love we love what we do trying to trying
to build a a a vessel shout out vessel
life science is a vessel for for the
hash to U you know preserve and make
sure that you guys are getting every
every single last piece of that dab so
um we we got some really cool things in
the work for
2024 um you we we launched our V2 first
square neck glass um last year it was it
was first first of its kind but more so
uh an evolution not a revolution and I
can't share too many specifics but
working with Addison on a debuting some
really cool back at at the next show so
you know you guys keep us working hard
um we just want to make the best best
package possible and you know it's all
possible because of you guys so congrats
everybody here that placed um and uh
yeah appreciate appreciate everybody
having me awesome dude well thanks for
being here for sure thank you guys all
for making it out and being the least
stoned of the whole bunch I knew Colin
Colin replied back in like a minute I'll
be there homie it's like [ __ ] of course
Colin the email what are these other
people that have never gotten an email
from me like I'm sitting in junk mails
right now like just at the bottom of 176
junk mails people are going to figure
out in a couple hours no way was that
already on it's like yeah dude it's 9:00
am West Coast time so I got to shout out
all the people uh watching we had about
250 people watching live at one point in
time there's still a couple hundred in
there now so we appreciate each and
every one of you for hanging out and
listening to our you know geeked out
banter on hash and live hash rosin um
shout out to all you hash makers that
crushed it so hard super proud and
excited for each and every one of you
it's no small feat to win a Legends of
hash when you have that group of
connoisseurs the Uber Uber snobs the OCD
snobs of the Cannabis World smoking and
tasting your hash and then being in
agreeance with it that it's uh you know
some of the best stuff is uh definitely
a badge of honor to wear proudly so
congratulations to each and every one of
you shout out to my buddy AK drone piic
who just came into the room up there in
Seward Alaska miss you homie hopefully
we hit Jamaica soon and otherwise uh of
course as always I would hope that the
full Mount blesses your bowl sooner than
later and uh that's it peace out
everyone thanks for
coming thank you guys thank you thanks
for having us man