hey what's up everybody welcome to hash
Church episode 2 well it has Church 2.0
episode 19 I literally thought it was
like episode 16 and then 17 and then 18
and so you probably noticed I changed
the title quite a few times fingers
crossed that it works today fingers
crossed that I can hear the people that
get invited in I'm going to send out the
link right away and like I said fingers
crossed
well that's interesting got a copy that
link again so I hope everyone's having a
great day I noticed there were some
people waiting in the chat room for hash
Church to start which is always great
we love that alright so there's that and
then there's that then there's there's
actually three different places I have
to go to send these links out so fingers
crossed that when people come in I can
actually hear them because I miss all
you guys I miss our Saturday
conversations I'm always was a big fan
of hash courage welcome and Sam hello
here we go No howdy
oh I see you have chimera with you do
you hear me
I can hear you perfect can you hear me
hello can you hear me no you hear me
[ __ ] alright alright that was exciting
I was exciting how are you doing Ben you
can't mutation is bad though
Oh weird I have pretty fast internet
right now so I'm not sure what's going
on there let's see if we get some other
folks in here and figure it out sorry
that I'm lagging I just heard from
Forrest he just sent me an email saying
he's unfortunately not going to be able
to make it they're having a small
gathering for Silas's birthday today and
got a list of chores to get through so
we should send side
a happy birthday how you doing wait I'm
good Marcus how about you well I was
having a little bit of problem with my
audio with skunk man he said it was
delayed it might be his computer do you
hear me fine I'm hearing you fine this
time around this oh hey well great great
great nice to see you hey I we can hear
you Sam or I can can you very Marcus I
can hear you very well Sam's a little
bit cutting out I think he might need to
like restart his computer or something
but we'll see what happens we've we've
got a nice slow start to church today
but the bottom line is there's a couple
of us in here and that's all we need to
start a conversation
I just wish time I just wasted Silas a
happy birthday actually I heard it was
his birthday today yes
yeah twelve years old now wild that was
his parents were told they shouldn't
expect him to make it to pretend so
we're thrilled it's incredible that's
incredible I miss Forrest and Silas and
the whole crew it's been a long time
since we've had them on the show welcome
to my quest Mike's got his Mike's got
his farmers gear on
he's like alarm remote I can tell hey
what's going on dude hanging out
beautiful beautiful little hash Church
and I like how you you know you guys are
huddled around the hash Church phone
it's going good man how would you sell
doing well
excellent excellent idea
good I'm having trouble hearing those
guys so I'm gonna restart I'll be back
in a minute
okay sounds good trichrome chromis what
I'm having my best luck on I was having
I was having bad luck with Safari not
being able to hear what people were
saying so I guess wade was having that
problem with you guys but I can hear you
perfect perfectly perfect skunk man Sam
just went and reset his [ __ ] as well
we're having mild technical difficulties
but hopefully you guys have a bomb
somewhere nearby and you're doing your
doing bong rips of the full-mouth I'm
sure
that's happening is it working now Sam
we got slow going today here I wonder
how many people there are in this room I
hope I I hear you yeah I hear you
absolutely 90% you got a small group in
here today I we said I think Wendy and
Colton Turner said they were gonna pop
in later and at an fortunately was
unable to make it but there were some
other yeses that I got for sure that
made me feel like yeah we should do a
hash search today so we'll just well
throw it around we'll see what happens
everything going good with you guys some
research this year it's kind of working
through all the all the kinks getting
everything yeah there sure oh they got
the link okay dragonfly earth medicine
said they were having a hard time they
weren't getting the link and for
whatever reason it's not letting me send
the link in my old computer technology
problems here as well yeah I don't know
what's going on oh they said they got
the link okay so the email that I sent
out probably showed up a little late and
so now they're uh they're gonna come in
here soon you know what I used to be so
nervous about starting hashed Church I'd
get so not aggressive but just kind of
like I would just want it to work I
would just want hashed churches to work
and now I'm so relaxed and chill about
it let's go down calling what up guys
sorry I'm on my phone today
I'm having issues I'll put that [ __ ]
down on a table so it doesn't move and
you'll be laughing Mike and Johnny are
also on the phone yeah oh yeah oh we're
doing pretty good it was a slow little
bit of a slow start trying to get the
the trying to get the links out to
everyone you know
right on not always easy man nope not at
all
but we I'm gonna get my rig oh that
sounds great yeah this is so strange
I've now frozen my messenger with Josh
and Kelly and I can't send them any
message so they said they just got to be
here in two seconds but I don't know I
don't know what's going on here I don't
know
it won't even let me force quit on
messenger my microphone work yes yes but
I can't hear your turntable that was a
joke yes yes yes now it is there to talk
are your beakers working is another
question cuz we're answering yes every
time you ask yes yes yes Johnny B got
the day I got the link I don't know I
sent the link to a bunch of people but I
think we should start with a bomb rip
what better way to start hash search
than with a bong rip so please everyone
in the congregation you [ __ ] together
what's that Sam's having problems
technical problems let's have a little
dab of doodle here my speakers are
working yeah you're cutting out a lot
your [ __ ] is not on point right now I
don't know what's going on all right
turning me up into headphones turn me up
into headphones turn it up turn it up
remember that scene from Dave Chappelle
show I think it was Dylan I spit
via I'm guessing he'd probably know he
was the one that said it in chat all
right Wendy Turner said she's running a
little late and she'll show up as soon
as possible so I think it's good time
for a bond rib for those of you that can
do bong rips I don't know what's going
on over there and in middle America oh
you pulling bong rips out of his ear it
looked like you just pulled a bong rip
right out of his ear you guys puffing on
that wax you guys are muted so I don't
hear you Collins made it as well there
were issues with their head say your ear
buds oh my god oh it's just another
ridiculous day on hash Church let's hope
it works out let's hope that we get
everyone working with their microphones
and their speakers and it'd be nice to
have a conversation I hear you okay Sam
think you could be cutting out a little
bit I don't know if it's when other
people talk or if it's because we don't
have our microphones needed or what it
is definitely here you need to get some
water oh yeah you need to go get some
water grab I will well I gotta get some
water
all right so this is what I'm all about
right now check this [ __ ] out
measuring this temperature of my banger
not great little temperature gauge dude
I am so loving my tempting qsa every
time I bring it up someone's like why
don't you just use a ten dollar
thermometer gun I'm like I don't know
cuz you got to hold that in your hand
and it's ghetto like I'm happy with this
it sits right under my banger I'm
watching it go from 700 degrees down to
694 oh right around 680 is one I'll hit
it rubberband that day right onto the
rig
make it art it mark those are 3d
printing right I believe they're 3d
printed yes yeah I'm sure they'll yeah
that's gonna end up being a souvenir
just eventually once they yeah those
usually you'll 3d print it and once you
kind of get the food worked out you
actually get it injection molded to
shape it hopefully they can start
building they actually start doing the
molds for them they can start making
them out of hemp plastic totally how
[ __ ] cool would that be they're
pretty cool guys
I've been talking to them and I
definitely am an unapologetic gadget
geek whoever just said that PK brewer
it's true
I love the gadgets oh wow I just check
this out I'm leaning down and my shirt
made it look like it was one of the
boxes in the chat and I was like oh
who's that that looks familiar
this is the legends of past shirt from
Barcelona this year you can check it out
the Lebanese hash makers going to town
there that must've been a good back do I
have part Scottish in me bubble man yes
I do
Allen Rohan I do I do I have a little
bit of Irish and a little bit of
Scottish in me sometimes what I'm doing
yeah oh listen to you mr. [ __ ] birds
holy [ __ ] don't turn the birds off bro
the bird Whisperer he's the bird
Whisperer so Colin's out on the East
Coast
yowzer you guys are in like middle
America I'm over on the west coast and
Sam's way over across the Atlantic Ocean
so that's what we got going on right now
dude your cat must be trippin on those
birds they're coming through so clear
I'll go on mute it sounds like he's got
like a high end and like like microphone
or something like he's pulled out one of
his studio mics and he's like recording
birds from a kilometer away very nice
very nice so I did a little wake and
bake yesterday hey what's going on there
dragonfly earth medicine you guys in the
room or is it sketching out on you I see
you you're it shows that you're a deer
now forget we're getting the work done
here there we go good morning guys you
guys are kind of a little blurry and a
little dark but it's great to see your
silhouettes
yeah hopefully it gets changed here soon
we get a little light but nice to see
you all this morning how you doing today
it's good man it's been a nice slow
start to church mostly we've been
technical difficulty in our mics and our
you know you know the longer we take
that we don't do a church the more it's
kind of like rusty when you get in the
room but I did a little wake and bake
yesterday just before church just to
suss out the vibes and I smashed an hour
on my wake and bake just by myself so I
figured if we can't like there's so much
to talk about right now because if you
haven't noticed hash Church was a pretty
big sort of place for us to talk about
these important situations and with
hashed Church not really around there's
not really another spot like it you know
there's there's spots like it there are
there are many spots like if there's no
real spot like it so I thought you know
we kind of owe it to the community and
ourselves to a get together and shoot
the [ __ ] see how everyone's doing maybe
mewed Sam while they [ __ ] coughs in
my ear for the 15th time in a row and I
just joking Sam but I didn't you you and
just have a conversation you know
obviously we're gonna get into some
things here today I definitely want to
talk about Philo's I haven't had a
chance to talk to maglia and invite him
in and I know Kevin mckernon who has
been one of the big opposition's online
is also unable to come in because he's
having a barbeque but
it'd be kind of cool to have a little
conversation about that but also a
conversation about all these different
things that are going on in Canada and
in the US and the farm bill and all
these different things that are
occurring in Colombia and the Caribbean
and in Europe and there's a lot going on
in the industry right now a lot going on
and I just feel that when we're not able
to gather we don't that information kind
of doesn't really get you know put into
yeah Justin put into a really yeah and
obviously hash search has always been a
great gathering of the minds you know
what it doesn't matter what what you do
in the industry it's a great place where
we can all kind of gather around the
campfire and talk about things as they
pop up so obviously we're open
invitation to moglie open invitation to
Kevin let's try and get them on and
actually hash this out and we can we can
certainly talk about that a little bit
of that controversy because there's
there's a lot of stuff that's kind of
popped up but for the last month and
it's it's all things that your growers
and breeders industry both paint need to
kind of understand because it's you know
the intellectual property right of
cannabis as much as we want to keep this
at a fair and open community we have to
be able we have to be able to protect
will protect the breeders we have to
first and foremost we have to be able to
protect the patients and I've I have my
personal thoughts on it obviously I'm a
you know being a medication we want we
want to see the patients have safe
access no matter where they are but at
the same and obviously if you know
growers breeders genetics companies
anybody starts spending you know lots of
time money resources developing IP
whether that be genetics or processes or
potentially developing patents you know
we we as industry leaders have to be
able to set the example that way you
know when as Wall Street or the public
companies kind of form and we set that
good example and you know for best
example is some of the predatory uh
patents out there for cannabis cultivars
a lot of those the cannabis cultivar
patents are fairly broad and they're
gonna have to get you know fought in
court but you know when you look at the
transition from black marketed gray
market to regulated markets there's a
big learning curve that has to go
through and you know the USPTO doesn't
go to the black market to research
potential patents so you know we have to
be able to set the example and you know
for the word patents you know the
government's that pull that issue those
patents make just as much money when the
patents get challenged as they do when
the patents get issued so what we've
kind of seen come up is you know a
couple different intellectual property
developments in the industry both
genetics as well as technologies and we
have to be able to not only develop that
IP protect that AG key but also be able
to provide that IP to the public I know
there's I I was a cannabis refugee 15
years ago moving to a state that you
know because I needed CBD in my life and
in Texas you did 15 years ago there
wasn't CBD available
so yeah tons of the cool stuff it's
going to be an interesting year um west
coast it looks like weather weather
report going to the Farmers Almanac West
Coast is gonna have a fairly phenomenal
year but a little bit dry so there's
gonna be some forest fires kind of pop
up on the west coast
kind of where we're at Central America
in the Midwest it's actually a fairly
wet spring a lot of the farmers we've
been talking to you know when you when
you apply for crop insurance the
Cannabis aside cannabis can't have crop
insurance yet but there are some federal
bills that would include crop insurance
poor industrial hemp but in the Midwest
you know they we've had a fairly wet
spring and yep all the corn farmers you
know normally in order to have crop
insurance for growing corn you have to
be able to you know plant it in the
ground before Memorial Day that way
there's a hundred days of sunlight for
your crop to be able to grow what if
that's corn and what we're kind of
seeing in the Mississippi River area of
the Midwest of the u.s. is you know that
hundred day mark is Memorial Day which
is today tomorrow so a lot of corn
farmers because these you know a fairly
wet spring a lot of the farmers haven't
yet plant planted their crops
hundred-day frogs so we're starting to
see some talk about okay well rather
than growing corn they're gonna
potentially have to grow soybeans
because soybeans have slightly shorter
growing cycles but you know the current
trade worth with Asia is kind of causing
issues with tariffs as well as value of
soybeans so it'd be great if you know
farmers in the Midwest had a you know
fifty to seventy day crop that they
could plant instead of corn hopefully
more sustainably and still be able to
pull off the harvest this year it looks
like knock on wood yeah and that's and
then we're starting to see that happen
and a lot of states you know industrial
hemp is kind of slowly making its
progress across the u.s. I think there's
four states that don't have industrial
hemp or cannabis laws and the vast
majority of Americans as as well as
people in North America are in
jurisdictions where they can cultivate
either medical marijuana medical
cannabis industrial hemp or cannabis so
I want to know what how it Josh and
Kelly how's it up in the up and where
you were part of the world how's your
spring been you I saw some pictures of
you guys greenhouses yeah well we just
probably about two and a half maybe two
weeks ago we just got done with some
soup or a cold evening so how to really
hard frost it seemed like spring went
from really really cold super hard frost
to really hot to like almost like thirty
degree days so we've had to transplant
all of our starts over and over again
not necessarily their cannabis at all
but like our chard and our beets they
didn't really like that super hot
temperatures our brassicas we had to
replant twice but everything's coming up
now and now we're feeling like a true
spree it's been really dry actually I
mean it's wet right now like right
because it just rained last couple days
which is sweet but it's been extremely
dry unbelievably so to where you're
walking around in the forest and its
really pretty brittle so that was you
know that was interesting it's been good
for the the GaN just starts we got a
bunch of seeds started on April 20th
4:20 and they're coming up really nice
really beautiful right now all of our
soils are totally prepped all of our
greenhouses are totally prepped and
we're really excited for the year right
now we got Otto flowers we're gonna try
this year we got a bunch of hemp a bunch
of cultivars that were you know are
growing in Canada would have been you
know come from wherever they've come
from to to grow so we're gonna try that
out we're also going to test whether
they finish up here in British Columbia
because a lot of the hemp strains
haven't finished all the auto the auto
one the auto two the cherry wine the box
the spectrum all of those really didn't
finish good in our area and couldn't
couldn't be in the field right now so
we're feeling really blessed we got like
a really long breeding project maybe
like a 40 year breeding project from
heart Rock and those guys gave us some
Otto flowers so
we're gonna be able to do some crossing
and really our our big goal this year
and you know probably the next five
years is coming out with a super high
CBD hemp strain that finishes up here in
Canada so we're really really focused on
that that's that's what we're gonna be
working on
yeah it's it's it's also you know
something we're working on as a
collective and as a pure certified group
a lot of us farmers we're doing a
breeding project together and you know
we're interested in genetics and public
domain and what that means and you know
what are the rights within public domain
what what rights are we giving up and
stuff like that so you know that's
something we're really exploring and
we're talking to people inside the
cannabis realm we're talking to people
outside the cannabis realm that are in
the food realms because food has been
hijacked you know long ago you know in
ways that cannabis might be just facing
now and I think part of ray of
legalization that we really always
feared was really this right now was the
you know the federal takeover and what
Lari agriculture does with crops is
something that you know we really don't
want to see in the cannabis industry so
it's putting a huge challenge to us
right now and I and we are excited
you're not excited but you know we are
excited but interested in just talking
about it more and fine and and for us
you know I I've been a really long time
friend of madly and Mowgli's you know
family is good friends of mine so
there's personal relationship there as
well and I personally want to thank
Philo's right now for opening up our
eyes to a lot of things a lot of people
in the industry have been asleep and
they haven't recognized that we needed
to protect this IP or that we needed to
share these seeds you know we're like
Josh said we're really in the public
domain we're reaching out to every
single expert that we know of anybody
that can mentor us so it really like
sparked a fire under our booties at this
time to really get going and what we
came up with was that we're going to be
putting it in the public domain we've
already starting a breeding project with
40-plus farms and the pure certification
we've got a whole bunch of data that
people can collect that we keep within
ourselves and then that actualizes your
seeds you know the thing that we worry
about patenting and marking it and
markering and all these things in the
cannabis plant is she's an adaptogen
she's gonna adapt so you know it's
really interesting there's a whole lot
of money in corporate cannabis and
people that are dumping into this sort
of patenting idea in cannabis but she's
an adaptogen so I could take a patent
seed and somebody could spend 2 million
dollars on patenting that seed and get
all of the rights and everything to it
and then I could put it in my deep
beautiful living soil beds for four
years and you wouldn't even recognize it
because she's an adaptogen so I'm just
you know I guess we're kind of putting
it out there wouldn't wouldn't cannabis
already have been genetically modified
back in the 30s or the 40s when they
made the cross over from him to cotton
or from hemp to something else what is
someone's thought on that one maybe it's
not really actually
pathetically modified but not
genetically engineered but it hasn't
been or what no it's dating back
thousands of years just dude of
Mendelian breeding cannabis has been
bred from a dioecious plant which the
industry will call from a frenetic and
you Manisha's plants and that was all
based on selective breeding so but
that's not the qualification that's
that's a selection
yeah it's its selection and for genetic
modification but it's not genetic
engineering so we're not actually
creating genetically modified organism
TMO but just due to Mendelian genetics
ever the simple act of you know doing a
analytical test to select for CBD and
then taking the CBD cultivars to
incorporate into your breeding pollen is
the form of genetic modification now I
personally am a big fan yeah my my
educational background is on molecular
bio genetics so you know before getting
into the industry I was looking at you
know developing biofuels for abuse and
because you know biofuels are far more
sustainable than the other
sources of energy but ultimately you
know we don't want to pull the wool over
our eyes and say that cannabis is a the
same cannabis that was around you know
ten thousand fifty thousand years ago
you know we have numerous different
landraces that but locally adapted to to
their growing regions and the simple act
of taking those you know genetics from
one part of the world to another part of
the world cultivating them for
successive generations you're gonna get
adaptation of that those hybrids or
those cultivars to your bio region and
that's that's a form of selecting four
cultivars and you Mendelian genetic
selection and that's the case all plants
on earth I mean there's you know that's
the case for walnut trees and and
everything is in constant evolution so
ya know there's a big difference between
you know I I could go in-depth into you
know the concerns that I have about
genetic genetic engineering the last
thing we want to do is to start you know
inserting genetic inserting gene
sequences into cannabis cultivars that
make them you know produce antifreeze or
produce pesticide resistance or produce
there's even ways that you can make them
possible fluorescent so glow in black
lights are glowing lights you could
gross you could genetically engineer it
inserting Rose thorns so you have Rose
thorns there's even genetic selection
that's going on for actually hybridizing
different traits into from non cannabis
varieties into cannabis varieties and
those are those genetic engineering
where you're taking non cannabis
genetics and putting them into cannabis
potentially have side effects we don't
know you know with big cases in corn you
know they've not only create pesticide
resistance so that they can spray really
bad pesticides onto corn fields that's
really bad for the ecosystem but you
know they've genetically modified
engineered corn so that it can resist
that now I think that is a travesty to
the ecosystem and
we have starting this new industry we're
gonna be able to promote new avoiding
that sort of thing by developing
sustainable ecosystems why would you
grow why would you Jenny I modify it to
be resistant to a pesticide instead of
genetically modify it to be resistant
against the bug yeah
told you in the first place yeah so
being able to select four cultivars that
grow well in but your bio region you
know the strains that grow grow well in
Florida are gonna be you know more
equatorial sativas with narrow leaves
were versus the ones that grow well in
the mountain areas were in different
different different Appalachians
so I I'm a big fan of being able to
incorporate a sustainable ecosystem
because every every bad thing in our
that could potentially affect our crop
has a natural bed the last thing we want
to do is start inserting genetics into
cannabis that could have adverse side
good example I've seen frost resistant
frost resistant genetic engineering
where they're taking genes that produce
antifreeze in arctic and putting those
into plant cultivars how do you feel
about feminized seed then I mean on that
note you know all the farmers using
feminized seed on a large scale in hemp
agriculture does that raise a flag to
you yes and no so I you know I I don't
consider myself a breeder by any means
but you know there are there are for
every pool there's there's a use right
if I'm plant there's several hundred or
several thousand acres
those the farmers the farmers that are
the farmers that are growing hundreds or
thousands of acres don't have the time
or money or resources to be able to go
through those and select for the
dioecious or hermaphroditic plants so in
some cases we need those those you know
feminized seeds but as a home grower
you're probably not going to find me
cultivating feminized seeds because the
male plants are the base
of breeding projects so being able to
select for you know good females good
males doing that hybridization and then
in in the case of feminized seeds you
know the commercial breeders can then
develop them and I see release them in
mass to farmers and hopefully have you
know any given farmer will grow a few
cultivars inter inter planted and it's a
good way to be able to create a form
that not only has you know industrial
hemp that's primarily feminized with the
low with a lower risk of
cross-pollination but then you know the
farmer can spend his time doing other
things like you know trying to inter
plant trying to get cover crops going
between the hemp plants and so that I
think there's pros and cons with
everything it's a lot of people hate on
strains that are that produced
hermaphrodite Didache traits but that's
really just the plant doing what it
evolved to do thousands of years ago so
I'm you won't see me growing feminized
plants but you know I may I may use
incorporate feminized plants into some
of the breeding but I think that the
bigger concern is when I when I see
people selling feminized seed and part
of the material transfer agreements
include that you're not allowed to
replant them you're not allowed to
hybridize them you're not allowed to
bless the seeds and there's there are
you know fairly large well known seed
distributors that aren't allowing people
new breeders to breed with their stock
and which cool that's not cool no cuz
you know they know any pieces they're
they're incorporating genetics that they
acquired on the open market exactly
doing the doing the work be able to
hybridize and stabilize those drinks and
then preventing other people from
hybridizing analyzing those prints so
there's there's pros and cons but we
what we want to be able to do is you
know we understand that there is a ton
of money and ton of work incorporated
into developing new lines and we want
those breeders to be able to protect
those block but at the same time we
don't want that to new animal
all the way point where you know it's
because I'm I'm doing work on genetics
from my farm doesn't mean that you if
that seed or pollen get out into other
people's farm then you have potential
litigation where you do down the street
or over the hill accidentally got
pollinated and we've actually seen
Monsanto Bayard do that where the BT
resistant a pesticide resistant corn got
bas pollinated in this due to born being
a aerial and feces and then you know
those large companies going after it so
I you know I have mixed feeling about
what some of the genetics companies have
done I'm a big fan of being able to do
genetic testing because I think that
that's going to start developing
intellectual property rights before the
breeders but in the same hand we want to
be able to have the open transparency
and I think it's a huge conflict of
interest or if if I was running a
testing lab and all of a sudden I opened
up a extraction lab or a farm there's a
potential conflict of interest it's the
same as if you're doing a genetic
testing lab and then start opening up a
genetic distribution pump
so I think that any any once you commit
to doing that genetic testing lab you
have to kind of keep that in your as
your wheelhouse
because then you're gonna be the one
that's developing the it helping to
develop intellectual property rights for
those breeders and I've spent tens of
thousands of dollars through company on
doing genetic research getting stuff
sequence thirteen for rare phenotypes in
the genetics p1 and it's a concern of
mine that you know some of those
genetics I don't think that any of those
genetics were stolen but I do think that
some of that data should have should be
available in the public art and as well
as should be you know Kirk right because
if I find the end-all-be-all genetic
mutation that produces entirely CBD V or
CBGB
or some of the other rare nab annoys
obviously we want to protect those
develop those and then as part of you
know raising money to become a business
being able to sell them but the last
thing I want to see is you know people
like cold and not being able to have
active people like myself and you know I
was I left Texas would be able to move
Colorado 15 years ago just so I could
have access to medicine and I travesty
that we have almost a hundred years of
prohibition preventing stuff from going
you know being available yeah I mean
there's a lot of great points there
feminize seed to to coal that many
plants on an acre per acre basis is a
tremendous amount of infrastructure and
to be able to start non feminized seed
takes a lot tremendous money
infrastructure and when you're a farmer
you don't have a tremendous amount of
infrastructure always set aside for
individual crops it's the main main
mainly a catch-all so it's it's
extremely difficult when you get into a
large acreage to be able to manage that
it's something I've had to deal with
it's something that and continuing I
having to deal with and what's large
acreage to you just for the listeners
large acres is over over 40 40 acres
I think that's large stars to become
something that is requires management
and in a much larger scale than then you
can do individually it requires
equipment that's much larger than
yourself it can be done by humans but
it's it's a tremendous amount of work so
that's you know 40 acres and up all the
way up to thousand hundreds of thousands
of acres so of cannabis of of hemp so
yes cannabis sativa L so I just think
it's it's really hard to manage that
when you're when you're coloring things
and it it it requires such
infrastructure to start your your your
program your genetics so early to be
able to select for that and
put them out at the right time so they
actually don't get too big or and then
there's the management of them of the
canopy in itself and you know it's why
in the East Coast we don't plant until
the second first second week of June
because their plants just get too big we
can't manage it so that's that's
something I see firsthand and and you
know as we learn about this I always
consider cannabis to be an ornamental
that we're attempting to industrialize
and there's a lot of things that we have
to understand before we can attempt to
start like you said before start taking
away things from the gene pool or adding
things to the gene pool so there's those
are major concerns in to bring it back
into the Philo scope I you know I've
worked with Philo's personally and and
and like yourself Kelly I I really am
fond of the people over there and what
they were they've opened my eyes up to
it is a very scary thing to me what is
happening amongst the the industry and
and in the world at large in terms of
genetics however I do think that there's
several ways that we can attempt to
protect ourselves and protect the
legacies that have gone before us and
the preservation aspect is extremely
important and we're all just trying to
make sense of it and I think and not
many people truly understand what is
actually truly happening around and I
just wanted to point yeah I just wanted
to just say that although you know
Mowgli's been a good friend of mine for
a long time what I didn't say is that
what happened and and the rock you know
and the shaking that it did within the
industry you know is absolutely not okay
and it was deceiving and it wasn't what
they started out as and it's not a way
to look forward and it's not a way to
build trust and that's why we're
thankful because it's like yeah chicken
corporations are here and it's for real
and you can lose some [ __ ] ah ha are you
doing best yeah and I just wanted to kid
just to continue that I worked with them
submitted 24 samples of my own personal
work
it was not on the pretense that they
were going to open up their own program
and my heart dropped
when I got the call I knew about that
six months before they did the
announcement and my heart was broken I
mean this is something that I've done
since I was 14 years old you take away
license you take away this whole
industry I still do this and it's it's
something that deeply profoundly hurt me
on on a deeper level than just in a
business move so I just want to point
that out that it's it's it isn't okay I
don't know how we move forward honestly
I'm trying to make sense of that and I
just want to be really open to that if
Mowgli and the team's listening Alicia I
would really like to figure out a way to
understand more about what you believe
that you can do for us but I'd really
don't see it I just don't so you know
I'd love for them to come on the show
Marcus if you can have that and I really
love a lot more transparency to the to
the general community and not saying
that you know since all this has
happened you haven't attempted to do all
that but you've got it we've got to make
make this right somehow it's almost
impossible to have a conversation about
it even now while we have this
conversation there's people in the chat
room who are claiming we're fully
censoring everything there it's like oh
it's a big conspiracy we're all a part
of this conspiracy it's like man listen
like everyone thought it was a great
thing in the beginning and maybe some
things kind of bounced and bumped and
now that people are feeling a little you
know for me I still acknowledge that
it's confusing to me because I hear a
lot of what people are upset about is
not really possible or happening it's
like this made-up
Instagram thing that's not even be it
based in reality it's like we're taking
old material and they're taking the
genetics out and they're creating new
plants like no they're not that's
absolutely [ __ ] ridiculous like at
least get your [ __ ] right if you're
gonna attack a company it did shady [ __ ]
great let's talk about the shady [ __ ]
they did but to just just to create this
other alternative reality is doesn't
help the
situation so I'm down for having the
conversation at the same time I'm also
down for welcoming Colton and Colton and
Wendy to the room the Turner's as the
world Turner's I like that very much and
to see you guys and also to welcome
Joshua in the room to welcome Johnny be
into the room and to welcome Beth who
just rolled into the room who may know a
lot more about this than maybe some of
you think that you know so I don't know
who wants to talk next I want to talk to
all of you but you know maybe Beth you
might want to chime in and tell everyone
who you are and how you fit into this
situation I'm sure and also I just want
to say thank you so much good morning
everybody I am the executive commuted
bath we can't hear you or I can't hear
you uh yeah does anyone not hear bath
other than Josh and Kelly did everyone
else here Beth hello okay thank you good
they'll have to figure it out no no well
I want for Josh and Kelly to hear
everything I have to say so you know I
hope that that that they fix the thing
so I'm the executive director of the
open cannabis project which is closing
on Friday and I am I'm here to join the
conversation to support and answer
questions and like like Steve and I kind
of talked about yesterday I think that
you know part of what has been I mean at
this point like I think everyone knows
the story I've spoken to the press my
story is out there people can read it
and I think that now I think I'm in a
place they're really being ready to well
1 make space for grieving and processing
2 to make space for you know really
defining like ok if an ethical boundary
has been crossed which it has then we
need to define as a community what our
ethics are so that we can better
I defined what it is that we stand for
and face and then thirdly you know I
think that I'm ready to just be in a
place that moving forward and solutions
and to do so in a respectful manner and
you know this has been really I I missed
the early part of the call but you know
I heard Kelly mentioned you know that
Mowgli
is a friend and Magli is a friend of
mine too you know like my heart hurts
for my friend and for our damaged
friendship right now and I think that
you know I want to see amends main on
all sides and I want to find solutions
and I'm here to talk about and I'm
really great all to have the space and
hear what people have to say and all of
that I've got a question for Wade I I
have had the honor of cultivating
harlequin for a little bit over ten
years and you know that was one of the
strains that not only saved my life but
saved multiple other children's legs
around me and I've done my best to try
and spread those CBD genetics to as many
patients as possible but obviously we're
starting to see some of those genetics
now getting incorporated into lines that
are being trying to be protected so you
know taking it back kind of we obviously
want to be able to have strains openly
available but you know how do we develop
lines make them publicly available not
only to the patients but to breeders to
work with and then obviously let's bring
it back to Beth and see how can we not
only you know preserve genetics and the
prior art but also be able to develop
those genetics into potential you know
intellectual property for the companies
great question wish I had an answer if
you look at the model of Harlequin like
THC B was found in the Harlequin as well
which is super interesting see
easiest way yes hello yes I know I can't
hear anyone if anyone doesn't have their
mic muted we won't hear Sam he's only
gonna come in clear if everyone not
talking has their microphone muted
otherwise he's gonna come in choppy like
that I'm not hearing him at all no now
he's stopped talking completely well
I'll try and answer your question I I
love that idea that cannabis is
incredibly elastic and able to give us
whatever we're looking for if we're
willing to go looking for it so what if
you look at what happened with the
Harlequin I see you guys I hear you guys
Josh and Kelly okay I heard that what
just happened I wanna take I wanted to
take a pause and I want to get back to
this conversation because it's very
important but I want to I want to hear
from Wendy and Colton as well because we
haven't heard from them in a long time
and then Wendy said she had some news
she wanted to share with us and I always
like to hear from those guys so we're
just gonna take a little pause we've got
lots more to talk about in regards to
Philo's but let's hear from the Turner's
how is the world turning for the
Turner's oh no no no now their
microphones aren't working do you guys
hear them well let me see if I can fix
this somehow some way let's see
Turner's thumb and today it's been a
quite a
a lot of technical difficulties let's
try now no I don't get it you guys might
have to come back in I'm so sorry which
is so strange didn't we hear them when
they first came in I find that if you're
I don't know if you're on a Mac but I
have found that yeah reconnected maybe
try Chrome
it's the Google it works best with
Google Chat so yeah nobody's nobody's
here and they're gonna come back I do
want to hear from you I don't want them
to you know have to wait around for
hours while we discuss Philo's because
we can go back and and have more of a
discussion and I want to hear you know
there's there's people going off in the
chatroom they want to hear about you
know obviously Robin and Sam's you know
part in Philo's in the beginning they
were the two of the first people that
brought it to my attention for sure and
so we want to hear from them let's let's
see if we hear you guys now no oh my
goodness I hate when this stuff happens
this is like the last time I basically
stopped doing hashed Church because I
couldn't get my I couldn't hear anyone
it but it's not just me nope that's not
hearing so we recycled our page and just
refreshed it and that helped us and
maybe somebody else can do that we'll
see how that goes
you just refreshed just your thing and
you got a saying I am plugged my
microphone I mean I'll just maybe if
anyone can hear us I think I feel like
it's large corporations act differently
than the common like person on the
street you know and it's not to say that
corporations are bad because a lot of us
have corporations and we can do a lot of
good with them and there's even be
corporate you know B Corp and B
corporations which are really awesome
and allow you to take you know
foundation money tax free and that's
really important but I think with people
like Philo's and different companies and
and even other big distribution
companies that are out there you just
start
investment and you start getting
millions and hundreds of millions of
dollars and then it's nearly impossible
for you to keep an authentic true
rightful vision when you have hundreds
of millions of dollars coming in because
the energy just shifts and it takes it
away from the original mission and I
think that's what we're seeing on so
many fronts you know here in Canada you
know farms are either having to join a
large corporation or be incredibly savvy
on their own to be independent of that
so I think that is a big part of the
problem and right now we're having
discussions on you know what we were
talking about earlier with acreage and
how big can a farm you know scale and
still be regenerative and it goes into
the same notion of how big can a
corporation scale and still be
regenerative you know how can we create
systems really that are brand new to us
you know we've seen really small
businesses go to big massive
corporations and how can we blend those
so that people are still having a say
and as well and that that that the rules
and the regulations are for the people
and I think that cannabis is really
giving us this new voice or this new
idea to you know how are we going to
tackle these things and I'm really
thankful that so it's opened our eyes to
a lot of different things there's some
social responsibility so all I could
call it
yeah I'll introduce a term that everyone
should be using corporate social
responsibility you know as you know
independent growers are becoming
companies and then they transition into
publicly traded companies they have a
responsibility to their shareholders but
part of that responsibility to the
shareholders you know you can't include
corporate social responsibility so since
we are the people that are everybody
who's watching this everybody who is on
this call has the were creating an
industry and part of that industry we
have the opportunity to create good
corporate social responsibility and that
comes down to the decisions
that we make you know do we cultivate
using pesticides do we cultivate
regenerative ly do we do we extract
using sustainable methods or non
sustainable methods and while there's
plenty of money to be made while the
price of cannabis is artificially
inflated due to regulation as we
transition into a commodity crop I'm I'm
a firm believer that a lot of the people
that are not cultivating sustainably
aren't going to be able to compete
because you know we can produce acres as
cheaply is you can home grow and even
cheaper you can you can if you're
cultivating using cover crops you don't
have to pay for a Newton as many
nutrients and that makes it far more
sustainable but you know when it comes
to developing IP companies that are
developing intellectual property have
have a responsibility to be able to make
those products available to as many
people as possible and what part of the
reason why I've been I consider it such
an honor to be that mark and everyone
has kind of popped on the church the
church train is because we've been able
to disseminate some of this prior art to
the public while at the same time
promoting good corporate social
responsibility so well put Mike thank
you for sharing that any any word from
Colton and Wendy's microphone are we is
there any sound over there
no oh that hurts me you guys that hurts
me can't even tell you I just want to
hear from them so badly but it's just
like not in the books I guess we're
gonna have to figure you guys know maybe
turn that computer completely off
restart the whole thing turn it off turn
it on don't do a restart do or like a
turn off and I turn on hey Josh Josh I
think josh is on this call Josh why
don't you talk about this class you got
coming up here next month and how people
can learn how to cultivate more
sustainably
perfect how's it going dude dude sorry
my battery died out in the farm Hey yeah
I'll see if I can i can't unplug is my
battery dad but I'm not transplanting
these clones first part the seedlings
and I was cool that Sam is an because I
remember hearing and a hash search maybe
about about this time last year he was
talking to Eric for Jim about yes this
German so I'm doing I'm using this tool
so I'm behind and so I'm transplanting
into four inches so I can cut these
seedlings in the dark for 24 hours and
then bring them back outside and in two
weeks down the road they they'll show
the sexes and so I can call my males
from there and so pretty cool tech I
appreciate that
well yeah so you're talking about the
the aquaponics course we're doing here
in a couple weeks
yeah Steve excuse me Steve and I I'm
really excited I've never hosted people
on my farm so I'm a little bit nervous
about it you know it's kind of feels
like I'm getting down to my underwear or
something and showing my my really
special spot you know it's just mines in
my spot so but I'm really excited and
we're gonna basically just kind of share
everything that we have it'll be really
you know because it's on my farm I can
walk through you know how I do my seeds
how do i do my clones my whole processed
and so yeah and then it there of course
it's an aquaponics focused and we're
gonna build a system here on my farm
I've already got the reservoir dug and
it'll be just a way for the folks can
walk away and say this is how I can
simply build a commercial scale you know
a foot wide aquaponic bed that'll be a
hundred feet long you know and you think
you can scale from there so great
information to be sharing I mean I I'm
sure that people will get a lot out of
it I know that from going to your last
conference there that you did it was
just it was simultaneous to lift which
was very unique in the sense that I saw
them both I just saw them as both like
parts the
need to like fit into one another you
know like so much of lift had no idea
what was going on at your conference and
so much of what was going on at your
conference was everything that was
missing from the lift conference and
everything those people needed I just
thought oh my god like if only these
[ __ ] realize like they just
need to walk two blocks down the street
and all of their consultants all of
their like they're just sitting right
there the people that they need and it's
just it's just you know I think that
with humans we just only know how to
divide and it's just so much like I'm
really as I get older all about this
cuivre idea and concept of having many
arrows in my quiver rather than a single
arrow in my quiver you know like from an
extraction standpoint being a part of a
company that has seven different types
of extraction including solvent
extractions that has never been my
interest or focus whatsoever but I did
get to the point where I realized that
my opinion is may be smaller than the
opinions of the masses and what they
want to have access to people want to
have access to everything they don't
want just one or the other you know
although they make it seem like that
when they put a fence down the middle
and sort of pick one or the other you
just it's it's hard it's a hard thing
man it really is because like what
everyone's been talking about is there's
this part of us that's lost and like
I'll personally want to see you know the
world be full of small farmers you know
I think that would change the world in a
better way a hundred percent but you
know and this is where I guess you would
never hear the 14 year old me saying
this about this but part you know what
we have is is a large agricultural
system and to take advantage of it to be
able to hop into it and change it from
within is the opportunity we have with
him right now and I'm just kind of
realizing that and myself right now with
you actually just getting to meet some
folks from the conference Tara Lee who
hops on all the time her and her husband
they they service you know big AG in
Washington and all the hemp farmers they
sell fittings and sprayers and tanks and
they explained to me that folks will set
up these nutrient ARDS
you know we'll be a two three five acre
facility and they'll don't be making big
new tanks and these semis will come in
and feed off these these new tanks and
then go out and you know apply to the
fields and her thought was like why
don't you and Layton do that with your
compost tea and why don't you grow hemp
and you know in Eastern Washington you
know it's just like yeah that's kind of
cool but as I've gotten involved in hemp
in the last couple weeks I planted
thirteen hundred seeds last night I'm
actually applied for my permit I'm doing
hemp up here on my property and I'm
really stoked on it I'm kind of just
figuring it out and and I'm realizing
that that's a huge way to make an impact
and so we're talking about kind of
partnering together and I'm gonna you
know grow the seed that we can then use
to sell to farmers and kind of get them
on a different path you know you want to
start on a new crop and here's a way
that we can help facilitate building up
your soil you know in the same token so
I kind of see it I feel both sides of it
honestly you know it's just it's the
world we live in in some some respects
well cannabis is unique in the sense
that it's been in the shadows it's been
in the closets it's been in the basement
and it has this like attachment to it
unlike anything else I've ever seen
where there's this real like like I
think it teaches people compassion and
empathy and they're rooted in those
experiences with cannabis and then they
can't remove it even though they're also
like it's removed them from this prison
of being a slave to a monetary system
usually at a young age you like you
figure out like holy [ __ ] like if I
bring like a couple ounces of this [ __ ]
like all my friends will buy it and then
they've got friends that will buy it you
figure out pretty early on that you can
make money selling cannabis it's it's
yeah it's crazy well you know I
definitely think cannabis is special in
that respect for sure Kelly talks about
it a lot and i you know but i believe
all plants really have that in them and
i've been listening to like the
regenerative agriculture podcast with
this this john kemp guy and he's got
these old school farmers on there that
are converting over to regenerative
style and I'm so damn impressed you know
because at the heart of it all these
farmers even the guys that are using
using chemicals they really
the earth you know yeah they can't make
money they're pressed and they're making
bad decisions and like if you can show
them of the right way they're all about
it you know be in this is out on this
podcast I just want to shout it out
because it's just brought showed me how
how you know these old farmers are
converting anger it's changing their
lives and the way they look at
agriculture and the way they look at
their their own happiness you know and
well-being it's just it's really
powerful you know what I feel the police
are having the same revelation with
enforcing cannabis laws as these
cannabis laws deteriorate it's it's much
the same thing where they're just like
any cop can tell you like obviously
people who use cannabis do not cause us
any problems like that's the no you ask
any cop or anyone that works at 911 I'll
tell you like alcohol is a big problem
you know like gangs are a problem
there's drunk driving and but like
people just using cannabis not a problem
yeah in the farming's away of life as
well you know so it's and they're better
drivers as we found out you know through
signs which i think is very awesome to
take some hits and go on a nice little
drive it's partly our responsibility
that way we feel about you know just
your growing you know in a way that's
better for the earth it's just like you
know we're even big large agriculture
whatever everyone's gotten sick at one
point we've talked about this before or
me know they see some kind of
degradation and so I just think it's
important for us to do our best to
regenerate life on Earth so you know
people say well you know what is
regenerative farming regenerative
farming is soil that's better at the end
of the year than when it started or
you've planted more new things on your
property every year and that's a good
start and earlier you know you all we're
talking about that it's great you know
people want different choices well I
think that if people are educated on the
choices that they're given they're going
to definitely true
choose you know the earth and they're
gonna choose something healthy and
they're gonna choose something that
makes them feel good and they're gonna
choose something that is socially
responsible because I think innately
people really want to make the right
decisions but unfortunately it's such a
vast amount of bad information and
marketing and look over here and shiny
flossy you know that is just really
leading you know more money and greed
and I think that we have a social
responsibility as cannabis farmers right
now because we are here having this
conversation that we need to educate our
patients we need to educate our
consumers and give them the choice on
you know what it is that they can have
and I feel like that's really important
in moving in the future yeah creating a
new system a different system one you
know like the the Swedish schoolgirl
there
Greta thunderbird and I'm sure you guys
have seen her speak she's really
inspirational she's like when in front
of the UN and was talking about climate
change and telling the adults they
weren't responsible enough and that you
know that they were just they were like
we're gonna take this over now and she
basically said when there are no
solutions to find for your in your
system then it's time for a new system
you know like you don't like Kat she's
15 years old like if you haven't seen
her before Greta Thunderbird Google her
up and check out her her whippin that
she gave to to the UN address there I it
kind of reminded me of David Suzuki's
daughter who also did a pretty good one
back in the 80s if you haven't seen that
one where she also just like lays into
the United Nations it's pretty pretty
inspirational but yeah Greta thunbergii
never heard of her
Albert Einstein Stein also says that
when you've run out of solution
you've lost your creativity hmm there
you go interesting we still can't hear
the Turner's is this like gonna be the
torture of my day sorry I don't know
what was going on normally well you guys
are a patient
lot and we do appreciate you spending
time with us on this Sunday of
afternoons how is everything going crazy
I bet yeah yeah foundation called the
Turner foundation nice we are going to
be raising funds to fund research into
the medical benefits of cannabis dude
that is so amazing that is perfect for
you guys to be doing you're the perfect
face for such a foundation and I'm
definitely gonna go out of my way and
bend over backwards to help raise funds
for your foundation we found that every
time we go to a doctor with Colton that
they say oh there's no evidence that
cannabis works right here here's your
evidence right here you know I I don't
know how much more blatant you can get
then Colton Turner's : and and even more
so than that the words of a mother who
was going through losing a son and then
have it turned around and like how do
you not just put like we all have
mothers we all have nothing but respect
for our mothers it's like if the mom
says so then it shall be so how is that
not proof enough exactly I don't know I
mean these these doctors we this is the
challenge that we have is that these
doctors don't listen they don't care
they have their own mindset they have
their own agendas and you know Colton
sat in the hospital for 31 days just
recently because had an ulcer in his
stomach or in his duodenum and they kept
saying oh no it's his Crohn's this is
Crohn's disease Crohn's and we're like
no it's not as Crohn's and and they were
like yet but it is but it is but it is
and I'm like but it isn't I'm like why
are you why are you not listening to us
um so one of the things that one of the
reasons why they don't want to listen is
because we were cannabis patients and
are they Keith and and that we don't
have the evidence the clinical proof
that cannabis actually works
in the United States now there is tons
of studies across the world Israel Spain
Canada that are coming out with some
major major awesome evidence that that
cannabis works for a multitude of
situations but here in the US the
doctors are still you know it's not FDA
approved
it's federally illegal still it's a
Schedule one blah blah blah we've all
heard the [ __ ] and we're tired of it
so we we want to create a foundation for
by the time it becomes available to test
to have these FDA approvals to make sure
that like when when you guys are talking
about genetics the it's so important
because I don't know why it works in
Colton and I don't know if it's a
specific cannabinoid if it's a specific
genetic if it's a specific strain um but
we've had to go through all of this
craziness and try to figure it out you
know we need more evidence we need more
research we need more people like you
guys
doing the work and you can't really do
the work when you're trying to run a
business too so we're hoping that this
foundation is going to allow people
farmers cultivators MIPS people you know
product and inventors to have the money
to do extra research on patients to make
sure that what their what their product
is is actually working for patients it's
so crazy that it's this once again this
division where you have this sort of
like oh we want to do things organically
and regenerative lis and they're like oh
we're gonna do it with salts and we're
gonna do it monster style and then you
have the same thing happening with you
guys where you're like you gotta kind of
are the representation of the organic
farmer being listen Bobby I just put up
the doctors and they're just like no no
it's his crohn's we know we went to
school for quite a while it's fine this
look we'll get to you here in a second
it's just unbelievable that there's why
don't we have a system that engages the
people in a different way like that uses
both eastern and western medicine but
also engages the patient as part of this
experience rather than just being talked
to like you know you're a wall but being
like listen to what I have to say like
it's really important what we tell you
is going to help you diagnose what's
going on here because you're not with us
24/7 and and we are you know like how
you not listen to that I don't know
I honestly that is the question of the
millennium I don't know why why patients
aren't listened to I see it every single
day on Facebook in all of these groups
that we were involved in my doctor
doesn't listen my doctor said it was
this my doctor said that the Salar
wasn't giving me those those side
effects and we hear it every single day
and then we're well you know they they
don't want to listen to the cannabis
situation you know they don't want to
say that cannabis actually does help
with inflammation they don't want to say
that it can actually Crohn's or cancer
or any of these diseases no they can't
believe it they want to deny that
reality they're like I deny that reality
and replace it with an artificial
version of my own exactly exactly and I
don't know because of the big you know
they're getting a lot of money from this
these pharmaceutical companies kickbacks
from the cannabis industry and so is
that the reason why we don't know I
think that most doctors are good though
and want to do well in their Hippocratic
oath is that they shall do no harm like
how you they must be so cognitively
dissonant to what is going on and have
convinced themselves no no this is fine
I've met great doctors I know there are
great healer they're healers they're
people that want to help heal people but
there's something how gone down this
road where you know I think it's part of
the schooling and the teaching you know
it's very much like it's not it once
again to use the metaphor it's not very
regenerative the way they learn
medicine and the way they go about
healing in in wet in Western medicine
and at least that it's not accepting of
cannabis I mean they've never been
taught about the endocannabinoid system
can you imagine being a doctor and not
having been taught about an entire
system like imagine them not being
taught about the central nervous system
or the immune system i know i i've
worked with so many doctors over in
third world countries and i've helped
set up clinics and we have to recruit
doctors from all different parts of the
world for them to come over and work in
our little small clinics that don't have
a lot of machines that go being and
don't have you know you know a lot of
that stuff so they have to be required
to use their hands and to use their
intuition and in working in a clinic you
know there's obstetricians that come
from all over the world and they're the
best in their field but when they don't
have their Doppler their machines they
don't actually know how to work with
patients and they actually feel ripped
off they feel as if they you know went
into a system where they wanted to
become a healer and they didn't really
get that information so unfortunately
here we go back to what you all were
talking about earlier x' we're set up
within a system that's totally broken
and there's something about humanity
that continues to set up systems that we
can't actually work within and I don't
know what you know that issue is that's
something really large and existential
and like you go on for hours and hours
but going back to doctors you know they
are not getting the proper education
education is through pharmaceuticals
they can't tell you about curative they
can just tell you what pharmaceutical
works and I think that that's incredibly
unfortunate and I blame that on the
system yet again and I think that a lot
of it is because we live in such a
society that is instant gratification
and they they just don't want to take
the time anymore and you know Colton sat
in the hospital for 31 days and 31 days
they did nothing but he was he was
getting
sicker and sicker and sicker and I was
like what what are you gonna do you're
telling me the same thing over and over
and over again but you're wrong and you
you're not listening to us and I don't I
didn't understand why that kept going
you know at other than you know finally
one of the doctors come in and said well
why aren't you giving him his cannabis
and I'm like I can't he doesn't have a
card in the state of Illinois anymore
and they and she was like I try to find
some anyway you know if that was that's
what works for them then we can do it
and then finally we were just like then
give us a medicine so we can get out of
this place and we take we get him out of
the hospital and here here it goes you
know we give him extra cannabis you know
double his dose and he's flying again
you know and all of a sudden all
everything is gone and and he's back to
normal and he's gaining weight he's
gained like 30 pounds and the doctors
just wanted that instant gratification
or they wanted to do the surgery so they
could have that $50,000 and for whatever
reason I know that there are patients
out there that have great doctors and I
know that there are great doctors out
there but I just don't think that they
understand the plant as much as what we
do and what you guys do and I think that
that's where the disconnect is I think
that me as as cannabis the compan abyss
community really need to get into
educating about genetics and about about
how things work in our bodies with the
cannabis plants I think that's the
biggest disconnect yeah and you're gonna
start to see you know doing FDA trials
in order to create cannabinoid
pharmaceuticals is fairly expensive and
in a black market or unregulated market
the it's difficult to raise money to
fund that sort of research maybe what I
what I liken it to is you know we have a
couple of cannabinoid pharmaceuticals
that have been fda-approved and you know
when you I have a couple family members
that are doctors and while they see the
potential medical benefit in cannabis
their Hippocratic oath do no harm
you know prevents them from suggesting
or recommending herbal supplement
cannabis or nutraceutical cannabis
they're obliged to only provide
pharmaceutically approved drugs because
they're concerned those pharmaceutical
approved drugs have gone through
multiple tiers of FDA review in order to
assure that there is no potential
side-effects or minimize the potential
side-effects now as the industry starts
rolling you see wider acceptance you're
gonna start to see more of those
cannabinoid pharmaceuticals but what
we're really seeing in the in the CBD
realm is broad acceptance as well as
broad deployment of cannabinoid herbal
supplements and nutriceuticals now a
herbal supplement is going to be
regulated differently than a
nutraceutical or a pharmaceutical but
they in we as patients need all three
you know the pharmaceuticals are
necessary in order to get them listed on
insurance prescribed by doctors under
doctor's supervision but you taking
drugs through FDA trials in order to
make a pharmaceutical grading takes
millions of dollars takes years of
trials that have to be supervised and in
the US it's incredibly difficult my my
lab in Illinois applied for to supply
night of four years and three or four
years ago now NIDA has yet to review any
of the applications there's currently
one supplier for the company and we're
talking about a company a company in
Illinois that has billions of dollars of
resources already affiliated with
multiple universities and willing and
capable of doing that research but until
we actually had the federal law change
we can't we have to do that research
abroad so I've done some work trying to
create some of that research in foreign
countries but until the US federal law
gets off their high horse and
reschedules D schedules or creates a
exemption for medical can
this research a lot of the doctors are
kind of stuck in that mindset where they
want to see a cannabinoid pharmaceutical
pill that and when we have those pills
they can be covered by insurance that's
great but what they cannot talk about
just due to the lack of research they
are the nutriceuticals and herbal
supplements and we have a wonderful
opportunity to be able to create
companies with good corporate social
responsibility to create herbal
supplements to minimize the deleterious
effects of many medical conditions and
you know we can't make medical claims on
nutriceuticals or herbal supplements but
we can formulate them in ways that we
know that they're going to be beneficial
to our microbiome and that and I think
that's really the key is being able to
you know everybody says he did it an
apple a day keeps the doctor away eat
your greens cannabis should be treated
as a essential amino acid it should be
treated as a essential fatty acid it
should be treated as a quintessential
part of the dietary intake of all humans
and the difficult part is you know when
many doctors have gone to school over
there you know the past 50 years but the
endocannabinoids system has not been
really researched and it wasn't
discovered until those 80s it's not
really research or even taught in
universities and we're seeing the same
thing the endocrine system wasn't really
discovered until the 50s you could not
learn about the endocrine system in the
human in any med school until the 80s
and 90s and all of a sudden we're
starting to see lots of you know doctors
specifically studying and Akron biology
to help treat the hormone issues and a
lot of those hormone issues are created
by bad diet we're bad by bad microbiota
in your system that's you know not
creating the right ecosystem within our
microbiome so I think that as you know
as sites like granny crows list becomes
more widely dispersed no granny crows
lit list has 700 reviewed research
papers on cannabis but
Stormcrow thank you thank you thank you
late
yeah it's so being able to provide that
education to the doctors knew they
cannot prescribe the nutraceutical
herbal supplements just due to due to
the regulations but they can kind of you
we can as a community create good
corporate social responsibility educate
those doctors as well as you know kind
of promote that research through the
companies that were developing how to do
the same thing is I had to force my
doctors to understand that cannabis was
helping with my conditions and just like
Michelle Rainey back in the late
eighties during the 90s we put together
doctors educational packages enough
education of some of them are 36 pages
long just for the applications in order
to apply for medical marijuana in Canada
but we put together little doctor
packages I focused on injured workers
spinal cord injury Michelle's focus on
cancer stuff like that like yourself we
can focus on getting those paths just
put together that has all of that data
that we've actually you can look to
PubMed case journal stuff like that and
and just put together a nice little
doctor's package one above your Aussie
bus you can present it but here's the
data that we have here's the stuff that
I'm working on it
there's a foundation and and get more
people on board I think it's kind of
like more back to the grassroots of
being able to like they're not going to
click on the link but if you give them
something that they can sit back at a
coffee and read then they might draw
some interest and they see how what's
working for you and they can see the
benefits and I think it's really
important that we still offer that
little little packages to the doctors
and stuff like that in order to get the
education out there in the draws more
interest I mean there's so many
different ways of being able to get
doctors to understand how it's working
for one another and your prime example
of what you're doing like just getting
getting that information out there I
think it's a good idea too and I
remember when you were doing that John
because even when you took me to go see
my doctor you brought a like a big it
way more than 36 pages in 500 hundred
pages or something but you know
basically if we can get these type of
really good packages for specific things
you know to these doctors and you get it
out to enough doctors eventually what
we're going
we're gonna find the cool doctor the one
who's really willing to hear and listen
and that doctor will be so important
those doctors because they are the ones
that will go on to teach the other
doctors that we'll never hear this from
from from a certain type of person
basically a non doctor no you're not
going to teach a doctor about medicine
it's just like it's uh it's part of
their ego like 99.9% of them cannot be
taught and there's this one and I seen
John get through to them the little 1%
where it's just like this is great stuff
do you have any more and they're
devouring it and reading it and they're
interested in it now they're going and
doing in their own deep dives and those
I think those doctors will be very
important in the sort of education of
you know this the line of doctors that
are that are up now but more so the new
line the the the new group that will be
coming and going through medical schools
clearly the endocannabinoid system has
to be taught in medicine they have to be
doing it now I think it's going to be
mandatory in yeah we have over a hundred
years of bad PR to get around and
there's only one there's only one
university teaching cannabinoid classes
that I've heard about there's a couple
of cannabis trade schools but I believe
there's a University Michigan that you
can take a certificate for cannabinoids
well if you're a doctor in Canada or
know she look up the synergies three was
presented in 2012-2013 in the educated
1200 to 1600 doctors across Canada on
opioid system the endocannabinoid system
and how it was very similar and how it
worked with in the CNS it was actually a
really good little thing and it's great
for a good start for doctors in Canada
to look at because it's our to be
presented I think one of the things
that's going to come is as people become
more aware of the fact that cannabis
itself can't do any harm as doctors
start understanding how true that is in
association with the benefits that
cannabis can do when they start looking
at the pharmacopoeia
all the pharmaceutical drugs that they
have every one of them has a lethal dose
every one of them can kill you and often
create all kinds of other problems many
of the old people that I speak with are
taking multiple pharmaceutical drugs and
when you start digging into that whole
list of things and start looking at
side-effects some of the drugs are
prescribed to offset side-effects of
other drugs that they're taking and you
end up with this mad salad of
pharmaceuticals in their bodies and it
creates all kinds of health problems and
what's true is when you start
eliminating those and you start working
with whole plant cannabis medicine
that's the thing it's like when you look
at specific isolated compounds like
Marinol is supposed to be a
pharmaceutical replica of THC and yet
they you see widely different results
from marinol it just doesn't work as
well as straight-up cannabis and again
no lethal dose with cannabis there's all
these potential benefits from its use I
think it was Russo that should be
credited with the concept of the
endocannabinoid deficiency syndromes and
it's and it's basically a list of all
kinds of conditions everything from
autism to cancer to epilepsy to EMS to
Hodgkin's lymphoma on and on that all of
these conditions respond some better
than others to cannabis preparations and
the suggestion there is that all of
these are conditions that arise from
imbalance in the endocannabinoid system
and it's not any one cannabinoid it's
not CBD it's not THC it's not CVC it's
the whole symphony of this beautiful
chemistry that this plant that we love
so much makes that's where the magic is
and what doctors and patients all across
the world are starting to understand is
that it's the plant itself and the
chemistry she produces that's going to
do this healing work for us when when
Kelly was referencing working with
clinics where doctors from Western
medicine don't have their machines that
but they still see a healing and that's
the thing healing happens in hospitals
but it also happens in homes and
increasingly at home people are making
preparations from the cannabis plant and
seeing benefit from it for people that
they love and that's because it actually
works it addresses the endocannabinoid
deficiencies that we're all experiencing
because of the toxic effects of stress
insufficient biome in our diet on and on
and on the list goes but many of us are
experiencing these health issues and
what's true is cannabis has the
potential to be a benefit to all of
those conditions and the trick is
finding the preparations that will
benefit that person but and Turner's
family you're a perfect example of it
you've got the you found the preparation
that was going to help Colin you
increase the dose to the point of
benefit and he was able to leave the
hospital and I'm blown away to hear that
you say I think you said he gained 30
pounds where did where did you put that
on your body as you're sitting there I
don't see it that's all I'm gonna sign
up and listen yeah I don't know where he
put it either he eats like crazy and
he's just so he's just a bin kid but
when it comes to when you were talking
about genetics earlier and talking about
whole plant and in making sure that this
the spectrum is there and one of the
things that we we were kind of back and
forth on that and that's what scares us
is that the medicine that he takes is
actually an isolate and and only because
there was an issue with th TV with him
so with a Crohn's patient you know he he
has a hard time gaining weight so when
he gay
thirty pounds within this last six
months we've been really really happy
but th TV is an appetite suppressant so
making sure that people who don't have
wasting syndromes like Colton not get th
TV is very very important so when it
comes to isolate versus versus full
spectrum this is a really really hard
situation for us because th TV you know
is you know bad for Pete it's not
necessarily bad because it helps people
who just want to lose lay or have
diabetes and I've also heard that people
with PTSD have been benefiting from th
TV but for someone with a wasting
syndrome its deadly so we need to care
that we are taking the cannabinoids we
need we need to be able to identify the
adverse effects you know I I have been
greatly benefited by CBD and CBD V but
th TV in particular in stressful
situations can trigger my Atlantic
seizures and so in general I avoid
strains with th TV but I also know
people who I've treated depression
fitted by CBD and CBD but these
cannabinoids make sure that we
understand the genetics of these plants
and and I think genetics is just exactly
where we need to be studying is is very
crucial to the the history and into the
future of this plant making sure to have
specific medicine for specific diseases
um and and we can grow those on the
plants and in coordinates with what
Colton needs for Crohn's disease or what
you know Sally needs for her seizures or
whatever you know and and those you know
hopefully and can help determine that
this this strain is better for Crohn's
or that strain is better for cancer and
because even the terpenes matter and and
it's it's just it's a wild ride and and
we have so far to go and I think that
creating this foundation and making sure
that we are supporting people that are
that are researching every single aspect
of this plant is it's so so so important
I think it goes back to the quiver once
again because if once again the division
of humanity you just you see people like
you know they'll make these super strong
posts about how why isolate is wrong and
it's all about full spectrum and I get
it it's like yeah skunk man Sam showed
us all about Turkey in modulation in the
early 2000s and years later some of
those people like Ed Rosenthal wrote
articles about Mersin and mangos and
Ethan Rousseau came out with the
entourage effect and you know 20 years
later this conversations escalated to
the point where everyone's really hip
and they're on it and they it's like
yeah yeah some people need terpenes some
people would like isolate some people
don't want this cannabinoid some people
want these two cannabinoid it's like we
need to have access to all of it we need
to be able to take it apart and study in
and figure out mechanisms and then we
need to have access to full plant
regenerative lis organically grown like
beautiful cannabis but once again I just
fall on both sides in the sense of like
both are as important and obviously as
Colton sits there telling us that he's
taking isolate right now obviously it
has it's a very dangerous statement to
go out and say you know ISIL it's not
going to do it for you
you need full-spectrum and then what are
people's versions of full-spectrum you
know like are they collecting the entire
cannabinoid and terpene profile and all
the different types of trichomes that
are present on their plant probably not
if they're doing traditional hash
methods they're probably leaving most of
the bulbous heads behind so that won't
be full-spectrum there's just so many
different ways of looking at it I think
personally let's make sure everything is
available for those that want to have
access to it
absolutely and so we we obviously want
to be able to leave yeah I'd love to
here stands take on all this I know
you've been working with Marinol for
extremely long time and it would be
really helpful and really great insight
to hear your insight on that well IIIi
can talk about that but what I actually
wanted to talk about was genetic IDs for
just a moment I don't know if everybody
heard that in Colorado they are now
allowing a plant registration of
cannabis varieties under you pop as
anybody heard that yes I have
SAMHSA's cone as four patents I've heard
several people say that you know patents
the plant that hasn't existed in nature
and the only way they can prove about is
is has it been tested and is it in the
literature then you can patent it and
you could challenge it all you want but
unless you can prove that was already he
in public domain before the patent then
you can't fight it is that right can
everyone hear him clearly because it
sounds like he's coming in and out to me
I lost a big chunk of that but I got the
very end of it I got most of it yeah I
have a real problem site i I don't know
what to do to make it any better
smoke some hash that always makes
everything better
smoke some hash
except when you've dropped your dabber
and it literally fell through a port all
that is gone my dad was gone my debtor a
diver has fallen I didn't totally hear
everything what was he saying that it
was really hard to patent no he was
saying that listen if it's if you can
prove that it's never a part of the open
source market you've got something
unique you can you can pay patented he's
basically saying I mean there's I don't
know if you guys want to get into like
technical patent land but I'm I'm here
to provide that information if you would
like it there's also Sunday morning I
don't know if it's too early for
technical patent land doesn't land give
you give you Pat land prior art in a
cannabis genetic realm sure no all right
so within so prior art in the genetic
realm so all tools prior arts sorry
there's people talking in my house I was
making
hard to talk to you guys I'm gonna go
tonight which is actually better anyway
because it's like beautiful out there
and then we can spend time on the garden
okay sorry about that though prior art
in the genetics realm so prior art in
general is any sort of like
documentation about a like any kind of
invention that exists and when you know
just to give people an idea of the
process when an application goes to
Patent Office the patent examiner has
the obligation to look for all kinds of
things that might be similar to it you
know so like it's like something comes
in someone says they invented something
there's a bunch of claims and then
patent examiner's go and look for things
that match the claims in the document
and that the evidence and the documents
that they look to is known as prior art
so within the realm of prior art there
are some specific rules about what is
and is not prior art at least within the
u.s. also I'm not I should also always
just say I'm not a lawyer and this is
not legal advice but there's the stuff
that I've learned from talking to lots
of lawyers and if there's any lawyers
out there I always ask them to if I if
I'm technically incorrect about anything
please openly correct me I am playing
with that but in any case but my
undertaking is the way it works is so
you know anything that the Patent Office
looks to is known as prior art and there
definitely there's a whole section in
the patent code that is about what is
prior art they definitely look at things
like old patent applications and they
also definitely look to things like
academic journals and printed
publications and another sort of set
list of things one of those set lists of
things is the National Center for
Biotechnology information the NCBI and
for genetic information and for genetic
data and for genetic data that has been
referenced on Open cannabis project it
is all actually hosted on the National
Center for Biotechnology information so
from a genetics and prior art
perspective that's really the place
where it goes
and where it's the most important place
to look to I've spoken with a last year
I got on the phone with the with a
supervisor at the Patent Office in the
plant department and let him know about
data open cannabis project org he also
knew about the FiOS galaxy so those two
things at least and through that kind of
realm are considered by at least by some
as prior art so and it's the prep the
plant officer told me that it was
something that he wanted to make sure
that his department knew about so in any
case so that's sort of how genetics
plays into prior art but within the
realm of the actual patents that are
coming in part of the reason why Open
cannabis projects which to collecting
chemical data last year was because a
lot of the patent applications coming in
actually reference chemical compounds
and chemical formulations and so that
actually also becomes in some ways at
least right now more important with
regards to prior art however many people
have argued that even though genetic
information isn't as useful right now
for prior art it can be useful in the
future and when it comes to doing the
most robust kind of prior art
documentation which is something that
open cannabis project was not ever able
to do but maybe is something that can
come from future efforts and like you
know new partnerships and all that kind
of stuff is the idea of actually doing
whole plant documentation and similar if
anyone's listening to dr. Eleanor Koontz
who is kind of my hero in this and her
work at the candor herbarium
which she's talking about is actually
doing really sip like thorough
documentation of the cannabis plant
itself which provides more information
that would be useful to the Patent
Office such as you know what strains
it's been and to breeder is actually
honestly depending on how you share and
sort the information you know what you
know what strains have been bred with
the strain what environment was it grown
in like what other special information
can you share about the lineage of this
plant and what's on into it like that
when you're talking about like what is a
plant I mean I think that most people
agree that it's like genetics plus
environment plus cultivation equals
phenotype
so like all of that really needs to be
documented if we're gonna do really
thorough prior art documentation and
then that that information can be as
long as that information is searchable
and organized enough and submit you can
submit it to the Patent Office in
booklet form which is something that I
think that as we look to solutions for
getting prior art in front of the Patent
Office it's either creating which we to
do with open cannabis project MIT
actually has a prior art database it
would be great to get all of these
cannabis strains into that I haven't
gotten a an answer on whether they'll do
that and of course universities are in
this really tough position when it comes
to information about cannabis because
it's still federally illegal and they
get a lot of federal funding so but in
any case that's the least hopefully
beginning to help answer the question
and I'm happy to answer any more but
speaking to the idea that like people
can just patent things already in the
public domain
I would I would actually say that you
know whether people realize that or not
like people have like open cannabis
project medicinal genomics pylos the
cannabis community people have made a
lot of noise about saying hey don't
issue patents on things that already
exist and I would you know I haven't
actually seen any more over-broad
patents issued since the Pharrell
potentially over-broad patents issued
since the first ones that has been
issued to the biotech Institute right so
I don't act and like I know that patent
applications like that are coming in but
how many do you see so far zero so to
some degree I don't see as much like of
an actual risk from the Patent Office
patenting things that are already in the
public domain because there is more
information available now and people
have made us think about it and they
know about all of these references and
since so it's yeah so I don't I think
that there is reason to fear it but I
also think that as where I think a lot
of the litigation that's gonna happen
with regards to over broad patents and
taking things out of the public domain
and actually has a lot more to do with
like herbal formulations
and like formulation and processing
methods than it does on the plant
Sunstone so anyway that's my long-winded
nerdy rant feel free to so normally when
you're developing a patent application
for genetic cultivar for a species of
plant in other other realms be it hops
or in the agricultural industry they're
looking for a couple different factors
that I've mentioned you know phenotypic
what's it what's it grow what's it
produce when you start looking at
genetically engineered you have to be
able to show that you the gene sequence
that you're selecting for is that it
exhibited in over eighty percent of the
populations and oftentimes the in order
to create that speciation or novel to
the Patent Office especially when
they're patenting germ lines or genetic
lines they want to be able to see that a
significant majority of the seeds that
are planted are gonna exhibit that trait
so a f-1 multi poly hybrid has not been
stabilized enough to be able to show
those you know standardized traits
within its cultivar so many i'm same
kind of several things happen where
people are finding rare rare mutations
in some of their CBD things and
considering it novel and that rare
mutation has to then be inbred
stabilized
essentially worked until it becomes a
significant majority of genetic
expression and essentially selecting for
the recessive traits in order to to lock
those recessive traits in with so i
think a lot of there's a lot of concern
that you know breeders are going to do
f1 hybrids and then try and patent them
the reality is that breeding is going to
involve multiple generations of
stabilization in order to start
protecting those patents or absolutely
correct you're dead on and that's the
most difficult part about everything
right now is that you know there's such
misinformation out there that everyone
feelers and everyone's feelers are up
and we just need to dispel a lot of this
stuff so everyone really truly
understands that it's a lot more
difficult than just like fixing things
and and trying to you know do a do a
basic flip you know you can't do that
yeah and ultimately you know that's
where I that's where genetic companies
that are testing the genetics being a
producing those tests for their
customers is really useful because you
know breeders if they can you know and
I've done this on multi acreage scale
will where we'll send in large numbers
of CBD seedlings to get tested identify
the ones that are female that also
exhibit the double recessive CBD a
alleles and then be able to mass
propagate those so that you end up
having if instead of one standardized
seed you have a couple different
cultivars that you're then propagating
into into a field regenerative system
that way you can then you not have to
worry about new coding all of the the
hermaphroditic traits orthene on teeth
the hot traits but on the same hand we
obviously it would be great if companies
that are doing that genetic tested
facilitated distribution of those
genetics through some sort of open
licensing even if those eye open
licensing includes kickbacks to the the
breeders or the genetic developers but
they can i think the concern is is a
perceived conflict of interest and i did
they admit there may be separate
companies but there is somewhat a a
perceived conflict of interest and when
a genetic testing company is then
creating a genetic nursery company now
the likelihood that a leaf tissue sample
could get turned back into stem cells
and then reap Rafah gated is very low
but there is a risk for anyone who has
submitted seeds especially seeds in mass
to a genetic company because you know if
I'm running a testing laboratory for
tests
Akim atrophic samples of cannabis I'm
going to save part of my sample in case
if the test comes back weird so I can
retest it just to standardize that test
now I don't think that any genetic
companies are repopulating genetics but
I do believe that they are you know
correlating their data and you can use
once you start identifying hey this one
allele trait that showed up on our
genetic sequence that we weren't looking
for your years later could potentially
be used for creating this precursor to a
novel cannabinoid because there are
numerous cannabinoids that aren't in
wide distribution and if we can find
those risk significantly recessive
allele genetic snips then we could
potentially you know say okay this this
strain from this breeder this strain
from this reader these four strains from
these four breeders now we can start
developing a breeding platform to be
able to select for those rare genetic
alleles to create rare genetic
cannabinoids reinforce those over eight
to ten generations until it becomes a
predominant profile and that that's
gonna require a lot of testing that's
gonna require a lot of work a lot of
space and we want that the people doing
that genetic work to be able to see some
some success from that but at the same
at the same time so I we in some realm I
think that you know I think patents are
going to be a necessity but what we do
with those patents we don't want to be
able to take the rare genetic alleles
off the market and only make them
available in pharmaceutical drugs we did
it far better to be able to have that
here a multiple Sam sounds like
the teacher on Charlie Brown you lost
you Sam we lost yeah
this is crucial Sam I wish you were in
this one I know it's like there's quite
a few things I want to hear from him
right now it's hard I do there's so much
well can you hear me that's the that's
the the truth of it all I hear you now
but now I don't is my voice normal or is
it all screwed up it's kind of screwed
up but that's normal I need you to
appreciate that well I just in color
proud of this month the first you pop
plant registration breeders rights has
been applied
oh I am wondering if this comment can be
submitted in the chat because I really
want to hear it and I think that all of
us are struggling because we want to
hear it but the audio connection does
not yeah you should type it Sam and then
I can we can all read it or send it to
me in Skype or whatever whatever it
works because I really do want to hear
from you right now yeah I think what he
only heard parts of that but I think
what he mentioned was the so recently
the US Department of Agriculture has
started saying that they're allowing
plant registration on cannabis cultivars
now they're primarily phrasing that in
the realm of hemp cultivars but there
have in the last month there have been a
few Colorado hemp cultivars that were
developed from cultivars not from not
indigenous to Colorado but they've been
worked by companies in Colorado and they
have been applied for on on that plant
registration so we are gonna start to
see that starting to happen and I've
even seen a couple of these CBD seed
breeders are requiring their customers
to sign material transfer agreements
that requires non non replication which
I kind of understand I see breeder
doesn't want to have the seeds knocked
off but they also include things like no
cloning and no breeding with those
strains and it's the reason why that
company is doing that is because it they
want to be able to start protecting
those lines and they don't want to have
their their work knocked off but I think
it's it's a little bit over intrusive to
try and require people to develop your
work and to be honest I think it's bad
marketing you know if you're developing
a line that ends up becoming for example
the next Harlequin or Charlotte's Web
tons of potential there and that's you
people working with your line or only
it's only going to benefit them so
you there he's there but I bet that's
not gonna sound any better than it happy
nuts that's kind of how we feel is I
mean we every every event that we've
gone to we have seed swaps you know and
it's always like the funnest thing about
the event you know just sharing genetics
and doing all this stuff but then it's
like we're we come around the corner
after a seed swap and then slam on
brakes or oh my god why we have to start
I'm gonna stop going to seat swaps now
I'm gonna start saving all my seeds
because I'm just nervous someone else is
gonna maybe do it better than me or
they're gonna mass-produce it and
they're gonna to take me out of it and I
really just believe that the art is in
creating the genetic it's not just the
genetic I think that we're all lucky to
even be talking about this if we're
honest with each other because this
plant came from wherever it came from
buddy did it before us and we're putting
intellectual property into it I mean you
know the the Bubba cush hemp do you know
I mean that's a that's an amazing you
know intellectual thing that was traded
there and and and you know there's maybe
there's there's a lot of value to that
but in general I think like with with IP
and recipes we've always given out
everything for free and we even have a
company that's potentially threatened by
giving out that information but we just
feel like if someone takes that and
makes the world a better place then
who's really losing so we're just
challenged to become better and more I'm
how how can you own a part of a plants
evolution we're all evolving I don't
understand like this ownership of
evolution it just doesn't make sense to
me we're always evolving the plant is
always evolving so you're patenting
something that's like way back in 2018
and then it's gonna evolve so many times
past that it's it's um it's just a
really interesting conversation and I
and I think that we have some kind of a
disease or a virus inside of our DNA
that we thrive off of competition and I
think that we have this ability
for the plant and what she's taught us
in the way that we commune with in the
cannabis culture to really drop that
idea of competition and be able to share
and open source it and make it already
art that has happened before so that
other people can't have it and I think
that a lot of people in the cannabis
culture are not really wanting
necessarily to own something they just
don't want somebody else to own it so
that we can't work with it and I think
that that's really more of the focus I
mean we want people to have good
business we want people to protect you
know something that they've created all
that is a real thing but I think that we
shouldn't be threatened by something
else bigger and better that's the way we
feel I mean and you guys can say well
imagine if the guy who created a guitar
said you could no one else could make
guitars I mean dude I use that is it's
super extract yeah at the same time come
on you know it's there would be no
diversity in music in culture and that
too transcends culture and humanity in
so many ways just yet at the same time
when Quincy Jones takes like particular
notes and puts them in an order
absolutely he can own those now no doubt
yep sampled and turned into something
else I think that because y'all are
talking about like like it's interesting
in this conversation because it brings
up a really important point and actually
I was it brings a really important point
about intellectual property in the word
intellectual property and and I think
it's a word that I don't want to use
anymore because it's actually really
confusing and it's confusing because it
is one word and this is actually like
after all of this crazy with open
cannabis project and reading more
Richard Stallman and all that kind of
stuff he's actually one who comes up
with this idea that like intellectual
property actually is a term that is
meant to reference depending on here
talking to between you know three and
nine different sets of laws that
actually all work differently so like
Quincy Jones's notes that he puts
together it's covered under copyright
that is one set of laws that is applied
plants are covered under not only patent
law but they're also covered under USDA
protections which is actually the plant
variety protection thing that I think
that Sam was talking about that opened
up in Colorado but I need to look that
up the plant variety protection is for
stable seed lines right and that's
actually run by the USDA and then there
is ownership law at play even in so
there is ownership law at play for
example like when we talk about plants
or seeds that are in the public domain
right plants and seeds that might be in
the public domain from a patenting
standpoint and from a USDA standpoint
still might be owned by somebody right
like they might be owned by right there
might be on my bubble man for example
and so you know if they are actually
owned by somebody then they are affected
by the law that like the rules of
contract law and so on for and like and
it's interesting because all of these
laws are kind of at odds with what we
think and how we feel but understanding
them and this is where I feel like
education is really important for this
community in particular I want for us to
be able to understand how these laws
work so that we can effectively use
these tools and I'm not saying that
patents are it I'm not actually really
don't like patents on fans especially
cannabis plants you know but like we
need to be able to understand how these
laws work so that we can effectively
navigate it and not be caught in a
situation where we actually hurt
ourselves because just we misunderstood
something or conflated concepts
yeah and careful when you're talking
about it and you don't make your
statement that you're not really Pro
plant patents because man can you
trigger some people who plant patents in
the cannabis world triggers it total
triggers and also like plant but this is
where it's I also like you know I kind
of have a like a challenge or like a
challenging question that I would be
interested to hear from folks on this
group about which is that like okay so a
plant patent really covers a single
plant and it's clones and that's it
USDA protection
a stable seed line and that's it
utility patents can cover like you know
within one document like a plant plus
its clones plus its seeds plus all the
products made with it plus anything made
with it and so you know my question is
like from an ethical standpoint what is
wrong with a plant patent or a USDA
stable seed line protection if all that
it really says is yes I invented this
but sure people can still breed with it
I'm not I actually don't necessarily
think it's a good use of money or time
but I'm interested to hear from the
group like what your thoughts are on
these like different types of like
protection options and where the ethics
ethical lines are drawn within the
beliefs of the community I think the
problem with the ethical lines is that
they are they are warped and manipulated
by the lawyers who write up these these
laws and these these these you know
documents in the first place so that's
that's that's kind of probably the main
problem that it's becomes corrupted from
the start literally the foundation of it
is like I mean a lawyer a good lawyers
job is to stretch and define that that
the the envelope and to kind of get it
you know let's push it even further in
our favor because you know that's that's
I work for my client and I'm looking to
you know you know best that interested I
mean there's lots of good jokes about
lawyers as we all know so the question
of the ethics behind the people that are
submitting that said patent and the
years you know the intention behind it
and there's so much that goes on and on
that you know is clearly undefinable
until it's too late
yeah and then let's let's start with a
clone because I think that's the that's
one of the more narrow ones you know
I've I've heard of several different you
know companies in multiple states that
we're looking for genetics to bring to
bring into their production facilities
now it's difficult to have interstate
commerce but there are ways that you can
you know immaculately conceived those
genetics into those things and then
create a licensing on copyright
I think it's copyrighted or trademarked
names and I've actually seen some
European seed companies that are
trademarking names and then if you're a
licensed producer you can license that
trademarked name in order to sell those
seed likes now I get approached all the
time like that to be honest there's
there's a ton of people that out there
absolutely going out there reaching out
to people yeah and if a breeder has to
spend the money and is you know we're
doing breeding properly I'm not talking
about pollen shucking I'm talking about
you know developing facilities that are
that are nude specifically designed to
prevent pollen from spreading around
cross-pollination you have to build you
know pollination chambers for your
breeding programs if you're doing those
Fino hunting - the actions to develop
those lines then as interstate and
international commerce begins it's going
to be very beneficial to the the
breeders to develop those lines and
potentially license them out just so
that you know now that said the minute
you start selling seeds for example it's
difficult to license a strain to a
grower they say to a farm if you are
also selling seeds because that farms
part of the the license e legally
speaking wants to know that they're
gonna be if they're gonna pay that
premium to have that specific clone then
you know they want to know that you're
not openly distributing that clone now
I've seen licenses where that you you
have that proprietary clone but you
still can have genetic hybrids available
and I think some breeders in Europe are
doing that where they're still sowing
seeds but if you want a exclusive
license on my this this chemo trophic
Pro
file of this phenotype of this gene
sequence cut of this clone then I think
that's a good way for you know grower
growers and specifically breeders to
generate revenue when you can't have
those genetics legally transferring
across jurisdictional boundaries now in
Canada has a pedigreed seed program a
couple European countries also have
pedigreed seed programs and part of that
pedigree see that I think Josh and Kelly
mentioned earlier developing feminized
line you know you have to if you're
gonna do a pedigreed seed program not
only do you have to create that
standardized seed but you also have to
be able to produce it where you you and
your farm minimizes risk of pollination
and there are parts of Oregon that that
had really big problems with cross
pollination from hemp farms that hemp
farms that were doing breeding we're
getting pollinated by hemp farms that
were just open pollinating hybrids to
harvest seeds and so Canada actually has
rules and regulations around pedigreed
seed varieties and while I personally
may not be really interested in a
feminized autoflowering line there are
lots of corn farmers and soybean farmers
and wheat farmers that need those
genetics need those pedigreed seeds in
masse by the ton to be able to plant
those crops and stop growing
unsustainable crops in monoculture a lot
of those farming realms have seed maps
you know different food food farmers
have seed maps of what's grown where
because if you're say a cabbage farmer
you don't want to be downwind from
Canada our kale farmer or broccoli or
something like that so you don't get
cross-pollination so I think that it
would be important for us to develop
seed maps within for sure the hemp room
because hemp is easily thrown around up
here
Canada or in different realms as is it
seed and fiber hemp which you would grow
male and female or is it medicinal hemp
which you would grow you know all female
for medicinal and there really should be
a different classification of that hemp
and I think there you know there's talk
about that but there really should be
seed maps because there's a huge level
of responsibility that comes from
growing cannabis because of its pollen
and obviously it was a problem with
soybeans because of what happened with
per she's Percy Schmeiser and and all
that with you know genetic pollen drift
and all that but you know it's it's
something that does require
responsibility and I think that you know
and and getting to know our genetics
better so we don't have hermaphrodites
because you could grow us you know forty
acres of feminized seed and they're
there there is still pollen that can get
created in that field you can't just
walk away and plant you know forty acres
of feminized seed and just guarantee
that there's not going to be some pollen
in there so I think there's some
responsibility say okay you know you can
grow 40 acres ahem you know it doesn't
mean it because you're you're a 40 acre
hemp farm and you have machinery that
you're not supposed to walk the field
still and to throw a little bit of a
loop in it you know there's everybody
who's the home grower and everybody in
every circuit has their four plants and
guaranteed there's going to be pollen
all over the place pollen happens yeah
we need to make a shirt it would piss a
lot of people off we got to get together
with the four plant fam that's what I'm
gonna make sure I write there everyone's
on board with with Canada and the four
plants and and with all the new growers
out there even I was at the hydroponic
store spent half the day there yesterday
with all these new growers coming in and
one of the way they can get seeds with
and get clones what's the best way of
growing and and right now for for us
we're just kind of putting people more
towards like an autopilot system for so
don't really go four feet or whatever
like that you want to go indoors but I
mean it comes down to a big thing right
now is about seeds what you can actually
get through the government right now
which is throughout birdie to buy some
seeds and stuff like that but there's
lots of online seed companies and people
are
buying seeds want to know about
feminized see the lines wanna know what
seeds to buy what's gonna be better for
the condition and where did they go to
get this information so there's this
whole new other industry that people
earning and looking at right now and and
I see it explosion in a local
hydroponics doors of all the new novice
quarries you want to grow for the ground
mower because they have this pain or
they want to try this for that and I
think it's just another real real way of
now educating people on how to grow
their own for plants in Canada and
really get into to know how they can get
up and weed and help them nice to be and
for plants in the world I mean countries
all over the world are starting to allow
for plants and people are really coming
on and learning about the medicine we've
made our hemp oil with medicinal
mushrooms for you know a lot of years
now and we've worked with families that
have had to continue buying medicine
from from the hospital in order to not
be red-flagged by the medical industry
and then just stop using that medicine
but they just kept buying it because
they just didn't want to be a red flag
and they were able to cure them
you know themselves through through this
medicine and everything so it is a
really powerful medicine I do feel like
we have this knowledge you know a
hundred years ago in the 1800's you know
cannabis was part of a lot of the
medicines and hemp was used in
agriculture and as fodder for animals
and that was at a time when THC hadn't
been read into the plant so there was a
wider spectrum I think there was a
general more health and I think that and
I really do wonder if as they were
starting to control plants and create
industrial farming with synthetic
fertilizers and I why I think the plant
being such a fractal medicine such a
changeable medicine is I think that's
what's good for our body I think that
when you when you're a patient you want
to have the same strain because you want
to have the same effects but I think
that that you can it's sometimes a
little bit of
variation with that with with similar
strains can be really positive to your
body and sometimes having the same thing
over and over isn't necessarily
something that's good for longevity so
the plant has shown us that a bit
changes a little bit and I think that
there's probably a point of health to
that that we might want to embrace and
and not need to like control certain
aspects or certain meanings but I mean
we're you know we're interested in
learning and basically just flooding the
cannabinoid system you know our
endocannabinoid system with all
different cannabinoids and that is
important and I do understand isolating
and I do understand you know the
distillate I get that in patients being
able to use that but also being able to
flood the endocannabinoid system with
with all different forms of medicine
whether you're smoking it you're vaping
it you're eating it you're using it
rectally you're using it on your skin
these are all really important things
that I think that we need to do to
better our health and and what Josh was
saying is that the plant is always
mutating it's always changing not
mutating but it's always transitioning
it's always in a form of evolution and
evolving so it changes a lot of its
cannabinoid ratios and terpene ratios
the different areas that it's growing in
and that's really cool we can follow
that lead the plant and and she can
teach us so much and that yeah nature's
chemist right I mean it's such a
beautiful thing but we also need to make
sure that you know we we have consistent
that medicine and one of the one of the
situations that we always run into just
being patients going into a dispensary
is that you can't always find heart of
one and you can't always find a Kim dog
you can't always find the specific and
strains that you you're wanting to that
you know make your headache go away or
make your hit like his Crohn's help you
know we we also need consistency in
genetics we need to keep continuing to
make new cultivars and and and and have
new products but we also need to have
consistency too and you know if somebody
would just keep keep growing at
harlequin or or
sorry tsunami then we would be so happy
because it's a consistent medicine its
interests totally agree with that and
not part of the evolution and fighting
new strains you know where we know is
the evolution of different medicine but
then when you find it it is really
important you know to continue that and
there's incredible power and for plants
and and learning from somebody who's
cultivated for a long time you can get a
tremendous amount of weight off of four
plants and I think that we're really
encouraging home growers to find the
medicine that's good for them get the
strains that works for them and make
their own medicine because then that's
going to be able to give us a greater
education and being able to commune with
the plant and and understand what it
gives us and what it means to be able to
make medicine so I think that that you
know I agree with you that we absolutely
need to find you know solid lines for
what works with us but that's gonna
happen through through people growing
therefore and you'd almost have to say
oh then you have to clone them and so
sometimes keeping clones alive is a hard
thing to do as a farmer so then we're
going to seeds and when we have seeds
then there's a little bit of variation
so what you know from a farming
perspective we have to kind of weigh
that out you know do we want to have a
clone farm for consistent medicine cuz
it makes so much sense and you're
getting what you want or even but
there's you know different yeah there
can be pathogens or different things
that come with clone farms so if we if
if I think if we can find a really
stable feed line that gives us keep of
ours that are really close to what you
want I think as a farmer and something
that's better for the you know for our
evolution I think that would be an ideal
situation but I armors and patients need
access and in states like Illinois they
can't home grow is difficult so it's not
allowed right not just difficult as a
state regulated process because home
grow in the state of Illinois is is
going to come but it is going to be
ridiculous
over-regulated and we're gonna have
somebody come into our home and check
our plans and check where it's supposed
where where we're growing it so now we
have a police officer in our house which
is total you know that's a another
conversation all together but I have
four children and I have AI and he's
extremely busy all the time and we own a
business and we have other children that
are off doing everything you know things
so so having a home grow is very very
difficult especially in the state of
Illinois if home don't grow passes
because you can't have your neighbor
come over and water your plants and so
home grow even though I completely
support it and I wouldn't and I would
love to home grow because I like well I
can't I suck at it
um but I would like to do it and at
least have that opportunity home grow
can be very difficult for a lot of
people and home grows very difficult for
a pace for a mom who is a single mom who
has a disabled child there they're doing
enough as it is so we really have to you
know depend on the growers in the in the
cultivation system you know the
commercial cultivation system because we
we don't have the time and effort and
and energies to be able to do that kind
of thing and you know there's a really
interesting frame here when it comes to
both trying to create really well
regulated consistent medicine you know
and then plants as well as well we've
got when we're trying to get that kind
of real variance and and like you were
talking about that the variety of
cannabinoid entering profiles that
naturally evolves and gives us that
diversity so it's not like we're eating
you know that nutritional analogy
something we're eating the same foods
every day we've got diversity in the
diet having diversity and you know what
we're taking in cannabinoid wise and
terpene wise in both of these cases a
huge piece of this comes down to the
epigenetics right that we've been
talking so much about the genotype and
and that and we've talked about near
that environment plus growing combining
with you know type getting that
phenotype expression
and really so much variance on that
epigenetic expression based on
everything from the microbiome in the
rhizosphere right to the soil to the
nutrients to the environment
environmental conditions you could take
you know one genotype and seed source or
even clones hold them in completely
different environments they get totally
different could be different cannabinoid
interview profiles and so I think in
addition to really emphasizing the
cultivating the the genotypes and those
really good genetics which i think is so
crucial I agree completely really
developing and refining how we're
supporting regulating that epigenetic
side of it both for you know we're
trying to grow specifically for really
consistent you know profiles I think
that's really important for that as well
as when we're trying to get that real
diversity that's gonna allow us to get
those different essentially cannabis
nutrients different cannabinoids and
terpenoids just such a crucial piece to
really have in play and and and I I'm at
a loss for words are you aren't you
Peters friend I am yeah okay what do you
think of them apples I preached everyone
on the panel today for coming in and
sharing your time and having these
conversations it's it's I miss it on
Sundays I'm busy as Wendy said I have to
sort of back Wendy up to on the like you
know the that utopian like everyone
should grow their own medicine I think
it's an amazing idea I gotta put you on
mic mute mic you're banging around their
room it's an amazing idea and I've seen
you know guys like Johnny be able to do
it there's there's there's people they
can do it I myself I have a 98 Plant
license I haven't grown a plant in
probably over two years I'm just too
busy I can't lay it on my wife who is
caring for three children at any given
time it's not
fair to her it's not that easy for
everyone to grow their own herbs just
like it's not easy for everyone to have
their own gardens and grow their own
veggies and make their own clothes
you're growing up soon you know they
might be able to help in the future in
my life had I if I had a greenhouse
behind my house with cannabis and food
growing in it I'd have to have someone
to help do that work because I'm just I
travel too much I go these things
require attention and they require love
they what they don't require is like
five and seven and ten day trips in like
during the most important like you know
like okay I've avenged them out they're
just starting to flower they're three
weeks in a flower I gotta go it's like
ooh like week four five six I've played
it out too many times and it's not that
easy for everyone and it's it's one more
reason why of course we need home grows
we need everyone to be able to grow
their own cannabis if they so choose but
on the flip side of things we have to
understand there's a whole group of
people who are unable to grow their own
cannabis for a variety of reasons and
they need to have access to both the
full spectrums the plants the extracts
the isolates everything like don't
anyone think that their opinion is
better and bigger than having access to
everything for everyone that's the
answer to me access for all totally
agreed I I love that thank you Marcus
it's so important and in all of those
different ways of extraction and of
caring and of cultivation just do it
socially and and ecologically
responsibly and and I think that that
then we've got it all the way around
totally totally and on that note I've
got this really nice Burmese hash out
from Whistler that our friends brought
out and I just got to give like some
love to the the old school hash bacon
Whistler family there that this is like
super dank it and really good and this
Burmese strain is like it's really sweet
yeah oh yeah
is that abby's [ __ ] incredible well
it's not aliens it's it's super amazing
and also this this ice wook big up to
the ice wook ganja Gil cuz this this
skittles gelato right now are you
kidding me really I mean like it's time
to take some tropical cookies you go
yeah
tropical cookies hash frozen from
heavenly days and then he also gave me a
tiny little bit of I'm gonna find it
show and tell what's the other what's
the other yeah yes part brat no that's
not skin on stron under bro that's not
skittles Johnny be on the bottom of this
no no cuz I talked to RO you're making a
mistake
you have the same thing I have tropical
cookies okay and men don't breath I know
I meant to tell you that earlier that's
right because I was like dude you gave
Johnny B the skittles he's like I don't
have any skittles I gave Johnny B the
tropical cookies special ok that was the
stuff after the accident that kept me on
the coach oh yeah that would be very
much right up your alley
naki whoa and it's really and that's the
big thing about extractions and stuff
like that really looking at that was I
was really grateful to actually come
across and getting some really sedating
really good in the hardcore concentrates
I got that accident which a few people
know a couple weeks ago and I was 17 but
I mean is it's right away I needed that
harsh sedation I needed that that really
good effect and it came to me just like
perfect timing and then the uplift thing
is I'm kind of getting out of bed now
feeling a bit better to kind of get you
going and understanding your medicine
and how it works is is is another great
experience and an education for yourself
and really paying attention to what you
use everyday and how it works within you
and this is just you know as that people
know it kind of gets me going
while talking about that side handed
cannabis Manta says never drive with
John I was rear-ended okay by something
is texting and driving now the c-4
reminds describe that was that major
surgery I was in rear-ended again by
some idiot we made a left-hand turn when
they said no left-hand turn and
rear-ended me and then once again I'm
driving through an intersection where
it's a flashing pedestrian crosswalk in
this a thing and as the light turns red
something I haven't vehicle speed doing
the Hyneman t-bone oh three activists
were never my fault but I'd be driving
so repeating never once again I mean I'm
only a really good driver and then I
didn't for my before my injuries when I
came out of my surgery
Marc showed up with 50 different
terpenes but at that point I really
realized helpless but really took my
pain away and that was really important
fact that Louie took me to that
different really educational for me to
take a look at how teens and then take a
look at a moisture content and keeping
that aw which we're going to talk more
about I know in in the future here
because I'm talking to Marc a little act
of water and both standardization and
keeping cannabis fresh for pain control
for other things were you looking at
that same terpene same freshness so well
something dries out you don't get that
same effect but when it's not a friend
you get that really nice effective well
here in Canada is the producer to
something really dry unstandardized
cannabis and I think it's a really big
to crisis in my opinion because I'm
getting nothing that's gonna be
effective for me on the legal market yet
and I'm hoping to see we I think you'll
be an extract guy once that comes out in
October I can't imagine you doing too
much flour anymore when you can just buy
the extract and the that same active
water won't affect the extracts nearly
as much as it extracts the plant matter
Johnny's been going deep down the rabbit
hole of active water I almost always
want to call it active water content but
I have been schooled and educated that
that's wrong Johnny's been talking to
one of the main
scientists at Boveda who was the guy who
designed and developed a lot of the
Boveda packs for different moisture
contents and whatnot so he he taught
John about active water and then John
got a machine and he's been doing these
tests and it it's a pretty important
work you know once again you can go
write a bloody PhD on any aspect of
cannabis but you know now you've got
companies that are unable to secure the
cannabis and seal it properly in a
container and if they are sealing it
properly
what are they sealing it with is it a
glue and is that glue affected by the
gassing off of the terpenes within the
package that now eats that glue pops the
package allows oxygen to come in and
have it all mixed up together so this is
quite a rabbit hole Johnny's going deep
down will probably end up having a hash
Church about it one of these days but
he's got a bunch of videos little
snippets on his channel at John HBO
fellow and we're gonna do a video on
bubble man's world in the next couple of
weeks hopefully where we go and get a
really good overall view of this what it
is this active water you know which is
basically the moisture content within
the flower but also the moisture content
in and around the flower within the
package that it's within so it's pretty
important as John has been learning you
know to give you an idea what is it like
in the in the high 20s and that [ __ ]
turns to dust John yeah 28:29 bread
crumbs aw is set at 30 pasta is 50
mostly account of us I'm testing it
between 29 and 46 and what do you think
it should be 55 to 60 Oh 55 to 58 I
think seems to be what the US government
I've heard some little things that are
key coming from government system a at
the 58 seems to be that aw reading
that's easy be at a safe zone or
anything at 64 and 65 we know 65 calls
us more these molds stuff like that 62
is kind of people a little scared a ton
so I think the 58 and I'm seeing that
more with the people that I'm kind of
more or less consulting with and talking
with they're trying to get people on
that 58 percent and there's relative
humidity there's there's gonna be things
I really want to talk about where I'm
going to talk about it on just you me
mark
do a whole section on it then probably
come back with Church after and get more
really deep into it and talk more about
it because something has to be done and
once we get that I think it's gonna set
a real standardization for just not just
here in Canada before around the world
of being able to standardize different
strange different products and I'm
seeing it huge for me because I mean
fighting that standardization by
decarboxylation with dr. Horne BT trying
to standardize my girl what's using a
one-part Kornblum and when it come down
all at the end it really came down to aw
I really started feeling that that
keeping this fresh all the time at a
certain moisture level really plays a
key role and being able to get that same
feeling all the time so it's a huge our
own ups yeah yeah I just wanted missus
yeah this is this is just I mean it's
nice it's fresh it's it's it's yeah it's
like guys yeah one day do you find that
flowers dry out faster or or differently
based off different growing styles
Johnny stay like soilless medium or an a
rockwool aeroponic or a super deep
living soil what's your opinion on on
how those flowers cure all right I've
seen them because I did some soil
testing years and years ago and I found
the more airier stuff kind of dried up
quicker and that was when I was just
using a pure cocoa to be honest and but
I was swinging this difference with heat
and then it does different soil mixtures
with just pro mix and then like an
amendment of cocoa and something else
III really comes down to is is is the
but if it's it's a team that's more area
it's gonna cure differently if it's more
into kind of harder it's cured
differently I'm seeing a different just
in and packaging and just saying if say
I normally used to package my cannabis
to say 62 to 60 percent
well that aw is actually 50 to 52 inside
a container so right there I can tell
you what provinces are packaging without
using control brooms
across Canada by testing all the LP weed
right now
just by testing and I already know what
province is coming from which is funny
so there's all these olds they're
interesting I I just you know gut
feeling is you know that the more
microorganisms you have in your iso
sphere and the more fight you know
fungal filaments and fine filaments that
are activated with minerals inside your
accounts that it's gonna it's gonna
create better waxes and better try comb
you know cellular walls and that's gonna
affect the gases and the off gassing and
because i know a lot of farmers that you
know and hash makers that you know will
hang their plants up in a controlled
environment you know for three three
weeks you know four weeks and and some
weed that would dry out too fast you
know and it would just get crumbly and
stuff so i i'm just i would that's
something that we like to see more
information on it's just you know the
difference on yeah we're we're testing
on a couple points here there is a lot
of evidence looking at the symbiotic
relationship between the soil microbiota
because of the soil microbe I will
actually provide nutrients my nutrients
out of the the minerals as well as
create turkey and precursors and excrete
through a symbiotic exchange for glucose
provide minerals as well as terpenes and
and other nutrients to the plants so yes
having a more diverse soil microbiota is
going to produce more greater chirping
contents in canvas varieties I would I
would hypothesize that different
microbial bacteria are going to be
providing different nutrients based on
their role in a soil ecology but on top
of that you know there's there is some
quite a bit of published research
looking at silica content so content is
going is oftentimes absorbed by the
plants and then used in building cell
walls
and same with calcium magnesium
magnesium more for chlorophyll
production solo of magnesium soils are
gonna have less chlorophyll less that
you have to cure out high silica soils
are gonna create more woody stocks but
also have thicker cell walls and then so
there is going to be that we see that
the same thing with grapes growing
grapes and different appellations or
terroirs are going to produce slightly
different notes based on mineral content
of the soil bacteria in the soil and
even growing conditions and even when
the plant has its own microbiome which
is called the end acidic reaction within
the plant and we know that when we look
at say the yew tree we there was tax all
that was coming from the yew tree and
what they realized was that the cambium
layer within the yew tree it was
actually the end of fights that were
creating that tax all so what we're
really interested in is that is the
interior yeah that they were interacting
to make it medicinal and we know that
this is a medicinal plant with just
seven several different opportunities
within its cannabinoid ratios so I'm
really interested in endo FIDIC reaction
within the plant that is actually
creating the medicinal compounds and
that's something that you know is is
really interesting and that's something
that you're gonna get through soil
diversity and through microbe a healthy
microbiome so we talk a lot about you
know the the microbiome within the soil
it's really interesting to talk about
how that relates to the microbiome
actually within the plant and yeah and
this is this is so huge because what
we've seen and we're you know our sort
of group and company is very much
involved in him specific and cannabis
specific it's all cannabis but
microbiology that really benefits and
supports oil production as well as
overall meal plan now that's really our
area where we live to geek out on and
you know we've seen both when when
you've got really that kind of a
specific biology in the soil how it
interacts with the biology of the plant
it's with its internal microbiome and
what that does to oil production and
terpene production in general we've seen
trichome actual formation structurally
with lower rates of decarboxylation when
you've got sir on when it's still on the
flower you know when we've when we've
got the right biology in the soil and in
the rise of sphere and how its how its
interacting so both how that relates to
the drying out of effect you know and
those increase resident oil levels like
you were saying the waxes and lipids as
well as all those different components
we found that to be really significant
for sure and also speaking to this
silica we've actually found there to be
about four key pillars is sort of our
feeling in the soil to really get those
highest oil contents which I think have
a big factor also on that drying out
approach but also just quality and
everything we've been talking about in
terms of that there's different major
quality pieces and and how things drying
and result as well and you know one of
those the first that we really found is
that first pillar it's definitely that
hemp specific or cannabis specific
microbiology in the soil with good
diversity at high populations is just
crucial both because of everything from
the nutrient you know availability and
an absorption soluble disease and
soluble icing mobilizing chelating it
and as well as really that comprehensive
root health but also like you're saying
they're stimulating with their secondary
metabolites a lot of those biosynthetic
pathways that are actually gonna be
stimulating those synthase enzyme
production for cannabinoids and turkeys
and providing those precursors so that
that's we found that to be really
crucial for increased oil production and
comeback I knew with that having you
know the right carbon levels in the soil
in the right forms sort of in that
second color because we need to be able
to feed the biology not just in the you
know the root exudates the glucose that
they're naturally producing out but also
having immediately available food
sources and slower release kind of
habitats for the carbon in the soil and
when you've got that the microbiology of
just seeing whole other levels of
biological activity which then are
stimulating the plants in all these
different ways
and you combine that with you know those
right macro micronutrients at each
developmental stage of the plant combine
that with having all those broad
spectrum trace minerals like you're
saying with silica and a lot of these
other ones that we won't even normally
talk about as micronutrients we've got
all four of those pillars really dialed
in that's what we've just been seeing
really incredible oil production and
just incredible terpene and cannabinoid
profile really sort of developed our
whole system around optimizing that yeah
I think the root root mass is your
stomach the stomach of the plant so the
bit the better the better the roots the
better the fruits
not the baby that reads the biggest
roots yeah and are you sequestering you
were working on sequestering some of
this carbon in carbon capturing that
yeah something I've been extremely
studying for quite some time and I'm
very interested in in that realm yeah
and and one of the things I mean when
you've got high levels of beneficial
biology there were Sapir fights that are
you know carbon eaters in their soil as
they eat that you know those exudates
another thing oh no he's muted there we
go
yeah and they're they're necro mass
really helps to sort of bind and hold a
lot of that carbon in the soil so we've
found that to be yeah really supportive
on that front as well for sure yeah I
like what you guys are doing over there
at soil balance I've always enjoyed
having Peter on it's been it's great to
have you on it and discussing and and
peace you know just doing the work once
again it's not always something that's
so easy to do without you know the
structure of a company you know that's
what that's generally what we work under
like unless you're like independently
wealthy yeah yeah yeah it's breaking up
on us
seems to be the thing too that I'm
actually um I've used the soil balance
Pro I mean there's your stuff there yeah
I'm also trying this one that uh dr.
Mary Jane's plant probiotics just give
it a shot so I'm just kind of curious
and I saw so much action in my soils
that I've actually had it like feed so
much more and a lot of people don't see
that and I've tried both and like I've
just because I'm always just kind of
curious on what's working and stuff like
that but that's the one thing a lot of
people and I'm seeing is I'm be trying
getting more into using these plants
soil bases and getting more into looking
at the root zones more and more and as
I'm actually increasing all my more
activity in my soils I am seeing
different plants and stuff like that and
half the changement nutrients right away
I'm like whoa guys slow down and stuff
like that so yeah a lot of people have
to really take a look at that - for
beginner growers and like team people in
myself before for a long time and I
start using some of these new soils and
then beginning I didn't realize it now
that I'm seeing that oh yeah I got a
feed more um you said seven I'm pumping
it up because there's just so much more
activity going on and realizing that's a
key and we and we actually develop
because we saw the same thing you know
you got such heterogeneous soils and
having the beneficial biology is huge
but there's these other pillars right
having the right carbon levels having
the right Mac of micros and the trace
and so we actually did was because you
know it can be so challenging like you
know mark like you were saying to get
all that stuff tiled and if you don't
have that budget we actually developed a
whole system where you know we've got
those mill you know cannabis and have
specific some beneficial microbes that
are stimulating oil production in
getting that boost and turkeying
profiles but then we combined it with
specific soil testing and bi-weekly leak
tissue and sap analysis so that we're
actually able to check you know you're
doing like a co2 and an h2o soil
analysis right off the bat to check what
nutrients are currently plant available
and which ones are still locked up in
reserve so that we can actually start
really getting precise and tracking what
that nutrient cycling is gonna be like
in a really highly biologically active
soil and then once you get the yeah and
then once you get the bi-weekly
tissue and sap analysis yeah then you
can actually track
what's an accessor deficiently not
deficiency not just a current time of
each stage but what will be that's
what's so cool about the sap analysis
you're gonna catch deficiencies and
excesses you know two to three weeks out
before they show up as symptoms before
they reduce yield profiles potency and
get rid all of those things optimized
yeah I mean you and it's it's so crucial
for by a highly biological active soil
if you're saying Johnny because it's
when you get that increased nutrient
cycling you need to be able to adjust
both the macro micronutrients make sure
you've got the carbon in the right forms
and when you combine all these testing
that we've got in the system you can
make the fertility recommendations to go
with that really high levels of
beneficial biology that's what we've
seen just that that mind blowing like a
genetic expression it's like taking
whatever that genotype is capable of and
really optimizing and amplifying it so
that's that's what we've been putting
together to support course yeah have you
have you been working on different types
of medians we could you know for
instance cocoa versus judicious soil
versus you know rock wall you know every
every medium holds nutrients in a
different way cocoa holds certain things
back and soil that's certain things
through and you know there's so have you
worked on the dynamics of that alone
have you guys been focusing on that yeah
I mean we've we've been growing with
growers using a whole bunch of different
mediums both living soils Coco's
different things aeroponics Antep onyx
and so it's something we've been looking
at and how one of the reasons again for
all this precision testing that we've
sort of built into our system it's
because like you just there is no
one-size-fits-all right there's no
silver bullet everything is going to be
different and the more we can really get
precise and helping each core a farmer
on a larger small scale really dial in
all of those different pillars that's
all we've just seen seem just the
amazing results and both on being able
to grow you know the the flour and oil
and the extracts that are gonna be most
medicinal for the people who need it and
yeah that's good
exciting for us that are incredible man
well what a great episode of hashed
Church today that was a solid three
hours like almost without a break in
conversation I know I have to read what
Sam said because he definitely wanted me
to read this so that was what he said
was this week in Colorado the USA's
first plant breeder rights for cannabis
under you POV were applied for this is
the alternative to plant patents and is
what fruit and veggie and flower plant
breeders use so there that's what he had
said III had heard to most of what he
had said when he had mentioned that
earlier I'm not sure if you guys did but
there you go Sam I know you're not in
the room anymore but I did say what you
wrote me maybe an hour and a half after
you wrote it but nonetheless so yeah I
think I think things look good - maybe
continue the conversation next week and
get a little more deep into some of
these tunnel conversations and topics
and as always thank you all so much for
coming in thanks for for your
perspective Beth for sharing your
perspective with us coming and hanging
out and thanks potent ponics this t44
linking me up with you and send me your
email and get me to invite you in and
always a pleasure Wade the right back
after Marcus your laughter beautiful day
yes absolutely thanks for coming out
dude and hanging out and share in time
with us and sharing a dialogue with us
and your perspectives always appreciated
and we do we do love having you here on
hash Church and everyone else mr. West
thank you so much for dropping serious
knowledge bombs today and just dropping
in depth knowledge about everything
you're just the [ __ ] encyclopedia
dude it's well it's something that I I'm
certainly passionate about because we
want we want to be able to have create
you know create good corporate and
ecologically social responsible
companies but at the same time we want
to be able to assure that you know the
the community at large the patients at
large still maintain axis so I think you
know I think there is a need for for
testing companies to develop help
breeders develop these lines there is a
need for nurseries to help distribute
these lines and in some regards there's
a need to be able to develop rights or
whatever you know do some commerce in
those genetics but we want to do it in a
way that it doesn't take away from the
industry so you know the all the people
on the call the people watching it need
to be able to you know understand and
differentiate and really support and the
the growers and breeders that aren't
they are trying to promote safe access
not not trying to capitalize off of
limited access yeah that's it right
there that's it in a nutshell right
there that's it just make it fair and
don't try to limit access and control
off limit access I'm also here the words
of Sam you know if someone spends
millions of dollars and there's PhDs are
hired that had to go to school for years
to get their PhD and the cost of the
infrastructure the greenhouses and the
breeding and the if incredible work is
done and novel cannabinoid profiles are
produced with unique novel terpene
expressions that we've never seen in the
black market like is it gonna chat my
ass if someone somehow puts a plant
breeder rights on that probably not I'd
probably be more like the glass half
full guy kind of like wow like they did
a lot of work to create something that
wasn't really readily available and now
it's going to be available like you
might be able to buy it and lease their
pad there there there cultivar or you'll
be able to purchase the end product of
it that's sold through whatever
companies that make the deal but people
are always just like you know it's the
internet nowadays it's like the wild
wild west with the keyboards people just
have strong personal opinions they want
to share about everything and it's crazy
how fast you just make a wrong statement
in social media and it's like everyone
just attacks you pictures if are in our
own nest on
everyone Colin and Jeff and John EB and
skunkman Sam and the Turner's who were
here earlier and I'm sure I'm forgetting
people Josh and Kelly as always the EMP
R and Josh who came in early Dutch
Bloom's who's doing the aquaponics thing
thanks everyone thanks for coming out
and thanks all the people who are
watching and spent their Saturday
morning or afternoon chilling out with
us for three hours we will see you next
week I'm gonna make sure of it and
hopefully some of these quick people
will return peace out everybody peace