here we go we're recording so let's hope
this works let's hope this works what's
going on everybody what's going on
everybody
we got welcome to the inaugural episode
of hash talk first episode ever
on this Friday 4/20 should probably get
our bombs going because we don't have
much time I'm going to admit a few
people into the room and we are gonna
smoke because it is 4/20 so welcome
everyone who made it for 4/20 nice to
see you all there can everybody hear me
okay very well
beautiful welcome welcome everyone let's
have a 4/20 hit to start the ceremony
shall we super stoked to have you all
here we've got the best friend farm
Scott tasted Cascadia we've got the
Great Lakes
what extractions is in the house brother
good to see you man a little bit of
noise in the beginning because hey we
can't start a 420 joint like that
chillin like that bowl blast that banger
or whatever it is that you prefer to do
because we are here to talk about hash
today and a lot of people have been
bothering me over the years
what does hash talk in it when is TAS
Church gonna talk about hash I'll admit
we do go off on some crazy tangents the
focus on this conversation is going to
remain hashish related so we were going
to talk about all things hash today I
don't have three to four hours to put
into it unfortunately today I got to
drive up to Whistler here in a short
period of time probably an hour and a
half maybe is what I could
probably pull off I'm gonna mute
everyone that is not muted because that
makes it so much nicer in my ears not to
have to hear all that stuff and my
banger is ready so here we go first show
I guess I should share this in the other
YouTube chat there we go we'll just put
that in there
so they can all come see us over here
let's hit it up and yes it's gonna be
quiet when I'm taking a rip because wow
it's the one time I can't talk alright
great so let's get right into it
everybody we're not going into a big
introduction let's get heavy ice in here
we got someone else coming in under the
name iPad what's going on brother are
you doing welcomewelcome that says
what's up Oh what's good what's good
what's good welcome welcome we're just
starting this first episode we got some
new folks in the house coach Kirk is in
the house give you great to see you
brother good to see everyone
hell yeah what's good brother I'll tell
you what's good right off the bat is
Instagram is good Instagram has brought
the hash game to a place where it really
needed to be we started well we started
in caves practically we got onto
websites eventually like overgrow and
cannabis culture and cannabis calm and
cannabis world calm that was kind of a
late eighties scene where you could
trade this information but Instagram
really blew it off the hinges
being so mainstream of an app and it's
really how I met the majority of you
guys I asked I asked Instagram to tag
hash makers that would be worthy of a
panel
for hash Church and you guys were guys
and gals were the names that came up and
so we did a little hash church last
Sunday and I felt like we really barely
barely tipped the iceberg in the
conversation started going and I we
squeezed out all the people who were
coming in for the rosin panel which
we're gonna do a hash search down the
road for that but it really showed me
how much of this conversation is still
really urging to happen and I feel that
there is a almost a reamer gence of of
hash making of solvent list extraction
if you will even though it's the
craziest misnomer of a name for us to
use it's them it's the misnomer we use
solvent list is what we call I guess
petrochemical with extraction free
whereas water is the universal solvent
hydrocarbons which make up the terpenes
of the plant and the building blocks of
all the cannabinoids are also solvents
themselves so I want to stay mildly
scientific in the terminology where we
kind of are accurate with the words that
we're using but at the same time I
understand that we're still gonna
sometimes called a cultivar a strain and
sometimes we're gonna use the
terminology solvent list I think it's
the worst just a little bit of a
misnomer so I've got a bit of a list
here guys in regards to kind of
conversations I wrote a little bit about
I mean as a hash maker if you're the
grower and you are finding the cultivars
and you're finding the fie nose and
you're using your olfactory to find that
terpene profile and then you're actually
growing it producing and creating the
inputs to grow that plant and then
washing it well I mean what can be said
that's just you're you're a rock star if
you're doing all that that's that's
that's the full that's the full meal
deal and that's I have a full
appreciation and a respect for that a
lot of hash makers are not that and
that's okay but we do have to sort of
pay attention to probably the most
important thing as a hash maker because
the quality has already been taken care
of for us if we're lucky all we really
have to do is isolate it which the
process does very very simply which
becomes then our only job really becomes
to dry it and I'm sure many of you have
seen in the years of dry
cannabis you can take beautiful cannabis
and dry it incorrectly cure it
incorrectly and and ruin it and really
drop it down multiple grade points I
feel the same is is true for hash so I
thought let's start out the conversation
today with drying weather you guys want
to talk about sieving versus micro
planing whether you want to talk about
air drying versus freeze dryers I'm down
for whatever I just thought that would
be kind of a good starting point as it's
probably one of the most important
things as a hash maker if you're not
doing all the other things that I
mentioned the drawing is probably really
the most important aspect of what you
should be paying attention to totally
agreed anyone got any thoughts on how to
start that conversation yeah totally I
was actually gonna say I got some hand
dried hatch right here and there's like
such a funny story about it like where
it almost died out on my part we're just
the people that are purchasing you know
like they just want the freeze-dried
because of the look you know but the
hand dried is such a traditional side of
it that I don't want to let go and keep
it like keep it around is really I think
important and it shows that somebody
doesn't need to rely on like a machine I
mean having a machine is good at all but
uh one I mean there's just a skill when
you you can use your hands to do the
same job type of thing I think it goes
to show that somebody that does do it
obviously is a little bit more like
passionate about it and dedicated to the
craft a little bit more which also says
a lot too yeah I agree I like that I'm
always a little bit funny about making
any comparisons about who does which in
whatever way I air dry I definitely been
freeze drying I used three jars at the
beginning in 2015 it's been an awful
super long time for some of us and I
don't think it indicates anymore I
wasn't more passionate about hash making
when I was air drying the
now that I'm freeze-drying or when I go
back to your drawing I think that's an
irrelevant part in the conversation I
think what's really important is I
myself I you know based on what I do I
get a lot of cash from a lot of
different people all over the world and
last week Marcus you mentioned that when
you had told people mistakenly so you
know roll up the hash a lot of times
people rolling up a sweat and that's
what I'm seeing whether it's
freeze-dried people are very much using
very small amount of numbers for their
hours for drying as if that's making
their hash any better and at the end of
the day I let you to sit out because I
want to know if I'm gonna write about it
and there's a lot of stuff that's just
not dry so whether you air dry and
you're doing some kind of seven to nine
day process or you live in Colorado and
it's done in three days or you have your
free dry tech dialed in at the end of
the day as long as you're putting out
good medicine good recreational whatever
you want to call it as long as it's dry
then it'll be good hash however you do
it is no way indicative of what you care
about
I think the like how the resin was grown
has a lot to do with it too
everything to do with it on my in my
opinion right I just went when when Kirk
was saying that it kind of reminded me
of like I get asked about macro
photography all the time but I do i do
my macro photography handheld some of
you do but I don't use a rail system I
don't use a tripod
I don't like build this giant thing that
I'm pushing a button to move my camera
half a millimeter at a time and because
of that I feel that that skill is a real
value to photographers to learn before
they get a rail system and I kind of
attributed to cush Kirk saying what he
said in a very much like I understood
what he meant by that like yeah there is
something about you know not all of us
are selling hash first of all it's not
all what everyone is just making hash to
sell it to people some of us are just
hash makers okay I mean truthfully okay
you know
don't have any issue about passion but
I'm saying we have a tendency to divide
ourselves when we're like oh I do it
this way I do it that way and this way
is better than that way at the end of
the day we will all want to provide good
medicine more than I had to shoulders
from injury from 20 years ago that
doesn't necessarily mean anything so
sometimes you know I do believe I do
believe that we should display skill no
matter what we should be able to like
make hats in the bushes as long as we
can get some ice and water you know I
mean I definitely believe that but those
who have decided to go through the
machines especially when you're doing
large large batches I don't think we
should look down on them at all when you
push a few buttons it's a lot easier
than doing it by hand you got to learn
to like do it through losing a lot like
I've lost a lot of yeah that's how you
learn you don't really learn just by
getting [ __ ] handed to you on a silver
platter these days I mean if you do well
they so you only understood certain
cultivars in certain situations and
that's why when something came out
totally different you just didn't know
what to do right Oh 1,000% 1,000% people
gonna open up their eyes and know the
plant before they even start working
with it on a detailed level like we're
talking about it's like and that's the
thing nobody really does they all just
jump to you know 0 to 100 real quick and
try to get that money so I just don't
think that sometimes people necessarily
do take those steps that are required I
think that will make you
I think I'm not just a better hash maker
but more knowledgeable in the plant and
more understanding and not get
frustrated when she don't go writers
you know don't blame somebody else like
the grower or something you know like
there's so many variables yeah I like I
like the idea of being able to finesse
the resin through a sieve by hand
you know observing everything you're
doing and just like observing the resin
throughout the drying process and
obviously like you said there are times
that you know when you don't have the
process down pat that it gets too warm
in the room or too humid in the room and
something happens to the resin and it's
kind of interesting to see you know what
what happens and obviously change that
but I love I liked the idea I used to
microplane but I like the idea of
finessing it through a through a sieve
and that's what we do can you guys hear
me yes okay yeah I would agree with that
as well I have always loved sieving the
hash micro planing was something that we
kind of discovered when we allowed
really high quality hash to gum up and
goop up before it was properly sieved
allowing too much water to wick out of
the hash and so we would freeze and we
would microplane and I remember kind of
doing it and I'll never forget the day
the conversation started like well isn't
that shredding the heads this was just
right around the time macrophotography
was coming in and people that were doing
it were like no no it doesn't shred the
heads and the first time I photographed
a microplane head I was shocked at how
shredded and flayed it was and it made
me understand immediately like well
here's this one more thing like fresh
frozen microplane your hash these are
two ways to acquire what I like to call
pro mount your [ __ ] won't melt if it's
dry so you need to well let's run it
fresh maybe we'll save some turps that
will give us that melt that glassy look
you know and then it's like oh well
maybe uh maybe if we might proclaim the
heads when the flame hits if all that
resin will be already outside of the
head and
appear to be melty er than it actually
is now I'm not saying all microplaned
hash is that I've seen six target
microplane that drips into a liquid and
you know drops right through the
tightest of screens but I will say that
a lot of people have taken into account
both fresh frozen and the microplane
hash to give them an appearance of a
hash that's maybe a little bit better
than it really is okay jump in on that
just for a second um you know it's
always good that new people are coming
into hash making people should be making
their own medicine top to bottom you
know I like super believe that at the
same time in the last year I have to
tell you I have met some many movies I'm
somewhat people haven't done a single
run and they're making their first run
first run fresh frozen and I just feel
like I'm how it's like just messing with
their head or something because they
don't understand that fresh frozen can
be a lot harder and at the same time
they're putting a lot of money on the
line but again I wanted to get that into
the cloud and be able to flex like
they've done something they jumped in to
do this fresh frozen and like this is
for me not about cured versus fresh
frozen because I will do both of them
but I just feel like people should start
off with cured because again as Kirk
said you have to be able to be willing
to lose a lot of [ __ ] like lose a lot of
[ __ ] in order to be good well I'll tell
you the funniest thing when fresh frozen
happened because I was right in the
middle of it all people going from using
dry material people loved bubble bags
when they use dry material because they
got real returns and now they're using
this [ __ ] that's really four times its
weight in water and so like you're lucky
to get a three or a four or a five if
it's really great whereas you know like
when you're pulling that actual 5 in
dried material that is 20% yield and let
me tell you when you pull that out of a
20 micron 20 gallon like 90 micron bag
there is something beautiful about that
that just can't be that just can't be
compared all the first hash I made was
all bone dry material the first full
melt I ever made was from bone dry
material so now it's not really known in
the world of making hash a lot of people
are constantly asking is it possible to
make like can you use dry material it's
like of course you can use dry material
when it's been grown actually like
baller style and the genetics is super
OnPoint that resin shines regardless of
whether it's fresh frozen or and I'm
also like maybe I'm old school but that
whole fresh frozen thing and I get the
importance of it for a lot of people
these are the very terpenes we cured out
of cannabis for decades we cured them so
when we smoked it it wasn't caustic and
harsh and now it seems as though when
people take dabs they're looking for a
cost of harsh dab my opinion I I see it
a lot out there who would think what's
that I agree I mean I was going to say
that I agree with that that the cultivar
as far as the way we do it is air dried
and into a slow and patient here on it
to kind of let the resin speak in terms
of its terpene profile really when it
comes to how loud it is the deterring
profile we know the resins there and
we'll take the time honestly I feel like
the cured resin bubble hash really
speaks truth for what the cultivar is
and like I agree with you it's there's a
lot of fresh poppin zesty you know I'm
tripping heavy and really isolated in
the fresh frozen state which I do a
little fresh frozen work also but our
majority is cured resin because as a
breeder into the cultivation to see what
the strain really is in its in its
patient true essence and you know that I
believe that's how we like the cured
resident let the plant speak and just
finish out the full way to maturity it
needs to yeah like that
welcome Colin and archive Fletcher in
the house sup guys thanks for having me
pleasure to be here damn it's because
everybody doing tonight it's been a bit
since I've seen Fletcher like for real
I'm kind of like barely recognizing you
but right now man and it's going good
Colin thanks for asking and welcome this
is this is a great topic I remember when
I first got bubble back from you Marcus
that was gosh it may be your first set
ever it's the I have that I still have
the set it's that long the 25 bag that
was soft was it was it pink it was pink
man I could probably go and that was
that was a 2001 and the reason that bag
was pink is it signified the birth of my
daughter that's beautiful 18 years old
yeah so 18 years years ago you know that
was my my first set from you and all I
did was washed dried material because at
the time that's all we really we'd never
even thought to freeze material it just
wasn't in our it would just wasn't in
our thought process at that point in
time but you know to to what to the
point the other guy was was making about
the dried heads are are really important
to give you a true essence of what that
particular progeny can actually do for
you long term because drying you know
there's several ways to do all of this
to get to that end goal to get that
maximum terpene profile that you're
looking for and there's really no wrong
way to do it but it's just personal
preference and I find today I like the
mix of both personally I think that
there's a lot to learn from fresh frozen
and then there's a tremendous to take
away from your dried material but I
think right now what I'm doing now is
all fresh frozen and I I starting to do
drying times and trying to back myself
back into dry material itself and that's
that's a long process but it's been
really interesting seeing the yields and
the results
I'm definitely pro both of them I just
definitely say if you really want to see
what your resin is made of dry that [ __ ]
out run it through some dry set screens
or somewhat some water hash bags and
just you know of course you can do it
fresh through through through bags and
whatnot but it's nice to have it's nice
to have that idea of what it can do and
there's also something to be said that
the way the resin breaks off when it's
been properly cured and when the head
has been allowed like stuntman talked
about on hash Church lesson they sort of
to raisin out a little bit
and to not be that big fresh water
balloon but to start you know raising
out a little bit and kind of getting
pruned up a little bit in that that just
makes it so the head becomes so much
easier to snap off and there's you know
something to be said for that as well I
think it's a really strange specific to
you know more so than I mean there's
certain things that wash ball fresh
frozen there's stuff that does well dry
there and in my personal opinion at
least is that a lot of it has to do with
the concentration of terpenes versus THC
inside the head so just like alcohol can
prevent water from freezing
if the terpene content inside the head
is too high it's not gonna freeze and
you'll see this when you like make a lot
of BHO and stuff like that certain
varieties the slabs literally will not
freeze just because the terpene content
so high and considering we can only get
water to 32 degrees really or you know
maybe 31 or whatever you're gonna have a
hard time getting varieties that have
thin cuticles and high terpene content
to not just break break apart and
basically become part of the water or in
certain cases I've even seen the heads
are still really sticky at freezing temp
or 32 degrees or whatever your frozen
your cold waters at and they'll stick
together and it'll be stuck in your to
20 bag like the whole bottom of the 220
bag will be gold I mean just full of
gold but there's no real way to extract
it because you can't get the heads to
break apart again in certain strains
when you dry them they like shrink
together and then the heads become these
little balls and when those even when
you when you're washing try those balls
will break off but they're well over 200
20 microns so you're just never able to
catch up these are your problems of our
trade totally agree it's like you know
I've been washing for the past month
you know maybe 30 pounds a day something
like that
and we're seeing all kinds of different
varieties you know washing and it you
know a lot of the CBD varieties we're
seeing a major yield in the the 25 and
45 really nothing in the 1973 so to your
point it's it's so that's so true yeah
it's every strain is different whether
it's better you know there's certain
varieties like they used to have a white
rhino cross with skunk number one it
made the best try sift and full melt
from dry trim I mean bubbleman that was
that photo that shroom he sent to you
back in the day that was the screen like
this with the two bubbles on both sides
of the screen probably like two thousand
four or five on the fresh headies
website I remember it I remember that
was yeah that was those dry stuff just
from sifting in a key box basically and
it was just really the heads broke off
really easily and they didn't have a
really high terpene content so they're
really easy to work with
and at the time I was using all the
power in my apartment or condo for
growing so I didn't run any heat so you
know 45 degrees 50 degrees inside your
house
pretty decent [ __ ] working
environment I mean you don't have to
talk to me I live in Canada bro so we
got like eight months of that [ __ ] like
all day long I'm not far from you that's
for sure that's that is well I've moved
to a reasonable part of Canada I was
just visiting Manitoba and it's minus 37
when I was there yeah well maybe uh
maybe there's a way to make cash in
negative 37 I mean one thing that I've
thought would be interesting although I
don't know if there's a reasonable way
to do it but so let's say you have these
lower temperature varieties that like
let's say they would wash if you could
get your washing liquid to zero degrees
or negative 15 right so if you have like
salt to your water or a glycol bath
instead of water there's like a million
different things you could do to prevent
the water from freezing but
would you be able to wash that out
afterwards and that's kind of an
interesting concept I don't know if it's
actually applicable but what other what
other liquid could you use that's not
water that freezes that that that
freezes at a lower temperature has a
lower freezing point um so that you
could have varieties that don't wash at
32 degrees maybe wash in that right I
got to admit there haven't been too many
plants I couldn't wash not so many that
I'd start designing methodologies to I
mean maybe when nay pro releases like a
10% terpene strain or something I guess
that'll become more more of a issue but
I got to admit like at this point in
time even after last Sunday when we all
just named a few cultivars that washed
really well I began to realize there is
a lot of cannabis that you can grow that
will produce beautiful resin and give
you nice yields beautiful terpene
profiles and it's it's being done on a
daily basis by just even the people in
this panel right now yeah names I didn't
even recognize dude like you you
probably would as your you have your
finger more on that pulse but I just
know a lot of varieties that are really
excellent flowers to smoke don't really
make very good hash dry trim or fresh
frozen but are really wonderful flowers
and and you can breathe those varieties
and eventually find one that has the
flavor and washes but just I was just
from a they'd be a good science
experiment is all I'm saying
right if so if you had something that
didn't wash at 32 degrees you're able to
get your liquid now let's say it's salt
water to 15 degrees and now it does wash
because you've reached that point of
where the head is actually freezing be
interesting just to see if that that is
what what is causing the the disparity
between varieties we should wash Hayes
somebody needs to grow some Hayes and
then wash the pace I need some Hayes
hash in my life I love Hayes Hayes is my
son's middle name
dosey doe right here that's it's pure
lemon haze funk it's funny because yeah
Chris Strom dump the Schrom dumps that
historically it's been a great hash
producer oh yeah so that's a I'm sure
that that outcrops you made especially
the Dancy dough is probably insane I
paid all the terpenes but you know I
just actually exhaled some seeds in the
haze and that [ __ ] was lemony real good
yeah the stuff that flood shared with me
recently was really Lemon Haze heavy
yeah you know you know it's good when
you ask someone happy what did that
taste like and they say another one yeah
yeah brother the resin texture
conversation part was what we do here
with some of the ones that don't wash as
well I don't really cultivate too many
like that um cuz you know what my name
is but when we find ones like CBD ones
or some lemony profiles like some tiny
lemony ones that gonna watch - well we
notice that they are really oily right
off the touch we'd like to make
tinctures or SABS or just like oils you
know with those um they seem to be like
water soluble if I wash them you know a
lot of the Terps are just floating on
top where if I if what we make it into
you know some other type of product it's
acting a lot better and none of a waste
and I like to see that kind of happened
- it's like we come up with a strain
list for hashes like let's come up with
a cultivar so I list for you know
tinctures and topicals and such you know
that'd be really cool too
how did I go me no no you're good I was
answering you okay you look cool yeah
that's like something that I always look
at here it's like as the grower when it
comes down to harvest time and we're
growing so many Yuki knows you know we
have a tendency we run a clones we got
our fee knows that we like to you know
we know what they're all about and how
they grow but then there's the new ones
and that's like more than half the
garden all the time and to just hunt
through the new stuff is so fun but it's
a real trial and error so getting better
with that is now figuring out the
parents and the of the cultivars to know
you know we're bringing hash plants and
we're breeding into more hash plants and
it makes it a lot easier for sure and to
know what ash plants are what I always
let homie snow and I'm sure you know
what the cultivar lists that you guys
were talking about the other day like
those type of strains like if anybody
looked up with those strains were and
then look at the parents of those
strains could really find out what I'm
talking about pretty easily but I think
it's really cool to dad to kind of know
the difference so it's like we're
already of leading to like waste time or
waste material and like I kind of search
at harvest time I like I I go out there
in the field and I work everything by
hand like kind of like charas rub it at
first and I wanted to talk about that
too is some hand rub hash because that
shit's really in next level if you want
to talk about that which I'll put on
next but like when you know you're
searching for the hash plants I really
like to find the ones that are you could
feel the heads like on your fingers you
know what I'm talking about yeah and
yeah that's yeah nice I thought that
thought I shared that same sentiment
where I look at the apparent stock that
was used before I even consider any any
seeds at all that's super-important to
me over a year work easily you know if
you're
even if you're just doing indoor if
you're doing outdoor like probably to
like year and a half maybe two years of
work just to potentially find something
yeah that's unspoken thing I feel like
it doesn't get talked about people that
find those Finas you know it's so much
work to find something that is actually
actually watches and checks all the
boxes and that you want to keep running
yeah I think I have more in my stable
that I've kept all this time out of all
all the time that I've been washing and
those four are with me still to this day
so it's it's hard it's hard out there
man well it's funny it's getting even
more difficult because you know everyone
kind of claims that sharing is caring
and is like oh yeah you know I like to
share to people right up until you ask
them for a cut and I gave a lot of cuts
away over the course of the last five
years so I feel like I can say this you
know I had cuts given to me by all sorts
of wonderful breeders and never once did
I feel like it was my duty to interview
the people I was giving them to to make
sure that they were going to be good
enough to receive this particular cut
and there was a ton of people in my city
who felt this way and actually got quite
upset with me for just giving them away
and I was always like I'd be like what
if you know you know this guy that
supposedly doesn't deserve the Cologne
what if he gets it but then one of the
first people who gets it too is like a
sick little girl with epic profile just
is so you know I'm trying to get him to
see like listen like the world is not
quite as limiting as you think it is
there are these connections that can
occur in in in in ways that you can't
possibly fathom and the only way to try
to kind of support that is to do good
and doing good as sharing genetics yeah
your mout because I can't handle
listening to people who lost their
genetics while hoarding them it's like
oh here let me pull the tiniest little
violin out and play you a song I'm so
sorry that you were an [ __ ] and
didn't give your cuts away to anyone and
now you've lost them and you have no one
to call and say hey I get my cuts back
so yeah that's in a 77s words you want
to save a strain give it away you know I
mean [ __ ] it's the crazy man himself man
but but don't give it away like this
okay you can have this cut but here's a
long list of like your Ozzy Osbourne and
you have a right or if you're gonna play
the venue or something I think I'm gonna
need the red M&amp;Ms I'm going to need
anything tied to that looks nice iPad
looks nice push Kirk you're about to
crush that out or what that's okay it
was just right in my both of my ears
like in stereo I love that and there's
no one in this room that understands
that more than Colin because he's
literally a professional musician and
does like studio music work and like has
headphones on all the time so I know he
appreciated that even though sorry
brother
I went for the mute and I just missed it
you know what it's all good dude I'm
happy to be here talking about hash with
you guys I liked what this iPad man
would you would you dab it up there
brother it looks great oh he's muted let
me unmute him that looks lovely what is
that what call tomorrow breath breath
Mendo Black Dog bye bye Oh vortex red
this one and I grew like a few fie nose
here I think like five or six different
fee nose of the new stuff and this is
one of them it was a good drink tastes
great no it's amazing what is it that
you're holding up the micron micron it's
um it's the 120 and then the 70 combined
from yeah so it's underneath the 150 bag
to the 70 back the 70 to 90 n to 120
yeah yeah I mix most of them I really
don't I just kind of separate the one of
the 40 and I separate like the 150 is
the outdoor got particulates flying in
so lationship our suits are just more
abundant and like but it's this is
outdoor resin this has been rained on
for every month this was at negative leg
or not neg it was at 20 degrees for a
few nights before I harvested this this
was this plant went through some [ __ ]
here in the valley
well excellent well thanks for sharing
it looks beautiful
yeah it's so clean it got washed every
night there you go
yeah there yeah somebody yo I will say
shout-out to bio vortex
hands down as one of the deck is like
breeders for sure all all this [ __ ] that
I ran from him was amazing I did the
banana dog as well which is banana og
with SSP black dog just unreal just hard
to get out hard to get his stuff for
sure but if you can it's worth it nice
good to have those tips that's really
what hash makers want to know I mean
they want to know every possible secret
they can possibly know by the time it's
not too hard to find varieties that wash
well or yield well and vice versa you'll
find ones that smoke well let's reel as
flowers what's really hard to find ones
that are really good flowers and really
good washers that's been my experience
it's pretty it's pretty tough just in
general and I just haven't smelled
flowers in 19 years
yeah I I agree with that a hundred
percent you know it's I you know og KB
is one that seems to wash really well as
well like at times most things is going
to do well in washing yeah exactly it's
a terrible yeah exactly
I've had five years now I still I rock
it every year just for head staff mostly
and then this select few homies that
come through and lots of [ __ ] it's
straight medical I quit
yeah it's hardcore medicine yeah better
outside than it does inside - yep Lee
and it does way better and if you like
yeah and they like a Hugo or something
like
like thick soil oh this doesn't need
much water like what we got kind of
going on in the backyard here it's
pretty gnarly yeah it's so what are you
guys watching right now like what some
of your favorite cultivars that you guys
are running that that seemed to get good
yields and what what yields are you guys
getting out of those I think that would
be a good good topic to kind of go over
yeah a lot of multiple vino so Chris
would know better yeah we're running a
lot of moonbow a lot of lemon cane a lot
of lemon peel moonbow and lemon cane and
the lemon peel are absolutely my
favorite ones to wash right now at the
shop moonbow between the night one like
the 99 and the 112 those tufi nose give
like four and a half to five percent
back and three and a half of that sits
between the 149 and the 90 you and the
rest is just you know 70 40 and you're
like 180 and stuff like that and it's
all you're collecting a bunch of it is
full mil so everything presses back
between like 85 and 92 percent so
they're fantastic to work with
we do washes all hand stirred between
ten to fifteen thousand grams at a time
and so we're pulling massive patties off
those they do really well especially the
limited field like if you're looking for
a strain that's like very heavy on the
limit herbs it washes extremely well
it's not the easiest to get but I was
gonna say no one can get their hands on
that one bro yeah come to the shop and
you can come get it you know but other
than that you got to really know
somebody you know like yeah but it dumps
it's really good and the lemon cane is
the one that we took down to like that
ego clash and you know took first place
in hash with that one produces really
crazy full mouth for a strain with that
chirping profile cool down if you took
first at the ego clash how that was
quite an event I heard a dude it was
crazy that was my first time in
California so I didn't really know what
to expect but it was like it was not mid
to seen
it was just like pissin rain tons of mud
everywhere you know but it was a
phenomenal event man it was tons of fun
there's so much good Mel everywhere I
didn't get to see a lot of the housing
that was there but I definitely [ __ ]
with a lot of the full mill that was
brought to the table and it was quality
there's maybe wanted few jars that I was
not really stoked on but you know he's
all it was all really good stuff and it
was all it was funny there's a lot of
papaya heavy crosses mmm so it's
interesting to see that everyone you
know is kind of leaning towards those
fruity turkeys right now you know the
Dutch variety has always made the best
hash I don't know if that was like a
product of Sam's selective breeding with
Scott number one most likely right but
right man a lot of those varieties
really like I said one of the best
washing varieties I ever had from dry
trim was white rhino cross skunk number
one and I mean it just it did phenomenal
there's some scope get that going at the
farm right now that's probably gonna be
dedicated towards hash like some fresh
frozen here soon so I'll report back on
numbers for that one shortly but it was
like grande Eddy skunker granny skunk we
got going right now so it'll be
interesting to see what that does I've
been raving this year about this
wheezing song from nature farm that we
grew we grew we grow eight plants and
every single one of them made awesome
hash just greasy and unreal yields like
near 20% probably so I'm really
impressed
really gassy like race fuel Terps I just
did a London Bridge London Bridge is
anyone smuggling in bridge no I've seen
those seeds around in the cut being
passed around but I haven't is that is
that London poundcake Ross what's the
range on the pound cake and sunset
sherbert it was from apparently and I
got it on my friend it's just like I
haven't smoked it yet I'm pretty
interested it's kind of like on a
next-level cookie gas gassy cookie kind
of gave me a GMO notes in there nice
fan-favorite over here that was I got
like crazy long list in my head what
else I got gold in the strawberries this
one is just like 20% I'm dry five and a
half wet that one's amazing that one
straight strawberry shortcake
and what else would wobble punch that's
my new one that I made from breeding the
strawberry guava from Oni
with purple punch go Seto I don't know
who the seat pack though came from I got
I took that it was pretty much a pollen
truck I took the mail from a buddy's bro
it took the mail because he was gonna
throw it out and I was like no way I saw
potential in it and I brought it home
stressed it out and ended up seeing
resident on the mail so I knew it was a
keeper then I just brought it into the
hole 32 plant straw - and knocked up the
whole room ended up washing the whole
room and collect and seed at the same
time and that shit's been a really good
[ __ ] one has anyone else done that -
that's been pretty frickin cool with it
I grew a whole room of seed for lights
32 plants and I got like that I mean
about ten thousand maybe more seeds and
a whole room of freshmen that's pretty
crazy
Jenny can like no neither environment
and tile and your guava punch though I
do movies
I took all the [ __ ] wash material and
I put it out in the hoop house and I put
plastic over the hoop house and they all
sprouted up out of the nugs and I let
that thing grow into the sticky shake
when it was this year if anyone saw this
take assured that I did that [ __ ] was
that was all just strong waffle mix fie
knows there was like 35 different Eno's
in there
we had like a party inside the bush I
mean I would definitely hope that no one
ever did do a seed batch and not make
hash with the material because if they
didn't that would just crush my my soul
to know that people are just pulling
these bad seed harvest what should we do
with all this bud because you don't get
the seeds wet or something and you want
to sell the seed but like yeah it was
like it's definitely my intention was to
wash the whole room first and then I
just saw the opportunity arise with the
male and then it kind of got a little
out of control like I only brought it in
there for it and day and I was like you
know how much pollen can come off in the
whole room was dusted so Google blunt so
yes it was badass though I mean job
provides so job does provide yes I that
is the truth hope to I you ever make it
down to the island down to Jamaica not
yet I got a bunch of homies though that
are ready to pick me up off the airport
and bring you to the Rasta village
shoutout to that okay in Montego Bay uh
yeah I'm pretty sure I haven't even I
haven't talked to him in a good month
and a half or [ __ ] it's been like year
and a half now it's a great country to
make hash in I'll tell you some of the
best hash I ever made in my life was
outdoor grown cannabis from in Jamaica
yeah I'd be glad be awesome I'd love to
go do that it's hard to get away from
the farm we're just like full-blown busy
here all the time yeah of course the
life of the farmer you know mad
vacations yeah I'm sure you know more Oh
than some of the folks but we have like
a full-blown like that we have a bunch
of animals and [ __ ] to take care of so
that's why and five acres that we like
fully
will utilize like every bit of it now so
it's pretty cool I always I always tell
everyone like that are homies that come
on out and come ticket for a damn day
and like just relax it's like paradise I
it's time for me paradise it's so Google
font i man I love it
that's enough I can agree Moorea it
absolutely is it's the greatest place
I've ever been to for sure that's
awesome Wow makes me kind of hurt a
little bit because I can't come to the
US but maybe one day they'll figure it
out and they'll just allow cannabis to
be federally legal and then I'll just be
like people coming down second way
Kellis truck when they're like all that
[ __ ] in there you could get down here
bro come on oh my god go across Josh and
Kelly sky what are you doing in here oh
hey what's up dude the last time I tried
to get over the border
I was driving my Volkswagen van
potentiating my stereotype you know and
I got to the border and the customs guy
was like where are you going I'm like
I'm just going down to California to see
the Grateful Dead man and I [ __ ] you not
this guy from the middle of nowhere in
middle of Canada looked at me and said
the brief will dead Jerry Garcia pull
over there and that was like that was
the I never got across the border look I
actually ended up giving all of those
concert tickets to hippies that I met in
the forest in British Columbia because I
was so bummed I had these mail-order
tickets they were like the shiny and
sparkly ones for like you know like jeez
what shows were they for they were for
like what's the big calli one the big
was the California venue they film are
no it was an outdoor venue it was all
summer so it was like they played a
Portland show I had I had tickets to see
Jerry with Merle in like Seattle it was
like this you know nice four or five run
thing and anyway that was the start of
my not going to the US so I haven't been
down there since since fish 98 at the
gorge was my last trip to so sorry to
get off topic we're back on hash here a
lot of people do some oak ash at
Grateful Dead and Phish concerts we can
talk about that room we can so dry so we
you guys were touching on drying before
and you know I think one thing I wanted
to talk about was drying times and and
pumps
you
in value and there's a company out there
called Lou Boyd and I just want everyone
to be aware of this and I just want to
share this if you don't already know
this and these fad at home I you're just
gonna have just it's le y bo d Laboy
they're very expensive pumps but they
will allow you to get at a really a much
more consistent vacuum so you're not
actually pulling all the Desirables out
so you know I could give I've been a
beingness for a really long time and I
just think it's it's valuable
information for everybody to have
because I think it's important to share
it they're a great company you can just
reach out to them but but it'll allow
everything to do meaning you can do what
I would do and let's say 40 or 72 hours
in in much less time with much higher
quality and it's it's just a lovely
you know addition to a not-so-great you
know setup it's like bringing a machine
gun basically to a knife fight it's you
know it's it's that it's that much it's
reducing the amount of time that you're
in the vacuum yeah exactly because it
gets to a much deeper vacuum so it's
what temperatures are you running on
that then so say that again and what's
Melissa what's the vacuum pressure that
you actually do get down to so the
vacuum pressures that we're getting down
to you for the Laboy I don't have my
notes in front of me let me see if I can
pull it up see if I can pull this up for
you guys I want to talk about ice what
you guys like for ice I love craft cold
not sure if you guys have heard of those
machine make really wicked ice just
really nice solid our own machines hook
up to them and they make really nice
cubed ice I've always found that there's
certain ice that just wasn't what I
wanted to use if I could avoid it like
the chip ice
you know that you get in hotels and
cheap store-bought ice any ice with
fluoride I always tried to avoid that
sort of stuff and even had quite good
luck surprisingly back in the day in
Switzerland when we made a lot of our
ice by freezing just like all sorts of
different things that we then hammer and
smash the ice was quite sharp and big
chunks and smaller chunks but it really
seemed to do the job on breaking the
resin off I think that it's something
that people don't always look at they
get used to their process they always
use the same ice and I'll I'll suggest
to them have you ever just switched your
ice up a little bit like maybe like like
how cold the ice is how clear the ice is
is it foggy like what's the pH of the
water like there's there's quite a bit
that goes into a simply making ice and I
just wondered some yeah you can come
back when you find it dude I just
figured while you've been looking I'd
keep the conversation going on eiseley
going but but it's it's like it's double
to triple what a normal pump can do and
it's it's going to it's yeah I'm going
to share this with you guys right here
so at the farm we make our own ice with
the same water we washed with and that's
been really helpful you know like makes
400 pounds I stress a day the guy have
helping me stir buckets bags ice a ton
of the time too you know and it helps
you know being able to make your own ice
with the same water that you're washing
with you know using water chillers do
what gives water chillers to preserve
that ice so you don't have to use so
much um the room that we washed it is
extremely cold so we don't really have
to use too much ice this stays about 42
to 45 degrees and you support your water
in that room the water is stored in that
room and the tab where the water comes
out of is also in that room everything
that I use is
based out of that route yet that's full
well also here in Oregon I mean our
water right now probably comes out like
what 40 like upper 40s mid 40s right now
it's pretty cold anyways it's very cold
water for sure yeah yeah but it's great
being able to wash with 32 in rinse with
you know 32 degree water that helps
tremendously yeah definitely it's
amazing how much ice you go through if
you're not taking the temperature of the
water and your water is a little yeah
than it needs to be and you're doing big
batches it will just melt your ice like
you eat oh pattern on ice absolutely
yeah when you're doing like 10 to 15 K
batches at a time of fresh frozen yeah
you eat up a ton of ice if you're not in
a cold environment yeah as well as it
makes a lot more particulate if you have
to have more ice in there you need that
ruin does water to lubricate and kind of
give that softening aspect to the wash
mm-hmm that's the biggest thing I
noticed is washing in that cold room is
I use a lot less ice and it's you know
it's a lot easier to stir those bigger
buckets now because there's not you know
60 pounds of ice in there
hurling around you're only using like 10
to 20 pounds at a time though yeah maybe
like 60 pounds for a whole wash like
that yeah yeah but per bucket you know
you're may be used to 20 at a time it's
a 44 gallon bucket with like I said 10
to 15 K at a time depends on the
material well as you get into larger
systems it becomes quite important to
have things like water chillers because
the otherwise the ice production just
really reduces your economic viability
of the whole project you know working
out and not turning into this overpriced
product that someone's just gonna have
to pay for so much ridiculousness along
the way you want to be able to scale
these things while not affecting the
purity I won't say quality because what
we work with is hash makers is really
more purity quality is what the genetics
and the growers have given to us we are
the ones who unveil it so what we unveil
is really dependent upon what you know
the work that they did the months and
months variables that they fought versus
the could be a day
a week of variables that we that we face
as hash makers unless it's a real big
action it maybe takes you longer than
that but can't compare compare it to the
growers and the variables that they have
to have to kind of deal with and
navigate over the course of you know the
three plus months of some of these
cannabis cultivars flowering out and
then being even some of the you know
like not running fresh frozen curing
that out for another little while and
getting that into you know ready to
process and then making hash and curing
that out I mean man the first time I
smoked Sam - I'm quite certain that
material was probably curing for three
or four months and then the hash itself
was probably three or four months by the
time I smoked it and it was you know
shocking to me in 1995 shocking yeah but
being the grower - it also helps
eliminate any errors that might come up
because you can think about it like okay
I did this this time you know changed up
this you know had a little lower
temperatures flushed for a little bit
longer or whatever you know this season
was a bit warmer bit colder at the end
you have a little more intimate
relationship with that resin head and
can understand what it's potentially
going to be doing for you yeah there's
nothing more there's nothing more
beautiful than walking through the
garden and seeing those head just just
stick out from a mile away and you just
know I'll tell you if you really want a
bonus tip for me to all of you a really
important factor of on hash making and
cannabis growing is being able to see
what's going on microscopically and if
you can get yourself a really good I
mean something that allows you to go in
and spend time in that macro world of
trichomes and just really exactly you
know getting right into I've been doing
this since 2008 and I can't tell you
enough that it's really a worthwhile
it's what taught me about trichomes I
mean while we've been on this show Marc
scaled own set sent me an article called
he said did you see this and it's called
chemical factories
what's the subtitle here okay chemical
factories cannabis trichomes under the
microscope a recent study has revealed
the internal structures of cannabis bio
chemical factories trichomes and note
that these hairs can be used as a
measure of potency it's like you're
kidding oh my god the guys at university
figured it out and finally that these
cannabis try comb hairs are what
determined the potency on the cannabis
plant and then they go on to I guess
claim that for the first time ever
they're explaining what's going on
inside these little I haven't read the
whole thing and maybe they have figured
out some new things but this
informations been out there for quite a
long time in a multitude of publications
even myself and Jeremiah from cannabis
culture wrote an article in 2000 and it
might have been three it might have been
five or six called inside the trichome
and it very much explains what's going
on inside the trichome and the different
types of organelles and the factors and
the plastids and the phenols and the
hydrocarbons and how they push up into
the upper membrane and cook with UVB
light and produce c vga and then from
there the entire cannabinoid and Turkey
and profile so that information has
probably been out there maybe since the
sixties or seventies evens I'm not too
sure but definitely something worth
checking out if you guys want I will
post it both in our private chat here
with the panelists if I can figure out
how to send you guys all oh here we go
I'll send that to you guys and then I'll
send it to everyone in the YouTube chat
as well so haven't actually looked over
here in a second but I guess we got four
hundred and forty people watching with
us right now which is just over four
hundred and twenty that's pretty cool we
send this to them they're compound on
your point a little bit too I've noticed
with lighting indoor with lighting grows
that have higher UVA and UVB lights they
actually do have usually higher both
higher THD percentages and more melty
strains and larger resin heads usually
while this mystery is going to be
unsolved or solved I should say in the
next decade maybe less where you know
you get a lot more people being able to
do
this and engage and key and you know
start kind of compiling this data and
there's gonna be all sorts of different
software's that are developed that allow
that data to be you know sort of
amalgamated or or or made out and
created into more of a digital landscape
that makes it for easier navigation so
I'm pretty excited for the data to come
out on all these different the
difference is in the cultivars and why
is this one waxy and this one's this
certain way and why is it that this
one's not washing well and these would
be interesting mysteries to me to just
have a full understanding and I'm quite
certain that science will answer the
majority of them I mean to go off of a
plan like a cheap like hundred twenty
dollar 20 to 80 AK stereo microscope is
like one of the best tools you can have
for sure yeah yes yeah look for house
making but just for growing for
identifying paths and all that kind of
stuff and they're real cheap like a
stereo microscope you don't need the
compound microscopes or anything like
that well let's you start navigating
that different world where you're just
you're silt look when I started shooting
macro cannabis I first of all couldn't
believe how beautiful it was it really
blew me away at how just beautiful it
was inside the plant I was blown away at
that but then I started like well what
is that you know why is that different
from that and what is that called and so
then I started you know like chimera was
really helpful and skunkman Sam and Rob
Clark guys that had some history with
this you know that had worked in labs
and that had been doing this since the
80s and understood some of the important
terminologies that if you were gonna be
able to even search the internet and you
didn't know the terminology of a
particular trichome like the cystal of
hair even fur for that matter it was
very hard to describe it into google and
get any accuracy or find anything on it
whatsoever so the macro photography for
me let me get to a point where I was
like okay I need to understand what all
these things are and then you know
starting to do that research was was
really helpful I guess today nowadays we
have it so good you just go on Instagram
and check out the hashtag and all the
sudden it's like oh you've got
all the information you need about
trichomes it's it's kind of a crazy
thing in a good way to be able to you
know share information in such an easy
way and connect with so many people that
it's I mean it's so Dutchess so it's
it's between 600 and we're maxing out at
900 mTOR that's that's where we're
that's the deepest vacuum that we've
attempted to do oh okay well the
scientific side you can go like
significantly lower than that I mean it
can mean way lower that you want to
bring if you have an updated system by
all means get lower than that because
you can definitely I've had it sitting
at 170 m for ya it's 125 to 215 for us
we use the pharmaceutical units yeah and
I can we ride 2 to 300 gram trays you
know in 12 to 24 hours just depends on
the stream so that's the top end right
that's the and then the what were the
numbers that we have for when we go in
to vacuum our reading from 25 to 50
that's getting down to yeah that's what
we're getting down to yeah so I'm just
giving you guys a range of like where it
can go yeah so and then actually and my
cousin he just texted me he's like dude
it can go down to 10 so that's crazy
there's also a chart and you can google
and checked it'll give you a reference
point of yeah you know when you pull
down to that kind of you know military
in temperatures
yeah the turkeys still boil off when
you're when you're in those ranges so
you can see you know it's kind of a very
fine line of how low do you really want
to go and how long sit at that point
because you know turkeys will boil off
obviously check your freeze dry or water
you know everyone knows that there will
be Kirby's leftover in that but I didn't
turn around with that myself you know
like how low do you want to go and how
long do you want to have to sit there
yeah those are you really start
to degrade the purity of the product at
that point or are you just pulling out
more terpenes at that point the
temperature because I mean like I see
I've been very surprised that people are
in the fifties I'm never over 35 degrees
yeah I know can you go it's all about as
low as heart rate to release a unit
where you can set each shelf to its own
temperature because I don't think
they'll ever do that
talking Tula Boyd a little boy I don't
even know if I'm even pronouncing that
and probably watching that name but but
you should talk to them they're really
great guys they've helped me out a lot
and thanks for sharing that yeah yeah
all we need is a software engineer right
yeah right yeah I mean dude it's it's uh
we're getting there you know and we're
gonna get there really quickly if we can
all just kind of share this information
you know I don't I don't think you could
realistically have different shelf temps
in the same vacuum space though because
it's all like they're you're the
variations aren't gonna be you're not
going to be able to like make sure that
this shelf and this shelf when it's in
the same vacuum is our actually 10
degrees different from each other I
think it'd be really hard to do that
well unless you're getting a three
million dollar liable is a ssin oven
like a true just what the setting of the
Shelf would be that at the sensor having
sensors that could detect that and
maintain that in in in it in one vacuum
would be really difficult I mean the
most effective thing I found
raccoons I don't I have never seen that
but but you know you might be able to
find like Marcus said there's scientific
ones out there that can probably do more
but I'm not I'm not privy to any of that
stuff man I don't know when batches get
that big for me I have to freeze dryers
luckily and I they're both seven shelves
so if I need to set one freeze dryer to
a totally different temperature than the
other one there's the option to do that
I haven't really ran into that all that
much you know well check it check out
mil rock technology live from laboratory
to production so that's an interesting
company that does a whole variety of
like a ton of different laboratory style
freeze dryers research development
freeze dryers pilot freeze dryers you
know small production freeze dryers like
for sure I would love to check them out
yeah yeah yeah yeah it's definitely
interesting it's it's it's big boy toys
in the sense like wow like I don't know
if they make like a four or five
thousand dollar unit but it's definitely
neat to know about and and you know see
maybe one day that technology will get
shrunk down I think the harvest rights
are cool but I think they're like
they're they're more like of a toy
compared to you know some units right
yeah I totally agree they're kind of
slow to it so it's you know and it's the
other thing is you know getting down to
temperature sooner is really important
for me so because it cuts down on the
time that you have to the whole thing
has to switch over to do all the
functions it needs to do and you know as
you said we need a software engineer to
get that stuff fixed out you know yeah
they do have really weird things with
like the screen that aren't even like
buttons that are notable you just have
to know to press in that area and you
can set you know from like it does crazy
weird stuff for sure they need to be a
lot more automated and made for what
we're doing you know totally so I want
to hear I want to hear a little bit from
some people that haven't been able to
talk because some of us have you know
loud voices and strong personalities and
some of us sort of quiet guys in the
background yeah I'm talking to you flab
and puah and best friend farms and even
Great Lakes a little bit heavy ice for
sure you haven't been able to say much
so just you know we've got about a half
an hour more so there I'm sure each of
you had little things you might have
wanted to talk about if you want that's
a great time to steer the conversation
any one of you that
like bringing something up and saying
bringing something to the conversation
because I know you guys all do I brought
my weekly list of washes for our
cultivars here for the last week that we
watched if you want to hear them oh yeah
absolutely give it to us we watched a
couple phenotypes of 91 Royale this last
week swamp boys gear they kindly we ran
a couple things of there is also the
guava jelly two different phenotypes and
she act great results on both of those
the guavas super-loud fruit forward and
91 Royale one of the fee knows was him
to be more on the tip of the I guess
lemon is it Lennon Royale
so whatever went into that I think a GMO
lemon tree or lemon something I'm not
sure exactly we ran a pineapple fields
from dynasty genetics also and a couple
of our own types the some of that kosher
pushback to Mac and had been again a
difference you know I got one that we're
calling gorilla food that I bred that's
the gorilla glued to Mac to a cake and
cookies and cream and yeah I don't know
if I mentioned a couple of GMO Tina
phenotypes and and my I guess it was a
ninety one Royale one of the peanuts
just dumped it down the most really
garbagey to had that GMO rotten kind of
thing on it garbage truck dumped nice
that's what's up it's always nice to
hear about washes and you know what what
came out and what's going on
how'd the pineapple feels good do the
dynasty stuff this phenotype in
particular this was actually the Cali
Snapple you know we had a Miss Universe
you know and a calyx that you know I
decided the Miss Universe is really nice
it was just kind of like that really
sweet the kind of pineapple and and this
the number three we call it but the Cali
Snapple for you know definitely I used
to grow a lot of Cali miss back in the
didn't has the same look on it but it
has that kind of overwrite but also
little sour under
west coast true pineapple turf there
minding the Goldstar pineapple I've run
southern Humboldt and yeah exactly I
think it's our first wash on that one
and this is from an indoor run organic
you know indoor living soil cycle so
I'll have more results on it coming and
we actually I dry for two weeks so I at
you know at first that I go for a sixty
degree or a fifty degrees 50 percent and
then I'll shift my second week into
sixty degrees 60 percent and I kind of
do my patch drying air drying the same
way it takes me two weeks like dial it
does the two weeks breakdown really from
like when we've getting cured resin even
material or from when we cut the plants
down with us a month before we even see
on our cured resin bubble - you know I
guess a couple weeks we'll know what the
pineapple destino did more and honestly
yeah I'm not exactly sure we run so many
flavors on it I'd have to just go back
to the room to see what the resins
looking like right now but and what the
date on it is for exactly the day we yes
I feel I feel really bad for you having
to do all that haha it's horrible so
tough
that's rough for sure what about you fly
got anything to share today man
going on make it hash you know you're on
mute let me unmute you there you go
there you go
well I do run a lot of Hayes's and they
return like one to two percent but
they're very worth it even though
they're flour for 14 weeks or so it is
my favorite hash to smoke I mean what he
had I mean you guys are talking to all
the right numbers for the freeze dryers
and everything I mean I do vary
depending on the resin so I find a lot
of the sativas have a lot drier resin
even when you wash them in water and so
I vary the temperatures I'll I'll have
15 for those and 20 for most everything
else other than that I run you know the
machines relatively exactly the same I
mean when you have so much knowledge
sitting it
right here what can you really add
compared to the people that borrow than
the rest of us
you could you could pop a big bowl of
hash out of like Bach Marcel Cola
I have no I have nothing here I'm at
work right now so you know I just came
up from tending to the moms oh nice yeah
don't care business yeah your mom you're
working with right now I have Congo
original Hayes
[Music]
crops and oh that I really like which is
GMO crop cookies my favorite that I'm
actually washing right now a lot - that
returns really good like 5% is the
Afghani bull rider the old Andy and Jeff
tech work from Brandi candy candy San
Diego because she dumped pretty good and
you know melty as [ __ ] so but I got a
lot I could go through the list but it's
like 70 or 80 well just give us 10 more
than some old Northern Lights some Super
Skunk Strawberry Cough some coastal
roads that my buddy grew and this 101
Labs is just a local Sunshine Coast guy
but he's phenomenal he does this other
one that he calls the miss killer that
has its King John cush to an old hash
plant and it's just has that soapy
caridy earthy [ __ ] just amazingness
to it that that you didn't have since I
was like you know 1819 like back in the
you know like just before 2000
so that's phenomenal stuff but nice well
I feel lucky because I can I could go
hit it
yeah for sure and I'm popping some
archive right away that I got in the
soaps that are coming up some tire fire
well that Super Skunk you got pardon
how's that Super Skunk fantastic [ __ ]
phenomenal I was always a really great
variety from yes or I mean I guess
seedbank
ya know for sure you had the old ones I
mean I have a lot of old on unpolluted
genetics you know so it's nice it's nice
to have unpolluted genetics and I don't
mean polluted by it
sounded bad but just on like I thought
what you mean they are hybrids but you
know haven't been modern updates oh it's
gone right exactly
it reminds me of my sort of rarest seed
that I have in my collection that I've
been collecting seeds for almost 30
years and probably my rarest that I have
and I got some good ones for sure like
friends they don't see banks just send
me their full collections like just full
here's this is what my seed collection
has and I get like every seed that they
have so I have a big collection but like
one of my favorites is from an old
internet friend called the Mulla Mulla
madman and it was his father who would
grow back in the day and was involved
with producing the Mullin didn't be
madness which was just this crazy plant
he used to post pictures of it on
overgrow it was like 18 feet wide and 12
feet high and get like 15 pounds of herb
off of it but like 10 would still be on
the plant and smalls that he wouldn't
bother coming out he just make I have
seeds from his dad's collection I also
have his seeds from like his own version
of it kind of thing but he gave me like
30 seeds from his dad's original
collection I have kept those things geez
for the last 22 years earlier for some
reason has the most diverse like mutant
type genetics that we've seen like the
mullet it'd be madness I think that
supposedly had some Papa New Guinea
something in it right yeah oh yeah dude
like everything you know it's which is
one of the most unique islands in the
world - in terms of genetic diversity
then you have the duck's foot that came
from out there while the ABC right the
Australian bastard cannabis which is the
one that doesn't even look like weed and
one of the most interesting ones that's
happened recently is the what is it it's
the one that looks like a fern
yeah freesia
yeah freak show yeah you know I don't
think that one necessarily has anything
to do with Australia but in terms of
like morphologically unique cannabis you
know three out of the four known really
weird ones are are from Australia or two
out of three it's just interesting well
I don't see kangaroos anywhere else in
the world either no or talk about some
tripped-out [ __ ] is the first the duck
who is the first one I ever saw and it I
thought while he was in Central America
because of just the photos he used to
post on over overgrow it just I just
assumed yeah I grew out some of those
seeds that duck ducks flip pure the
Ducks foot blueberry I can't remember
what there was one other cross that he
had to and I've also grown like Hawaii
webbed indica which seems potentially
related or you know hybrid of something
of that nature I was just gonna quickly
say that you know shout out to wali duck
for almost setting his hair on fire at
one of the first legends of hashed
dinners that we ever clearer than
Amsterdam and also shout out to Wally
duck for literally carrying like 75
pounds of ice on his head like a boss
and plus like I don't know who's
probably 105 degrees in the shade in
Jamaica when me him a gypsy Ravana
walked through the bush with a couple of
hours the far-end dudes to the mountain
of weed that was awaiting us and it was
like this hour-long hour plus long walk
through the jungle to get to this
mountain of weed and we had to carry we
all have to take turns and man I'll tell
you both gypsy and I were looking pretty
red when that that thing of ice was on
our heads but Wally being from Australia
and he's a little guy he's not a big
dude it was just like no it was just
nothing you could tell that the work
ethic ethic of an outdoor Australian
gorilla
was no [ __ ] joke for real that was
legit well he's the kind of guy you want
coming to visit on your farm cuz he
won't be sitting and hanging out on a
hammock he'll be like I know exactly how
this works and I'm gonna put in the work
to make sure it keeps working I
appreciate people like that you go to
Brandon's farm he'll put you to work -
that's what's up of course as he showed
you got - those are big sad tale I went
down and learned how to make - and it
was like I spent the weekend with him
and it was not just making hash you know
it was like tending to the fields
feeding the animals you know shoveling
[ __ ] into the the hubell like it was a
bunch of work you know and it was a ton
of fun I learned so much more than just
how to make and isolate pure resin you
know well because to him that is making
how much exactly the inside out yeah
it's lifestyle at this point thank you
for sharing with me thank you dude thank
you for being like one of the true
homies that like you know deserved it
and like well you know respect it and
[ __ ] - there's a lot of people there's
some [ __ ] boys out there I like to say
and yeah yeah I'm glad you respected it
you did it right
he came correct and that's what matters
man I'd like to feel like teaching him
acted like knighting a knight and like
or like kinda you have to like chill
with like master Rafi and like sign wax
off and and like when you learn this
[ __ ] like that then it's like this upper
level of respect and yeah that's what
it's all about
yeah right plus big-time brother I
appreciate you yeah it was that was my
all-time favorite thing back in the day
to do back in the early days when really
it just it wasn't known like nine point
nine out of ten people I'd show it to
would just be like whoa what is this
like this is so crazy it was a very
unique time and I definitely missed that
now being on a level where I don't I
mean I I try to do as much as possible
on that level but I'm definitely more
removed from it and not being able to
just have my greenhouse out behind the
house and have people come over and be
like
it's it's hella hard when you don't have
land and even with some you know a lot
of people have land around here but then
you have to have the motivation so it's
like this big look on a on an acre you
could do a lot with it anchor you know I
will tell you that so I mean you know
it's just whether you got the time or
the means of doing and this and that you
know it all comes together but I look I
look up to the ones that you know that
food storage like a year's worth of food
and not have to go to the store at all
to even buy food like we don't go to the
store to get you know grow material but
we do have to go sometimes to get you
know sugar or like know or something
like that but we you know we raise our
own poultry and stuff so we we knock
things out like every year to be like
more sustainable and more off-grid but
still like you know how the lights
running
we appreciate it you know but I was
going to show off this real quick
because this is what a man has been
doing while I've been doing this the
whole time is we're Club already
figuring you know what we're planting
this is all just veggies and flowers for
this is upcoming year so you did a lot
of pre-planning it goes deep and this
isn't yeah it's not him the erbia not
even the herb thanks for sharing that is
appreciative it's good if that
inspirational life I mean who doesn't
want to like have a farm and have
everything like be regenerative and
sustainable and way beyond what you know
organic it it's more than just quality
of resin I mean like I eat you know
three meals a day and those have to be
quality to well I say it all the time
man if you're gonna smoke full melt hash
why wouldn't you eat full mount resin
and have full mount relationships and
your entertainment is full mount and
everything is that it's just a bar that
you said that's like this is this is
what full melt means to me and what it
means is that clean is then but the
purest that just like perfectly you know
grown sustainably grown because you know
a lot of stuff that we do nowadays is
nonce is not sustainable and now it's
catching up with with the young
generations there they're seeing like
all the things that have been done are
not so easily undone yeah totally I feel
that a lot of people get inspired by
what we do here and I just found that
you can go out and just gotta try to
work together in your community and
build something out of nothing it's
really possible you it's the effort that
beforehand no one really wants to do
because it's not you know you're not
custom and or not used to doing it so
it's just a little bit harder to get
that new new change but it's possible
people just gotta do it and it takes a
long time to get to that level I mean I
know Brandon you can work in your spot
for like what nearly a decade or
something so I mean it's it's not just
overnight like oh look at me oh I don't
know like whatever thousands of
followers on Instagram it's a lot of
really hard work that you put in day and
night you know like yourselves like
you're losing all the time and that's
the best teacher right dude it totally
said I mean like I said it's a lifestyle
at this point we eat sleep and breathe
this five acres that were on and it work
full-blown like I could tell you how
many days off I have a year and it's
probably like around a week of my life
is its separate you know and it's
full-blown but I love what I do you know
and and if I didn't do it I don't know I
wouldn't be doing as good for the earth
you know and that's why I woke up one
day I just got woke and that's what it
all came to it's like how can I help the
earth if I can just stay on my property
and just be smote it out and make this
place fertile and collect seed to ensure
that that's my security and that's
that's the quality of life you know I
mean this it goes deep yeah it just goes
deep that's a whole nother like
different topic of like everything yeah
we're gonna get into that conversation
on a hash Church in a couple of weeks
with the director and some of the people
that are a part of the need to grow
documentary that came out and you should
definitely come on as well dude I know
Josh and Kelly are gonna be there and
Dutch blooms Josh was gonna be there and
so will be it'll be a good group he'll
be amongst family
yeah I can I can say that really really
good hash made me want it was one of the
things that made me want to grow my own
food and is one of the thing is one of
the reasons why I do grow my own suits
is because of what you said if you're if
you're dabbing really really good
organic cash and you're sourcing it and
you're growing it like you might as well
be eating six star - all the money the
minute you're educated to it right you
see like oh that filter gets dropped in
and now you see everything through the
six star filter and you're like oh damn
like what's all exactly bagged in my
life really clear mind of health people
like you know I've got them smoking an
eighth or plus or whatever just a good
hash and they call me up days later and
say do my quality of life has increased
for sure yeah and that's like you know I
just say that's that's that's the first
step right good resin good mind get
everything and then it starts thinking
better there's not bother huh
not the destruction not the poisons
[ __ ] clouding up the mind you know
one of my first customer letters that
one of the first women that bought
bubble bags for me and sent me a letter
she wrote me a letter she said her
father was it was elderly and he was
suffering from wasting syndrome and he
was very like maybe 90 pounds or less
and he was passing away from from not
being able to eat any food from from the
drugs they had him odd and so she had
somehow seen like a video I did on pot
TV about water hash and she was like I'm
gonna buy some bubble bags and you know
she was at first it was through emails
and she finally said him to thank you
letter that I'm about to get to the end
of the story it was mostly just emails
you know explaining to me okay I'm gonna
I'm gonna go out on I'm gonna go out in
the streets you know she was from the
Midwest and I'm gonna try and buy some
marijuana and she ended up finding like
an ounce of herb I think she got burnt
the first time it was like totally
sketchy for this woman to do this and so
she ended up doing it she got the herb
she went home and made the hash out of
the bubble bags for following the simple
instructions
and she so she had written me a letter
saying you know I did all the stuff I
basically put a little tiny bit of a
cash into my father's corncob pipe I was
like old and he smoked this little bit
of hash of bubble hash and basically the
big you know she she said he ate an
entire chocolate cake a McCain's
chocolate cake he ate the whole thing
that night and this [ __ ] had not
been eating food period so I I get it at
first I laugh - I was like oh my god cuz
it's the classic stereotype let's make
fun of the the stoners that have the
munchies it's just so much more profound
when it's gonna put the elderly man
who's passing away from wasting syndrome
who is now not only improving the
quality of his life but actually
increasing the quality and the extension
of his life and so it was a very
profound story to be told you know like
1999 selling bubble bags kind of just
like more of a connoisseur guy myself I
had come out of the BC compassion club
so I did have that full history of
helping the club and acquire in cannabis
for the club and getting busted for the
club for those of you that don't know I
started the bubble bag company after
getting busted with a bunch of herb that
I had for the for the BC compassion club
for Hillary blacks compassion club which
I ended up going through court and
getting no fine in no time and the judge
even ordered the money be given back so
it was kind of a big deal at that time
when I had that happen that I decided I
wasn't gonna be doing that anymore and
working in the underground cannabis
world I was gonna like transition and
create an above ground I mean really it
was my lawyer who taught me because I
would they caught me with six grand cash
and they called the proceeds of crime
and then my lawyer would be like hey you
owe me ten grand and I'd give him like
ten grand and then he'd throw it into
like a paper bag and put it on his front
seat of his car and drive home and I'm
like how the [ __ ] is that not proceeds
of crime and he's just like well you
know cuz I went to school about degrees
and I'm a lawyer and when you give me
that money it's not proceeds of crime
and so I figured is there a way for me
to access money from the cannabis
industry and give them something back
for it that's not breaking the law but
still acquiring because man let's be
honest every one that bought bubble bags
since forever has bought those Bo
bags with money that they made growing
cannabis it's like literally like 99.9%
of people that bought ice and that's
okay that's okay don't don't shush me
man I liked it though so just a little
story I think I got six more minutes if
you guys if Pula wants to chime in pull
you got the killer hash dude and you're
on the island who aren't you in like
Hawaii no I'm in Oregon now well you are
in Oregon yeah weren't you
oh you just during that last meeting I
was in white for my family late
Christmas it's straight fire I know you
you know a little bit of your story but
we I don't want to invite you on and
then not have you say anything because
all of us were so anxious to talk I want
to hear from you I value your opinion
oh right on um so lately I just been
messing with the like wicking timing and
the temperature of like the fridge that
I use to keep the hash in because I only
are dry and seep so with all these
different cultivars like they they have
different timings to where they can
become easily break apart into rough
edges that touch the sieve and will just
turn into dust by itself without having
to really put pressure on it or change
the hash and I like it because I get to
see the whole process of it becoming dry
hash yeah but yeah definitely the way
that cubicles and the waxes like hold on
to moisture and like all of them as well
just have all different feels to them in
different textures and I've just been
messing with the Wiccan time a lot
lately especially for really greasy
trainset like don't really yield very
well today I was doing a great pie and I
don't really like great pie but it's
really greasy and really hard to work
with but if if I got enough water out of
it fast enough on the screen in the
fridge and it has to be down to like
around 25 I'm getting disliked fridge -
and and it's crazy like what Fletcher
was saying earlier about you know
terpenes like sometimes don't freeze and
like you know it's crazy to play with
that of how cold do you need to go to
like work with it like another stream
that is easily workable in like a 50
degree room but um so I've been playing
with that a lot and in the past year
we've been like really into looking at
like chem crosses because we really like
chem dog me and the farmer that I work
with and a lot of it just has a lot of
waxy stuff but when you go through a
bunch you can finally find something
release 5% and and most of its full nail
and it's there's even some in 180 and
the one we found lately in the Kimberley
chem has been our favorite and even 180s
clean and full mill and like honestly
the rosin off of it's like the tastiest
one out of all the microns from that
strain it's a pretty cool strain in a
really cool plant from it so and you're
talking fresh frozen for a five percent
yield fresh frozen yeah it's good damn
you know twenty percent yeah so so it's
pretty sweet because we really like the
chem dog profile and we want to be able
to have like nice clean hash of it to
you at a reasonable yield it's delicious
very good man I really enjoy it oh yeah
thank you relate to that too with the
breeze Ryan you know the thing I found
for retaining the most terpenes is
really just getting as is reducing the
amount of time it's under vacuum that's
obviously right place to start right
removing as much water as you can before
you're putting it in to the the vacuum
while avoiding compaction right where
it's like compressed on itself and now
it's hard harder to freeze dry uh so you
know like I made those screens for
awhile I just don't have time to make
them but that's that's the thing that
you know we've had batches of hash that
dry in six to eight hours in the freeze
dryer
overall time or just final dry time just
just running final dry basically right
so freeze it ship it so freeze it with
you know hardly any water leave
basically what you're trying to do is
get the water out of it really quickly
through wicking and then you pop it in
to your pre frozen freeze dryer right so
when you pop it in and immediately like
within a couple minutes the whole patty
is frozen and you can literally go in
break it up into chips and throw it back
in on the screen and run your cycle and
like we've pulled stuff out like six
hours and except for like the very
thickest pieces there'd be a little ice
in the center right on and it would be
strain dependent and summarize there'll
be already be dry and that's the you
know that's not you can't do that with
everything right and that was like
smaller runs not big hole trays full
right but that's just what I've seen is
basically removing as much because all
you're doing is removing water right
during the process so if you have less
water volume to start with of course
it's gonna take less time to finish then
increasing the surface area by chipping
it up and breaking it up as well I feel
like that really helps also being on a
screen inside of the instead of being on
a tray we're only one sides exposed both
sides are exposed so it's I know it's
all of these things together all
contribute to it but the main one being
if you have let's say 100 milliliters of
water in a typical pour pour into your
regular tray and you reduce that to 15
milliliters it's significantly less time
the first time I saw that tech being
used was in Spain babi colada from La
Caleta was showing it to me and then you
know although we had talked to I had
talked to space greens over the phone
one time with Frenchy and nicotine and
we really didn't understand exactly what
he was saying when I saw it from Bobby
colada I have to tell you it was fast it
was way significantly faster
and the drive that I finally drive I do
and it was really nice that chipped that
chipped ice now when I use the freezer I
check mice no matter what even though
I'm not using the space mean stick but I
want to say that everything I've seen
from that has been pretty sad match
absolutely big shout out to Bobby colada
always has treated us amazing when we're
in Barcelona he even made a private
non-smoking room for stuntman Sam and
myself one year when we went up to try
his dry set that was a huge thing you
know Spain they smoked so much both
joints and cigarettes and for him to
make this little room and hit within
colada that we could go and smoke you
know it was basically just Sam and
myself in there and then and then Bobby
and a few of the like a lot of guys but
it was very cool of him to do and it was
definitely above and beyond and those
guys know quality they make great hash
dry sift as well as bubble hash and they
have they were the first ones to that I
saw laser etched logos and such into the
rosin so I've seen a couple of people do
it since but and it's not like it's the
most complex technology but what a cool
thing to be the pioneer and I got I got
to give it to those guys that's where I
saw it first
I hate to cut it down because I could
talk with you guys for another hour easy
but I do have to go to Whistler I have a
place rented up there for the weekend
and it's my whole family is on the other
side of the store literally my little
guys wearing his pajamas right now like
bouncing off the walls ready to go up to
Whistler because he's got ski school at
at 8 o'clock in the morning tomorrow and
it gets to go I don't know they're doing
some Avalanche training or something so
imagine you're 5 years old you're going
to the top of Whistler mountain to do
Avalanche training tomorrow that's your
day so shout out to Tanner cuz that's
his day and shout out to all of you for
joining me thank you so much best friend
farms flat 41 I know I'm gonna see you
soon as later Dan touches and taste of
Cascadia cool extractions heavy ice
we're gonna hear more from you next time
dude I know we didn't get to hear from
you much archived Fletcher it's super
super stoked to have you show up dude I
really appreciate it as well as push
Kirk I really appreciate you coming and
sharing with us man all of you Great
Lakes grease and
damn it Bobby and Collin thank you all
so much for making the first episode of
hash talk a good one we had 400 420
people watching the whole time so that's
pretty cool I'll try to do it again next
Friday maybe with the same people maybe
with some different ones but thanks
everyone I really do appreciate you guys
yes thank you man have a good night