the cloud and then we're going to go
live what is that sound oh that's my
phone that is my zoom telling me that
it's time to go live that's funny Live
on
YouTube might throw the old airpods in
as
well getting ready here all right I'm
going to put my camera on as well
sweetie if you want to bounce I know you
don't like to be on camera what's
that okay well then you can stay right
where you are look at that you're only
half on told you my wife is
shy all right here we go let's go
live meeting is now streaming live on
YouTube all right I just have to share
the link hey welcome everybody to Hash
Church 3.0 episode
18 almost an impromptu episode it uh
came together pretty quickly I just need
to share the new YouTube chat with the
old one because for whatever reason the
way Zoom is working these days that's
the way they make us do it so there we
are we're good we're live we've got a
crew of people I want to welcome
everyone today I'm very excited about
today's episode uh very much so inspired
by um SRA International's panel of uh
wonderful wonderful cannabis officient
AOS and cannabis Warriors if you will
will uh Dr Mark Lewis who's in the room
right now from Neo uh you know I'm going
to let him do his introduction because I
could spend the next hour introducing
him uh first met in Liden in Holland at
the international canabo research
society and I think it was Ryan Lee my
good friend Chimera genetics who uh
linked us up and that was great uh Ryan
Lee is hopefully going to be popping in
as well today uh Alec from SC Labs is
going to be here uh I also invited Ian
Davidson from seg hopefully he's going
to be able to make it he's very busy on
Sunday so it's not always possible for
him uh we've got Wade in the room we've
got skunkman Sam we've got Peter coming
in from uh soil balance we've got Colin
Palmer coming in from vessel life uh and
I'm probably forgetting a few people oh
Mojave Richmond is also coming in I did
also invite Rob Clark I'm not sure if
he's going to be able to make it or not
but wow what an incredible group of
people and then Joe Sullivan as well
which will get you to introduce yourself
as well a good friend of Alec from SC
labs when I told him about the show we
were having he uh he said hey we got to
get uh we got to get my buddy in there
as well so welcome all of you guys I
hope you're having a great day I see Dr
Markell Don is also in the room how
could I forget and Fontan is in the room
these are our our regular panelists that
are going to be joining us as well today
so some some regulars and a bunch of new
people so well I think we would love to
start maybe with you uh Dr Mark Lewis if
you want to give a little introduction
to yourself to the hash Church community
that would be uh that would be amazing
sure thanks Marcus longtime listener
firsttime caller um like to give a shout
out to David and etan haven't seen you
in a while um I think I met etan the
same time I met you
Marcus um yeah I I grew up in Indiana uh
went to IU Bloomington and discovered
kind bud started growing when I got Dr
D's chronic
album been playing with cannabis and
getting uh technical Science degrees to
support that effort ever
since started Nao research about five
years after being in
California uh and started um developing
methods to elucidate the chemical
constituents that are in the plant and
um use that methods those methods to
create a marker assisted breeding
program that um that we're really proud
of multiple clients use our Technologies
we service clients we don't actually
cultivate cannabis so if you know any
Growers who are struggling and they want
some help that's kind of what we do uh
we also recently licensed our um
proprietary phyto facts to SC
Laboratories since we've been tpine
focused for about a decade um that Tech
technology is really helping the uh
cultivation Community with quality
control standards learning how to fill
holes and menus and really helping
consumers make purchase decisions
so awesome thanks dude that's awesome
amazing um I'm really looking forward to
the conversation we're going to get into
here today the for those of you that
didn't see the segra panel that had Dr
Mark Lewis on it uh it had Mojave rich
and Rob Clark from bioag omics it had uh
Ryan Lee from Chimera genetics and it
was just I went on se's website today on
their YouTube and I couldn't find it uh
but I will find the link and I will put
it into here because I think it's a
really good sort of prequel uh to the
conversation that will potentially
happen today uh here on hash church I
want to welcome Ryan Lee AKA kimar
genetics to the room how you doing
brother not bad yeah that link is not
public on YouTube yet um they're still
doing as like a registration through the
SAR website so I'll just send you the
link but if you want to watch it in the
next week you have
to uh fill out your info or some fake
info so that people can can get out and
watch it but it'll be up on YouTube in a
week I'm
told okay cool yeah I'll see if I can
get uh possible uh permission to post it
on my channel as well uh once they've
gotten past trying to whatever they're
doing with the IR iring uh you know
contacts and whatnot with it but yeah it
was a
great yeah it was was interesting it's
funny there a whole group of people that
kind of freaked out about it think it's
something that it isn't just not to be
surprised in the Cannabis
industry but uh yeah I mean it's just
talking about basic breeding it's
nothing too in depth
or um I don't know conspiratorial minded
It's funny when you start talking about
cannabis breeding in the post phos world
everybody thinks that it's all about big
companies coming in to steal your [ __ ]
and I don't think they realize that you
know I mean there's 500 licensed
companies in Canada that are
operating um so there's like yeah there
are some big cars but in case anybody
hasn't been paying attention they're
failing big time in the
marketplace and a lot of the smaller
cultivators that you know have a smaller
footprint and put a lot more care into
their flowers are starting to do sales
and and do a decent amount of sales and
you know maybe they're not multi-billion
dollar businesses but they're successful
cultivators providing flowers to the
market a lot of these people are
transitions from the Legacy Marketplace
so I don't know I
just the the whole conspiracy thing is
is is kind of funny but H I was a bit
disappointed by it I will be honest when
you said uh that Sam had posted on IC
mag I was like oh I want to go check it
out and see what people people are
saying and I I was kind of disappointed
to see the sort of low brow level of of
I was just like oh man this must be why
I don't really post on the boards
anymore like which is hard for me to say
because those boards and I I don't turn
my back on those boards easily they were
everything to us you know like when when
the Cannabis Cup only existed in
Amsterdam and the only boards were
overgrow in cannabis world and you know
cannabis St like these these boards were
everything to us they were the community
we didn't have the social media we were
segregated onto these small little
platforms and they really were
everything and and when I look back at
it now I I mean I went into the IC mag
chat yesterday just to kind of try and
like even see what everyone was up to in
there and it just seems like it's really
stagnant I it's it's like I guess we
left those boards and we started sharing
this information everywhere else almost
but those boards thank God for you Sam
because you're still on there sharing
valid information do you find that
there's still decent dialogue to be
found on the board
Sam Sam paging skunkman Sam he's like
out of the room maybe well we'll welcome
uh Jerry Jeremy Plum to the room good to
see you in person oh you're there Sam
yes it was my mute it I was muted I
self- muted myself how in the the day
are you right now just out of curiosity
what what is that now I said how many
bong rips into your day are you
currently oh I know exactly I counted on
my uh iPhone uh it's
792 that's impressive so yeah about the
boards though do you find that there's
quality conversation and dialogue
happening on these on these well let's
say that there's uh a handful or two
handfuls of individuals who are capable
of discussing it without you know
sinking down to aluminum
hats and they're they're not all on this
podcast right
now uh no because uh there's a few I
know who are quite nice people and
privately message me saying they
appreciate what I'm doing but whatever I
mean if you're really interested check
out the uh bibliography that I have
posted that's maybe the most interesting
thing
that's
all you're muted Marcus we can't hear
you sir yeah sorry guys I'm just talking
to myself I wanted to welcome Jeremy
Plum to the room this is a gentleman
that for some reason I just did not know
in the industry like our paths have not
crossed but in the last few days since
the segra panel catching him on
clubhouse uh and listening to him speak
uh so absolutely passionately and
eloquently I think I'm not the only one
that shares that sort of perspective
it's absolutely a joy and a pleasure to
have you here on hash Church Jeremy
thank you for showing up and honored to
be with you Marcus uh really excited to
see the crew and I remember one day in
the Netherlands where we ended up at
Sam's and had a few bong rips and Sam
helped me to understand the error of my
way and that the open cannabis project
was a [ __ ] terrible bomb about ready
to detonate I think he was one of the
first people who said you know with
absolutely no minced words that that was
not going to work in any sort of way
shape or form just appreciating that
moment when we were together in the
Netherlands um anyways so great to be
here really really a joy to connect on
clubhouse too seeing some like amazing
dialogue and really really the level of
depth and conversation that just keeps
it going keeps it growing it's funny you
know I think I have pictures of of all
of us together outside that restaurant
in Amsterdam so I'm amazed that you guys
didn't cross paths before then I think I
do too Ryan yeah yeah it's pretty
amusing Jeremy's good [ __ ] he uh been a
good friend for the last few years I
when we cross pass Jeremy I think it was
2013 or
2014 when you were speaking at the
emerald Cup on tpin with
Mark um
but yeah Jeremy for those don't know he
runs proof cultivation or does the
cultivation and data analytics I guess
well why don't you tell us what you're
doing at proof I'm gonna let you put it
in your own words Jeremy because it's
some pretty impressive stuff down at
proof and thank you Ryan I I admit I I
just know that uh to have this time with
you guys actually like means a lot I
haven't been on social media in two
years until the last 24 hours and just
kind of went underground because
primarily proof has been the total focus
I really gave everything like every
minute of every day for the last four
years pretty much to turn the ship I
took over this uh high-tech sort of
indoor controlled environment facility
about four and a half years ago and it's
been quite a ride when I started there
was a huge amount of pest pressure and
all kinds of issues but bottom line is
we are now actually by sales data the
top producer in Oregon we're all organic
cultivation I've been the director of
production science I've had an Ops
director that's kind of my right-hand
guy that ran a Microsoft Factory and
helped me to really bring like lean
manufacturing and some really stringent
approaches to consistent execution and I
think we've done a lot of exciting
things we've done photobiology trials in
partnership with a bunch of different uh
University folks that have like Dave
Holly from fluence and presented some
data on Far red wavelength at the
Cannabis science conference a couple
years ago we've done incredible Agronomy
I think right now I'm in this huge
Wormhole of balancing minerals and
really understanding sort of Nutrition
By diverse variety at a level that
completely surpasses anything that I've
experienced in the past being able to
respond to some of the erratic and
interesting things that show up that you
know were entirely Organic Crop
Production but also uh just excited to
see the constantly booming yield by
virtue of pursuing the data to the N
degree one of the coolest Parts was uh I
actually worked with a team from
Colorado that does a lot of data science
and analytics we built a custom platform
called proos that essentially was an
environmental control system with a
bunch of extra features to bring in
phenotyping capabilities um back in the
day I actually did do some phenotyping
partnership with phos but then that all
of course went to [ __ ] um so there's a
bunch of other partners that I've worked
with to do basic stuff we don't have any
kind of geneic science per se happening
other than what we're doing with
cultivar Discovery we've had some great
seed sifts gone through about population
of thousand seeds and had all kinds of
exciting sort of really unique varieties
come out um I've of course been working
on my own hybrids for a long time but at
proof I've been able to actually grow
many of them out and see some really
exciting things like this dog walker
strawberry Malawi cut that actually has
the recessive pining uh expression and
is getting like 6% total oil of all
Alpha and beta pining um I found an
array of other really exciting type ones
but been principally focused on type two
hybrids I have a plant called astral
works that I read years ago it's won a
bunch of gold medals actually one of the
sweet spots I'll just share this this
was a cross-section of my life where in
October I won a gold medal at the
cultivation classic which was an event
that I founded five years ago with
Congressman Bloomin hour it's become the
largest craft cannabis event in Oregon
and of course Ryan you came and blessed
us and many others have have joined over
the years but uh pandemic has [ __ ] all
that up but anyways it was amazing to
kind of close the gap on the supply
chain where as works the plant that I
bred won the gold medal in the type two
category at the event that IID started
which then was grown in the facility I
direct and then sold at the retail I
founded called Pharma and it was like
each one of these things to me are weird
in their own way you know they're
distinct from the other versions of
those things happening elsewhere and I'm
just trying to in my own way build a
small narrative about some of the themes
that I've learned from you and a lot of
other people here certainly Mark and
just uh Sam and Marcus and they're
trying to build this kind of different
version of the supply chain while I'm
watching you know all the capitalist
crashing going around in in the market
down here of course everybody's going
[ __ ] crazy now with Federal
regulatory reform around the corner and
there's lots of like stupid money coming
in again after a pretty big deficit four
years ago we didn't understand what
would happen with the supply glut we
expected it but then had to ride through
that and it's been a incredible effort
and efficiency and being pragmatic but
also pursuing as much research as I can
so some really exciting things in the
controlled environment there and would
love to get to share more about some of
the strategies I've uncovered that have
really helped to evoke some of the most
expressive chem of ours and just really
thrilled about what's going on but I've
also finished my employment contract and
now I'm engaged with a number of uh
different producers internationally I
have a partnership in New Zealand that
I'm really excited about because they're
doing [ __ ] differently there's a mauy
owned company there called Rua
bioscience uh Ethan and I were there in
January or February right as the
pandemic was hitting and I'm really
excited about what they're doing they
have a different sort of ethical spine
than what you typically see here it's
it's a little it's pretty inspiring but
anyways that's some of the stuff there's
also actually one other thing I should
mention Ryan there's a cool new Advisory
Board role that I've just started I
don't know if anybody's heard of Dr
Barry BC Barry is an MD from Colorado
who for 50 years has been going between
Nepal and Colorado and in Nepal at kman
do University he's brought together a
team that I think will probably over
time ambition to include many of you
it's called the multi-dimensional
Cannabis Research Center and they
they're building this really cool
International collaboration near Center
of origin just have some great vision
about how he's approaching that and
really including like you know
everything in the kitchen sink and the
kind of research and approach they're
doing um hoping you know postvaccine
getting out there in October getting to
check up on them but that's another neat
thing that's just been bubbling anyways
just [ __ ] great to get to be together
with family on a Sunday with a lot of
bows to look forward to and ideas to
share shout out to Nepal um shout out to
markk Rose and jti and the whole Nepali
family who have been making and
producing Bubble Bags uh almost since
day one my wife sewed up the first ones
and we've had them made in Catman de
ever since so that's awesome to hear
that that's going down in Catman do and
Mike Rose actually recently got in touch
with us which is really exciting because
he has a beautiful piece of property
outside of Catman do that he wants to
completely and fully convert to
regenerative agriculture in Nepal he's
already burying logs on Contour in the
hillside fully ready to sink and
recharge the land with water and build
the microbiology for those very
extremely rare Cult of ours that can
show up in Nepal at times big up to Mark
Rose I want to express G deep gratitude
to uh Jeremy Plum for uh hitting on type
two cannabis thank you thank you thank
you thank you because I really think
that's where the magic in healing
is why don't we get into a little bit of
that conversation the different types of
cannabis you know just for I mean
obviously you guys are all at the
highest caliber but it would be nice for
some of the listeners to say hey what
what does he what did he mean by type
two
cannabis I could probably take a stab at
that Marcus we uh love that we we we
we've been in type Twos for a long time
they're they're tasty um but what's cool
is you type one cannabis is Mo most of
us are aware is high TC cannabis was
previously defined as having both two
btbt Al the TCA synthes genes
um type three cannabis is essentially
your hemp um mostly CBD or not
containing THC as we are learning that
hemp is defined by an arbitrary metric
of less than 3% thca and not much else
um and type two cannabis arises when you
breed a a type one parental with a type
three parental and you get some sort of
mixture of uh THC and CBD in the
flower um and we I think one of our
really good favorite people molecular
Farms they started really focus on
creating parental lines in the type one
world and the type three World I.E hemp
and THC only plants Ryan helped uh lay
the foundations for that breeding
program and what's really cool is they
created parentals of type three hemp
that have all of the noses that are
commercially favorable and even some
other noses that you know don't exist in
the marketplace you know that they have
a hemp line well technically it's not
hemp because it will it will go hot and
have approximately 6% thca but it smells
exactly like OG Kush so if you take that
type one that smells like OG Kush and
the type three that smells exactly like
OG Kush and you hybridize them they will
create a homozygous seed line that has a
nose that's OG Kush and then a thca to
cbda ratio that will vary depending on
the parental um certain parentals will
yield and the most common and most
dominant uh parentals yield seeds with
one to two THC to CBD so it' be a CBD
dominant plant but then there are other
parentals that yield one to one and
others yet that yield two to one and
four to one and so forth and some are
mixed chemotype as they breathe out like
uh you know you'll have a a scatter of
them and similarly if you take a type
two plant and you cross it with another
type two plant you'll get type one two
and three back out in that F1 population
because it segregates so as blessing may
be when they passed the farm bill uh we
had groups sitting on parentals of type
three hemp that has all the beautiful
noses and they're still being hoarded
because the first two lines they leted
out were legendary OG and Jack's blend
and Heavenly pepper there three and
there wasn't any real hemp with tpine
dominant noses in it uh prior to that
and the very next year of course
everybody had tpine dominant so some of
these more exotic noses they're hoarding
until there's a way to create or find a
group of farmers who want to exclusively
grow these you know EX IC pineapple
hemps and all this different stuff but
uh it's really cool the way that that
you can create those parental
lines thanks for sharing I was wondering
maybe Ryan if you could get into a
little bit about what Mark was referring
to when he said you laid some of that
ground
[Music]
work I was one of the first employees at
Nao so I was kind of brought into set up
the breeding programs
really um
yeah so I mean we just we just you know
we the group down there had a bunch of
affiliations with dispensaries and the
idea was to get some novel medicines for
these dispensaries and so um through
like a really big kind of M Market
survey using a really sophisticated
laboratory that we
built we were able to to see what
chemotypes existed in the marketplace
right essentially it was just to you're
just running thousands of of samples
through the lab and cataloging all the
the turpine profiles and the canono
profiles and in doing so when you're
starting to organize the data you
realize that there's groupings that
again Mark can talk more about that um
it's kind of he's
been pull I I want to talk about all the
hugs you had to give me because of the
freaking Girl Scout cookies vaporizer
incidents where you know the panic
attack came in I was like man I wish we
had a Girl Scout cookies type to so I
wouldn't feel this
way yeah well I mean I don't know it's a
different crowd here I mean I think most
of the hash churches are probably like
pretty heavy type one dabbers so you
know dabbing the the plants that are you
know 25 to 30 plus THC acid percentage
um and in certain people that can induce
anxiety when you hit it if you if you
take a big dab and we were rocking the
volcano back in the day uh down at the
farm or one of the Farms
and um Mark yeah mark would have these
like anxiety moments where he'd have a
big dab and would freak out but was
going I don't think it was only the THC
I mean you had a pretty high pressure
life at that point in time a lot was on
the line but um like I think your body
changes over time too because in college
you know I I'd get hot I'd get rosted
before every pra practice and every
football game I get high all before
tests and everything wouldn't have a
problem with high THC and then it's like
I don't know get a little older a little
wiser got more bills to pay I don't know
it's kind of interesting but the type
twos are are perfect like you can I can
smoke as much of a 1.5 to one like high
higher THC and CBD and I get high I get
good it lasts longer I just don't get
the the where's my keys or the what the
[ __ ] what's going on you know what I
mean about feeling good it's about
feeling good as versus how high can you
get you can tear the top of your head
off with enough THC and it doesn't feel
good I love THC but I've had too much a
couple times in my life and it's just
not fun type twos type twos uh they dab
beautifully and there's just this
physical as well as mental experience of
feeling good which there's nothing wrong
with feeling good yeah Mark's another
interesting thing about the Ty twos that
we discovered at the cultivation classic
which Dr ad Ray ran the back end as a
neuroscientist evaluating judges who
were actually like a massive group over
many years were actually going to
publish and sometime shortly I think uh
in the next hopefully month or two this
piece that summarizes all the findings
one of the most interesting things the
women overwhelmingly when blinded and
randomized selected type two and so we
created this women's Choice Award that
was you know I don't think there has
been trials like this with contemporary
product a large population over time
with rigorous analytics and the sort of
credibility that 80 brings to the
research piece so really exciting to see
that here's a product mix issue and not
serving you know this broad demographic
and like being inclusive with all the
people coming in that I also agree that
just with everything Mark said I I
really genuinely like I really love type
twos in the daytime I I absolutely feel
grounded focused and able to have kind
of really really tight focus on a task
and carry through to complete execution
I like the type ones a lot more in the
night I mean it's just that's been a lot
of the Rhythm but I currently have about
14 different type twos and of course
we're working on different tpping
dominance as Works was a terpinolene
dominant type to which was funny because
it definitely I got some of that
feedback there was certainly some people
that that was not a positive thing for
and then a lot of others that have
really loved it for me it's a little bit
psychedelic I I absolutely have an
altered state of consciousness that's
distinct from just high THC there's
there's a kind of an expansive state
that I think it's beautiful and I love
the idea that there's a way in which
this might open the door to a whole lot
of people that are not currently um
engaging with cannabis Therapeutics to
kind of replace way more harmful things
and have a sustainable lifelong
relationship with our with this
beautiful plant it's interesting you
mentioned the product uh trials with
specific specific audiences because you
know um I have a classical education in
Academia so I I presented a lot of
non-cannabis conferences and one of the
most interesting conferences I uh talk
at is called the food flavor and
fragrance uh conference and when you're
trying to figure out what potato is best
for a french fry or what Tomatoes best
for tomato sauce you actually have to
segregate your populations because some
people don't have a certain type of
taste bud so they can't taste a certain
flavor and so when you're creating your
demographic your target audience you
have to break them apart and use
different um products to see which ones
they like and then actually create a
prog product that is targeted to a
specific audience and that that's
exactly what the Innovations in behind
enhanced or type two flowers are um our
group calls them enhanced because when
you get to the store level and the
consumer level they love them but but
when you say hey type two they kind of
get lost but when you say enhanced it's
like enhanced with CBD or whatever it
sounds a little bit more um palatable on
the consumer tone you know I kind of
want to go down the rabbit hole of that
anxiety experience because I have always
smoked type one like dabbed large rips
you know had a high tolerance you know
the first time I ever met Sam I'm quite
certain he was trying to kill me uh and
he didn't and I survived and it's almost
what bonded our friendship I remember
the next day when he smoked a bowl with
someone at the Cannabis Cup and knocked
them unconscious and then they got up
and they had been sharing a booth with
me uh the guy was working for hemp
employed uh and he said oh I want you to
do that to him and he was pointing to me
and Sam was like yeah yeah that's not
going to happen to him sort of thing and
you know it wasn't until my father was
killed in a motorcycle accident with his
wife U my stepmother um on a motorcycle
I purchased him for his 50th birthday
that I had this sort of trauma and
stress that occurred in my body that had
never occurred before in my life and
cannabis high THC in particular seemed
to bring it up to the surface and I I
can't say it was a bad thing because I
think it's how I worked through that
anxiety and stress I pulled it out I
experienced it I held it and I
transformed it uh and it took years I'll
be honest um it happened again years
later when I was in a very bad dirt bike
accident of my own and I absolutely
crushed my lower back I mean I was
walking you know like like like a like a
baby for about three and a half months I
still have pain four years later I go
see an IMS guy all the time and you know
when it flares up I and I'll take that
what really high THC particularly High
terpinolene narrowleaf drug cultivar
that it almost flares up that pain and
and and and creates these sorts of
anxiety attacks now for me I've sort of
worked through those as well and I've
gotten back to that place where I can
really enjoy a big dab but those were
two instances in my life where I was
unable to take big dabs uh even in my
YouTube videos you know I'll I'll do the
video where I did the the rosin press
it's got almost five million views on it
and I took a half pound and I ran it
through the pure pressure and at the end
I take a little dab there's probably a
hundred people on there that comment on
the small size of the dab that I took
well the cultivar was where is my bike
and where is my bike is a biker cush
crossed with an Amnesia Haze so it's
extremely high in terpinolene and it's a
very strong cultivar that gives people
anxiety attacks and I wonder if we could
get into that what is the psychology of
that are we pulling up stress to
transform it is it you know like is it
finding something that's there that
needs to be processed or are we just at
a point in our lives where we need to
look at maybe some of the type two uh
and and and type three plants I can
speak to the chemistry if you want
I terpinolene is basically a structural
isomer with lyine
and on the phytx terpinolene is red
because of that exact reason it's like
one of the most sativa it gives you the
most sativa like effects right lyine is
also um a stimulant and anti-depressant
the only difference between the two
molecules is the location of the double
bond and the first time I ever smoked a
tpine cultivar was train wreck in Santa
Barbara and some dude's house who he
slept on the couch and every bedroom had
black and white paper being sucked in
from all the carbon filters and I had
the same experience Marcus was
describing with David where I was like
oh [ __ ] I'm he's setting me up
somebody's coming to bust me right now
and and was like then after that we
super bonded and it was the research we
did with the type two terpinolene
cultivars where we noticed in the blind
study that as you added CBD to THC the
tpine uh the tpine Entourage effect
became more apparent
so you know people would feel that
stimulating effect and we also used to
just take tpin and put them on the
volcano and inhale them and see how they
made us feel right and terpinolene and
and it sometimes made things sparkly and
definitely increased your heart rate
like with loning make you talk a little
faster that's kind of the background on
that thanks Mark Sam you had something
to
say yeah but I'm spaced out and I forgot
we were talking about anx xiety and
stress and uh you know in inducing those
things when they're deep down no I was
just going to say that a lot of times
it's fear of like with psychedelics it's
fear of the fear that pushes people
really over the edge when they've uh
smoke too much for themselves if they
just relax let go and don't worry about
it they're actually fine yeah we know we
know from DC is anagenic Right which
just means that it it promotes
anxiety but there's you know on the
terpinene front there's definitely
something there because I mean that's
kind of been anecdotal about those
Amnesia hazes and that that class of
weed um for years people have said that
you know it kind of makes them squirly
so there there might actually be
something to that um I think something
that maybe wasn't totally clear when
Mark was describing the ratios and the
typ twos when we started doing all these
crosses and and making these original
type two lines um from unstabilized
parents we realized that there was
different plants um that would that
would essentially spit different ratios
of canabo in The Offspring so we had you
know the first ones to come out or like
the like Mark was saying the one to tws
the one to ones and then the two to ones
we always put THC first because it's you
know in the ratio just because it's easy
to understand most people it's the it's
the it's the number most people are
looking at
um but after breeding and creating par
parental lines that would make each of
those crosses and and doing some kind of
nifty breeding tricks in between the the
types we actually found that there was
plants that were like 4 to one THC to
CBD and and 8 to1 um THC to CB or sorry
THC to CBD and those numbers aren't
really like those those plants you have
to do special breeding tricks to pull
them out like they're not just floating
around the drug the the marketplace okay
um and we started to realize when you
have those different ratios of THC and
CBD really the different it's like you
have a total THC with a little bit of a
CBD buffer I think is what we were
calling it at first it really changes it
takes a lot of the edge off of that
anxiety from the
THC um which for some people it's just
too much you know there's a whole
segment of the popul I know everybody
likes to do these massive dabs and get
as high as you can but when you're you
know when you're using cannabis for
medicine um and you you don't come from
that world where you're just trying to
get blitzed all the time there are
adverse you know some of these these
anxiety effects that you have with THC
are kind of like adverse right it's not
it's not ideal for Mom to be getting way
too high to the point where she doesn't
want to use the medicine right because
you lose the benefit you lose the
medical benefit if you're getting too
high you're scaring people away from the
medicine um and so having these you know
we what we we realize is that having
these these kind of different levels of
CBD buffer it kind of takes the edge off
the THC for a whole different group of
people
um type in the market you know could
that be could that be action on on
dopamine
release I I because I I I I I think CBD
is different than THC isn't it in
dopamine the man when we're talking
about these kind of things it's for me
it's like you know I I studied
Neuroscience in
University um and after coming out of
that process I kind of my feeling on the
brain is that we're still just pushing
buttons right like what does this lever
do kind of thing it's because they're
such complicated hair balls right it's
like THC interacts with dopamine which
cross talks with norepinephrine which
you know impacts the opioid system and
serotonin to say conclusively that X
does y is really really difficult
especially when we're you know we're
we're essentially just specul it
mechanism and we find what we find a new
receptor every month or well not
literally but kind of and I think it's
going to have to be big data that ever
figures it out no human's gonna figure
it out it's gonna be big blue or
whatever on an individual basis it's
really important to remember every
person's endoc canono system is
different and their need for this
cannabis chemistry
differs I love the idea of building data
sets so we can sort of generalize more
fully but yeah um our bodies are not
single molecule systems and and the
plant is not single molecule so it's
really I love that image of a hairball
of of things going on in the body it's a
big knot it's like a big yarn knot right
like how do you tease that whole thing
apart when you're trying to understand
the the bits at play and you know we we
exist in a system where you know a
doctor doesn't like the idea of having
to try you on T 10 different drugs
before they figure out which one works
they want to say oh you're this type we
need to give this type of drug and we're
just not at that point in time yet but
um the you know the range of type two
plants that we now have and I assume
Mark that you've continued to put those
canono ratios into all the different
flavor PL profiles it's like you're
essentially creating a spectrum of
plants that people can then you know
choose from and and really you know
sounds lame but it's like Choose Your
Own Adventure right like you can dial
the the the experience into the user
when you have all these different types
yeah um just for a second Ryan one of
the product lines out here that these
technologies have gone into is called
special and it's uh it basically is a
like a lemon crush or a really gassy OG
nose and there is a low THC version a
one:1 version and a high THC version the
1.5 to1 version uh is is on the market
as well so it's basically all the the
flavors of a gassy OG
and the the the THC to CBD ratios cross
the whole spectrum and you know you
mentioned you know all the people on the
show or or big dabbers or whatever but
we have consumers that once we turn them
on to an enhanced or like a one: one or
a two to one dab that's how they start
the day and they find and even in the
surveys show that they feel like they
get higher at night when they use their
type one again so it's almost like you
look at the science and mcpartland and
the study out of Australia it it's like
you you have this endocannabinoid tone
or health that you're trying to maintain
and if you're constantly banging a large
signal of 80% THC your body actually
changes and you start downregulating
receptors so not only is your ball of
yarn or hairball complex to tease out
it's constantly changing and rewrapping
itself so if you if you're a heavy user
of THC I'd just urge you to just try it
a couple couple times in the morning
some coffee and then then go back to
your high THC and you'll find that it's
actually that's perfect it's like a
great thing that's that's actually how I
use now it's you know perfect yes yes
yes I wanted sorry and also there's
something about what Marcus brought up
as the intro this that I really wanted
to catch that I love um there's a
psychological perspective about anxiety
different than biochemical I think about
the role of anxiety um and this is my
background I went my graduate degree was
at Pacifica I was really a Yan but the
reality is I think about the ego
distonic experience and the way in which
one of the things Universal to
psychedelics is that you must have this
ego distonic moment in order to have the
opportunity to leave behind a lot of the
baggage and complexity of this kind of
last awareness to be very very present I
think about fear as Sam brought up and
the kind of low-laying a latent anxiety
like modern living disease and the way
in which you know most of us throughout
varying levels of stress that would
surpass what other humans and other
Generations may have even uh possibly
conceived of that there is a a
fundamental stress Baseline that I think
is quite high you can look at
epinephrine and biochemistry and stuff
but the bottom line is I think we're
primarily producing cortisol throughout
the day most of the time I actually did
a trial at one point where I had heart
rate monitoring and I was really working
to understand at what point I could
reduce cortisol production I could not
even get to that state in a sitting
meditating position the only way I could
achieve it was in a slow walking
meditation following really slow
breathing and eventually I got there and
then realized we're basically on these
really hard drugs so much of the time
and this of course is very damaging but
again back to the anxiety I feel there's
like Marcus was saying an invitation
towards an opportunity to be present and
to filter some of the fear and the
latent trauma and the experiences that
hopefully do get cleared so I think
there's a really like I've always been a
pretty high anxiety person I think
that's one of the things that's drawn me
to cannabis in general but I've been
able to mitigate the worst expressions
of that and be high functioning by
virtue in part and especially in the
last eight years or so with type twos
I'm excited about what that represents
and that also one other thing you said
Mark just this notion that I actually
get I I really enjoy my type 1 highs
more there's a dimensionality there's
something it's punctuated when I get
into a Groove where I'm on type one a
whole bunch throughout many many days it
it's just it it flattens out I'm missing
nuance and depth and dimension it's that
it's opening up this much bigger space
so I I really love that diverse endoc
canabo diet to accommodate also diverse
endoc canabo tone I just think it's such
a a cool Direction you know one thing
more I'll oh go ahead Kelly hi everybody
um and welcome oh thank you so much it's
so nice to be here the conversation is
super important and and really awesome
um I just think that when we're talking
about cannabis and we're talking about
analogic effects of cannabis I think
that it's really important that we don't
forget that this is a conscious
changing uh plant this is not
necessarily A symptomatic plant this
plant can get to the root of things
very quickly so when we're talking about
analgesics we need to also delve into
the analgesics of the emotions of the
mind that this plant is not just going
to hit some type of a symptomatic effect
it's going to go way deep into the root
so when people consume this they're
going to be maybe uplifting a tremendous
amount of past emotions because they're
not just dealing with the symptoms and
this where plants are so different than
Pharmaceuticals because Pharmaceuticals
are so incredibly symptomatic you take
it it deals with a symptom but when we
smoke cannabis or when we ingest
cannabis or even when we use it
topically it's going to be going to the
root it's going to be attacking it's
going to be breaking
down those subconscious layers that we
have that hold us back from our ultimate
healing and that's where we're talking
about fear we're talking about all these
things because we also have pain is
associated with emotional ties just like
you were saying Marcus you know when you
hurt your back that there's so much
emotions that are tied into that like we
have symptoms upon immediate effect of
some type of an injury and then when we
ingest cannabis it brings it all up to
the surface so in talking about the
scientific measures of it in talking
about the cannabinoids
there's this whole unknown that comes
into play Maybe Jeremy you were talking
about it as the ego and I'd like to go
even deeper than the egoo this is our
ultimate you know bodily function that
we have and how we're dealing and of
course cortisol is a huge player to this
so when people are ingesting it's like
they have to un how many layers of onion
you know do you have to be able to get
to the center of dealing with the issue
that you're trying to get to and I find
that in dealing with patients you know
I'll be treating a knee injury and then
one month later wow we really were
dealing with some massive childhood
trauma that the plant brought up all of
these different symptoms and then that
was what healed the knee so I think that
if we pull more away from symptomatic
healing which was what alpath and which
is what w Western medicine has shown us
then we will be aligning with the true
healing nature of this plant which is to
bring science and bring ex uh um
observational experience to bring
emotional experience and not
differentiate when we talk about um pain
and healing that we don't differentiate
the physical pain and healing with the
emotional pain and healing because they
are all one and the plant continues to
show us that I would just add that you
know our disposition of our microbiome
affects our endocannabinoid system so
health and well-being through food is
going to affect the Cannabis as it comes
in also toxicity in the plant can often
create anxiety in the person and we know
often we've met people and and have
close family members with you know that
have gone through hyper Mesa syndrome or
or or or anxiety with cannabis and they
will smoke a regeneratively grown
organic flour
and it will not give them the same
effects so we are dealing with toxic
overloads it's very important for us to
detox ourselves so that this medicine
can be so powerful we love and
appreciate and I just I'm sorry just to
jump on it one more time I believe that
when we talk a lot about the science and
we're pushing a lot about the
cannabinoids that we really need to
almost step back a little bit and we
need to not ask more of the plant than
what she can offer I believe that this
new time and this new outcoming this
plant is having you know an outcoming
from a time of victimization of of being
shrouded and and we're asking so much of
her and we're trying to come to like all
of these finite answers and magical
remedies without letting her just sort
of unravel and show herself and and and
watch the experience that we're all
having with this plant rather than
trying to come to definitive definitions
of it right away because each person is
having such a differential experiential
effect could agree more with that I mean
when we do our panels one of the things
we notice is that um it's it's not just
a high it's a behavioral distinct change
things taste better things feel better
you're more intuitive so there is
definitely a spiritual component and
what's beautiful about chemistry is that
you can take a dive into everything that
I mean you can look at thousands of
compounds that are in this plant I mean
you can dig down to the the heavy metals
the flavonoids the tpin and and then you
can cross-compare and analyze and have a
whole panel where people discuss you
know it changes the flavor of salts to
some it makes sweets sweeter to others
and it ties right back into what Rafi
mulam says where he thinks that the you
know indoc canabo system has a major
contribution to your your personality
right Ryan I mean that one of his famous
sayings yeah there's another uh thing
that we would be remiss to uh bring up
if as move is not with us today and you
know Mojave has a variety that he's
worked with for a very long time called
Zeta it's a terpinolene Dom variety it
reminds me a bit of zel's gift actually
which I love that plant she's so
beautiful I uh but that I think of
Mojave reminiscing about moderate THC
combined with terpinolene as this
spiritual plant from Big Sur and and
this population at the root of that kind
of moment in time was the most
sought-after and and spiritual cannabis
I just think it's fascinating though
that that was again probably like 10 to
15% THC and turpening da and I think
that's a that's a really beautiful
profile and and hey this is Colin this
is Al also touching on on a conversation
we had the other day which was you know
the physiological and the the the sense
of of memory tied to uh the different
tpine profiles or chemical profiles I
think there's a lineage directly
correlated to those things and and how
we're associating our personal uh you
know opinions of what is good and what
is bad um and over the years you know
trinoline I think has been a dominant in
terms of everyone's profile and I think
there's there's no mistake over that
there there's definitely some memory uh
sensories uh you know being evoked in
things in you know in our bodies and in
our minds and I think that's uh also the
the connection that that happens with
with all these different chemicals is
the the sensory of memory and how that
uh brings us into into
now yeah and I believe one of our trials
also showed that you know you add a
little bit of CBD and it actually helps
with the memory loss issue um so there
definitely formulations for that and you
know that's why we like to call the the
type twos enhanced because we feel like
they can enhance every aspect of your
life whether it's you know waking up in
the morning being creative going on a
run or partying down it's like there's
there's this ability to find a chemical
mixture cocktail that's going to improve
your life and you know what in the world
isn't chemistry you
know yeah you know also I've noticed
that a little little uh splash of that
CBD and working with patients over the
years and then really fiting our oneto
one I really am believing that that
splash of CBD is what brings those
cortisol levels down which
helps you know have
aiz of what is actually going on where
it that
weers you know need to focus think that
that CD brings it down just and realize
where the medicine needs to go also
something that we're not talking about
here is that in working with patients
there's an incredible intrical um almost
electric energy that's going on when a
person is ingesting cannabis it's so
it's it's it's so experiential it's so
incredibly personal that almost to
have a
relationship with the person that is
offering the medicine to you or Dr Lis
you know you're talking about having
patient studies having these patient
studies that are more intimate and more
involved I'm finding we really get to
the root of things much faster which is
again not an alpath model it's following
something a little bit more different a
little bit more natural and following
more about what the plan
and Kelly there's a wonderful piece uh
there with
psychopharmacology there's this whole
body of research that illustrates say
you give somebody an SSRI and they have
depressive features you'll actually find
statistically over time very often that
will not benefit the person at all but
if you pair that with counseling now you
have this unbelievable opportunity so
it's a relational element that I feel is
often missing in our therapeutic
conversation I've approached that in a
way the Pharma counter that I got to
experiment with a huge community of
patients where it always felt like when
people were new to cannabis there was
this simple orientation to here's an
array of phytochemical profiles but you
know don't attach too much value to that
but at least have some association with
what s of different profiles you're
consuming but then you know titration
and dosage start with these tiny
increments and really get to know those
different increments at different times
and then let's move into the Delivery
Systems and here's the array of
different ways to relate with the plant
but at some point bringing in a
journaling process and an observation
process and then watching people's lives
transform again and again by essentially
providing both education but more than
that empathic Attunement really feeling
into that hugeness as somebody
approaches the possibility of bringing
an altered state of consciousness into
their life I do think to help that
altered state of consciousness to then
uh sort of be midwife
or carried toward a sort of therapeutic
Direction can be a relational Dynamic
and that cannabis very often provides
that opportunity the spirit is there but
also now there's this one other element
that I feel Community actually needs to
uphold and to hit that highest level of
meaningful benefits it's great because
that's what the plant plant medicine
continues to teach us over and over
again is that set in setting and how
wonderful that now plant medicine is is
even infiltrating into Western medicine
and they're even starting to have
conversations about set in setting and
maybe even painting their their offices
a color that you know is more soothing
to their patients these things are all
coming from from plant medicine you said
color you said color that that's why we
developed the phyt OFA was because
people couldn't know what was in their
medicine before I have a question for
you Dr Lewis which is
what's type four type five type
six what's four is what
cbga five is canabo
list Rose by Any Other Name who cares
who cares well it's it's it's important
because right now this is a
one-dimensional product in a Marketplace
that craves multi-dimensional products
you add CBD now you have it
two-dimensional product plus with all
the tpin oh look there's a phytx that's
nice I absolutely agree with you so so
when you're dealing with all of these
these things these components and then
you have all the you have the cultivar
strain names on top of it it creates
this white noise where no one can hear
anything and this is why we developed
the phyto fact was so that people could
look at a tool and and and recognize
things for instance somebody comes in
and they're looking for something that's
limine dominant and they usually use the
space force one that's on the right it's
high THC thing but then they have all
these other googly Gob names out there I
don't know I've heard a bunch
on for you you we put these up a lot or
not I I just think that a lot of people
have SE these for the first time so why
don't you walk us through the different
sections of the phyto fact so people can
understand how to read them like the
Canada and then the you know sounds good
so if you if you look at the sorry
Marcus can you make that a little bigger
because I feel I find it a little hard
to read and if if you could that would
be cool bring the screen in but go ahead
you can also Zoom it in on your computer
Control Plus or if you're on a Mac just
use
your your your scroll pad or whatever
yeah on Zoom also you can move your bar
over so it gets
larger nice cool while he messes with
that I'll get started here so are these
are these DET turpine profiles of cured
bud or of Fresh Harvest okay these are
so the reason that this was developed
just so give you a little backstory
here was back in the wild wild west days
at dispensaries you know intake day
where they were buying flowers would be
a a a line
of people out the door with duffel bags
and you know managers would be on the
spot to Eton knows exactly what I'm
talking about especially in Berkeley I
mean you would have like 80 people lined
up half of them with dirty fingernails
and like cat hair in their weed oh yeah
yeah so much cat hair dog hair sometimes
it out right yeah dude we found bloody
razor blades I mean you you name it it's
in there and you would actually be
physically sick for a day or two after
from smelling all the mold and and pests
and pathogens are you know coming up
anyway so we would find that there was
no quality standard for the products
being purchased and you know favoritism
was a thing we got commissioned to
create a certificate of analysis for
finished products so this isn't a phyto
effect of a wet flower these are
chemical analysis of finished products
and starting at the top or at the very
bottom because it ties into the top uh
is the phyto print that's essentially a
tpine
fingerprint that is you know our
laboratory analyzes like 60 plus low
molecular weight and high molecular
weight tpes and molecules that actually
create the total nose bouquet these
aren't all of the molecules that
contribute to the uh flavor and Aroma
but they are the top 17 that are
commonly occurring and most biologically
relevant Okay so it's colorcoded from
just like Roy G Biv like a rainbow and
the warm tones are associated with
sativa like um effects we don't have a
terpinolene dominant plant in here but
that would be the red bar at the very
top and you've heard us discuss how
terpinolene has a tendency to make some
people anxious While others like David
really liked the train wreck bubble hash
that was hydrenaline because he said it
was the most sativa uh hash that was
available when he visited um lyine is a
warm tone as well so those represent
kind of sativa like plants and then as
you go down into the green is pining you
know the blues are the your your cesa
Turpin your humin your caropines and
then linol and mercine are at the bottom
they're more associated with your
indicia like effects so you can kind of
associate your cultivar name so like if
you look at a Girl Scout cookies if it
would be just beta Carling dominant with
little huming and limine little
mercy and then once you find a cultivar
you like based on nose and flavor you
don't have to remember all the strain
names associated with it it just becomes
color pattern recognition which is way
easier for our Simple Minds to to grasp
I like the purple ones I like the yellow
ones and you know Dave would like the
red ones right so um if you go
back it's important to notice too that
like the colors for example that you see
on this Bottom bar graph like the actual
colored bar graph is correlated to the
Entourage effect and the smell and the
aroma um so you can see that the
Entourage effect they're also um they're
also colorcoded so for example on this
one that we're looking at here on the
left it's hyamine which is the orange um
on the the lower section of the phyo
print or the turbine profile is you can
if you look up one panel above it on the
right side you can see that it's also
highest in in the orange triangle which
is associated with
Comm right so the idea is that this is a
lab report format that either that a lab
will give you that you might see at a
dispensary or you might see it on a
packaging but the idea is that like Mark
is saying even without getting in all
the nitty-gritty details you're
subliminally being fed these these
messages um like Mark can you actually
scroll up a little bit since you're on
we're sharing your
screen how much VAR do you see inine
profile from from Harvest to harvest
from grow to grow it seems like that
would be really variable and that
ultimately is gonna affect that graph
above and the other thing I just wanted
to ask you Mark we had an interesting
discussion in in clubhouse with Mike
Backus the other night and I asked him
specifically um does he see what change
in the tpine profile between Fresh
Harvest and and cure does he see and
specifically does he see uh any increase
in lenol with decrease in in uh in
Marine and the correlated question I
would ask based on what we dis what you
had discussed earlier is you know
terpinolene is one of what four isomers
of of turpine and all of those can
oxidize to terpenol and tpol certainly
has a very different fragrance than than
T terpinolene itself so I was wondering
if you could comment on how these tpine
profiles change between Harvest and cure
okay um real quick I I'll hit that in a
second just that you see the cultiv our
name at the top of this report and then
the top three tpin create that color
code so that's that was the pattern
recognition I was talking about about
now when we discovered so one of the
things we do in the laboratory when
we're trying you know Skunk Works no pun
intended actually we'll buy analytical
standards and we'll smell them you know
because we'll find little blips and hit
on the mass spec and determine its
molecular weight and like oh I wonder if
it's this or that and one day we opened
up a bottle of hexal
butyrate and it's it's it smells like
luden's cherry cough drops I mean it
literally a string Cherry makes your mou
mouth water as soon as you you smell it
so very different than Beric acid right
very very different yes and so acid
smells like puke so what we did was we
went straight to the chromatograms uh
well we shot that on the on the GC we
looked at it retention time we looked at
all the chromatograms for all the plants
that we'd analyze and um we found little
blips then we immediately called up
molecular farms and said hey these code
numbers have those blips start
inbreeding them and they they imbred
like four generations until that blip
became so concentrated it was almost 1%
hexalite and I mean that plant when it's
in the field you you get that little
Tricom rub and smell it makes your mouth
water smells like luden's cherry cough
drops it's pining dominant with merine
in it you take that plant and you cure
it dry it and cure it and you know it's
best fresh not like sitting for a month
or anything but over time the hexal rate
will just and it be gone because it's a
low molecular weight tpine right and Dr
is that just evaporation it's not
transforming into something else correct
correct it's just fugitive okay yeah so
um so and if you it can let me back up
it can transform to something else if
you leave it in the jar too long and it
get oxidized but if you look at the
flowers on the plant to to to the I mean
sorry the Turpin on the plant to the
finished product um there can be little
change or there can be massive change to
the relative profile and it all depends
on your post Harvest
postprocessing um conditions and that's
that's one of the things that Nao really
helps cultivators with because most
cultivators and you know I I know that
the people listen to show aren't most
cultivators the people on the show
probably know how to dry and cure a
plant to preserve their Turpin but most
people destroy the plant like they
they're they're worried about cost of
goods they're worried about bus business
stuff you know not not not like us we
worship the plant you know it's like we
want that exact flavor of a fresh flour
in in our products at the end because
that smells so freaking good and it
tastes so so good and the you know we
work with folks in the on the hemp side
who um do tpine distillation of the hemp
and they they exclusively beg for the
the the bi um hemp genetics because they
have that happy pineapple in hemp they
have pining dominant cultivars and hemp
so they can get those cannabis drive
tpin and they they they literally chop
the plant down and throw it in the
extractor immediately don't freeze it
don't take it anywhere and the tpine
profiles are very very similar to those
that you find in the plant and then
those cannabinoid or those hemp or
cannabis Drive tpin can be used in Vape
pins in in the you know THC Marketplace
and when you hit those Vape pins and
exhale it smells like fresh flour it's
really it's really amazing um and I'd
like to if you want to pull up the phofa
I can finish going through it or or we
can ditch it it's up to you Marcus
you're the sort of the moderator but I I
would like to show that you know this
thing has these two bar charts at the
top that have cannabinoids and
terpenoids and we set this scale at 25%
and 2.5% because when people would come
to the dispensaries with you know pounds
from the hill or whatever if we just
looked at these two bars and they were
pegged the manager would know that's
good flower that's that's that's some
good [ __ ] but most of the stuff in
California even to this day doesn't test
above 1.5% TP sometimes in the two 2%
range and you know canabo are all over
the place and it depends on your
laboratory and whatnot but this uh you
go down below that bar chart um and you
have a a dial of THC to the next highest
cannabinoid in this case of happy
pineapple it's cbga so this is about 20%
THC about 8% CBG and this is a very very
unique cultivar it tastes delicious and
when you long cure this particular flow
it takes on an distinct vanilla Aroma
it's totally unique but when it's fresh
it smells straight up like fresh
pineapple because you know this osaman
dominance there was only one plant uh of
osaman dominant cannabis ever tested did
in the state of California until like
two and a half three years ago and um
and now is there more there there's a
couple more yeah well I mean most of I
mean molecular has about 10 of them that
goes through the system but you know
there was the live reson of this taste
like yeah I was gonna ask Dr Lewis we've
we've only done the and shout out to
Marcus for turning us on to the the pure
pressure we've all we've only done the
flower rosin um they they just uh this
they just planted enough this this
spring to be able to do a large run of
of you know the the bubble hash to live
Ros and thing I'm more of a scientist
and you know I I see oversee the quality
control of those types of things but
there's like hash experts that do that
stuff um and we just do the chemical
analysis right or offer ways to improve
the performance of their extraction um I
I have a question for you Dr Lewis with
your phofa the happy pineapple it shows
what like an orangish color then blue
then green why those
colors because osine is colored orange
and it's the top tpine beta carara
offene is blue in the phyto print and
it's the second most abundant and the
green is the tiny I I yeah I can't see
the entire bottom of the photo by pack
so that's why
gotcha now it's becomes much more
apparent right so so then you think
about uh the smoothness of a smoke right
like because that was one of the things
that you know Ryan and I always wanted
was smooth
smoke it all it all has to do with
having beta carry offline in there I
mean that that really takes the edge off
of any tarpine and you know some turpins
if you like Alpha pining if it's really
pining dominant and there isn't a whole
lot of anything else it can be pretty
harsh on the back of your
throat so so it's it's similarly with
terpinolene um but it you have to
balance that and when when you're
breeding parentals or other things for a
product you have to take all of that
into account you can't just pheno hunt
you know I mean that's part of it that's
the funnest part but you have to be
really thoughtful on how you design a
new technology like a plant like this
holy crunch right here I mean this thing
has
28% you know canabo and it's beta carene
lming it's a one to one basically and it
it it is the smoothest tastiest smoke
and most people you a lot of these
products you just have people smoke them
and they can't distinguish you know
they'll be like that's great and be like
hey you know that's enhanced you know
type to and they'll be like know what
I'm like yeah see you can get high off
this stuff it's not CBD is not a buzz
killer it just makes you feel good you
know what I mean and it's like this one
is very very popular it actually won the
emerald Cup in uh last year uh or two
last year yeah I think so in the CBD
flower category technically CBD can be a
buzz killer if you smoke a 100
milligrams of pure CBD early in the
morning then try to smoke uh even 100
milligrams of
THC but you know wait like a half an
hour or so and and you'll find out that
the THC has little or no effect if you
fled yourself with CBD first yeah well
nobody I don't think anyone really wants
to bedge in themselves with CBD when
they wake up in the morning that's it's
painful so there's there's a couple of
things with with type twos in the
marketplace I mean they've tried to roll
them out and granted I think the vast
majority of type twos that have been on
the market in Canada have been M SE
dominant they're all canonic and canonic
hybrids
um but they they're having like zero
uptake on the market right like it's all
type one everybody wants everything over
20% THC actually Ryan there's an amazing
shift that's been happening in the
Oregon market we've been fighting this
battle for a while of course to out
production space
to Sor I know what happens down there in
California I'm just trying to make a
point about the Canadian Marketplace how
it's not able to adopt you guys been
able to do a bunch of product knowledge
you know Market education that that has
led to the acceptance right so how do
how do we go about doing that in in
markets where they're not as refined
like how do you how do you go about
rolling out in a new market the question
often is the popular education element
combined with the genetics combined with
The Talented folks who are producing
breeding growing but I really love that
I think cultivation classic was a big
impact in Oregon Market because there
was huge emphasis on type two it got
equal attention to ones and threes and
obviously there was way fewer entries
but I just remember back to only three
years ago when I was trying to sell type
tws and couldn't get $400 a pound I am
now selling astral works and this is one
of the more exciting personal
accomplishments that like it exists for
at least more than the cost of
production and it is finally a viable
product that lives and now there's about
three other products that are also
almost at that level it's been such a
battle though like you said I I just the
question is really how do we help a lot
of people come into a kind of new
awareness about a new product category I
loved what Mark said that there really
are these kind of entirely new
categories and this is why I like types
I mean the CBG dominant varieties now
seeing type four hybrid
coming into this uh this new space I'm
really excited to see like I've yet to
see a type four hybrid on the market in
the wreck market and I feel like that's
going to represent a whole new set of
interesting possibilities and i' and
I've yet to wonder and I've yet to see a
type four hybrid with tpping like
somehow when they knocked out that
cannabinoid pathway I mean they don't
test higher than 6% turps it's very
bizarre but they smell kind of like all
of them have a similar like citrusy kind
of smell note to them and they look
really beautiful like Frosty kind of
like blackberry kush did back in the day
remember it like was the frostiest
flower and like where's the triome heads
but pretty pretty interesting production
plant
there hey guys this might be a good uh
opportunity to um hear from a few people
who we haven't heard from um I thought
Alec was going to come in and sort of uh
introduce his friend Joe who I'm
actually just meeting so I wanted to
maybe get an introduction from you Joe I
hear you're going to be um doing some of
the emerald cup flower judging this year
and Alec thought it would be good for
you to be a part of the conversation and
once we've heard from you I would love
to hear from uh Mojave and then I would
also love to hear from Peter and then we
can get right back into our conversation
awesome yeah thanks for having me um
obviously there's a bunch of Legends on
this panel super super happy to be here
uh Alex's a good friend um I've been in
the industry a little over 20 years um I
host a cannabis education talk show on
the radio here Sonoma County also been
an emerald cut flower judge for a couple
years um I'm also a buyer for a couple
dispensaries in our area um so it's
awesome to hear you guys talk about tpin
uh Dr Lewis I was actually uh can
sympathize with sitting in those rooms
when the people were coming down off the
hill and those lines you know kind of
going through those different bags um it
it's kind of awesome we're one of the
first dispensaries to do require testing
um that's kind of how I have my
relationship with Alec over at SC Labs
um we've been rolling out a whole
turpine education program over the last
six months um and then yeah with the
judging this year it's funny I've
actually been you know listening to you
guys talk I love it I'm really curious
to know kind of what those tpping levels
are in some of those enhanced strains
you're talking about um that's actually
how I've been curating now with the
tpine profiles on the R&amp;D it allows me
to have a more diverse menu on the shelf
and really start to focus on the tpin
and the different effects you're getting
from those plants with their
relationship with conoids and it's not
just all about those 20 25% hitters so
yeah we're going through the flowers
right now I actually have a bunch of
them right here it's kind of cool
they're they're actually you can see
they're they're uh they're typed out by
their different profile what you do
working my way through that right now he
and um yeah it's really interesting but
um I am curious to know kind of what
those tpine levels are um that you're
seeing in those enhanced strains um so
yeah thank you guys I'm really happy to
be here hey are you uh using the phyt
OFA now that se Labs is uh pumping them
out yeah we've been using the phofa for
a while um I started we started reaching
out obviously for myself I started
watching cultivars die in our space as
Growers were unable to make money off
them anymore because they didn't hit
certain THC percentages which we know
with the labs can vary so much right and
so when we switch from our traditional
Market Days to U the new Rec days the
way it was marketed is um everyone's
coming in for that you know that that
liquor proof you know it's like you
don't go to the bar looking for Hunter
proof schnaps all the time you might
want a beer might want something a
little lighter so everyone's been kind
of trained to go to that THC and so
using the phofa we actually have a QR
code um that we put on all the flavors
that are um displayed in the store next
to the tpine wheel um and it kind of
directs them straight to those so
getting people to understand it it
starts with um the butt tenders um you
know at our store we're lucky enough to
see around 25,000 people a month um and
so for us we feel like you know that's a
good platform to start and we we wanted
to work with SC we've been testing with
them for a long time and you start
looking at these different R&amp;D tests and
you start and you start seeing where the
tpin are um and you start noticing that
you know mostly if you're seeing those
top 25 30% THC with like you were saying
in our Marketplace mostly it's around 1%
% tpine you know a little less you're
basically looking at biomass in my
opinion so for us being able to cult uh
curate something that's that's
beneficial um on a medicinal level
considering that we were rooted in that
and that's that's kind of our culture
here in our area is the medicinal
benefits from the plant um it's really
being able to pair that right cultivar
with the person so um yeah it's it's
been a challenge um but that's why
conversations like this are so important
and I feel so great to be here
wow thanks thanks for that oh I was just
going to add on to something that he
just said so does it matter if Labs like
SC labs are in sort of high throughput
testing mode and using GC to profile
their tpin or I think you guys use hlc
is there going to be a real big
difference no what just just so just a
little background on Neo um I brought a
bunch of chemists from my grad school
from Big Pharma to help develop these
methodologies
um and we wrote a paper we validated a
method for a ro robust reliable um
analysis of Turin and cannaboids that
essentially became the gold standard for
the Laboratory Testing industry we made
it free we paid extra to make it free
open source to everyone because we
really wanted to fix the laboratory
problem because we want you know it's
important that if you want to compare
apples to apples your Labs can't be you
know doing that confirmational bias
thing where're like well if we say it's
28% we're going to get more business and
it's like that doesn't work when you're
trying to you know create a an an in a
real industry right like you don't go to
the pharmacy and pick up the generic
Tylenol and look at it and be like oh it
says it's 500 milligrams and it's really
only 200 um so we made that paper open
source and the Laboratories uh you know
base their methods off of it and you
know groups like SC Labs we work we
service clients who are producers who
are Distributors who we actually SC
laabs is one of our clients so when we
send products
or uh when when one of our clients sends
a product SC Labs or there's a problem
with pesticide or there's a problem with
heavy metals what we do is a root cause
analysis so and then we work directly
with the with the Testing Laboratories
to try to figure out where the problem
was was the problem with the producer
was the problem with the Laboratory
Testing and SC lab's chemistry is super
tight like I mean I'm very impressed
with those guys have been for nearly a
decade now and yeah so the methodology
is pretty ironed out and it doesn't
matter if they're going high throughput
because you can only go so fast in a in
a in a in a run for like a GC because
you have to get you know Baseline
resolution and you have to run your
check standards between every run and
all that stuff and those guys are ISO
certified so you know they've got their
chemistry buttoned up really tight so I
don't think there's really a difference
the the difference between a lab like SC
labs and lab like Neo is that we focus
100% on R&amp;D so we develop methods with
like perk and Elmer for their
instrumentation so then when a new
laboratory opens up they can say hey
here's this method that we've already
validated over here and you can analyze
heavy metals or pesticides or whatever
it is and you know the it's a it's it's
a symbiosis right you know everybody
helping everybody and Meanwhile we're
developing methods for Growers um you
know whether it's breeding projects or
or or just simply increasing yields and
lowering the need for pesticides or you
know things like that it's all
optimization for us and we have a really
good template so any farmer or or
cultivators who ever need assistance you
know look us up for sure I mean that's
what we
do you know and really quickly like what
the base how to preserve the T beines in
a grow you know is valuable for people
to hear again and I maybe the a quick uh
just what is your best quick way for
people on farms to preserve their chines
for the market our saying is 60%
humidity 60% degrees for two weeks or
what what we call mpm minimally process
minimally handle slow and cold so you
got it down if you have a vacuum cooler
those are there's fun experiments there
that you know when you when you harvest
lots of lettuce um you have to use an
actual gigantic vacuum cooler because
otherwise you'll get a mold front as the
head of lettuce begins to try to get
cold so you have to cold get it cold
fast
there's lots of cool things you can do
and I'm sure I'm sure Marcus is fluent
in terpanes with all of the the bubble
hash he's done around the
world hell yeah you know I'm uh
definitely fluent in tanese shout out to
Young turp shout out to Chile for those
of you that know you know for those of
you that don't you'll figure it out uh I
did want to also welcome move to the
room um how you doing buddy you want to
uh tell everyone a little bit about
yourself and what you're working on your
name came up a few times uh while uh in
the last hour and a half so it's great
that you showed up yeah man thanks for
having me um sorry I came in late it's a
had one of those family mornings Break
Free then all a sudden everyone went off
to their respective Zoom calls the kids
are on their zoom and the wife's on
their Zoom so it's like it's my turn
yeah um my name is mve Richmond um to to
those who I don't know personally um
good to see everyone on here it's been
nice chatting with you all on clubhouse
over the uh past couple weeks um and
yeah I'm uh you know a lifetime cannabis
Enthusiast and activist and bit of a
breeder and cultivator and now a little
bit of a allaround um wearer of mini
hats and I work with um I work with Rob
Clark with cannabis uh with bioeconomics
group also with itian Fontan who's a
member uh an important uh co-owner in
the company which I would like to
mention um and we're doing some other
stuff we're working as well with um
breeders best which is a um IP cannabis
IP company founded by Dale Hunt um with
Ethan Russo as well and yeah just trying
to stay involved and loving the
conversation you know I always feel like
I you know um I had such a great
opportunity to sit on the panel with
Ryan and Mark and Rob on Thursday for uh
Seer inter International the greeting
panel and uh I just want to listen you
know I get into this the conversation
gets so high and I just want to you know
more than chiming in I love I love you
know learning and I I I thought it was
really interesting what uh what Ryan was
talking about earlier about trying to
bring these uh other tpine profiles into
um the Canadian Market I had this really
interesting just on that kind of topic I
I've been having having this interesting
discussion with a couple Distributors
here down south southern
California who say the entire Southern
California Market doesn't want Jack
train wreck hay Sage that their tpen
dominant varieties just don't do well in
Southern California for whatever reason
and they do continue to do well in
Northern California and you know there
there's been some people have kind of
made this hypothesis that it has to do
with the nature of the Southern
California consumer um which might have
some validity to it you know there's
definitely is a a a different kind of
ethos going on down in Southern
California but more than anything I
think it's just about exposure you know
specifically because these tpine
dominant varieties are they grow well
they grow really great Under the Sun
make big beautiful trees um and there's
a lot of that going on in Northern
California but very little in Southern
California so you see what about the
pears can I ask you about the purples
like I mean you know grbs and that blue
dream is in that same family
and you know a lot of these other ones
are high in mirene how do they sell down
in Souther in SoCal like I'm wondering
you is it is it actually that they don't
like the terpinolene or is it that
they're only so focused on the beta
carry off lean like OG Sour Diesel class
well I I think it has to do with
exposure like for instance I mean the
the terpinolene thing I think is just
because there's not enough tpine uh
dominant varieties on the market because
um they just traditionally haven't been
grown here but it's the interesting
point about the purples I mean in the
late 9s early 2000s Southern Northern
California Purple Kush purple Urkel uh
GDP they were everywhere you know and in
Southern California they weren't and
they still slowly started to trickle in
in the the the um you know the prop 215
Medical Market but what I found was back
in the day people just there wasn't this
open sharing of genetics like there is
today so it really showed up there first
it bloomed created a market had the
following and then slowly it trickled
down to Los Angeles and then eventually
those purple varieties got down here and
people started working with them and
Crossing them and then they have now you
know I know cultivators who won't grow
anything unless it's purple that's
that's okay this is all this is all
we'll grow so um anyway it's yeah it's
it's just really interesting how you see
these different markets and there's like
a legacy of what varieties were first
introduced into that market that still
kind of ripples as the market shifts and
and now we have full access to cultivar
through the nursery system we can get
any cultivar that's available up and
down the state um but yeah mve I have a
quick question when you say purple and
tpine you know historically uh outside
of the the Nao ecosystem we don't see
cultivars at test much higher than right
at 20 low 20s maybe 20% THC most of the
purples are dip under 20% and I just
wonder if it's the buying habit of the
SoCal consumer shooting for that 30% or
more so than and same with the tpine
dominant lines they they don't they
don't get at it it takes some breeding
tricks to get those things up into close
to the 30s and maintain that tpine
Integrity what do you think about that I
I think that there's something to be
said for that I think the the purple
phenomenon has a lot more to do with
marketing you know and and certain very
successful marketing campaigns behind
bigger groups that have been able to
really sell you know I mean it's just
crazy you know just the other day there
was you know SE junkies did a drop at
blah blah and and in the valley and
people were lined up overnight camping
out waiting
to purchase seeds you know and and I do
think you know same with the cookie
store every time a cookie store opens up
you know there's lines around the block
It's like Star Wars in 1977 you know so
it's it's far out you know but and
that's that to me that has so much more
to do with marketing and how far your
social media reach goes than it really
is about how desirable those varieties
are um so and that's the challenge you
know that the purple's just like like I
mentioned on the in our our breeding
panel purple is a beautiful color that
people love you know and in attaching
that your predisposition to Aromas
colors flavor flavors kind of leads you
into what varieties you first try as
soon as they become available and it it
can kind of grab hold of your
preferences in a powerful way like me
for instance I don't really like purple
varieties but I love the flavor I love
grape I love purple flavors so you know
there's like this battle where like I as
I'm inhaling and I'm enjoying the smoke
I'm like wow that brings back all these
memories of all these different these
different uh you know you remember when
you were a kid purple was a flavor back
in the 70s you know you got all great it
was great right yeah know but it often
was like purple and red and green those
are your flavors um so it brings back
all those memories why you said that
because they're not necessarily the same
and I that's exactly the question I had
so purple and grape aren't necessarily
the same in cannabis no not at all not
at all not to me at least you know a lot
of the grape the grapey flavors that I
get come from more like that that tarte
grape skin you know a lot of a lot of
the stuff with the new purples that
you're seeing like C junky genetics and
stuff a lot of the Allure there is that
through some of the breeding tricks
they've able to kind of turn some of
those purples by eye more of like a
gassy limine dominant tpine profile when
when you're opening those back up or
you're smelling that it tricks the brain
um it's not more of like that kind of
traditional GDP or like uh the grape
Vape which is a little more creamy and
it's going to remind you more of that
grape flavor so I I see at least in our
area too um most of the people now
especially with the purples I mean
traditional Market obviously we know
that's just Unstoppable the ogs are so
dominant down south um it's starting to
it's starting to come up here but mostly
now with those purple crosses with more
of the lening effect little a little
more of that gas to it that's we're
definitely seeing a lot of that um in
the lining category in the Cup this year
um I want to say at least by I think our
records with SC Labs I think mine's the
most heavily dominant tpine uh in
cannabis tested throughout the state
here and so when we're when we're
starting to see these different tpine
profiles with the monot Turpin um those
different combinations that's where I'm
starting to see these Trends uh
happening at least by um going tripping
first at the store um it's kind of what
I'm seeing with that here and you just
reminded me of a question that Mark
asked like an hour ago about um seasonal
change in tpine profiles and if you're
if it you know as you you all know um if
you're growing in a greenhouse you're
obviously going to have red shift and
blue shift different types of the Year
times of the year and that's why a lot
of people really like those depths
because they're getting that really
intense light for 12 hours and then
getting blacked out and um
not to spend a lot of time here because
you need data for me to show this but I
did a a canmed talk a long time ago that
is online and I showed tpine variation
across multiple harvests in a single
genotype and you know basically what
happens if the if the plant is suffering
at all whether it's sunlight stress
merine starts to take over um it almost
seems like it's a stress default um
tarine so
it's funny you were talking about the
turpine preservation too um I I was
actually talking to Alec about this the
other day that we know there's some
Farmers up here that actually turned to
harvesting at night uh obviously we know
some of those tpin the monot Turpin they
they boil they boil down that lowest
temperature so you're automatically
losing these tping as they're going off
so um I'm curious to know kind of you
know if anyone on the panel has has
heard of other people using utilizing
that trick or technique as far as t
reservations concerned there's a patent
for harvesting on a full moon on a
certain day of the month isn't there
Ryan can't Pat verbalism come on that's
unfair even if SCU man Sam does it it's
not fair and it's not cool I'm not
making this up herbalism I'm I'm not
making this up sure you're not so so on
the East Coast you know you brought
something up that's interesting that
I've paid attention to and I've I've
been doing some some studies on is is
our lights a lot Bluer um especially
when we're growing in in uh green houses
out here so we are getting very
different expressions from different
varietals um and then to someone else's
point when we're harvesting especially
during the fall it's just naturally
cooler we're getting different CO2
levels we're you know different things
are happening um because of the
environment and it's changing um the
Expressions on all these different
varieties that I see versus a much uh
you know more uh you know 4200 Spectrum
or something like that so it's we're
we're getting a different expression
from the chines and and also the canono
expression and then all the way through
Harvest we're able to keep things really
cool a certain time of year you know if
we do light depth usually June's a
little bit different for us out here
where it's dry but it's it's still um it
gets hot so um it it's just different
but but absolutely over the years the
fall has been a key placee for doing
those chem and ogs and sours that's
really where and I think why our sour
when we did them well um during the fall
they just they really were a great
expression of those particular
varietals just goes to show how
important environment is
Right absolutely I was gonna say thing
because we're also talking about
microbiology because in the morning
there's a tremendous amount of
microbiology in the air in the early
morning and this is why ancient
practices of when you're trying to
collect sort of those volatile oils of
any types of herbs and ancient herbology
tells you you know before the Sun Peaks
on the horizon is is when anything
should be picked for its aromatic
effects and that just goes back I I mean
I think thousands of years even 5,000
years in
Chinese I don't know about that but um
it's a you know when we're talking about
curing we're talking about microbiology
and it is so important I loved you know
that cool long dry cure is so helpful
for the stabilization of the
microbiology during that time and I and
I think that there's a really big role
in uh tpine preservation and
microbiology so it it's it's sort of a
an unknown it's another fractal
immersion yeah another fractal that we
have to look at changing the same I
couldn't agree more it's like and it's
also you tie the chemistry in right like
it at cooler temperatures most of those
aromatic plants have tricomes tricomes
are made out of waxes and fatty acids
which when they're colder are stronger
and hold the aromatics in better and
then when the sun's out you have the
heat hitting the molecules causing them
to turn into a gas and then it's gone
and I found this patent by the way it's
uh if you want the patent number
the the actual title is about moon
phases it's
um very interesting would you guys like
to look it up or do you care yeah yeah
put it in put it into the chat and I'll
also I'll put it into the comment
section I think you know getting into
the the microbi biology of the soil
leads perfectly into an introduction uh
with Peter and you know a bunch of us
have been going deep down the rabbit
hole on clubhouse the last couple of
days uh into all of these things that
we're talking about right now and this
is a perfect time to bring in the
microbiology so welcome Peter how are
you my friend cool Marcus thanks so much
for having me um it's uh great to be in
this room with all of you Minds you guys
uh just sitting here listening man the
the minds in here are beautiful and I'm
so just like humbled to be in the same
room as you guys and your industry
knowledge it's it's amazing I'm like a
listener you know in the audience just
blown away by by you guys so um but um
yeah Jeremy and Mojave and I have been
having some really interesting
conversations on clubhouse lately and
one of the things that I thought was
cool that we could bring up was the
concept of
saites which sapres are a type of
organism which are so important uh for
turpine production and canono production
um they're like you know the Frontline
workers of the uh of the work that needs
to be done in the rizosphere to actually
increase uh what's called Trace nutrient
absorption right so what we're what we
have found and I'll give you guys just a
little bit of background is uh in
2019 uh our group consulted for 162 uh
largescale hemp farmers and what we
found was that the trace nutrient
absorption your coppers your zinc your
your borons
were like the physics or or the
foundation of of the necessary
absorption in that risos spere to build
the different types of Tarpin within the
profile so it was uh seen by us that the
Growers that had a biologically active
system with a with a good amount of of
of sapric organisms and I I can go into
what those are a little bit more but
those
Farmers uh were getting like 25 types of
tpin in their profile and then the The
Growers that had maybe five types of of
good sapri organisms or I'm sorry um
that had low amounts of saprophytic
organisms were getting maybe five or six
types of tpin and they were all really
high so you'd have like four or five
spikes in the profile but then the
biologically active soil would have like
25 different types of tpin but they were
more balanced so you would have like 15
types that were all over like point one
versus you
know the the uh the soils that didn't
didn't have the sacrifice and so one of
the one of the things that I thought
would be cool to talk about today is the
um the uh the way that sapres can
actually help with powdery and dowy
M so this is this is just a cool concept
and it's just part of nature it's the
way that it that it works um and
so a sapry is a living organism right
and and to understand powdery and dowy
mildew what you kind of want to
understand is is maybe where it comes
from so in in the soil in all organic
material there's this there's this
little tiny ball it's called an O Spore
and it's like a little bowling ball it's
super small it's microscopic so you got
to take your mind and think really tiny
right now so this little o Spore is like
a bowling ball uh particle inside the
soil and inside of it lives this
organism called peronospora which is
another which is the scientific name for
Downey
Milo so no amount of chemicals like if
you hit it with methyl bromide or a
systemic fungicide or whatever is going
to destroy this little oo Spore so it's
very hard to to to
destroy and once you get the correct uh
physics and the and the correct uh
temperature and the correct um moisture
levels that little o Spore in the soil
it
cracks and out comes this this this
peronospora this dowy mildo and it
begins to just kind of colonize the
carbon in the soil right so what's
pretty cool is if you have an abundance
of these types of of bacteria and fungi
called called saprophytic organisms what
they'll do is they can actually grow on
all the carbon and then when that uh
that disease that soil born pathogen
begins to to colonize and and it has the
perfect environment it doesn't have any
space because there's all these these
good guys that are on all the rest of
the carbon that are basically like
having a party on there and they're
doing a really special form of work so
what happens is the bad you know the
path he's not a bad guy but he's a
pathogen who just wants to eat to
survive right and take and and and so
what this little guy uh does is he tries
to get into the party on the carbon and
there's no room for him to jump in there
so so biologically speaking he can't
gain traction he can't gain confidency
now normally what paranos would do is it
would actually colonize the carbon and
then it would actually colonize the the
root and there's another cool little
thing in in the soil it's a little worm
and sometimes those little worms called
nematodes can actually make holes in the
roots so now what happens is the
peronospora that came out of that little
bowling ball will actually go into the
plant's vascular system it'll Cruise in
through that hole and it'll and it'll
get into the glucose and the sugar and
it just has a a field B it's like oh man
there's all this food and delicious
stuff so now it's traveling through the
plant and guess what happens so in a in
a in a nutrient deficient plant uh
system what ends up happening is you get
this this like this area where there's a
lack of Trace nutrients so you don't
have your your boron your zincs your
coppers all these amazing you know um
minerals that the plant needs to to
Really you know produce its full genetic
expression and that's where the the the
peronospora will begin to eat and then
what happens is is it will colonize so
much that it gets on the top of the soil
um and and then like in a natural
environment a big wind comes or or a
droplet of rain comes and that can
spread it to the all the other plants
right so this is how this guy gains
traction and so what we do as Farmers as
Growers is we actually you know will
just figure out organic oils or
different things or hopefully um or
we'll hit it with something called a
systemic fungicide now systemic
fungicides go into the vascular system
of the plant and into our food so what
ends up happening is this this uh
chlorinated hydrocarbon just kills not
only the peronospora but it kills uh all
the beneficial bacteria that is so
crucial to tpine uh uh synthes enzyme
CBD THC synthes enzyme so so we got to
go back to the the the the the saites so
this is what's so cool about certain
saprophytic organisms so the definition
of a sapry is is a organism that eats
and digests carbon so think about like
like composting right when we're growing
growing organically the first thing that
any organic farmer does is he um
composts his soil for two to three years
to get that soil biologically to a point
of Competency that it can actually have
these natural um efficacies right so we
don't have enough compost to compost a
100 million Acres we just don't have the
resources the material but we do have
enough beneficial bacteria we do have
enough uh sapres in the form of fungi
which are also mushrooms right which is
a big a big trending thing right now
people are really connecting with with
mushrooms and starting to explore that
um which is fantastic it's it's it's
it's it's this it's this Unseen World of
life that is the defining factor in
quantifying quality and and producing
quality I should say so um so one of the
cool things about saites and then I'll
I'll shut up but uh the um the cool
thing about sapric is they have these
two main objectives right so one of the
first things that they do when they
first get into the soil which is which
is awesome is they will um begin to like
decompose old carbon so like a plant is
trying to place carbon into the soil
right with its roots so as a plant grows
it deposits its its roots in the form of
carbon into the soil and these
saprophytes will actually go on it and
they be begin to um to live in in the
symbiotic relationship with the root
exit dates that the plant is producing
in the form of sugars and carbohydrates
so think of it as like the root is
producing like a bead of sweat you know
it's like this it's it's like this
little bead of sweat and the sapres love
to eat sugars and carbohydrates you know
and so do my kids they they love the
donuts sometimes and I give it to them
you know we try by organic point of the
riseof fasi cycle that's the point of
the riseof fasy cycle where the Endo
fidic fungi and bacteria enter into the
roots and enter into the plants so it's
not just saprophytic fungi right the
whole entire totally nod factors
right I'm trying to just give it a give
it an overview for the audience to to to
give it kind of like there's so much
diversity right so much abely yeah and I
think that we can bring it back really
easily to understanding the mic
microbiome of the plant is really no
different than the human microbiome so
what we're feeding the soil is the same
as what we're feeding our human
digestive system so whenever we're out
of balance with say like an
oyes or some other type of a yeast uh
Leaf eeding mildew we have a yeast
infection the plant has a yeast
infection it's absolutely no different
than if our own microbiome is totally
out of balance with a tremendous amount
of yeast or or different types of of um
aggressive microorganisms that will eat
up our beneficial so having a really
well-rounded diet that has a lot you
know doesn't have sugars that isn't
feeding a lot of those yeast and mildew
is the same way that we need to look at
our soils so when our soils have a
tremendous amount of carbon then we are
actually drawing and and composting
carbon like Peter was just talking about
and satic fungi and sapric fungi then
we're also drawing a myriad of different
types of fungi which is a a huge
decomposing raw materials that's why
we're raw materials Farmers because you
can't stop goodness from coming in yeah
and I think that once you you have this
sort of balanced soil then you have a
that that beautiful clean
balanced
endid system the same as the microbiome
so it's high fungal soil is what you're
saying we're agreeing with you yeah and
as you're talking Peter it's awesome
because I'm always drawing which which I
always do as my background in human
health I'm always drawing the two to
human health and soil and plant and
human health and and how they're so
incredibly related what you so spot on
what you said so spot on I love
everything you're you're putting out so
yeah you guys are
amazing uh in what you're doing I'm I'm
so appreciative of your permaculture of
the way that you certify people like
it's beautiful I'm I'm humbled to be on
the same stage as you guys you guys are
that amazing to me like beautiful what
you're doing um true feel the Sameer I
love what you putting down it's so
incredibly important for people to be
able to get this information everyone on
this panel is amazing this panel today
has been awesome like totally
mind-blowing thank you guys so much
every single person on here I've smoked
so many bong hits sitting here just
blown away this has really re-sparked
something in me thank you so much bong
rip mother
lovers Peter if I may there's also one
thing that I think is a really important
implication of what you're bringing up
and what Josh and Kelly were just
emphasizing yes Jeremy right now we we
have this massive industry scaling with
Consultants around the world telling
people with money that the only reliable
production model is a mineral salt
program under HID lights with this one
siiz fits all crap one of the exciting
things that I have fought for for a long
time and I'm really proud of in Oregon
is that reality is I think that the
Organic Crop Production model finally we
can point to like the rale crop trials
has been more successful in out yielding
out consistent or more consistently
yielding and of course from all the
qualitative attributes performing as a
production model on the whole and
absolutely convinced it's because of
belonging to biology in an intentional
way participating with Biology
encouraging biology I can't pretend to
understand all of the biological
elements and in fact I think soil doctor
does some great talks about that where
you know we look at the various kind of
biological assays and the complexity of
being able to really understand those
Dynamics and it gets incredibly complex
it reminds me of Ryan's hairball earlier
but this notion that we can create the
conditions by which biology can flourish
and I'm so excited about whether it's
rise ofy or this kind of overall sort of
um Shield against like a bios Shield all
pathogen pressure I am convinced one of
the reasons that proof has only 6,500
square foot of canopy and many of the
other tier 2 folks are like 10,000 and
we're producing in most cases two to
three times the output it is simply
about working with Organic cultures and
that the organic cultures you know are
absolutely in addition to all those
qualitative attributes you mentioned so
eloquently Peter in my data I always
show more chemo diversity in a profile
and whereas when I contrast that to the
mineral salt products it's more chemo
intensity but it's a far less desirable
product I just I would never choose that
product if I have the options from a
sensory perspective from a physiological
perspective from a spiritual perspective
but yet we continue to see these scaled
Gardens moving forward without any of
this awareness so it's one of my
missions to be able to quantify and
characterize this sort of production
performance to simply be able to help
people who are not as amazing as all of
the humans on this panel uh who are new
and fearful of losing capital and
listening to the kind of prevailing
ethos of all the existing Consultants
that actually in fact obviously the only
way forward is to really create these
hyper biological systems and to tend
that with care anyways I so love every
it's been such a joy to communicate with
you over the last days by the way
well I think we could really easily just
ask the plant like if we bring the plant
into this conversation so often exactly
what you were just saying Jeremy is that
we're talking about mergers and wagers
and all of these different signed
documents and and Sops and IPS and
everything that's got a letter and
sometimes it's just so simple to pull up
a chair for the plant and ask her how
she would like to be grown ask her you
know how is it that that she would like
to to to have medicine Prevail inside of
humans on the planet in the relationship
that she would like to have with humans
and of course she's going to say that
she would love to grow outside under
polyculture in deep soil what plant
wouldn't want to say that and I think
that now that we get to actually match
that scientific testing with what the
plants ultimate you know wants would
want to be and in in growing out and
also speeding and onto the next
varietals and onto the next
Generations it's really going to be
amazing to match that science with what
we perceive a plant and what we perceive
that she would really like to be
involved in and even to see that Dynamic
happen indoors as well yes yeah that's
that's the trick well that's that's the
trick that's everything and that's what
you were speaking to Jeffrey is or
Jeremy is is how do we how do we
assimilate the two so many of the top
producers that I've been talking to
lately that are that are producing
cannabis in volume uh indoor you know
there's this huge separation between how
can we Implement Organics how can we
Implement a biologically active system
in a sterile environment right so
there's a whole business Dynamic around
this which is listen my investors don't
give a [ __ ] uh what the quality is right
now we're being purchased on output and
so dude if I if I bring some Organics in
here I'm going to [ __ ] up my whole grow
and I can't use it my my investors will
cut my cut my funding off and Joe's
saying yes on this so you know exactly
what I'm what I'm talking about so most
of my most of my Growers most of my
customers you know that are that are
cultivating conventionally um this is
the biggest this is the biggest
separation of state right now between
the two between
between redefining quality and and and
and and and and being able to actually
do that in a practical way yeah so
that's one of the things that we've done
with soil balance is we're trying to
work with with salt-based conventional
Growers primarily by incorporating Riso
bacteria that actually have a certain
mode of action and I want to tell you
guys this mode of action because it's
far out it's super interesting um and it
helps you just kind of see the
relationship that we're all talking
about here so eloquently um and I'll
keep it very simple so go just
digressing back to you know going back
into the soil and and feeling into you
know what's happening in there these
sapres so just think of them as these
tiny little microscopic you know
organisms right and they're growing and
they're living and they're feeding on
these roots now these sapres can be in
conventional operations they be in
Hydroponics they can be in soilless
mediums because they only like to live
on the on the roots of plants um compost
te is not going to necessarily do this
these these are not the type of Riso
bacteria there are going to be some in
there but a lot of the compost tees that
you'll find will have microbes from uh
you know crop residue or animal
intestines not necessarily the types of
strains that are going to grow on the
root comprehensively and proliferate
like crazy and that's what we need in
these sterile environments because what
what happens in the sterile en sterile
environments is people kill the kill the
microbes then they reinoculate them they
kill them they reinoculate them they
kill them they reinoculate all in the
Quest for higher tpine levels so just to
kind of break down how this works um
it's very simple so as these Riso
bacteria are living on the root in a
hydroponic setting right what they're
doing is they're eating the sugars and
carbohydrates that come out of the root
all plants create it as they eat these
sugars and
carbohydrates they they have to go to
the bathroom so they have to create a
waste product right scientifically a
microb waste
product is called a secondary metabolite
so this is the way that microbes
communicate just like how tpin or how
plants communicate um microbes
communicate by creating secondary
metabolites now a secondary metabolite
can be all kinds of things it could be a
chemical it could be an acid it could be
a you know a hormone an enzyme it could
be the saliva in your mouth it could be
the the liquid in your eyes those are
all secondary metabolites
so in in The Roots what we want is a is
a secondary metabolite that can be in an
acid base because what that's going to
do is it's going to micronize and
pulverize your salt-based nutrients so
as you're cultivating if you're actually
able to implement you know these
microorganisms they're going to break
down your calcium particle into a size
that the that the plant can actually
absorb and like I said if you can absorb
iron and copper and zinc those are the
the physics the building blocks that are
actually going to uh go into the turpine
production to create this very highlevel
um you know connoisseur s smell and and
variance where you've got all these
different notes and it seems like that's
where the industry is trending right
it's going not so much for the for the
THC but it's going towards the the the
the craft cultivators like a good IPA
and supporting that in our expansion
into the
future for sure and um I'd like to just
add that you know when we look at all
the different growing
techniques um because we have
Hydroponics indoors LEDs all that stuff
and it's like you know growing on a
spaceship it's cool that we can do that
right but like Kelly said the plants
perform by far the best when they're
actually in the soil that is connected
to the Earth not in a pot um and Under
the Sun and they actually perform better
Outdoors than in Greenhouse typically if
you could keep out the Environmental
other environmental factors like if you
could just remove the plastic and or or
poly and and have the the plant in the
sun in the soil getting the air from
Earth it's great it's true but for the
market in California that's not the case
the indoor is way better and it's way
tighter the buds are tighter um there
you know I I'm based I'm I'm sorry I'm
based in California and I would have to
humbly disagree now if you're talking
about I would Su at you Dr I'm in
California and that's not my experience
either here's the thing there's a big
difference I think so there's indoor and
outdoor right and everybody who's a
cultivator understands this and you
can't distinguish outdoor from indoor me
personally an outdoor flower grown in
soil with a tap rot you know I mean the
tap rot is everything and and and
growing with the son and growing with
with the with our mother yeah of course
like that's the way it should be grown
um 100% so I agree with you I'm I'm an
organic Regin ative agriculture
consultant I've been doing that for 20
years so I'm a soil dirt farmer um not
an not an indoor grower at all I don't
really know much about indoor grower
growing what I do know is what my
customers tell me um and what what
they're doing and to be able to you know
try and bring in the organic experience
that I have for 20 years into that type
of cultivation is something that's going
to hopefully change the the quality uh
of of the uh of the commodity so you you
know you mentioned your work with daddy
Milo I work with um Dr Jim Simon out of
ruter and helped them breed a Downey
mildew resistant basil because in the
early 2000s Downey Milo practically
wiped out the basil industry in South
America and North
America and one of the things that we
learn there is that outdoor plants grown
have um stronger cuticles taste more
like leafy green but if you grow them in
the greenhouse they're softer they're
more like uh more edible in general more
palatable um and what I was trying to
say about cannabis I didn't say if it
were outdoor I said if were if you could
remove the plastic off of a greenhouse
and remove all of the environmental
inputs like the wind the dust the
rain that product is far far better than
a product grown under lights it is
100% not comp correct and it's IND
distinguish I mean I'm GNA tell you
right now I know Growers that have been
growing in green houses for you know
decades and their products were always
indistinguishable from
indoors and they got sold as indoors so
when you look at quality it's about the
chemistry and the bag appeal it doesn't
doesn't really matter where it's
cultivated but if you want the best best
best product it's it's soil Sun hands
down from seed period cure exactly I I I
couldn't agree more Joe Joe really
wanted yeah I wanted to jump in yeah
because I I obviously there you're not
going to get a better expression of the
plant than full seed full sun in the
soil I think what Peter what you were
talking about is more like what's
commercially viable in our right and
that's just the case like I have right
now I have 266 cultivars right sitting
right next to me right here uh there's
personal use entry mix light entry full
sun grun full sungrown entry and there's
indoor uh these are from some of the
best growers in the whole world in the
Triangle uh the outdoor is far by far
distinguishable from the indoor you can
tell tell it apart anyone who looks as
many colds of bars um as we do Can it
can easily distinguish what's from
outdoor and indoor um it's really just
about what you're getting from the full
canono uh Spectrum from that full sun
and for us obviously you know looking at
all these entries they're going to have
a Best in Show from what goes up it's
going to be a sungrown plant that wins
um it's not always about the high THC
but with um you know craft cannabis by
definition not really being able to
scale with the cost of uh what it cost
to produce a plant and to have the um
batch sizes uh makes sense for the for
the farmers to to have some of these
higher-end um um strains you know they
they need um they need to have they need
to have a large bulk flower gr so you
lose a lot of that craft scale the
farmers that I work with who are working
more mixed light um they have the light
deps or they have some of the smaller
outdoor Farms they're getting much
better they just have more attention to
the plant the the harvesting they
actually take the time to harvest
they're not rushing to get to Market
because they have um you know investors
they have to get payb or they're not
having a distributor that's um
controlling it um and they maybe not
know how to house it and that kind of
ruins the flower so there's a lot
involved um with it what actually comes
to Market I think just the indoor with
the faster turnaround time what's how
it's marketed and what's more
commercially viable it sends those mixed
messages so uh you know I'm battling it
all the time and for the other people
that might be in the the the retailer
space it's either highend or lowend
there there's no middle anymore um you
know and most people don't understand
that some of the stuff that's on my
shelf that might be priced you know at
at a lower price brings just as much
medicinal value or better value than
some of those higher and indoor Str the
Cults of our so I think there's a lot
more involved with it than just you know
how it's grown yeah totally and and
getting back to you know getting back to
the essence um you know it all comes
down to costs really and affordability
and and the protection right the
integrated Pest Management so that's one
of the biggest things that I that I
think is important to recognize is that
um if we can really take our our time
and do and follow some of the things
that like dragonfly Earth medicine is
doing and really Implement try and
Implement a lot of those practices um
especially the the higher amounts of
biology in into any operation um whether
it be a you know your closet or a large
scale operation um really working to to
to find the right microorganisms and in
my opinion what are called saprof
is really the beginning um aspect of
just improving any environment because
um because they're the composters so so
we have to get the soil filled with the
right U layers of humus which is what
sapry create then you're going to have
bioavailable nutrients so the
conversation keeps coming back to
Quality and tpin and quality and tpin
and that's the future and the only way
to get quality inpin is is if you have
bio a ailable nutrients in a particle
size that the plant can absorb your
Trace nutrients that that's everything
for for triome density for triome
strength for for
um you know and both of those things
triome density and strength are
indicative of your biology they really
are you can see a much tighter like if
you measure a square centimeter of plant
tissue biologically grown and
conventionally grown in low biologically
active we have Quantified that you will
have three to 10 times in that square
centimeter of of of triome heads than
the
non-treated total oil production total
CBD and THC synthes enzyme production
has been um um bio enzymatically
stimulated so the plant's biosynthetic
Pathways have actually been stimulated
by these
microorganisms to to create more oil and
a more diverse uh flavor compounds
within that oil yeah isn't fundamentally
one of their one of their main roles is
is to fix nitrogen because the plant
doesn't fix nitrogen itself and these
things are the things that make soluble
nitrogen so the plant can make proteins
and peptides which all need to be made
those that's the Machinery that makes
the right here's a really crazy thing
about the industry Mark is that right
now what most microbial companies are
doing is they're focus on what a microb
can do on its own so they're like okay
this microbe solubilizes phosphorus or
this this makes nitrogen available or
this this does this right but what's
really important just like in strains
and cannabis and just like human beings
it's not necessarily what one microb
does but what they produce in
combination that make them truly
effective
so what we've been doing is studying
microbial combinations and the different
secondary metabolites they they produce
in in combination for 20 years and so
when you have a a a bunch of givers is
what I like to call them because there's
like these different kinds of organisms
in the soil there's there's the
microorganisms that live on the root
that they just give like a lot of
cannabis providers and Growers just like
us right these types of microbes are
going to give give give give give to the
plant to keep it alive because they
innately understand that their survival
and the survival of future Generations
their children is based on how much they
can give to the plant so it's almost
like they create this protective biome
around the plant to to care for their
children and to care for their planet to
care for future Generations right so now
there's the other types of
microorganisms and they're not bad
they're just a part of the natural
system and what they believe innately is
that if they don't eat they're going to
die so they will go and they will eat
your [ __ ] plant that you're trying to
grow that you're trying to take care of
so there's there's this there's this
system and what I'm talking about is if
you can get the good guys the guys that
are giving to your plant that are that
are breaking down nutrients that are
giving it all of this love and energy
and light and utilizing you know
that then when the bad guys come to the
par party and they want to smoke a bowl
you're like dude there's no room for you
guys get the [ __ ] out of here that
that's kind of how it is Peter you
mentioned
Rd that showed three to 10 times as much
uh triome heads per centimeter or
whatever well is that published and I
I'd love to post it in this room and I
I'd be happy to share it publicly sure
let me bring it up right
now I can facilitate uh getting it to
you as well from Peter Sam oh we we'd
all like to see it actually um because
we've been running studies like this
including time course analysis on
metabolite accumulation for well over a
decade in cannabis specifically and as
mentioned we work with basil and other
culinary herbs but um can't wait to see
that yeah there it is so if you if you
wanted to zoom in on it Marcus and
just I'll be honest I I I can't zoom in
on it anymore because I'm now on my
phone driving up to Whistler to catch
some powder I I couldn't give a past
church or powder today so uh I can't I
can't do that
man Peter I was wondering pet there's
been some connection oh sorry please no
I have a quick one which is did the THC
or Andor cannaboid levels of those
varieties increase Le three to 10 times
yes the the total oil production went up
accordingly uh to the plants uh genetic
predispositions so this was done on hemp
right yeah on 162 hemp farms and you
know we had University professors
overview it and study it and and it
showed the impact of what a highly
biologically active system can do in
cannabis cultivation for Quality so if
we're talking about yields as far as the
organic versus the the other guys um we
hit 5,000 pounds per the acre the
conventional Fields were hitting 3,000
pounds approximately so we had that as a
huge Advantage um we produced
approximately 30% more total oil
production than than the non-organic the
other thing is that we also Sam to
answer your question saw some really
unique things in the canono expression
so one of the things that we saw was
through the the biological mitigation of
stress induction on the plant in the
soil uh we saw um the the delta in in
it's interesting in the hemp plant we
saw Delta 9 actually levels
decrease
um and the CBD uh levels increased so
the cannabinoids increased the CBD but
then in medical marijuana we saw the
Delta 9 go through the roof so it was
just interesting how the biology just
give allows the plant to just achieve
its full genetic
Expressions um which was interesting so
the Delta 9 mitigation in hemp was
interesting because what
we concluded or hypothesized was that
the um the actual uh stress induced by a
lot of the plant parasitic nematodes or
the uh the health ISS ISU in the soil
weren't as present um so for instance in
heterogeneous soils especially
conventionally treated where they were
cultivating large scale cannabis they
ended up um you know just putting the
plant right into Old tobacco fields in
North Carolina and this particular plant
instead of like you know the cannabis
plant instead of when it got hit with
all these health issues this disease
instead of like the leaves curling up
and you seeing all the Sun L like you
would like a tomato plant um this plant
just said [ __ ] you I'm not going to give
you guys any oil so we got like 9% CBD
and the Delta 9 was through the roof
whereas once we mitigated a lot of those
stress inductions that were over the
limit of what it would be to trigger a
turpine reaction we ended up seeing um
uh really high cannaboid output like 21%
CBD and tpes that went up as high as 3%
in hemp which was pretty significant
what was the THC level in that
case so they usually went hot so it was
based on the genetics so the THC would
actually go up um based on the again the
the plant's genetic expression so
usually they would be up as if the
cannabinoids went up the T the THC went
up so so you you didn't see any
differential change in the relative
amounts the only difference we saw was
that the Delta 9 was lower in the
biologically active treated but the thca
was the same I want to throw in a
thought uh to kind of revisit what Kelly
was talking about earlier around the
needs of the plant one of the things
I've come to realize and believe is that
the genetics of the plant suggest what
it's going to produce but the
epigenetics the environment it's in and
how it's treated and how it grows is
going to have some a lot to do with how
much of that potential it
expresses and uh what I'm realizing or
feeling somehow is that um the the
cannabis plant itself because
of is producing this chemistry for its
needs to address its situation its place
in the garden or in industrial facility
that's it's in or whatever but the the
Cannabis chemistry is at least partially
shaped by the needs of the plant like I
think certain tpes might Express where a
plant is being attacked by pests and I
I'm just there's some Beautiful Minds in
this conversation I'd really love to
hear some thoughts on that point of view
of how does the how is that is that real
is it the plants needs that are actually
causing the expression of this chemistry
thank
you well I know that in the trials that
we so Neo oversees a lot of different
cultivations right and similar to
Peter's study um we look at same
genotypes across multiple environments
within the same identical environment I
mean our data set is definitely the
largest in the world for replicates of a
single genotype Andor seed hybrids over
the course of um the past 10 years and
the variations and experiments where
we've altered one thing at a time not
not like having an open field trial
where you have all these different
environments micro environments micro
micro environments but instead if you
know we're using the identical soil
across three rooms the rooms are
identical height width length and in one
room we use
conventional uh salt and every all the
other inputs all the other Pest
Management everything is the same the
other room we use convention ass assault
plus a bio stimulant or you you know
another amendment and generally the
trend is when you use the salts you have
higher cannaboid concentrations and
lower and less diverse turpenoid
concentrations and when you use more and
more um organic techniques you have uh
lower overall cannaboid production but
higher and more diverse more body in
your turpenoid production so on that
part we agree but the yields are
consistently lower uh with more and more
increasing organic uh contributions but
again you know you can only have so much
good and so much bad and you got to
weigh what you do and and like you were
asking about the tpes and pests you know
there's there's certain tpine profiles
that attract cannabis aphids certain
turpine profiles that attract the broad
Mite so it's it's very interesting
because it it's almost like those are
singing out to the bug saying hey come
on over here and they they go over there
and it's really really neat they're
attracting pollinators right I mean
isn't that the the reason why the the
tpine profiles are expressed in the plan
to begin with it's in in an evolutionary
sense is to attract pollinators and it's
is wind pollinated Mark well I'm sorry
well actually it's human pollinated and
it has attract the [ __ ] out of us
because I love the SM okay but I meant
before us
humans hey uh Mark I just wanted to
mention how funny that you work with Jim
Simon at Ruckers um I I also worked with
them on a completely different plant too
on on cat Min so oh yes yes yes the
tiger deterrent uh for well for the
insect repellent sorry but you don't
want it to attract the Tiger
as it turns out that's a um an effect
that's conserved throughout the feline
Kingdom so so yeah they they they have
the same I guess reaction to these
nepetalactone uh containing oils so and
you definitely don't want a mosquito
repellent that attracts the cat to come
play with you right yeah but again help
us postulate we've talked about this on
hash Church before you know why would
why would a plant like cat catnip is
just really variety that is again just
something that just intrigues me just in
terms of plant evolutionary biology is
it attracts cats and it actually it's
insect repellent but it attracts the uh
I I think a certain lace Wing so I think
there's a certain insect that it
actually attracts but it it repels most
but wh why would evolutionary biology
end up having such peculiar properties
for one
plant well lce swing is a beneficial it
goes after apids and all kinds of other
pest right right so it attracts actually
a good a good insect but I don't get the
cat connection that's what I'm trying to
figure
out what I don't have any Notions there
but there's an interesting thing that
I've observed in canopies we've talked
about sort of chemistry calling in sort
of other allies or adversaries but I
think about one of the most interesting
things was when I started getting a lot
of terpinolene dominant varieties into
mixed cultivar rooms suddenly varieties
that had no terpinolene expression began
to have low-level terpinolene presence
and even uptick over time I'm fascinated
about VOC signaling above ground as well
as root exudates and the fact that you
can co-mingle varieties and clearly have
an impact I even wonder then could you
take and I've never done any of this
work but you know a certain distilled
turpine say lemoning and have that same
sort of impact without even the plant
present but that that conversation
that's happening in voc's is something
we're starting to measure there's these
high density sensor networks that are
these little bluetooth enabled devices
that pick up the VPD and CO2 and ppfd
but now they're adding voc's to them and
every three feet in the canopy at two to
three layers you're able to really get
this comprehensive view it'll be very
very interesting to then correlate some
of the aromatic expression in the choar
or in the chemotypes within what we
observe in the highdensity sensor
Network just trying to observe and
listen to in a way that we can
analytically quantify that dialogue I
there's another thread that I think is
so important that Josh asked earlier and
that has been kind of floating around a
little bit that I just think for folks
who might tune in and who are looking to
sort of some information about how do
you once you've harvested all of these
incredible aromatic compounds get that
to the patient to the consumer in a
meaningful way I what I see universally
in the Oregon and California market and
I I do mean a vast majority of all of
the flower that I'm seeing is what the
Hops Growers would call spoiled flower
and hops when I interact with the team
at yaka Chief hops a lot they they
Define a spoiled hops a variety as
something that has lost more than 50% of
the aromatic contribution that was
analyzed at the beginning and then they
have really incredible time trials where
they pack at zero degrees and myar with
noble gases and are able to extend the
longevity of the profile that was there
at the beginning it's fascinating
contrasting preserving the original
expression as opposed to the distinct
effects of uh curing and all of the kind
of Transformations that can occur I I
think there's a bit of a tension between
those two different goals but in any
case I think a vast majority of all of
the flour that is being served at retail
dispensaries is currently what we should
Define as spoiled and there are a
variety of practical strategies that I
think can be put into place to really
preserve freshness and that we have a
freshness crisis as especially scaled
options came and people stopped putting
love into that postprocess and a few of
the observations I've had is essentially
if we're packing at about 10% moisture
and we are able to uh alleviate that
8% water activity Mark pretty rapidly in
drawing as Dr Allison Justice actually
if anybody's not aware of Allison's work
she's one of the only people I've heard
of who's really done some strong
analytics looking at postprocess and
she's lecturing about this in a few
different podcasts she's easy to find
but the basic gist is that if you can
hit 8% water activity buritis cannot
form you're not going to have fungal
pathogens so typically she's advocating
more that aggressive dry for the first
48 hours to just simply be able to
attain that of course that point8
doesn't remain static over time it does
sort of obviously the exterior of the
flow is going to lose moisture first and
things will equilibrate as they're in a
sort of drying room together over time
or they're packed together so there's
ongoing monitoring that's needed but if
you can hit that and then really slow
and low kind of carry it as as far as
possible without being concerned about
the fungal issues which in Oregon I mean
easily the greatest loss of crop value
is related to Bettis and everything we
can do to prevent that loss is is just a
tremendous means of staying afloat and
it's very very important so I think that
is one of the most important pieces but
then in terms of packing I do think it's
fascinating when I was in a wholesale
buying trip for this company that had
helped uh hired me to get wholesale
flour for them which ESS I was able to
secure a lot of exclusively
regeneratively grown produce from people
like Tina moonmaid and all kinds of our
peers in Northern California last year
um what I saw almost universally was
that it was all packed in Turkey bags
and that we still are using porous
membranes to hold in this incredible
sensuous Aroma and of course are losing
a lot of that Aroma as a result but then
there's this issue with myar where now
do we want another massive waste stream
like the gram containers and the
pre-roll containers that literally are
littering the streets of Portland
anywhere you go it is an absolute you
know eyesore [ __ ] that has to get
solved but the so obviously glass as
Josh is lifting up is like the Fantastic
solution and I love even I don't know
how many people are using this sort of
fermentation equipment where you can
pump oxygen out of glass there's a lid
that attaches to any normal sort of
glass jar and then like a wine preserver
you sort of pump out the oxygen
and then with removing that oxidative
stress and bringing that into
potentially a refrigerated environment
but being able to just extend the
longevity of that Aroma intensity I
think is one of these giant qaqc pieces
one more tiny riff here is that I think
that sensory science has been coming up
a lot in the clubhouse conversations
recently and that one of the fascinating
things is here we may be um according to
the Hops people overweighting the
importance of the Analytics obviously
the analytics are unbelievably important
it's just that from a product quality
perspective and the average patient and
consumer perspective it's so much more
about sort of the experience of of that
product and the fact is there's really
amazing technical ways to do
sophisticated sensory evaluation that I
do not see generally happening in our
space I see individuals practicing that
but there's a woman named Lauren salzar
who's at new Belgian Brewery for 10
years who built this really robust
sensory science program that now has
gone out to all kinds of other breweries
she's just recently started working in
cannabis and she has some fantastic
podcasts this notion of in order to move
from more subjective perception of
effects into a more objective evaluation
of sensory using the human old factory
which I mean we could say that we could
detect up to a trillion potential Aromas
but really let's just go into the
infinite with numbers we can't quantify
or characterize it's and that we don't
even have language or will ever have
language to describe the Nuance of that
kind of vastness but we can take panels
of people who are highly trained to
identify their own anosmia which are the
things we can't smell well or at all and
essentially through a diverse group over
time get pretty consistent results and
talk about that in a lot of ways I feel
like this is one of the things that
challenges the hegemony of purchasing
high THC product to open the door to all
of the modern potency poetic incredible
expressions of the plant that I think
she genuinely wants to be in the world
because I keep finding some of the most
Aroma intense profiles beneath 20% THC
and that ultimately is like just a
really valuable experience to be
cherished but literally can't exist in
the wholesale Market I can't sell that
product I can't grow that product I will
lose every dime that I put into that
product which is absolutely horrifying
to me that if we have an educated
sensory approach that then we'll have a
lot more uptake there so one last bit is
that the cultivation classic has data
over the last couple of years that Dr ad
Ray Jeremy sacket and myself will be
coming forward with shortly that looks
at that population Dynamic that's I've
already described that one of the cool
findings was that aoma intensity when
blinded and randomized was by far the
most important qualitative attribute in
cannabis um when blinded and randomized
seven out of 10 people would always
choose varieties that were under 20% THC
that is exactly the inverse of what's
happening in wholesale and now in the
new scaling production environment so I
just want to pay an homage to all the
sensory scientists and the people who
are working to describe in a pretty
objective fashion that element and then
that to counterbalance the amazing
analytic work to ultimately open the
door to more product diversity more
product enjoyment a deeper connection to
the diversity of the product and not
just get stuck in Fruit floral fuel or
sort of like massive archetypal sort of
descriptions and missing all of this
Nuance especially that's coming out of
the organically grown products which I
consistently experience as exactly as
Mark described uh slightly less
cannabinoids potentially although I
routinely I'm getting up to 34% total
canabo in many varieties that we're
cultivating but in general lower but
more diverse more sensuous more present
more evocative few thoughts there yeah
man
when you talk like that Jeremy that
you're just really in total um alignment
with what exactly what I was saying
before with if we're rolling up a chair
for the plant and we're asking the plant
what is it that she would like to come
out with it is you know quantifying in
all of those different expressions and
in that same way we find that full
expression when we put her in deep soil
when we put her out in the sun she is
able to have those full natural
Expressions because her ultimate
potential is fully ripe at the full
expression during fall when we have all
of the microb biome in full expression
yeah all of these things then fall into
full Harmony and holistic expression of
the plant and I think that that's really
important with with what you're talking
about and really quickly when you were
saying about drying that is also you
know what we are following here on the
farm but it's also what's happening in a
natural expression when you let your
plants go to full fruition there's a lot
of moisture in the air during the fall
time and then when you bring it into a
5050 or a 6060 you are going to get that
quick dry and then that prolonged sort
of balanced expression of a good cure so
thank you for uh talking about that I
think it's not natur Al happening as
well and Dr Lewis you can say something
on this too in a sec I was just
wondering that the the tpin are higher
in the organic you know or the
regenerative Gran and maybe the
cannaboids are lower but do the tpin
make the cannabinoids more powerful I
mean I I would think Ethan Russo or
someone would also well you said
remember our analysis were with the same
genotypes when I make that assertion
that lower canono in general and higher
and more more robust terpenoids in
general that's comparing the same plant
to each other in the two different
environments I want to make sure to
distinct that it's not in overall
because if you have you know something
that naturally produces 30% canabo it's
still going to get almost 30% canabo
it's just going to be in general a
little bit lower and their tpine
profiles will be a little bit higher and
one thing that we didn't talk about with
respect to you know pres preservation of
tpine profile is genetics has a
contribution to how a plant cures one of
the biggest problems that we experienced
in the early days of breeding the
enhanced flowers which that contain the
CBD is that they'd turn gold really fast
like it it was you know so we were we
tried to get the you know TOA forall
content up to preserve that shelf life
so they stay a little bit Greener and
and brighter and more poppy but also
some things if you store them uh they'll
turn they'll kind of start smelling like
wine or you know kind of kind of smell
old really fast while other things
preserve really well and overall the
best way to preserve anything is as soon
as it's dried to just freeze it and then
you pull it out of the freezer a year
later it's still going to smell fresh
and gassy like an OG um but you have to
have it sealed properly or else it can
collect water moisture and all those
different things and don't open the
freezer a whole lot all that kind of
stuff so
well it helps to displace the oxygen
doesn't it
Mark it does but it depends on the size
of your container and the amount of free
space because if you have a really large
container that's really full to the rim
and you don't have a whole lot of oxygen
it's not going to get harmed a whole
bunch or if you pull out that oxygen
it's going to obviously preserve better
right and you know we've done studies
where you know we use nitrogen or argon
to you know displace the oxygen but
really if it's stored properly the
differences are relatively insignificant
it's actually you see in our experience
you see more changes in the
TCA uh to THC conversion than you do in
the tpine nose if you store it properly
of course well I I know that in the not
that it's related but in the potato chip
um industry they've they've switched to
now blowing up those potato chip bags
with nitrogen because what they find is
that the nitrogen does blanket you know
the the uh I guess the polyunsaturates
in potato chips that would degrade and
create you know oxidative degradated
smells and other aldah and other [ __ ]
like that I'm sure it would be the same
thing with canvas maybe much to a much
lesser extent than say potato chips
right well think about a potato chip
it's like the maximum surface area
possible right so and you think about a
bud it's it's all compact typically and
most of the flavor and compounds are
protected by the triome and the cuticle
so you have a couple layers of
protection there and and actually that's
that's one of the things that we did for
a client about eight years ago is
started uh they started using different
um the sorbent bags that like you know
nuts come in and stuff and they would
blow them up and only fill them up about
halfway so that you couldn't you could
not squeeze it to crush the bud you know
whereas with turkey bags they spin them
all down and pull them tight and smash
them into duffel bags or whatever and
that really helped with preserving the
uh Aroma as well because you weren't
destroying the physical structure that
encased the aroma and and the molecules
it's funny you bring up the nitrogen we
actually switched to nitrogen sealed
packaging about three years ago with our
Collective um it changed the game
completely for us and for me as a buyer
um you know we went from housing
probably 15 to 20 cultivars to at 1
point4 regulation I think we had 108
cultivars on the Shelf um how long are
you how long are you storing those
packages so the things that you're
putting under nitrogen how long are they
in storage for before they're opened up
again and are they at room temperature
sure no yeah so we keep those uh we keep
those in a temperature controlled Vault
um obviously just to help with retention
there we've seen and we've done studies
I mean I've opened cans that were two
years old and still had a crazy nose and
um you know we're we're out of this
world it took a long time to um gain the
consumer trust because they're used to
opening and seeing and being able to
look at that but for us as far as being
able to um create consistency for the
consumer as far as being able to
purchase enough to have it be stable on
the Shelf um and also um add variety it
is was game changer for us um you know
it allows me to buy more um and and also
we can house it a little longer and and
we've seen you know um retention there
with the tpin it's kind of out of this
world it's it's sealed you know and with
the jars you see with glass and anything
else it's still dis dissipating oxygen
they're not completely sealed and so uh
it's a ticking time bomb and we all know
how hard supply chain is um on the
retail side most times when I see
something that is a sample um I feel so
bad for the farmer Because by the time
it's to me uh like Dr Le was saying it's
either um oxidized to a point where
maybe it's gold there um those tpin
start to change to like narid dool and
some of the other ones that are a little
less appealing um so it's um it's a race
against the clock the whole time for the
tpin um luckily for us uh we have a
situation where we're a little more
vertically integrated I'm allowed to
work with the farmer directly um we have
our own distribution that packages one
door down from the retail so once you
know um you know really just having the
Sops in place to make sure that um you
know your your dryness levels the
moisture the humidity everything in the
room when your packaging is ideal um it
all takes place and making sure that you
can retain that
tpine
yeah oh sorry I was just gonna say
something totally obvious is uh you know
bridging that communication from the
farmer to the packager to the final you
know person that's going to sell it even
the bud tenders because what what you
just said Mark about you know different
variet have different needs and how we
want to preserve them and as Growers we
really understand that we know that you
know certain open varietals might be
drying faster they need to be more
upfront and that's something that we
could really pass on that information
all the way to the bud tender so that
they even know how to touch it in the
very end so I I know this is really
obvious but I love it that we're even
having little drips of conversations
here of having that bridging
communication all the way back to the
farmer because I think we really have an
understanding of all those different
varietals from a different view from the
packager and the distributor of them so
I love this I I love Kelly we were just
on the same wavelength I I was just
thinking the other part of the
connection is when consumers and
patients are going to retail and saying
gosh if you have that big jar of flour
with all of the breakage on the bottom
under lights and you're taking more than
a week to go through that inventory this
is disrespectful to the farmer to the
plants to the whole equation and that
there needs to be some reconciliation
around how even that last point in the
chain works I know at Pharma I created a
Russian nesting doll strategy where it
had to be a series of progressively
smaller containers all to the point
where never would we expose the flower
to the environment if it wasn't an
amount we were going to go through in
that day and interestingly I don't know
if everybody knows but Oregon is
actually the only sort of deli style
Market where we don't have forced pre
packaging which was a battle that I won
at the OLCC roeming advisory committee
there was many I lost but I did get that
unfortunately in the pandemic that's
kind of out the window but the idea that
you can connect people to Aroma and
actually View and connect with the
product is a really important part of I
think the selection process but back to
uh I think the Russian nesting doll
strategy is one Element another thing
that we've tried I've ordered pickle
jars off of sort of like Alibaba that
are stainless steel that have clasps
that can fit a half pound and enough
room to then we've used a mixed gas I
was in Chile working with my friend
Pablo Mendes at diam three years ago and
they had some really interesting food
scientists and Mark or Dr Lewis I don't
know if um you might know more but their
strategy was to have an 8020 80%
nitrogen 20% CO2 and they claimed that
that addition of the CO2 actually helped
to suppress fungal pathogen over time
and that there was a lot of food packing
that was using that solution in South
America so we just adopted that I
haven't seen a lot of data to support or
substantiate that but then I like this
idea of packing small increments we
wanted to create a reuse program and buy
these containers and then have a
sanitation process where we would drop
only in 228 gram increments all so like
mountain of these like containers into
the retails and then request those
containers back unfortunately it was
literally I kept running into compliance
issues and the sanitation issue was a
big cost in terms of getting the kind of
equipment that you need to clean that
it's just that we're really in this
conundrum right now with packaging and
thankfully actually one other little
highlight is that in the last year for
the first time uh if you're aware of
sauna packaging there's a few people who
are working with like you know
compostable packaging with uh recycled
ocean plastic with 100% postc consumer
stuff and you know it's there's at least
some options that just in the last year
are now cost effective maybe it's only
like 2x the cost of the Dube tube that
is the crap that fills the landfill but
as companies are starting to feel
pressure from consumers that are
informed my hope would be that nobody is
going to be able to make a bottomline
decision with regard to this
unbelievable waste stream that the
industry has just created um
I think what you're you're illustrating
is something you know me on the East
Coast it's it's we don't have this this
luxury of deli style or the badega style
um you know experience so to speak it's
it is a cpg world so we have to look at
the supply chain and then we have we
have ratios of medical versus wreck that
we have to keep at all times and it just
forces us in a regulatory way to have to
to to package you know we chose to go
with glass I chose with you know to
induction seal and to try to do the best
that I could but I don't you know like
you're illustrating we just we have so
many things we have to look at what is
enough to package how many batches do we
really go through a day do we really
need to have all this packaged up um you
know all really valid questions and I
think you know for myself it's it's
really hard because I see a totally
different product behind the scenes that
I see my customer walk away with and
it's just a really hard thing to go
through because yeah we're we're we're
essentially packaging up you know dying
flowers you know things that are
changing composition as it's sitting
there right before our eyes so it's it's
a really tough tough thing you know I'm
always looking at new containers like I
have this caly container here while I
really love where their heads at I want
to see it glass you know like it's got a
seal and has this I idea where you can
you know snap it shut so you know we
have our our CR right here so it's
there's a lot of people thinking about
this but I think we just you know we've
got to keep pushing to get glass we've
got to get keep pushing to get reusables
here we go nice so yeah so if yeah and
what you're talking about um Jeremy is
amazing I use those in the lab for any
oil that I've made it's like immediately
I'll do that to preserve to try to try
to um then put that in refrigeration or
a a you know refriger a freezer if you
will so I think we're in this conundrum
right now where we have this amazing
behind the scenes uh efforts happening
that are then like you're illustrating
Jeremy just quite simply being uh being
not uh represented at at a at a retail
level so it's it's really heartbreaking
in some respect and I know I go through
that with my hash all the time
where it's you know I can only do so
much it's a cold chain item you know
yeah it's a huge conundrum because we as
the consumer level we see more people
just putting things in a jar whereas the
jar is this big and the products this
big so you're left with an overabundance
of you know decomposition due to the
oxygen then that's left in there and how
few and I think Joe can probably attest
this is how few people are actually
doing any type of nitrogen spiking or
that 8020 that you were talking about
Jeremy which I think is is very
fascinating because some people were
playing early on with nitrogen and they
were concerned of degradation and there
was some degradation depending on ratio
so uh I love the concept of the 8020 but
again still the consumer in California
majority of what they get is very dry
very
unfortunately over oxygenated product so
that they don't get an actual
representation really depending on when
that comes to Market of what that flower
expression fully is and that's a shame
you're 100% correct it's um it is a
shame I mean you just think about the
supply chain and how many cooks are in
the kitchen right you have you have to
bring it into from the you know the
cultivator to distribution then
depending on the distributor's Sops and
how they handle the flower then you have
to schedule it with the lab then you
have to wait for the lab to come then
the lab touches the flower then it goes
back into quarantine then it comes out
of quarantine so you're getting touched
and moved over from different climates
and different areas throughout the whole
entire process and unfortunately not
everyone um as as a good fortune as we
are to have been vertically integrated
you know there's a lot of people that
just don't have that and so being able
to tell that story um like you guys were
talking about earlier of the plant and
of the cultivators you know it's really
about establishing those relationships
and and really trying to um get that
flower to Market where you're really
giving it the true representation of
what that plant's supposed to be um it
is frustrating especially with taxes uh
in the state to see these eights go out
the door where yeah they half the jar
three a quarter of the jar is full you
have all the air in there you have the
tax you open it up and it's uh it's gone
it's dry it's dust you can't even roll a
joint and so yeah it's a shame um I
don't think a lot of The Growers who are
just getting purchased out they don't
even get they they don't see what their
flower looks like on the end result and
uh so really it's just that battle
against the clock on top of that it's
you know and I think this is a terrible
Injustice you know there's four
universities here in the United States
that teach packaging and one's here at
San Jose State University and so they
actually have a nitrogen infusing
machine right there in the classroom
just to show them how they actually do
coffee and we were discussing that
literally a decade ago on infusing that
with cannabis so I mean there's four
universities here people so if you
contact San Jose State University they
have over a thousand students that
actually have that are in the market
right now they can find your properly
biodegradable or secondary use uh un
recycled products it's just it's going
to cost more thenan that's the reality
but the consumer has shown that they
will pay more if they know a product is
quality and sound and even packaged in
quality so there needs to be an
education so that more manufacturers and
Distributors actually make that
investment so that the consumers can
benefit from it otherwise we're left
with tons of trash and not including
cartridges well etan alsoo I appreciate
one of the things you just brought up
was that the negative Impressions on
nitrogen packed cannabis in the Oregon
early wreck Market we saw these
survivalist tins that had packed eights
and there was like some big IP deal
where you had to pay a lot of money to
use that technology but bottom line is I
think one of the issues that we saw was
people simply weren't measuring moisture
with like a moisture analyzer or getting
consistently correct 10% and if they
were packing just a little bit over
moist then you we seal it you or unseal
it you get this moment of you've got the
nose but then the product is crap and we
saw a lot of bad brand Impressions
exactly but now that we're getting the
moisture really on point and packing in
that way I am seeing absolutely benefit
from suppressing that oxidative Force
there's one other quick trial I just
wanted to mention that's happening right
now that I think is fascinating Ethan
has been coming down to proof and we're
doing this trial on a sort of folk cryo
it's very much this is a little bit of
an aside but I think very related it's
all about preserving these attributes
that we see at the production then
hopefully getting it all the way to the
end point uh essentially he's made a
freezer that is a chest freezer or
excuse me it's like a cooler that we
have dry ice on the bottom a metal
vessel we put the flower on on top of
that's conductive and then a metal tray
on top with dry ice above it then the
cooler has a spigot and the spigot is
left open and it creates a convection
and it is like a very cheap way to get
to a lyophilization like process we took
fresh harvested plants we immediately
put the fresh harvested plants in the
cryo chamber then we did a very brief
dry of the fresh material then put that
into a mechanical separator we have lab
results from light scale Labs uh for the
flower before it was keed the flower uh
after it was keed and the KE we did that
process and now we're contrasting it in
the second wave with my my typical like
technical drying process and we're doing
the exact same sort of three points of
data the first thing that we saw was a
low yield of course because we actually
did it too short of a dry and didn't
have a very hashy plant and there was a
few variables there but what we saw was
remark
the exact tpes that were in the flower
at the same ratios were in the cryoe and
even when I'm running normal Keith
process I do not see that I see
variation uh whether we're seeing
degradation of monot Turpin or other
elements that just seem to have moved
around we were able with a freshly
harvested plant to really really secure
that and I do think hash is one of the
ANS like the most ancient answer to that
preservation of this product that
creates a shelf stability with this like
incredible rind and there's this wisdom
in that process that I still feel is
very underrepresented in this freshness
conversation but I really love flower
and I want people to see the flower as
we do these unbelievable passionate
massive expressions and I think we have
some ways to
go yeah well if you think back you know
10 15 years ago when you walked into a a
health food store all the essential
fatty acids and the
probiotics were still just sitting on
the
shelf and you know like my my old Co-op
they didn't keep it so cold in there you
know because they were running on a
budget it wasn't like going to Vans but
then over time we all started to demand
that you know our probiotics and
essential fatty acids needed to be
refrigerated and if and then you saw for
a while they had some of them still on
the shelf and then some manufacturers
who were really adamant that this
product has to stay in the coal chain
all the way through manufact in shipping
and then eventually retail and then we
you know as consumers we started we got
more educated and then we only bought
the probiotics that were in the
refrigerated section you know and
obviously to there's some that are more
shelf stable and some that are more you
know dependent on temperature and all
that so yeah it's really about the the
cold chain you know I was talking to a
cultivator the other day um about some
products that they had me sample and you
know I was trying to be polite and just
the turps were a little low and I was
asking him about why his trips were a
little low and I looked at the COA and
the water activity level was very low
and he said straight out he said look I
can't control what happens when when
this flower leaves my farm and we've had
big issues with mold and sometimes it
sits through the manufacturer I mean in
the distribution then it sits at the lab
by the time it's tested we don't really
know what they're testing so to mitigate
that they they bring the water activity
low below 50% which is you know at
serious risk for turpine loss obviously
depending on your your your profile but
that's their fear they're just like look
like you said Jeremy the biggest one of
the biggest losses for for um Farmers is
is failure on testing so I was also
wondering you know it's anyone heard
anyone using oxygen absorbers in their
packaging I never see oxygen absorbers
in cannabis nearly as much as I do in
other food products I am move I've I've
been deploying these food grade oxygen
absor
there's an issue where if you have too
much of course they get hot they're
creating heat in a small environment
it's a nominal amount of heat I'm not
overly concerned but that's the primary
consideration I typically I my ideal
process was the rigid lightproof
container airtite um packed by hand then
filled topped off with gas not a
scientific process for nitrogen sealing
just simply literally uh running the the
gas for a count and then uh packing with
about two oxygen absorbers per 228 grams
that's been essentially where I've seen
the best uh sort of shelf stability of
some of the more nuanced profiles one
tiny thing moav you missed this part
about terpinolene there was this whole
riff in the beginning that was so like
part of your soul and one of the things
I think about that's fascinating in My
Vault when I have astral Works which is
a terpinolene dominant type two it's
been there like we couldn't sell it when
we were first growing it because people
would not buy a 6% THC profile but it
lasted in the vault for two years two
years later it's still the terpinolene
was so remarkably stable it was a bright
foral intense note that I mean it was in
a temperature controlled situation like
that but there's no other product I have
that had that longevity or rather any
other profile that I've seen that has
had that kind of longevity it's a
fascinating thing that it's so I I wish
Dr uh Lewis had not I left because I am
fascinated about that stability and I
don't know if even uh Mark might have
information yeah so so so maybe it's a
sacrificial scavenger like maybe it it
scavenges oxygen with time and so if
there is any uh infiltration of oxygen
into the packaging the high terpinolene
content would react with that remember
that I yeah what we were saying earlier
Jeremy and I don't know if uh Mark kind
of picked up on the question which was
that um terpinolene if it oxidizes makes
terpenol and and depending on where
those double bonds are in the molecule
because these are all isomers of of
lyine right and and and so when these
are made in the plant you're kind of in
some
thermodynamic well which is that okay
you get a little bit of limine you get a
little bit of terpinolene but I I think
terpinolene oxidizes on curing to
penol and you know again I don't have
any data to support that but you you
just look at the structure and you say
Well it wants to be an aromatic ring now
Pine is the completely aromatic ring
with a methyl group on one side and an
isopropyl group on the other but when
you have two double bonds like you do in
terpinolene that wants to do chemistry
and it wants to do chemistry with oxygen
and if it does chemistry with oxygen I
think it makes turpine null so it'd be
interesting to look in that sample and
see if you see a little bit of TP your
tpol Spike going up I want to measure
that I will do exactly as you've said
one question is I've never smelled a
standard of terpenol only
terpinolene isolated have you smelled
that and would you describe them as
relatively pretty tight or one's a
little more kind of like I guess I would
call it less fuy and more nutty I I
nutty isn't isn't the right word it's
just it's got kind of like a a cinnamon
more like a Caraway but less like a
cinnamon but I spicy wouldn't you
wouldn't you say I I have some
degraded
funny this is it gets
rounder spicy and round yeah this is
exactly what we were trying to talk
about in the room the other day in
clubhouse and we just we diverted to
well tpin are aign unto themselves you
can't put words let me grab some
actually I have some degraded turpion
let me I'll be right back so you can't
necessarily put a word to it so again
like when I think about like so so turpy
turpy n is less gassy more nutty uh
terpinolene to me anyway smells gassy
smells like and and I can't really smell
the difference between it and some of
the other monot Turpin certainly lyine
smells completely different but limine
is is very shallow Citrus where venine
that other um cesa turpine we were
talking about the other day has a much
more Fuller bodied orange kind of you
know bottom note to it um one's the
Contra bassoon and the other's the
piccolo flute you know what I mean in
the
orchestra so they just have different
frequencies as well as the different
volume and I think what was really
interesting in in those graphs that Mark
was showing earlier is that one osam
dominant thing you know osine is very is
like it's kind of like merine it's very
fleeting it it's going to evaporate and
depending on again how well that stuff
is cured how well the the uh the the
butt is grown to begin with you might
see that Peak go go up and down quite a
bit so mark it really
it's quite it has this like mint this is
from Jack
herrer this is very it has a mint kind
of vibe to it and it's very round like
it just has this like
soft mint and then you can kind of like
just kind of barely smell the the Jackie
trinoline uh sharpness in there on the
very touch end of it really back end of
it though yeah not nearly as bright as
as
it's really odd I mean
it's yeah but it's so you're smelling
cannabis derived tpin not the pure ones
right yeah just cannabis drive so
there's more going on here right but
it's a dominant right it's a whole
different b as soon as you combine them
with other right it's a whole different
thing right right still beautiful it's
so it's so like no I'm not saying it's
not beautiful I bet you it's much better
than smelling the monot Turpin but the
monot Turpin are overpowering and they
don't really have the full
bodess that that a cannabis profile of
tpin would have so Mark I was I was
looking at beta aamine and Alpha aamine
do do you know the distinct differences
between the effects of those two um
because I really haven't really found
any
definitive no and I think what's even
crazy with anything definitive about it
I I I don't know this for but aren't
those two forms of osine
interconvertible yes they are yeah so
it's like one's a cyst and the other
one's a trans double bond and if you
stare at them crossey they kind of
interconvert so yeah Mother Nature you
know playing with their Tinker Toys yeah
I mean you could really you know move
the atoms around and make different
molecules and it's just it's so crazy
again how sophisticated are old faction
response is in being able to detect
slight differences in say you know those
those molecules in these in these
fragrant mixtures Mother Nature playing
with her Tinker Toys that is the best
thing I got out of this whole thing
today it's about time I did something
useful no I I think the discussion with
Mark was just great Marcus so thank you
so much for getting him on and and
Mojave it's great to have you on here we
need to have you on here more often you
know our uh that um Clubhouse app is
just
we're it's just off the hook right I
mean we get a certain critical mass of
people in a room and before you know it
it's just like yeah a bunch of stone
people talking about our favorite
subject how long could that go on right
our spouses don't like it at all they
think there's a hash church that happens
every night
yeah exactly true
story no where it's like uh it's like
some serious uh building the new
religion of cannabis it's all coming
together the big that the disciples are
all Gathering and it's get it gets a
little
hot in a good way it's powerful yeah
that's a good way of putting it um my
young son will you know he'll be like
Dad is it has church
again freaking canaban nerds and they're
[ __ ] wanting to know everything about
pot gez I cannot believe this shame on
you all I I I could say though with a
with a fondness Marcus that my wife
knows the tone of your
voice and just can hear like down the
hall and says oh yeah yeah marks on hash
church I could hear bubble man talking
it's kind of like your your voice has
been uh a very welcome vibration in my
house household for many years now oh we
give thanks brother right back at you
all of you guys uh you know super amazed
and stoked for the conversation today
and how deep it went I felt bad that we
were so deep in it we weren't sort of
able to say goodbye to those who had to
drop off so we Ryan Lee and Joe Sullivan
and uh we had uh why am I spacing Dr
Mark Lewis um and and anyone else that's
no longer in the room I'm on my phone
now and I'm not uh able to really touch
it so I can't see who's in the room and
who's not in the room but uh great great
episode guys thank else yeah thank you
Marcus and all of us and yeah it would
be nice to uh do more of these uh and I
suppose Clubhouse is the platform for
the moment yeah Peter thanks for sharing
that manuscript too I'm really enjoying
I'm reading that and and at the same
time it's it's so fascinating to read so
thank you for that can we share that
like can I upload that like to like the
hash Church um Facebook page or
something I think I could share a PDF
there totally man that'd be an honor
that'd be really
awesome yeah it looks really cool I mean
I I think as more studies like this come
out I think they're really going to see
the power to regenerative growing right
I mean when it actually makes a yield
imp
and people can understand the economic
impact that it has that I have this
field producing this and this field only
producing this what's the
difference yeah yeah so it's it's real
data this is fantastic work thank you so
much for sharing yeah mark thank you for
appreciating that and checking it out
man thank you so much for doing that for
me like brother thank you you're such a
class act
man good guy blame it
Garcia I blame everything on
Jerry why not no seriously it was great
to see Dr lewison here earlier uh he and
I went through the uh the first uh Dutch
master class together back in
2011 uh with Dr hosac comp there in the
Netherlands so that was a fascinating
you know dive down the rabbit hole of
understanding the uh whole Dutch uh
system and providing and if any of you
have the opportunity to do so I know Dr
hosac comp does those once a year or so
and uh it's just a fascinating Deep dive
into a country's legal cannabis Market
we actually had to go to the you know
bedro cans grow and actually check out
everything even to go to you know a
pharmacy where they buy it in bulk and
actually distribute it um you know to
patients directly so um yeah do it's
good to know that Dr Lewis is doing good
things and still continuing on and being
awesome he was a great addition than I
think I think we'll see him more often
for
sure if you guys ever get a chance um
Mark's
um uh 2018 Emerald cup um Talk is really
great he does a good a great PowerPoint
and showing why there's a there's a
variety of cannabis for everybody and he
goes through this kind of timeline of
the soccer mom trying various types till
she finally lands on what works for her
and it's just it's just a great talk
it's a it's a great example of how our
supply chain isn't really addressing all
the potential consume consumers that it
could you know um so yeah big kudos to
Mark if I can get access to that and I
can ask you know either someone through
the emerald cup side U through Tim or
you know right through Mark Lewis if he
has a copy of it I would for sure post
that up on my YouTube channel for the
audience
yeah it's definitely out there I I know
I've seen it online it might be on the
emerald cup it might have been on their
emal Cup site or it might be on YouTube
we we should reach out and ask him hey
um Everybody calling and uh and uh
Mojave you know what's really cool is
that we the the three of us actually get
to uh [ __ ] hang out with like the
founding [ __ ] fathers of the church
right now some of the founding fathers s
so I for one feel like humbled to be
here with like e and Mark and Wade and
and Sam these are like the [ __ ] these
guys are like the guys that created hash
church and so much [ __ ] gratitude to
you guys for that and having people like
us to to share with you
guys 100% man you guys have I mean the H
church as a platform has done a lot for
cannabis has done a lot for cultivators
breeders manufacturers you know
everything it has just been a an
invaluable resource over the years and
you know it is an honor to be here
sharing the space thank
you goes to Marcus he created it and
invited us all in you know so uh if it
hadn't been for him you know he's the
man so thank you Marcus yeah big love to
you that and his spouse lets him do
it and the tolerance of his for allowing
him to continue to yeah he takes family
time time out of his family day you know
so we all sleep eight hours right we all
work eight hours and then eight hours
for our family he takes that eight hours
out of his family day and unselfishly
spends it with all of us so thank you
very much
Marcus and hey everybody go easy on the
man just because this decides to do
Clubhouse because it's easier to access
Etc doesn't mean you have to give them a
whole bunch of Guff you know uh we we do
this out of love this is all volunteer
so you know we just do it because we
want to share the knowledge as well but
you know don't get all up in Marcus's
Grill just because he's unable to do a
hash Church you know uh go easy there
kids that's all I'm saying we do what we
can when we can and we appreciate when
we're here but we can't do this every
single day you know that's the reality
but sometimes we can on clubhouse so you
know go easy yeah join Clubhouse if you
guys want to get in on on the
conversation it's always open to
everyone it's here because of each other
yeah it seems CL house is actually not
open to everyone it's only open to
iPhone users that was the point of
contention but I do appreciate you
mentioning that atan because uh yeah we
took a little bit of gruff
there yeah and you can also do it on the
iPad too but hopefully they'll expand
onto you know other platforms because
it's expanding quickly and largely you
know because it's an accessible platform
for everybody and it's uh it's mobile
and we can you know jump on whenever as
well as jump off whenever whereas we got
a specific time and date that we're
trying to the so you know uh if you get
the opportunity people try Clubhouse
it's worth a shot you know if you're on
able to be patient it's coming soon and
join us on hash church here when you can
much love
awesome well what a great episode today
I want to thank everyone for uh just
coming and
sharing because I'm driving I'm not
going to go through the whole list of
incredible people but you all know who
you are I'll make sure I add it all into
the comments what an episode for like no
mention whatsoever no no promotion of
this episode no um you know letting
anyone know who was going to be on it
just sort of fell together um I always
hope to be more organized for the
audience to let you know who's coming to
kind of gear you up for it but uh the
loyal ones that have been watching since
day one and that are always here well
you know it's really it's really for you
guys and then for you guys to use your
relationships to talk about and and
expose these conversations to a a
further audience so I definitely want to
thank everyone for that um I'm not sure
how I'm going to shut this down because
it's all going live from my computer
right now but I think I can make myself
an administrator here on my phone uh and
if that's the case um I should be able
to shut down the recording and all that
other stuff so you are host now it does
say that so you should be able to okay
awesome well I want to thank everyone if
you guys all want to say goodbye I'm
gonna shut her down in the next couple
of minutes thank you Marcus thank you
everybody it was a great meeting and
conversation this day thank you
thank you love it love it thank you very
much Peter and Mojave for joining us we
hope to see more of you in the future
you're awesome and your knowledge is
exponential appreciate it sharing uh it
with you and I look forward to reading
all about it Peter I'm going to order
some of the soil because I want to try
some of my H seeds out in it yeah love
you yeah thanks everyone really great to
be here look forward to back mve we need
you again for sure yes yes yes maybe
we'll uh we'll pick up a Guitar next
time Mark and we can yeah definitely yes
yes my uncle was the first road manager
for the Greatful Dead by the way
Jonathan rer get the [ __ ] out of town D
wait a second there's stories there well
we'll have to jump into that the man I
call my uncle is my dad's best friend
partner in crime Guy taught me how to
drive but yeah next on hash Church yeah
there you
go see you guys peace everyone have a
lovely day
e
e e