working helps
yeah yeah all right I think it's episode
10 today our special episode of hash
Church 3.0 Let's uh wait to go live here
on
YouTube there we go yeah we're live guys
welcome everyone for uh hash Church 3.0
episode 10 but also uh the special
episode an episode where we'll be
discussing our fallen uh friend Horatio
fallen
soldier um yeah kind of sad times to as
etan was just mentioning Gathering today
for uh you know to celebrate the life of
Horatio Delbert one of our hash Church
alumni uh he was great he always came on
church and shared his information and
got everyone uh kind of amped up and he
was always doing things that was
different than most of the things
everyone else was doing and that's
another thing that I really appreciated
about Horatio so uh want to welcome Wade
laughter to the room good to see you
buddy good morning good
morning oh there we go I hear my voice
coming out of one someone's computer let
me make sure this is
mead yeah and I also want to welcome F
our another hash Church alumni how you
doing
that I'm doing well good morning much
love to everyone much love to the spirit
and love that was h
um needless to say his uh spirit was
enduring and changed and made a lot of
uh lot of people excited about what he
was doing and he was helping people and
you know it's a lot of what we do is
just try to do our best to help people
and spread love and um it really hit me
hard the other day because his birthday
came up
on yeah my Facebook feed
and that kind of hit cuz he didn't reach
you know that's uh yeah it's just
humbling all the way around so it's just
a reminder to live laugh and love and
hug those that you know and care about
and give them love and spread love and
joy and do the best you can in these
dark
times and have bong
rips and have bong rips well said and
Bong rips and Bong
rips awesome hey welcome Colin hey guys
how you
doing you know we're here gathering for
a hash Church episode I'm always happy
to gather with you guys um it's always a
good time it's a little bit of a sad
episode today to be celebrating the life
of uh of a friend who's passed away who
did some great things in the Cannabis
industry and I just thought you know
even though I I hadn't really spoken
with uh uh Horatio for probably a year
or two even um I still felt the need to
honor him on the platform what he shared
on the platform and all the people that
he touched uh felt pretty important to
do that um be a part of his um GoFundMe
that raised money thanks to Johnny B
Johnny B really you know there he is
right there as I mention his name what a
crazy timing that is um he really kind
of went above and beyond as John often
does you know supporting the family and
being there for the family and making
sure that I knew about what was going on
in other key people while it was being
kept very very sort of on the low we are
not going to be discussing what happened
to heratio today so please don't anyone
ask what happened to Horatio we are just
going to celebrate the life of Horatio
we don't get need to get into the uh the
depths of exactly what happened because
a lot of people uh uh have been asking
that so yeah I feel blessed uh John for
sharing it all with me and uh I'm very
glad that you've been there to support
the family and do everything that you
can for them and help with the GoFundMe
and all that so as always Johnny B good
job pal how you doing this morning doing
great brother thanks for um all the kind
words and um yeah I just uh I've been
I've been there helping the family out
totally um with everything that they
need and uh
just it's what I could do to help a
brother you know
so absolutely I'll join you on that one
and Sam skunkman Sam how are you doing
my friend holy Christ you I'm barely
alive dude that's why I'm wearing a mask
dude first of all when you told me that
you had covid it blew me away because I
think I've known you for like 20 some
odd years and I don't think I've ever
known you to be sick ever at all like do
you get sick I got very slightly ill in
Barcelona at the uh cannabis event yeah
when we almost died that's what I'm
saying people don't even know that when
you say that that's not a joke like your
wife was in the hospital I've never been
sicker in my entire life and you got a
tiny bit sick and you did it after we
left Barcelona like I never even saw you
sick yeah well to be honest with covid I
was sick I got it from My Wife and then
I was sick for 24 hours in bed sick as a
dog and the next day it was 85% gone the
next day 90% gone and then it was over
wow it really speaks to your immune
system Sam because that's some Next
Level crazy [ __ ] I mean you're not a
young man first of all you're you're
getting up there in age and uh that's
amazing that you overweight and I'm an
old [ __ ] gezer well I didn't want to
go too deep into it but there you
go good for you for surviving wow that
was uh that freaked me out yeah Arian
got it as well I saw Arian was in bed
and going through his co uh
experience crazy that was just in the
chat room his experience was he made it
pretty real it's pretty cool how he kind
of went through what his condition was
he started jogging again he talked about
the rock what happened with him and he
started really explaining what to do and
really getting to the people like hey
when you get a stay home try and build
your immune system we don't even know if
that works right now right but
yeah well I'm glad you're okay Sam and I
hope uh I hope the wife is going to be
okay as well I I didn't eat for 24 hours
I was in bed for 24 hours I didn't smoke
for 24 hours it
was smok in 50
years holy so now you know that that
[ __ ] was was real if Sam didn't smoke
for 24 hours that was
probably I'd say 20 hours longer than
he's ever gone without a
puff something like that for sure but I
was in China one time and uh I barely
smoked it all in China but I
did oh I can picture you I can picture
you I know exactly how you did it too so
I'm not going to go into it in detail
but I I can picture it hey welcome to
the dragonfly Earth medicine Josh is in
the house how you doing brother good
morning everyone doing well I got stung
by a bee the other day so I kind of have
a little bit of a stung eye everything
who you got stung by a bee on your face
yeah wasp just like [ __ ] came out and
just directly bit me like right here
right on the eyelid I was gonna say
there's no there's no way a bee bit you
your Vibes are too high for a bee but a
wasp now that makes sense I I do have a
lot of friends yeah yeah you're right
they do sting but sting they hurt and
when you get it on your face I can't
even imagine we have a lot of bears
Story how it happened yeah there's a lot
of bears on the property and uh Sky's
got these crazy bike jumps out there and
the be like the Wasps made a huge nest
in his BMS and I came out in the morning
and there was this giant like hole dug
out of the BMS and I was like all these
bees flying on I was like oh [ __ ] I'm
going to go check this out and I had my
camera with me I'm like oh I'm going to
film this
and I walk up to film it and they just
[ __ ] attack me they just came out bam
right in the eyes oh
[ __ ] around and I was like well usually
the the Wasps are really awesome and you
can just be like hey I'm here but when
they're house gets ripped out of the
ground by a bear they're just they're
pissed off
so so that's what happened a a bear open
that
up yeah yeah we had a bear at Mama and
two Cubs in the tree and I I think she
dug it out with her two Cubs we got the
same thing in Lions Bay right now they
were in my neighbor's yard yesterday two
Cubs and a and a mama just cruising
around it's uh you know black bear is no
problem Squamish has had a grizzly bear
hanging out for the last month and they
finally were like yeah you know what as
cool as we are we got to get rid of this
grizzly bear because this thing's 700
pounds and it can literally eat people
out of their cars so they they had to
put it in a you know trap it and bring
bring it up north I suspect up to the
yakum valley or something like that
that's cool yeah we've
had we've had some Grizzlies in our
community here recently over the last
few years and and recently we've had a
couple Grizzlies in the community they
act a a lot different than the the black
bears they're really awesome they're
they're still cool here hey Mark what's
going on
brother hey everybody hey
Doc how's everyone Gooding
yeah let me get this you doing brother
doing
good just chilling out trying to stay
uninfected GL then then don't go to
Sam's
Place
exactly oh my God oh my goodness well
welcome Dr Mark it was beautiful words
that you wrote about Horatio the other
day in the hash Church there I was quite
uh taken back by those words it was I
know we had our own discussion but it
was it was nice to see you know he uh he
was a very I'll never forget the first
time I met Horatio through Johnny B John
was you know John's always like excited
like a kid in a candy store you know
he's like excited like a kid in a candy
store he's legitimately like you can't
be upset with John because his his his
excitement is that of a small child he
is so excited about Whatever It Is Well
he came to me this time and he was like
dude I met this guy he's doing
extractions with lemon they're like
tpine extractions I got it right here
you got to try it with me he's like
Beyond excited and I'm like I'm kind of
like he gives me some and I kind of put
it on my desk and I'm like I'm not
touching that [ __ ] shady [ __ ] like I
can just I'll just leave that right
there and then time kind of went by and
I was kind of like I was looking at it I
was like this stuff does kind of look
crazy [ __ ] it's got that crazy smell so
finally I took a dab of this [ __ ] and uh
it was definitely the early um Inception
of Horatio's um of his extractions and
I'm sure it was Dr Mark who helped him
uh figure out how to distill out the
Citrus oils the 5% Citrus oils that show
up in a five gallon tub of delemon and
these are if you watch the inner sanctum
with Horatio and I that's where I did my
first solvent extraction he actually had
me pour the lemoning through the tube
There You Go Bubba Kush right there uh
uh you're on mute Johnny B he's got the
D lemoning right there and this is the
number one so the very first one he made
is actually sitting on my desk in my
office and it was with Med which was
pretty cool um and and yeah like you
said Mark I first met her ratio at a
night smoke shop through Brandon and
uh in the basement and they were like
you got to meet this guy downstairs he's
like just like amazing and I'm like
what that's how I met her ratio was
through Brandon through night smoke show
and Rihanna and Rihanna yeah and then I
went down there and like this guy's all
about research just like you are John
you gotta down and talk to this guy and
I went down there like he I'm John he's
like uh I've be making these extractions
and I'm like I need I think he found me
through I I think he found me through
Jim fra remember remember Jim Marcus he
did and so so Jim and I were on an Adam
dun show maybe I want to say um like
right around um just before 420 uh in
2014 and so Horatio had reached out to
me and um I don't even think he knew who
I was I mean I I and I barely used face
well I didn't barely use Facebook but I
didn't use it really to reach out sort
of to cannabis people he was one of the
first people who sort of reached out to
me and just started asking all kinds of
questions and it turned into a a
relationship where I gave him some
background references on how to
purify uh lyine because he had been
getting it from maybe not to both
sources and there was really a lot of
question around you know well what is
this you know the intended use for
because it is used in foods it's you
know and derived from from Citrus the
Citrus industry but it is filled with
all kinds of nasty [ __ ] in a technical
grade like they have like a 85% grade
and there's 15% other stuff and this was
simultaneous with having the discussions
around tnca crystallization which is I
went back Marcus you know what this
really did it was so cool to do this man
I went back and I listened to every hash
Church up to the hash Church where I had
first uh signed in now Horatio had been
like texting me during hash Church like
not texting but sending me a Facebook
Messenger things on hey Tony is saying
this Tony is saying this is this right
having me like you know check up on what
Tony was saying because Tony was on on
hash church and then finally he's like
you should come on and and talk about
Turin and stuff and my first episode was
um was episode 19 I went back and and
watched it and you uh had just come back
from Amsterdam I think or J Jamaica no a
Amsterdam I think because hash Church 18
your episode was going over to Amsterdam
and then you were over there for a week
and then you were in the airport in
Toronto and um it was just me and
Horatio at first on that episode episode
number 19 so that was a the my my first
episode on hash church that's awesome
yeah life wasn't the same so it kind of
forced me to go back and look at that
but it also looked I went back and
looked at this long messenger thread
that we had and it's like my gosh he
would just spill his guts about all
kinds of things you know and I know
there was a little bit of a falling out
there for some time he had a falling out
with Kenny he thought that Kenny Trion
Kenny was going to sue him for some
thing or so I I I don't exactly recall
but um the the turps it's funny how it
all connects he unloaded like a three
page you know just ah I just don't know
what to do and you know I can't really
you know I have to think about myself
and I was just like hey man just keep
doing your thing and you know stay pure
to what you do and again like I was
saying in my Facebook post that his last
message to me which was about a year and
a half ago is like a little incoherent
it's like didn't really make sense I I
didn't really know what he was talking
about but uh I knew he was going through
some some difficult times so it it was
too bad about K you know I I I've always
liked Kay I still like Kay he still
won't talk to me over the tpin you know
it was Kay that called me and he said
listen I have a gold nugget for you he
said he was working with shulan he was
doing the tpine extraction he had
already posted the picture of shulan
smelling the tpin that classic picture
and he sent me a message or called me
actually and he said listen you need to
figure out how to get the tpin out of
the bubble water to Ste them down and
get them back into your product and I
was kind of like I was like do I like do
I need to do that but I kind of you know
like he was like listen it's really
important I just want you to to to do
this and I I did not have time to do
such a thing and was not in a position
to do such a thing so I told literally
two people about it told Tony and I told
Horatio and those were the two people
that brought tpin to the market and Kay
was pissed about that and I mean pissed
he he was really mad like the text he
sent me I had to delete off my phone
because they were so harsh and uh he
told me he had a patent his patent was
for every method of tarpine extraction
from Cannabis whatsoever it covered
everything it was very much not like K
it just wasn't it didn't sound I've
known k for 20 years at this point in
time and this was the first time I ever
had a disagreement with him let alone
and I send him a message probably every
six months saying hey bro I'm thinking
about you he still won't message me back
over this T he was so angry that that
Tony was able to create a success with
his tpin and that herio was creating
tpin and and for me I look back and I
think well man you could have just come
out and done your tpine thing I haven't
seen him do anything in regards the tpin
since 2014 and it was like it was a
fairly important you know was as
important as it was for Sam to do what
he did with the very few of us that got
to learn the modulating effects of tpin
back in early 2000s in his apartment in
Amsterdam because that was of course you
can always trace it back to Sam and
Sam's not the one crying that everyone
took this idea from him but it's always
seems to be it always seems to be Sam
right 2000 I think he hit me with the
pure cannaboids and the pure tpin I had
never seen anything like it but it was
really Tony and Horatio who made it
available to the public they were
suddenly now able to have these cannabis
drive tpin hold them in their hands see
them feel them smell them touch them
consume them dab them and uh that was a
big deal and it's it is unfortunate that
sometimes we end up in these clashes and
I know you know Horatio was never in a
position where he was you know making so
much money that he was just very
confident and secure so for Kay to have
laid that on him that he was gonna GNA
sue him that weighed on Horatio like a
great deal I had
I had conversations with him about that
you know where it was like listen I had
already gone through like a six-year
lawsuit with Reinhardt so I was like all
right K like Bring It On You Wanna you
want to do lawsuits like I I I know how
to do lawsuits and uh that's another you
know two more uh well Reinhardt was
never on hash church but he was
certainly a giant part of the hash
community and the and the hash world
because he created that machine and that
machine was exactly where the bags were
created from rip to Elden who was uh the
gentleman who came up with the bag idea
uh rip to Reinhardt who passed away at
the end of 2018 or the end of 2017 right
when his patent expired if you if you
can imagine Reinhardt passed away as his
water extraction uh pass uh patent also
perished and I also want to give a shout
out to Dr Lester grinspoon who was also
a hash Church alumni made it on here for
a couple of episodes uh and obviously
lived an incredible life it was not
quite the same um sad story that it was
with uh Horatio dying at such a young
age I'm sure Lester was more than twice
Horatio's age um when he passed away so
he lived this incredible life he lived a
long life a fruitful life and one that
also affected the Canabis industry in a
very very deep and meaningful way so we
just want to shout out all the Lost
brothers and sisters uh over the years
uh and just let them know that we're
thinking of them and uh regardless of
whether we had uh you know falling outs
or that we maintain these friendships
you know you still can be a big enough
person to uh show respect for these
people and I'll I'll say you know I have
nothing but respect for Kenny Morrow uh
K from Tricom Technologies I hope to one
day be his friend again I I personally
have never stopped being his friend but
that tpine thing really really bit him
the wrong way and it's uh it's
unfortunate but it is something that
happens in our industry uh quite often
and we'll have to uh learn how to to
mature out of these experiences and and
bring things back full circle because
it's easy to burn bridges down it's a
lot harder to to rebuild them hey I want
to shout out to Dr Lester grinspoon you
know I was the pts study in uh marijuana
The Forbidden medicine and uh you know
he touched my life back after the war
and was uh willing to put forward we all
published anonymously but I am thanked
in the forward um
but that was one of my
early to
self-healing uh was to actually you know
write down my story I'd gone around and
told it for a few years going around
being an activist with canvas action
nwork I was fortunate to do Ries in 47
States you know got kicked out of Canada
with our legal marijuana from Elie
musika but um Dr grinspoon was a force
and you know he suffered the slings and
arrows uh for the things that he
published and took a lot of heat for it
as a Pioneer and as I look around at a
whole bunch of other Pioneers here we
all know unfortunately
the painful piercings that can happen
when you tread where nobody else's tread
and tried and um Dr grinspoon definitely
deserves an honor
[Music]
inall in the darkest of Ages and pushed
forward with his life all of us to see
and giving me a shoulder to stand on uh
needless to say was beyond humbling um I
kind of want to give a shout out to
because I've been doing my own uh
veteran healing shout out to the
veterans access initiative Rico and
Pearson and uh veterans virtual happy
hour Jose and them on Fridays they've
been keeping me staining during this
covid stuff so um we're working actually
behind the scenes we have some really
cool stuff happening did you all know
that the compassionate indd program or
at least the investigative new drug
program was reopened by the United
States government due to epid
dialects oh yeah and uh so what we're
gonna try to do is we're gonna try to uh
re access and uh take veterans through
that and get uh access again be it most
likely from importation as opposed to
getting that crappy Mississippi weed but
um yeah look out we're coming out as a
force yes sir the epilex is made out of
a CBD variety I developed a licens to
GW I know you did because you're the
master and thank you very much for what
you did because uh I have not tried
epidex but at the same time its creation
uh and due to set of x's failure allowed
the indd program to reopen so um that's
huge for patients who want access to
investigative new drugs because it was
shut down in the early 90s due to U A A
A Congress person basically saying
because a bunch of AIDS patient were
signing up that people were trying to uh
you know get access to the program so
they could spread AIDS around the world
so they think they have the access to
marijuana and so they shut down the
program Robert Randall helped arrange
for the AIDS patients to make those
applications for the program and for
those who don't know Robert Randall was
the first person to win the right to
have access to Medical uh cannabis from
the United States government grown at
the University of Mississippi in Oxford
so do alol and them are still at it but
uh maybe through this program we can get
them to grow some good weed finally by
get importing from either Israel or some
of these other countries that'll force
them even Canadian weed which would be
able to import for the com combas
program speaking of which would you
recommend as an access from of your
Canadian weed what would you recommend
to us American veterans companies Etc we
would recommend regenerative hemp that
or or or cannabis grown organically
because we find that the chemicals that
are often used in The Grow can affect
you know the Mind space of the medicine
afterwards so especially with uh you
know know you know people from the
military and stuff and there there are
more people in our area in the cies that
have been licensed recently that could
provide you with some of that medicine
which is I'm going to say somewhat new I
mean you know the the licensed producer
program here in Canada has not been set
up to really produce like you know let's
say intentional medicine and whatnot so
you know I would love to to hook you up
with a couple of people in our area and
see if it would work out some of the
problems in Canada with Organics as well
just like it's the same problem in
California and the selenis valley is
that trying to grow organically while
everyone else is bombing Avid and
malathion on their avocados and their
raspberries and blueberries makes it
damn near impossible to grow organically
you you really have to make sure you
choose your farm position wisely and
also potentially hope to control your
neighbors Farms if they're uh being
farmed or if they're being sold to
people coming in to with the intention
of farming because the amount of people
who grow um conventionally which is the
word they use for poison um is just
astronomical it is absolutely
astronomical how many people and so
we've seen this we've seen organic
cannabis fail um pesticides and just and
without ever having sprayed a single
pesticide on the plant so that's that's
kind of disconcerting when you think of
the energy and the time and the and what
it takes to do it in in the right way
also with health Canada not really
allowing uh kind of like the US was
there where microbial counts you were
failing in microbial counts uh and they
weren't necessarily the microbes that
were the negative microbes so these
things have a long way to go I think I
you know like obviously in health
Canada's um programs you're not allowed
to have this sort of full closed loop
like have goats [ __ ] over there and
have like you know your compost like
it's very very structured and very
controlled and hopefully you know people
like Josh and Kelly can have an
influence and that more and more people
I I think the way to talk to these
people is through the words terar and
Appalachia and understand that we can't
scrub those things out of cannabis the
way we haven't scrubbed them out of the
wine industry and out of the grape
industry if you ever considered uh uh
offering that to the wine industry hey
let's scrub the Terre out grow in
aseptic rooms with lights and and
nutrients salt nutrients and let's see
what kind of uh what kind of wine we get
out of that I think that Community would
be like in an uproar and say well you
can't do that that's like the most
important thing when we grow our grapes
next to the genetics themselves is the
terroir in which we grow and so if the
Canadian cannabis program Health Canada
can start understanding the value of
Terr and how it applies to cannabis we
may very well get to that place that uh
that you're already at Josh there are
two different crops though Marcus
because uh grapes are grown in Native
Earth yes cannabis very little cannabis
grown Outdoors is actually grown in
Native earth almost all of it is in bags
or manmade soil yes yes that's true too
so in the case of in the case of the
regenerative farmers
and and even some of the licensed two of
the licensed farmers in our area they
are growing in native soil and they are
growing outdoor varietals and with the
help of some of the genetic uh research
going on with like Daryl Hudson and
implanta and all that there's um hemp
that's being you know tested still um
outdoors and whatnot that can finish out
here because as we've stated before
Kelly and I have personally grown out a
lot of the hemp Vari almost all of the
hemp varietals I mean you can't say all
but a shitload of them have we've tried
to grow them Outdoors out here and it's
they just don't come they just don't
finish and they don't have the same
flavor or the same profiles so getting
an outdoor varietal that works out here
that's also registered in the Canadian
hemp um uh bracket is is is is still in
process and let's say since the licensed
producers here in
Canada have somewhat had a failed run
you know and the Cana and the Canadian
government is seeing you know how how
this isn't working they there's change
coming to our community and and and uh
you know there's people that are are
looking at making changes and maybe ATN
or something you can like talk to some
to the Canadian people about like what
California's done with microbials and
California only tests for human
pathogens if I'm correct um which are
you know like eoli and botul is it
botulism and leria I you could maybe
name off all of them but uh and I think
you know using human pathogens as a as a
you know um something to test for and
heavy metals that kind of makes sense to
me um I have a
question because of soil not everybody
can prep their soil properly okay which
is true right and I have veterans and a
lot of people ask me God what's the best
over-the-counter
soil that's on the market that you would
recommend for cannabis Growers that
don't have access to do what you
beautiful people do up at dragonfly and
others that actually prep their soil
what would you recommend as an
over-the-counter soil that you could add
to
Etc um I
mean go ahead I like I like builda soil
a lot I think they have a lot of options
for for the the hom grower U they also
offer some some cover crop um solutions
for you
um you know I think that's a good way to
start and then there's also super soil
recipes online that you can easily look
up um and mix and match your favorite
amendments from you know such as you
know the Dem pure offerings that you
have you can mix your own soils pretty
easily um and it doesn't really require
much space to do something like that if
you're doing you know a small grow for
yourself and i' I'd highly recommend
that um for anyone out there to to
really get into the soil biology and
biome of of what you're doing um so and
I I wanted to interject on what Josh was
saying about growing at scale with with
you know regenerative practices in
Upstate New York there's a 2600 Acre
Farm that is rotational of with 30 acres
of hemp on it and all we do on that farm
is is grow regeneratively using cover
crop and then we we you know we it's in
a rotation uh with other crops so it's
it's very much on a schedule much like a
you know conventional farm would
actually run their schedules however the
inputs are actually forged from the land
itself also doing carbon sequestering
and and things of that nature so I think
what I've seen over that time working
with that project I've seen you know a
lot of trials and tribulations but I now
feel you know it's really it's PL
plausible to do this large scale and I
do believe that that is something that
we can all look
towards I was just sitting here talking
about all the organic growing and stuff
like that I remember when uh Rao he um
started baking all the compost piles and
stuff like that and adding all the
chicken [ __ ] to and stuff like that and
he had like I'm at his house right now
and he's got all big cement mixers and
and you should see all the piles of they
have all the organic Growers there and
stuff like that and all his beds that he
put out there because they're growing
all their own food and stuff like that
and he he really got really into what
you guys are talking about but he always
tried to do it a little different he
always tried to do it his way he always
tried to kind of reinvent the wheel in
some way and stuff like that um I'm just
seeing all these piles of um near the
hen right now and he's got all this
tarps over it and he's he's he's getting
all this dirt ready for for spring for
next year and stuff like that and I
think I'm G to go there and grab a bunch
of that actually and pile it back in my
truck and bring it to my house today um
because I know he worked a lot on that
and that's my first of my living soils
that I'm going to start thank keep
talking about it
yeah grow some grow some urban htio grow
some Urban Horatio's uh soil I am I'm
totally going to do that I I I I can see
it there as you're talking about it and
thank you for talking about that because
I just forgot about what he was doing
there and and then now seeing it there
I'm sorry I'm a little tear out about of
course because he was a good friend um
but uh that's it was it's pretty awesome
to see just the what what we always put
and he was always saying the turps we
got to get those turps going he was
always about the turps and he knew that
the generative way was how they going to
get the best TPS and and and then he
went into hydro and and I'm going
through all this Hydro Gear right now
and I mean he literally tried
Reinventing growing guys it was like
he's these Spinners and all these tubes
and discs and it was um and he was
always trying to get there and and when
regenerative soils come into play here
and all these living soils and stuff
like that like the flavors that we're
getting from the Cannabis is is just so
amazing and and really it's um it's it's
really cool to um you know talk more
about that about trying to get those TS
trying to look at that that whole
natural thing and that's what Hera was
all about was was all about natural he
didn't want any chemicals in anything
and if he didn't an extraction that had
anything that was sprayed on it he would
he give it back to you like you can't
spray anything on there it had powdery
Milo so it's not working and it it was
um he was always chasing that and and
and I saw the soils as you're talking
about that and that's how we really got
to give back is by growing and getting
those turps and and and living what you
love to do right well I'll tell you we
have it all on record you know like
there's a lot of Horatio recordings on
hash church and in fact there's a lot of
all of you guys on hash Church we're all
going to have meet our maker one day and
pass on and we'll all have done a ton of
different things but the amount of time
and energy and talking and sharing that
you guys have done here on this platform
uh will sh will and should live on for a
very long time I have them all backed up
I've removed them all and you know
copied them all off of uh YouTube so
they're secure on multiple hard drives I
think of it as very very Priceless
information that I never ever plan to
monetize but always plan to share and
give away and and make sure that you
know what a great thing like Mark said
you can go back and you can watch
literally hours and hours and hours I
think there's probably half a dozen to
10 videos with just myself and Horatio
maybe Johnny B as well but then however
many hash churches I don't know if he
was on a hundred or 150 or how many hash
churches he was on but he was definitely
on more than a
few freshly Frozen taking over the show
now I I don't know what happened I was I
was saying good things
there you was profound we were all
wrapped oh [ __ ] Hero's playing games
with us
you know that's good you know I would
just um add or go ahead if you want to
say
something Hora is shining his love down
on us right
now um I would add to what was said
about all the soils saying that I agree
with every that's said there and it's
beautiful that Johnny's being able to
connect with you know Horatio through
the soil and through the turps and
everything and you know there's there's
buying there's buying soil you know um
on you know line or getting it in bags
and that can be done and then you know
people will use teas on top of that to
make it really work and a lot of people
will shoot for the a a big bud kind of
like you know like the the the
bodybuilder or whatever they go for the
big bud rather than the actual depth of
the soil and the and the flavor and the
chps so what I'm going to say is it's
really important to make your own soil
so I think it's great calling that you
that you brought a builda soil and
making your own soil so when you make
your own soil and even you know veterans
or people that have a small amount of
space I think it's really important to
to look at the the components of your
soil and what the act of mixing all that
and make and getting microbes living
microbes and putting that together is a
healing process in itself and then you
start getting your seed together you
start thinking and connecting with the
soil and and then the seed and you put
the seed in there or a clone and then
you put that in there because I mean
growing isn't an automatic thing it's
something that really is a spiritual
connection so making your own soil is
really the first part of that and buying
dust and powers and stuff from from
stores is only so alive so I would say
going out on a walk and and I want to
make this really clear is and and
selectively grabbing some and inoculant
from nature you know whether it's and I
realize some people don't live near
nature so I'm I'm I'm in full awareness
that you know not everyone can do this
so you know but the for the people that
can you can grab like a small little
handful and put it in a bag a small bag
of leaf stff and leaf matter and that's
your living organisms and the living
organisms really need something to
continue living so adding a little bit
of mulch to that gives it something to
continue living on so the interaction
between raw materials and soil is the
living part so you you a person doesn't
have living soils by buying a bunch of
amendments and mixing them together and
them being called biological they're
they're biological and they're alive
when they're eating something so top
dressing you know nettle powder or
alphalpha powder or you know whatever
you can get ganja Leaf any of your
defoliating leaves that are healthy you
could dry out or you could just drop
them right on your soil and that feeds
the top layer we know the top layer of
soil is the most active so you want
layer of soil once you get your soil
based so that's where the depth of tping
come from that's where the plant is able
to express itself we know the plant is
expressing itself and and Mark can and
different people can talk about the
science behind
how a plant is able to be different in
an aeroponic situation or a hydroponic
or a fully biological rich soil
so there's a lot of you know lot of
people nowadays moving towards you know
using these soils in a production way
and also in a backyard way and um you
know and I just want to really encourage
people to continue with it because it's
it's the future and it's how we're going
to make it into the future and it's how
we you know are going to be able to
connect with longevity and Longevity is
missing right now in our lives in many
different
areas I would add I would add to that
joshing your own soil is really really
important I would I would add to that
that if you want a great book for
learning all of this that's really fun
and easy to to to read this comic book
is like Second To None it blew me away
grow organic it starts with this Dutch
guy and he's growing uh he's growing
with salts and chemicals and he's
looking on the labels and he's like what
the heck look at all this stuff this
stuff can kill you and so he tosses it
all away and he starts learning about
Organics and he basically go they go
through the entire book the nature cycle
takes you through like this beautiful
visuals of what's going on in the plant
what's happening with the cellulose
strategic cocktail room Nitric and
citric acid like all of this complex
information put into a comic book that
I've been reading to my son and
basically picking up the knowledge just
while I read this to him uh at at
bedtime for uh to to go to sleep so
definitely check this out it's on Amazon
freely adapted from the organic grow
book by Carol shell Hut and mishel pan
husen I'll put their names up because I
didn't spell them very well you take a
little snapshot of that and it's it's
also on
Kindle yeah yeah exactly it is great and
it was alpen glow that I believe shared
this the first time on um a show that
Josh and Kelly were
doing and also Jesse bio Vortex uh yes
regenerative cannabis farm where Jesse's
got a character in that book and he was
in in communication with those two and I
believe France when they were creating
it yeah it's an awesome book totally
agree it's a definitely France kid yeah
kids book made you know for you know
everyone also rodale's guide to compost
is a really good base from the 40s till
now you know that and they continue to
bring information about regenerative
farming another another thing to look
into is in your local community is a
municipal compost and Municipal dirt
that's being made in your area the the
issue you might run across and you can
ask them for testing is if there's any
roadside sprays or any vegetation that's
been used from say golf courses or
something that can contaminate the soil
so maybe before you use a local M
Municipal compost hi Alice um before you
use the municipal compost maybe ask them
if they have testing for uh fertilizer
residuals or um uh herbicides or
fungicides um so Municipal comp post is
also kind of like if when it's good it's
it's a local soil that has organisms
from your local area and we could go on
and on about soil but blessings Alice
how are you today are you how you
holding up in your
community hey everyone good morning
happy to see you all sorry I'm late on a
Sunday I woke up kind of late today uh I
am well uh the sun is shining today of
being kind of stoked that there's no not
that much smoke in the air here North
kale and pretty excited to see the soil
movie too and uh I you were talking
about the soil and I can't wait to see
the kiss kiss the ground has you guys
were talking about this before has
anyone seen it uh Flynn's here with me
too he's gonna join in a minute and just
want to say happy Sunday to you
all awesome well welcome Alice it's good
to have you guys both here it's uh yeah
we wanted to definitely talk a little
bit about the fires today as as well and
how that's affecting everyone down along
the west coast and how we can kind of
Point people in the direction of the
right uh the right ways to offer help
you know I seen uh I'm on an email chain
with Josh and Kelly from dragonfly Earth
medicine you may very well be on it as
well Alice I I I don't look at the names
but uh yeah it was nice to see all these
people just offering help and you know
like whatever it is no matter how small
it's offered and it's like look this is
what I can offer and this is what I will
offer so that makes you feel good when
uh it's not you know people using each
other as ladders to climb on top of one
another to get to the top but they're
actually like helping each other and
putting a hand down to to lift someone
up so that's that's the kind of
communities I want to be involved
with yeah and during this time of
political turmoil and environmental
turmoil there's just a lot of divisive
potential out there you know who's going
where you know which direction and
everything and and even the Cannabis
space you know we've talked about it
it's it can be com a competitive space
because people are trying to make it
work with ideas and all that but you
know what we've
really done within our community is just
really bring in the supportive aspect
and realize that us all coming up
together is a success and part of the
success is just supporting each other so
during this fire situation I mean it's
been a a long like almost a month now of
problems with fires in Oregon and in
California and some people have been
awoken at night not knowing there was a
fire like the ones in Oregon recently
and and definitely California too but
what you know as far as Oregon goes some
you know a lot of those fire were
started during that that night of wind
where it was 70 miles an hour wind and
uh people didn't even know there was a
fire and by the time the fire came and
just engulfed everyone and um it was at
we know we know there there was one
person you know that there's a bunch of
people that got burnt up in their houses
and one of our close family members you
know ran out of his house his neighbor
woke him up and every he went out with
two you know two different socks in his
underwear and you hear a lot of these
stories you know um and he lost
everything and he's a cannabis grower
for 20 years
on of Oregon big they loved to Sheldon
and uh you know he lost all of his
clones he's been working on and our
family members and and Portland and
Megan Liz and and Pat and a bunch of
people Casey um you know helped get a
lot of his strengths back to him because
he gave plants to people in the Portland
area and they were flowering out and
people went to their
houses to get back to him so he could
continue his journey of you know
breeding and get his life back together
and he's working on court cases right
now against the electri compies because
electricity went
out and then uh the F don't know what's
right and wrong you know with
electricity but electricity is a big
thing that's killing us you know when it
comes to massive fires you know so wires
go down and fires start and it's it's
insane you know there's no
forestry management that's going to stop
that you know and we go on and on about
managing and all that but uh so it's
been it's been phenomenal so another
thing is is actively at the moment in
Trinity County flower day's Farm is
super you know nervous about a fire
that's in their area and um you know I
I'll say a few things that we don't know
for sure but there are
like backfires and fires getting started
you know to to to burn back the fire and
drones maybe starting fires to to stop
the fire from growing and burning out
some people and it's it's like a level
of insanity going on around around there
you know and people just don't know I
mean you just wake up every minute of
the day looking which way the wind's
blowing and you know um Wade maybe you
can talk about some of the links that
you know about um but uh you know Rio
and alpen glow and Gil uh ganja Gil and
Walter from Soul Spirit Holly Hall and
Crystal um you know a bunch of other
people but you know those people have
said like you know hey Carla and Jacob
we got you covered we got a truck we got
the last toes we got a pump you know
we're come what what food do you need
we're we're on our way right now today
you know and and maybe it was yesterday
in the afternoon but it's like right now
where they're bringing over a total
support crew for them
and I would just say you know we have
our Network because you can only have
what network you have but you know
people are really willing to help one
another right now and uh it's really
important to to band together and also
to help protect each other because
insane people are out there and take
this opportunity to pray on your
property so as you're evacuating reality
is true you have to [ __ ] guard your
property too because [ __ ] are coming
to [ __ ] steal things and so it it's
it's insane so be diligent and strong
and you know use you know your community
and uh you know I just want to give
special love to the the pure certified
community and all the people that are
beyond that that are helping people and
the fires are crazy right now um Wade do
you have any input on that because
you've had a lot of of input also
Valerie carral and Santa Cruz you know
big love to Brett and do peros who who
did lose his home
completely um you know and I know
Valerie right now you know has said that
her all of the floor space on her in her
house is taken up by people who have
lost their homes yeah Foxworthy
Foxworthy Farms who supports Us in
Berkeley um Martin O'Brien and he just
lost his uh house and part of the farm
part of it was saved it's just the winds
are so Random I mean
it's
it's survives and what doesn't so much
love to Valerie and everybody else I
know they've had a very challenging time
uh I heard
they did he mute himself right at the
end there or was that just me what was
the last thing you said
ATN I said I heard that Valerie uh
Valerie's Farm was saved
yes they didn't know it first and it was
like one of those things oh what's up
but they they from what I know at this
moment it was saved yeah there was a lot
of Confusion And even she didn't know
and I saw her posting on social media so
uh I heard through the rumor control
that you know it was saved so to hear
confirmation is great to hear although I
know there's definitely damage
Etc and um expect a lot of uh Smoky cush
and Hickory cush on the East Coast this
year people
Chipotle
bubble say it again Marcus what was that
I call it Chipotle bubble people are
like oh there's something weird with
this bubble and I'm like oh that's like
wildfires bubble i' I've I've maybe the
chipotle sauce yeah it's just got this
Smoky flavor it's terrible like it's not
definitely funny like it's not funny but
it is like [ __ ] like it's unbelievable I
just pray and I pray and I pray that
2020 one doesn't say to 2020 hold my
beer
yes people have to understand because
the cat the plant is resonance all that
smoke debris sticks to the plants and
kind of gets into it and you can't wash
it off so unlike fruit you know yeah but
I I think they could just turn it into
distillate right because they could they
could clean up distillates so yeah
that's what they have to do Mark that's
the only thing only option you know yeah
a lot you know and it's nice to have an
option but a lot of those people are
grow you know it's they're they're all
organic Growers on in the thing they're
like oh sweet I just made an isolate
it's like it's not really very
successful in that sense you know but
yeah from the farmer point of view I
know go Ahad Farmers yeah from the
farmer point of view uh turning if
you're business model if you will is set
up on the idea of being able to sell
highend trimmed flow hours that people
consume by smoking uh you got a price
point that's considerably different than
what's usually offered for material that
ends up being distillate it's a really
significant difference in price oh yeah
and um and what's true about the fires
this year is it's really kind of a
tragedy all across California and across
the country actually it's kind of a to
me it's
a a like Marcus was saying hold my beer
because more is coming
um what happened here with fires back in
August was early in August around the
8th or the 9th one night a line of
thunderstorms blew from south to North
along the length of California mostly
along the coast range and there were
like 12,000 lightning
strikes at the beginning of August so
everything was bone dry and literally
thousands of fires started
most of them were clumped like I said
along the coast range and um I think I
saw that uh on Cal Fire's website uh
this year um and this was like a week
ago we had 26 times the amount of
acreage has burned so far this year and
really we're early in the fire season 26
times more has burned this year than
burned last year A bad fire season last
year think there I know that this is
overhyped in the news a lot and
certainly things that we should be
concerned about but do you think there's
a direct correlation to climate change
of course
well climate change and um large areas
that um to be speak plainly belong to
either large property owners and or the
US government or state governments and
there's no funding to do any s Forest
management other than cutting trees for
lumber 60% of California is is is
federal Forest land on top of that we're
also as Wade is talking there's also
been not proper burning for decades so
there's unfortunately a lot of fuel out
there on top of that sudden Oak death
has also caused problems throughout
forests because you have certain trees
dying in certain areas and those are dry
Kinder which only and there
spotted yeah in theot I didn't mean to
interrup
there in si the pine
beetle yeah you have the the eucalyptus
as well that's that's uh highly highly
flammable yeah
so it is worse now it it is worse now
for all the reasons you guys are saying
but let's be perfectly Frank and honest
it's the natural cycle of the forest in
California to that lightning strike
burns down huge areas it takes a hundred
years to regenerate this has been going
on for thousands and thousands and
thousands of years Manan is what stuck
his houses in the middle of this yes
exactly
Sam I'm a good example of that I've got
you know a little farm uh at a th000
meters in the sier Nevada near Grass
Valley Nevada City area and uh I love
part of why I came here is there's so
many beautiful trees we have huge huge
chestnuts and Oaks I mean we have four
on a 4 acre property we have Four Oaks
that are 120 feet tall and bigger than
our house uh they're just amazing and we
have am an amazing amount of acorns
dropping this year as a matter of fact
but back to fires uh what we've done is
a pretty serious effort of fire safe
clearing as it's called and we haven't
really satisfied the requirements but
you kind of live with this idea that as
Josh was saying at any
moment particularly on a windy night or
day all of a sudden there's smoke in the
air and you've got literally a couple of
minutes to get your [ __ ] together and be
ready to leave because you might get
burned out and what's real about that is
it's actually happened to a number of
people we know and um uh and those of us
who have not had that and we are in that
category there's been a couple of fires
in our County uh the a big one uh north
of us is happening in the same area
where the fire two years ago killed 80
some people in the town of
paradise um and that was a fire that was
started by PG's electrical transmission
system failing in a River Canyon uh one
of the hangers on a high tension wire
broke and cascade of Sparks and it was a
windy morning about 5 o'l and by 7
o'clock the town of paradise was on fire
and everybody that was in it that didn't
make it out is one of those 88 dead uh
so we all live with that idea that that
could happen at any moment particularly
for those of us that live
in an urban or excuse me the wildlands
you know the where like myself I live in
a whole bunch of trees it's a beautiful
spot I'm me really grateful to have it
but yeah fire happens here just like Sam
was saying well one of the things you
can do besides a fire break is to have
tile roofs and have a brick or stone
exterior walls of your house those are
almost impossible to burn yeah know
another really good thing to do is um a
a lot of the Conifer trees and things
that are right directly around your home
you cannot have those a conifer tree
right around your home and then have
more grassy or garden areas right around
your home and then putting a sprinkler
on the peak of your roof and hard
Plumbing in like with maybe a a metal
conduit sprink like sprinklers on the
top of your roof and turn them on so
there's like a wall of water coming down
your roof and a lot of people have been
able to save their homes with fire just
going right around their house so you
know I I'm a little nervous that
everyone's just like oh we gotta cut all
the the branches and trees down in order
to save ourselves from fires and I just
want to encourage people instead of
burning off your branches consider
digging them into the Earth consider
putting those branches if you leave them
around your house going to burn anyway
from the sparks in the
air and to speak what Collins was saying
mini excavator or someone and dig them
into the Earth go ahead a uh eucalyptus
trees are not only a problem they're an
inundation problem because California
brought in a whole bunch of eucalyptus
back in the day I think 27 different
varietal here and they're not indigenous
they brought them because they wanted
them to grow paper or grow wood
unfortunately the microbes in the soil
causes the
wood just broke up there oil also kills
a of
everything sorry the uh the oils also
you know kill everything below so you've
got a a combination of trees that will
also full of oil that can explode so
that's also a problem in California that
isn't really talked about you know
eucalyptus
also out all the moisture from the
ground and Eucalyptus is not good to
make a hugle pile from go ahead
Colin yeah I I was just gonna uh just
kind of add to what what you guys were
saying and it's it's an invasive species
and it does need to be managed and to
your point it's it's hard to Deforest
eucalyptus because it's so invasive it's
just it's unbelievable how invasive that
species
is so I'm amazed how people don't talk
about that reality you know what I'm
saying none of the news touches on that
and it's so because it's so invasive
it's in every forest and thick and they
overtake a great part of where they they
grow I think yeah you're right I think
it's a good Marcus wouldn't you say it's
a good time for a for a group dab yeah I
think Johnny B had some of Horatio's
turp champagne out he was going to make
a toast maybe and we'll have a nice
little dab I think that's I think that's
in order I will definitely open this
bottle but it will be in a room of some
special friends
and it's a Horatio Delo concentrate L
and he gave me one of these bottles like
you guys is like five years old six
years old it's one of his first
bottles and I was going to kind of crack
it on his service but um there's going
to be a day that we open this bottle in
honor and uh today's not really that
morning right now but I would like to um
One Day celebrate with his TP champagne
and I remember when he came up with the
first sh champagne and I know Mark
you've tried it and I brought some
bottles to um my friend's wedding there
back in
2016 and um just an honor to be able to
have some of the first the turp
champagne and still be able to celebrate
but right now got La show on the end of
this dab rig right here get up my
temptech heat it up and uh I uh I
started smoking a little bit of this
right away there when his passing
happened and I got like one left but I'm
GNA keep that last one for my last
time mother
lovers I've got
um uh some uh nice hatch here from flave
Marcus flave 421 came on over Dave and
uh spent some time in our house last
night it was super good to see him and
and he know was his first time here on
the property came out with our buddy
Alex big love to him and and them and
they dropped off some nice hash some Pie
Face I've got I've got some of that pie
face do you nice yeah he left he came
here and we squished uh some Pie Face
some Renee some OG what was it it was
like uh it was trop Santo crossed with
cookies oh yeah I think I think that's
what this I think that's when this one
is Dave
you right now is I'm just sharing it
with you because I'm just dabbing it
right now and it's being like six years
old wow I can't believe the flavor is
still there like totally that's so
flavor well it was it was literally made
with
TPS did you save it in the freezer
Johnny he been in the fridge the whole
time inside my little box here
specialness I got d420 K's first Little
Dry St you gave me I got your first dry
mark on here when you did your first
sift for me I got everybody's little bit
of box in there I like uh all all those
memories is all on this little box of um
Trippy Stick Trippy Stick box even got
from you dude if I open it up I got all
the Little Treasures that we've done
over the last little bit with the first
static sifts from right here to some of
the first Lei to some of the first dabs
that we made all the little histories of
the stuff that we've done over the years
is pretty cool you can see like when we
when we laughed so so hard after that
dab that it took me 45 minutes to make
oh [ __ ] that was that was hilarious man
like yeah and laughed our heads off and
stuff like that but I mean it's uh yeah
I can't believe the turps in there and
stuff like that like so amazing you know
the Banger's pretty you know Chaz though
that was one thing right but Chaz out
your Banger hey is it the time I was
gonna say is it the time for the for the
oh no I it's the time are we doing uh uh
slow starts uh
little cold I did a I did a cold start
myself I'll do a cold start to here a
little
quicker I don't do the cold start
actually yeah I got some uh Sol Miss
some good time sitting there on cchq
doing dabs with ratio and stuff he
pulled all the dabs I got some great
pictures of all of us together there's
one really good one that's one of my
favorites it's it's a mi Horatio in d420
K and um I think Flows
In kind like shout out what are you
smoking Alex and Flynn what are you
smoking um now uh I just did some
24K to start the day that
orangey Vibe it's a beautiful um string
that I actually taught from resing
wrench brought up and he has a this
great cut that has beautiful mouth and
for me it's like a morning orange juice
seriously super creative we got a 24K
taffy from uh from Joey
and I'm pretty sure he must have made it
with Todd during those times when they
were at the meno Hideout maybe it's this
one oh it probably is it probably is
yeah we got some we're still working on
that those those varial in that line
right now it's pretty sweet do you know
what the Taffy was by any
recollection yeah okay and this
one it was a test that's what I thought
to that's from Brandon and Amanda it's
their papaya punch their papaya punch
cut we it for the first time they gifted
us the cut and then we watch it for the
first time we we're doing also actually
the the mail test here just check out
where is it gonna be gift thanks we got
um the strawberry guava cut from them
and and the purple punch cut
from is insane dude it makes hash I've
ever seen it's
crazy ready to make the first bits of it
from our light dep that we did this year
and it came out just so good cuz
British columia had a good year the
purple
punch to get that strange since Mark put
those tping underneath my nose when I
came out of surgery and it took my pain
away I really want to grow it so I've
been asking for it for like five years
so and if I could get a cut of that or
even try it like just actually have some
of it to see how it affects me again
it'd be fantastic all right well hey
Johnny we're gonna get our trim done
here and we're GNA take like big trip
out to the
coast and we're gonna come visit you and
Marcus and some of there spend some time
so we'll we'll bring you what we have
and we just gave uh FL some of our
ruffle plant to to try and uh to clone
and whatnot
stuff John had literally just gotten out
of back surgery like neck spinal surgery
when when D and I went to to put that
purple punch under his NOS I brought 30
different tpin that day in a in a in a
Pelican case and sat by his hospital bed
and that was a super intense floor of a
hospital like every single person had
these crazy posts coming out of these
casts around their necks like attaching
them to their beds like it was heavy
duty and then John is all like hey guys
oh what's up guys like just like super
animated man what a trip and of course
it's all filmed on YouTube it's there's
a video of us that whole thing even what
you can see him smell it and be like oh
my God that like took my pain away just
for a second I pulled it away from you
I'm like give that back to me yeah you
did I watch so much you guys are like in
the
[Music]
par what's
that it's got a very deep like rich
flavor to it and it's kind of like a I
feel like a little Ani or some kind of a
like a deep licorish is Flavor if I'm
right on that I don't know it's it's
it's very nice and then they made the
guava punch Brandon and Amanda the guava
punch seeds um and those turned out
phenomenal um and I could probably bring
you a few of those seeds if you're
interested Johnny oh I'm I'm always
interested in growing and learning about
turps of finding different strs that
work for me and stuff like that and that
was the biggest thing and and when when
you find something that works like
that's why I preach it so much to
everybody because [ __ ] works it's like
it's a no-brainer guys it's like if
you're in pain or you're suffering in
any way or you just want to relax or
just like just just have a good time
smoke a joint but that one that one
smell it was literally I would pull it
away and like and that's when I started
looking at you know save the turps
looking at Turpin that modulate and how
it helps me that's why the big thing
with hertia was the tur means he saw how
it helped me so much because hertia
spent a lot of time coming over to the
house and putting trans normal creams on
my neck when I first came out of surgery
so if you guys don't know they took out
my C4 and C5 vertebrae um and that's
what I really started looking at how
tpin were helping me with my pain
because of what Mark brought in and what
Horatio was doing and just everything
that was happening at that point of my
life really pushed me to know that tpin
was a way of being able to standardize
my medicine
by controlling water to chase trying to
standardize my medicine by decar oating
her she was doing a lot of creams and
stuff like that that help with healing
effects which I wish we had that one
recipe U but I mean yeah um now I'm just
talking about you know how great
cannabis is and how the tpin help so
much but that purple punch was something
else man it was definitely and we talk
about the the Hindu Kush has a really
nice flavor uh profile that you might
like too which is a really good one we
got the graceand cut um from Southern
Oregon and grew it out this year and
it's just like ah the old pushes work
very well for me so look at the many
Kush is more of like a pre 96 pre 94
like a Kush uh the Bubba kushes the
Hindu kushes um PK was that much but
those heavier indicas is what works well
for those tpping and those flavors the
high THC more a higher CBD lower CBN um
that was a lot of uh yeah a lot of
research I
beautiful glazed
Cherry um crosses that we did this year
and the the glazed Cherry is like so
dark and deep red on the stock and the
leaf and I really love the flavor we uh
we got some of that it was glazed Cherry
I don't know if it was glazed cherry or
Cross of it from Brandon and Amanda the
rosin and dude it was some of the most
interesting tpine profile I've had from
a hash in a while that was like it
wasn't really like anything else that I
could say it was so interesting and
unique I loved it a lot it was it a
White Lotus glazed Cherry does that make
any does that remind you no okay it was
a glazed Cherry dog I don't know why
okay but that makes sense that could
have been the dog from Jesse and the the
glazed Cherry from Green source is my
guess okay yeah said it was from bio
Vortex actually so that makes sense
yeah it's nice to see the lot of the
Ecuador uh lineage kind of coming back
into into everyone's pet again you know
the indicia stuff was really dominating
for a long time and I've been really
partial to the flavors and to the you
know I love gas but I I want more than
just gas I want I'd love to see you know
the expansion on it it's kind of nice to
see it's
uh it's it's it's really exciting you
know there's a lot of really nice stuff
coming out
I'm growing a lot of really really fun
stuff that's just super turpy you
know
Johnny
me I was gonna say Johnny you might like
the straw Nana uh to get that get the
the 14center cut or something like that
uh that might be a really nice one for
you to run if you like those types of
chines I just actually tried something
that no one's tried yet it's a the
24-week black flaming cross with the
girl SC cookies that was that first when
you saw me like for the first time when
I first L House Church I was sitting
there smoking it and that was kind of
something really nice so I'm I'm playing
with all kinds of different flavors but
I like the old school so I'm kind of
digging into some old vaults of some
8889 91 some of the genetics from just I
guess you know that's what I grew up
with it's what helped me it's what I
like those flavors and all these newer
flavors I mean hitting and I was talking
with Darren about it and stuff like that
there it seems like the gas isn't there
anymore it seems like that old gas is
just missing from the strains with all
these new genetics and stuff like that
so it's the gas that kind of works I I
like that I like that dank I like that
gas I like that flavor terpinolene I
think that's
tpin we grew the Jack we drew grew the
old Jack clone again this year Jack her
yeah Jack is high in terpinolene
Jack daren's that OG Kush from like 91
and everybody wants it because it's high
in that yeah I'm kind of looking at why
are we losing it Mark what are they
doing you just want this you need the
sourer cut then dude I don't know what
any of you guys are talking about I love
everything I love it all I just love all
the different flavors and differences
and I'm like I never seem to be
complaining I always have like five or
six different things that are bommer in
front of me that are just all different
I always have the straw Nana definitely
like always have some
strawana it's like it's it's like
picking the lead violin out of the
orchestra and saying yeah I like the
violin yeah like
the I see I see you guys are mostly
vaping on uh uh pipes with a
torch do you have there he muted
himself what do you have there Sam show
us that put that that's a Swiss perk
it's a Swiss perk for sure with an email
exactly but what's unusual is I haven't
turned it off in three
years it's been
the except for I took it to Jamaica for
a couple of weeks ever since Trump got
elected as soon as Trump got elected he
turned it on right oh my god dude that
was three years ago right I left my Dil
on for about two years and then one day
I was in the shower and I came out the
whole bottom of the bow F off and it
burnt a hole in my counter and I
unplugged it and have put it away has it
been plugged in for years now almost
burnt down my
house don't do that maybe it's because I
have a
davinator they're built in Germany with
discipline yeah they don't they don't
they're not good on humor but they're
great on
engineering that but they work with both
a European and American electricity
that's that's that's that's what I liked
about the dabinator to be honest I
always would like take my dils to
Amsterdam and then I would forget that
like 40 pound inverter converter thing
that they would give me at the
krasnapolsky hotel it was I I carried
that thing around Amsterdam with me
that's how ridiculous this is and when I
finally met the daban dude he was just
like here take one of these check it out
and I traveled all around with that
thing and all I had to do was plug a
different plug into the back of the unit
and I didn't have to carry any giant
thing and I was like okay that is pretty
awesome also works with 12 volt yeah
well now companies make them in EU
earlier ones was a challenge but I know
like yeah denail mini they all make EU
units now so you know what would happen
did you have it happened to you at like
what happens when you take that to a
different country and plug it in with
the different plug with no
inverter I had no issues yeah well
generally what would happen to the dils
when I first got them and I I don't know
what years this was 2000 something it
would uh it would Pooch the whip the
electricity would go through and just
instantly Pooch the Whip and I have a
video where I'm in my little apartment
in the K and the pulsky and I've got the
camera set up and I'm kind of moving
around I'm setting everything up and I
realize it happens I go over I'm like oh
no [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] and I it was so
[ __ ] hilarious I kept it in the video
I was like oh I got to let people see my
reaction to this because it's so
honestly like bummed and pissed and then
I find I remember I brought I remember
this had happened to me already at least
one time so I had brought an extra
whip you may may if you were you'll be
in the video I think it was Tony for
some reason but you might have been in
the video too it's on YouTube it's one
of my videos pluged in the inverter and
you didn't plug in the inverter we plug
I think I might have plugged into the
wall and blew it and we didn't have the
Dil in the be remember that one was that
Spain well that might have been no that
might have been Amsterdam the year
before which is why I brought the second
whip I'd have to go back and watch the
video but it doesn't sound like the one
you did that day after you had done it
in Amsterdam yeah correct that the
customer lost FY
yeah yeah the the
kolski yeah know you have a different
one mine mine worked fine no problem in
Barcelona so yeah U I'm sorry to hear
that but I will know in the future to
take an extra whip just in case dude I'm
telling you that was like a super bummer
hey I wanted to give a shout out to my
colleague uh work colleague and friend
Shahed who it has just recently left in
bark she's going back uh home to Ontario
but she painted this photo of a Tricom
of mine I took this photo at my friend's
house in Port Al Bernie uh a long time
ago I don't know if it was over 10 years
ago the cultivar is uh burmes [ __ ]
incredible is the cultivar but she she
painted this little triome photo for me
up above my shoulder here and I just
wanted to give her a shout out and a
thank you because uh she should have
painted the one with your face in
reflecting in the triome head those were
the clear domes I do have a video where
I put headband hash on a sapphire insert
by denail and I put it on and I it's the
most incredible thing it starts bubbling
like crazy and in every single bubble
you can see my reflection of me hitting
the pipe it was definitely like some
crazy hash Inception uh type [ __ ] but if
you guys haven't seen that I'll uh I
could I could find it because it's
pretty it's pretty ridiculous I like I
want to see that yeah yeah I want to see
that
too moment you actually bubble man yeah
exactly true that's where it began I
think so right [ __ ] mental I hope I
didn't delete it I kind of feel like oh
no there is man in the bubble hey Mark I
like your Garcia
hat oh thank you very much
there's uh we're we're working on
um you know getting the the Jer line oh
go ahead Marcus oh I don't have to say
anything I'm just showing you this is
the video of me in the clear
domes bubble bubble toil and trouble
wait I just saw you right there on the
big one on the right d dude I'm in
everyone if you look closely it's
crazy oh that's funny
Marcus every bubble
dude he's actually bubble men
exactly wow right there yeah I saw it
again there it is Holy
CRA on your YouTube channel like you
should change it like for this bubble
it's pretty funny huh awesome awesome
it's like a s family reunion it's like
all your cell over how many
different dude I wish I had a video of
me making this video and then watching
it while editing it and realizing what
had happened I wish I had a video of
that because I was also very Johnny bees
I was like a child in a candy store oh
it's like you're getting high in all
these different dimensions oh my god
dude as a macro photographer
videographer like I had never captured
anything like that before I'd have been
working with for fractions this is the
first refraction photo I ever took and
if you look closely in the Tricom
there's a reflection of a cannabis leaf
in the two main tricomes in the in the
tall Tricom so that was my first ver
version of it that I ever got and uh I
never really went too much further in it
and then I got that video and so really
this photo and that video are really the
only two refractions that I have where
I'm like in in you know something's
reflected in it looks pretty
cool marus I'm G to ask you something do
you have videos of teaching how to take
macro photographies you inspired a lot
and I just got a macro oh nice well you
know what we'll do another show but
there is one where I invited some really
great macro photographers I I can't
remember maybe Eric nug shots was on
there and uh Shale I think showed up and
I had invited like all all the
guys yeah yeah I I basically had invited
all the people I thought of as sort of
had that had taken M that macro cannabis
photography to the next level I sort of
stopped at a level these guys just took
it to the next level uh doing a bunch of
things that I wanted to do but never
really got uh you know inspired enough
to to make it happen and like for
instance Shale creating his own
measurement scale with the triome heads
and now like you know 118 microns like
that I wanted to do for like 10 years so
I was I hit him up the other day I was
like dude where did you get that
template he's like I made it I just made
the template I was like damn right on
bro that's what's up that's cuz that
shit's not easily available to just go
and find somewhere so we did one show
all of those guys were on it and we
talked about macro photography um I
wanted to invite a variety of people
because depending on the lens that you
have you really need to take your advice
from someone who has that that lens you
know if I give you advice for an MPE
Canon lens and you're using reversals
with Billows and and uh extension tubes
it's a it's not quite the same so um I
don't know what kind of macro camera you
have or lens but uh it makes it inspires
me to do another show invite those guys
on I really wanted to photograph like
resin heads too but not only on the
plant and you you talked about it a lot
like actually photographing the Mel you
know like the Tricom heads like
separated and that's what I want for and
photograph all the single Source we make
so we can like understand more not to
make not only to make photography you
know but also to study the plants like I
think Marcus check out check out duie
duck he's an amazing macro photographer
I've known dubie for years dude his
stuff is whole other level yeah
noell did you ever do stacked shots so
that you increase your dep the field
well that's what these guys do now the
majority of them are stacking shots I
never stacked shots I did Stack
photography I remember the first time a
guy showed me he's like this is how you
do stack photography and he had a rail
system and this intense thing and it was
like moving the camera a tiny little bit
each time he took a shot and I was like
you know I think I've got a better idea
and I put my subject the first stacked
image I ever did it was 35 shots I put
the subject on my bubble box with a felt
bottom on a wooden table and I took
shots and then I pushed the the the the
box over to the right like just a a
millimeter each time and took the shots
his chin was on the floor he couldn't
believe it he'd always been moving his
camera he never thought to move the
subject and so I just did that took 35
shots snapped him together it was
similar to this shot um this has shot
but it was uh it was a little bit
different it looked great but it felt
like to me I think I'm just an old
school photographer it felt kind of like
cheating it it took away that challenge
it is Che
yeah it took away the challenge
of well and reducing the depth of field
I'll tell you something from my
photography and it I started taking my
shots like this one handheld I don't put
my camera on a tripod I want to learn
how to actually take that photo and
manipulate that small depth of field
that I have and I always suggest to
people who want to learn macro
photography learn to do this first and
then learn stacking because if you learn
stacking first when I talk to these
stack guys they can't believe that I'm
taking my shots handheld and getting the
shots that I'm getting yeah automatic
yeah some do some some do stack in the
macro I I have a Lumix gh5 and uh it
does amazing stacking just totally
automatic on the 6K
function nice I I was goingon to say you
know Marcus I think you were the first
person I ever met uh you know I think we
connected as artist and creatives really
and then cannabis was kind of second for
us um who really made sense to me to
look at the plant from a closer point of
view and using your lenses and the tools
that you're using as creatives to make
other projects and other things to learn
about the resin and really look towards
the plant as not only a subject matter
but a vehicle to learn about the
chemicals and the the different things
that you
could um such as extraction and and
whatnot but
um I think that's really the first you
know some of the first photography
Marcus was was from of Tricom heads was
really that I saw other than scientific
photography was really from you um in
the work that you you had kind of put
out um so you know helpful and so
graciously because you know not
everybody was sharing that kind of point
of view at that point in time that that
you know that late 90s early 2000s kind
of black space as we will yeah you know
I got I got to shout out perhaps your
giddy Aunt who took the first clear Dome
shot on a screen that was like Epic on
an overgrow days I met him in London and
he brought me framed framed photo of it
and some beautiful bubble has that he
brought me each day of the of the
conference we did in Wembley Stadium I
puffed Wembley Stadium down hard and
also shout out to monkey from uh really
shout out to Monkey because from my
perspective I wanted to learn macro
photography I asked Jason King who was a
friend of mine at the time I was like
hey dude like you've taken a couple of
macro shots like would you mind showing
me how to take some macro photographs he
said oh yeah yeah no problem uh just as
soon as you show me how to uh design and
manufacture bubble bags in Nepal and
sell them around the world on the
internet and I was kind of like I was
kind of like oh [ __ ] like did I was that
a bad move on my part and I kind of in
the end just took it to the fact that he
was maybe being a bit of a dick and
being insecure but uh when monkey when I
he was taking bug shots on overgrow
shots of uh his insects his pray
mantises that he would order from the
from the mail mail order and crack these
eggs and grow these incredible pray
mantises out that would he would take
photographs of that were just shockingly
beautiful and he had the MP lens and I
hit him up one day and I was like Hey I
want to get into macro photography he's
like okay buy the 65 millimeter MP lens
with the 24 uh e ex M Mt dual flash from
Canon uh set your ISO on a
set your he starts telling me all these
settings as a base and since he did that
I have always shared every I don't even
feel like it's my I always feel like I'm
sharing his information that it's just
like pass it all on even though at this
point it's like 15 years of my own
knowledge that I've learned from taking
macro photography I just don't see why
it would be a bummer for me to to show
people like there are people who will
put time into this in a way that I don't
have the time anymore there are people
who will put time and have access to
certain things whether it's exotic
looking plants or beautiful resins you
know that's the key it's one thing if
you want to take macro photographies of
resin it's another like do you have all
the top quality access to you know the
highest grade material because that
becomes the super duper key these love
birds looking at each other about their
beautiful resins they're staring into
each other's eyes they're like loving
the fact that they got all the flavors
they're like oozing and gooing good on
you guys the other thing Marcus is you
know the there each photographer is
going to bring a different point of view
like I I was inspired by people like
Tobin Yellen and like even Bruce Weber
of shooting like weird black and white
fashion photography and you know the the
ideas that you can you know bring to the
subject is is really kind of really
Broad and and just like cultivation and
extraction there's a lot of creativity
that you can bring to it so I also got a
shout out you deas he was taking photos
in the 80s in Holland with the electron
scan microscope um when I went to the
first Cannabis Cup my first Cannabis Cup
not the first Cannabis Cup was in
1995 uh and I saw his little postcards
he had them at all these different sort
of smart shops and I would buy these
beautiful perfect Tricom shots they
would look so surreal and if many of you
remember my first advertisement in
cannabis culture for Bubble Bags was a
photo that I purchased off of you I
remember remember I was so blown away
that he was willing to sell it for 800
gilders I was just like like it's my
photo he's like it's your photo like you
buy this photo it's yours you can put it
on shirts you can tattoo it on your face
you can like do whatever you want with
it so what I did is I took a full page
ad out in cannabis culture I had one of
my customers at the time from overgrow
be like hey let me do the you know let
me let me create some cartoons on the
Tricom I'm like yeah I want like I want
some like heady people like climbing up
the side of it with bags hanging off
their sides and I want them have
pickaxes and be chipping away at the
head and little chunks of bubble flying
everywhere and that was my first ad for
bubble bags in cannabis Culture magazine
and it was yuk dumas's photo in
1995 that I first saw I didn't take my
first macro photograph till 2008 to give
you an idea how far ahead of his time he
was so shout out to yup that's Jo o p uh
Dumas d m s if you guys want to kind of
look him up and and see what he's into
also uh really stoked about Chris from
candid Kush he's been taking some really
awesome shots and and staying with uh
Caitlyn and Ed from uh the pot snob cast
um they're really doing a cool uh
podcast and they have built a beautiful
Tasting Room in mesino Northern mesino
Caitlyn and Ed and been doing some
really really cool stuff so anyone can
uh should check out candid Kush and the
work that that he's doing and it's just
amazing to see like a far away nug shot
where it's spinning and then it goes in
and then in farther and farther all the
way into like the heads you know from a
far away shot it's like [ __ ] that's
[ __ ] s such a killer I think Eric
might have been the first one to start
doing that I I I could be wrong but I
think it yeah he was in there for sure
yeah I remember seeing it too and being
like this is
spectacular like
absolutely crushing yeah know I love
these guys doing all this
all this great stuff with macro
photographs and Alice has inspired me to
put a list together if you guys have you
know want to send me a private message
with some names and I'll check out the
photography and I'll get a nice like 10
to 12 person group think about it it's
never been done those guys have never
gathered in one spot and and who knows
maybe lives changed maybe they're not
going to want to share their information
as readily as they once did but maybe
they do and maybe is is a real special
show particularly in the sense that it
turns into a lot of other people being
inspired like
I don't get the idea of like if the
whole thing is to pass the flame and
like some little spark starts it over
here and then that gets passed over to
here and it finally makes it to you like
do you really want to put that [ __ ] out
before you pass it on to the next person
or hoard it and you know burn your whole
interior down like I think you're just
supposed to have it for a while and then
share it at least that's how it feels to
me yeah I don't believe in hoarding
information I believe no the message
like free up The Vibes I teach everybody
how to use a rail system how to use
Focus you know push and pull you know
I'd also teach them lighting and I I'd
love I think it would be really I don't
know Marcus I think that that would be a
really cool show to to go
through you know what it means to to
shoot you know it's totally it's a
specialty as much as it is growing andow
growing with Organic soils and hash
making like it is a very specialized
things I kind of one thing about
cannabis is that it has definitely got
me over the years to have to learn an
enormous amount just to learn about it
and to and to be able to share it I
started have now I'm a photographer now
I'm a macro photographer now I'm a
videographer now I'm an editor now I'm a
like it's just like one thing after the
other that you have to learn now I'm
doing like podcasts and live streaming
and I got to learn that like it's just
one thing these things are like you
don't learn them overnight take take a
good amount of uh investment in time so
I I do agree with Michael Poland when he
wrote in the I don't even know if you
wrote this in the botney of Desire but
you definitely spoke about it maybe in a
podcast in regards to how successful
cannabis if you considered cannabis as a
virus like the same way like Corps can
infect an insect control that insect's
brain move it to the top of a tree so
when the spores fruit and and blow out
they get a greater distance cannabis is
truly the corps plant uh to humans to
some of us anyway because it's it gets
in and then it literally is like I
should grow lots of cannabis I should
make lots of hash from the Cannabis that
I grow I should do shows on YouTube
telling people about the Cannabis that I
grow and the hash that I make and how
great it is and that they should do it
and I should do shows on photography on
cannabis and hash and how great it is to
photograph and it's really quite
something how deep it's rooted in some
of our brains it's uh sounds like church
and that's what makes it a true Master
plant that's why it's a master plant and
that's why plant medicine is so
important to us hey I want to put one up
in the air to my man Martin out in
Ireland um hemp in Ireland um amazing
person out there he just had you know
some uh put his aunt you know to rest
and I just want to give him special love
big shout out to my man Martin he's
taken dabs and and taking hits with us
he's holding it down in the UK building
an amazing family really into just glass
and just making things happen so lots of
love to you Martin big love take care of
yourself put one in the
air I'll shout out I'll shout out to
Martin too I met him at uh the in h
Barcelona great cat very educated really
spreading the word doing the right thing
I'm sorry to hear my deepest condolences
Mon frer and wish you nothing but the
best and love
I feel like I must know Martin as well
so I'll give shout out yeah know you do
you do you do he's he's mentioned
meeting you before and he's uh you know
our dragonfly uh Ambassador out in
Europe and you know along with uh the
green grass connection elel green Swiss
Farm uh the regenerative hemp Farm out
in Switzerland um Thomas and and all
those guys out there big love to those
guys as well um also Thailand I know
there's a bunch of family out in
Thailand that watch us too so big love
to the Thai fam and and everyone out
there shout out to everyone shout out to
d420 K who was in the chat for a little
while he might still be in the chat
giving respect to everyone on the panel
and uh yeah absolutely I'll I'll put a
put a little dab in the Banger h g
thanks for this lime pop this lime pop
coming from Dave I got that too nice got
the lime pop from Dave 87
yeah
87 big shout out to
Jean big shout out to Jean from me and
Jean big shout out to Jean big shout out
to Nick out in uh
Michigan Nick risden and the lime Rising
amazing people they were growing one of
their best crops ever this year had a 18
almost 20 foot tall plant and saddest
thing in the world they went to go have
their dog's leg amputated and they came
back and their whole crop was [ __ ]
ripped off a a good a good portion of of
all his weed was was jacked in his yard
and it's it's they're the heart I mean
I'm not going to say they're the hardest
working people out there because
everyone's working so hard but it's
just huge heart and soul in that family
uh to Big Love to the dad you know
everyone who was there um so you know
anyone who wants to help help any of the
people in the fires anyone that wants to
help Nick risen and lime Rising reach
out to us later reach out to us on on
our Instagram and we can
pass the
links maybe we Marcus will send you as
many links as we know like Brett from do
peros and and maybe Sheldon and
different people that we know that have
lost their Farm uh we could put those
links in this YouTube video for people
to check out um like go fun me and
things that are people using to build
their uh their life again because you
know people have lost everything and
whatnot so anyway a lot of people want
to help this is a year where we've
helped you know more people than ever um
you know as a community uh it just seems
like you know you know not every so
often it comes up and all a sudden you
know we got to put it out there so let's
not feel like we've helped people too
much you know we might all as a group
have to continue helping people so um
you know just put let's all put
ourselves out there and reach out to
people in need you know there's there
there's a good good group of people in
need right now so well
said dude [ __ ] rippers like wow what
an absolute piece of [ __ ] low-level
thing to do to steal someone's hard work
like that and their livelihood
medicine yeah it's uh happens
yeah it does in the case of Nick risen
he makes RSO or cannabis oil for himself
to fight limes disease and he's truly
keeping himself alive he would be a good
person to have on the show sometime you
know because he's just so knowledgeable
about strains and medicine and what it
takes to survive um you know he just
recently had a you know crazy skin
eating bacteria and things but he's
making it through a lot of stuff so big
love to him limes is a really serious i'
I've had limes twice and uh it doesn't
go away but when you get bit twice it's
it's pretty serious the second time
around it's really
intense so I feel for him he the true
warrior indeed also and YouTube probably
for having that and there's one I just
took could up to and since you guys are
saying some stuff I just want to shine a
light on the subject too because I think
we talked a lot about the fires in
California and in the west coast and all
over United States and Canada today but
there are big huge fires happening in
Brazil right now too a bit different
than here because it's not natural fires
they're all criminal fires and in the
highest biodiversity places in Brazil so
I just wanted to send some love take
this dab bunch of animals have died a
bunch of animals have burned uh we
actually what was burned right now in
the last last month was over what was
burned in the last 20 years total so it
was very crazy what happened so I just
wanted to like to shine some love over
there for everyone that is here and
everyone that is like watching it too
anyone's taking a dab smoking a joint
just send some love and to all the
spirits of the fires and the winds be
like have mercy on all of us and just
like help us out so I just want to shine
a light on that too and just to CAD I
wanted to offer this
de very well said that's uh that's heavy
when you think of David attenborough's
quote about 94% of all mamalian life on
Earth is humans and the livestock that
they cultivate and the other 4% are all
the zebras and lions and wild animals
that live out in the forest
4% like think of how insane that is and
when you have fires of this size and
that many animals are dying that could
literally be like half a
of like the
4% like 20% of all animal life on Earth
I don't think people really understand
the uh the impact that that something
like that can have we've already you
know messed things up to the point where
cows are taking up like all of the space
that you know wild animals used to take
up it's it's pretty messed up that's
it's insane in Brazil that's what's
going on Marcus that's exactly it they
burn all the land so they can either
plant soy to feed cows or just to have
cows over there it's of course totally
criminal action uh it's a it's a direct
result from a lack of state that we have
and from everyone that being everyone
political being careful with like our
our environment and it's just very very
very sad it's not even modern nature you
know it's like a land that it's not
usually burned so when it burns it burns
it's not like you rebut
like because it's
like think of what's fueling that what's
fueling that is human beings desires to
consume
flesh how about that for a thought yeah
that's an insatiable appetite there's
just you never want to stop eating it
it's like you can't make enough Burgers
you can't feed enough of the world's
grain Supply and enough of the clean
water just give it to the cows give them
the rainforest cut kill everything else
cut everything else down I need my
burger
[ __ ]
yep yeah it
is so that's all sh some love so I have
a
picture I have a picture of these
rotting birch logs behind me because
we're putting these in the earth and
growing weed on top of them at at a
friends at out of some family and here
in the cies building a new farm and
creating uh you know hugle cult culture
and and putting the logs in the earth so
they can last because all these fires
just burn up everything and it goes into
the atmosphere it's gone forever it
doesn't become microbes it doesn't
become long life forever and you know I
just again want to encourage people to
put wood in the earth and sequester the
carbon for as long as possible in the
earth and uh you know it's it's crazy
what's happening with fires in the case
of Southern Oregon in Medford it's
amazing
I really feel for the Rogue Valley I
mean the fire ripped through an urban
area like you were talking Wade like
paradise I mean we're talking from
Ashland all the way through to Medford
10 miles of all towns Phoenix and talent
I mean massive 3,000 Helms I think
that's right some thousands of homes
were were taken out down there and uh in
teila and Southern Oregon they really
mobilized as a community and really did
a great job of protecting their
Community um from the fire from Happy
Camp that was coming over um so
incredible mobilizations have happened
from people so you know um it's it's
pretty powerful and I know Wendy from
sunbus obviously couldn't make it
today oh I I thought she's maybe she is
Gonna Come on she was going to talk
about Ash mitigation on the flower um
and I guess we're going to try and send
her a link to get her on right now um so
you know there was people that had the
fire within a half a mile of their house
just blazing crowning you know just
dropping [ __ ] on their house and stuff
so you know and these are people with
you know a good amount of weed out there
so um you know there's anyone who has
any information on ash mitigation Colin
have you ever had to deal with that or
do you know anyone since you're on right
now um yeah so I have some friends that
are that are out there um everyone's
using uh blowers don't you don't want to
wet your plants down ever you you really
want to to to refrain from doing that um
you just want to go out there and try to
keep it um dry if you can put some hoops
up try to put some hoops up but don't
put anything that's flammable because
that could cause other problems um you
know it's uh you just got to be diligent
and be on it and be patient and and
really you know keep air flows you as
much as you can I've heard two friends
are putting fans out there with Jenny's
um to try to get air flow through the
through the uh through the rows to try
to just uh help mitigate things and you
know just doing your best that's but uh
in terms of uh just ash mitigation is
just blowers um and uh and
fans and uh if you're in a greenhouse
too you can if you have the ability to
run power to it use maybe a carbon
filter and fan so that the air you're
pushing in is clean and you have
positive pressure in the greenhouse so
you're not drawing Ash into the
greenhouse yeah but for full terms you
know that's just tough
yeah that's one of the reasons why we
grow in green houses here in this area
is not only from rain and all that but
you know if if you're concerned about
chem chem trails or things you know even
metals from the sky you know you can I
also totally agree with growing Outdoors
Under the Sun you know but there's a lot
of reasons more and more to have a cover
I think it's even possible with Outdoors
is to to even it to put a shade cloth I
know you don't want to shade your plants
when it's already Smoky but some type of
cloth that can go over the top of your
plants that can stop ash from falling on
it could be really useful you could use
tea steaks if they you know with bamboo
on the top and then put you know even
just a horizontal cloth over your plants
and maybe you'd only have to do that for
a week when the ash is really falling
heavy in the case of Oregon um they had
a really heavy duty
rainstorm right on the tail of all those
those uh heavy so they they had that
week of million Acres burn type thing
and then got you know a heavy rainstorm
on it you know maybe in the case of
rain potentially that could actually
wash it through rather than just turn
mud and I haven't had too many um
conversations with people that have have
have reported anything negative from
that
rainstorm um but you know maybe if
you're trying to wash it with like a
spray or a hose it's a lot different but
I guess with nature with the rains I
think in this case it may have actually
done okay but um that's really good to
hear hopefully Wendy
can yeah yeah because the that carbon I
don't know I I think Dr Mark could
probably talk about uh Mark you could
probably chime in on on what Ash might
or might not do a bit more chemically
than anyone
hereon
come it's gonna flavor the plants right
it's just GNA give it like a smokey
flavor and I think I I remember uh when
we had fires a couple years ago we had
some people on hash Church who are
discussing uh Smoky flavor in some of
the extracts and the water hash uh who
was that Marcus so I'm trying to
remember we this may have been like
about two or three years ago on hash
church and there were
fires and um we were talking about this
very issue and whether or not it comes
through and extracts um again you could
probably clean it out of the distillate
that's probably not I think that's the
only way honestly I've never seen it
come out any other way it's it's totally
R marus do you remember who we had on
that we were talking to this about do
you remember this off the top of my head
there's been so many people that have
been on over the years like we probably
are over a hundred different
people yeah I seem to remember that what
we were talking about again is that you
know again a lot of folks who grow not
necessarily for oil markets or for
extraction who growth or flower markets
were saying hey we can't can't sell our
flour can we extract it and there was a
whole surge of again people wanting to
actually get into extraction just
because they had to you know do
something to recoup the material that
they lost because of the
fire and there was a bunch of smoky
material on the open market back then I
probably take it that there will be
again this time and it'll be interesting
to see if some of these folks who track
it who track like uh like wholesale
index prices like uh cannabis benchmarks
for one I'm sure at&amp; you know about
cannabis benchmarks right so what they
do is that's a website that um uh uh
basically based on large transactions
with large license dispensaries they're
able to track the wholesale price of
cannabis flour and what you see is in
these kind kind of cases again Supply
demand Economics work where again if
there's a constant Supply and all a
sudden the supply tightens up or it
doesn't smell as good and then people
are now extracting you know you're going
to see fluctuations but typically what
they do is they follow uh things like
outdoor and differentiate outdoor from
light dep and uh you know um indoor and
look at the various wholesale prices and
typically those numbers right 18 are
always around like anywhere between
1,200 to 1300 a pound to as much is
1,500 a pound and they they
move a little bit right but right it
fluctuates it's gonna go up slightly
this year you know uh because of fires
and also local
regionalizations um and Market
stabilizing uh but also just because of
uh yeah here in California we're still
over taxed how's it going there in
PA it's still I mean you know our
governor wants to do legalization and
legalization is on the ballot in New
Jersey and it seems like there's going
to be just this domino effect between
New Jersey Pennsylvania and New York and
that legalization is just right around
the corner and um you know I the the
product in the dispensary 18 to tell you
the truth is pretty good and comparable
in terms of pricing of like what you'd
almost get on the black market I mean
certainly Black Market is still alive
and plentiful all throughout the East
Coast Black Market in New York is still
you know it's even when legalization
happens I don't think it's going to go
away anytime soon hey can we use the
term can we use the term elicit Market
you know we're trying opposed to using
the term Black Market weed what about
traditional Market yes Trad
traditional
Market Market I like traditional markets
y youall know what I mean but I think an
interesting Trend and at&amp; you could
probably speak to this is in California
you know my son's out in La now and he
goes to dispensaries now and he's in the
industry extracting so he's seeing a
little bit of this dynamic in the
marketplace which is uh the popularity
of beverages he says that going to be
going to um dispensaries and buying
beverages by the cases you know like
these fruity limey whatever beverages I
think there's all kinds of new products
that are out there in the market but uh
I guess that being a new category and
again not something necessarily you can
make at home right unless you're making
your own soda or taking an extract and I
don't know it would be interesting to
see if you can take like an extract that
you could buy at a dispensary and use
like one of those home soda makers and
try to make a carbonated beverage with
your own canabo you know I I I I don't
know if that would work but I mean that
why wouldn't it I mean everything we
made is created by you know was created
by patients for patients originally so
but yes there is an uptake more if
there's an uptake in Edibles period in
the covid era you know uh people were
you know we had the evoi problem
uh the cartridges so cartridges have
dips uh they're starting to come back
but you know flowers and definitely
Edibles and concentrates too people have
a lot of time to sit around apparently
so we've seen an uptick definitely in
the quality as well of the the rosin
we've had access to and uh natural
extractions as well as the extracted
products are definitely getting better
the quality of the flow is still not to
where I want it to be for the price
point I still think it's about two price
points higher than it should be uh
compared to when I was actually dealing
internally of selection Etc so I thought
the market corrected itself better in
Nevada and California it's still too um
production for my uh expectation there
are some some quality uh uh craft
Growers uh but this is the problem with
the fires the craft Growers of the ones
that are being hit very hard where as
opposed to most of the indoor production
is going on without any type of problem
but the Exotic Outdoors [ __ ] man it
pisses me off it's challenging and
painful to see uh the loss because one
of my main suppliers like I said
Foxworthy Farm You Know M Martin and
them lost access or had problems prior
they were able to save some and get some
out as the fires were encroaching but
have to see how it's harvested and you
know dry to see exactly the quality of
what it'll be so a lot of people are
dealing with this reality right now and
it's it's frustrating and it's sad to
see on top of that fire season ain't
over you know we're still in the midst
of it here so you know blessings to
everybody and to all of you stay safe
stay sound stay uh wet as much as
possible keep it damp out there talk you
were talking about markets I just wanted
to say black markets matter
black blim oh that is so
not could be too
soon one thing the one thing that's for
sure is that there's a lot more there's
a lot more processing
capability today uh than just simply
like two or three years ago so that
process capability see the dog agrees
with me that that processing capability
means that there's now people who are
doing toll processing in cannabis so you
can grow cannabis legally you can bring
it to a p processor and they can make
oil for you so that's kind of cool the
other thing is that you know in hemp you
know we were talking a little bit about
this before you know I mean that bill
that's in Congress right now which is
the
8178 I think which is the thing that's
going to basically regulate CBD as a
dietary supplement this just totally
needs to happen because right now the
painful thing that epidex has done is it
put CBD on a list of being an active
ingredient of an FDA prooved drug and
you can't put active ingredients in food
or Cosmetics or dog food so what's going
to enable that is this this this thing
that I pulled up the thing just on my
computer for a second now um was
the uh act that's currently in I think
it's called 8178 it's either blumau or
the other guy from Oregon who's
basically put this thing forward
supposedly even Mitch McConnell wants
this to happen so again that's sort of
like the gate unfortunately in our
government of whether or not things are
actually going to get voted on is the
head guy in the Senate has to be okay
with it to bring it to the floor for a
vote
supposedly they have bipartisan uh
support of this but what this is going
to do is this is going to carve CBD out
of the process that um you were talking
about before the indd process which is
an investigational new drug thing with
the FDA you know they want to carve it
out and put it into the dietary
supplement thing kind of like the kol or
the vitamin C or the other things that
you could extract from Plants put it
into a capsule or how about that [ __ ]
Prevagen what the [ __ ] is that right
some thing from a jellyfish they extract
jelly fish put it into a capsule give it
to senior citizens and now it all a
sudden improves their memory I mean what
the [ __ ] is that you know Prevagen right
so I mean that's the category that CBD
and and tobacco actually all belong in
or maybe not tobacco but um but what do
you think of that interm rule the DEA
did recently on the hemp farm bill and
don't you know the way it kind of opens
up for GW because there's a thing in
there that says anyone with FDA uh
approved products correct we no longer
have to use have permits or licensing
for import or export I'm like listen
like these guys are getting ready to
clear the inter okay so what the interim
final ruling is is an attempt by the DEA
to harmonize the controll dangerous
substance act with the American
agriculture Improvement act aka the farm
bill right so the farm bill basically
says if it's below 3 THC and the plant
it's legal it's hemp high five go grow
your hemp right they forgot that as soon
as you Buck those hemp plants and you
take not the entire plant at0 three now
you take the more ENT parts of the plant
as soon as you trim it to extract it to
distill it to isolate it oh way over
yeah well except the is if you're
talking about CBD isolation portion but
the dirty secret is is again we talked
about this on hash Church a couple times
at .3% in a typical yield of these high
yielding varieties like lifter and
cherry wine and whatnot box and all
those uh on a typical yield of of acre
of hemp if you grow like a drug Variety
in in a drug variety kind of way that's
almost like five pounds of TC per acre
it's a lot of THC right that's what I'm
saying it's a lot yeah and so they never
you know gez the intellectual furnaces
weren't burning hard enough to realize
that well even if we regulate this stuff
and put this stuff as0 three in the
plant that every step along the way
until you're in the diluted you know
tincture obviously the diluted tincture
is back down the point three or whatever
it was in the plant but everything along
the way which is called working in
progress hemp extract is all is all
basically illegal just based on the
amount of of of THC and the whole Del
not only that Mark but the truth of it
is if you have a high CBD variety that's
over 10% the odds are it's hot if you
let it mature because
CBD synthesis produce about a 25 to1
ratio of THC yeah yeah yeah Sam I I was
in a field yesterday just right down the
road here in Maryland that's growing a
high CBG variety of something called
lifter and there is no THC in that
variety at all zero none zil I can
second that
Mark it's got It's got about one or two
per in dry weight it's got about one or
two perc CBD but it's got like about
18%
cbga so it's completely got all of its
syntheses shut down at least after after
what the the got the the the geranial
alic transferal phosphatase whatever the
thing that puts together cbga but all
the other syntheses that either make
cbca or thca or you know cbda we're
we're all basically shut down in that
variety so I'm really interested to see
what that's like I have a small nug of
it downstairs I'm drying it I want
to smoke it people have asked me they're
like What's that like when you smok I
don't
know I was gonna extract CG we developed
High CBG varieties more than 15 years
ago what what kind of level I mean 15%
that's pretty it's pretty high right
that's pretty high I agree and ours also
had little to no THC at all but you
don't smoke CBG for recreational
purposes yeah yeah so how does it make
you feel does it make you feel high or
relaxed or not not at all I but then I
don't like CBD I don't like CBG I don't
like CBC none of them get me high and I
don't like them I smoked get high not to
get healthy because I'm already
healthy did just crushed Co out in 24
hours how about
that and he's patented it
probably Mark uh I've been uh I've been
dry sifting some CBG and it's it's
really uh a nice resin to work with it
produces it's unlike CBD where it's um
very viscous and very low yielding and
um typically a lot darker in Amber and
by Nature it's for some reason so what's
a full melt what's a full melt dab of
that like I mean what is that what I
feel just to me the the the feeling I
get from it when I'm at at kind of base
level which still has I still have Delta
9 in my system um I feel kind of relaxed
um if I'm really in tune with myself and
I think individuals that are more
sensitive to canono and minor canono
that don't have as much Delta 9 in their
system feel a bit more sedated from it
um that's what I commonly hear um so
there's you know it's it is still very
individual and that's it's still
anecdotal at best right now um how
everyone's kind of tapping into it but
there is I see a lot of Promise it's
from the extraction side I think it's
it's really desirable I think I'm I'm
really curious to see what what I can do
with some fresh
frozen well we developed it 15 years ago
for medicinal use absolutely but we
tried it for recreational use and like
THC pure thcv varieties or CBG varieties
or CBD or CBC they don't really have
true recreational value uh I mean some
people will say CBD calms you down and
okay but that's not getting you ripping
High which is what I what about together
um Sam like what about all of these
major and minor cannabinoids together at
various levels would you agree that you
know removing removing one of them would
change that expence not tried them all
but of course everybody's tried uh equal
mixtures of CBD and THC because all of
the imported sifted hash traditionally
was a mixture of THC and CBD sure
there's some arguments out that the
cannabinoid synthes in terms of the
Entourage effect you know the
General subject that we kind of touch on
you know to remove one percentage of
let's say CBC or CBG from a you know
cultivar profile which completely
reshape the experience of that cultivar
you know same thing on the on the
turpine
synthes um so it's I don't know if
anyone has any thoughts on that but it's
it's it's something that I've I've been
kind of thinking about lately I
traditionally read High th
varieties for recreational now when I
was interested in medicinal varieties we
created the world's first CBD only
variety the same thing with CBC CBG thcv
we we did all those uh but they were not
for recreational use they were for
medicinal
use yeah I see I use the full cannaboid
spectrum so I mix all my water
concentrates together
uh and
sees and then I put all my bhos Etc
together and mix them because for me
that's work for me is a full spectrum if
I try one thing I get a little bit of
this I try something else get a little
bit of this so for over a decade
personally I've just mix it all together
into you know um and keep adding to it
like an everlasting Gobstopper so that
sounds like full spec
drums yes yeah but that's works for me
because I
have to but you know because some people
can find a certain flower specifically
works for them I have because of my Gulf
War syndrome I have various different
symptoms from nerve damage to nausea to
migraines to you know uh different
situations so each one sort of matters
so you know combining The Ensemble
effect of them all allows me to be
productive and allows me to be a part of
society
feel smoke what did you smoke in the 60s
and the 70s before there were the minor
canono variety uh I was hanging out in
my mom's ovaries uh you know we're
having a great time you know me and the
other eggs we were all like up no I
didn't hey Sam you're old it's just for
me yeah I mean I didn't get turned on
till I was you know uh yeah 1819 so and
I didn't really get turned on to real
concentrates until I was was out here in
California in my early 20s so I mean
your
experience you were you were well into
it way before it's just this is what I
found over time for me during the access
because early on in in oaksterdam I was
able to get a lot of quality water hash
too I had the original machine from
working at the Galaxy gallery back in
the uh late 90s so I was making my own
water hash and people were Contracting
with me to make their water hash for
them because they'd never seen a machine
that could make quality hash like this
that bubbled I mean that blew our minds
you know so I just would initially just
take scrapings off of the coffee filters
and then mix them together in a coffee
grinder and that's what started it for
me and
so honestly you're way ahead of us by
decades you didn't know what canono you
were smoking because until when was was
it uh
1990 or no wait till 2000 there was not
analytical labs available in
California and Sam when do you think the
first analytic you know analytics really
were for for cannabinoids you know
because it you're you're touching on
this this
idea people like Dr have been doing this
for decades and decades we began our
work in in uh the very early 1990s where
we got an analytical lab which was uh we
checked with Dr BR Eisen with the same
sample to Brian Dr BR Eisen and Dr o and
our lab and we got identical results and
we knew we were doing it right and who
was running that lab Sam like was Da was
Dave Pate the main chemist there correct
he was the chemist that uh was hired to
do all this work correct
so at that time you you guys were really
kind of for you know the this is really
great because it's you know the stuff I
look at every day you know is probably
on the shoulders of the work that you
and your team was doing you know in
terms of the analytics so you know what
we you know what we're looking at from
in terms of the micral test is really
kind of I would still say kind of very
limiting in terms of what we're able to
see and test for would you kind of
agree uh yeah our Focus was not that to
be honest we were growing organically
and we didn't worry about it because we
were not selling it but that said I mean
uh the truth of it was no nobody had
minor canbulat nobody knew what they
were and uh if your variety happened to
have some in it you didn't know
it right so yeah that's why right so
what varieties do you think were what
regions of the of you know the world in
terms of of the you know where things
kind of stem from post ice age do you
think a lot of these these miners were
really kind of coming from or were they
really selectively
bred no they they were all over when the
way we bred High single cannaboid
varieties of a minor cannaboid was for
example
thcv I used California orange because it
had small amounts in it I used a Thai
variety that had small amounts I used an
Afghan variety that had small amounts
and I used a South African variety that
had small amounts of thcv and then we
self those for generations and then
combined them all at the end and had a
variety that was well over 10% THC but
little to no
THC right wow and we did the same thing
for all the minor conoids took about
four or five years for each one of them
but we were doing a lot of them at the
same time so you guys went through like
a whole gener you went through several
Generations like you went oh we went
through several Generations absolutely
correct and everything was was uh uh
analytically analyzed everything so that
we were able to use the next
generation's best of for that targeted
compound so the were you guys able to to
Really track what what asset for you
know what acid forms were really
happening at what times through the
process did you guys get that could we
weren't so interested in that but yes we
had hlc and we had uh gcfd for the tping
because I think that the thing I'm
trying to understand now is is how we
can track that through certain varieties
to to feno hunt and you know to to
maximize the the most out of a you know
and you said variety to get not only the
best phenotype but the best
chemotype well my my suggestion is grow
them organically in the ground I I used
a greenhouse but I lived in Holland I
didn't have a choice so uh and uh they
will Express the canono turine maximum
that that variety can do and uh yeah I
mean it's not hard to grow excellent
weed as long as you don't make stupid
mistakes but we all do yep well that
means we shouldn't DeForest then we
should take all that and do what uh Josh
was saying right wait wait wait wait
wait wait grow organically with it Sam I
thought you were perfect what are you
talking about he who has patented
everything I thought you were the
perfect well I'm So Perfect know I'm not
quite perfect
well I appreciate the information Sam
and the knowledge it's uh you know it's
it's something you know I'm always
trying to pick up
on uh hey uh Sam when were you first
that early lab I would say Dr Ole Bren
Eisen and Dr Mulan Associates uh were
three of the very very best uh and
that's who we emulated and we considered
our uh leaders
and when we got the same results from
the same samples uh as they did we knew
we were doing something
right when when were you first educated
on Beaver tpin there uh
Sam well the first time I went to Canada
and
uh I can't help but think Horatio would
be smiling knowing we're still talking
about Beaver
turps what's funny is that they're
actually used in the food and fragran
raspberry yeah like raspberry Rasberry
flavoring vanilla raspberry bunch of
Beav TPS yep the Beavers sitting there
in Canada giving us the
raspberry you know earlier
about I wanted to go back uh really
quickly hi everybody sorry hi Kelly I
had a million going on hi oh my gosh you
good to see you oh I love all you guys
so awesome to see you Kelly you're like
you're like a beacon of
light I feel the same about you mark a
you guys um I was just saying you know
we were talking about the mitigation of
Ash and a lot of small farmers are
getting hit and ATN you were just saying
you know Sun grown it's getting hit
harder than ever and we really need
those small farmers to be successful
it's one of the single most important
things that we could do on the planet
Earth is to help small organic farmers
be successful and one of the ways that I
just wanted to say to everybody out
there who's listening who has a small
farm your success is really important to
us it's important to many of us and I
just was thinking you know maybe being
done earlier try to put something in the
ground that's going to have all of your
crops done a good you know a good
portion of it done early whether that's
these beautiful Auto flowers that are
coming on you know some really beautiful
um tricomes that they're done in early
August or to do light deps small light
deps so at least part of your crop is
going to be finished before the Fire
season comes on because it's just really
really important one thing one thing I
don't like about Auto varieties is you
can't grab the best clone so easy easy
and use it for years you got to be
reading it for
seeds and can be a pain in the butt so
uh it it really depends but I just want
to mention there's a company up there in
Canada called SRA and they have
developed a way to keep Mother plants of
Auto varieties so uh anybody who needs
their services can check them out
and also because we've come into the
legal Market you know keeping clones for
a lot of sungrown people is not
important breeding is absolutely
important having seeds direct sewing
into the ground you said it earlier Sam
you know direct sewing deep soil beds or
how we're going to reach the ultimate
potential of the plants so we're really
encouraging these small farmers to have
their own breeding stock that's
biologically intelligent
to their soils to their areas to their
zones and the more that we breed for an
early finishing we can really beat out
those fires and these farmers can have
great success and the Heart Rock lion
Claw is so dank and filled with flavor
and buds are
super uh solid and I mean it's it's he's
doing I mean in Daniel's case at Heart
Rock I mean he I think he did 140
crosses this year and he's planning on
doing 300 crosses next year so and for
good breathing power to the
SE and for good breathing you really do
need yeah and and also clones if they're
part of the breeding
program oh I mean there's a reason to
keep clones there is but I I don't know
if you have to in the case of like you
know Auto flowers I you know but I'm
there's a there's an intention to
everything so if your intention is to to
do some certain thing with a clone and
you know well I don't know you know I
think that we could really have that
discussion I think that that's a really
interesting topic Sam because when you
take clones you're really starting to
mitigate the immune response of that
plant then you have to take that plant
inside you may have to put it into a pot
it's no longer in a microbial rich
environment it's no longer in the
sunshine can't have round and I think
for small farmers I think that it's
really great for them to continually
choose their varietals by using
chemotypes a lot of these Farmers now
have field tests that they're able to
look at their chemotypes out in the
field and they're really able to track
what it is that they're looking for and
they're able to do it intelligent it's
it's just an interesting if we're going
to be just small farmers
and not just talking about science and
we're not just looking at it in a
scientific way but we're get out a good
triome Rich crop that can be used out on
the market breeding seeds is a wonderful
um opportunity for them so I just wanted
to bring up the other side of that um
you know and not taking clones okay but
I I for example I maintain my mother's
in the ground 15 feet
tall wow I wish I could do that Sam I
mean I I have I we have some big mothers
we got a whole room of them but even
even at a at a facility that's that's a
big M we we change our mothers out more
often than that um to try to keep them
more vigorous and try to keep the you
know as much uh Vigor and and as least
pathogen you know filled as as we can
you know because there's a lot of things
that go along Pest and pathogen problems
because I use so many bio controls as
preventatives to be honest yeah mother
lovers Hey so uh so Sam do you I mean I
Kelly I think you know the it's an
interesting topic because um I think
about a lot of these things and you know
there's when you're talking about saving
seed and saving varieties Sam wouldn't
you agree it's good to save save the
seeds and save you know save those those
potential uh new phenotypes and
chemotypes that you could get from you
know starting Offspring from bringing
things together that you know you you
may have hand selected even though it
might not be 2,000 or 5,000 of each to
to keep the gene pole as we say um I
think it's a good thing um I I think I
I've kept clones for 22 years 24 years
actually um but I also still without a
problem right so but I've also started
new seeds and I also recognize the value
especially now when I'm now that I'm
growing at scale for commercial reasons
we're starting like all types of
different varieties and I'm seeing some
really interesting things that I would
have never thought as a younger self to
even you know to even try or attempt to
do because I just have these clones that
I just know so well to be honest I think
the closest uh agricultural crop
similarity wise is
strawberries when you want a new
strawberry variety you you cross a bunch
of different varieties that H wild or
whatever that have the traits you're
after then they grow out 20,000 seeds
and they select the 10 or 20 that are
the most favorable and then they
reproduce Runners from those mother
clones and uh they eventually have
millions of Runners to use as a
production crop and that's the way
canvas is sure and I I think to Kelly's
point I think that's you know I think
it's a good thing to I don't know
personally I think it's a good thing to
be exploring and uh understanding you
know what different varieties could do
do together because you know it's
expansive in terms of the creative
aspect it's Natural Evolution I mean you
you know without that the you know the
Clone never changes so obviously you're
going to be doing seed breeding you know
but it's fun to keep like a sour diesel
forever for example you know what I mean
like who doesn't want to who doesn't
want to grow a whole entire Greenhouse
of Sour Diesel like come on right and
and the recessive traits always come up
when breed with it so it's really
difficult to recreate um and that's the
other thing for me that I'm interested
in is trying to work with the dominant
traits that on some of these really
Elite things that I have and you know
it's it's fun to to try to see what
other Offspring can you know can kind of
do I think uh Marcus and I were were
talking to a friend uh to a friend of
his the other day he was or a little
while ago on a on a chat and he was
talking about using the sky jarro from
meene to to breed with his other crop
because it was so non-invasive so it
really brought the dominant traits out
in the in the the parent stock that he
was using so that you know it's I think
there's a lot of value to
that it is
true
Sor I keep
clones for for breeding and pro
production but I every year grow the
majority of the plants from seed because
that's where the new exciting [ __ ] is
yeah yeah and you know it's a lot like
an apple tree you can you can have this
beautiful gorgeous apple tree and it's
the best apples ever and you can seeds
off of that apple tree and you're never
going to be able to recreate that same
apple tree so when you do you know bre
with that clone or whatever it's never
going to be the same so there is
some beauty in the sour diesel being
held forever or that Jack hair that you
know is in Eugene I'm so stoked that
people are holding on to that with app
the Cavendish banana they gra them they
gra them because you can gra a mother
onto one billion different graphs and
you get a branch of that unique Apple so
there's easy ways to maintain apples
forever resin Ranch resin Ranch what's
up in the house
there just stopping by and Alice was
like hey you want to say
hi how you guys all
doing good man how are you doing I like
the shirt we're uh we're
surviving are you yeah we're getting
getting pretty impacted by the fires
we've been by the August the August
complex fire in your area fire is uh
been smoking out the farm yeah uh down
here in Sebastapol we've pretty much
been flanked by fires all
summer so it's been totally I feel like
it's starting to take a toll on my
health at this point yeah you know I
wanted to come on and that's what I
wanted to talk about today you know
really quickly I didn't know if this was
uh the right time to do that but just
about you know how we can you know
mitigate some of the toxic intake of the
smoke in the ash you know we've been
really focused on our plants because our
plants is our income our plants is our
future
but our health and well-being is also
our future and how we're gonna you know
make our next decisions and how we're
going to move forward we really need to
be healthy and I just wanted to talk
about a few things that people could be
allying with down there so you know
let's let's talk about that is this a
good time are we like cool come on in I
got nothing going on and cool
I just wanted if you wanted to come in
and talk about some updates that were
really important that people need to
know in the region and area first or uh
updates it's kind of hard to stay up
with I I just tell anybody get on the
calire website because it's I mean it's
changing some days it changes
hourly uh the August complex fire is
definitely taking a major toll on the
Cannabis industry in Humble trend this
year I think more than any previous
year uh definitely more Farms actually
burning than just being impacted by Ash
and
smoke uh I don't want to get into the
stories I'm hearing about how calir is
treating the situation up there on some
properties uh it's just messed up that's
all there is to it and we I
think it's pretty eye openening most the
people in the room I think would agree
with me that as human beings we need to
open our eyes up to what's going on and
make some serious changes because and be
aware human beings we can't we can't
live like this you know that's kind of
the thing I was thinking about the other
day I remember a Discovery Channel show
on the end of the world and them talking
about climate change and massive fires
in the west that would burn uncontrolled
and air quality and I remember thinking
oh man that sounds horrible but that
probably won't happen in my lifetime and
here we are living it so so like the
last two weeks pretty much have had a
low grade headache the whole time really
low on
energy uh and when we looked into that
they they call it a carbon headache
apparently from inhaling so much smoke
and like you said yeah we all worry
about our plants because it's our income
and I definitely have put myself in some
situations this year that probably yeah
does put my health on the line in order
to salvage the Cannabis which
I'm not sure how I feel about that
personally at this
point which is you know we always you
know we we hold this plant so high and
we do so much for it but and when it's
your income it is hard to make that call
that I need to walk away like it's not
easy and you were faced with that this
year yeah yeah I mean we've been faced
with it more than once yeah and then I
have uh you know a farm I consult on
that is up on spyrock which which is now
starting to be evacuated really been an
evacuation warning for a while I don't
think spyrock it's gonna actually get to
that point
but we've said that a few times and it's
crossed the eel they didn't think that
was going to happen you know
so fingers crossed Spyro yeah well that
that that carbon headache that you're
feeling is just massive inhalation of
smoke and what happens is there's a
restriction of the capillaries in the
body because the body starts to react to
such a massive change in the environment
we are so much a part of our environment
like the Earth resonates at like a 7.82
or something like that don't quote me on
the same numbers but you know that
humans resonance and our bodies resonate
on the same exact you know uh frequency
so when there's like a whole lot of
smoke and fire in the air not only is
there a whole lot of smoke and fire in
the air but the actual
Resonance of the vibration of the area
and the zone that you're in actually
changes so it's incredibly detrimental
to us on lots of different levels so not
only are we getting smoke inhalation but
the resonance is changing and we need to
be dealing with mental health issues you
know a lot of people are like whoa
another day of smoke not only is it that
we're yeah in covid and that people are
having restrictions all over the place
but we're dealing with the lack of
sunshine uh you know Ash and smoke and
also the resonance changing so in order
to take care of your internal health you
know allying with oser right now oser
root is so so important you can get it
in tincture you can get it in um any and
and it's found in the hills of
California some people call it bear
grass you can and and go oh yeah OSHA
and that's something that we can really
find in a lot of zones and regions um
also any kind of immune
stimulants uh eonia right now is being
dug
up I can't say you know more than ever
this is a time to really look at our
Farms look at our little Gardens and
what haven't we planted do we have
burdock root really good for cleaning
the blood right now uh also activated
charcoal taking a lot of activated
charcoal because when you're breathing
in these toxins you know it's actually
being lodged into different areas of
your body and activated charcoal can
help wash it out and I guess and
bentonite clay is another one zealite
clay even more activated more charged
easy to find um and also you know your
indigenous
microorganisms however you all are you
you know making indigenous
microorganisms for your plants make sure
that you're drinking a little bit of
your em a little bit of your lactic acid
bacteria culture your sourkraut water
your k Chi all of those things that are
going to boost our microbiome is
incredibly important right now and what
I wanted to say last is the most
important is water we have to be
drinking water you have to be drinking
more water than you even think that your
body can be handling right now even when
your belly is full of water you have to
be drinking more water because just like
the plants and in the air all of that
Ash is taking all of those humidity
particles out of the air and it's
causing an incredible dehydration in the
air and in our body and when we have
dehydration all that does is exacerbate
all of the other maladies that we might
be holding on to which is absolutely the
same as our mental health so if we're
already on the edge of not feeling so
well we get dehydrated it's over it's
done we're we're in a hole of of
depression or not feeling well Al so
really important drinking water and and
and opening up our hearts right now to
compassion for those people that are
really needing help I think as human
beings we are here on this planet to be
a collective Consciousness and now more
than ever we need to recognize that a
part of our planet is really is really
hurting right now so whenever we can
those people who aren't on the west
coast send Good Vibes to the West Coast
send Good Vibes to our brothers and
sisters are out there it's meaningful
prayer matters you know so people on the
west coast feel like they're getting
burned out right now I mean you know I I
think you may be talking about that Todd
whatnot I mean it's uh that's kind of
the other thing is this the stress level
that I know I'm operating at and I can
imagine that everybody else in my
position is operating at this year on
top of it just being 2020 and all the
other crap going on is it's pretty
insane that I've actually gotten
comfortable operating at this stress
level it kind of scares me and yeah it's
just this year more than others has me
rethinking things like when I first
hopped in Alice said you guys were
talking about you know starting earlier
different time all that stuff I was just
talking about that the other week that
yeah totally has me rethinking how I
want to run the
gardens and do that you know I don't I
don't think I'm GNA even attempt a
second depth next year yeah diversify
and really make use your product go
ahead hard for me to pull off a second
depth in my spot just as it is and then
stuff like you know we flipped the Hoops
the fire happened the next day we didn't
see the Sun for three weeks my plants
went through the roof you know node
spacing is like a
foot it's you know it's it's and the
full terms do all right because they got
to set up earlier in the before Fire
season they seem to handle it a lot
better they they don't seem to get smoke
damage as easy because they've already
kind of Co it up yeah know back to more
full terms more seed starts less
STS yeah and here we are you know we're
allying with a plant that's an adaptogen
and we uh you know as cannabis Farmers a
lot of us who have been in this for a
long time have been really adaptogenic
to laws to regulations to still trying
to get our crop out so I really
encourage us as a community even though
we're feeling really beaten down we are
resilient we're an incredibly resilient
group of people I've never met a more
resilient group of people all over the
world so let's take that resilience and
become adaptogens and switch up what we
need to so we can still get out the good
medicine and if we need to just have one
depth that's even bigger that's earlier
or you know even longer varietal that go
even way further you know let's also
talk about that we've been talking about
finishing earlier but what about those
you know really long flowering
SAS you know thin Leaf varietals that go
and go and go that aren't really done
until the beginning of December a lot of
people in California can be doing you
know those varietals well you know
they're well out of uh you know the Fire
season one other thing I wanted to say
is that as well as the Cannabis is an
adaptogen the other thing to Ally with
is our medicinal mus
mushrooms are really important a lot of
people are doing micro sweet medicinal
mushrooms so incredibly important right
now um and also so many people are doing
uh cubensis and and really doing a lot
of micro dosing Ann Arbor Michigan woo
just legalized or just decriminalized
cubensis um or any kind of psychedelic
plant uh uh medicine which is really
awesome and people who are experiencing
depression you know a lot of really
super low dosing psychedelic mushroom
has been really helpful for people too
and also um also agaron and Corps are
both very supportive to the lungs so you
I to use a gacon and Corps in teas and
ingest that is going to be supportive to
your lungs and turkey tail as well so
you know the other thing that I was
saying just really quickly is that we
were talking with Wade yesterday with
tricks uh and potent ponics on his
awesome live broadcast that he did all
day
yesterday um yeah is that cannabis is
just such an incred an incredibly
intelligent being we've been working
hand inand with this plant for so long
its intelligence is ours our
intelligence is it I just really believe
that those of us who bred 2020 seeds
it's just incredibly important for us to
get get out that that
information this year is so potent it's
so powerful it's so transformative we're
in this this state of of new discoveries
and the cannabis plant is also feeling
that vibration of us being in the
gardens every day and then those plants
that are the seeds that are being bred
then being popped next year we'll have
all of the intelligence we'll have maybe
even all all of the answers to to uh the
future remedies that we need so it's so
important to just keep popping that
those seeds especially the ones that we
made this year I'll end it yeah I gotta
say uh just with you saying about the
seeds created this year all that stuff
uh you know the last two seasons it kind
of got away
from kind of what Joey taught me with
this big seed starts start early they're
overall they're generally going to be
healthier more bug resistant and got
into a scene that really we really had
to make it kind of make money as you
guys know we need to pay our bills and
all that stuff so we went more to the
depth thing and this year I talked my
partner and hey let's let's clear a
little area and do some big full terms
again and I gotta say just with again
with all the crap that goes on I'm fully
sold on big seed starts again and
starting from seed and like you say they
have all that knowledge now of this year
and what what's that going to be
advantageous for us in the future if you
know the Cannabis starts figuring out on
its own hey I need to finish earlier
because it's going to be Smoky as hell
like and there's got to be genetic
coding on the evolution that says that
the cannabis plant has lived through
fire and its Evolution like there's
probably important tpin that come out in
it protecting itself from Ash I mean who
right Mark I mean
there's actually actually so the one
thing I do know is that after a forest
fire um what sort of comes out of the
ash from the forest the Brea of forest
is there's a compound that's that fits
into a class of compounds called
butenolides and this particular
butino is actually one that um enhances
seed germination and it totally makes
sense from a natural perspective point
of view so after for fire happens what
happens there's a whole rebirth in the
forest well when it turns out that the
compounds that are in the soot are
actually the compounds that actually
encourage seed germination it kind of
makes sense it's Mother Nature using her
own chemistry set to sort of enhance you
know the replacement of the of the force
and you get the fire
weed he had a fire fire I no like fire
weed is the pink plant that grows after
forest fires it's it's one of the first
plants that comes up yeah it should be a
huge year for morel's next spring and
just because you're bringing that up
which is really odd is I found that the
that the Cannabis aphid the bong aphid
the only other plant that they as
interested in a as the cannabis plant is
the fir Weed really notice that just
just saying and also you know if we're
thinking about the plants mitigating
themselves into the next year what about
the idea that they're feeling our energy
every time that we're in the gardens and
they start mitigating new you know chemo
types to be able to help us out in the
Years coming I don't know I just ha I
just happened to go through Yellowstone
I think like about uh six to eight
months after they had some very terrible
fires there in the early 90s and I think
I was on dead tour so I'm trying to
remember what year it was I want to say
it was ' 92 but it might have been 93
but um
what what I remember is that when when
you look at the areas of the of the
forest that were scorched by the fire if
you got down on your hands and knees and
you looked there was a whole new Forest
you know what I mean like everything
that was huge and big was now just small
like all these low to the ground plants
were all there and obviously plants that
were living off of the carbon from the
soot and all the burnt trees everything
like that but the forest was just you
know replenishing itself and kind of
what we were saying before on whether or
not it's really climate change or is
this just the cyclic nature that the the
fire and the burning of the vegetation
kind of creates the next soil for the
next forest and it just is this natural
cycle and how unfortunate for us people
like Wade whose house is like right in
the way of this natural process that
that's been happening for thousands of
years and oh by the way now it's
inconveniencing humans because we're
putting our homes in these beautiful
places that this happens
to that's really true one important
reflection that I've come across this
year we've talked about before is like
living outside of major cities and major
like you cities are toxic you know and
when they burn that Ash isn't really
like it's not good you know it's it's
toxic you know when cars burn and houses
burn and propane tanks go off that Ash
is detrimental to us for forest fire Ash
is isn't so bad I mean it is it's part
of our natural process that Ash is
carbon it's going to go in it's part of
our Evolution I think it's part of what
we need with the mass sickness and the
pandemic and and all that that's going
on is another reason
why you know cities are you know
something to be careful of and another
reason where if if you can make it work
out in the country and live their life
even though there's sicknesses out there
even though there's forest fires making
it through that is is a healthier
process and I'm feeling really thankful
for my country Roots back to the land
decisions right now even though I know
that we are in the forest and Anything
could
happen I'm still allying
with natural uh compounds and I'm
feeling really healthy from it and I'm
feeling for those people who are not um
but as a or people that don't have the
choice because you know we've been set
up for you know 100 plus years 200 years
that you know now people have their
roots in the cities and that's where now
culture is so that's really important I
guess we just have to see both sides of
it serve their purpose I go to cities
cities are you know but I just recognize
like there's a point of Health that
comes from living on on the land even
with fires burning and things but you
know and also smoke travels you guys we
could we didn't see the Sun up here in
BC for over a week like a week and a
half we had a big orange Globe because
of all of the fires down in Oregon and
California and Washington and Washington
so we were down Washington too and we
didn't really any fires around us at all
and we couldn't see the bottom of our
field so you know just like how our
Collective Consciousness we are all um
connected we're also all connected in
this microbiome that we call Earth so
you know the smoke that's happening down
in California is the smoke that I'm
breathing up here we're all in it
together and we always like to separate
ourselves that we are not in it together
but the smokes and and that are
happening over in China or over in
Siberia that went on forever and ever of
course are affecting all of us so and
it's it's important to recognize just
South of the Border Whole Town's burnt
down from
Spokan Central Washington all the way
through Oregon all the way through
California I mean probably close to
seven or eight million Acres of burnt in
the last month on
what um air in North America up here in
Vancouver it's I was I'm out of R ises
you can't see 15t in front of you it's
hard to breathe up here and you're
talking about those headaches and stuff
like that I'm starting to really
associate the headaches and how I just
been so down the last couple weeks and
stuff it's hard to breathe out here I'm
in avford and uh it's it's it's right
now you look outside coming home last
night through Manny Park and stuff like
that you can just smell it just like
it's it's bad it is the smoke is bad up
here
so take a lot of the advice you guys are
talking about about those supplements
and stuff like that I didn't really
think about that but uh there's
definitely a lot of smoke in the air up
here that's for sure Cava Cava um you
yeah we we all a lot of us you know
we're all outlying with cannabis and
it's wonderful it's a great analogic
it's very helpful but you know kavak
Caba is a wonderful nervine it really
helps sort of coat the end of our nerves
that are sort of fray you know that
feeling of feeling braid and at the end
of your rope we use that term all the
time I'm at the end of my rope well
that's your nerves talking your nerves
are literally at the end of their rope
so allying with cabak Cava and not just
smoking cannabis but also ingesting it
when we ingest it it's much more of a
nervine it helps coat the end of the
nerves so and
algae Mis Mis soup thank you thank you
hn that's yeah I use Ava and miso to get
away from my golf War syndrome because I
was dealing with a over toxis body so I
studied on what they used in Hiroshima
Nagasaki and that's what they use they
used um you know uh especially miso soup
but kabakaba I got turned on to as well
and you know those changed my life you
know especially if I'm having I have
permanent nerve damage when I have
really bad nerve days kavak Cava works
yeah oh I'd love to hear
thatav and also you know that's there
that there that wonderful aspergillis
microbe that is in um is is in miso ASP
Gillis or aspergillis or and we always
talk about aspergillis as being the
enemy well you know here is this highly
intelligent uh microb that really is
incredibly helpful I love that thanks
for sh neurotransmitter that actually
has C now that you're talking about this
this is a lot in a lot of my amino acid
papers and stuff back in the day so I am
actually taking that I just have me
taking it recently so I'm going to jump
back into the vitamin coverboard open
that thing up and jump right into what
I'm looking for thank you for reminding
me so I'm gonna hop in here again quick
uh since we're talking about fires and I
see comments over here in the comment
thing is all the orgon outdoor trash is
all the Cali weed
trash I don't think so
you know uh the the first year I moved
out here the first time I went into a
dispensary was right after all the fires
in Calas and I gotta say every single
jar of weed I smelled smelled like smoke
I don't know what happened there that
that happened but I've never seen that
since I've seen cannabis
completely smoked the hell out and come
off the line smelling and tasting just
fine uh I know a lot of people are going
to go into the peroxide and lemon juice
and baking soda dips this year uh
personally if it I'm I'm not sure where
I am on how clean the Cannabis is coming
out of these fires if it's not treated
versus treated and if if it's something
that we really need to concern ourselves
with or if it's kind of one of those you
know you're already combusting something
you're already smoking something that
you know cannabis has it it's you know
positive medical effects but let's be
honest you are doing damage to your
lungs by doing that what else are we
ingesting by smoking that cannabis that
is out in those fields I personally
don't feel it's ruined I in 2017 with
the San Roa fires we had stuff that got
ashed we had stuff that didn't get ashed
we had stuff that had smoke no smoke all
that we did multiple different ways of
harvesting we did the dip on some stuff
we didn't do the dip on some stuff we
washed some stuff we didn't wash some
stuff we had all of that stuff tested
and we had a very clean results come
back that year we had a few you know you
get the OD
ones like oh chloroform or whatever and
they tell you just send it back in and
retest it and it came back clean so I've
kind of always been the mod of thinking
that it's it's not doing as much damage
I think as the end consumer kind of
thinks you know they all just thinks uh
barbecue OG and all that crap and that
we're smoking poison I don't don't know
I don't know if any of you guys have any
more insight on
that I agree with you the ash that the
ash that falls what's falling if it's
Ash onto the plant itself is typically
just just you know again very very light
mineral content and very very little you
know in terms of toxicity the toxicity
and what we were you know referring to
before is the way that these a city fire
would smell as opposed to say like a
country fire where in the country you
might just be burning brush in a c or
something like that we're in a city
there's probably going to be like a lot
of a trash the the bad part of of smoke
the thing that can cont contaminate
cannabis would be what's in the soot and
what's in the soot there's a class of
compounds called polycyclic aromatic
hydrocarbons and these are like some of
the most toxic
hydrocarbons known to man but
ironically this is part of the the
barbecued flavor that that people love
like if you like barbecued brisket or
smoked brisket or if you like you not to
talk about the meat diet again markets
but if you like charcoal grilled food
those black stripes on your steak and
everything like that where it actually
caramelizes a lot of that um degradation
you sugar degradation and whatnot
pyrolysis ends up with these polycyclic
aromatic hydrocarbons which are really
toxic and that's why you could probably
go to a Burger King go scrape those
black lines off the hamburger send it to
a lab go show that there's polycylic
aromatic hydrocarbons in there and shut
down Burger King because they're selling
toxic hamburgers because but that's part
of the grilled taste that humans love so
much so you know yeah but but Mark
with cannabis that's not part of the
taste and smell that we love if you
taste smell it I wouldn't smoke
it no no no yeah I'm just talking about
like the elements of fire mixing with
cannabis and where where no I I agree
you remember I I love a good burger or a
good steak and I like them grilled so I
know exactly what you're talking about
and say love e but with cannabis I got a
choice and uh if I can smell it or taste
it meaning the fires I don't want that
cannabis product yeah I mean I got to
agree if it smells like smoke I mean
nobody's gonna want it I'm talking the
stuff that comes out and doesn't smell
like smoke you know so like when we were
talking about this on hash Church a
couple years ago when fires were
happening in California I thought what I
remember and the nice thing about hash
church we can go back and watch him now
and go listen to that is I think the a
couple episodes where oh my God there's
all these fires there's going to be all
this Smoky weed and then a couple
episodes later where yeah there's a
bunch of smoky weed out on the market to
a couple episodes later to where hey it
makes really good fire oil you know to
where again you know if you're making
dlit you're GNA purify any smokiness out
of the dlit I'm not saying that all that
material was destined for disate and
certainly I think the way that most the
economics the most
[Music]
grow would be like you want to sell your
premium flour your best flour at a
different rate than you want to sell say
like your bulk biomass which is just
going for for distillate or just oil
formation you know for for Rick Simpson
type oils or things again where maybe
flavor really doesn't matter but those
you know canabo are still going to be in
there you know in some cruds there's
almost like a y flavor right waade I
mean I've tasted some cruds that almost
have like I would say a smokey Essence
to it but maybe like a a somewhat of
like a burnt Essence to it where maybe
in the way that they're recovering their
solvent from their extraction actually
kind of like put some kind of like burnt
flavor into the oil itself it's still
effective and I still think you could
make capsules out of it and cancer
patients could still use that oil so
just to answer your question I mean I I
I don't know that again the burnt all
the premonition that oh any weed that's
grown in a fire ridden zone is just
ridden off as not being good or as
valuable as it would be
otherwise I think the fire has to be
like within a mile of your property and
dumping [ __ ] Ash on your weed like in
that case you know I mean that's going
to be tough to to get that off but right
when it has a chance to get somewhat
cleansed in the atmosphere I'm sure
there's some molecular change that's
happening in the atmosphere even you
know when it's you know but if you're
next to a crowning fire I mean my
goodness you know what what can you
expect but I think when it has a chance
to to fill up the atmosphere and the odd
ashes falling which is probably still
the majority of people although this
year is a unique year we'll see what
happens but I think you're right to say
definitely a lot of it's good s is so is
usually black soot would have like s
think of soot is kind of like the the
component that is left on the inside of
your chimney that's why you have to get
your chimney clean because when soot
builds up there essentially it could
basically just be you know
flammable later later on but it's oily
yeah EX exctly it's oily it's kind of
like it's kind of like it's s Creo right
so Ash is different like ash um again if
you were to do the it's
absorbable yeah ex different way exactly
I I I don't think Ash is as much of an
issue as if your plants are kind of in
an area where they're getting fumigated
with the syy flames and effluent of a
fire does does that make sense
right hey Mark would it be like spraying
geranium oil and then letting that kind
of happen you know naturally and break
down naturally and then it would just
the the the smell goes away and it
breaks down over time and I would
imagine similar things are happening
with with light Ash I I've had no
reports from anyone that I'm close with
that they've had any
Smoky I mean leaf leaf microbes are
still eating things that land on the
leaf so if you have an opportunity like
those plants are still growing and if
they the fire went away then I believe
you know then the plant the stada and
everything you know every minute of
every day is consuming what's on the
leaf so I the plant does have the
ability to consume a lot of and we do
know that during fire and when there's a
lot of Ash that the cyanobacteria on the
surface of the leaf you know
exponentially doubles triples it you
know it starts to grow because there is
so much dust for it to consume so I do
think that there's a you know some some
type of a homeostasis balance that
happens and let's with outdoor uh flour
also one thing that I wanted to say
that's super easy for people to
understand when we were talking about
City fire and and forest fire is that
the smoke coming off of City fire is
carbon monoxide the smoke coming off of
a forest fire is carbon dioxide side big
difference so that's sort of well
they're
both they're both there who's telling
you that who said that to you i' I've
heard that is that not true that there's
more carbon monoxide in City air no
combustion makes both CO2 and and and
and and Co I I think yeah I I I I've
yeah there's no rational basis for that
chemistry wise so combustion you
Mar what about atmospheric carbon coming
yeah so there's no in the air there
wouldn't be like some type of you know
City toxicity in the Smoke yes there is
from plastic
and that's kind of what right like like
if if my laptop here were to fall into a
fire and start burning uh most of this
plastic is a thermoplastic called well
it's vinyl which is poly Vinyl chloride
so when poly Vinyl chloride or when
styrene all the conventional Plastics
multiple Plastics that we use when those
things burn yeah they give off basically
they thermally degrade and give off very
noxious soots and particulates that you
don't want to be breathing in that's
absolutely true no question about it I
don't think it's down to the co CO2
mixture here it just down on what you're
burning a lot of that stuff again
especially the polymers what happens is
as they burn the neighboring polymer
next to it so if this part of the
plastic is burning this part of the
plastic is melting and vaporizing that's
why when you throw plastic into like a
campfire you start to see little kind of
like floaties all over the place and
everything so and well those toxins join
together with carbon pieces and and
chain off you know what they're going to
do though they're just going to end up
in the upper atmosphere as just you know
volatiles that you don't want to be
burning and you don't uh certainly I saw
people throwing trash into a fire and
then cooking marshmallows on there it's
like oh my God people just you know I
mean you know part of it is having um
again this cradle tog grave recognition
that all the packaging material and
everything that we throw away into the
trash a lot of it does get burned and a
lot of that stuff does have bad effects
in the environment so yeah since we have
a chemist in here here's another thing
I've been talking about that you can
probably clarify more where there's a
chemist
where I I was horrible I was horrible at
chemistry so like
horrible the other thing that people
have been talking about up here on and
on and on and on is water plus Ash
equals lie and what's that going to do
to plants what's that going to do to
soil I've gotten into a couple
conversations uh Wendy from sonibus I'm
sure you guys know Wendy dragonfly and
uh she's kind of the one that brought
this up and she shut the comments down
on her post about it because I think she
knew it was going to create
hubub uh first of
all what kind sort of concentration of
Ash needs to land soil for it to cause
an issue and at this point in the season
my thing was I'm not even concerned
because my plants are big enough at this
point there ain't a damn bit of Ash
hitting the soil underneath them I'm
sure there is
obviously it's all as you recognize it's
all concentration it's all a matter of
how much of that stuff is there and
there's so little there that it's never
going to be able to balance what acid
rain has done right so acid rain has
basically moved the pH needle on what
comes down from the sky almost by a
whole pH unit in the last 30 years right
so I mean yeah on the LIE right there's
a whole lot of acid rting to neutralize
that was exactly the argument is it was
going to change the pH in your soil and
that you need to watch out for that
probably in a local sense hold on Sam
let me just add this so if you take a
bunch of Ash and you add it into your
grow yeah on a local sense you're going
to see a swing of pH no question about
it so lie against some of the components
in there are like sodium and lithium and
when they get wet combined with water
they make hydroxides which is going to
basically increase the ph and give you a
more basic pH no question about it just
like lie would but you know again
everything's all in you know the stuff's
floating down from the sky for Christ
sakes it's not like people are dumping
pounds of this [ __ ] on your grow right
that's exactly what I thought now it's
not Mount St Helens that's all well yeah
I mean Mount St Helens is yeah I mean
something like that is going to uh you
know that was yeah was great there was a
Grateful Dead show going on in in Eugene
I think when Mount S I think it was
Portland Portland I think it was
Portland like Meadows I think yeah they
were Fire on the Mountain played Fire on
the Mountain and there was really Fire
on the
Mountain yeah I mean that was um wow I
mean I I guess in it around and in fact
a lot of what we know about how
volcanoes and replenish the ecosystem
has been some of the publication that's
come from the science that studied Mount
St
Helens and looked at like the
neighboring areas on how quick it was
you know terrified back into you know
organic existence that's what I was
going to say Mark was that at first on a
volcano slope nothing will grow for the
first couple years but after that it
grows better than the surrounding Farm
man it does
yeah yeah there's a whole zoo of micro
that start inhabiting that and once the
microbes start I mean Josh and Kelly
will agree that it creates basically the
chemistry of soil inside what was just
an inorganic glassy Rocky substrate
completely void of life you know it
takes that thing and just turns it into
yeah just a sponge and a zoo of of life
so so [ __ ] cool Mother Nature's
pretty good chemist
I I've seen excellent cannabis from
volcanic soils like in Hawaii and other
places I I know it
works I wanted to Circle back to
something uh that was being offered
about Ash that settles on
Plants um over the last couple years
with the fires in California I've asked
some of the Growers who had crops out
when the ash was going on or when they
were threatened by fire and the folks
who took their crop down while Ash was
still falling and they were concerned
their crop was going to burn or whatnot
reported
more problems with their finished
product versus those who left their
plants in the ground allowed them to
continue their life process and
harvested um after they'd had a chance
to deal with the ash was something that
you were saying that I thought I was
trying to understand how that would work
but that makes a lot of sense I wondered
what else folks what were the problems
that they had a phyto remediation plant
what kind of problems did they have with
the material that they took down oh it
was taste taste and cure uh the The Cure
uh yeah just didn't work out uh the the
flour didn't taste nice it had uh it
burned poorly this was over near Santa
Rosa when the urban
area of Santa Rosa burned a couple years
ago some of the farmers in that area are
who I was talking to and yeah they were
trying to save their crop got it down
and into a drying facility away from the
fire but we're real disappointed with
the results whereas some other Farmers
again not Urban so there's a variable
that may not be relevant but or it may
be uh but these were more uh rural
farmers who let their stuff finish uh
after the smoke had cleared more or less
there was not the ashall and whatnot and
they did with blowers and whatnot and
they felt like they got a really good
harvest that year so is there Ash in the
hash so it turns out leaf blowers leaf
blowers are good for blowing tear gas
away from you they're also really good
at blowing Ash off your weed so wow you
know leaf blowers are turning out not
important this year 2020 is like the
year of the leaf
blower in the hash I can tell you
firsthand if there's not too much Ash on
the starting material it can pretty much
be washed out and tested clean yeah for
sure and I think that there is a phyto
remediation that happens and also I
would think just you know that when
you're curing it is such a microbial
fermentation process that happening if
your microbiology has changed
dramatically as like it would after a
fire and you had a tremendous amount of
Ash then you're GNA have a different
microbial Colony so you're GNA get a
different type of cure so I loved it
what you said wait I think people should
just hold off let let mother nature take
care of it especially those who are you
know working with um deep soil and
microbiology and have a lot of you know
regenerative practices around them I
think their flow is absolutely going to
be uh just fine and also I you know and
anybody who's listening out there just
because we're talking about the smoke
and the ash damage of course there's
going to be amazing beautiful small farm
flower coming out of this year please
you know just because you're hearing
about this doesn't mean don't go out and
try it I mean I've already seen some
flower that was even just recently cut
it's beautiful it it it's smells amazing
people are are having a lot of successes
now
so well if the if the if the ash washes
off into the into the hash water the
theoretically again to go back to this
theory of lie theoretically the pH of
the water should increase because now
you're dissolving all those minerals
which are bases and they basically make
an increase in PH so would be
interesting to see is in your Washings
of Ash
hash do you actually see a higher pH of
the water I'll grab the pH pen and let
you know do it and I think that would be
good water to sink into a compost pile
or into that aisles of your garden to
kind of sink that ashash water tell wuce
if he works with anybody on the legal
spot to do the same thing and that's
kind of what I was getting at with the
ash thing is where is that concentration
point you're really going to see that I
mean how much has say a 32 gallon wash
with 4,000 grams of material in there
what concentration of that needs to be
ashed to actually change the pH of the
water uh not much actually not much I
mean I think what what you would see is
you you'd see a a change so if you're
washing like I don't know how much are
you washing at a time like five or 10
pounds about 4,000 wet grams of can so
call it two pounds pound yeah two two
pounds yeah you should see a little bit
of change in the pH especially if it's
got a lot of Ash in there you know yeah
you think it's that much two pounds from
just four four yeah I guess I guess yeah
about two pounds
sorry the
2,225 gram conversion which I've heard
somebody say that the BCC uses 2450 but
then Flynn WSU laughed he's like the BC
doesn't have any any parameter on what's
fresh frozen because you pay by wet
weight so they don't want to
do the far that's just California 2225
that's what they've used forever how
accurate is that I really don't know uh
we just did a huge Harvest at a friend's
farm and one of his guys pulled some of
the bags and dried it and according to
his numbers it's 2000 is far less than a
pound so I Me game Farmers too of the
like you know you you you equate 2225
wet grams to a pound but that's
untrimmed and that's actually not equal
so it's more like twoth thirds of a
pound so in their head it's hard for
them to wrap around freezing weed you
know you know yeah the water weight
accounting for that it would be
interesting to see again is is there a
change in PH and do the natural
components of what's else is in the hash
water somehow how buffer that change in
PH so no matter how much Ash is in there
you won't really sing a SW see a swing
of pH well one of the experiments you
could run is you can take your water
after you've done your hashing and add
Ash to it and see if you could change
the
pH see see if the see if the natural
components of what you're extracting out
of the plant is capable of basically
masking the increase in PH that you
would see if there was Ash in there and
again the way you do that is you spike
it with Ash to see if you actually see
you know the increase in PH I'm just
going to you know take a wild guess here
but with the amount of Ash I'm seeing on
that size run I would expect maybe you
know like a gram or two of it to be Ash
you know out of the entire weight of the
whole thing yeah and and that so if you
just think about the stochiometry of how
much how much you need you would need to
add to swing the pH a little bit you're
going to see a difference in PH right
I'm G to check it out I can almost
guarantee it y cool you can report it
back here on hash
church I'm all about figuring those
things out because I get I get I can't
tell you how many times people ask me
all these crazy questions of what can be
washed what can't be washed what should
I bother with and you know we've I I
will sit here and admit that we've
washed some pretty crazy stuff so that
we could run it through testing or see
just see for ourselves exactly what
happens in the end if people only
realize their questions are literally so
they don't have to see what happens they
like it's it's such an insane thing it's
like oh I'm just gonna I don't want to
make any mistakes because mistakes lead
to Innovation and yeah we can't have
that like I need to just ask everyone
what oh hey just can tell me all your
mistakes that you made so I don't make
those same go out and make those very
same mistakes and make a bunch of new
ones and come back and tell us all about
the Innovation it led to don't ask me
questions that keep you from that
journey I get a lot of those questions
man I'm just like okay how do I answer I
feel like that's one thing I've always
I've always no matter what anybody tells
me I have to find out for my own so I
just stopped years ago and throw it
through and see what we get you
know yeah if you're not making mistakes
in your garden or figuring things out
and dealing with different issues you're
never going to learn it's one thing I've
always pushed my plants through their
limits and I leave plants in one gallon
pots for six months just to see what I
can do to them just so I can learn from
it so you can understand it like you
haven't botched a run you haven't done
it right
right I mean I've had everything every
problem known to a gardener I
think scales anybody's ever had scales
and sure I sure enough got them but
learning how to deal with all those
problems a great way and and that's all
it's ever been it's just research and
understanding and seeing what works and
everybody's still fighting powder how do
I deal with it how do I deal with
it it's hard to yeah you learn a whole
lot more from an experiment that doesn't
work than from an experiment that does
work if you do an experiment that works
why' you do the experiment to begin with
right wasn't much of an experiment if
you knew if it was going to work
research is what you do when you don't
know what you're
doing yeah you know he's just try [ __ ]
that is the truth I like the way you put
that listen we got seven more minutes
for today's episode it's been great
having everyone on here I just wanted to
let everyone know I'm going to go and
spend the rest of the day with my little
son who's anxiously awaiting on the
other side of the door there and so yeah
let's uh finish it off seven minutes
left if you guys want to say anything
about Horatio feel free to now this
might be a good time to mention a little
something something because this is the
end of the episode go ahead anyone you
know Mark hero is the reason why I
became on the panel at hashir so you
know you guys wouldn't know who I am and
I wouldn't know any of you people and so
I have to be grateful for his friendship
and for you know he reached out to me I
never reached out to him he reached out
to me and and then I was I think he was
like on his phone with me a couple times
while he was on hash church and he'd
like ask me a question and then he go
back to Hash so he's and then it just
became natural hey Mark why don't you
come on and so I think Mark did he
introduce me to you right did 100% yep
so I have to be grateful for how hash
church has enriched my life with all of
your friendship and you know I see the
comments in the chat everyone seems to
like when I pipe in with knowledge and
it's just my pleasure of my life to be
here to share that knowledge with yall
and to be everyone's friend on this
panel uh you guys mean a lot to me uh
kind of like my internet family so I
really I have to be grateful for Horatio
for introducing me to you Marcus and for
your continued you know friendship and
Johnny's continued friendship and Sam
and everybody and so I think what we
find in life is it's not like what you
know and it's not necessarily who you
know but it's like who you get to know
and who you bring into your circle and
your um the influence that you have
amongst your friends and the collective
knowledge that you're able to share uh
you know the old saying a rising Tide
Rises all boats and so uh I think that's
what hash Church does is it rises all
boats and so for my contribution here
I'm directly thankful to htio for for
inviting me and bringing me in man yeah
100% I give thanks to Johnny B for
introducing me to Horatio and give
thanks to Horatio for introducing me to
you and just like I said passing that
you know spark on down down the line and
letting everyone get inspired he
definitely won't be forgotten his uh
words are on hash Church forever uh and
anyone that wants to go and look those
uh up I'm sure eventually someone will
put a cool list together that has all of
the episodes that Horatio was ever on so
yeah props uh props to Horatio anyone
else want to mention anything
I miss go ahead Johnny oh no you go
ahead please uh I when I came in I think
I came in on episode 24 and her show was
you know uh a regular and I um I missed
learning from him I love the way he
challenged thought I love the way that
he challenged
ideas
um and his compassion more than anything
he was always willing to share and
always willing to lend a hand I was
always helping someone out and you know
that's beautiful and that's a a great
spirit to have and one that I hope to
leave in my time and uh I'm sorry he's
gone but I'm thankful to have known him
and to have been a part of him and he be
a part of
us Johnny
B wow yeah know um
I was just talking with Marney and um
his wife and daughter um in between the
house church and she was watching this
morning I want to say thank you to
everybody here and the kind words and uh
just for all the support and the gunm
and they were really just uh really the
whole family was uh just so overwhelmed
with all the comments from everybody
from the community so uh they just want
to say thank you and um of course htio
was
a good friend he uh came to my house
quite a bit oh
[ __ ] he help me out a
lot like more than anybody he made
creams for my neck he made certain
things for my pain he really just went
an extra way to help people like Mike he
created um stuff from my freezer um from
the leing when he first started doing
those extractions and he was always just
wanting to help that next person and and
like he always said he was doing it for
his
family and um I was
[Music]
and everything that he's done and just
all you guys out
there just thanks
I was uh really looking forward to uh
seeing more of his research and I know
some people out there know a lot about
Mark and some other people and I've seen
and worked with ratio quite a bit so
there's some stuff that uh all the
barrels are leaning there and just
different things of what he was doing at
the end uh he took a break and really
focused on jewelry and uh wait till you
see the jewry line come out guys his
whole bement was full of all jewelie
making equipment and he he did some text
that of course Heria would do that no
one else was done and to look forward
for Mar to releasing that so it'll be a
type of Jew Lise and stuff like that
that they actually put together at the
end of the last year and that's why her
should stopped talking with everybody
because he went deep into uh his passion
was into doing his art and doing all
these molds and uh so um you'll see some
pictures of that I'll share it today on
Instagram when uh it's over and stuff
like that I'm going to head over there
now and just kind of do some helping out
there and stuff but the family's really
grateful and uh they're really uh I mean
uh daughter's just touched to see how
much her father has touched so so many
people and help so many people so keep
those comments coming they're reading
them every day they're saying thank you
so much for the support and everything
that um you everybody's helped out for
the family so um and you know what
thanks Rachel for um all you've
done and I know his Spirit runs strong
and
uh actually um got the the freeze dryer
on remember when he brought this over
the border and uh and how he got that so
um they'll always be here beside me
thanks
guys thanks Johnny B for the touching
words I know that the family appreciates
that for sure as do we did anyone else
want to mention any words before we shut
her down and send a rest in peace to
Horatio H I didn't know the guy
personally but obviously been following
him since day one on hash church but one
thing I just want to share what what I
thought was cool about Horatio not as
somebody who didn't know him is you
could tell that that guy anything he got
into he fully geeked out on went way for
the fence swung way for the fences all
the way out there every detail like that
and that to me that's cool because
that's kind of the way I am when I get
into something it's it's just full geek
mode so I can inspires me a little bit
no that's that's absolutely true you
know and it teaches all of us that you
know you don't you don't you don't let
your own limit you don't limit yourself
on your own limitations you set stretch
goals and he you're that
you now on the head he was he knew a lot
more than he actually really understood
if you know what I mean I mean he he
just he knew things instinctively in the
lab and when he would call me and we
would talk he would say things that I'm
like oh yeah there's a reason why that
happens and you know I kind of explain
it to him but I think it teaches us all
the lesson that you you know we should
achieve set our goals high and even if
we don't hit that goal even if we fall
just short of that goal we'll go a lot
farther than we probably would have if
we never set that goal to begin with so
I think it's a good model to live your
life totally and to have the heart of
faith and to have the heart space while
you do it so you know a person like ctia
taught us how to dive deep and to go
beyond the Realms and then how to have a
quality with it and then to how to have
the heart space and and that's what I
really appreciate about you know him and
and this community and and this moment
right now is that you know this is a
it's it's more than just a business for
us it's a it's a connection and it's
really important to us and these are the
things that keep us up every day and
waking up to go to go on so we really
love and appreciate you you all um big
resp respector Horatio Johnny B everyone
here um thank you on this journey it's
one day one more day in our
Evolution um we just appreciate you
being out there calling us if we if you
need anything ever we'll we'll call on
you thanks to everyone out in chat in
chat land you're a part of this too so
we're on the screen right now but you're
all a part of it we're all a part of it
um let's go make the world a better
place
Yeah well yeah
Horatio Mark you know Horatio really
brought out the creative and Science and
that's what I really gravitated towards
um and that's something that I you know
I really respect in terms of the work
that he contributed to to everyone and
everyone here and I remember Marcus you
talking about the processes and
everything that he was going in on and
you know to have a mind like that to
your point mark is is really special so
that's that's a testament to being far
more interested in just uh processes
it's understanding the plant in a really
deep deep
way absolutely met go ahead I never met
htio in person just on the internet with
on your show a zillion times but what I
can say is he had a deep deep love for
tpin and uh because of that I had a lot
of respect for him and uh
yeah 40 years is is not enough but uh
what it is is what it is
yeah all right everyone well thanks for
coming out I really appreciate it we'll
finish it off with a rest in peace to
you sir Horatio you
were gone but you will certainly not be
forgotten so thank for the time you
spent with us here at hash church and
thank all of you for all the time you
guys have spent here at hash church both
the panelists and all the people
watching I think we have about
42 people in the chat room right now so
uh yeah we'll try and do this again real
soon uh shout out to everyone on the
west coast who's dealing with these
fires uh we'll try and get some help out
you know I know the community is is
opened arms let's hope that the rains
come soon that these fires are go down
and more people's homes are saved rather
than lost and uh yeah thanks everybody
um vote peace out vote vote V vote V
vote love you all say hi to Tanner send
love to everybody hang in there we can
get together I
already gonna throw the bum
out Daren would say bomb
awesome everybody everyone peace out