all right recording in progress you know
what that means it means it is time to
go
live with hash Church there we
go let start letting everyone in once we
go
live and we'll give a big old
welcome yes we will
all right we're getting close fingers
crossed always nervous while waiting to
go
live come on how long can you
take all right here we go redirecting
there we
go there we
go I believe I believe hope there what's
going on here let's let everyone in and
we'll figure it out
together welcome
everybody just trying to uh organize the
disarray of going live here for the
first time in almost over a year trying
to see if it's going to go live on a new
page or if it will be live on the same
page I'm trying to figure this out right
now
um can you guys hear
me yes
yes okay okay welcome everybody hash
Church 5.0 episode 1 with Wade laughter
in the house dude good to see you
man really good to see you thank you
Marcus yeah man it was nice to see your
email come in being like hell yeah I'll
join for an episode of hash church it's
been too long the funny things that come
and go in our lives and we sort of just
don't even realize we miss them but this
is one of them for me man I missed uh
missed hanging out and seeing you on a
weekly
basis yes let's do it
absolutely I'm trying to figure out if
it went live on the same page that I
created or if it created a new page kind
of having a hard time figuring that out
but uh it's you're not you're not you're
not live on
YouTube what do you mean or I don't see
you live on
YouTube yeah we're live on
YouTube really I can send you I can send
you the link if you like hey welcome I I
have it in front of me I guess maybe
wait I'll try refreshing it
it it it went to a different page Thomas
it didn't it does it to me all the time
I go to Open live on on zoom and it
opens a completely different YouTube so
I'm a little bit uh not doing it right
you'll have to help me for next week and
uh in the meantime we're live on YouTube
I can see it there's 59 people watching
right now and all I usually do is I go
in to the one that's live and then I go
into the one that's not live and I just
send the link a bunch of times but it's
seems like a ton of people they must
have gotten the notification or
something gotcha I see all right well
welcome Ryan's in the house Papa Sith
that's my homie in Michigan he runs the
bubble man brand in the lab and makes
all of our live hash rosin and hash hits
and traditional hash and all the
products that we making over in Michigan
and Ryan really uh yeah he's been the
indispensable help over there and he he
helper I thought well I'm going to
invite him on to Hash Church create some
uh some new panelists so welcome to you
homie good to see you thank you thanks
for having me yeah of course man of
course and welcome to Mojave as well Mr
Richmond's in the house good to see you
dude got the guitar here man yeah thank
thanks for having me absolutely little
rusty but uh yeah no Thomas you'll have
to help me I I did all the the key and
the this and the that and I must have
done it wrong and that's why it didn't
go live on the actual no worries yeah
we'll be able to I can help you with
that no worries I also edited it right
at the end of the day and changed the I
I added episode one and that might have
also glitched it out but for whatever
reason it shows that we're live we' got
75 people watching us at
9:03 so here we are it's uh it feels
good man I know skunkman Sam's going to
be popping in I think uh Dr Mark said he
would be making an appearance so I'll
just hit up Sam real quick make sure
he's all
good etan is out of town so we won't be
seeing him today but hopefully we see
him in the next uh oh in the next couple
of weeks or so if we keep uh if we keep
going here tell you the first time I
started hash church I think I did 162
Sundays in a row and that was uh that
was absolutely insane around 1:40 my
wife sort of pulled me aside and she's
like what's wrong with you like what's
what what are you what are you doing it
was so
stressful trying to make sure the
episode was perfect that the panelists
would show up that everything would
start on time that I would have internet
depending on the country that I was in
and uh now it's just much more relaxed
so I'm happy to uh just catch up with
you guys you know get a little get a
little update from everyone in regards
to how you're doing and what you've been
up to and you know it's been a long year
and I'm sure life has been a hard year
not just a long year it's been one of
those years that's kind of like woo gez
get that one under our belt and move on
to the next year if we
can Bizarro world
man what's that it's been a Bizarro
World
year it has been a Bizarro World year
you know anyone that's uh eaten enough
psychedelics can know that the uh the
energy in the world right now is uh is
very intense there's almost like you can
just feel some something going on
underneath in in a way that uh Hey Dr
Mark hey what's up how are you dude how
are you doing man oh that's it he's like
I'm out of here I thought I thought this
was he'll be back all right so audio is
good not sure Marcus say the usual mic
settings um is the audio okay yeah yeah
okay okay we're good H before the storm
oh it did just say something went wrong
here um let me see what's going on host
on YouTube
live something went
wrong of course something went wrong I
think we lost our oh no no we're good
this one's live this one's
not yeah welcome back Dr Oh I thought he
just popped in in and
out I'll tell you if I ever took a hit
and the smoke came out the color of the
smoke on Thomas's room right now I would
absolutely I'd be like what the [ __ ] is
this I obviously clicked on the long
wrong window hey welcome back I guess
yes welcome back Dr Mark I thought maybe
you were like this isn't a fish show I'm
out of
[Laughter]
here I'm gonna hit a a nice little dab
just to how are you
Mai
Ryan what's going
on where is Sam I don't see
Sam Sam I just sent I just sent him the
link on Facebook two minutes ago he
definitely said he was gonna be here so
we'll uh we'll have to give him time
he's why did it go off
again okay there we go I got close that
make sure we're live make sure we got
the
chat and load up a bowl and uh start
some conversations with you guys because
it has been way too long I
um yeah it's it's been uh it's been a
long a long year as we were mentioning a
little earlier on I was thinking maybe
uh Wade it would be great to get an
update from you see what you've been up
to in the last year and catch us all up
man
well glad to thr you all in but I'll
start by saying there's not been a lot
of warm fuzzy stringing
news um Cancer's a
bear to keep it as simple as possible
um I've been uh dealing with multiple
Myoma I don't know if you all know that
but that's my situation I was first
diagnosed in the fall of 2020
um at that point uh according to my
medical records I had
innumerable this is a great phrase
innumerable liic fractures bone
fractures from my
skull my jaw my neck my chest my rib
cage my pelvis and my right femon
innumerable Li fractures where the bone
gets eroded by the
cancer and uh
to make it really short uh the real
issue here is pain and uh I'm here to
testify for the beauty and efficacy of
cannabis in the relief of
pain I have uh my oncologist asked me to
stop
smoking wow that was a big deal and I
did uh now I I I make ensures High
potency ensures for myself and um and I
eat rosin and hashish I found that uh
there's really lovely tastes available
by consumption into the gut as versus
inhaling uh so that's a whole
conversation
um at the moment I'm I've just started
cotherapy
again and after being off of it since
May and
I suppose one of the things that I'm
really looking forward to chatting with
you all about is I came across a paper
in a journal called
biofactors and they looked at three
different multiple myom cell lines and
compared those multiple my cell lines to
how did they react to quote unquote
minor phyto
canones and it turns out hello CBG iume
golf and CBN as in Nancy have really
remarkable effects at slowing the growth
of multiple my cells and at the right
dose trigger and cell debt in mulp
my I came across that paper on Monday of
this past week and I've
already I put out the word here in
Nevada county in
California asking for help specifically
asking some of the
manufacturers who had access to CBG
material and or CBN
CBG I I'm really grateful one of our
local manufacturers uh supplied me with
uh almost 30 grams of the high potency
50 plus percent oil of uh CDG still
working on trying to get some CD in and
um I gotta say I feel really blessed
to live in about a county
Califoria uh it's a small County we got
about 100,000 people Al together in this
County but somehow or another this is
one of the places where organic
agriculture particularly in the Cannabis
realm took rout back in the 60s and
70s
um hell
this one of the fellas I know here
locally has been into minor quote
unquote phyto commitment
long enough that he bought the web
domain name CBB
oil.com back in the day for $8 and
change that's how long he's been in
it um I want to name names I mean uh
vital I itel
extracts uh
flaska um I could go on and on Emeral
Bay extracts all of these people are
making high potency oils and providing
them not just to me but to any person
who shows up at our local dispensary
with a cannabis recommendation we have a
program to give these products at no
cost for the persons who need them and
uh for the first time I'm actually a
recipient of a program that I help set
up that way and I I would I would just
go to
summarize my situation at the moment to
say uh my spirit I I feel very full of
myself in the spirit but the body is
really having a lot of trouble and
um I will note that for most people
multiple myma is not a fatal condition
there other things that happen as a
result of proving the condition that
usually results in death
so I'm here for years to come let's keep
doing hash church I love talking about
hash I love used to love smoking it now
I love eating it um really looking
forward to hearing what all of y'all are
up to and what's been going on and um
yeah I'll go back to listening much love
and thank you Marcus really enjoy this
opportunity to see some of the people I
was [ __ ] so much in this work thank you
yeah agreed Wade and great great to hear
from you and listen if there's uh if you
want to share any of those names in the
chat I can put them in the description
so maybe some people who are living in
your area hear what you say and rather
than you know in inable to shorten the
ability for them get to A to B we can
remove sort of all the middle things by
just putting up a few links for
companies we're not trying to blow
companies up that are doing good work
and and donating but I would also say
perhaps for some of the Growers may be
watching as well if we put up these
links you know maybe they won't just be
people reaching out who need oil but
there'll be people reaching out who have
biomass to donate for companies like
this that can give that oil away because
without that aspect it's really just out
of pocket for the one group and what a
great thing to be a part of uh you know
gifting out oil to people who are really
in the needs you know a lot of people
are looking to fill a hole in their soul
right now and it doesn't happen with new
Nikes uh and and and Bugatti Veyrons it
happens by serving the people and when
you can do that you will uh you will
feel you know God or whatever it is you
believe in in your heart uh by by
serving others and I always feel it when
Wade comes in and shares with us I can
it's so crazy to think 10 years ago he
was sharing about the harleyquinn and
about like creating and doing this work
himself giving away biomass and now he's
on the receiving end of it uh in this
beautiful sort of uh karmic retribution
where it just came right around and said
hey homie like you took care of so many
people for so long now there's going to
be people taking care of you so it's
really uh quite powerful to see um
welcome to uh to to best friend Farms
who just popped in um you know we're
just chilling out you probably caught
the end of of Wade's update he's been
fighting the good fight against uh
against cancer and uh looking good and
yeah and and looking good man and you
know didn't even skip a beat doctor told
him he couldn't smoke anymore he's like
he's gobbling it down which I will say I
have never seen a human being eat more
canabo in my life than Thomas up in the
corner of the screen with the rain
falling down that [ __ ] guy ate like
24 every time I say this he's like oh it
wasn't that much man it was only like
1,800 no it was 2400 milligrams for a
plane ride I can't remember if it was
Berlin or Barcelona it was one of those
places but this is this gets into the
chemistry and the science of the body
obviously Mark we're all metabolizing at
different rates how is it that someone
can get destroyed by two milligrams and
another person can take 2400 milligrams
and totally be cognitive talking to me
like right sitting next to me like hey
man you want a
bagel
CBD CV no that was thca THC is what he
was he was consuming I just uh yeah it's
mind-blowing to think that someone could
consume that much I don't mind eating it
myself but I'm kind of like once I get
into the 30 milligram range that's like
I'm like oh I'm like more High than I
want to be you know I'm good with 10 and
20 I don't know about the rest of the
the group here I probably got some
Hondos in the in the mix but oh yeah how
B available it is right I mean but does
it not also depend on how you metabolize
in your liver
right well yeah yeah it depends on a lot
of things you know like is it so if it's
if it's T8 CA right it's one thing if
it's THC it's another right but yeah I I
think that like if you're just eating
hash if just the a lot of it is just
going to be sort of you know making it
down to the gut yeah it's probably
entering in the system more in the
stomach than in the liver but I I I I
don't know I
I think it's bioavailable you know when
it gets metabolized and yeah I mean
that's probably helping him and in great
ways and you know I mean again this is
like the full what do we call this the
Entourage effect or Ensemble effect or
whatever the fact that CBN and CBG both
play a role so You' imagine that you
know you could almost dial that in to a
specific oil that's got a specific
amount of CBN um that's what I was going
to ask you Wade I mean like what what's
effective in terms of CBN concentration
in the products that you taking I mean
is it um highly concentrated CBN because
actually there is CBN isolate but I
think it's completely synthetic that's
out there but there's also just tied you
know in concentration CBN oil um are you
doing more of a full spectrum or isolate
treatment I haven't uh I have not had
had any uh success so far in sourcing
CBN uh particularly at the quantities of
milligrams that I'm hoping to be able to
access
um yeah I I have access to Abundant CBG
still working on
CBM and um from my point of view one of
the things I think is most interesting
is the canono that are produced very
early in the plant's life cycle and the
degradation products at the end of the
plant's life cycle show the greatest
promise for this particular cancer and
it's intriguing to me that as a consumer
of cannabis I tended to avoid CBG and
CBM right of course see any anti-cancer
effects from my can from my cannabis
consumption that we've
always go ahead um yeah so there's a
there's something that's going on to
make sort of so-called um compliant
distill it so when they um distill you
know quote unquote hemp like it's like a
21 variety or better or something like
that and you still have enough THC in
the distillate um what they've been
doing is if you uh heat up that
distillate and bubble air through it the
air um will oxidize the THC convert it
over to
CBN such that you can actually make a
quote unquote compliable oil that's
below
the3 threshold because a lot of these
distillates are like a couple percent in
THC and even you could do this at the
crude level too so it's just like a
crude ethanol extract if you bubble air
through while you're heating the oil the
air will convert the THC into CBN
so you might be able to do that on your
own and not have to rely on somebody
else providing it to
you thank you Mark that sounds like a
plan I will be talking to some of our
local
manufacturers thank you yeah they do
that to make so socalled uh well they
they call remediated oil or what's
called tea free oil or tea free
distillate and the way that they're
pulling off that stunt is Yeah by um in
that process you don't lose a lot of
your
CBD you could eventually start
converting some of your CBD but you
could sort of finesse that process to
basically remove THC or get it below the
detectable limit or at least below the
three limit and make it what's called T
free so when you see that category of
tfree distillator tfree crude that's
probably how they did it which is this
remediation process by using just simp
air we have it available in Canada by
the leader uh
CBN fairly pure but it's expensive it's
like the last time I checked I think it
was $11,000 a liter whereas like
distillate like THC or CBD is I want to
say like below $2 like maybe under a
dollar even I somewhere around there
anyway per gram yeah so you could buy
CBN isolate for cheaper than that right
now CBN isolate down here is somewhere
like about three or 4 thousand a kilo
American this will be from a plant like
derived right from cannabis for sure I
don't think that Canada allows any type
of synthesis on can this is completely
synthetic Mark yeah yeah yeah no I I
knew I that's why I mentioned it I
figured you were talking about the
synthetic I I couldn't I was actually
talking with someone yesterday and they
said it was $1,200 in Canada for
distillate that was 92% THC I I was kind
of mind blown buy it a dollar T I was
like well what's the point of growing uh
when you can buy it at that cost and I
wanted to ask Wade are you taking
everything or
orally yes yeah okay um my uh cousin 18
months ago was diagnosed with stage four
liver cancer and um he can't take
anything or orally just he gets way too
high and he can't really smoke but he's
been taking it suppository and pretty
it's pretty incredible in the they just
did like um like they tested all his
tumors they did X-rays and in three
months they haven't had any growth at
all and he's been just take yeah it's
it's pretty incredible and you know he
he was told he only had six months to
live 18 months ago and he was he came
and actually stayed with me and he's
been just like taking so much oil and he
goes in um in a hyper barar chamber I
think it's called We're with pressure
and it seems like the combination of
these two um it's pretty incredible that
he's still with us anyway I just wanted
to say
that right on man cheers yeah thanks Tom
it's always good to uh share the
like-minded stories um listen I wanted
to uh introduce Ryan Ryan's gonna kind
of give us a little Lowdown Ryan's kind
of like uh you know um how do I put it
just like one of these younger gung-ho
guys that you see yourself in like his
passion and his excitement about hash um
I couldn't have my brand in a place like
Michigan without Ryan or someone exactly
like him you know someone that has the
passion someone that's been like I watch
the hash churches I studyed what you
guys are doing I listen to every video
I've learned from my own mistakes I went
off and did my own mistakes and created
this knowledge that uh you know you just
obviously we need great Growers and we
need a variety of things to do a brand
but really without uh without a guy like
Ryan the brand wouldn't uh wouldn't be
going anywhere fast so why don't you
introduce yourself homie and uh tell us
uh about a little bit about you like
where you came from how you got into
this and and now a little bit about what
we're doing
together yeah my name is Ryan I'm a
hatch maker in southeast Michigan I'm
from Cleveland
Ohio and uh I moved to Michigan I've
been up here on and off for five years
now
um so yeah I Marcus reached out last May
and we've been uh up bringing the bubble
man brand here and uh it's been a lot of
fun um yeah lately we're working on some
brick hash and some hash hits that we're
about to bring to the market and then we
also have two flights of rosin pens like
70 9010 of two flavors of strawberry
lemonade and uh Queen of Diamonds and
then we did some more full spectrum pens
too yeah dude
put you on the spot there hey sometimes
it's not so easy just jumping on the old
hot seated hash CHS be like all right
tell us about yourself man yeah I'm
trying to uh figure out how to change it
to just one person's screen when they're
talking I've actually forgotten this you
have a update for me Thomas yeah in the
top right where in the view view speaker
thank you brother look at that now it's
you with the with the LED lights
appreciate
that appreciate that yeah why don't you
uh tell us a little bit about yourself
Thomas I don't think you've ever been on
hash church people have obviously seen
your show on my channel but yeah Thomas
and I have been working together for a
little while now I don't know if it's
been six months or even if it's almost a
year um but yeah he's got The
Grandmaster LEDs the UVC lights the
whole variety of insanity Thomas is kind
of like a mad scientist Savant when it
comes to producing and creating lights
that uh if you tell them you can't do it
he will absolutely [ __ ] do it yeah
well my team kind of gets mad at me that
sometimes because uh well in just even
the light that you're looking at we re
uh redesigned it three different times
or well you know when doing something
you have a completed product and then
all of a sudden you see a better way of
doing it um so I've been in the lighting
business for seven and a half years I've
been growing indoor since 96 been
growing outdoor since 94 it's a it's a
really big passion um for me and to me
like I obviously I got involved in this
originally to make money but then just
obviously fell in love with the plant um
we actually had like a really big
breakthrough well there's a couple
things that I really wanted to talk
about I think the biggest breakthrough
is the UVC and using it as a pesticide
because um well in all my years of
growing we've broken the rules by just
using a little small amount of light
with a small amount of wattage for a
short period of time and we we've
developed a way to be able to completely
just eliminate the need for predator
bugs and pesticides when you're to deal
with thrips and other um pests that
we're still working on so it's been
really really exciting another thing
that's like just absolutely huge that's
uh changing growing for everybody is
under canopy lighting and it's been
highly debated for years and um I
actually you know two years ago had
designed an inter canopy light where it
kind of goes in the middle of your canop
and it's kind of like a low wattage and
then I we just did not see really good
data or anything and then I saw other
clients of ours using under canopy
lighting and having stupid results when
I say stupid we're talking 30 to 40%
gains and not not only that at the same
time eliminating all your be Buds and
all the color differences so um it's
pretty exciting and a lot of people have
been making this argument about oh it
doesn't line up with the science well
the science of it is the light is
actually going through the leave and the
leaves and being caught um that's the
only thing that makes sense because
we've just seen incredible um results so
that's one thing that's just um we've
just kind of finished developing too and
just kind of exciting seeing what's been
happening with the um because it's
really changing um the game and just
it's so hard like uh like I've been
seeing for some of the people like it
depending on where you're producing I
know well Michigan we've just set up
shop in Michigan oursel and it's cuz
it's so much cheaper to operate and real
estate is so much cheaper over there
than California like when I was seeing
the cost of what people are having to
deal with and operating in California it
is insane like I thought we had it bad
here in
Canada like the California rent and just
the cost of everything it is
insane seriously how it's it's so many
of my friends that have I mean I I'm
sure move and Wade have a bigger list
but uh just lots of people dropped out
dropped off they just were like [ __ ] I
can't [ __ ] with this this is absolutely
impossible yeah yeah like scenes people
paying
$37,000 a month rent at like un certain
places and these
$20,000 um bills like it just I it just
it would be so hard to operate I just
can only imagine just seeing the and
some of the red tape like Canada has
some really disgustingly bad red tape
especially like but it's gotten EAS
easier to do things like it's so much
easier to become it has yeah like five
years ago becoming an LP took like
millions of dollars like you need almost
needed like $5 million do liquid cash
five years ago to do it you did yeah
absolutely did we we rented our facility
my partners rented the facility before
they brought me on to the company and I
was like I came and looked at the
facility it's 45,000 square feet three
stories this just gigantic building I'm
like how much are you paying for rent
they're like oh it's like 60 Grand I'm
like $60,000 for
rent then because there was a cannabis
shop right down the street from us
called zenabis we figured well this is a
no no problem like we'll be able to get
in all day long we got licensing came
fast from the government within reason
like six months fast but the city of
Delta decided that they were going to do
a caseby case study on each company
wanted to bring cannabis to their to
their City because they were convinced
that what we were really going to do is
take the Cannabis out of the facility
and go down to the high schools and sell
it for $358 this was the mentality of
these people and it cost us an enormous
amount of money because they didn't give
us the um you know the their okay for us
to put a cannabis company in that
building for almost two years paying
60,000
a month rent if you can imagine Thomas
how how's that for a Burn It To The
Ground like what are we doing here guys
like oh my God I was so naive I just
thought as long as I make cash we should
be okay as long as every day I've just
got the equipment operating and making
hash we should be okay in the end that
company was not okay they flailed it
[ __ ] it right into um uh
bankruptcy but it still exist this my
new partners we have no debt we have you
know no equipment debt no CRA debt no
partnership debt the company is a
unicorn in Canada for processing now we
still have the same facility it's just
on one floor of the three stories uh all
the equipment's paid off and we're full
up with you know rosin presses from
sasquash 55 tons we've got the [ __ ]
Creek filtration electr plasmatic dry
sifting unit we have the Whistler 300 uh
wt300
uh washing equipment uh we have a ton of
well not a ton but like three XL
resonators with a walk-in freezer so we
have the abilities to get a lot of stuff
done uh without those crucial mistakes
that were made by early companies and uh
wow did we ever see it a lot in Canada
and you got to think like that's that's
people's money you know that's not just
like some dude like burning It To The
Ground cuz he's incompetent that's like
it's an entire team of people all from
what I saw and it's not like they were
all terrible people it just seemed
like they were coming from Corporate
America or cor corporate North America
because they were all Canadians and
bringing all the things that they
learned the marketing people were like
we're going to bring all the things we
learned at marketing school it's like I
would try to tell them you can't it
won't work that way it won't come across
as authentic you actually have to you're
going to have to start a new which your
knowledge this is an opportunity for you
to Pioneer something you can take the
Little Gems that you brought from your
education but what you're going to need
to do is you're going to need to shift
your perspectives and
apply something new and novel to how you
bring this to the market and I've seen
little bits of it happen but for the
most part there's highly regulated rules
that say you know this is what your
package can look like you know in
America it looks so much nicer but in
Canada that's what you get you know this
is a totally different product totally
different product in Canada look at that
can you imagine like that is insane
people go into stores they don't
recognize the products at all they're
kind of like so they're still we're not
under prohibition the same way as we
were but they're still stifling they're
still like let's see what key like I
swear they must have had a think tank of
brilliant people because they could not
have accidentally [ __ ] this up this
bad this absolutely Ely has to be on on
purpose I'm not a paranoid delusional
person I'm just saying that these people
government officials and the people that
are passing these regulations really
don't Health Canada less than two years
ago in Canada said we still believe
there's no medical uh factors no medical
aspects of cannabis in any way uh while
interacting with the human body like
they made a statement even though they
have a medical platform all across one
of the only Federal Medical Platforms in
the whole world you know one of the
first and yet um they still don't
acknowledge it so I don't know I'm
rambling sorry about that guys probably
need another dab I was oh go on sorry I
was just gonna say that you know that's
like in California California is like
the fifth largest economy in the world
agriculture is a huge component of their
of the economy here we've had we have a
serious Heritage Legacy with cannabis
you know the story The worldwide story
and California dropped the ball and it's
almost like it's impossible to think
they dropped the ball that much you know
like and I'm not a conspiracy person at
all and but I think it is a weird it's
it's super [ __ ] complicated you know
and I do get that that nobody really
understood what to do um but I think
your point about the the the leadership
that we
didn't there was no like I have this
like you think of company like uh a car
company or some invention it starts with
like the founder it builds it becomes
bigger and bigger and then it becomes a
giant industry and then maybe someone
else takes it over like the outside
influence like you could build a you
could build a manufacturing company and
then 30 years later you're super
successful and your new CEO is from
insurance or entertainment or whatever
or the CFO so you bring in this other
guy but we as an industry we brought in
that guy from the beginning as soon as
we transitioned all the leadership
across the board was like oh we need
business specialist guys we need people
who know how to do business but none of
them were Ground Up cannabis people none
of them understood cannabis a lot of
them made really bad decisions and
influen policy in a big way and no
one no one really predicted what no one
ever thought what would happen if
prohibition didn't exist
and what is cannabis really worth what's
the real value of cannabis not just to
people as a as a medicine but the
commodity to the farmer the manufacturer
the distributor nobody thought like
what's a real number and and if that's
the real number then that's the number
we're all headed towards and if we're
all headed towards that number then how
do we transition from where right now
it's 3,000 bucks a pound but it should
probably be 100 or 200 bucks a pound and
you're paying $8 a square foot for
cultivation
facility it's like that's not right the
the state shouldn't have allowed that
because and then you're paying a half a
million dollars for a license and
spending $80,000 a month on rent and
like the state the a state should have
like had the foresight to say look in
order to transition out of prohibition
we got to be realistic with people about
what their opportunities are and they
because everyone everyone wanted to
transition out of proh
and not have jail anymore but nobody
wanted to let that prohibition dollar go
you know that prohibition dollar the
people came in they were like all right
we're going to legalize this we're going
to change everything oh wait a minute
Bill uh let's not change the prohibition
dollar it used to make sense getting you
know say $3,000 a pound which is like
4500 Canadian that is like we're growing
it for like you know in the 90s maybe
2000s you know 1500 so the profit margin
of we from Canada to America was just
astronomical now it was that way because
if you got caught depending on the state
you were probably doing like a five or a
10 year sentence depending on where you
got caught the higher the the the money
amount like if you're going down to
Arkansas and getting 6,200 well you're
definitely doing the 10 if you get
caught like even with like a zip let
alone you know a 100 pounds so it made
sense in the in a sense it didn't really
but it made sense in in the sense that
this horrific jail sentence was the
reward or the the anti-reward you know
of making this enormous amount of money
they got rid of the jail sentence and
then suddenly the they wanted to keep
the same prices right the algorithm the
algorithm changed and and the funny
thing is the corporate guys who first
the first Rush the first wave they were
chasing that prohibition dollar because
they didn't come from a they weren't a
tech people they weren't people who were
ethnobotanists they didn't really
understand cannabis so they were like oh
[ __ ] man there's a lot of money to be
made even if it's 500 bucks a pound
we're still making crazy money and now
the can costs more than what's inside
the
can dude how about even crazier I'll
I'll step it up for you when I go to
Cannabis stores and I try to explain to
everyone cuz all the corporate people
want the same thing they're like we need
to stabilize and Shelf ready these
products I'm like oh you want us to take
a volatile compounds and stabilize them
for the Shelf all right well that I
don't know a ton about a ton but that
sounds very difficult um that's what
they want to do they want to stabilize
it then what do they do you go to the
stores and the only thing that is being
made cold are 10 milligram shots of
distillate nanoemulsified into a
beverage in a little can sitting in the
fridge and I'm like looking at all the
hash at room temperature I'm looking at
all the weed I'm trying to explain to
them that all of your volatile compounds
they're they're they're they're boiling
right now at room temperature and
they're oh yeah the Vault smells amazing
I'm like no no the and the companies are
so new that they've gone so big so fast
that they're not growing exceptional
cannabis yet some are some are doing a a
great job but many are not so already
you have the disadvantage of the the
volatile organic compounds are already
in smaller amounts than they would have
been had they been grown more properly
by better people under better conditions
with better cultivars and and now
they're boiling those off it's like dude
it's only 1.5% as it is by the time the
guy gets it and he it's dry and the
Tarpin and all these beautiful volatiles
have have boiled off it's not the same
experience and that's that's where you
get people being a little bit
disgruntled with uh with their purchase
it's come a long way Canada I will say
there's a lot more companies that are
sort of on the par for you know
producing nice things people from the
the black and gray Market that have
transitioned over and understand that
growing smaller Amounts is probably a
better idea uh than trying to grow you
know a million square feet when the only
thing you've ever grown is [ __ ]
chickpeas you know we were talking about
um just about government screwing things
up it's crazy to see what's happening in
Germany right now like boy if they like
they have just really screwed everything
up where I I think they're basically
limitating or limitating people to only
able to do like 55 light shows I forget
how many people they can do it for so
then you have to extend groups I we've
been talking with multiple people out
there and it just just sounds like such
a headache and just such a bad idea a
bunch of real bad ideas that aren't
going to be sustainable
who would have thought that the Germans
would come up with a bureaucratic
nightmare for cannabis like I would have
never
thought so weird it's like a weird it's
like a it's like a a Spain weird hash
it's like a club membership based thing
that's what they want to do in Germany
exactly a quota base perk patient it's
it's impossible for any businesses to
make money really but they're like I
think the logic was like well we'll
figure out a way for you guys to smoke
weed but no one gets to make money off
it yet
exactly they they figured it out they
figure it out to make it be like if you
do the numbers and I can't remember the
exact numbers it's like five Keys a
month or something or some small amount
if you do the math you're allowed to
have a certain amount of members 200
members or something they're allowed to
buy a maximum amount of cannabis twice a
month and if you do the max numbers and
all of those guys are buying then it's
like okay this is an okay little
business but the problem is is unless
you're producing great cannabis they're
going to be a part of other groups
they're going to get cannabis from a
multitude of places it'll dilute your
sales you won't be selling 100% And your
number is already small it seems like uh
and then they're all they're all
investing in their own grows which from
you know The Grandmaster LED perspective
is like woohoo like instead of just like
a bunch of big companies coming in it's
literally going to be like I think they
put the cap at 10,000 and I I could be
wrong but I thought I heard when we were
in Berlin that they're going to allow
10,000 private clubs uh throughout
Germany yeah be be growing their own
weed processing their own house and
selling it to their own private members
that's uh that's a lot of work I don't
think 10,000 people are going to find
success in
that
yeah all right I want you all taking a
dab right now and I want Brian to tell
me about what his best hash Dash rosin
is that he's that he's growing and
smoking right now because I I miss your
deep radio voice describing in detail
rosins and hashes I do man I miss that I
grabbed a couple just in case we're
talking about that kind of thing yeah I
got awesome this is Rosen form but this
is some lime peels I'm calling it and my
friend uh Jacob habash friend bred this
yeah I shared some breeding technique in
my last year out in Humble which was
eight years ago we worked together in
the field and he sent me some seeds he
made a couple years back and this was a
lemon peel by uh lemon peel again on on
ghost train banana sherbet by
zace that like really creative he made
and it's super duper loud like can't
wait to share it with him back but
anyway there's a look it's hard to smell
through the computer but it's definitely
like you stepped on some like gassy lime
Peels and it's right in your face and
the taste is almost louder than the
smell on this one like the translation
is almost overboard out of your ears on
the taste that even from the smell so
I'm liking this one it's got a really
good sativa kick too in that profile the
lemon G on the I95 shines in this
one F yeah dude that's what I'm saying
yeah so I'm liking that one I stick to
my gas mask heavy and then I just did
finish um well breeding and working with
my new 207 headband kind of threw back
to the old East Coast headband clone I
came into when I was first moving back
here so I'm kind of on the gas ticket as
usual but working with some I got a
whole list of interesting new ones
coming up to talk about when the time's
right but I'm excited I hear I want to
hear about every one of them for sure
once you holding the jar in your hand ah
well I got a few new ones I'm turning
that is I got a strawberry headband I
made from my strawberry Midas into the
headband clone I call Strawberry
headband and I crossed that into the gas
mask for a strawberry gas mask I did I
also am like checking fenos outside on
these projects right now and seeing
which ones shine which ones keep or make
it and I've got a like the strawberry
headband lines into some different
things because it just shines so well
outside last year is actually most of
that
and I did a sour banana sherbet on the
strawberry headband for like a straw
Nana band type of thing like an you know
contemporary straw nana I got that
Citrus smoothie which is the comes
that's what the lime peels I Nam the
feno but it's actually his creation is
called Citrus smoothie Jacob the habash
creation so I'm tying that like yeah
like a mailin that shine the same lemon
G profile on me like the the lemon peel
profile so I'm working those out in the
yard I seem to see like we talked about
this I think a couple few years ago but
I see a really good resistance kick on
the lemon or the lemon tpine out into
Maine um as far as like Health carry
through the season but yeah so I got
some different interesting gas mask on
GMO is a new one that I'm really working
with calling
GMO yeah so that one
po one that s that skunk man would like
Sam would like I got like a really
skunky feno on that one and one that
lean more towards the GMO um both of
them just or one of them dumps hash I
can only imagine the other feno next
time we wash it we'll we'll do the same
but um yeah I could go on and on and on
there's all kinds of that love for the
for the strain work and just trying to
you know I I just love how you
articulate it and it's you can just tell
and hear the passion in it and you can
hear the like this guy has not only
grown and touched and like experienced
the expression of this plant he's also
like processed it and and and dabbed it
out on all levels and and you're able to
uh articulate that in a really good way
man I'm telling you I I like that I love
it thank you Brian can I ask you about
the East Coast um
headband I have a I have a a kind of
strange relationship with headband um
just real quick
um my uh good friend I think he's known
in this in the on the social media as
Manny in the whole story of Sour Diesel
he was the guy who put the seed in the
ground but in the pot he wasn't the you
know it's a long story but he he's a
close friend of mine and when he came
out to um the West Coast in the late
90s um I did a swap with him with Sour
Diesel and kush before it was called OG
um so we did a bet trade and I gave the
OG guys the sour for the first time and
I gave the sour guys the OG for the
first time and long story crazy story
short but when he was up in the Bay Area
707 at first he was up in in mindo area
but when he was in somoma um I told him
not to I suggested not calling the OG OG
okay call it Kush because it was a weird
a weird time in the scene you know and
not that many people that cut at the
time and it was just a little bit
volatile and just the weird money
element around it anyway he called it
headband okay and that's where the 707
Headband came from and the whole story
was that when he back in the east coast
when he was a kid in the 80s you know
late 80s early 90s they used to use the
term headband as a descriptor for like a
certain effect which you know we've all
had you know that rubber band coming off
your head right yeah but so so the
question I had to him and I've asked
this of other people who were on that
scene back in the day is was there ever
a real was there ever a
cut ever called headband that survived
through that transition because from
what I know everything that's called
headband today came from that renaming
of OG he was selling OG and sour at the
same time and some of it was called
headband and some of it was seated and
some of it was just OG it was just sour
so I've always been trying to trace like
if anyone can have an origin of an
original East Coast headband cut that
predates 99 2000 era it's a great part
of thetive around Kim dog and OG and
stuff I love the story yeah those are
great pieces you're throwing in right
there that's the history I think like
it's none of it's really well it's
written down but none of it's locked in
you know written into stone where a lot
of pieces move with the OG story and the
sour diesel story I only really know
like what my history line with it is and
um definitely raised up on that real
ecsd cut that I've heard Source back to
the Albany called such things um this
had been when I was out west I lived in
in NorCal and did this work medical work
for 11 years so I got to touch some
really good genetics out there and I I
did work through a different a batch of
kushes to get to that true OG cut it was
called out of Southern humble
circulation from
oaksterdam or Oakland area and I really
love that one and I would say as far as
the headband out west I tried the 707
and maybe another looma or something a
couple few of them that like my glass
blower friends up in Arcada were in love
with that 707 and a couple variations
that were more cush sided out there that
I noticed definitely more OG sided and
then when I moved back here I just had a
friend kind of blessed me with some
plants when I stepped in doing the first
light dep and there was a Super Lemon
Haze CL cut that it was amazing and then
there was this headband cut just
reported to me as it moved through the
lines people shared it it was definitely
like East Coast heavy head band cut that
some people reported to be possibly
what's termed or original diesel or the
day wrecker that's been thrown in the
mix with it which it might be that same
synonymous same cut and then what I
noticed part of the story as well when I
first went out west myself in ' 06
0607 I had a friend from out east doing
workout there that grabbed a cutting
from Vermont we were in Maine but he
called it all day he called it Eco Sour
Diesel and it was not the Alban C that I
was used to but it was so dank like
peanut butter fudgy thick like not your
mass Super Skunk as much sided it was
more thick like a Kush thickness to it
versus you know the ecsd and you know
that was East that was Sour Diesel D
youco Sour Diesel but then I heard other
people out there when I was in working
in the you know the Santa Ros sonomi
area was some actually a market like a
farmers market and such some people had
some clones and some medicine or some
flour of it and some people termed it
the mistress cut I don't know if you've
heard that one thrown around out there
like the the sour diesel you cheat on
your other Sour Diesel with yeah yeah
yeah God there could be another story
attached to the mistress cut but that's
that that's maybe getting a little
too no but that's a really interesting
story because um I think so the first
time I showed these guys the the OG
around 98 99 they took a look at it and
go that's the diesel where'd you get
diesel and and and I I mean like and
these are the sour diesel guys I'm like
you mean Sour Diesel like no no no
diesel because sour just Kim sour
Diesel's just sour Kim and then they
just Chang it to diesel because diesel
was a popular you know so did you did
you hear this you'd be one I think I can
ask about because you have some of this
folklore the story
my friends that circulated around the
first early cuting like oh 99 2000 even
2001 that came around for us back then
um years later when I came back a friend
of mine said that he had heard the sour
diesel Story coming out of this you know
the East Coast side actually pertaining
more to that it was diesel was like a
term like you're saying that referred to
like strength power it was you know that
Powerhouse right so and then what I
heard is the sour got flipped onto it
because if you had that real cut of that
diesel then other Crews were sour over
it have you heard that one a lot well
well that's that's part of yeah that's
that's part of it yeah AJ right yeah
soured
relationships yeah but it was originally
it was the the first seeds were from Kim
dog and it's unknown male for two two
generations basically so the whole Mass
sco super skun side nobody really knows
but the basically the seeds were as far
as I remember you know in my memory
Fades man it ju they were it was our Kim
on the seed pack on the little film box
and then they put the s in front of our
Kim and then it was Sour Kim and then
once and then once it because it was Kim
dog and then once it hit the
market when people started purchasing it
it was like oh it sells we'll sell it as
Sour Diesel because diesel is like
chronic it's like San fire you know it's
like PFF piff or yeah exactly yeah cool
I was waiting for the piff to get
mentioned
piff I haven't worked with any of that
one in a while any
variation and I just heard the nice
little download on the stories go ahead
move is it is it really supposed to be
piff is just a a is a um supposed to be
purple purple haze purpa hazes P hazes I
saw this on some video that the piff
they called it the piff because the
Dominican guys that were and Hayes were
calling it purple it was nl5 Hayes but
they were calling it purple hay cuz hay
and purple Hayes just were attached and
the guys who are hearing it didn't get
the accent right I don't know if that's
just an internet story but I've always
wondered where the word piff come from
I'd like to know the
same how to get those Miami guys in
here they all we called it Haze back in
the day and then piff came later for me
actually after I moved back even ago so
it was always Haze for up us up in in
Manitoba you know it was that that's
what it was 18 plus weak flower right
you know big monster plants little tiny
buds just I was so lucky to truly
that as much of a commercial grower as
my mentor Ron hickey was because he was
just all about like building these like
secret grows and houses all across he he
was also um you know one that would be
like let's just grow this it's it's 20
weeks of flowering and just like people
would be like whoa what are you talking
about Ron like we could Hammer off like
three crops like we can't we can't do
that it's like oh we're he'd be like oh
we're doing it and that weed was just so
spectacular to have that in my history
of that you know people would come into
the room and they'd be like they think
it was like perfume like literally just
on their tongues in their mouth down
their throats like what is that
perfumey smell like it's the haze and in
fact this is an amazing thing because my
wife is not a huge proponent of cannabis
obviously she has an appreciation for
the fact that it's been um funding our
life uh for the last 35 years um and she
has her own relationships with wearing
hemp and CBD and whatnot but uh yeah
just not overly a huge cannabis
proponent but uh when my first son was
born and we named him Tosh she suggested
that we use the name Hayes for his
middle name which in fact is his name
he's Tosh Hayes and I just thought that
was such a cool thing and I even asked
her later I was like what made you do
that like what made you say that and
she's like you would always just get so
excited about the haze I wanted to
transfer a little bit of that over to to
our son I was like that's
amazing the haze it's the haze that's
how excited we would be I you guys know
I'm sure you were the same my my wife
did the exact same thing with my son
it's so weird you said that man because
she it was she suggests my son's middle
name is
sage and and awesome wife is not a
smoker and she like it didn't even
really like she doesn't even like follow
the whole Heritage of me as a breeder
and stuff like that it's not a big part
of our lives and our narrative um she's
like well what about the word what about
Sage isn't that a cool I'm like honey
you realize that it's kind of weird for
me it's like to do that she's like yeah
but it's a cool name I'm like yeah
you're right it's a really cool name
let's do it I mean dude listen that is
unbelievable because you bred both of
those sages yeah that's right man I'm a
sage breeder that's right you are the
sage breeder on on multiple
fronts that is super cool shout out to
the wide and how cool they are yeah
couldn't do it without them that is for
sure
sure well man what a nice uh chill out
it's been about an hour so far I'm good
for a little bit more and puff some
bowls and missing Sam I'm hoping that
everything's okay with him and that
maybe he just uh maybe had some family
or something else going on that he
couldn't uh couldn't make it
today but it's good to hear from each
and every one of you what's that I
thought Rob was just out there for his
birthday right yeah that's cool yeah
guys are
living living the birthday life I wish I
could go and travel around for people's
birthdays Rob is the consant traveler
always The Traveler yeah kept it
consistent too like did not slow down as
he got older he's just like I'll just
keep visiting
countries yeah wow I'll never forget
really that it kind of blew my mind that
he had this apartment that he didn't
really live in but it just held like
boxes of all of his stuff I was always
just like dude that is is that is neat
that's wild you're just like and and I I
can't count the amount of times that I
would go visit him at that apartment the
old one on the toll Sprout
there and he would have just gotten back
from somewhere so we'd have all these
crazy like tools from you know
harvesting hemp in Vietnam and like
cloths and Beads and like just going
through Rob stuff with Rob uh was uh one
of my coolest memories of hanging out
and getting to know Rob
really get to know that guy when you let
him go through the stuff that he's
collected around the world and sort of
Express his passion that he has for the
weaves and the culture and the once
again I just have uh I'm attracted to
Passion I really have an attraction to
Passion it doesn't even have to be
passionate about something that I
personally love if it's palpable and the
person is just truly authentic in their
passion for the thing they're sharing
with you it's it's a pretty lovely
experience I think if more people put
their phones down in fact uh and hung
out with people uh just you know next to
each other rather than uh s what what
what what were you saying here oh did
you see this you got to check this out
it's like I don't want to check that out
I want to relax and connect and uh puff
some
dabs
indeed indeed Thomas are you going to
tell us about the UVC light a little bit
I feel like we should probably talk
about that a little
bit sure um you know what I think I can
actually let me start it off you you do
what you're GNA do what I'll start off
is how Thomas I've known for a long time
he's Grandmaster LED he's got popular
YouTube channel he's lots of traction
he's always been doing stuff um but it
was only about a year ago he he was
reaching out to me on Instagram which is
a terrible way to reach out to me for
anyone that wants to know it's much
easier to just hit hit me up on my BC
bubbleman at icloud.com you can find it
almost in all my social medias but he
hit me up on on Instagram and I I get so
many messages on there I'm not always
quick and he had sent me maybe three or
four
messages and I hadn't gotten back to him
he was like I have something the
messages were like I have something
amazing you got to check this out it's
it's crazy blah blah blah blah blah I
was like H I gotta get back to this guy
I gotta get back to this guy lose the
messages in the in the list finally get
back to him and he's he's like I got
this light that like uh kills bugs and
I'm like I'm like okay dude like sure
you do and he starts telling me about
this UVC light it's listen he got me
hooked I will admit I had to go and
photograph the garden that he showed
which was full of I think the first one
he showed was full of thrips and as a
grower I you know I haven't been growing
every day for the last 35 years but I
started growing almost 35 years ago and
I've grown some crops and I know what it
looks like when you get bugs and I know
how devastating it is when the plants
look the way they looked when he showed
the crop with the thrips and so he
showed a crop you know the same crop
later I don't know if it was 30 or 40
days later this was when he really first
got the light and didn't understand
there's still a lot to learn about this
light a lot um but he was using it for
very very short intervals it was like
five minutes um a day
on and it's they're just little five
watt scrip lights that point up Under
The Canopy uh and they disrupt these
bugs in a big way the the the what were
the other ones the aphids they were like
literally running away go ahead Thomas
yeah absolutely jff can you spotlight or
spotlighter pin my video here and I'll
hit play yeah let me see how I can do
that um Spotlight for everyone here we
go so this is actually like thrips in my
own medical Garden on the very first day
I was testing them out myself um and
what's like really crazy about this is
well before I'd even started this we had
already done tests and been totally
successful so we were taking basically a
a tent taking just like one plant and
introducing spider mites we started off
our very first test were spider mites
where we were introducing five to seven
mites and within seven days we're
completely beating them like I'm talking
like at this point I thought okay I can
beat spider mites and we're also um
beating thrips so this was the fir but
it was only like on an individual plant
with like one or two thrips and or with
only like five or seven mites so this
was the first thing where we actually
have an actual thrip infestation and you
can see how they're just like bars that
go underneath your canopy they're only
five watts each and we were only doing
five minute just trying to think right
no at this point we were only doing
that's right five minute treatment so
this is actually going to jump um 10
days later of doing five minute
treatments and seven or 3 days before
this footage like we have about four or
15 hours worth of footage crammed into
about 15 minutes here um but three days
before this I cleaned the bottoms up and
I moved the lights up and I like I I
couldn't really find any thrips or thrip
damage at that point and so right before
I took this footage I had found thrips
in the corner it's going to show it in a
sec in the one area where I didn't strip
the leaves like I totally forgot to
strip the leaves and it's like the one
area where the lights not treating so it
was pretty incredible this was on the
ver at this point um like basically the
footage is just trying to show like you
can't really hi you can't hide the
damage that thrips do it has like almost
like a slug paste that goes everywhere
and this is where um this is right where
I found him and you can see I I moved
the light into the corner right before
I'd taken the footage but you could see
they went
right into the corner and as the crop
went on I thought like I it you know I
considered it 97 to
98% um protection because we couldn't
kill them or beat them at at five
minutes a day but you couldn't see a
trace of any damage in the top 30 plus
inches which to me was beating them um
because you know you you I just we you
can't normally beat them and they will
just spread like um just insanely fast
so anyways um we we started then wanting
to use UV to stress out the plant
because UVA and UVB have been or UVA is
commonly used to like enhanced THC inter
turpins and then you know UVB there's a
lot of evidence that it works a lot
better so then we started you know UVC
has a much higher efficacy so we started
doing um two 15minute treatments and six
days later the thrips were completely
gone from the room completely just you
could not find a thrip we uh we blew
Matthew Gates out from California he's
like a IPM specialist just to see if he
could find any and it was just kind of
mindblowing we accidentally dude I came
out there with my macro [ __ ] lens and
photographed that cop that crop looking
for thrips or any type of bug I have the
macro photographs there's not a bug
there's no bug [ __ ] there's no there's
no there's no sign of any bugs which
which was the thing that caught my
attention that was my full circle yeah
it it was just kind of mindblowing to
kind of see that well we didn't even end
up beating them until like the sixth
week and when we were trying to enhance
THC so at this point right now and this
is another shipping container I have
where I had three tents and there was
another lab that participated with this
and then someone else in Michigan and
someone else in Oregon where we're and
at this point when I was developing this
there was all different types of UVC
diodes they all have different types of
efficacy they all have kind of different
types of wavelengths so we were trying
to determine what is going to be the
most effective and so we were make and
we were also using different diode
counts and we're um and we were running
different mamps through the diodes just
kind of developing it and at the same
time this is when we were testing
spidermites and um and at the same time
while we this is when we're we're we're
taking like on our very first test we're
taking five to seven spider mites now
we're taking hundreds of spider mites
and with lima bean leaves that have eggs
and letting them establish for hours
while these ones what you're looking at
right now this Leaf was clean 12 hours
ago um so they've had 12 hours to like
what you can see the damage of what
they've done in 12 hours and it's pretty
mind-blowing what they can do um it
hurts my
soul yeah so then the every all the
footage that you're seeing they had 36
hours to establish like well this is at
TW the 12-h hour mark But W with this
treatment before we actually started
using the light they had 36 hours to
establish and we started doing 10-minute
treatments and like we're about to do a
whole bunch of more testing on
spidermites but it's still pretty
incredible so this is seven days later
so you can remember what they did to
those leavs in the first 12 hours and we
can come to the very top leaf and it's
totally clean and like the still alive
on the plant but the simple fact that
after they're they've been like after
they get treated they get suppressed and
they just start walking around almost
aimlessly you can see the adults are
they're on the plant and they're but a
lot of them are just kind of sitting
there they're not doing setting up shop
what they normally do it screws with
their DNA and their RNA um like I said
we have a un we're working with a
university that is assisting with the
white paper so we don't have all the
science on it yet but we do know that it
just a totally disrupts them without
question it's slowing um the spread down
by 90 to to
95% but that's not to say that when we
incre with two 15 minute treatments that
we like we we have a chance to still
potentially beat them because we
couldn't like 10 minutes treatments
could not thrip like we couldn't beat
thrips with two 10 minute or with a
10-minute treatment but two 15 minute uh
treatments we absolutely can beat them
where they are completely gone
eradicated and right behind here you can
see these are kale plants that have
hundreds of regular aphids and we
um it's within a couple days you can see
that there's like a trail of them
leaving and dying and it's extremely it
has a high very high efficacy on aphids
within 14 days over 90% of them are dead
on the plant just right in their tracks
breaking down so I will say the first
prop that he showed which was that death
buba with the um thrips I went there I
photographed
it then we harvested it he harvested it
and we ran it through bubble bags in my
living room because I just wanted to see
I to me it it didn't seem possible that
a plant could get that bad of an
infestation and not be drastically
affected in its yield and or quality and
caliber of resin and it came out like
festar resin and we I think we got about
22 or 23% so the yield was there the
quality was there it kind of blew my
mind I'm not going to lie and that's
that was really sort of the the the
nudge I needed to be like you know what
this seemed I just remember being a
young grower and how de I mean listen
from the perspective of like even food
production peppers and all these other
different things like this
is pretty insane when you think about it
now obviously I have always concerns
about just disruption of DNA and RNA and
I wouldn't want to be in the room while
this thing is on Thomas suggests that
you're not in the room while it's on um
because it is UVC yeah ABS well
absolutely like uh this can cause cancer
it's just a fact so you absolutely don't
want to be anywhere near this and you
want to use it in the middle of the
darkness and that's where well we came
across an article that kind of led to
everything and how everything developed
but um bugs are attracted to light in
the middle of darkness and even though
UV 5 Watts might to our human eye
doesn't look like very much and it's not
enough to disrupt the plant sleeping but
it's a lot to an insect and it's enough
for them to be kind of like attracted in
and um what what's really exciting here
is what we haven't discussed yet is we
had a timer failure um that led to
another really incredible Discovery Well
we have like I already brought up that
people it's commonly known that people
use
UVA um to enhance THC Turpin which UVA
is basically like a blue it's 315
nanometer to 400 nanometer wavelength
and um you know going back almost seven
years ago I saw a whole bunch of people
that participated when they're go going
and using UVA against UVB UVB is 280 to
3155 and we saw like a like the UVA
there was almost no gain um but the UVB
there was a huge gain so we knew with
UVC with like 100 to 280 nmet that there
is um well it's going to have the
highest efficacy for hurting or doing
damage so anyways we had a timer fail
and came in the room and the plants
every part of the plant was completely
[ __ ] like so that's when we learned
that the light can be systemically
admitted into the plant um so that is
something that we're going to be playing
with um it was also really good that
this actually happened because we
realized like hey oh my goodness if
someone has a timer failure they could
kill their crop with these lights so we
were able to develop our driver um the
MCU and the driver so it can only run
for 15 minutes at a
time anyways I don't really have too
much more than that on it um well simple
fact that we're developing it we have a
Utility Patent too on how it mounts and
um like I I believe in two years from
now anybody that's doing commercial
growing will be using it or like a
knockoff of it because it it break the
rules of growing um we it's also the
very first EPA certified pesticide light
in the United
States Thomas can I ask you can I ask
you a question about how um is it is it
drawing because you said it the small
amount of Lights attract insects so is
it drawing the plants to the UV and then
the UV is having the effect well I I it
definitely draws it to them and then
it's screwing them up but like we were
confused by the science when we
absolutely like eradicated them like the
first time like when I thought that we
it was you know stopping them from being
able to reproduce initially so I was
thinking okay it's taken us five or six
weeks to get to this point and now all
of a sudden they're gone but then uh and
here's another thing in the very first
test we were also moving the lights up
to get it as close as possible to
anywhere where it was infected where on
the following crop we realized we didn't
have to even move the lights up we just
ran it for those two 15minute cycles and
it's like they were gone so like they I
I definitely think that they are um
attracted to it I can't say I can't say
just all the science behind it but all I
can say is that 100% eradicates thrips
and like I actually believe that spider
mites it's possible well we we already
have like 90 to 95% protection with
spider mites but I think if like 250
minute treatments could have a similar
effect on um like as it is to thrips and
know thrips and spider mites are what I
would consider the two biggest pests in
cannabis obviously there's a lot of you
know fungus snats and aphids and
obviously rude aphids are another kind
of level and um broad mites and rusted
mites but I actually believe it would be
very effective against broad mites and
rusted mites the problem with rud aphids
is they can stay their whole life in the
soil even if they're a full
adult I like the idea that as a
preventative you know like for sure
there's going to be people in initially
that are like I got an infestation I'm
going to go out and get these lights and
blast it hard you know I like it more as
a just have them in your room they're
five minutes twice a day they're just
preventative like you said Thomas it's
not like you're going to get 20,000
spidermites at once it's going to be
like a few and if you exactly yeah it
also someone I saw someone in the
comments asked about mold and it will
fact kill mildew so like you could put
it right in front of mildew and it will
kill it but it's not going to kill or
solve a mildew problem like a mildew
problem is like if you're um for example
if your VPD is totally way off the
biggest reason why people get mildew in
my opinion is in the nighttime the cycle
it gets too cold with your humidity that
gets too high and you get a doe point
and that's like how um it's it can't
can't fix or it's not going to solve
something like that but like I said it
definitely is going to fight and help
microbials um too it's kind like the
ultimate well like it works to enhance
THC and turpins it fights mold and it
fights um
bugs and for such a low wattage and um
like let's be realistic even using 10
watts for 30 minutes a day is not going
to make it it's not going to change
anybody's Bill
basically per
light yeah they're tiny tiny little
little Dodgers I'm always interested in
um
I mean obviously my all-time favorite is
outdoor regenerative organic like that's
that's that's my favorite but I do love
the fact that like I've even grown some
incredible cannabis like just
indoors just with food that I bought at
the store I mean it was an organic I
think I used like what was that [ __ ]
called Earth Juice I think was something
I used like 25 years ago or something
just smelt like fish emulsions and other
like death Tea open that [ __ ] up and
someone was like oh my god did someone
die in here it's like no man it's my
Earth Juice got to put a little bit on
oh I [ __ ] have got some on my hand oh my
God that's gonna smell for a
while the
concentrate like really strong yeah it
was super concentrated we come out
like like a little did not pour very
well that Earth Juice especially if it
aged for any amount of time but uh what
I was meaning was I still appreciate
cannabis expressed in all these
different ways obviously I'm not a big
fan of cannabis that's been sprayed by
deadly chemicals because I am going to
uh vaporize uh the materials and inhale
them into my lung so you know organic is
is definitely it's crazy that we have to
use a word for just normal this is just
normal like no no it's organic organic
that sounds expensive it's like no it
can't be like it has to be more
expensive to buy chemicals and spray
them all over your plant then to not put
chemicals on your plant it has to be I
don't know what kind of [ __ ] crazy
world we're living in the Bizarro world
that Mojave was talking about earlier
where they just subsidize things so that
it makes no sense in the economy because
clearly what's that do you see bit pin
Scandal here in California over the last
couple months with the remind me oh man
well the LA Times went and pulled
products Off the Shelf at a at a few
dispensaries and had them tested by a
far more comprehensive lab than the
state mandated labs and found they were
filled man they were filled with things
that are banned in the US not just
banned for cannabis but banned in the
entire us they were they had some stuff
that was in the single use potential
harm realm you know just for irritance
and all that stuff and and pack
lutrol which is has nothing to do with
fighting off any it's not going to kill
your crop it's just about rock hard nugs
so so it was still everywhere and
basically what it comes down to is and
the whole California supply chain is
[ __ ] and there's like elicit [ __ ] that
makes it in and it gets all flopped
around but the crazy part is now they're
realizing that out of the three big
distillate manufacturers in the state
you could have as many as 80 Farms
contributing to one Vape pan
because they're literally dumping it all
in the big
VAP and so if one out of the 80 Farms is
a a dirty player which there were and
there probably were more than one out of
the 80 but just the idea that we've
gotten to this point where it's this big
giant you know uh corn syrup world that
we live in you know high fructose corn
syrup that came from how many different
corn fields and the fact that there's
still the greed element is a big part of
it and failing farms and all the
problems and everyone's like oh I got to
make money but the reality is you know
and the sad part was you know the the
DCC had just done a $5 million campaign
to show DC is the Department of cannabis
control use tax money collected from C
cannabis Revenue to do a $5 million
campaign to show people that buying
cannabis was safe you could walk into a
dispensary and just like we test it and
all this stuff and then they test it and
you know it it exposed the dirty supply
chain it also diso exposed that the labs
aren't necessarily testing as much as
they should it exposed that some Labs
don't do some Labs give you a pass you
know some Labs will say like you know
hey we'll give you a pass you know shop
with us and we give you the highest THC
numbers and we also pass your you know
so the whole the whole industry is all
[ __ ] and and it's kind of the fast
food side of it it's not the Su grown
you know Family Farm Boutique organic
thing it's the big commercial failed
Farm trim Market you know where people
are selling five or $10 pounds of of trm
or moldy weed or whatever and turning it
into distillate and isolate and now you
know we've got a a huge vape and gummy
and you know edible market and it's just
uh it's been exposed so now shops are
like going through like you know a lot
of a lot of customers are showing up
saying hey is this safe so some shops
have taken it on to actually test their
own products with the expanded panel um
that the state doesn't mandate because
we now know that there's things in there
that they're not even testing for and
it's just far that's exactly
it yeah so anyway so all these years
later you know working in cannabis it's
still a mess and there's still a lot of
people you know that came into this
industry to make money and and the state
hasn't managed the transition well but
this Vape pin thing was really a big
story you can look it up it's a LA Times
piece and it it's got a lot of traction
this is why I need hash Church in my
life because I would not have been
exposed to this otherwise and I'm always
happy to hear about things like this and
make sure that uh you know we're going
deeper with our own
hardware for the brand like make sure
that you're picking and choosing the
right things obviously we're already on
the conscious side of things in the
sense that we're not using moldy
material we're not using chemically
sprayed material and we're not making
distillate we're making live hash rosin
which is um yeah it's so crazy how greed
is such a crazy factor that it turns
into these monster scandals it's like
people don't start out evil they just
they just kind of like one step at a
time as they get into a deeper hole and
they need to be pulled out it's like
well I can just sell all this moldy herb
to the lab and we could turn it into
distillate then we could put it in
with uh uh tpin uh Botanical Turpin that
also have contaminations you know I
think when when Horatio bought his um D
lemoning the contaminant was called
Citrus oil and it made up 5% of what was
in in that five gallon drum it was like
a full leader of just like
orange
strange [ __ ] that he pulled out of a
clear liquid which I think you might
have helped him with Dr Mark if I do so
remember yeah I did oh my God man it's
it's a it's a [ __ ] show what what what
um you know um I it's hard to even know
where to begin I think you have to begin
at least and you know we haven't been on
hash church too much since um um the
Farmville right so
um it it it's just it was never intended
I think when they signed a farm bill I
think they got snookered on seeds oil
and rope right I mean I I don't I don't
even think they contemplated C CBD
because CBD at the time had just gotten
its approval as the active ingredient
for epid dialects so um there was no and
yeah you the the um the food drug and
cosmetic act prohibits the use of FDA
approved active in ingredient in food
feeder Cosmetics so basically that means
the whole CBD industry as it exists
was never contemplated because they're
basically in violation of federal law it
it's interesting because if you read
that law it basically says for
interstate commerce so I guess guess as
long as you keep within a state I guess
it's okay but um that's where it it kind
of started Marcus really I mean I think
yeah I mean this this vape pen thing is
the fact that um you
can chemically convert CBD into
THC at about one1 the cost of yeah and
you Mojave will tell you too it depends
on you know what your economics and your
supply chain are but when CBD has
cratered to $250 a kilogram it only adds
a little bit of cost to now convert that
into Delta nine so the people who were
originally converting it were converting
it into Delta 8 and that's you see all
these delta8 products really proliferate
for the most part in states where there
isn't you know good cannabis products
now California again is a notable
exception and so there's a a lawsuit
between several dispensaries in the Los
Angeles area and these hemp
manufacturers who are basically making
$8 disposable vape pens that you know I
I I don't know it really depends on like
what your cost of production are but
whatever the cost of production is the
hemp guys are a whole lot cheaper
because they don't have the regulation
and they have a much larger addressable
Market as soon as they could sell on the
internet two clicks after saying you're
21 years old they're asking for your
credit card information so I mean how do
you compete and how do you expect a
population of people to go to the
dispensary and buy stuff at the
dispensary when they could get stuff
online or at a gas station a whole lot
cheaper yeah a lot of these places you
could still go to jail for smoking weed
but on the way to jail you could stop at
the gas station and get yourself a Delta
eight pen or you know some gummies and
now that they're in gummies and
beverages Mark you know like beverages
is huge what what um what Minnesota did
so there's just the patchwork of
Regulation down here in the States and
what Minnesota did is the the the liquor
people who sell alcohol in Minnesota saw
this THC beverage thing coming and all
of a sudden they're like okay um uh uh
liquor stores in Minnesota could sell uh
10 mgram CBD you know cans of Seltzer
and fruity soda and [ __ ] like that and
that just opened up this huge Market
because basically you know let's face it
we are a
commodity um in a
commodity uh it's the race to the bottom
so you need to reduce your production
cost at all wherever you can and in
reduction of production cost yeah at the
end of the day why am I going to spend
10 times the amount of money to make
that 10 milligrams of THC when I could
chemically convert that from cheap ass
CBD so in my building I'm bringing in
CBD right which has been made legal
because of the farm bill and now I'm
chemically converting that what people
really want not CBD THC right and the
converters have gotten sophisticated
enough so they're chemistry at first was
their chemistry gain wasn't as good as
it should be and they were basically
dumping everything into Delta 8 which is
basically the thermodynamic product uh
so Delta 8 is not made by the plant
Delta 8 is a de is a regul is a um is a
degradation product right plant only
makes Delta n configured canono but the
Delta 8 that's there is usually just in
Trace Amounts and usually I think it's
just a artifact of the measurement
itself so in that sampling of the
process you're actually converting some
the Delta 8 there's no delta8 in the
plant there's no Delta 8 made in that
biochemical pathway only Delta 9 but
like Delta 8 is not mentioned in the
farm bill so it created this loophole
for people to say okay as long as I
convert my CBD into Delta 8 people get
high they don't give a [ __ ] they can
just put some SpongeBob kind of cartoon
character on some label and next thing
you know gummies vape pens soda pop all
that [ __ ] will be sold and not out of a
dispensary and not the kind of products
that you guys like like Marcus and you
know quality Growers and quality single
Source hash this is just THC the
molecule in some fruity drink or some
fruity candy that kids can eat and sneak
while they're in high school and yeah I
think it's a real big problem and it's
probably only possible because of
prohibition itself that this problem
actually exists it wouldn't exist if if
people had access to good quality weed
they wouldn't need delta8 and hhcp and
thcp and and and and acetate there's
been a lot of people going to the
hospital because the T C acetate that's
not very clean and I guess what they now
found is that when you heat up THC
acetate it converts into something
called ketene which is something you
don't want to be breathing into your
lungs but yeah all artificially made
because of prohibition I'll stop
there you know it's crazy I have some
friends out in North Carolina and they
they're super conscious like they grow
organically they process everything
themselves they do live has rosin but
they're in that World they don't do the
deltan 8 they're just literally making
the you know they're using that
that weakness in the farm bill and
exploiting it to get
like yeah well exactly with live has
roosen though so they do it in a way
that's
like I can't exact well it it's
THC a well that's the other thing is
that is that it when they read the farm
bill only references to thca or THC but
we all know that thca is the precursor
to THC in the plant so these people are
all hiding behind this
so-called loophole sing that somehow but
if you read the code of federal
regulations and most lawyers would it
says that you have to apply gas
chromatography which as you know will
decarbox your thca and convert it into t
see so there is no real loophole there
but you'll see like cookies and other
brands like this Mark selling oh yeah
t8c diamonds that gram at a time and it
depends like some State like Vermont
doesn't allow it so you can't ship it
into Vermont but in certain States you
could ship that [ __ ] over line overstate
lines and the other thing that's
happening is they're taking cheap bulk
pemp that's grown outdoors and they're
spraying it and not only spraying it
they're actually adding
thca isolate so you could actually add
thca isolate to have flour and then
putting it into the pre-roll I mean how
[ __ ] up is the market that that's
that's like throwing sand down at the
beach right like so can I explain the
way that they actually do get that
loophole and and so the the testing of
the flow is a
USDA um um umbrella so and that has a 30
day Harvest
window so you need to test 30 days
before Harvest to show that you're at
below 3% Delta 9 and that is combined
total
THC right so that's where that's where
it gets decarbo decarbo decarbox so if
you're growing a 60-day variety I know
everyone is going to like just like Jaws
are going to drop but if you're going a
60-day variety and you send in your
Harvest sample at day 30 there's not a
lot on the
plant okay so then you pass your Delta 9
USDA inspection right so then you go to
full Harvest on that plant and you
harvest it and now you know that you're
way over on the total THC right because
you now got a right plant USDA it's no
longer in their purview now all that
needs to happen is that your COA has to
show that you're at 3% Delta 9 so now
the thca number regardless of whether
it's a total THC it never gets decarbox
elated because it's separate so now all
you got to do is keep the supply chain
cold enough that your. three never goes
over3 yeah and now you can sell that all
over the place even though your total
combined could be in the 30s it could be
all over the place so it's a ridiculous
loophole and and it's all about the
Harvest window but the other thing that
I I I I find interesting because there
the guy Rod Knight the attorney who's
had a lot of he's had he's the guy who's
been kind
of right yeah he he's he's the guy who's
I think's on the cookies website but
basically the what he says is that even
though they only mention Delta 9 in the
farm bill they exclude a bunch of other
things and the fact that they put an
exclusion in there
implies that there was it was on purpose
meaning if they excluded derivatives
they excluded alkaloids salts whatever
other things they said let's give it
broad language so you're saying it's
only Delta 9 not all these other things
let's not mention what the other things
are but let's just say not all the other
things you got to remember Mojave with
all due respect that he is a paid shill
for the hemp in
this guy is hey before we get to off off
off point Wade had his hand up so I want
him to be able to speak on what we were
talking about before we go too deep into
it and then we can get back to the page
shell because uh I just got to speak up
as a patient and a longtime advocate for
patients um on the one hand the ready
availability of hemp products if they
are free of contaminant is a real gift
it's a boom to people it's inexpensive
etc etc the problem is as we've
discussed greed comes into it and people
will do whatever they can to create a
product that will sell and what's
happening in the California Market is
the people who are good actors are being
undercut and undermined by the whole
hemp industry and the sad part is there
are actors in The Hemp industry who are
good at this who are doing good work who
are creating good product but we don't
know who they are for sure and then if
you go into the legal
Market to what uh Mojave was talking
about with this thing down in La uh yeah
what we're seeing
is cannabis crops showing up with
compounds that are not listed in the
prohibited compounds under California
law they're not even they're they're
prohibited under federal law so of
course California didn't call them out
extra but they're showing up in cannabis
that's in legal
dispensaries because California law
doesn't
require producers to test for that
particular
contaminant and I and I'm I know I'm
ranting I may not be making a lot of
sense but to me the real tragedy here is
again prohibition has created all of
this crazy [ __ ] that is not serving
anyone other than maybe some bureaucrats
who are looking to keep a job
um yeah I grow your own and do it
regeneratively you can make your own
medicine fairly
easily I'll stop there and if you can't
do it come to Nevada county in
California there's a whole bunch of
regenerative practitioners right here
and I'll I'll stop there much love
awesome thanks W all right back to the
page
shill no exactly and and that I think
that that the point that that we're all
seeing is that is it a loophole and how
long are people going to profit during
the loophole and then what's going to
come on the other side because it
something will and they'll definitely
ratify it or change it because there's a
it's kind of cuckoo but and also just to
to follow up on what Wade said all the
the HP products and the thca products
and the thcp and all the different
things that are sold all over La at head
shops those are dirtier than the flow
than the products that were tested so it
let's not assume that the hemp versions
that are being sold in gas stations and
stuff are cleaner than the state
regulated stuff that was really dirty so
it's like they're not even being tested
they don't even have it's just wild wild
west so it's it's just kind of mess and
you know it's yeah I I don't even know
what to say about
there there's a gentleman in the chat
named Dennis K he he wrote the loophole
was almost 30 pages that defined D9 as
the controlled substance that's not a
loophole that's an intentional act He
also mentioned while you were talking
about how to keep the numbers down he
said I run a grow in Wisconsin we test
our plants at week two of flower to get
less than 3% thca D Delta 9 then do an
independent Freeze Drive sample at week
nine to get a clean COA just prior to
harvest so just wanted to throw that in
he seemed to have some knowledge uh in
regards to uh well so so like like with
um with the regulation at harvest the
usda's regulation ends so like if you
wanted to produce corn and produce cans
of corn then you would need to build a
factory where your Productions of cans
of corn are Reg ulated under FDA
guidelines because you're now taking
that harvested crop and you're turning
it into food right and so this is where
the ball has been dropped which is that
the Food and Drug Administration is
supposed to regulate crops after they're
harvested because that's where the USDA
sort of washes their hands and so with
no regulatory
pathway that's compliant to bring CBD
products to Market what did they expect
to happen so so now all this CBD was
produced you know the beginning of the
farm bill a kilogram of CBD was like
$7,000 a kilogram then uh maybe a year
later it was about 2,000 bucks a
kilogram now that same kilogram is down
to $200 a kilogram so the conversion of
CBD into THC has been known for a long
time um and and you know it's not a
clean process and it depends on how well
engineered that process is you're going
to get multiple products um to say that
we don't know what's in these products
is not entirely accurate because if you
look at uh like Josh swier from Affinity
in San Diego for one or or Chris hudalla
from um from Pro in Massachusetts
they'll show you on the COA that they
test for all these non-natural isomers
not all of them but like things like ISO
Delta 8 and ISO Delta 48 there's now
certified reference materials so third
parties can basically test for those
those things and so people like Josh
will tell you that yeah I could
distinguish a synthetic THC that's been
chemically derived versus a natural th C
which has been extracted from cannabis
plants which I think is where we all
want to be but this synthetic thing kind
of popped up because of what Wade
mentioned the one word greed but it also
mentioned from the fact that they
unleash this 800 pound gorilla in the
room which is the hemp industry without
properly contemplating how to properly
regulate it you know it's not a drug
well I guess epidex is a drug it's AED
drug that you can get a prescription for
that you can buy at a drugstore yeah
that's an approved drug but cannabis for
the mo most part is a medicated herb
right and and they need to come up with
sensible regulation and even FDA threw
up their hands and said yeah this
doesn't really fit into our
monomolecular medicine model which you
take a active ingredient through
clinical trials to show that
statistically the outcome for that
patient works better when they take that
medicine at this particular dose well
cannabis doesn't work like that right
and if michul teaches us anything
teaches us it's not just about the
single ingredient it's about all the
ingredients that are in there and
everything that we like about the
varieties that you guys breed and the
hash that you guys make I mean it's just
it's an
incredible thing but it can't be
regulated and I think the hemp industry
and the Cannabis industry are fighting
at one another and in some estimates
they they they size that that hemp
industry is being greater than 60
billion dollars you know that's that's
greater than all of the collective
cannabis Industries in all the different
states you add all that together the
hemp industry is bigger than that
because large addressable Market
everything's about cost everything's
about making the cheapest thing that
suffices out
there you you you know how do you how do
you tie that together somehow you got to
figure out a way to tie that together
big beverage is now in here because of
what's Happening places like Minnesota
so now you have you know these canning
lines that could make literally
thousands of cans in hour of this hemp
dve D9 10 milligram beverage I tell you
when it's not emulsified Mark even
seasoned THC users like us I can taste
it about halfway through the can I have
like whoa holy [ __ ] that
nanoemulsification really does something
to the biological activity and the onset
of activity so I'll stop there but I
just think that yeah Mojave I don't know
what you're seeing in California but
everywhere else in the United States the
Cannabis industry and the profitability
are in the toilet because they have to
compete with this unwieldy hemp industry
which I I think they're losing the
battle
I think the hemp Farmers too if they
only really understood that you
know there's huge money in the grain of
the plant like here in Canada our hemp
industry is not CBD it's just not a big
part of what we do we grow grain we grow
the seed and then the seed gets either
crushed into oil or it gets dehaul and
and sold as hemp parts and that that is
a a massive business right right which
is not a drug variety you're not you're
not growing a canopy right it's just
completely different I think actually it
actually follows the law I don't know
Mojave don't you think that that the
people in Washington were snookered on
what exactly what Mark is saying I think
that they viewed pemp as being this
industrial grain that makes seed oil uh
by the way there's new studies that show
what we predicted back on H hash Church
many years ago uh that if you feed hemp
seeds to chicken those chickens are
healthier well now Tyson has got that
data and it's just yeah it's a wonderful
we predicted it on hash church weits
claic but yeah I think our government
was thinking steed's oil rope they did
not contemplate CBD right I and if
Robert here he would say because we've
written about about this quite a bit is
just simply what is hemp because that's
that's the big discussion in the US and
I've consulted in Minnesota for the past
almost four years now and it's pretty
weird the transition that's happened
there and it's kind of like become this
petri dish for what is cannabis what is
The Big C genus cannabis because it
started as um a no flower medical only
state where it was just Vapes and
gummies in the in the Delta 9 world and
then quickly CBD became a thing and
people wanted to grow but they didn't
know like what they did literally
farmers were growing plants they didn't
even the farmers themselves didn't know
what the downstream product they were
making was someone just literally showed
up and said hey plant these seeds it's
going to be good for you and they kind
of had an idea so is it CBD is it fiber
is it is it grain it was literally that
confusing and I can tell you stories got
literal harvests where people backed
semis filled with plants into big
manufacturing floors and they didn't
even know what was the product that was
going to be made because they jumped so
fast as Farmers like hey we grow plants
and they say this is a big economic boom
in this anyway over the years it's
transitioned to the most almost the most
liberal model for cannabis on Earth I
mean I drive from Minnesota gas station
to gas station every single gas station
is selling cannabis Beverages and Vapes
gummies you can get you can get cannabis
beverages on tap at a bar in
Minnesota which I don't even understand
how that works because they do have
regulations on per serving amounts and
it on tap it's pretty vague what 16
ounces is or 12 or and anyway and they
have adult use you can grow up to eight
plants at Home they've been incredibly
um uh for Ward thinking in their social
Equity program with the tribal
relationship in terms of giving tribes
uh a head start into the wck market um
that being said the whole thing is still
wacky because it's an island in the
middle of this big crazy continent of
cannabis laws and they also have a
interstate commerce band on what can and
can come in but the far out thing is
just like like um other states it's not
based off of federal DEA guidelines it's
their own like in like in California you
can't order order a BB gun on Amazon
right they'll ship it to you in other
states but you can't order one because
that's just a California law we don't
take BB guns online you know and
Minnesota's like well we also don't take
thca online it's like it's not whether
thca is legal in the state or whether
it's legal wherever but we just have a
ban on Imports because they know how
threatening it is to their emerging
market that California Colorado and
Oklahoma who are now not even you know
now and that's this is the big question
mark is that it's CBD is so cheap
because people grew so much that they
couldn't sell or process are they now
going to be growing
thca instead of high CBD varieties in
order to just circumvent the processing
completely and is that going to be the
new Farm built crop in these states that
are still
well the the the problem with well
there's there's there's lots of problems
there you know I I I come from the
regulated cannabis world you know I I
know about the hemp world but I'm more
along the lines of like you know getting
licensed operations growing you know and
we have to do background checks on all
of our employees we have to have
security cameras 247 you know the whole
nine yards I mean this is like the
cannabis industry treat it like nuclear
waste kind of [ __ ] believe me I'm not
about the or over orous regul
regulations that apply that they apply
to it but if you look at it again I I
don't think the intention of when
Congress passed the farm bill was to
unleash active pharmaceutical
ingredients on the farm I I I just don't
think that that was the case and I I I
don't think again they P I think they
were snookered on seeds and rope and oil
I don't think they ever thought about
you know the CBD versus THC and
converting CBD into THC hell that
chemistry is as old as Roger Adams so
the the the worst thing is that is that
there's products like thcp which don't
come from hemp and don't come from CBD
that are just completely synthetic and
if they're completely synthetic well now
where can you get completely synthetic
active ingredients Pharmaceuticals made
places like China and India so now it's
just you know
again these are these aren't being
extracted from plants that are grown in
the ground they're chemicals that are
made in the laboratory that are
exploiting the wonderful activity and
safety really of
phytochemicals but I've heard from a few
people that have tried this thcp thing
and it is serious business it like puts
you down in your chair and like for two
days you don't want to smoke anything or
be around any like weed and it's like
that's not a very pleasurable experience
yeah can you turn up the volume of
compounds that can agonize your C CB1
receptors absolutely that's the way
Medicinal Chemistry works but there's
something that's great about the
cannabis plant is it's got more than
just THC right so you'll know that your
experience with cannabis doesn't
necessarily have have to do with the THC
level the reason why the THC level is so
important in Commerce is because of
prohibition and because like when
dispensaries and Distributors are doing
bulk buying and they're like gee am I
going to buy the 25% or am I going to
buy the stuff that analyzes for 15%
chances are the stuff that's analyzing
for 25% is really 15% they they're just
cherry-picking their data that they're
getting their COA is made on all this is
just an artifact of prohibition and I
think like the last thing just about the
hemp thing is that you know there's yeah
probably people who are going to listen
to what I say and say oh man you're
against the plant you're against taking
it's like no I'm all about the plant but
if people want cannabis and they want
thca they need to end prohibition
because only when prohibition is so I've
said this many times before as long as
there's prohibition everywhere
and anywhere there'll be a black market
everywhere and so like in California for
example right it doesn't matter what the
laws are in California the laws are
[ __ ] up in other places so California
becomes basically the supply chain and I
think the worst thing that's happening
now again is that there's this war
between businesses that are trying to
get products out through the camp
channels versus cannabis channels
they're in law suits together right now
because again the folks in Southern
California because they've had to pay
large dollars to get their places
licensed and to get their places up and
running and now there's an unfair
competition from this you know
competitive landscape that's outside
their jurisdiction that's bringing cheap
products into their state you know it's
the perfect storm I it's going to be
interesting to see how this changes if
it changes at all in the next version of
the farm bill which as you know Mojave
they just kicked the can down the road
uh but you know it's an election year um
who knows maybe things will happen and
they'll end up deregulating the plant I
think moving to schedule three is an
absolute nonstarter because if you read
the
regulations you you know none of the
Cannabis supply chain that exists today
would be compliant with schedule 3
listing so I think this is basically an
invitation for big farmer to come in and
start acquiring msos that are positioned
to get you know their their GMP
certifications so I know I'm doing a lot
of talking here but yeah things are
[ __ ] up down in the states Mark but
you know hopefully everything will move
forward because of people's love for the
plant and I like to almost put it back
to like micr Brew I mean once you let
the micr Brew kind of bug out there were
no you know no going back for some of us
who will never drink Budweiser again
I'll only drink a locally brewed micr
Brew right so I think maybe with
cannabis again art artisan quality will
really come through on that and that'll
end up winning um
anyway so much about Walmart hemp and
cannabis give there's no shortage of it
for sure yeah it's it's always a balance
right you know the whole
time there's that I bet you most people
are happy with the vape pen gas station
thcp diluted with CBN or whatever like I
I don't know I just we are the anomalies
our group is a special group that's like
you know part of a smaller group that
will grow just like I'm sure IPA beer
has grown I don't know what the
percentage of IPA beer is versus like
Kors and Old Milwaukee and Budweiser
micro mean in general you mean like
locally brewed micro brew yeah compared
to big beer you know what do big beer
own of the beer industry is it like 50%
or is it like 80 or 90% I have no idea
that that's it
Marcus to my Costco down here and I
could certainly buy huge pallets of Bud
Light but right next to the Bud Light
there's locally brewed Vermont Beer
that's so much better right
so yeah but but people aren't buying it
by the pallet probably you probably not
it's gr it's growing we'll put it this
way it's funny because me and Rob write
a lot about the comparison between Hops
and cannabis and also the craft beer and
craft cannabis kind of um issues but um
as craft beer grew what what happened
Marcus was the big alcohol bought the
craft all the crafts companies so that
so there are now that's why micro brew
became a thing you know and now it's
actually Nano Brew because even the
micro Brews are often owned by anheiser
Bush but but to that point it got them
and I say this you know it's like hey if
if uh you know if it made their beer
better and it expanded they said hey
we're aner Bush and we think we can sell
that to our customers as well then it it
to me that's a better world and I think
our quality of canab the issue the big
issue to me is that cannabis is really
complex but growing it is just
Agriculture and as soon as we figure out
the growing part it's actually not a lot
harder to grow amazing cannabis that
tastes amazing and has a great effect
versus complete [ __ ] once they figure it
out it's like you can get I mean I can
go and buy blueberries from Chile or I
can buy an Apple from New Zealand and
it's perfect and it's like the whole
supply chain we can grow amazing weed
for people and they can be big giant
corporations that will be involved and
there'll be small companies that'll be
involved but ultimately right now it's
just a mess because there's so
much data and so much transition going
on that people you know it just opens up
a can of worms but I do think like when
when like and that's one of the biggest
issues for me is like you can't hold the
plant to a higher standard than other
plants so you can't blame agriculture
for wanting to be involved you can't
blame business as usual for being
involved because that's just the way it
works we've always tried to normalize
the plant
but like we're supposed to be like the
Shepherds that make it through that
transition to hand the plant over to
those people who are going to take it
anyway like so we have a little bit of a
like protector kind of entitlement over
like shaping the future industry and the
cool thing is I think we can I think
like working with the right people
becoming successful with your Brands and
your genetics and all that [ __ ] really
shapes the future of cannabis so it's
like you know I just I don't I don't
think that you know it's all doom and
gloom I just think that it's going to be
a completely different thing on the
other side you know and that's cool
because that's what we all kind of
wanted you know it's just it's difficult
to hold the hand through the transition
and take the blows but you know we I
think if you look at if you look at like
what's happened in retail in general I
mean we've reduced it down to Costco
Walmart and Jeff Bezos right I mean the
the the whole
distribution business model I mean those
big corporations you talk about Mojave
those are the ones that are basically
predicated on roads and cheap gasoline
for their trucks to basically go from
their fulfillment centers out to those
stores and put all those goods and so
like when you're in Walmart and when
you're making Walmart purchase yeah it
would be
great like again I don't know when
Walmart and cannabis are going to team
up but when they do you know it's going
to be like yeah it's just going to be
part of your shopping right like oh I
can get a pair of blue jeans I can get
motor oil I can get you know a pack of
chicken breast and oh yeah I can pick up
some weed all underneath One Roof
because they own that distribution
Channel and that's super powerful
because like when you're looking at like
dispensaries like I was giving some
advice to a client of mine around you
know they're like okay we gotta we gotta
think about where we want to put our
dispensaries I was like you know what
next to the BMW dealer you know you
right I mean it's like like today in
retail I mean you have to think about so
many different patterns about like how
humans purchase things and where humans
go to get things and my god when you're
sitting at the uh I don't know
McDonald's uh a drive-thru let's hope
you're not if you're watching the show
but you're looking at I don't know some
sign like hey you know what I'm going to
go pop over to that store because I just
was looking at that sign while I'm
sitting here waiting for my kids in
their Big Mac you know like today retail
is a completely different game it's
completely different just even in the
last four or five years and I I don't
know I mean like if you're going to
introduce like retail
cannabis I mean I mean my God as the
companies that have put a lot of money
into their dispensaries you have to you
know really the again draw people in you
have to have aquariums you have to have
like nice couches and
everything what's the differentiator at
cannabis retail and ultimately like yeah
what are you up against someone just
putting an 8 vape pen on their credit
card you know that they're going to get
shipped to them a day later with their
Jeff BAS package from Amazon you know
it's a different retail Marketplace it
really
is yeah and you're not even getting into
predictive algorithms that actually
manipulate and predict the buying
patterns of the humans because it's not
just about fitting in and finding your
place that's a rabbit hole that unless
you're a complete and total sociopath
you probably don't really want to go
down that rabbit
hole well Marcus I I don't mean to make
cracks at like some celebrity branded
cannabis but I I've always thought that
you know if you need celebrity branding
to sell your cannabis find better
cannabis right I mean like right I mean
don't you feel like that too in a way I
mean just like this whole branding thing
I mean you might buy that Bob Marley jar
once right and now oh you got that nice
jar what do you do with it put it on the
Shelf with all your other J yeah for me
I'm more interested in the Branded ones
that like the name means something
something like a hash maker or a grower
or both who's doing you know what I mean
and that and at that point it's like uh
I I think of my brand more along in the
lines of that like people are like okay
this guy like sort of helped Pioneer the
water extraction thing it's been like
focused on producing quality what's that
has before hip hop
right right
exactly yeah well geez I think we've
done two hours I that was pretty good
for me today I think uh I really
appreciated the conversation it was very
natural like it was a year plus ago just
getting into it and having good
discussions and I learned things today
that I didn't know that were going on
I'm definitely going to look deeper into
that LA Times story Mojave about the
vape pens and the hardware and the the
[ __ ] that they're putting in those
that's uh that is not a good scene at
all um Brian always a pleasure dude I
hope you come back with more flavors
we'll have another hash church here next
Sunday uh Mojave thank you so much for
your perspective and your your knowledge
and your stories love love the stories
when you and Brian were going back and
forth I love that old history you know
because it really is like you know we
need we we need to get Chris Bennett
back on the the Cannabis historian
because Chris has always gone further
back into the history but I think his
ability to keep history to receive these
stories and to put them to pen would be
uh a very valuable um addition to to our
to our community Papa sift Ryan thanks
for showing up homie thanks for making
the good hash and [ __ ] maybe next
time we'll talk about the differences
between the Osprey and the hashte
because you're one of the few people
that have both of them in your lab and
you're operating simultaneously with
both of them so we'll get you uh get you
talking about that next time dude Dr
Mark Salone thank you dude from Vermont
in the on the good side of town you and
you and Brian must not be too too far
away from one another like four
hours that's not too bad that's worth
like a dab session you guys should link
up one of these days and of course Wade
thank you so much for coming dude thanks
for sharing your story and your Vibe and
your positivity and uh I hope to see you
guys again next week I'm GNA do it again
invite a couple of new people if you
have anyone that you're thinking of that
you want to get invited on for next week
just send me an email and uh in the
meantime thank you guys everyone on
YouTube uh we just went under 200 people
but we had over 200 people watching for
the full two hours so that's pretty
awesome uh big thanks to Bing Bingo
Lombardi for holding down the chat and
all the good folks that are in there
chatting away and keeping it going and
agreeing and disagreeing with us at the
same time uh and a big thank you to
Thomas from Grandmaster LED for uh you
know hooking up with the knowledge on
how I can change the view for coming in
and sharing your great new addition to
the panel here on hash church and uh I
will say May the full melt bless you
sooner than later you're all welcome to
say goodbye and then we'll end it peace
everybody cheers bye everyone by thank
you nice to talk with you Mojave nice to
hear with from everyone