record and then we will go live on
YouTube because you know we deserve it
welcome Wade we're g to go live on
YouTube right now and I believe I
believe we're live right now so why
don't I say the welcoming morning
welcome as I often do welcome to Hash
Church 3.0 episode 13
today starting it off with uh with Wade
and atan already in the room how how
about that so there I believe we are
live
oh you believe it buddy here let me just
share this in the other chat so we can
get our crew because for whatever reason
the way Zoom works now is it doesn't let
me go live from the actual video that
the the link that I put up on YouTube it
used to do that but now it starts a
whole new link so there's 80 people in
the other chat room and they're kind of
like what's going on here all right
there we go let's let in Mr Mark we're
going to talk about Mark's cultivar
today early because Mark didn't get to
talk last week because hash Church uh
you know we're we're aggressive talkers
you you gotta you gotta really get in
the get in there if you want to have
something to
say through that true that welcome Wade
it's nice to see your smiley face
feeling really good this morning Marcus
right back at you an Aton hello sir
amazing how you feeling good is
noticeable on your face and is making me
feel good oh I'm happy to hear that yeah
oh that's the truth I can't deny it I
cannot deny it hey welcome Mark how you
doing
buddy good how's it going guys it's
going good I like you got your hash
Church uh hoodie on
there yeah yeah rocking that out this
morning thanks for the invite appreciate
it yes yes of course of course I felt
bad last week we didn't talk about the
hash Church uh we did have a great hash
Church episode though and I think that
was the problem there was just so much
to talk about and it was pulling us into
the mushroom and once the mushroom gets
a hold of you well you know that's uh
that's usually five or six hours before
it lets go
so but we got you back today um I'm not
sure who's gon to come in today it might
be kind of a small hash Church it might
be a big hash Church um last week I sent
the link through Facebook but some of
the people in that link didn't receive
it Dr Mark shalone said he didn't
receive the link uh which I haven't
figured out how that is because there's
two groups I send out emails to certain
groups Wade for instance is on the
emails and then I do Facebook Messenger
invites as well uh of which most of the
rest of you guys uh probably would have
gotten your link that way welcome Johnny
B maybe Johnny B can't hear yet welcome
Johnny
[Laughter]
B joh John Johnny
Johnny Johnny can you come out and
play oh is that a Warriors
reference
yeah I figured isn't it come out to
play come out to play yay yeah there we
go there we go well nice to sit with you
guys this morning I think uh like I said
I kind of put it together last minute I
would prefer to just do any old hash
church just to keep it consistent that's
what kind of everyone's looking for
right now in these crazy times that
we're living in um and I just figured
you know what even if we got together
for a couple hours and shot the [ __ ]
puffed some bowls and talked a little
bit about the hash church cultivar and
some other things uh I figured we'd be
good yeah Johnny's trying to configure
his audio by looking at his shelf he's
just like what the [ __ ] is going on what
the
[ __ ] he'll figure it out
it's usually a setting in your Zoom
though you have to sometimes it
automatically uh switches your audio to
your mic if you have an external mic so
you have to switch it to your internal
audio I just switched it to my Yeti so
is it working now lima charlie
yeah yeah colins's hitting me up saying
he can't find the link and I just sent
it to the email so he everyone should
have gotten it on that
email that is very I saw it was a little
bit hard to find uh but this morning
was easy thank you okay good we always
want to make it easy we don't want to
make it hard but I'm going to send it
out again just in case I need to go get
a pipe
INE I have three computers going I know
which one to hit so garage living room
or the
office Johnny
B I hear you good okay so now I'm gonna
hit mute so I Johnny B and Colin
P Colin p
morning
Colin never really saw the connection
between Johnny B and Colin P but now
I'll never be able to unsee it it's just
how life is if if only Colin had a
keyboard Just One
keyboard yeah exactly if he had a
keyboard he could make it all work but I
don't know know I have none I I don't
know what these things do behind me one
of these one of these days you're gonna
have to rip a tune is what you're going
to have to do because I will we've been
watching you in that room for like I
don't know three four five years y it's
true fake background right yeah it's one
of those fake right it's funny because I
have two drum kits here and i' I've been
collecting instruments since I was maybe
a teenager when I first started uh you
know moving some stuff
uh it was a good uh good way to to put
my energy into other things so I launder
your cash uh I don't I'm just
joking it's a positive
[Laughter]
experience oh hash Church hash Church
jokes for sure listen today we're
starting by talking about the hash
church cultivar that Mark Hallet who's
in the room right now hit me up with a
while ago he first hit me up with that
infamous picture which I wish I kind of
had it on my computer right now and
maybe I do let me see oh I do I do I can
just share my screen look at that so
this was kind of the picture that
started it all off for me and how we're
going to get into this conversation and
Mark's going to talk and we're gonna
have to you know give him some patience
because he's kind of new at these hash
church thing so there you go that is
what started it all now so so plant
plant porn you got some plant porn and
that started all up some some plant porn
right and you know lots of people were
like oh you know is that the hooked
triome cultivar I don't see you know
there's I don't see the heads as clearly
as I should is it you know so you know
Mark hit me up and he said listen I've
got this cultivar I want to name it hash
church and I was kind of like a little
bit like oo I was a little bit like I'm
kind of a little bit protective of like
the hash Church name you know I haven't
monetized it I haven't done anything
like that and I told him like I'm not
going to I don't want to be up I don't
want to take anything from you I'm not
trying to be that greasy guy that just
starts monetizing everything that I'm
doing with you guys I just didn't really
you know feel that it was the thing I
wanted to do but he he said look let me
let me send you a cut you can grow it
you can Harvest it you can let me know
if you think it's it's it's it could
hold the name hash church and so he sent
me the cut and I managed to get one to
Flav and I completely [ __ ] uh the rest
of it up and uh I just for whatever
reason it was one of the first plants
and I don't think this has anything to
do with the plant itself cuz Flav is
crushing it but generally whenever I've
had a small tent I've been able to throw
a couple of plants in there and never
have a problem with this one it just
gave me a problem for whatever reason
and and funny enough I ended up putting
a Congo just to sort of save face as to
you know realize that I'm not talking
[ __ ] on the hash church I threw a Congo
into the same tent and the exact same
thing started happening it just started
looking like it was nutrient deficient
like it was locking like and I mean like
I know how to grow weed I feed very
simple Med I'm using medy one of course
no what light I'm listen I'm not gonna
get into a huge alian LED conversation
with you right now but it is I had an
LED light in from one of the companies
and I had an HPS in there as well the
old tried and true which I've always
been able to grow great resin with full
melt resin anyway totally [ __ ] that up
and you know Mark being as awesome as he
is was like well maybe I could send you
some flour and you could just like make
a batch like run run some hash or
something I was like oh man like I feel
bad you know like I told him well if you
send me flour I'm not smoking any of the
hash it's all been sitting in these um
pizza boxes since I made it I actually
made it for my course on camera uh but I
wanted to talk about it and the hash
came out completely white I mean
complete like super light colored uh it
did have a melt Factor to it it wasn't
uh like a six-star but it definitely was
melty for me what I really loved about
it is it reminded me of an old cultivar
I used to grow back like 25 plus years
ago called The Dutch Treat now people
may hear that name and think they had
exactly the Dutch Treat that I have or
had I never really saw it as that again
and I saw the Dutch Treat many times
over the years but this particular Dutch
Treat looked very much like this it was
very coated it had this real sort of
unique flavor which I also found this
particular cultivar had a little bit so
Mark why don't you tell us a little bit
about how this cult ofar came to be the
parental stock that was used to create
it and just a little bit about uh a
little bit about the hash church I also
want to mention before Mark starts is
that he's been you know beyond like okay
look he's he's he's like all of us like
there we're all hurting you know this
covid-19 was is a real Crusher to him
and his family it took a lot away from
him and now he's in a position where
he's got this thing I started posting it
people were like where can I get that
where can I get that and they're hitting
him up like you wouldn't believe like we
want to buy seeds we want to buy this we
want to buy that and he's told me he's
like listen I'm not selling it I'm not
giving it away until you give me the
okay that I can use this name and so I
feel a little bit bad because it's taken
a long time and if I really think of
what CO's taken away from this guy maybe
I would get off my ass a little bit more
and make it happen and so today that's
what we're doing we're talking about
hash Church on hash Church uh he's going
to let us know a little bit about the
genetics a little bit about you know
running it growing it Etc uh and then
we'll go on from there so Mark the floor
is yours my
friend thank thanks Marcus uh I'm not
sure if I'm going to become coming black
glitchy or not to you fellas that you
guys were a little bit glitchy so long
as I you guys can hear me okay I think
I'm good to
go yeah we can hear you great absolutely
okay okay excellent uh so pretty much
started with uh years of watching hurch
to be quite honest um you know ever
since this show started I've kind of
tuned in uh I see dragonfly has just
signed out now those guys have been a
big inspiration to me I I kind of
started uh in the hydroponic type area
back in the early 90s and then once uh
stumbling across h church and realizing
you know Organics are definitely the the
full way um I just kind of going down
that dragonfly rout of like a fully
regenerative organic kind of uh growing
style so from that point um I just want
to say a big shout out to all you guys
every one of you Growers on here whether
you are hash makers or not uh big
inspiration for the this cultiv I don't
think and I've told this Demarcus before
I don't think the thing would exist uh
without the show or the man channel so
to give you quick rundown this fast
story of how this come to be um I was uh
skimming across online and stumbled
across a bubble man's Channel and
um he was advertising his solventless
extraction class um so I thought what
you know to pay bit bit of respect back
I'll will sign up for that and the thing
that blew me the way it was literally
like a light switch going off in my head
um he does uh his introduction a part of
this solventless class uh hosted by ganj
University um he starts off his
introduction in his wakeboard boat
actually uh sitting in the middle of the
ocean and dude you break down that plant
within the 20 to 30
minutes uh it was like a light switch
literally going off my head of how
little I really didn't know about the
plant and from that point I realized yes
I needed to you know I wanted to create
my own kind of hash plant so at that
point
um I I I did my first cross it didn't
turn out that great I'm just a small
little grower in in you know little 4x4
t0 so uh very very limited of what I
could do inside that so I figured I'm
going to go back at it again I I'll try
it again why not I I really wanted a
good hasher um I just didn't have access
around this area to anything any quality
like you guys talk about so uh that's
when I crossed the DNA's kosher sorbet
with uh kuu
cookies
um I collected roughly about 190 seeds
off that particular
cross and I I figured oh like I got to
give this a shot I popped the first seed
uh um as this thing was progressing into
flower I just noticed that the large
number in of Tri chromes that were
growing on it and I had enough
experience in the past where I realized
that I had uh something that I thought
was a little special as far as the tri
Chrome production went so at that point
um I just you know kept growing it out
taking as many photos as I could and the
cool thing was it started to produce um
this turine like Marx had mentioned it
reminded me more of a a northern light
skunk cross I grew back in the 90s it
just was a super super gassy dank coming
off of it and uh my lights the photo
period would go off from s at night to 7
in the morning and I just noticed that
the the carbon filters in my indoor tent
just were not keeping up to it um that's
how gassy and stinky she was so as it
got later into flower the the the thing
that struck me for the hash Church name
was I was taking an upshot of fan leaf
and to me it screamed like it looked
like a church window stained glass
window of a church which was super cool
so I thought [ __ ] well how cool would it
be to H you know have a a strain named
hatrid I thought the potential could be
there um I knew I needed to make cash at
that point so I ran a B of has um and I
pulled the 120 I was telling Marcus the
very first run I had made of this I
pulled the 120 and it was just jammed
full jammed full I couldn't believe it
how bad this thing dumped in the
120 um my previous runs past that point
it just seems to have changed into a 90
and a 73 now but just a mysterious part
of it but anyway at that point it
reached out to uh Marcus I said hey I
think I have something that you might
want to look at I think it's got a good
potential um I'm sure he probably said
you know gez who's this guy why you know
why is he want me to name at
hurch um so at that point I said well
let's make you know a little bargain
deal I'll ship you some clones you guys
grow them out um at first I thought that
you know they they were going to flip
them a little bit sooner and I know Flav
had his in quarantine which was super
cool I respect that um so I thought
yeah sorry no sorry to cut you off I
just want to show everyone um you know
when you're like yeah so I shipped them
off a couple of clones we talked about
this before but look what he shipped the
Clones off
in this is what the Clones showed up in
just for everyone to know this guy is
top [ __ ] Notch okay I couldn't
believe it when these custom homemade
PVC pipes that he's glued a couple of
tops onto who the [ __ ] has ever sent you
clones in a clone oh and he also added
lights he had tiny little lights
inserted into the unit with a little
battery pack taped onto the outside so
they were they never were dark at all
the entire time that he shipped them I
have never received clones in anything
this absolutely beautiful I'll keep
these forever bro like I'm telling you
this is some tattoo art that you sent me
on the on the on the tubing that you
sent the Clones so sorry to interrupt
but I needed to let everyone know the
level of Awesomeness and the level of
caliber that you're that you're
operating at I'm loving
that that's beautiful yeah no I
appreciate
that thank you appreciate that um I knew
yeah I definitely [ __ ] the bed the first
time was ever very first time I had
shipped clones actually and uh the very
first ones I sent to Marcus he probably
laughed when he opened them up and
thought what the [ __ ] is this but anyway
uh he I said up you know I knew I had to
take care special care of the second
batch so I packed them up and sent them
off to them um but pretty much at that
point uh yeah I wanted to kind of speed
the process up for Marcus at least to
get an idea of what the tpin were like
on this particular cultiv bar so I said
dude you know can what's chances I can
ship you some flour yeah man he says
send me some out so I shipped him out a
small little bit of flow so he could
watchh just to see and and you know
obviously pictures one thing and at
least he could put a tpine profile to
the to the photo anyway um and at that
point now I just pretty much continue to
run it out and try to get all I can out
of her uh trying to push her as much as
I can and I know Marcus had said you
can't really wave a a magic wand and be
a a a full melt grower right off the bat
so I'm definitely a a little dragonfly
in training I'm going to say uh but that
that's pretty much the story of where
where you know how it came to be and um
yeah mad respect to you all like I don't
think honestly it would exist without
the knowledge drops that you guys have
done in the
past Mark those designs that you dropped
on there what were they from and uh why
did you select those on the packaging
that's pretty epic all in all to send
such one a nice packaging but of course
you wanted to make an impression and
apparently you very much did so how'd
you go about the art selection
process uh to be honest that's a it was
the temporary tattoos so it was quite
easy there were like an armband tattoo
you would purchase that you would just
stick on and I thought you know I got to
go all out and make a little impression
for Marcus that I've you know took a
little extra care this time and thought
what what the heck why
not how many weeks is the uh is the
cultivar in terms of flowering times um
and what are you doing um you want to
talk to talk a little bit about what
you're vegging how long you're vegging
for and um what you think the the cult
ofar likes and what have you seen so
far yeah thanks col I'm a big fan of
yours too dude I I mad respect to the
hash you've been making too I've been
checking that out all you guys man it's
it's incredible uh but but veg time has
changed I've just been pretty much
playing around with it um the node
spacing could be tighter um if flower
time sits which I'm experimenting with
uh sits about anywhere from I'm guessing
55 to 60 days somewhere in that
neighborhood um the one thing that I did
and I think Bubble Man may be seen some
photos of is I was harvesting fresh
frozen
flour once every about four days as it
was growing late in flour and trying to
run hash that way in Mason jards just to
see how it actually acts and you know at
what point is is it going to smoke the
best so I got a lot of work to do yet
but just trying to get all I can out of
her how much does she usually yield on a
wash percentage
wise um
I've even pushed probably closer to
quarter pound per
plant that's in a 4x4 single plant run
though you know it's not it's not a huge
yielding plant there's no doubt about
that doesn't have uh but I you know I
think Frost makes up for the yield
myself when you wash her what percentage
of uh rosin are you left with in the end
um I was for the rosin I was getting
back anywhere from 20 to the highest I
got was 22% so
far it's not too bad at all I
unfortunately when I washed it was I
didn't have a scale and I was unable to
do the math on the returns I think from
a bubble has perspective it was probably
around like 14
15% uh but I wasn't actually able to do
the accurate math I did squish a little
Ros and and I also got I got a little
under I think I got around like 16 14 to
16 I only I got to admit felt bad having
this guy's flower and I didn't want to
like smoke it all and press it all and
wash it all I was just like you know
I'll I'll make it and then I'll send it
back to him so I've got 99% of his hash
I did uh someone did just ask me hey why
don't you just take a quick little bowl
so I've got a little bit right here I'm
going to dump in the old Bowl right now
and it's definitely bubbling and and
melting and and and
boiling and just another thing qu to
mention is that you know
hopefully one day all you guys get a
chance to grow it out that would be
super cool that was kind of my overall
goal was you know eventually if all you
guys could have the cut or if at least
you wanted to try it out um that that
kind of was my goal eventually would be
super
cool very cool
man it's it's good there's no doubt
about about it it's reminiscent of that
sort
of Dutch Treat flavor it doesn't have a
really super there's not a fruity flavor
to it I hear what you're saying with the
gassy flavor but even in this dab it's
it's more like a Musky kind of I don't
know just like a Dutch Treat really nice
that was my first high of The Day My
Little My waking bake if you will uh and
very much like right in right in here
almost like a headband feeling pretty
good it's got a really nice high when I
first hit it I was like oh it's it's the
hash church it's got to have the most
resin it's got to knock people out and I
HIIT it and I didn't get knocked out but
I realized I don't need it to knock me
out I've got like wedding cake and some
other cultivars that are nice and heavy
that I can go to bed with but this one
was a really nice sort of you know a lot
of my hashes I've got congales in the
morning that's the one that lifts me up
you know I hit the heavier ones in the
evening and I hit some of the real tasty
kind of upbeat ones in the middle of the
day as to not burn out and fall asleep
but hash Church funny enough I can hit
it in any of those categories I'm happy
to hit it at night I'm happy to hit it
in the morning I haven't hit it much but
I know how bad I want to hit it and
that's generally what decides for me if
I like something it's very easy if I
have something on my desk that sits for
a month and it's not really generally
something that I'm that I'm excited
about or that I'm feeling good about so
hash Church definitely is a nice
cultivar I would I'm going to get clones
back from Flav so I can actually grow it
in my tent try and get one over to some
over to Johnny B and maybe to the
dragonfly Earth medicine folks and any
of the other Canadian um yeah welcome by
the way you guys welcome by the way I
have one one quick question just uh for
Mark real quick uh if when you water
wash it which Micron had the best uh
glands on it for hash chur
90 120 going back to yeah I'm going back
to that very first wash at 10 that I did
the first run um it dumped in 120 and
had a beautiful beautiful melt point and
I hadn't been able to achieve that since
for some strange reason it seems to be
all in the you know my last few runs of
it have been in the 70 and the 90 73 and
90 that's what I saw as well uh I just
hit the 73 and it it really is a nice
Vibe hash like there's no doubt about
that the plant looks beautiful under uh
the macro lens maybe I can actually um
find I'm pretty sure I photographed it
and uploaded those pictures unless
they're on my camera right now in which
case obviously I would not be able to
open them up but let me just go look
real quick and
see if I can't find at least a
few macro shots of
the this plant we love so much okay so
yeah I think I do I'll have to open it
up in Lightroom give me a second here
welcome to the dragonfly Earth medicine
if you guys want to have a little chat
with us real quick while I'm checking
this out while I open these hash Church
uh photos we'd love to hear from you
super thankful to hear the story good to
see everyone this morning um really cool
to to hear your story Mark and uh you
know I just I love that about cannabis
you know it it shows itself to the
people who you know often are really
dedicated you know and I can see that
you have this dedication inside of you
and and uh you know I get let's say the
plant's rewarding you for it and uh you
know and I love the idea that we're all
sharing it and learning about it and
stuff and it's just uh it's an exciting
time it gives us something positive to
to think about and work with the plant
and everything so good to see everyone
this morning and just when we think that
you know like all of the best strains
are already out there it's really
awesome to see a new one come out and
then and then how it rolls out and how
we're looking at it and it's just really
awesome conversation this morning good
job on the Clone delivery as well I'll
have to Second That Emotion yeah yeah
thank
you keep chatting guys I'm looking for
these pictures here and I can't both
chat and so Mark um you said at first it
came out heavy on the 120 and then now
you find it coming out more you know
heavy on the 70 and 90 do you have any
gut feelings or intuition about that um
in your
experience uh I I just I'm a little
confused by that I actually had
mentioned that to bubble man that the
very first run was all in the 120 and
and for some reason it's just you know
I'm getting a big amount in the 90 and
the 73 and even the
45 um the melty is sitting in the 90 the
last couple runs so
uh I I I'm just trying to find that I
guess um I I've started using live worm
castings and that was kind of stemmed on
by you guys as well I've kind of Taken
and started composting in indoor using
uh a live worm casting worm B and I
believe you know it's it's getting
approaching about three years old now
and and the the microbiology and you
know like you can just pop it open and
you're seeing all the the
microbes all the tiny little beneficial
bugs got some questions for you Mark I
was just curious on like temperatures uh
DLI if you know what your da integrals
are if you if you're running like your
VPD uh what's your temperatures humidity
levels like I'm really curious on the
strain because of course I do so many
testings on different varieties so I'm
kind of curious on like how are you
running the
strength hey Johnny a big big fan of
YouTube brother um I I just going to
throw this out quick too Johnny because
I know you're running LEDs so the two
lights that I've been running with this
particular cultivar were the op the 8
and uh the electric sky
300s I've had the most success um under
that electric sky uh both are you know
getting huge amount of frost but
Electric Sky seems to excel I I'm not
sure and you know I got a total draw
watt for my two electric Skies can
approach to be about 600 watts if I
fully crank them and this cultivar likes
to sit about the 300 mark which is you
know quite quite low lighting so I think
it likes uh particularly low lighting
compared to my optic8 is is you know
crazy amount of it's it's bright those
cob
lights um so it just prefers a little
bit of a lower lighting as far as VPD I
have haven't really messed with BPD too
much um yeah dude I I I just haven't
really messed with that I kind of did a
little bit but uh I found that that BPD
is a little strange as far as how high
they you know they wanted the humidity
at certain points just seemed like a
almost a nightmare ready to begin as far
as PM but um I I could see uh uh trying
to get into you know a little bit better
range of that over time hopefully it's
hard to dial into my basement the way
I'm growing in just a small 4x4 t0 so oh
God that really changes
everything is really hard to control so
I understand that are you planning on
making any seed or germ plasm of hash
Church sorry atan I didn't get that are
you planning on making any seeds or germ
plasm of hash
Church besides I know it's you what
you'll have to explain germ plasm that's
new one to me that's just another word
for seeds oh okay um I'm sitting the f1s
I'm sitting on about 180
and math says if I've only popped one of
those seeds happen to be the hasch I've
popped I think four more just to run the
outdoor just to see what they were going
to actually be like still Frosty and and
turpy but not quite like that first one
and I you know math says there's got to
be some other ones in that package uh
I'd like to make an F2 cross though
eventually but uh I'm just kind of uh
following bubble man's guidance kind of
with this one of what he recommends
honestly I want to an opinion um one of
the things that I learned early on in
this work is that the health and
vitality of the mother plant that you're
taking cuting from has a lot to do with
the Vitality of those cuting once you
try growing them out and so if your
Nursery your mother plants are also in
that 4x4 tint or in that same
basement uh it's likely the
uh the Vitality of those mothers might
be deteriorating and that's why you're
seeing a reduction in the size of your
tricomes just a thought yeah agree Wade
um I've had a tough time actually
keeping the original mother alive she's
looking a lot better than it did about a
month ago uh but yeah it's it's it's
tough I'm finding it super tough to keep
a a mother around for as long as I have
now and um just trying to keep her as
healthy as possible like you had
mentioned and uh yeah I realized that if
the healthy healthier the mother is the
better the Clones are going to be for
sure
yeah I second what Wade saying about
propagation uh propagation is the most
important part of your cycle
um if you don't start with the right uh
cuts and take care of them uh you're
going to have a really hard time through
your through your growth
cycle so um rejuven rejuvenating those
moms often or is usually very
helpful and um don't give up on it it's
it's it's it's a battle
sometimes Ohad
no come on
now um you know with mothers too you
know I mean I broad mites and and russet
mites have been around for a good amount
of time for a lot of people but you'd be
unbelievably surprised how often they
still go by without being diagnosed yeah
and the only way to really know whether
you have them is a trained eye you know
or a a microscope and looking at the
bottom of the leaf and it doesn't have
to be a microscope like a table
microscope but one that's around 60 you
know and and well and then you look at
the bottom of the leaf and at the bottom
of the leaf looks like it has tricomes
on it the bottom of the sunleaf you know
that there's not tricomes on the bottom
of the sunleaf and that it's broad Mite
eggs or rusted eggs and and often the
plant can look like it's depleted the
plant can often look like it has hmag
deficiency or it doesn't have the growth
that it's looking for when really it's
just eat being eaten by a microscopic
might so and and people have all kinds
of different regimens but you know just
the the simple regimen of of a sski and
cucko Maris uh Duo of predator mites in
with your mother right in with your
mother and your clones of course you
you're put it in your closet on your put
some of the Predators on your your
closet you uh on your jackets and
everything you know just get Predators
everywhere eating so you become a
beneficial organism when you go around
and then um and then as you propagate
and put it into the flower room you have
another fresh round you know on in the
flower room and then that allows your
plant leaves the leaves of your plants
to be flat and people in this community
need to understand that flat
leaves and preing
is Health that's our goal that's our
goal we all the tricomes come all of the
the good smoke the Melt everything comes
after you have a flat healthy leafed
plant and that's a h you know something
to for everyone to just re get to know
about and I think that you know we go to
a lot of uh different Grow rooms and a
lot of outdoor Gardens and I'd say that
in the indoor grow rooms you know a huge
percentage of people have broad m
and people always say Hey you know I
don't see the broad mes well if you
actually see a m then you're way over
infested they're super fast moving
they're incredibly fast moving and also
the male broad mites disperse the female
eggs throughout the leaf so it's not
like you find like a bundle of eggs or
anything go ahead John had a question I
like this cuz I'm actually seeing
exactly what you're talking about right
now I mean talking about this because
what happened is I got some clones from
a friend Mark no and Monty went to the
neighbors who had these mites and they
were in his bathroom and at the about
week seven I started getting him in my
flower room so I I it was didn't make a
difference to me um because it came in
but now that I'm seeing him on my mom's
I'm like okay next step so I'm on the
bug lady right now I'm like I've always
sprayed I've gone around that thing but
I don't want to spray this time I'm like
okay you guys are so convinced me right
now so right here now bug lady what do I
got order you know
like try try to look beneficial
nematodes are really helpful as well I
found a lot of comfort in using them um
it quite a bit in my soils in the past
because just all that all of it together
is just a great IPM system and it's I
love what Josh and Kelly are saying it's
it's so needed this is one of the
reasons why I have an appreciation for
tissue culture right Meemic tissue
culture just just micropropagation
you're still cloning but you're cloning
like a a tiny tiny tiny tiny little
fraction of the marem and then growing
it up right growing it in this agar
medium in a little in a little jar and
it it starts growing and all of its uh
fungi and bacteria and viruses it they
they try to keep up but they can't keep
up and so you cut that little marem you
get it into their that that Medium which
is really the IP that's going to
convince that plant to grow a dominant
Chute and and start growing upwards and
so you do this for about four to six
months in tissue culture and they call
it initiation and so what it does is it
removes all of those fungi bacterias and
viruses by the plant growing faster and
faster and faster so now you've got your
clone you're cutting it up here you've
got your viruses and fungi and bacteria
that are trying to keep up and
eventually you can get them out of that
plant completely and which is what Wade
began this discussion with in regards to
hey you know you might have some sort of
thing going on with your mother stock
that now the triome production is down
well that thing would be fungi bacteria
and viruses impregnating your plant and
slowing down its ability to express
itself under the perfect conditions that
you're trying to to to to produce for it
so had Ian from segra been here today
he's with his uh daughter this morning
so Props to him for being a good dad but
I really wanted him to be here and he
would have been able to uh say what I
just said much more elegantly and maybe
even clearer but well not only that not
only that um you know my other company
that I have is bio agronomics group with
Rob Clark and Mojave and our genetics
were just cleaned up by SRA and so on
our bio agronomics site we have three
cultivars that were actually fully
biologic cleaned up and it took some
time and it's a quite a process but um
quite excited that we're getting ready
to put out a press release uh regarding
uh our our cultivar so uh look for that
in the coming dude amazing yeah I know
all about it I just didn't want to say
anything but amazing that you got to say
it and I can't wait for you to release
the uh the uh the public release that'll
be awesome to hear about that's really
cool that you're involved with bio
agronomics with Mojave and Rob Clark uh
that's a pretty strong Trio of people
right
there very very cool that's a that's a
great group right there you are you guys
um are you guys working with any older
older stuff that you can talk about is
there anything that's exciting that you
wanna tell us about uh you know we're
just in the midst of Licensing you know
we're doing what uh old Driscoll does
here in the states which licens uh
blackberries and raspberries so we're
doing that with
uh the older cultivars and genetics that
robs has collected over the decades as
well as Mojave since he's you know his
master botanist so uh we have a few
things that are in the pipes but you
know the contracts and all that we're
still waiting for so as those come
forward we'll be more more than happy to
to make those aware but and you know
contracts but uh yes there's a lot of
interest as well as uh especially toward
the old world genetics because they're
just so missing on top of that you know
we were subjective to such as Dave's
palette Dave liked the sweeter type of
palette so now we'll have access to the
full range of the older pallet for new
cultivars to be developed and made from
so uh that's what I'm most excited about
is to to you know bring back the old so
that we can pull out some of those
things that we miss because we've all
been subjective to the pallets of the
actual botanists who have made these PL
and there may be some that I like that
you not like or there may be some
nuances that we're going to find but um
yeah it's gonna be an exciting next
couple of years for sure that's awesome
that's awesome at the same time I just
uh took cuts and and reup a bunch of
older stuff um that I've kept for around
21 years to date and it's um it's been a
battle for to keep these things going
but um you know it's I'm in the same
boat I've had my stuff for 15 18 years
20 years the Northern Light number five
like the I call medic Kush is more like
a pure kush if you look at the land
races and the strains that were around
back in the days and just the eror and
the time that I was in place of just
genetics I got myself on some of those
those rare ones those first ogs those
first Hindu kushes and Bubba kushes and
the lemon ties I'm well that's all we
ran that's all my friends said we laugh
about said that's all we used to run
back in those days and right was all the
seeds we were popping and I'm hearing
stories about this and we're like we're
laughing I said that's the one I called
an M4 cuz it was a it was the fourth cut
of the M of this and it came out some
name over there and it's it's pretty
cool to start seeing how people are
looking at those old genetics and
realizing that that's where the fire
started and that's what they need in
order to kind of there's a lot of a lot
of stuff out there it tastes really good
but it just doesn't get you there you
know it's like it's like it's nice but
it's like doesn't give me that punch
though I'm still that's the problem
we're all going in different
places
yeah there's a lot of theirs could be
the beauty beauty of it all though too
hidden beauty of course every you know I
I kind of appreciate the older varieties
that that are um that are more floral
and more ecuatorial um they they have um
a certain Entourage effect to them that
I I don't get from a lot of uh the newer
stuff that I that I some like that
peanut butter breath that came to me one
time it was just like oh I have to have
it please and
someone else had this wedding crash I'm
like can you can I get that cut from you
like by any chance because it's just so
tasty I like that I mean it's the
variety is out there with the Breeders
and the people just popping and growing
for 2021 it's just like a whole new
beginning a whole new whole new
generation of of Growers and seeds and
varietals coming out there it's it's
pretty cool it's it's really nice to see
that 20201 is going to be a growing year
for everybody and looking forward to all
these new strains but let's try and find
those genetic that they're com from
because some of these names I hear I'm
like what is that I'm on seedfinder it
doesn't exist like like give me tell me
what these strains are where are they
coming from like what are their parents
right and and it's it's like they just
you can't call this you got to call
something else and then now you don't
know what it is so
well sorry go ahead Kelly I was just
saying I think that it's more important
than ever like I know I had said this
one time before on hash church is to pop
those 2021 because of all the intention
that went into the 2020 you know
breeding time you know we're all in this
crazy lockdown there's so much energy
going on we're all dealing with really
heightened emotions or heartstrings and
all of this energy has been going into
our Gardens and now we have this great
opportunity to pop these 21 you know
seeds that see what kind of answers that
the plant can give us as a as a
collective Consciousness so super
exciting to me and I love it that you
know John you're you're really you know
bringing up the energy of popping those
seeds so I'm encouraging everybody share
your seeds pop them let's get them out
there let's let's let's really let
cannabis you know do what she's meant to
do which is really heal heal the planet
well that's why I was asking Mark about
seeds earlier but you know it's
interesting um I got selected to be a
judge for the emerald cup uh and it's
happening in the spring this year
unfortunately it's not a gathering but
we're going to be doing the um you know
the the uh sampling and judging part uh
this year they're actually going to be
be doing it by tarpine profile they're
not doing it by names so it's GNA be
very interesting to see how because we
had I've always had the issue of names
or suggestions or tars Etc so now we're
going to be issued them by tpine profile
so that's going to be very interesting
uh SC Labs is actually doing all the
testing again and uh we're they're still
receiving currently for the next couple
of weeks uh so you can go to the emerald
cup uh uh online and if you are domestic
uh they're also having a traditional
Market cup as well so it's not just a
legal Market cup we're having a
traditional Market uh cup so those that
are in the uh underground markets can
actually try to compete against uh those
that are in the legal market and it's
going to be very inter to see how
everything's broken out but uh I think
we're going to be judging in March
officially or the this ceremony is going
to be but uh shout out to Emerald cup
and Tim Blake and the crew for still
keeping it going after covid and we
weren't able to meet this past December
because otherwise I would have seen
dragonfly and y'all beautiful smiling
faces and hugged y'all and smoked out
but unfortunately it's just not that way
and not GNA be that way hopefully next
year big up to Hazel Bagwell Hazel we
love you yeah all the work that
everybody's doing out there hey we want
to let you guys know that um wait hang
on wait wait just want to say something
sorry oh yeah I want to jump in for a
second just say it's actually in my mind
pretty good news that the judging is
happening in the spring because the the
the things you're sampling have actually
had a chance to cure
properly I have talked to Tim Blake
about that the second or third time that
he did the emerald cup and he said look
man I own that weekend in December I
can't change it just because the will be
better but much respect and enjoy the uh
judging
process I I didn't know you wanted to
say something go ahead no I got one
other thing I wanted to say we were
talking about all the beautiful old
cultivars that are coming to hand maybe
uh at Johan thank you for doing that
work um and others everybody uh I want
to add in not just tpes like everybody's
talking about all the different
experiences that primarily type one
cannabis THC gives you and I'm really a
big fan as you probably know of type two
cannabis where you've got THC and CBD
and other conoids together and I think
that's part of the minor conoids and CBD
in relation to THC is where I think the
Feelgood part of cannabis usage comes in
type one high THC is really about
psychoactivity and and it's can get
literally psychedelic we were talking
about mushrooms last week and I was
thinking about people whose first
experience with cannabis was a really
fat edible that some friend gave them
that because they said they wanted to
try cannabis so they got a 150 milligram
dose of THC the very first time they
ever tried it and got obliterated I mean
that I've had that experience
myself and it's um anyway yeah cannabis
can be not just about getting high but
it can also be about feeling good and I
think that's one of the things that I'm
personally very excited about because it
works in my life makes me feel good
makes me feel happy I like being happy
people like oh you're a stone I'm like
so I like being happy so I I use
cannabis Because I'm Happy it makes me
happy and I'm addicted to being happy
I'm addicted to feeling good and
cannabis makes me feel good so what's
wrong with that like nothing wrong with
feeling good that's the best thing it's
like we feel good and if that makes you
feel good then that's fantastic and and
and someone's mentioned something on my
Facebook page oh you're just a junkie
and I mean people like like s Mission
some people are just like ragging on the
sky like I use cannabis because it makes
me feel good and that is the best part
about being who we what we do we use it
because it makes us feel good it it it
inspires our mind it makes us do better
things for ourselves or for others I
mean most people smoke a joint want to
help people oh hey can I help you can I
do do something for you like look at
this cannabis community and uh the I
think that the walls are down things are
changing people are growing and enough
of what's happening and and let's goow
forward for 2021 that's that's the whole
idea there are some major obstacles for
Californians this year with the fire
development and the widening of Roads
there's a lot of people in California
that are feeling like their whole entire
growing season is under threat with new
law their whole Farm not their season
their whole Farm is under threat for
them to be able to receive a new license
so if they don't widen the roads to
where there's a truck turnaround that
every fire truck can make a turnaround
that they're not going to allow any
licensing of any type of businesses up
those roads so a tremendous amount of
California licensed Farms are under
threat right now um and a lot of uh the
farms and a lot of people who are very
politically involved feel like it's a
definite attack against the small
cannabis farmer rather than just a good
idea for wildf virus in in California
there's lots of other ways that um you
know things could happen other than the
farmers are responsible for widening the
roads or basically put everybody out of
business shout out to Spring Creek Farm
for you know bringing that to our Pure
certified uh Attention our group and
stuff yeah and happening in Maine as
well uh Maine is is starting to to
squeeze down on the caregiver Market um
and it's it's getting it's getting
pretty dicey um so if if any activists
out there or anyone that is involved in
the community um please comment please
talk about it please be vocal um it'll
it'll really help us all yeah I mean we
got to keep Compassionate Care the focus
of the legalization and everything and
compassionate car is what was gave us
the the the ability
it gave us this Evolution so to turn our
back on Compassionate Care for the sake
of corporate business and the sake of
profits it's horrible and when Johnny
says oh I'm addicted to feeling good and
that's why I smoke cannabis we're
addicted to to to helping the Earth
while we create cannabis to feel good so
we're creating all these systems to say
hey the Earth is also ailing and so I'm
not going to take a a a a a compound or
or a plant like cannabis grow it
degenerativa human Humanity so like I
just want to encourage people to
recognize that all of the actions that
you do are part of the health and
well-being that we're going you know
that we're moving towards and uh we're
working really really hard on on um
making our medicine available um in
Canada and creating a new website for
Compassionate Care to make it available
to patients for medical patients in
Canada so this is going to be a really
big new step for us and and uh we're
really excited about it and it's not
finished yet so we can't share exact
details on it but uh I think it's for
the betterment of all people on Earth
and I hope it's all going to be great
for uh Canadians and also it's called
plant medicine I just want to remind
everybody it's plant medicine so all of
those plants out there are speaking to
us as humans we have this long
incredible in-depth history with with
these plant
medicines I want to jump in about this
thing you mentioned happening in
California and it sounds like in Maine
as well uh the specifics of it is the
board of Forestry uh is considering the
new updating of the fire
regulations and where it applies to
where it affects cannabis Farmers it
also affects everyone who lives in rural
areas in California because the way it's
going to play out is if you want a
permit to do anything like repair the
deck on your house or build a house or
uh have a cannabis commercial activity
on your property you have to have a road
that allows a firr to come in and a car
to come out at the same time which is 20
feet wide plus a couple of feet wide on
each side and every so often you have to
have turnouts and it's it's basically
appropriate if you wanted to put a
Walmart or a gas station or a shopping
center on your farm you would need a
road like that but to require that for
any kind of permit especially a cannabis
permit means a lot of the Heritage farms
in California are being faced with the
environmental impacts of putting in a
commercial scale road to their Farm in
order to get a permit to get have
cannabis license and really the whole
idea of legislation or legalization as
it's called it's really
commercialization but the whole idea of
legalization was to give Heritage free
market Farmers a chance a way to come
into compliance with the law this this
effort through the board of Forestry is
a thinly disguised effort to shut that
effort down and perpetuate in my opinion
prohibition and the whole War on Drugs
thing
one last little remnant of
the only a few more days left president
if you will in the United States
pardon people have to understand that
most once you get into Northern
California once you get off the main
roads it's all dirt roads you get up
into Sonoma you get into medino you get
into Humbolt you know that's the reality
I mean one Farm I went to was literally
45 minutes off the County Road okay so
it is uh honorous and um very
frustrating because I was a previously
Legacy Traditional Market grower up in
mesino myself so we had a farm and we
had legal numbers Etc and then the next
year they changed it from 99 plants to
25 you know so it's unfortunately been a
frustration because then we lost our
farm because we couldn't afford to keep
it open because the numbers just didn't
make sense in the end for what we were
trying to do whereas 99 plants it made
it okay to do but uh very challenging
given the terroir and what we were
dealing with so um it's definitely a
frustration and so this is um a a direct
threat to the traditional Market uh and
some people that I know in the
traditional Market because I know
somebody who purchased our farm in
mesino county and now they're a legal
Market but these types of restrictions
will run them out of business because
how far off they are in the road and the
cause will get it to get there etc etc
it's illogical and on top of that um
yeah it's just a frustration all in all
so I'm sorry to hear that that's also
happening in Maine and other states but
uh this is where push back needs to
happen we are having uh challenges so
this is why you need to show up at your
waterboard meetings your forestry
meetings uh people say oh I don't want
to get involved in politics well all
this is politics around you affecting
everything from your roads to your
sewage to your access and your access
point so we really have to uh you know
always think you know globally but act
locally completely so you know plug in
um be at the table otherwise you're on
the menu and nobody wants to be on the
menu so show up and be at the table you
know it's a pain in the ass that's the
the the price of Liberty unfortunately
but if you want to continue you know
what we did in the past sitting back and
hiding in our shelters growing our
cannabis quietly no longer works for us
we have to actually plug in and speak up
on top of that we have to figure out a
way in California to uh raise up the
traditional market we've been able to do
it with the over regulated market but we
need to figure out how to make the
traditional Market safer for consumers
because consumers have chosen that but
we know the unscrupulous cannabis that
does not make the Great
in the legal Market goes to the
traditional market so uh I'm always
fascinated from traditional marketi ists
on the frustrations that they that I
hear from them which is you know the
over uh uh salification of their plants
uh that they get and the the Cannabis is
uh no longer the craft quality they used
to get prior it's it's kind of a
commercial quality that people are
utilizing to make money so we've got
this fortunate continuation of the
prohibition that has led to back in the
day remember we used to import all that
stuff from
Canada in those bags Etc that extra wet
weed that we would get back in the day I
remember that yeah you
knowers beers beers beers you you know
yeah so I mean we we all we let me just
defend Canada for half a
second because it didn't start like that
but I will say
this I met quite a few buyers over the
years that would tumble the
flowers before they brought it down to
sell it to their American Brethren they
would tumble the flowers and I'm talking
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
pounds they're pulling like so much
resin off that plant and then the poor
Canadian Growers were getting like
burned for like oh you guys are growing
the swag up there we call it no trikes
it's like yeah well you should talk to
your brother who's selling it to you
because that's not cool
[ __ ] Al go ahead also an issue of
hydroponic growing taking off you know
and the whole Warehouse grown hydroponic
blast blast off mode that happened in
British Columbia and then of course mies
that with the the syndicates that bring
things back and forth then you just have
those remnants around still today and
when we talk about commercial weed not
being very good well we can talk about
that in the same light as beaster that's
exactly what it was it was really sort
of the first time that North America had
seen such volume of that salted
commercial weed and that was definitely
coming from you know a particular uh
variety of of people up here in Canada
but even that even that didn't start
like that you know cuz I remember how
that started and and breeder Steve was
really one of the people who he gave
that cut to key people and uh they were
just like oh wow like we can do this
instead of this other very dangerous
thing and I remember back in the day
like when those guys first started doing
it it was actually it was grapefruit and
it was they it was unbelievable that
people that never grew before were
growing like this beautiful grapefruit
flow the problem was within about two to
3 years they were just like we get the
same money we don't even have to dry it
we don't even have to finish it it's
like five weeks whatever and it sort of
turned into this sort of thing where it
was like that was a big part of the
beers at uh name as as well 100% but I
remember when it first started I was
blown away at the Quality that they were
able to produce early very early on it
surprised me most people go in the other
Direction the cies of of British
Columbia are one of the the homelands of
cannabis in all of Canada right I mean
there's there's one of them there's
Vancouver and there's the islands and
there you know there's certain areas but
is a big one I I'll be honest because I
I I first went to the Cy almost 30 years
ago and they were growing and digging
holes on the mountain and mixing soils
and had a deep knowledge of Organics and
sustainability and I'm telling you like
some of the flower that I saw there in
particular one that I would love to find
if anyone ever knew the the the
background of this lineage it was called
the A1 magenta and it was one of the
most beautiful cutney grown flowers it
turned ever so purple but very very
light purple not that purple that you
look at and go that's probably not going
to be very strong or tasty but this
really nice light light almost like a
light pink would come over this plant
and it was just such a
beautiful beautiful high I would compare
it high wise to um ka's
coffee oh yeah that sort of very
uplifting just like this is beautiful
stuff and that was that was probably in
1990 or 91 that I went there and dug
holes and planted those plants and and
helped my my friends from the Cy grow
one of their I me we first came to we
first came to the cies in '98 and our
mind our brain exploded we we came from
Oregon and Northern California and it
was so militant and so hardcore and
harsh and had this like super Edge like
I'm from there like I I know the edge
it's it's fine it's a beautiful thing
you know but when you come up to to the
C oh my God especially back then this
place is serious and then we were
smoking weed like in town in a store in
1998 smoking hash oil off of coold
you
know dude we were smoking hash oil in 98
and then um you know those guys who do
you think I was talking about exactly
and uh you know and these families are
are you know what I love about this
region and is a kind of a potent for
this time of politics and everything is
the conscientious objectors that live in
this area it's important for people to
know the term conscientious objector and
they were the ones that came from you
know decided that they didn't want to go
to the Vietnam War and a tremendous
amount of them came up to the cies to
grow ganja and they were the ones when
we first came here in 98 it was all the
the 50y olds you know now our age people
that were giving us all these seeds that
they had been breeding for 15 and 20
years and they just sort of set us out
like here you go kids good luck here's
some good pointers and you know go for
it so I'm going back 10 years to 88 when
I was sitting on the back of the steps
of a police station in car me smoking a
joint hanging out with the guys that
were growing all through there and
that's where that's where my best
friend's dad lived and that's where they
were growing that's where some of the
seeds that I started getting back in
those days ' 89 991 so we have seen we
have a lot of oh yeah common Commons
right there just because you guys are
like 10 years later but we know the same
type of that whole thing going all the
way up into Ashcraft under Vernon yeah
um a lot of fire came out of there in
those days a lot of genetics back then
created a lot of the companies out there
today that people don't know there's a
lot of Hardcore lges back in those days
and it was the buyer again you know I
you know Marcus just mentioned it it was
the buyers that were you know sifting
out flour whatever and it was also the
buyers that started to tell us way back
in the day that they didn't want it to
smell that they wanted it to look some
certain way that they didn't want potent
and you know not potency as far as you
know potency of feeling but you know the
tpin so it was just like remember these
t a real family vibe that turned into
sort of like a commercial buyer thing
and that's what really made those
awesome amazing old school varietals up
here in Canada turn into the beers and
and and that's how we got that that um
reputation later on before the beaster
started was when we got here and we got
98 so by 99 we start we got given a soil
recipe by a local gondra grower here who
had just come from Victoria and lived
over and and worked in a a food
production where uh greenhouse on the on
the island and he came back and and the
the soil recipe was very similar to The
Living soil no till recipes of today
which was pyroclastic clay um you know
three third of compost third Pete Moss
was big here you know there was no cocoa
at that time you know the oyster shells
the glacial Rock Dust the um there was
key components the the clay that but
anyway it was very similar almost almost
identical it sounds like what we were
mixing in like 90 and 91 those guys have
known for so long we've been making
these soils you know since that since
then and and it's cool to everyone's oh
theyve changed so much well I think the
way they've changed is we add more
actual raw materials and Haze and living
cover crop like that part's changed like
we didn't put living seeds and and
living things on so it's definitely
hybridized nowadays but the base soil of
has is damn you're exactly the same and
I think those originally those soil
recipes came from Cornell University I
mean those those old organic so a lot of
them you know Cornell University is is a
is a Homeland for that but I just also
like we were doing soils we were you
know down in Oregon and we were just
digging holes and trying to put as much
stuff as we possibly could put in the
holes make the holes as big as you
possibly could because that's what we
thought was the right thing to do so in
the early 90s we were growing hug hug
Among Us plants in sort of Virgin soil
that was really awesome and amazing too
so learning about soil recipes off of
that and like oh wow I guess that's what
we were doing when we were mixing them
in these big holes and and uh you know
even putting like some of the dead
animals in the bottom of the hole oh you
find a dead frog on the road put him in
the bottom of the hole or dead snake or
something put him in the bottom of a
hole the rule of thumb as we were
growing up was to like she said put you
know a fish or some kind of actual
living dead animal in in the hole and
then to have fish like when I was in
high school so this is like 80s or
whatever it was uh you know my I have
close friends that were rotting fish in
water
and and it was the the the the the goal
was to make it the most disgusting
smelling liquid you could possibly make
because that's how you make stinky weed
yeah so like you know you get the the
Purple Kush was very common back in the
late 80s in southern Oregon it was
probably the most potent good purple
kush that you could ever get and I just
remember absolutely amazing flavors on
those on those herbs back then in seller
Oregon incredible just just to mention
how prolific and I'm sure it's as
prolific now but how prolific it was
just even in the early early 90s growing
cannabis and the Cy while we were out
there digging these holes and planting
these plants you know it's it's the
cutney a lot of it is around cotney Lake
and it's like this one road and so it's
a very kind of In-N-Out sort of thing
and so they would set up roadblocks and
they would actually be looking for
gardening equipment shovels pots uh mud
like and the first time I ever went
through one I just couldn't believe it I
was like are you kidding me that the
police are doing roadblocks just to see
if you guys have like shovels and pots
and stuff and then they just like write
your license plate down he's like oh
yeah man it's like all everyone here
it's just like and they just they're
going for it they're like ah just throw
a tarp over that they won't be able to
see it it's like well what if they ask
to lift the tarp oh whatever man we'll
figure it out I just loved the attitude
back then it was uh
Wild Wild West we're smoking weed in
town you know but then now all of a
sudden there's a roadblock on the way
home you're it's like what the what are
we
missing we always used to have you know
some wildcrafted stuff in the car and
just say that we were wildcrafting all
the time you know that was just always
the thing always make sure you've got
some kind of nettle or something in the
car that would say that you out
wildcrafting for your Gardens and most
most people didn't get in trouble back
then and we know at least a good amount
of of people that when when they did get
in trouble there you know they could
have in the past retrieved the goods
taken from them out of the dumpster out
of the back of the cop shop this is true
story I've heard the same thing to be
honest but it's that's the thing it's
not like they were arresting tons of
people but they would go and take your
plants and for and for the Cy that was
like pretty devastating to have your
crop taken uh you know like to me like
all my friends in the cies were not
driving Ferraris uh and living in
mansions they all had like nice little
homesteads and they were all like
working really hard to get this crop out
so that they could kind of have this
money to invest into everything they
needed for the next year they could
travel in the winter and their life
through cultures well and also you know
like our our patch was a seven and a
half hour hike that was like you know a
really big hike so we'd have to leave
you know at dark and if we wanted to get
home you know having you know some kind
of a farm home life with the animals and
stuff at home we'd have to leave at dark
and then um you know come back at
dark super intense and really amazing
Kelly did you guys ever look at Korean
far natural farming early on I it was
one of my first foray into just getting
out of salts and looking deeper into the
land um you guys yeah it was just really
inspiring because at the time there was
just nothing that I could read at all
there just was nothing um but then there
this and there was books and I so I
really honed in on that I was I'm
curious to see if you guys maybe did
some of course of course yeah it's a
it's a great question so when we first
came um when we first started growing uh
cannabis we learned about what was
called weed teas so you know you put a
garbage can in your garden in your
vegetable garden and you take all of
your weeds and you throw all of your
weeds into basically is a liquid
composter so you're throwing them into
water and you're liquid composting your
plants well then we started doing
research on like all of the different
cultures that do liquid composting so
the Japanese did Li liquid composting
all of the Europeans did liquid
composting we got a lot of um those weed
te recipes even from uh some of the
Quakers that live in in our community in
this area so they would even say Hey you
know if you do nettle and you do some
chickweed so we really started out our
growing doing sort of this liquid herbal
uh decoction mixed with raw materials
going mix in with no Bashi like so
basically what she's saying is in 99 we
got here and we were following natural
farming Concepts without knowing the
word natural yeah we had already been
doing liquid liquid composting and using
herbal uh decoctions and a lot of the
tea recipes that we do today came from
that not necessarily from k&amp;f and then
later we we went to Hawaii in 2008 in
2008 and do Master Cho was doing a h a
workshop the very first workshop on the
big island on the big island in Hawaii
at that time and he was talking about oh
all these k&amp;f ideas and we were like
whoa that's sort of what we're already
doing that's really amazing and and then
we sort of find United some of our
skills with the lab adding lab to it so
we took some some little treasures and
Little Gems from a lot of the old world
farming practices and we took some of
those gems from k&amp;f as well you know
we're not fully entrenched in k&amp;f
because we really want to do what's
easiest for us what works on our farm
what works for what we have growing what
type of biomass that we have growing and
we're really specific on what we bring
in we really don't bring in any anything
we bring in a C90 which is a 90 Trace
mineral onto our farm other than that
we're 100% closed loop so a lot of the
k&amp;f recipes asked to bring in things
that just wasn't conducive for us as all
so we just continued on with a lot of
the old school recipes that we had been
doing since the beginning of our growing
practices and then again fin nighted it
with knf in 2008 so like a a hybrid if
you will of all these different
ideologies and and you really kind
borrowed from the things that you felt
were important yeah great yeah because
we we walked out seven and a half hours
so we really couldn't carry anything
with us at all so we had to really look
at what type of herbs were out there
that were good for different types of
nutrients and different types of
minerals so with all of my herbology
background I know what has high
magnesium what has high Cobalt what has
you know high calcium so we just started
you know doing tee ferments with those
type of herbs um in treating plants for
whatever malades and nutrients that they
needed at the time I I would just add I
would just add one more thing really
quick which
is so all through the 90s we're studying
Midwifery right we're studying plant
tees and naturopathic medicine for women
right we've already said this plenty of
times and locally but then we move up to
you know this far away place we're not
citizens we have to survive out in the
mountains we have to be underground no
one can know we live here you know so we
chose to mean take that as like oh okay
we're not going to the grow store so now
we're we're we're living on the land
we're going to be self-sufficient
homesteaders we moved to one of the most
you know powerful places probably in all
of British Columbia to do that to be
real and we have this incredible root so
now we're like okay we're going to grow
gardens in this herbology Midwifery
style oh we're gonna do stuff like
biodynamics I mean good God since you
know forever you know
uh uh Rudolph Steiner has M millions of
pages on on spiritual sacred cultivation
our library in our community is filled
with books of biodynamics homesteading
you know uh stuff from Europe stuff from
Asia and so we're we're we're we're
engulfed in this there's no internet
there's no way of communication there's
so that that's part of our inoculation
let's say so then we get into this you
know growing the Hillside and then we
and then we find this Revelation you
know of Korean natural farming you know
and then we put all the parts together
and then we find oh hu hugle culture you
know and and so one of our biggest
things is Unleash Your Dogma because
when you become a k&amp;f person you think
that you are in the dogma of life like
Korean national farming has to be this
way or it's not actually crean natural
farming you know or or maybe even
biodynamics you know you can't be a
demer certified Farm unless you use
biodynamic preps you know I mean which
is then you can do all sorts of other
things that don't make any sense so I
think what Josh means by unleashing your
Dogma is just do what works for your
farm you know accept other people's
means and ways if there's you know
natural processes that you're using it's
awesome we say that you need closed
loops with the demm certification well
we hear about new closed Loops every day
it's so awesome the incredible
creativity that people come up with to
create natural closed Loops by utilizing
all these different modalities of
ancient growing practices and now every
year all the time it's just constantly
validated give thanks we love family
question uh for dragonfly uh if if you
were going to summarize what you're
doing or people who are listening what
they could do to optimize their soil
health wouldn't you say that like really
what we're what we're trying to do is
capture the biology that's already
happening on your soil in your land
around you uh and taking advantage of
the inputs that are already there and
just recognizing them for what they are
and building again not so much things
like worm castings or um any specific
tees but it's more about the biology the
microbiology the micro biome if you will
of fungus and bacteria and viruses all
of the various things that are happening
that's really what we're trying to
enhance if you will with closed loop
systems would and as my teacher on this
kind of thing I'd love to hear your
thoughts
on one of the number one reasons to do
Clos Loop was if it's not coming from
your farm where is it coming from how
did it get there and and what what was
it made from you know so that that was a
thing that said if and maybe you live on
a farm that doesn't have everything that
you need on it you know so there's might
maybe reasons that's why you want to
grow different plants and also for the
success of the farmer so just to add
real quickly when you bring on things we
were noticing some omry listed things
were were not uh were failing tests for
Farmers so we really wanted the ultimate
success for farmers go ahead and um yeah
just the idea that it puts you in a more
self-reliant more powerful place like I
again we have to look at to where we are
in life right now are we reliant on the
system to be healthy are we reliant on
the system to create health and
well-being in our soil well we think
it's more powerful not to well and I
think if you we think it's more powerful
to get your power from nature which has
survived mass extinction in the past you
know so we're trying to Ally with that
that survives you know and and
microbiology is what survives science is
is a is a Folly in in the in the in the
in the evolution of nature you know so
here it's very helpful with the
evolution of nature but we're always
proving something different with science
it's an Ever Changing you know end line
you know where is the endline and
science is always changing the end line
but nature never really seems to change
her endline her goal number one goal is
to make soil so if we want to mimic
nature and what her closed Loops are
then all of our number one goal is to
make soil so if we want to you know
continue on the path of what Nature has
shown Us in her health and well-being
and being able to overcome such
incredible amounts of opposition with
what she's been thrown at uh by humanity
and toxicity then we can recognize that
nature is able to uh detoxify almost
every
so why not utilize her as as the main
Mentor basically and enhance the the the
ability of your plant to evolve you know
I mean we're we're trying to give it
more microbiology so that it can enhance
its own medicine so we feel like that's
done through local uh raw
materials I came to the practices you
guys recommend uh through trying to make
the cleanest possible version of
cannabis so that we could make medicine
uh and that was really what it was all
about for me and yeah I remember hearing
about I guess somebody was at the that
same event on the big island when and a
friend came back talking to me about k&amp;f
when I was still working indoors uh and
uh uh it was an exciting concept but I
couldn't see how to make that any of
that work inside a warehouse in San
Francisco so not to be confused with
KFC for sure had one of those just down
the street from the warehouse also we we
there it's also important to note that
natural farming is not just from Korea
so like there's a whole natural farming
modality from Japan you know and all of
the Asian countries and again all of the
Asian countries um but uh Em which is
effective
microorganisms has been um you know has
lactic acid bacteria untreated uh or U
uh
purple H nonsulfur bacteria pnsb and
yeast so em is the yeast the purple
non-sulfur bacteria and lactic acid
bacteria and you can do a million things
that's where you learn how to make Bashi
so you know Bashi is locking in lactic
acid bacteria and yeast and those most
vigorous fermenting microbes and locking
it into brand right but most of the
okashi originally that people would
cheap out and the brand would not be
organic because they'd be like oh the
microorganisms are going to change over
the toxicity of the plant no and then
also it would be like oh well we're
gonna we're gonna activate em or we're
gonna activate bokashi with
nonorganic molasses and then you're just
like well that's a horrible thing right
there because you know sugar in itself
when produced you know is is a terrible
thing so you have to be careful um so
the you know anyway there's incredible
manuals of of farming modalities from
the Philippines from India from Thailand
from Myanmar Pakistan all using just em
technology um so it's Dr Chu oiga from
uh Japan has an incredible manuals on
there and um so but you know there's
jadam the newer manuals you know using a
lot of leaf molds and things I think
it's just use what you can to enhance
your Zone and try not to get caught up
in things that you don't know about and
a lot of these natural farming
techniques are really to speed up what
nature is already doing at a really slow
rate which is making a a a soil it's
creating a wonderful microbiology medium
and with all of these different
modalities it's speeding up the process
so that we can farm and we can get those
nutrients faster it's sort of part of
farming that you know you want to be
added a lot of mulch rather than waiting
for the mulch to come by the leaves
falling so you know you're speeding up
the process of of getting rich soil and
and and having healthier plants and hey
Mark scalone how you doing you know
maybe uh you I don't know if you could
talk about Endo fidic fungi and bacteria
maybe you can but you know part of
living soils and all this crazy Natural
farming and stuff is to create a healthy
bi Liv PL to to supposedly extractor to
use in full but I just wonder what
you're up to Mark and and what's
happening with you well hey everybody uh
I I was out in the gallery last week
listening I was I was uh what was I
doing was I cleaning the
house I uh but I listen last week it was
a good episode and uh yeah for some
reason I I didn't get the link but I got
it this week so hi everybody uh great to
see everybody um yeah you know part of
the essential role that biology plays in
the soil is because um biology has
figured out how to fix nitrogen from the
air and and nitrogen is this um
wonderfully abundant uh gas that's in
the oxygen and the air or not in the
oxygen it's in the air we breathe it's
in the atmosphere I think 79% is
nitrogen right and it's pretty inert it
it's pretty what we call inert it's
chemically inert there are things that
react with nitrogen but for the most
part bacteria have figured out how to
fix nitrogen and the reason why that's
important and they don't spend a lot of
energy doing it that's that's the other
important thing so man's figured out how
to fix nitrogen but it costs a lot of
petrochemical derived energy to do it
and that's something called the the
habber process which was basically how
to turn nitrogen into ammonia which
created liquid fertilizers that began
the whole you know use of chemicals to
fortify soil I think Josh and Kelly will
agree that bacteria have have long since
figured this out because they've been
playing chemistry in Mother Nature's lab
here for billions of
years but you know France Haber did I
mean it was it was important at the
beginning of the Industrial Revolution
when they figured out how to fix
nitrogen because it really it it started
the whole chemical industry mostly again
for making liquid fertilizers because
you know they just hadn't figured out um
they hadn't figured out regenerative
farming at the time they actually did
but they didn't know it right and you
know was funny uh Josh the the point you
made about making stinky fish broth and
that's how you can grow stinky weed you
know for us kids who are out on Grateful
Dead tour during the 80s you know for a
lot of us you know Grateful Dead tour
was where we went out and we bought we
got our stinky weed and yeah I remember
talking to some Growers who were like
man we take everything from the apple
orchard and we take everything from our
garden and we just we make this compost
of just just just the richest darkest
soil you could possibly imagine and in
that you know they created you know
these
really aromatic varieties of of of weed
that
would fill Arenas on East Coast Dead
tours with the smoke of noral right and
so yeah I would also say Southern Oregon
just just saying
you Garcia well you know and and the and
the dead were connected to Oregon
because as you know like ramrod and
Sparky and most of the crew they were
all from Oregon and key they were all
from Oregon so the the trip Carn
Garcia that that that's right so the
Grateful Dead scene down in the bay and
and Oregon was was was was connected and
um yeah I mean you guys are connected
with mountain girl and you know Mountain
girl wrote one of the first uh seminal
textbooks on on regenerative growing and
is is that is that right can I say that
isn't that right it's definitely right
1976 the Primo plant and it's specific
to cannabis regenerative cannabis that
book specific to regenerative growing
like there wasn't a oh yeah no her her
father is a botanist she came from
growing she loves weed she's super
inquisitive she's an awesome person what
a cool time in Grateful Dead history you
know because that's right when when when
Trixie and Annabelle were were were
young kids and and Jerry was they were
living in Stinson Beach and Jerry was
in they you know she they had gone and
left and gone up to Oregon at that time
because there was so many they had got
you know that there was like issues in
California they were flee they like kind
of like left the California scene and
and lived on the coast over in Port
Orford and lived over in the beach so a
that was a lot of that was written while
they were you know had kind of left they
said left the scene or whatever and went
up to Oregon and things so but it's all
it still just a wonderful time of of uh
all kind of things going on in the scene
and and you know me being a young kid
from from the from the East Coast I mean
again a lot of us it was uh uh for Mo
many years easier to get things like
cocaine from New York City you know you
could just drive over George Washington
Bridge and go get a little sack of
cocaine go back to your suburban party
in New York City and and the only weed
that you can get was this little manila
envelope which was Chuck full of seeds
and stems it was just the worst
thing in the world but on dead tour we
had stinky green Bud from the from the
West Coast I know I've said it a bunch
of times on hash church but hey that's
where the chem dog came it's pretty cool
because you know I was I was slinging
the kind bud I that's how I made my way
through university University of Oregon
thank you very much for the degree
everybody off the kind butt um little
did I know that that that that kind bud
was DJ shorts blueberry strains and that
was all coming from him and
old world genetics
old and and and and Marcus will tell you
that that easily transition from kind of
like the Grateful Dead scene over to
fish fish was certainly the people who
took the torch from the Grateful Dead
and carried it on because again you can
go on fish scene and you could get
really kind stinky nugs in the mid90s
right Mark and it wasn't beaster you
know when you guys were talking about
beaster before that's funny because I
remember people slinging beers on fish
lot and be like yeah yeah yeah we let
you know it looked good it just didn't
it didn't it wasn't it wasn't as good as
as as all the other [ __ ] and that's
right around the time that again chem
dog really started taking off Sour
Diesel started taking off the late to
mid 90s and then you know right around
that time I would say that you know
again is is is there again a a sort of
like a Next Generation that sort of took
really good weed and made sure that you
know it was just distributed to the
masses
or music or things that were were
cultural icons that brought people in
and were like holy [ __ ] did you smell
that weed that's not like the [ __ ] that
we get at home let's go buy some weed so
people would go to the shows stock up on
weed and go home it was a dangerous time
I would like to say because first of all
great weed stinks loud and you'd go to
these shows in the early to mid90s on
the East Coast the Midwest even on the
west coast to a degree but more so in
places like Montana and even Spokane but
like on the East Coast all these
different shows in New York cops would
literally sit in buildings around the
parking lots with walkie-talkies and
then literally just H have people get
busted on on the lot like it was a
dangerous game we were playing and yet
you couldn't not go and play the game it
the the beautiful thing was in the
parking lot if anyone was ever
identified as a narc there would be
probably 15 people walking around the
dude going NC n NC this guy's a n this
guy on on fish tour it was six up six
six up six up meant there were cops
heading your way they could be
undercover they could be uh uniformed
but if you heard that six up it was like
a wave traveling with them as they
walked down shake down everything would
roll right up man you just watch
everybody just pull their [ __ ] up and
start stepping yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
and serious H H how key do you think
those years you know the Grateful Dead
touring years and then like Mark like
the years that you were on fish tour and
like the mid90s in in in into this next
millennium how important do you think
that those years were in the
proliferation of really good herb out to
the masses of people right think it was
important right along with psychedelic
mushrooms and LSD gota add I used to
walk around fish lot uh late 90s with
overgrow flyers and hand them out to get
people stoked on going and learning
about growing I was that
just in passionate about the plant it
was just people thought it was crazy
like what are you doing why are you
printing these
things scoo actually sent me a flyer
from overgrow to hand out and I I was
like look I'm I'm gonna go to all these
shows and I I want to pass this out I
feel like we need to we need to share
this like people need to know there's
knowledge out there that you can learn I
would send Slinger with bubble bags on
the you know to the great went or to
like these huge fish and I'd be like
just take like a hundred kits you know
I'll give you a 100 and he'd be like
he'd be like all right bro all right and
just like young Slinger you know trying
to like with a hundred kits of bubble
bags and [ __ ] meeting the whole crew
we're going to seol for the for the new
year show and Marcel brought the fish
2000 pipe and there there were bubble
bags that that were sold at the parking
lots of fish shows is that what is that
what I'm hearing here oh yeah dude 100%
99 man like there's there's hash that's
been made from bubble bags sold at the
parking lot official I used to there's
hash that's been made there's hash
that's been made in the parking lot of
fish shows I Bartered personally bubble
hash for tickets
literally dude you could go to a fish
show with nothing but six-star bubble
and you have everything you do this the
TR Dr Mark I would say for sure back in
the day like when I was in West Virginia
all we would get is pressed Mexican
cocacola so when we heard about good
weed we heard the dead would come
through my ass would go up to Pittsburgh
and just roll through Shakedown Street
and I'd get grief they' be like sorry
[ __ ] you're bald I'm like no no
no I'm not an arc I'm not a cop I just
want some [ __ ] gassy [ __ ] weed and
once I got turned onto that weed and
then then we were back back when I
finally you didn't stay for the show you
turned around and went home right you
didn't no I never done to the shows no
no no only went for the drugs I wasn't
into the music I was a punk you know you
know I was I had you know I had my v i I
had my boots on and my braces you know I
was a sharp skin heads against racial
Prejudice so we beat up Nazis but you
know you still roll in bald they're like
you're a [ __ ] cop like no no I'm in
the military I'm in the National Guard
but I need some weed because I'm a
patient now but you can't really talk
about that because there's so much
[ __ ] music and people are like
shrooms shrooms weed bud bud bud so you
know you gotta it's it's so tricky back
then but when we got to California and
then of course we're here at the Dead
shows when I was with the Cannabis
Action Network they would let us set up
legally on Shakedown Street right and
then they would let us go inside and
gather signatures and that's how I met
bear and everybody else but even still
back then when I was with K and I was
bald behind the thing they'd be like you
sure you're not a cop like I'm on
Shakedown you there 30 people around me
yelling narc right now and people they
look around and people like yeah yeah
yeah oh yeah we would [ __ ] that that's
that's how Justice goes here he'd be
[ __ ] shun the [ __ ] off but look
seriously not been for at the dead lot
and and and going around and traveling
around I do not think we would see the
proliferation of cannabis and the high
quality of cannabis in the time that we
did because there was no understanding
that that quality was there and once I
had tried it from somebody who had a
dead lot when I was in [ __ ] West
Virginia I was like I got to go to a
[ __ ] dead show and get some [ __ ]
weed because that's where real weed is
because whatever I'm getting and selling
isn't real [ __ ]
weed that's just how you're a Baldhead
dread yes yes totally bald dread yes
that's what it called me yes so many
times I would go out onto dead tour with
with you know beautiful kind bud and
people didn't even know that it was weed
no joke way back in you know like the
early early 90s late 80s I'd have a nice
stack of weed and people would be like
that's not weed what are you trying to
sell me what is that be like no it's
it's kind bud this is really weed they
didn't even really know what it was or
yeah the first time that people had ever
seen Keef or just when you're just
separating so you know before there was
bubble you know there was Keef and
people were using Keef and at dead tour
you would get these little teeny tiny
gorgeous pressed blocks tiny little
pressed blocks of Kei that was so
exciting you know to to be able to smoke
that and feel that high I remember that
well I had I actually when I got busted
back in the late 90s with many pounds of
cannabis I Had a Little Rock of
beautiful ke that was just like clean ke
that was like rocked up and uh they
thought it was crack cocaine they tested
it until it was gone and then I couldn't
get charged for that particular batch
but it reminds me what you just said of
when I first started posting on overgrow
in 1999 bubble has and people would be
like that looks like Mr whippy Mouse
[ __ ] like there's no way that that's
hash like they just people didn't know
and when I put it in their pipes and it
would bubble and boil and melt into a
liquid they would just be like what the
[ __ ] is that like is that some like that
I don't think that was hash that that
guy smoked with us plus back then
because it was so unknown it used to and
maybe Sam could agree with me I don't
see people getting knocked out the way I
used to people used to fall like flies
when they smoked bubble for the first
time and I'm sure Sam has stories of of
his dry sift way before bubble was even
a glimmer uh in in the eye yeah but to
tell you the truth even cannabis back in
those days uh I mean I saw people smoke
original Haze in the early 70s and they
would turn white and pass out or throw
up so I mean it's just the relative if
you're used to smoking you know 10% and
all of a sudden you hit something that's
you know 50 60 70 80 uh yeah it it is
you you'll turn white you'll turn pale
your your heart I mean you know you've
seen it happen a million times well not
only that you also had the huge
proliferation because people weren't
just going to smoke this amazing weed
and hash just out of anything this is
when the Snodgrass and everything
started to appear I mean Johnny B is
showing his huge chalice over here I
mean this was a huge proliferation I
mean if it wasn't for the dead lot and
the turning on the fish scene I mean how
would the glass you know whole art thing
that is taken off that is a whole
underground art movement here in America
I mean it would have never taken hold I
mean snot grass was the one I mean guys
would always whip out and say this is a
snotty this pipe cost thousand two
$1,200 you're like holy [ __ ] [ __ ]
seriously you spend how much on a glass
pipe this is an original Snodgrass right
here actually this was gifted to me by a
friend of mine I've had this since 90
something mid90s I've had this um this
is that's very valuable this to me is
very valuable to me people have asked me
how much I'm like there is no price on
my soul no um we need to get Bob on here
let's get Bob on oh yeah
yeah Caroline Garcia and Caroline I'm
telling you the last she phoned me a
while ago and was like hey am I still
going to come on hash church I was like
is this I love this this is such a
beautiful she's like it's Josh and
Kelly's friend Caroline I'm like
Caroline Caroline Caroline I've never
been to a fish concert and when I was in
Mexico in
2017 and can it was Cancun I was in uh
just outside of Mexico and there was a
fish concert there and I was on the on
the suite at the front where there was
no one in front of me just the ocean
it's 8:00 a.m. I'm down there and I hear
this Johnny [ __ ]
B and the girl she she like are you
kidding me and I go out there and these
all these people from fish that I've
never met before and and I met them all
because of has church and they're all
like Johnny B Johnny V and it just felt
so amazing and at that time when where I
was I was in Mexico I mar mar orenda and
I actually picked up this pipe that was
blown at a fish concert by Slinger and
got his hat on here and stuff like that
and I brought it home because it was a
memory that had to come back to Canada
way I looked at it so it's just pretty
cool to show that pipe a little bit I
was going to comment on your hat the
Slinger hat caught me in the immed this
was made at at a Grateful Dead concert
this is uh from what I understand um
this is this is a sling this is a collab
this is because someone's torches were
stolen or something no yeah oh right
right right yeah let me think about that
we got to get SL we got to get Slinger
and some of the glass community on here
one day as well someone mentioned it in
the chat so this is this is some epic
piece that I I know a little about but
not too much but I know Dave knows a lot
about it so does uh Ro high integrity
and they told me some cool stuff about
it they're like this is a classic so I'm
about ready to smoke some bubble out of
this thing for the first time ever with
you guys I remember when Jason Lee
figured out that particular Weld and
showed Slinger and I remember when they
all started doing it it was during
overgrow days actually and they would do
um first they did the double bubbler
then they did the triple then they did
the quad then they did this the the five
and then they did the sex Tupper and I I
bought them all I had the sex Tupper I
ended up selling that
to a drum from Amsterdam ended up fixing
it one day because it got broken there
and he did a pretty good job fixing it
but instead of cleaning it he just
heated it up while it was all still
dirty and so it fumed the the gold clear
glass so it was almost like this
metallic black looked pretty cool I
think I think maybe like s or Gypsy
Nirvana or some one of those characters
ended up with that piece but uh I know
there's S Class blowers on this one
because this is a certain blower that's
D at the back there that marble looks
like Slinger that's a uranium marble I
have a few of those very same ones yeah
Slinger would have done that for sure
and as there's a piece that went in here
like a some kind of a tool that's I
guess maybe because now I just put a
little sword in there but uh yeah it's
definitely uh it chugs nicely Marcus
what year did you first what year did
you first smoke
homegrown here we
go geez the first year I smoked
homegrown with me it was 69 or
70 it would have been 87 for
me 90 for
me 19
87 wow how time flies I've told the
story quite a few times wow that hit
really nicely that was awesome 93 for me
80 early 80s for me because it was all
homegrown yeah and me was
all me was all Mexi and then in Arizona
and I didn't really get any awesome good
weed until I uh started smoking on
matusa [ __ ] in
1988 so
that was the that was the best homegrown
my parents are some friends with some of
the original grillers in southern Oregon
Original M we had giant big fat kind bud
colas in in by the late 70s by by the
mid late 70s and I have pictures of my
parent you know Family holding it and
stuff and it is definitely awesome I I'm
lucky I never went through the era of
not having good weed around ever like
wow how lucky is that and thing is
beyond Grateful Dead uh was the barter
Fair Lots B barter fairs so barter fairs
were a really big deal you know seeds
we'll just and and tascet in in
Washington was where you know the US and
Canada met up and the tanas barter fair
was really cool but you know hey family
we got to take off right now we're going
to go help some uh local cotney Growers
out we're going to go help trim out some
uh some black
do some black berry Kush by the doy do
by the gelato from the uh uh Jordan of
the islands seed bank and down at Twin
feathers farm and we're also working a
lot on uh getting getting something up
to all of Canada in the medical realm up
online so we'll be letting you all know
about that as soon as that starts
happening and uh again Marcus and
everybody you know you just you make my
week you make my day when I'm having
whatever I think about hash church and I
think of all of your shining faces and
the people that you all are and and I
just I just have so much love for all of
you and Marcus what you have put on all
of these years and and the incredible
honoring of the cannabis plant that just
continues to happen on this show is just
Second To None thank you so much and big
up Mark for the hash Church strain nice
work brother big up on you let we'll be
stoked if we get to put that in our yard
this year big up everyone everyone out
in the crowd every other podcast that's
ever happened every other person putting
Education First let's make this world a
better place the government's not here
to serve us we're here to serve us we
love you give us a call if you need
anything be healthy we're always
available to anybody that ever has any
questions or anything hit us up always
we just want to help out as much as we
possibly can we're Servants of this
plant just like so many of you all out
there watching resist the military
industrial complex I love
you nice I like it good words dropped
from the dragonfly Earth medicine Josh
and Kelly always Marcus I wanted to to
talk about bog for a second if that's
all right yes I would love for you I
wanted to talk about bog as well and
seeing as we talked about overgrow and
all those other those characters we
gotta talk about bog one of the
ogs yeah so for those of you guys out
there um that don't know bog was an
incredible breeder uh activist
grower family guy beautiful human being
uh gifted so many seeds probably more
seeds were gifted by him than he sold um
and we lost him this past year to uh
complications we don't know about but um
wanted to let everybody know that um
James Bean se's here now um and a bunch
of other people like me and Jean from
Freeborn selections and I think Miss
Jill's involved and James loud and all
these different individuals are all
coming together um to do bids for bog um
so you guys are on IG please go follow
uh bids for bog and there's amazing gear
going up every single day to benefit um
his wife Pat and I think that um it
would be a really great thing for
everybody in this community that follows
hash church and and everything that's
going on here to um to get involved and
and to help um it's a hard time out
there and I I think you know the least
we could do is try to support a fellow
Community member um and their family
when we can let's light one up for bog
everybody let's have a a nice round of
uh bong rips all the way
around I'll puff to that puff to
Jim um bogs varieties were were really
easy to grow for those of you guys that
are um out there that are new um and
even experienc Growers like sour bubble
is an incredible variety great hash
maker um and something that you guys can
all kind of put in your garden and
really it'll accentuate anything you
have in there whether it's a newer
gelato or an older Super Skunk or a
skunk well when I met him years and
years ago here in Amsterdam uh he his
most famous at that time was bubble
gum yeah the he had a nice he had a nice
bubble gum that is for sure I puffed
some full melt on that more than more
than a few times with
bog what are you uh what's everybody
puffing on what are you puffing on
Marcus I am puffing on some concentrated
X it is the cookies and cream and if you
take a really closeup shot it kind of
looks like macaroni and cheese or kind
of looks like some other crazy [ __ ] it
is absolutely [ __ ] Stellar hash Rosen
look Top If I was telling my French
friends it is
absolute damn near Perfection shout out
to concentrated X that's what's going
into to my Banger and I'm going to do a
cold start
because why not I like the cold start so
I'm I'm puffing on this is the medic
cush that I did the fresh frozen from
from my last grow and with this one I
put it in the freeze dryer and it was
all so this is the 7390 n120 I was going
to press it but it melts so I'm not
pressing it so I me smoking it so longer
next up
just so oh go ahead go no go
Mark just so happens fellas I'm I got
some a little bit of uh has Church flour
rosin it's all buttered up
nice just a tiny little bit I press the
morning it butter go up pretty much
instantly mine did the same thing and
looked the exact same color super light
yeah and just to clarify uh atan there
earlier you asked me about the yield on
and I kind of [ __ ] that up um it I'm
getting about in a 4x4 area whether it's
a single plant or four plants I'm
getting about just under a pound so not
too bad but not the
best no no that's that's still solid for
what you're getting re reaping in trikes
you know I got starg here I guess my
background is just unbelievable starg
and garlic and then I also have a little
lemon cake here um
90120 and then I also have uh some 73
right here so I was I was interest
interested because I was listening last
week and you guys were talking about the
hash Church strain and that's that's
really cool that there's actually one
that exists so as you know what makes
these you know strain I don't like using
the word strain variety cult ofir
whatever K ofar what makes these things
unique are the
uh you know phytochemical profile so
what what's the what's the cannaboid
profile and the turine profile in this
in this new variety here do we
know uh so what what I've had tested so
far and it's been at a fairly small lab
so it's not a commercialized lab by any
means they do have good equipment but
what I've gotten so far is just the THC
test back and it come back at 26
3% um I'm just waiting on the T beIN to
come back at this point right so that's
the only uh canono that is uh is shows
up in the canono profile of the of the
of the of the biom of of the plant
material well I actually had it tested
through a friend of mine and that's
pretty much the only thing that they've
given me so far I'm they're supposed to
be doing a pro a full profile of tpin on
it here shortly
yeah typically they'll do a profile of
at least no less than seven of the major
canabo you know because they all have
hopefully standards in their hlc to tell
you what the minor profile and yeah
you'd expect because it's a a strain
that gets you high you kind of know it's
it's got THC in it so what makes it
unique are all the other minor
cannabinoids that are around the THC not
necessarily the th see I I think what's
even more important I couldn't agree
more is the
Tes yeah well T tpin to yeah the entire
phytochemical profile which includes the
tpin but most when you look at most
smoking marijuana it's but basically
just THC with little or none of the
minor Turpin or canab excuse me that's
not true at all that's not that's that's
not that you're not looking at data on
of uh commercial cannabis and that's
just not true at all there's a whole
bunch of the minor uh canono that are in
there as much as a a fraction uh to uh a
single digit percent of of CBC CBG
there's varieties that are out there
that are uh 2:1 6:1 7:1 CBD I mean CBD
is all throughout the Commerce chain now
most of those wer
most of those weren't bred for for to be
smoking marijuana they they were they're
a newer variety with medical because
when you look at the traditional
analysis it's really just
THC uh with little of the other canids
until indica or WID Leaf started being
used because it had a lot of the minor
canono but ganja K stick columia and
stuff like that was really just T mostly
THC a little bit of other
things yeah well it depends what you
mean by a little bit so today's hlc
methods pick up what that little bit is
and what that little bit ends up being
you know a few percent and a few
percent AR made about looking at the
picture of the Mona Lisa from across the
street you kind of know there's THC in
there right so forget about the woman in
the picture look at everything else and
everything else is yes the turpine
profile the canono profile we know these
things are monsters that create a lot of
THC you kind of got to look beyond the
THC to really find the real unique right
but also you got to remember something
else Mark the other canono don't get too
high and they have very
minor yeah but they have this you know
ENT or what what do we call it on this
show Ensemble effect Ensemble
effect way way more well I I tell you
what though I mean I I hear this more
and more and again because I've been
doing lots of work in the hemp space
There's real a real thing when it comes
to that minor cannaboid profile that's
in full spectrum oils that just aren't
in isolates and I I've seen it I I've
gotten witness testim not uh witness
testimony feedback on products where
they're like oh yeah this is it it's all
about there is some full spectrum
biological efficacy and that's why I ask
about the minor canabo profile because I
think there is something about the minor
canabo profile that drives that full
spectrum you're you're both right you're
just talking about different things of
course what you're saying mark is
totally true and Sam himself is one of
the people who started that discussion
in early 2000 when he had all the
variety
ofy definitely you were you were no
doubt about it yet I also see where
Sam's coming from where he's looking
about he's looking about getting high
he's just looking for that rip that gets
him high and when he says those other
minor canabo they don't do anything for
for that particular thing in him you
know but that's not to say that a full
spectrum oil is not going to be more
appreciated uh from a medical patient
suffering from some sensitive disorder
and I can appreciate that really easily
that medical people have different
priorities and different needs and
different yeah I totally understand that
I think almost I almost think of it like
like like almost like a volume like a
volume issue and that people who listen
to music at a lower volume than you you
do Sam those minor things make make a
difference and so people who use less
THC who have like a lower tolerance than
say like heavy users than us you know
people who use a lot maybe that doesn't
really impact but people who are lighter
users I think that minor canono profile
and that full
spectrum uh uh bioefficacy is a is a
real thing I will also add that in
Canada I've seen a so many coas I can't
even explain how many COA I've seen and
they are very often not ripe with minor
canabo it seems to be more often than
not it's a decent tarpine profile and
then it's going to be THC somewhere
between you know 12 and and 28% or
something like that and this
is what right here on your test results
on biomass on plant material yeah of
course we can't process anything until
we see um so what you just talking about
on sorry talk about these these
different you're talking about canono so
here here's here's something that's 20
40 milligrams now these don't do
anything to me I take a I took a couple
of them last week I got a little bit of
anxiety from it but most people these
are flooring them someone like salmon
myself I I like I I was talking about
this I think the CBD is blocking those
those different and those different
cannabinoids are cuz I mean this is a
full profile basically this is what I'm
using for my pain right now and this
seems seems to be working and it doesn't
get me high it just actually helps ease
my pain so I mean these are the
different canabo that we will be talking
about all right I wanted to just do a
clarification for those who are watching
uh as you know uh Dr Mulan says uh it's
the Entourage effect but if you actually
look at nomenclature entourage is just a
group of people arriving together uh
where as uh Ensemble is exactly like
listening to an orchestra if you're
listening to One note you hear the horns
but when you hear the whole Orchestra
That's The Ensemble and so that's why I
and others have coined the phrase The
Ensemble effect so just to clarify for
new people who are watching who are
saying Entourage so just wanted to
clarify so uh I wanted to bring up a
thing I sent a COA number over to you
Marcus that was
10.75 came back from I remember that was
great job separating great job for
breaching the laws of everything of of
of of of yeah breaching the laws of of
Def redefining physics yeah um it uh so
I just wanted to just just talk about
this idea because I think there's a lot
of um a lot of nuance with all these
terms and things that we've we have and
pop culture seems to move way faster
than science in for some reason in in
this field so Dr Mark in your
professional opinion um where does 10.75
really makes sense I know that there's
minors put in there but when the thca
comes back at
98 98 and then there's like all these
other minors it just feels odd to to
read that and then put that on a package
for a patient just because I just feel
like we're at a zero to 100 range at
what point do we feel like it's okay to
have the Liberty to go beyond these
lines and and what does that really mean
because t as we know means absolutely
nothing um there's so much more uh to
The Ensemble and and as you really
beautifully put it the
Dynamics um if you're using recording
instruments you know for example you
want to record things at a low level
with great compressors and eqs and you
know and all that Dynamics really adds
to the overall experience to that sound
so what's your take on that so so there
there's two things you got to consider
so when when you're when you're when
you're trying to measure potency when
you're trying to me measure the amount
of a cannabinoid either like in hash or
in
flour um it's 90% of it is how you
prepare the sample and so like in a
typical hlc method you would take
something like about a couple hundred
milligrams of material and you have to
weigh it out like you can't weigh
out just well this is almost 200
milligrams it has to be
200.1 two milligrams it can't be 20013
or two that level of precision will have
an impact on the measurement you're
making because what you're doing is
you're taking that measured amount of
stuff and then you're going to do a
number of delusions to it and every time
you do a dilution to it you you
basically are are um I was going to say
deluding it
right you're you're making it less
concentrated until it gets down to the
level of concentration that your machine
has calibrated to read now these
machines separate things I know Marcus
we've talked about hlc a lot on on U on
hash church and we've had people like uh
the fellow from Su Labs his name's
escaping me now Alec yeah people talk
about hlc but how in hplc works is there
there's a column that you take this
diluted solution of your of your sample
and the the sample goes through the
column and the column think of it like a
uh like a water filter cartridge like
that's on your refrigerator if you have
filtered water that comes through your
refrigerator or your house or wherever
so as the solution goes through there
the canabo have a different affinity for
sticking to the packing material which
is called the column and they elute out
the other end of the column and there's
something called a detector that's
looking at a particular wavelength in
the ultraviolet spectrum that knows what
wavelength each of the individual
cannabinoids absorb at and so there's
something that they call standards and
so in order to calibrate this machine
properly what they do is you have to buy
a standard of each of the individual
purified cannabinoids right and then you
take that standard and again you do
what's called serial dilutions which
basically dilutes the concentration of
that standard and you inject this into
your hlc column and what you see is yes
Johnny showing one right there what you
see is that there's a linear response
between the amount of material that
comes out and that delusion that you've
made and you you read what's called a
calibration curve because the intensity
that the detector picks up of the
compounds coming out of the column is
directly proportional to how much of
that compound is in there and so for
like 2500 PPM you'll get a signal up
here and then for like 500 PPM you'll
get a signal down here and then for like
100 PPM it'll be down here and so you'll
draw what's called a calibration curve
and now what you can do with your
calibration curve yes Johnny showing a
chromatogram here so Johnny can now take
the peak Heights from that which is
called the chromatogram which is the
reading of the detector as the compounds
come out of the
hlc go to your calibration curve and say
if that Peak which is exactly that high
is that reads this on the calibration
curve then the concentration is this you
back it out through your dilution
calculation you can calculate how much
canono is actually in a sample so you
can see with all the mathematics that
you need to do there and all of the
manipulation of the sample itself right
because you have to weigh out exactly to
the you know what
0.0000001 gram yeah you know Precision
that means you you need an analytical
balance right there that cost like what
three four5 th000 I mean those are not
cheap the hlc machines most of them run
somewhere between maybe 25 $30,000 you
could get them used for less than that
but the really good ones with the
detectors and then you have to buy the
standards and the standards are really
expensive because the labs that make the
standards have to have a schedule one
license because they have to have a lot
of that material and then they dilute it
down to the level that the DEA says it's
okay to ship off as a standard and a
little bottle like this right Johnny
cost like a thousand bucks it's really
expensive it's really expensive but at
the same time you just can't buy it not
anyone can buy it so not only have to
buy it
fromed you can buy it I I was lucky just
the way things worked and
most you need a license they they don't
they don't just give those standards out
to anybody and then there's another
thing is that you know even these
instrument manufacturers I mean they
will not unless you can show that you
have a license to operate in your state
legally they're not going to sell you
this instrumentation because they don't
want to be liable for some clandestine
operation and so it's important I guess
to have standardized testing and all
this but you could see that it's really
easy to come up with a result that's
101% because what that means is that
somewhere along the lines in the sample
preparation most likely or in the
mathematics that takes the raw data that
the machine measures and converts it
into milligram per gram canono or
percent weight or whatever measurement
unit you're using all of that is going
to be impacted on the sample that that
the machine meas the machine just is
measuring its thing and then you have to
assume that these machines get clogged
if people don't know what they're doing
there's all kinds of crap that goes in
there we use these two Micron syringe
filters that are really useful to filter
out any crap because you don't want any
crap going in there and if you're
testing a lot of biomass that already
has a lot of fats waxes and lipids it's
really advisable to put what's called a
guard on your column and what that does
is it it just it extends the lifetime of
your column because it keeps a lot of
the high molecular weight [ __ ] from
dumbing up your column because once so
mark this this material was was
solventless thca that I had
extracted mechanically so it came back
that high I just felt like I just
couldn't I just don't it's like Tall
Tails to me you know yes so if if your
sample doesn't have doesn't have fats
waxes or lipids it's probably best to
dissolve that in methanol but like
Johnny was seeing when you dissolve
samples that have fats waxes and lipids
and methanol Johnny remember this we
were seeing white floaties in there
that's yeah
that's years ago and it was interesting
the way I had to figure it out is
because then I had put it in hexane and
the hexane melted the fats right so I
saw that we thought it was they thought
it was stuff coming from the parment so
then I called the parchment people and
they're like there's no [ __ ] way the
parchment is breaking down and that was
had to do with the raos in back then so
it was a lot of fat when we were
squishing temperat so so what that says
is that is as that part of what you
weighed out as part of your analytical
sample is that fats waxes and lipids
that that aren't being included so that
whole measurement is just that you can't
quantify anything based on that but here
here's the thing now like if you use
something like acetone or something to
dissolve all that stuff now you're
raming all that [ __ ] into your those
columns cost about a thousand bucks a
piece or they're you know they're
expensive and the Machine you're running
it on is like you know $20,000 machine
and it it you know there's so again
answer your question column lots of
places for that error to occur but um if
you're looking to do like a a purity
analysis where you need to get like
absolute you know you have to do a lot
of testing to develop a relationship
with a lab and I would say the Alex
operation SC is probably one of the more
better ones I don't know ATN if you
would agree but I would say the SC in
general the Steep Hill lab that we work
with over here in Maryland they're
really good um Steep Hill Labs they're
really hit and miss because I've seen
results on stuff that I know that we've
already tested and other people T like
this is what we're saying I'm like hey
you know what we have the data to
support it right I mean that's what's
good about the hlc is that if your
analytical methods are all proper and
you have everything that you need to do
you could challenge the result of some
marginal lab now what we found is that
some labs are in high throughput mode
you know why because their business bus
model is to run as many [ __ ] samples
through that lab as they possibly can do
they give a [ __ ] whether it's. 28.9
point they don't give a flying [ __ ] they
just want to get their report and get
their money that's it right so not us
we're a little more careful because we
need to make sure especially in hemp
operations that we're totally compliant
and you know what that means that means
that you know your THC is compliant
right at that3 level and you know you're
putting your business at risk if you
don't know what the hell it is you're
sending out the door because that stuff
can be confiscated or other people are
using those products again to formulate
into soaps or tinctures or whatever and
if it's not at the right level then that
means their their doses aren't at the
right level neither so it's really
important to have accurate testing all
along the way the lab that I use is is a
well-known lab I I don't I don't this
particular one I that's quite surprising
to me and it was just it was just the
whole thing surprising and and I see a
lot because I'm always sending samples
out um like yourself you just just had
to ask ask out safe but here's these old
samples this is kind of some memories
for me these are old so here's the
little boxes they used to come in they
used to come from Switzerland we had to
order them through a different company
sent to a different address it was they
were so hope you're keeping those in the
freezer Johnny oh these no these on I
have samples in my fridge ones for a had
from hlc and these are just the boxes
from like
1988 that's how old yeah these are from
like 1988 like I said this is from 1988
oh my God yeah the other ones I have are
in the fridge I got those in like 2012
but these are when I first started uh
working with Paul on the with the hplc
and he taught me a lot of just how to
use it how the call everything you
talked about just put me into memories
of looking at all those different Peaks
and profiles and all the different
strains and and really chasing those
profiles and seeing what was happening
with all the different strains it was
interesting to learn that knowledge so
thanks for that memory oh well that's
why we had to bring somebody in
internationally who made the solutions
so that's why we did that and he taught
us how to then suspend it in 100%
alcohol and so we had a standardized
methodology right so that we could
actually because we were just going for
THC originally remember that's where we
started yeah see there's the old Sigma
samples CU we were looking at that
originally we're were like oh my God and
then they wanted to know who we were
because this is way before testing we
were in a lab we're a dispensary and
they're like get the [ __ ] out of here
with that [ __ ] so that's when we
realized when I started asking Ethan
Russo and all the other experts I was
like okay who can I pull to actually
test but my question goes to Sam is so
you were originally testing for
THC I guess originally and then when did
the other cannaboids start to get added
when did you start to add from the
beginning we were we were testing for uh
at least the top 10 con
cannaboids so you had those you had
those those standards yes we had them
all legally and uh also too we we had uh
more than I think 50
54 uh of the uh
tping uh and that was you know very
early in the uh in the late 80s we were
doing that because see we had to start
with THC and then when we had THC then
we found that secondary Spike you know
and then we did research and found that
was CBD but you know we didn't have any
of the standards of CBG CBN you know any
of that so we' had to add that so it's
quite amazing I thought it would have
been a step-by-step process but to know
that you had access to them is kind of
mindblowing we just we just bought them
all we had thcv CBC CBG the propyl
homologues of all those I mean we we had
them
all how did you know to have those and
which ones to have versus ones not to
have well I didn't know which ones were
which but uh since I had them all I
tried them all and uh I I found out no
it was known the hlc characterization of
cannabis extracts was was discovered was
not discovered was reported actually by
Canadians uh in the early 60s and so
this was actually just prior to M mum's
paper in in 64 on the structural
elucidation so hlc fractionation of the
canavs uh was was no was hlc was new
wasn't hlc didn't ex how old as we as we
know it I mean this is like this is such
such cool because like if you look at if
you and you know it's really interesting
I just I wrote an article that I think
is being published um on the thing that
I think I've talked about on hash Church
which is the group from uh England that
first isolated
THC in the late 1800s so in
1896 is the first reported isolation by
vacuum
distillation of THC distillate and if
you
look uh no not Todd no Todd was Todd was
a contemporary of Adams in the 30s no
man this is in the 1890s this is wood
Spivy and easterfield oh yeah I've got
their paper yeah yeah we didn't I Comm
didn't I send you the preprint that I
wrote on this Dave sorry um I think
might sent you one of their papers you
didn't have too yeah yeah yeah yeah okay
so so so actually if if you go back and
it just it's such a fascinating Story
the
premum
THC chemistry you know and and and and
the way it happened and so this group
from from England in fact one of the
guys died I think before the paper
actually came out wood speed and
easterfield
still the stuff that they characterized
as toxic red oil and that they the way
they describe it they describe it just
like THC disl it would be you know it's
very sticky and they called it toxic but
to them toxic really was just short for
intoxicating it wasn't it wasn't toxic
like the way that we think of the word
toxic now it was it was the intoxicating
oil the intoxicating fraction and and
they thought it was actually canaban o
and they did Elemental studies and they
called it canaban all and when you do
Elemental studies what you're actually
doing is you're actually burning a
little bit of the material and when you
burn carbon containing material it goes
to carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide
right so from calcul or from calculation
how much carbon dioxide and how much
carbon monoxide you measure from the
burning of a sample this is just called
combustion analysis you can go back and
figure out what the carbon and hydrogen
empirical form formula of the material
that you're analyzing was I mean this is
this is 20 years before the discovery of
the electron folks okay this is
contemporary with the discovery of the
light bulb the this is like the
1890s okay it tells you how far ahead of
time this this science was that these
people were doing so their their
Elemental formula came really close to
canab andol but they didn't quite get it
but called it canaban all on the paper
and then later in the 20s in three or
four backtack papers in four consecutive
years a British chemist named Sydney
Khan uh who actually I think he was a
Australian chemist but I think he ended
up at a at a British
University um figured out the empirical
formula of THC and figured out for the
most part the structure and this is all
before Todd and Adams so this is prior
to Todd and Adams man they had this [ __ ]
[ __ ] figured out dude and this is
[ __ ] crazy [ __ ] so then when Todd and
Adams came along he thing the thing that
that messed up I think it was more Adams
than Todd because Adams in uh in two
years published about 30 papers on his
isolation of CBD and THC and what he
thought their structures were were and
remind yourself that they didn't have
hlc they didn't have NMR they didn't
have all the modern methods of
instrumentation that the later chemists
that follow like michan and myself have
so it's just it's just so great for us
now to be able to understand that
history and understand where all that
this stuff came from and so this is way
before mulam and so so it what
complicated Adams's assignment was in as
we know there's a uh a configuration of
the double bond in THC called Delta 9
and if given the opportunity Delta 9
under goes what's called an
isomerization over to Delta 8 and Delta
8 we hear a lot about of today because
there's a lot of people who are using U
mul chemistry to convert CBD over to
Delta 8 because Delta 8 is the
thermodynamic resting spot for that
double bond you know when you're looking
at the chemical structure of THC it
looks like chicken wire you know there's
kind of like in that North piece of
chicken wire there's kind of like a
double bond and where that double bond
resides is is whether it's not it's
Delta 9 or Delta 8 and if given the
opportunity it likes to get away from
the Benzene ring so it likes to move
from Delta 9 to Delta 8 it's favored
just on an energy profile by itself so
you know Mark that that when you find
archaeological remains that were high
THC or even moderate THC it's often
found as Delta 8 because the Delta 9 is
gone or converted and the Delta 8 sticks
around yeah I I I've described it before
on hash Church go back and do our
homework as kind of like a roller
coaster right and and that like Delta
Delta 99's at the top of the hill but
Delta Eight's at the bottom of the hill
and once Delta 9ine goes to Delta 8 it
doesn't go back it's like it's the it's
the more thermodynamically favored
resting point and and your observation
there Sam totally speaks to that so so
anyway and again Delta 8 and Delta 9 by
most uh hplc methods can be separated so
you can separate and you can distinguish
between those two isomers there's a lot
of talk about this online because
there's concern about about hemp derived
Delta a on its quasi legality on and
that's a whole different uh ball of wax
but to just go back to the mulam story
and the and and and Adams is if you go
back and look at Adams's work it's all
he doesn't know where that double bond
is and so he puts it I think in the nine
position but I think his methyl
assignment was wrong or they just didn't
have all the structural data that you
know michul and others had later in the
60s after NMR was invented and then when
hlc was invented I think right away like
right after there were commercial
systems the paper I have in fact Marcus
I believe we talked about this on hash
church too because it was a group of
Canadians that did it um uh first
characterized the hlc separation of the
cannabinoids and I believe the tpin on
of of of cannabis I think that was a
Canadian group that did that when did GC
start being used Mark do you know yeah
then GC was around the same time so it
was important for like all these
chromatographic methods that they
actually have the the the packing
materials and so what made hlc work was
the column what makes the column work is
the stuff that goes inside the column
well check it out that was invented by a
guy named Jack Kirkland who I actually
had the unbelievable honor of meeting at
one
point um Jack used to work at Dupont
many many years ago and he left when
they splintered off uh hulet Packard
which became now agilant and he was a
kind old guy I mean really nice guy but
um they they invented macroporous silica
which was required in order to make the
packing material for these
columns and that enabled the whole
hlc thing to exist and when they did
that for GC so gas chromatography rather
than dissolving the material what you're
doing is you're again going through that
elaborate sampling process where you're
weighing out the sample you know exactly
what it is and then what you're doing is
you're you're injecting it into a uh
injection Port which is a very hot um uh
plate and on that hot metal plate when
your sample hits it it's instantly
vaporized and and and that Vapor now
travels through the column and so rather
than a solution traveling through the
column and separating Things based on
polarity in the GC what you're doing is
you're basing things uh Separation on
differences in boiling points and so
your your your most volatile components
are going to come out first right so as
they percolate through the column your
tpes come out and then your cannaboids
come out later because they're your
higher boiling stuff because gas
chromatography is based on
separation based on uh boiling through
the column which is basically just kind
of like a maze that the compounds have
to get through and then like hlc there's
a detector on the other side of that
column that lights up and makes a peak
every time a compound comes
out oh that's a lot we went through GC
and
hlc that was a lot but very well said
and people appreciate that that is uh
that's good information on a Sunday
morning it's cool because you know I'm
getting a lot of inquiries Mark people
go back and they watch hash church and
they want to know about like things like
this I'm going to reference this church
just because people will know oh what is
hlc or what is you know one thing i'
have to say is thatc is really important
for measuring your canabo and GC is
really important for measuring your tpin
and the thing about GC remember you're
squirting it onto that hot plate on that
hot plate canabo decarbox silation
happens
instantaneously so you're not going to
get a measurement of your
canabo uh uh profiles in terms of what
you're going to see in your in your hlc
because in your hlc you don't see
decarbox
silation so I'll add it in the comments
section as well Mark so when people come
back what was that I said I'll add it in
the in the comment section that you me
that you're what you you know the
breakdown between the differences and a
little bit of the history are there any
questions class I was going to say Mark
when I had that GC in my garage I found
that a lot easier to use than the hlc
was a lot more technical a lot more prep
work a lot more time where just putting
it in the side and heating it up and
putting it into the machine itself um
was great again there's two types of
analysis there's qualitative analysis
where you're looking to qualitate
something and then there's something
called quantitative analysis where
you're just looking to find out how much
of something is in there and sometimes
just a yes or no decision you know you
want to just get a quick shoot on the GC
and you want to just see your big THC
Peak and maybe a couple other Peaks and
that's fine and dandy but if you need to
correlate it or measure it and
especially measure it because now you're
going to take that stuff and put it into
say I don't know MCT or you're going to
make some type of product that has to be
dosed at a particular label
concentration I don't know how you do
that without having hlc in internally
you know U question about uh things like
orange
photonics uh these I can't remember
there's a few other um different yeah
the products like this that you know I
dream of walking into my hemp fields and
just like plopping it down and being
like yeah let's go grab all these
samples how realistic is a lot of this
stuff um AR very ACC
it's not that they're not accurate they
can only give you a level of precision
that that's good for you know if you're
making a decision on whether or not to
take a crop out of a field you could
probably use one of those but you can't
use that to basically use those numbers
in say like the dosing of a product to
meet a label requirement no way because
you're just not going to have the level
of accuracy it's plus or minus two or 3%
that just doesn't you know like I said
that's not even ballpark that's that's
exit that the ball parks that results
that's close
enough I don't find them very accurate
at all we did all of our lab work for
both GC and hlc because we had both we
always had to First dehumidify the
sample down to almost zero humidity
moisture and so if you don't if you
don't have it together you don't have it
together yeah I mean I mean you bring up
a a great Point Sam and this is probably
again a a potential source of that of
that 101% error that you're seeing which
is that if you're not drying the
material and and there could be water
there as we know you know biomass and uh
there's Alec okay we get the authority
in here to tell us about it so it's this
this sample that just be aware is what's
called hydroscopic which means it'll
absorb moisture from the air
and certainly like if you take
biomaterial that's been dried and you
reintroduce it to a moist ambient
moisture environment it's going to draw
in moisture and that's going to affect
the weight of what you're trying to
measure down to the hundredth of a
milligram and if you're really trying to
be really really really really really
accurate it has to be dried to the point
of zero water every time every time
every time and if it's not yeah you're
gonna have a little bit of Squish in
your data right so that material was
bone dry it was just straight thca you
know mechanically
separated I mean you're talking long
presses I mean exorb right send me a
sample I'm only I'm only kidding I would
but yeah I I appreciate your Insight on
on thaty you know I I think the FED has
something bigger on their mind these
days it does things to my head when I
put that into the market and I have to
put that on the label but here here's
the thing you know like like with thca I
mean this is this is just a real kind of
cool thing so you could melt thca at a
lower temperature below which it
decarboxylates at yeah so think think
about that for a second you could
melt
thca into a liquid before it'll decarbox
so if if you have a melting point
apparatus that's a wonderful wonderful
way to see how pure your sample is right
and in fact you know you can in my
melting point apparatus I could do side
by side samples you know where you can
do maybe another recrystallization or
multiple recrystallizations try to
recrystallize that stuff to
99.9999% and do side by-side mouthing
points and see how sharp your melting
point is sounds like you need to do my
testing melting point apparatus are
pretty cheap and and I think you can buy
them I don't think they're that
expensive but it's a great indication
for crystals like CBD isolate on on
Purity so it's kind of like Poor Man's
hlc just to tell you how pure your stuff
is hey welcome to Alec Mr Alec must have
heard us chatting I don't know if he's
still there I see a blank blank spot
where his camera was but uh he
definitely was here for a
bit we'll give him a
welcome he connected telepathically
right that's it he did he just he felt
his ears burning he was like I think
those guys and they're doing the
testing testing for the emerald cup so
you know he's the authority right
remember the day he came on hash church
and he was like he had just done the
emerald cup and he's like I kind of feel
like the Grinch Who Stole
[Laughter]
Christmas we l him for it because we
could see through the talk and the lies
there he is he's moving around again you
know because now we had real science to
see through the the [ __ ] and the
hearsay in the conjecture you know
science ended it and yeah Alec felt bad
because he kicked a whole bunch of
people in the groin because they all
[ __ ] used you know pesticides and
things they shouldn't have been used and
they got caught so it just was
surprising I think the amount of numbers
that you know Alec and them found at SC
Labs you know that uh people thought
that could got away with so you know
shame on those people for trying to
compete with tainted product and go on
Alec in them for actually catching them
using real
science well I don't know that I don't
know how widespread that issue in in
water has was really known right I mean
Mark I mean it we we talked about it on
hash
and at the time I did a little poking
around on the internet but it wasn't
universally known that if your cakes
aren't [ __ ] dry they're GNA start
molding within hours right I mean this
is just like a biological process that
you just cannot stop and you need to
keep your [ __ ] dry right I mean that
that happened I think in or
frozen but but didn't that that whole
Revelation wasn't known in the hash
Community was it well it kind of got
learned this way first you know there's
lot you know I'm not going to go over
the entire history but at a time where I
was doing this let's just say there was
almost nobody online on the internet
promoting this process and I made a
massive mistake I made the mistake that
I would take the bubble especially here
in the Pacific Northwest and I would end
up you know leave it in patties let it
so you think it's dry but then it's
really not dry you roll it into balls
you get this really beautiful Mar marble
but if you're getting that marble that
always told me you know that hash is not
dry yet it's gone through stages of
drying and then you're breaking it open
releasing the lighter color to the
darker on the outside and mixing it all
up into a marble and what happened with
an enormous amount of the the earliest
water hashes made from bubble bags at
least from 1999 and and and upwards to
about 2003 or four um we weren't drying
the hash properly it just wasn't being
dried so it would do this buttering
thing where it would just start to kind
of fall apart and when you crack open a
ball and smell it you'd have that funky
smell where you were like there's
something not right going on in that
hash like that's a guarantee not right
that took me
years of promoting seing and
microplaning and trying to show people
like don't P don't put it into a pile
don't put it you know then people like
Nick te came out was like oh you can dry
hash in like a day a day and a half but
not really going over the fact that he
was in colle
in this in this dry Aid Place versus the
Pacific Northwest if you're telling
someone over and vice versa you know for
me to be telling him hey it's going to
take you at least seven days to dry your
hash my God it would have no turps left
in it so we learned things like that by
being different people promoting these
similar things in different places we
learned that the hash acts differently
and which you mentioned earlier in
regards to hydrophilic when the hash is
sitting out and there's tons of moisture
in the air trust me it's never going to
dry it'll literally get more wet by
pulling that [ __ ] out of the out of the
air so that's where the desicant came
into play and that's why I always wanted
people to dry on something like a food
grade thick cardboard before freeze
dryer something for home use that didn't
cost thousands of dollars people are
already bitching about the cost of
bubble bags this was 22 years ago and
they were a couple hundred bucks for a
pair so they certainly weren't going to
be going out and buying a $8,000 freeze
dryer to uh you know to take this to
that level it was for personal and if
you did it right you could get the hash
dry in the Pacific Northwest without
using a desant it was very very
difficult grading it or seing it very
very thin so it wasn't piled up and
holding you know itself inside itself
again sealing up that hash because it
would do that even freshly seed so you
know these are definitely things that um
we Lear the point that I was making and
I think Alec is is here now and maybe he
could comment is that I think our
discussion about this on hash church
with the data that Alec presented and
this whole awareness now I I think was a
outcrop of that of of that episode that
ATN was talking about which is that you
know I hate to give you the bad news but
you know um so totally is that right I
mean is that the first time that data
that
supported um
microbial contamination of improperly
dried hash is a widespread
phenomena iiz was that was that for a
question to
me yeah yeah well so so yeah I mean uh
it it yeah it's been very fascinating I
think I feel like through through um you
know incredible kind of vehicles like
hash Church you know I definitely feel
as though it kind of helped to push kind
of forward a lot of the Consciousness
and understanding of these these kind of
shortfalls in or pitfalls with certain
types of extraction whether you know
kind of you know microbial kind of
overgrowth is a PO because of the
presence of moisture or in the case of
pesticides the way kind of pesticides
carry over and concentrate in extraction
processes especially ones that aren't
necessarily water soluble but um yeah I
mean I definitely dig up pastur just
understanding how many people kind of uh
that are passionate enthusiasts of this
plant and of of perfecting that have
kind of gained and learned from this
this uh this Avenue um but yeah I mean
but but Mark I because I I I I tuned
into the the live YouTube and I I heard
you talking about hcgc and and you so
much respect to you I mean I'm not in
any way I mean I'm one of the
co-founders of SC Labs I'm not a
scientist myself I'm kind of more from
you know the cultivation kind of
cannabis side of um you know
front-facing side of our business but I
you know I'd like to think of become a
trained parakeet and being able to you
know at least grasp understand talk and
convey you know some high scientific
kind of perspectives and understandings
that you know I've come to learn and
we've come to learn from Trends you know
from testing over the last
decade yeah totally I mean I I think
that you know I mean you mentioned hash
church and before we were talking about
kind of like the Grateful Dead scene and
it's like to me man I mean h how how
lucky are we to live when we did we
Traverse a millennium okay we were born
in another
Millennium and and and we were alive
during during miles DAV we were alive
during Bob Marley I was I saw Jerry
Garcia in a building I think what almost
200 times I it just to me it's like we
we we have a really unique opportunity
to really bring
together this you know passion that all
of us have for the plant and people who
really love you know where this industry
is going when I say industry yeah
there's a lot of things that I don't
like about it because there's like suits
and ties and money and having to raise
tons of money but you know on the other
side of that you have an industry that
has standardized testing you have people
who understand that hlc is not just
something that you're paying for at the
testing lab but I have to have that at
my production facility too because how
the hell do I know what I'm making if
I'm making extracts and I I don't do any
internal testing before so we use
thirdparty testing all the time and it's
always to validate things that we've
already tested 10 ways between now and
last Sunday we know what that result's
going to come back when we send it over
to fence to third party lab because
we've already tested it a whole bunch of
times and we're making sure that a
tinure bottle or whatever I mean the
right label information is coherent with
you know again every best you know
analytical method that we have now we do
have the luxury of standing on the
shoulders of these Giants that came
before us and as you look at you know
all the cannaboid chemistry literature
which is Rich with just Discovery
discovery made in an environment with
Incredible headwinds where you can't do
research on this plant you know and
still people did research because they
knew how important this plant was and it
happened in other places other than the
United States because of it and and
that's fine I mean the chemical
literature for a scientist like me is my
crystal ball right and I could look into
that crystal ball and I could see I
could see what can be and and only I
because my eyes grew up I mean I used to
play with Legos when I was a kid right
and not like Star Wars Legos and these
were just the the blocks here's just a
bunch of red and green and blue there
were no no directions and I think
nonlinear thought and how kids are able
to really put together in a nonlinear
way things helps people understand you
know that you know we're just part of
this Continuum you know and we're all
lucky to be alive right now because man
where the plant is right now and we're
at the BRD of a new uh Administration
that's going to get in there and change
a lot of the laws that are wrong and
still we need to be proactive and I'm
sure ATM will agree with me that there's
still a lot of things that are wrong
that need to be fixed you know we need
to be able to get records expunged we
need to be able to get away from this
all the things that prohibition did to
drag down our society and to me it's
like the Grateful Dead was this thing
that was going along and that was just
gonna
again eventually expel its fruits into
something that was going to be bigger
than it ever imagined it would be and
that's where we're at so are you saying
are you saying you don't play with Star
Wars Lego
anymore no I'm just saying that the
Legos that my kids grew up playing with
were different than the Legos that I had
when I was a kid right I mean we were
lucky to have the Legos where I can put
two little rubber tires and a wheel in
there you know but I you guys um my dad
just walked in the door so thanks very
much and I've had such a great morning
talking with you all keep passion and I
will see you guys all again on the next
church love you Johnny B see you later
Johnny B and and I'd love to love to
build on a part of Marcus's I'm sorry uh
um um yes Dr Mark's points he was just
making um you know that's one of the
most fascinating things and I mean I
I've described it kind of in in effort
kind of across uh different episodes of
House Church that I've been able to be
part of but you know just learning from
the data you know the trends in the data
over hundreds of thousands of data
points over the last 10 years you know
it's it's really so much brought me such
excitement and optimism about where this
is going although there's all these
efforts and corporate Predator
capitalism trying to come in to try to
pillage and you know kind of take
advantage of this plant or profit on
this plant but there's so many built-in
teachings and lessons that you either
have learned or you have not even you
don't even [ __ ] have a clue you know
excuse my language but you know kind of
you know service to this plant in
various methods of hash extraction I
mean there's so much to learn and and
and you know kind of if you you know
just using cultivation as example if
you've never gotten hit by broad mites
and spider mites and white rud AIDS and
white flies and you know all the
potential pests how do you know how to
deal with it and so I just feel like
this's this built-in like tribal
knowledge and awareness that that those
that have been serviced plant for so
long have that is a massive competitive
advantage in the in a coming Global
regulated market especially you know and
and and and on this idea of how do we
you know kind of as thought leaders in
the community really help drive you know
kind of the way this is all shaped up
you know because in California you know
we're seeing so many efforts uh you know
to kind of just monocrop and just blow
this plant up but you know I feel like
the level of huis that people come into
this plant with thinking they're just
going to throw money at it and kind of
just Crush everybody is proportional to
how quickly face plant you know off The
Starting Line you know and you know just
I'm I'm just witnessing everybody
invests so much money into the worst
spaces in the state to grow that are
just right in the deepest heart of you
know the EG the industrial egg kind of
legacy and and you know in areas like
Selenas which you know I'm in Santa Cruz
California and you know Selenas is you
know kind of a 45 minute drive Selenas
you know and that area is you know the
the solid bowl of the United States you
know like 70 80 plus % of the you know
vegetables and produce kind of produced
out of that area and so whenever you
have cultivation kind of happening in
the in in the heart of these areas you
know it's like that area particularly
you know it's not just one crop that
they're growing like almonds where
there's a set regimen of Organo
phosphates and pesticides and fungicides
they spray each year it's a rotation of
all these different crops from brasas to
Greens to kind of you know in each crop
planted throughout different times of
the year sprayed with different levels
of pesticides and fungicides and so I
feel like you know just uh on that idea
you were talking about Mark with the you
know the the crystal ball you know from
the data I almost feel the same thing
almost see like this back of future
sports Almanac of you know to seeing who
are you coming potential winners and
losers of where it's going and and um
you know just I feel like as long as you
know we have this eternal vigilance to
kind of not have things kind of be
deregulated or allow the deregulation of
this you know because they put in so
much regulation and I think there's yeah
tons of it taxation kinds of stuff that
is um incredibly important that we work
to kind of Reform and change but you
know with regard to the testing
regulations you know I feel like um it's
a it's a barrier of Entry it's a it's a
leveling of the playing field you know
you know once this goes National you
know you can't just plant a 100 acres of
of cannabis in the middle of the Cal you
know in the middle of the heartland of
Agriculture like the the millions of
Acres of uh of dust bowl across the
Midwest
you know because that has there massive
bi remediation fire remediation has to
occur you know before there can be any
potential to grow cannabis that's going
to compete on a national Market that's
going to pass and be able to you know be
made available to the public you know
with these levels of public health
safety standards sorry go ahead Mark
what I see Alec I mean I think the the
these are all great points I think Colin
might be able to comment on this too as
well is as programs open up out in the
eastern United States out in the states
be uh this side in Mississippi
is that I think they recognize the
importance of the testing industry has
to kind of like be a sister industry to
the to the production industry itself
meaning that they need to have two sets
of businesses in the state they need to
have the producers the people who are
growing extracting making formulated
products and dispensing those products
but we also need to have third-party
independent Testing Lab that need to be
completely different set of people doing
those business operations not the same
set of people you know and I think
there's always a confusion I think that
people always have about testing that
it's somehow it's some Panacea and some
it's some box oh well they'll they'll
test it everything will be test it's
like again I think that it's really
naive to even open up a production
facility where you're going to be
spending you know hundreds of thousands
if not millions of dollars uh to put
into developing a licensed production
facility without having internal
analytics and if you don't have internal
analytics and you're just going to send
all your stuff over the fence well then
you're going to have prohibitively long
production timelines because in order to
your formulate your distillate you need
to know what your distillate test that
so what are you going to do test your
distillate then wait around 10 days for
that result to come back before you
formulate the distillate no you want to
test it right then and there and and
have testing capabilities all throughout
the selection of your biomass you know
you don't just take a COA from some Farm
you should be testing the biomass
yourself any type of whether you're
buying crude or whether you're buying
distillate or whether you're buying any
process intermediate yeah it's going to
show up with a COA but wouldn't it be
great to do the testing yourself and
what we found I mean this is in
interesting Alec because again I don't
usually say this with a lot of people is
that some testing labs are again in this
high throughput mode and they're just
sort of like you know grinding out never
failing yeah totally yeah so you know
how you run your hlc is kind of like how
you drive your car in a way well and and
if I real quick to it and I apologize
Colin I think you were about to jump in
but just I'd love to make a point real
quick because you know that's another
thing we're seeing from California and
and some of the leadership that the way
California you know regulated the you
know test or just as far as testing
let me just finish my car analogy I
think I think it's funny so how you
drive your car is how you run your hplc
so if there's a road with a bunch of
potholes in it you ever drive down it
really fast and you hardly hit any
potholes at all right because you're
driving down so fast that you never hit
any of the but when you drive really
slow you hit every every [ __ ] pothole
right that's a beautiful analogy
my point of um Mark it's like having
this awesome instrument here and not
being able to know what it sounds
like you know what I mean I'm like it
just it looks so good and it's I know
what I'm playing I know I'm playing the
right chords and the right in the right
key and I know exactly what's what's I
think what's happening but you're
missing that call and response that um
as a formulator as a product developer
and a hash maker I I just I yearn for
that immediacy because that to me is the
art and that call and response is
necessary for myself to really make
decision making that's actually educated
rather than waiting around I wait around
I mean I've
waited waited long times guys like
months where to just be like well where
is the sample this stuff it's just been
sitting on ice for me essentially it's a
hurry up and weight situation in in the
regulated market sometimes and it's it
becomes actually
frustrating I think and to your point
mark yeah if you're constantly throwing
things over the over the fence you're
just it's h you're at the mercy of of
them so it's yeah and yeah really I
couldn't agree more I and I apologize
for any Interruption there um no don't
don't be never apologize I I appre I
appreciate these these points you know
and you know I think so much of the
foundation though is quality analytics
and and to actually do the work to learn
how to drive um or or to to play that
instrument you know and and uh and what
and I was going to hit on two points one
around kind of internal testing and then
the other one on kind of third party
testing because you know if you're going
to put people through so much
regulations and burdensome testing you
know for third party certification to
ensure for public health and safety you
know you have to be overly regulating
the analytical labs doing the testing
because if you don't have you know
substantial kind of auditing and ongoing
data package review processes from the
regulat body on the labs doing the
testing you know then then there's no
point in even having testing regulations
on people because if Labs aren't held to
a certain standard and you know they can
just you know and people know you know
there there becomes an economic dis to
work with good labs for good reasons of
accuracy and precision you know to more
chase out high THC numbers or to just
always go through these Labs because
they would pass you know but you know
kind of as an example just with turpine
testing you know um whenever we run a
turpine test or a GC you know it go go
you know the runtime through our column
is about 90 minutes per example you know
so that we can ensure that there's full
separation for every individual Peak
because if you if you if you rush it and
you have the 15 minute run time because
you're trying to do this High throughput
thing then you can see it in the data
being completely wrong because of the
ident misidentification of co- alluding
compounds that you know you identify as
eucalyptol or something that's not even
ever showing up in any substantial
amount in cannabis and so I think you
know the foundation of
of good chemistry good science good
analytical chemistry is is is doing the
work and validation to ensure that
you're actually test identifying what
you're looking to test you know and and
you know I completely agree I think I
think the partnership between you know
um thirdparty Labs like ourself and and
those that are in cultivation or
manufacturing is you know especially as
as groups are bringing on their own
internal hplc and GC capabilities it's
to develop that relationship and
partnership and helping to you know in
in you know show that we're you know the
same
page uh third third party testing Labs
but also individual groups setting up
Labs because you know if you're
formulating off of a bad method um you
know then then you're then you know
there's no ability to be consistent
or in comparing that to third party
testing yeah like to your point that
that you just made right there the
the differentiation from batch to batch
or the same batch tested unknowingly to
them or maybe they do know because it's
batch number related but they do come
back differently at times and we've
addressed that um and yeah think good
things take time and that's the other
half of it is that you're illustrating
the the most the biggest point it's it's
it's I take a lot of time in Minecraft
and and doing what they're doing in in
the lab that's the same way if you cut C
Corners you're going to see in the data
and that's you're exactly right and I
don't know what the answer to that stuff
is but it's you know I know from my
point of view because of all the
ceilings that we or the lower ceilings
that we have in the particular state
that I'm in in our facility it's just it
it becomes um I just want things faster
I'm it's only human though I guess you
know um so I think it's it's good that
we can push labs to to to think about
this but to your point what there's a
give and take um yeah and you know in
California for compliance testing you
know we're at two to three days so I
mean you shouldn't you should never you
know be satisfied with 30 days you know
and see I would I would be happy to get
there that would be
incredible and you know it's taken us
long time to get to that but um you know
but but to the Quality uh conversation
that's where I think California you I
think a lot of states that have
regulated in the past haven't taken
haven't done their job of regulating
labs to they should be and so what
happens in California you know
eventually as every lab is fully
licensed no lab has their full license
currently you know every lab that's
currently uh licensed is operating on
provisional license at most and and um
by the end of the regulation there's so
much ongoing auditing accreditation and
and the be the Bureau of cannabis
control in California has this process
known as data pack
review um and so at any time the BCC can
reach out to a lab and they they come
from client driven complaints on uh in
consistency and quality or from just
random audit but they'll request a data
package it's about 12 gigabytes of data
the lab has to get to them by the end of
the following day and so and and it's
all the calibration data quality data
who touched it went every aspect of of
uh the of every test that was done on
that batch and then the BCC has a panel
of PhD analytical chemists then
essentially grade these data packages
and review and you know and and
scrutinize these data packages and if
they see any issue with the data they'll
reach out to the lab you have to the end
they'll ask you a question and you have
to the end of that day at four in the
afternoon to answer that question and
based on your ability to answer the
question they'll either say all right
cool you're good or they'll initiate an
investigation and so once they initiate
investigation they begin doing deeper
Dives and auditing you know the lab's
Quality Systems and uh different batches
of data and from uh their findings they
they'll issue a tier tier two or tier
three violation tier one's like a fix it
ticket tier two is a suspension and
ended there's you know I mean lab has
been suspended for five six weeks you
know currently in the state of
California from this type of uh you know
and and you know and then the top tier
violation is a tier three violation and
that's like um identifying you know
because tier two violation you're
suspended until the until you can
demonstrate to the BCC that you
corrected the action that they found a
violation in you know in the quality of
data and the method development or
validation um you know and and um and
then so so tier 2 is a suspension for
however long it takes to fix the
violation and then a tier three
violation has happened to you know
probably about 10 Labs already in
California and that's a full revocation
of license because they found
fraudulence or gross negligence you know
just juicing numbers like you know kind
of tweaking their methods to never see
pesticides and whenever the tier three
violation happens know they essentially
do a consumer level product recall going
back to the beginning of the date of the
investigation began and uh you know
there's a few labs in California that
happened to and the the most horrifying
part of it is you know the the producers
and processors and manufacturers of
batches are the ones that take the
biggest hit in those cases because they
have to go through these product recalls
after they already you know got cashed
out you know you know counted on you
know you know invested their money back
into their business you know all of a
sudden product recall and so you know we
we really pride ourselves in kind of you
know working to be a leader in the
leader in in the space of what we do um
and and
[Music]
and testing regulations as know spot not
just because we're in the business of
testing but as a cultural um you know on
a cultural kind of uh sociological level
you know we see you know testing as a
way of evening the playing field again
back to the other part of the
conversation where you know if everybody
is on the same account held you know
there you know it's David can complete
comp against Goliath and um and then
once we're all on the same level of
quality and data you know then then you
we can begin to actually you know really
help people tune their methods and their
internal labs and kind of you know the
whole industry can progress um but yeah
what's your take on Tac uh do do you
mark Dr Mark and and also you Alec uh
and everyone here what do you what do
you guys feel T what do you mean by Tac
well you know how Market is really
looking at Tac as a as a mechanism in in
retail um 30% the 20% Club it's the you
know the these types of terms that are
being have been historically thrown
around you know what do you think they
mean in terms of of science I'm not
familiar I've never heard of ATT before
at all total active
canids canids Okay
total sure sure yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
okay yeah well I mean yeah to I mean
because you know I mean I think that's
that's the whole thing thing I mean
everybody been so focused hyperfocused
on THC in regulated markets as the sole
indicator of quality and it's really had
an effect on the market in a huge way
not only because Bad Lab data exists
where numbers are just Juiced and it
just throws off the whole thing but also
because you know I mean when I think Tac
combined with total tping content and
the relative ratio is really one of the
best numbers you could ever judge or
value weed on right because you could
have a you know 30% t total active
cannabinoid you know kind of containing
strain but if you had less if you know
if you dried it and cured it like you
know terribly and you volatilized all
your monot turps you could have say less
than 0.2% total turpine content so now
you got 35 canab or 3% total canab total
cannabinoids you got less than 0 2% tpin
that's like a 90 to1 95 to1 cannaboid
detering ratio and in my opinion that's
what really begins to Define what bio
masses everybody's using that word in my
opinion biomass is when material that
has no other
value because the turpins are gone or
it's old or degraded to where then dis
distilling it is the only real option to
capture value from that material whereas
if there's a bunch of tpine content
because preservation and ongoing like
you know because you know a lot of
people are farming cannabis but not tpin
right and and you know we see from the
time of harvest even if you dry and cure
in the most ideal condition
you know you there's 60 to 80% of tpping
content lost you know so I if you
harvest in the middle of the day versus
of the night you know by going to field
harvesting in the middle of the heat of
the day you smell turpins in the air
they volatilized into your nose right
and so I think you know and and and and
so going back to that analogy right if
you had a if you had a strain that was
15% total active cannabinoids when
unfortunately and these regulated
licensed legalized markets you know can
can have uh deflated value because
they're not above 20% right if it was
15% but it had like but if it was Harve
if it was cultivated optimally harvested
in the middle of the night around the
full moon um you know dried cured
preserved under like ideal conditions
below 60 degrees you know or or more
whatever you know like the you you know
you can see that in the relative ratio
of canab cannaboids the tping and so all
of a sudden you you could have three and
a half to 5 and a half% tpine content in
the dried flour relative to 15%
cannaboids that's like a 3:1 cannaboid
deter ratio you know so so all of a
sudden reality of the Entourage effect
or The Ensemble effect and how much the
the effect is going to hit you know
because the lining is 3% and versus you
know half a percent right so I think
there's something really big there in
the future you know because it's it's
it's you know paying Les less I mean
total active cannaboids I think is much
more important than total you know THC
you know right because what other canabo
are in there and what amounts right but
but total act canono in relation to
Total tpine content the relative ratio
that's like a that's more of a measure
to actually judge so what is your what's
a good measurement for you that you see
in terms of tpin um you know I mean we
see like anything I think you see so
much that's why I'm asking I just I feel
like it's good for the viewers and even
myself to you know because we we've
arrived in this regulated market we have
a lot of
terms and things that are being thrown
around every day and it all amounts to
Art and commerce to me at least at the
end of the day and how they quantify
that is just so op it's there's a lot of
opinion around
it well uh so we can thank we can thank
our friends in Italy again for helping
another piece of the puzzle become
unraveled right so not only did they
discover the the the T8 CP and the
cbdp
C7 cannabinoids so they've now
discovered the C6 cannabinoids right and
I posted the link in our chat Marcus I
don't think I can't post it over in the
in the um I can try to do it right now
in the YouTube chat if you guys want to
put that in there but so so this is the
this is the cannabinoid structure but
rather than having the C5 tail it's got
a C6 tail so it makes sense that you
know all of these things are in the
Cannabis that we've been smoking for
years the C6 the C3 or the varens the
C7 are the P's and the c5s are the ones
that were you know analyzing routinely
but constantly finding that we're not
characterizing the full amount of what
we have well you know these are all the
little pieces that are
you you're saying that these compounds
are affecting the high I doubt it the
found it I I didn't say they're
affecting the high who said that I
didn't say they're affecting the high oh
okay I misunderstood good thing because
he doesn't agree with that well well
wait wait this group of Italian this
group of Italians did show that the
compounds are active I think in a mouse
uh paw pain assay for no Ive uh uh pain
I I I read the paper really quickly but
um it's just another again it's
fascinating because as analytical
chemistry is happening and as varieties
I think if I remember correctly the name
of the variety was the fm2 if you look
at the paper in nature and I think the
paper is widely available it's not like
you need some subscription to a journal
so all you need to do is click on that
link but you'll see that they have the
CBD version and THC version that they
isolated in very very small quantities
but it's just Again part of what the
plant is making the plants making these
compounds that totally makes sense that
the biosynthetic pathway exists and the
thing I'll leave everyone with is that
now that they've basically been able to
make cannaboids in yeast they can now
genetically engineer yeast just to make
specifically now this one with the C6
tail or with the C3 tail and then
combine them later on so you know you're
not limited by just plant genetics
because you know they know the
biochemical mechanisms and how to
basically engineer yeast to make these
compounds how valuable do you think
that's going to be longterm Mark oh I
think it's really valuable I think the
yeah I it's incredibly valuable these
compounds are incredibly medically
active and making small subtle changes
to the structure seems to have impact on
the biological activity so I think those
small subtle changes to the structure
just even if you compare t8c to T8 CV or
if you compare the C the ones in the
CBD um uh uh a family I mean all of
these compounds basically are active in
the same way the question is is what do
the subtle changes in the structures do
impact their safety and efficacy and I
think for the most part that's widely
unknown so an open field worth
study right no absolutely I agree 100% I
would think
so I mean more stady more stady changing
in regulation yeah does invite all the
corporate aspects of this but it also
invites opportunity to uncover
incredible value propositions which is
that these molecules which you know the
plant has basically taught us are
biologically active and oh yeah by the
way they're also safe for humans have
all kinds of myriads of biological
properties that are you know we need to
discover and exploit in terms of you
know manifesting it for human health and
not taking all this pharmaceutical crap
that they're trying to sell us
yeah I've been really I've been I've
been really I've been really freaked out
about the Frank and canono you know kind
of future
idea Prevagen what the hell is in
Prevagen some ground up jellyfish
there's commercials on it all over TV I
see it on the Nightly News I see it all
during you know Prevagen it's like some
you know herbal supplement that old
people are taking and it says it
improves their memory I look at these
commercials I'm like why aren't these
people smok in the ganja it'll improve
their memory what the [ __ ] they don't
they don't want to say goodbye to the
anal leakage they get from their
pharmaceutical uh yeah but Prevagen is
totally not FDA regulated it's just
herbal flying under the radar of some
herbal supplement [ __ ] with some
nice you know you know whizbang
marketing it's snake oil for Christ
sakes they I mean again they say I don't
know it improves your memory they say a
key ingredient is derived from jellyfish
you know so it's interesting I don't
know just wondering you know stick to
Lion's
man yeah I'm sure if you send Sam some
Bitcoin he'll get you some yeah but what
about my Beaver anus I love my Beaver
anus I want I'm really
fascinated I'm I'm really fascinated too
with kind of uh um and you know and I'm
curious to Sam if you have any thoughts
on just uh you know cuz you know a lot
of in medicinal mushrooms like um you
know cabs chaga all the different you
know kind of medicinal mushrooms it
seems like there's TR they're TR Turpin
that are some of the major compounds
behind their medicinal values and so so
just this future of uh combining these
triterpenes with cannabinoids you know
and and you know whether you know there
might be some interesting unique kind of
you know shifting of you know the way
that cannabinoids or these tropin are
binding the or having effects on the
system um are you asking me that what
you what what you think about that is
that yes he is and you better have the
answer I hardly know what to say because
uh I never did any real science on you
know mushrooms cannabis together other
than you know personally enjoying both
but uh I I I really don't know what to
say well I'll go back to the
found in mushrooms whereas I've studied
them extensively we'll send you the
paper that Josh shared last hash Church
which is I downloaded that paper did did
you check it out no I didn't read it to
be honest want paper check it out I
think it'll pull you in it's called
traversing the fungal
terpenome I'd love to send it to you as
well
Alec it's a good one I again another
thing that I think the hippie and
Grateful Dead culture got right
psychedelics is uh a way to deliver your
mind uh from the oppression of what's
going on in your life and uh it's useful
for uh all kinds of folks that I know
who started going down and doing the
iasa down in South America who claimed
that it basically saved their lives that
they would not be alive today if they
didn't go down there two or three times
a year and have this experience and the
other thing I wanted to say is that man
isn't it just great to see kind of
psychedelics follow in the wake of
cannabis when you look at you know
policies that are being opened up and
say like Oregon and Denver where now you
start basically saying okay you know
what yeah everything's going to turn
into a big parking lot at a Grateful
Dead show I mean it it just it goes to
show you again you know I I don't know
if there is uh you know an equivalent to
like religion or what replaced religion
for a lot of people in their life but
whatever that experience was that
delivered them and the dudes who were
psyched all week they were going to see
The Grateful Dead Friday and they had a
bag of shrooms and then they ate those
shrooms and then Garcia and the boys
came on that was like a moment for that
guy you know well that was the Rapture
that was that was the true experience
the rapure that that was the Rapture no
Fai required right right that delivered
that
indiv go ahead Alec I so much love and
appreciate appreciate where this is
going um so for one there's a book that
you should check out if you haven't it's
called is it the the immortality key
immortality key yep immortality key it's
about yeah yeah 100% same page yeah yeah
it's about the the root of so much uh
religion kind it's exactly what I was
thinking [ __ ] mindblowing yeah that's
awesome and and and uh and because the
other part I've you know especially over
this last year in 2020 is just such a
crazy heavy year you know so you know
the fear is thick you know and the
mental Corona virus is like
[Music]
over so um and I so you know everybody's
been freaking out like we're in the
apocalypse right and if you if you look
at the definition of the word apocalypse
it's the time of Revelation or the great
unveiling and and on that idea time of
re of G veiling it kind of feels like
we're in that right now you know it
feels like and and and and Mark I love
what you're were talking about with
cannabis and you know because I feel
like cannabis and hemp are the leading
Horsemen of this Apocalypse in a way you
know that are charging and kind of
leading this way you know you know
providing this great plant that's
helping to alleviate suffering and
provide empowerment and kind of and all
the all the tools for the you know new
economy and and Green Revolution that's
to come you know with this plant and and
you know and so I feel like it's helping
us with to gain Clarity in this time of
Revelation and and the way it's leading
the path for these other plants and
entheogens and ancient medicines to have
their way forward and through this
pathway you know I feel like are you
know they're the other horsemen of this
apocalypse this giant full circle I mean
when Mark said it's like we're all
instead of you know instead basically
the story of the immortality key and and
that shell is that there was this
unknown unnamed religion that had to
have had something major going on in it
because it wasn't about faith it was
more like this ancient Greek methodology
of thinking and Sciences and physics and
yeah the yeah the yeah exactly and that
Elixir that they were drinking and then
him having to go to Barcelona to find
proof that there was
erotized uh grain that was made into
this Elixir and just really incredible
story and then you got your Palo
Christians and they come along and they
kind of remove all these sacraments
replace it with the blood of of Christ
and the bread ritual which is very just
all of a sudden there's no Rapture
there's no experience it's all faith and
you're just sitting there talking to the
priest who controls it all and you can
kind of see how we're coming out of that
after so many Millennium really you know
like coming out of that experience
getting back and cannabis is of course
you know the leading uh Horseman like
you mentioned and and psych cannabis you
have okay we can take care of you know
it's very much reminiscent to me of the
bag ofa's and the way they look at yoga
for the body and meditation for the mind
you've got cannabis really I I'm sure
you can say it's for the mind and body
but then you have the psychedelics that
are for now you know outside that five
cense prison you know Spirit exactly
like completely removed from goad Alec a
question I have so as psychedelics
become less regulated and more prevent
in kind of recreational ways are are
Labs like SC are you guys doing testing
of psychedelics or are are is is there
testing of psychedelics or what what
would that look like I mean is that
again an industry that has to kind of
parallel the developing of psychedelic
products or mushrooms or whatever you
know people are going to be ingesting or
eating totally yes so um so so real
quick before that um just to to wrap
that other thought too you know because
on the like immortality key and
everything you know I'm really
fascinated by this new kind of field of
archo chemistry you know where they're
kind of scraping the insides of these
ancient found kind of you know artifacts
you know of like chalice and um and also
of H like you know the the kipe which is
a tool that you administer you know this
these South American Brazilian Amazon
kind of powders you know uh through your
through your nasal cavity right um you
know there you know they found one in
Chile you scraped it did some aroch
chemistry on it and found five Meo ndmt
bantine which you know essentially you
know
and the the tool carbonated like 7,000
years ago and so essentially it's
predating kind of the use of this tool
to administer YOLO or Vila which are two
kind of uh you know really powerful
Spirit medicines you know through your
through your nasal cavity to your nose
you know and so and and it's just
fascinating how deep it's going you know
kind of and all the compounds they're
finding but but to your to your point in
question on on testing you know I'm
really excited about you know CU with
right now you know it's it's you know I
mean prop 215 set you know in California
set for where Labs could you know had
legal abil or had had had at least state
Proposition of coverage to be able to
take you know these federally illegal
schedule one substances you know and you
know order analytical reference
standards and begin testing so there was
a little bit of coverage like right now
there's no coverage right so you know
all the compounds you know that we're
talking about that are coming to be
liberalized or legalized are all
currently still ferally one Controlled
Substances you know complicates matters
right you can't you have to have
standards for it like I said
and it's like all those compounds unlike
the canabo I believe all these compounds
are water soluble um there uh you don't
necessarily have to have oil oil
solubility but the nice thing is that if
they're def phenethylamines they have a
nice chromophor so they're good
candidates for hlc detection and again I
have like no clue like maybe you guys
know or maybe just throw up for
discussion like when we look at cannabis
like this beautiful picture of the hash
Church variety we're looking at we see
something that's got like 20% canono on
that on that flower material what what's
the percentage of uh of psilocybin on
mushrooms does anyone know I mean is it
like 5% 10%
well well so and so and so and that that
kind of leads to finish that thought
though because because I think that's I
mean there's a lot to that you know to
be discovered just like kind of was
happen avonoids in testing cannabis
whenever that kind of came to be but in
Oregon measure 109 passed which is which
legalizes cybin and now um now the the
state has the next year and a half or
two to develop uh licensing and
regulation for for for licensed and
legalized cybin and so there's going to
be three LIC includ analytical testing
standards yeah there there's three
production this is how you make it and
this is how you that produ well yeah
yeah totally totally well there so
there's there's a there's a cultivation
license there's a therapy center
therapist license and then there's an
analytical Testing Lab license and so
and the and this and this and the the
organ Health authorities going to be the
ones regulating and Licensing the
testing labs and we're already regulated
by the organ health to the highest of
degree for cannabis and up in you know
for we have a lap up in Tiger just south
of Portland and so we're really excited
because we're we're hoping that that
kind of gives us just a bit of a shoe in
to be able to do start doing that
testing because we have a group that
we're we're going to be working with
that has over 120 unique psilocybin
geographical discerned varidol that
they're looking to have us begin to like
develop testing to identify the MCO
characterize or whatever to Cho you know
the chemotype of all these different
mushrooms so I'm really excited to see
how that comes about but until then you
know kind of then you have to have da
schedule one license would't it be
interesting when you walk in you walk
into the dispensary or the the mushroom
dispensary or whatever the hell it is
someday and people are buying based on
hey that's got 20% this has got 15
that's got 20 oh you know and the kovar
the kovar oh this one's got Bist and nor
Bist I'm grabbing these yes exactly I
was just about you just finished my
sentence I was just going to bring up
nor nor noris or noros yeah yeah but
there's and then there's certain varials
and have kind of their own maois in them
and so it'll be really interesting to
see where that goes but ultimately one
of my biggest passions in life is around
ethnobot and and the Ooty and um and to
be able to build off of what we've
learned and been able you know because
cannabis you know for what it's worth
represents probably one of the most
difficult matrices that analytical
chemistry has ever had to approach or
test you know and so to be able to have
learned um you know and so it's an
incredibly difficult process to learn
and to actually get right because of how
much you know 30% resin content up to
that you know gunks up all part of the
hlc's gc's mass effects and so to be
able to develop methods to resolve that
Matrix so that you can do the testing
accurately and repeatedly is is such an
Endeavor and you know I think those labs
that have
that that do the work and learn how to
how to operate on such level are going
to be some of the highest performing
analytical labs in the world you know
because I mean it's we're not you know
testing dirt testing water Sol you know
a lot of water Sol they're relatively
straightforward but you know cannabis is
just presented this very difficult to
challenge to analytical chemistry but
but from there you know being able to
learn and ultimately test all these
other coming you know incredibly
important plant compounds you know is
one of my excitements and passions for
you know where where I'm going
personally so Alec then when I when I
start the traversing the fungal
terpenome live show on my channel here
which is going to be a similar one to
hasur you're in right yeah yeah all in
all in thank you so much that that's
such a beautiful beautiful that's such a
beautiful name of the paper too and I I
appreciate that turning me
on for sure yeah absolutely Dr isn't
that just funny that you know again not
to go back to the Grateful Dead but so
as a Young dead head you would have your
shrooms and you have your bag of weed
right so in a way they kind of
knew ABS knew right they totally knew
what are you talking about forget about
kind of was like 100% are you kidding me
so you know one thing takes you one way
and another thing takes you completely
in a different direction I will mention
again because I I love saying traversing
the fungal terpenome it's just just
awesome but I did start a Facebook group
called traversing the fungal turpino and
we've been sharing all sorts of edible
mushrooms and psychedelic mushrooms and
identification tips and tricks and
stories and books and it's actually
becoming a pretty cool little community
so if you are on Facebook um if you're
not and you hate Facebook I don't need
to hear about it it's all good um but if
you are join the group check us out
we're uh we're in there and it'll be the
same name of the show uh when I hope
hopefully get it together so I'll try to
send out an email here soon to Alec and
Dr Mark and a few other people I've been
thinking about for this particular show
it's going to have some different people
on it for sure and we'll be talking
about uh you know not just mushrooms but
uh you know a variety of the Psychedelic
uh plants and and fungi that we yeah
Colin I got your comment last week you
know on hash Church you were like oh I
wish Mark was here because he lives near
kenet yeah you're near kenet and uh yeah
also was read you know I'm a I'm a big
fan of of you know of psychedelics and I
was reading about you know um f mayo and
the Frog and hunting hunting frogs just
from you know it's it's fascinating how
the work that was left behind led to
synthesizing that
and um perhaps we can get a couple
friends of mine to come on and talk
about about
that um as well as as you know so what
are your thoughts what what are your
thoughts on on that is you think that
area is going to get reinvigorated
again well uh you mean in fungus
yeah
well F fungus is so fungi is so diverse
they have their own goddamn Kingdom for
Christ sakes right I mean they're their
own [ __ ] thing dude they're just like
yeah they figured out how to make very
complex molecules and everything from
yeast to uh what filous fungi I probably
just said that wrong but you know the
fungi that are in our guts the fungi
that are behind Marcus my family in uh
Upstate New York uh used to be Avid
hunters and Seekers of the so-called Hen
of the Woods which is sort of
domesticated here down in kenet square
Phillips calls it the Mitaki mushrooms
which they grow on um on towers that are
made I think of a PVC pipe and they have
some kind of meshing where the nutrient
around it and the flower bodies are kind
of growing radially from the nutrients
that flow through this thing and um they
they really only get to only so big when
they're uh when they're grown
commercially but when you find those in
the wild those things could be as big as
the trunk of a Volkswagen I mean I've
seen these mushrooms be so huge and
they're delicious they're wonderful
pickled they're great just in any
mushroom recipe you know whether you're
making soups or whatever you do with
mushrooms I mean it's a wonderfully
edible mushroom and of the woods I like
to gobble them gobble gobble
there's a couple restaurants of noted
Variety in Vermont called Hen of the
Woods and there are five-star
restaurants that are absolutely worth
going to so if you're ever in Vermont in
Waterberry go to The Hen of the Woods
It's a Wonderful restaurant sweet I'll
check that out listen I I wanna oh go
ahead I was gonna add one one thing
about psychedelics Mark and you'll love
this is that you know again if you go
like the fish tour where fish tour kind
of got kind of crazy is when people
started doing powders and like MDMA and
all other [ __ ] kind of came in there and
to me it's like the TR right all that
other crap kind of like was this
toxicity in the scene that was now we're
using the word toxicity to mean toxic
and to me it's like the only true thing
the only true thing was was mushrooms
and you know LSD if it was good LSD now
that's big if but you know but to me I
we stayed away from everything else
because I just saw that tear people up
and make idiots out of people and
eventually lead to people who are no
longer here and change the vibe of the
whole scene like it really did Chang the
vibe when I showed up accidentally you
were going right Mark right I mean I I
showed up in 93 and it felt like it was
still pretty legit it felt like this is
yeah it felt pretty OG it seemed like it
was around I don't know maybe 97 or yeah
maybe even 99 there was a little bit of
it in 97 on the East Coast but yeah it
is what it is they they made it through
they're still alive they're rock stars
they had to have some stories but it was
it was heavy for sure the whole powdered
drug thing seemed unnecessary but uh you
always have a
choice terrible humans love white
powders I don't know what it is well
humans love seems as though you know not
to get too heavy into it but you know if
we can agree on that it's likely that we
came from some somewhere maybe a source
maybe we were all one energy and we're
going all to this one energy and this
particular experience is a splintered
fractured ego version that you get to be
you and you get to do whatever you want
and you don't have you're not a part of
everything yet you kind of are but you
get to make mistakes and you get to make
bad choices and some people are here to
make bad choices they want to make lots
of bad choices and guess what that's
that's the freedom of life right there
they get to do that if that's so what
they choose to do other people we try to
make good choices and we end up making
some bad choices along the way so it all
seems to be a challenge around every
corner it's like should I eat the
mushroom or should I snort the cocaine
and I mean metaphorically because I'm
not a big cocaine snorter at all but
metaphorically there's always those two
options it's kind of like should I make
take this Choice over here or should I
take this Choice over here and they all
tend to lead us to one place where we
all get to end up which is 6 feet in the
ground uh unless you're getting like
Prince you know we gonna die what what a
shame again that that he had a doctor
who was feeding him with all that toxic
[ __ ] and as talented as Prince was and
it it's terrible to lose someone and now
to just have his musical Legacy around
but you know just um yeah we've all lost
loved ones to substance abuse and it's
it's just it's terrible and you'd think
man if they just would have ate some
mushrooms and smoke some weed they'd
still be here well you know and and I I
really appreciate both those those those
those two thoughts you know um I feel
like I've been on a mission kind of uh
especially you know kind of doing as
much work as I've been doing over the
last decade with with other plant
ceremonies medicine work kind of iasa
etc etc um you I feel I'm on a mission
to help uh my friends learn how to do
better drugs you know and and and and
and to be you know I feel like we have
an obligation in this life to be
spiritual forklifts for each other and
and I feel like there's a lot of really
like basic like low vibration you know
Vibes that are just overly consumed and
leveraged you know by some of you know
our closest friends and family you know
and so to be able to help you know in
that way educate and like live by
example you know of how much they've
benefited us I feel like we can
hopefully help kind of you know that
hundredth monkey effect of you know
getting off the bed and onto the real
medicines that are actually quite
fascinating my my my wife and I we with
a couple other couples and we had
dropped some acid and we were sitting at
this one outdoor uh restaurant we were
just laughing up a storm we were just
having such a great time we were having
such a great time that the table next to
us said we want whatever they're
drinking so I mean yeah I mean I I think
it kind of like it radiates people know
they're like those people are extra
happy that's when you bring them a tiny
you bring them a tiny tiny little shot
glass and you're like here you go
they're like what the hell is this it's
like it's about 250 milligrams uh here
you
go
yes well listen it was a great
conversation today I completely enjoyed
it I did want to finish up one thing
which Alex just meant in regards to we
need to be spiritual
forklifts um for each other and I think
that is a very good um term I really
like it and what I wanted to mention
about that was you know I've been
following this guy on YouTube for a
while even wait for quite a while now
he's a rapper freestyle guy I've
mentioned him a few him a few times
Harry Mack is his name he used to rap on
Venice Beach and he was at one of the
High Time Cannabis cups and uh he's got
a video out right now on his channel
it's called making an emotional
connection through freestyle it's from
two days ago I'll share it in the chat I
would definitely implore everyone to go
see that because man what he does in
that video is he is he becomes a
spiritual forklift for the guy right at
the end so this this heavy set guy comes
in at the end he's kind of he seems
pretty drunk and he's kind of happy but
he's really sad at the same time and the
way Harry connects with them and
freestyles about what this guy's going
through from having a two-minute
conversation with him is absolutely
phenomenal it'll definitely bring a tear
to your eye and I thought what a great
way to end the Sunday show uh with that
if I thought it wouldn't breach um a
copyright law I would sh I would share
it right here and now but I wouldn't
want to take the chance to lose this
episode of hash church because it's been
such a great one I want to thank
everyone for coming out superly
appreciate all the panelists who really
offer up their time uh to come on here
share and talk and create a dialogue uh
and to me that's uh that's you know a
level of Consciousness that I want to be
around I appreciate each and every one
of you guys and gals and of course uh we
we love and appreciate all the people
who spend their Sunday mornings watching
us the usually four to 500 of you that
watch live that are in the chat holding
it down we really appreciate all of you
guys couldn't do it without you that is
a fact and uh I'm going to try and do
another hash church next Sunday going to
put the invites out see if we can't get
back uh just you know continuing along
this vein of conversation uh and you
will see the new hash uh the mushroom
show the traversing the fungal terpenome
come out here in the next month or so
just give me some time on that so
awesome that everyone came and showed up
thank you all so much may the full melt
bless your bowl sooner than later hash
Church 3.0 episode 13 we're out peace
Everybody by everybody
take care thanks Mark that's what's up