all right here we go welcome welcome
everybody so we have just started
the The Stream I'm going to go over to
the old stream and let them know that we
are now
live that should do it and now let's let
the people in from the waiting
room oh thanks everyone for joining us
today hash Church 4.0 episode
three uh pretty darn excited about it
actually got to give a shout out to Josh
and Kelly for reaching out to me the
other day and saying let's do a hash
church we got all these incredible
people that want to share their
information uh I want to thank everyone
for being very patient and sitting in
the room for the last 10 minutes
Alexandra Rio Gardens dragonfly Earth
medicine uh Duke diamond in the house
thank you all for your patience it's
been a while since I ran a hash Church
got my little buddy The Lorax here
taking care of business with me so uh
all is good and welcome all you
beautiful smiling faces we are Live on
YouTube nice good morning family good
morning family is so awesome to see
everybody Duke beautiful beautiful to
see you especially nice to see you dude
because it's been so long yeah top of
the morning to y'all and it's really
good seeing your smelling faces too yall
are always just so happy and just
awesome you too Mr Bubble man ain't seen
you in a hot minute as well you have an
H to day it's been too long well I'm I'm
growing my Gray beard so it makes me
feel more
distinguished yeah wise you get the wise
look like you could do some wizard
wizard stuff or something
and Alexandra how are you this morning I
love your beautiful background
yeah yay can you tell us about that
design the Earth right behind me yeah
it's a it's a cosr that is connected
directly to the creative healing energy
of the Earth so I thought it's
appropriate beautiful I love it and Rio
it's nice to see you in your Greenhouse
right now how's the weather there and
how's it going I know you've already
been starting planting it's nice to see
you yes we're up here at the farm today
we got our Wi-Fi set up and Katie's here
with me
awesome um yeah it's lovely the
weather's been uh beautiful but it was
like eight there was a 50 degre swing
days ago it was 35 at night and then 85
in the daytime so
ends 20 degrees so kind of caught us off
guard definitely yeah so oh [ __ ] I
thought it was a cancer moon yesterday
and we were supposed to
plant people are showing up Tina are La
La Gardens how are you
today doing just wonderful it's a it's
warm it's it's going to be a windy cold
day uh compared to yesterday's 70
degrees so yeah these swings are
everywhere it would be really nice for
everybody to say where about they're
from because we're all a Dem pure panel
all of us are farmers from all over the
place so uh Rio you're in you're in
California and then laa and in the
beautiful Southern homeb bio you can all
this is my co-conspirator and girlfriend
and plan hey Katie expert Katie
um and we've been
uh been I've been here off and on since
I was seven but uh 10 years on this farm
and we're we're kind of we're like 1,800
feet so it's a really beautiful
appalation for
sativas
which this is Highland W Haw and gold
Katie was gonna showcase we love our you
know unique and fun strains to grow up
here
so yeah it's a beautiful
paradise we had some fun with your
African orange I believe I believe that
was your maybe it was it was it was it
was Joy's but crossed it with but we
also had some shash shamani did we had I
feel we had some Africans shash shamani
and one other one from you I believe and
I forget the African
lady yeah Africa yeah that's that is a
shash shamani with cherry pie that's
right and been poison right is that
correct G der been poison as well oh
there was another one with
and der poison yeah yeah yeah yeah this
highland ww and gold is our favorite
this year though this
is fun love to smoke that we have some
seeds from Waka or
from colia from the 60s
that gave us that we haven't
[Music]
tried be cool for
us those like germinated and grown
especially in one of your areas we talk
about that later but yeah for sure so
Lala where are you in Colorado what area
are you it's your Appalachia she's maybe
Frozen or where Frozen she might be
frozen my
back yep you're back yeah Colorado but
um basically a cash pter um River that's
um the river that feeds this entire
area and are you guys starting to have
some um bulbs and stuff come up are
there any tree tips starting to bloom
yet or you still getting some snow yeah
the Aspen's just coming out a little bit
and the Leaf tips are starting to show
but yeah things are a little slower this
spring than they were last year we had a
later winter and then even though we've
had fluctuations it's been a slow spring
so I don't feel too behind fantastic
Alexandra where are you at what's your
appala what's going on in your Gardens
uh I am in Vancouver Island or on
Vancouver Island
and yeah my bulbs are all up uh but we
also have a really late spring and wet
very very wet what comes out it's happy
to come out and then it gets like uh
smashy
moldy but
um yeah so we also have a really cold
winter a little bit Frost here and there
which is
absolutely uh not acceptable but we take
it yeah can you do it's like last year
actually we had a really cold uh spring
as well and really really cold winter
for our Regent and um I'm going to the
garden and see what has died or not
coming back so that's for me that's the
first thing I'm going around and see all
my babies who comes back welcome them
and not it really hurts in the heart but
um what can you do it makes room for
something new I mean um then it goes out
and it gets replaced with something else
it's like okay you didn't do well anyway
out of the
pool so no uh we we starting to get more
more green here but so wet so much water
so much
water that's a blessing when you're from
California because it's a terrible
drought over there and stuff so well I
think in in quality in quantity right
one of the good stuff can always be
bad exactly and Duke where are you from
and what's going on in your Gardens and
I know that you're planting some indoor
stuff as well as some outdoor love to
hear what's going on oh man um so I'm uh
back in
Colorado um down southern part of the
state like St Louis Valley area um
weather's pretty cool it's like been
warming up and everything so lots of
sunshine and warmth so I like that and
then uh yeah getting cranking on the
setting up the
indoor literally you know starting from
scratch so we got uh got the lights
going up and everything got the veg
already kind of kicking clones coming
back in you know little by little and uh
man just really really happy and uh
appreciate y'all so much cuz uh you know
what them babies going to be eating
on definitely some dragonfly Earth
medicine now what are some of the
strains that you're going to be really
excited to get back into because
everyone's so stoked about Dominion
seeds and and Duke diamond seeds and the
skunks and all the stuff that you've
created over the years huge UPS to you
for keeping it real for the family and
the team just curious to hear what your
some of your thoughts are on the new
varials well uh some of the the the new
varieties you know how I am I keep it
like real hush until you know it's it's
that time there's a lot of you know uh
I'm in church and I don't want to curse
so uh you know there's a lot of scamming
people out there you know so they
they're looking to rip you off
so and stinky you
know that's what's up and I'll just I'll
just shout you out one more time when we
at the emerald cup and you had your
booth and the inside there you had
definitely some of the most like
ridiculous smelling weed at the show so
I was it was amazing you know smelling
it everyone has good ganja so it's not
about that some of the stuff he had was
insane but it is it is it is true to
know that when you're at the emerald cup
and then there's one person's pocket
that stands out amongst everybody else's
it really was Duke so I got to say he
was the one I could smell out of
everybody at the Emerald cup so Duke I'm
just we've been running your varietal
now ever since then and uh we've been
doing some crosses and some really great
stuff with your stuff so we cannot wait
to get it back to you we're really
excited y'all are first on the list get
some of this uh
new you grow this stuff I'm like man
organic slow dragonfly inputs I remember
when y met you like you GW this with red
fla too I was like oh yeah that's all I
eat and you have some special
fermentation concoctions that we know
about over the years too so pretty cool
oh yeah and it's definitely a love for
the plant and an energy so any of y'all
out there who know this man he's just
one of the kindest souls and totally
dedicated to the plant as so many of us
are here that's why we're growing the
fire and I definitely say that about Rio
Rio when I came out from everybody that
sha shamani when we came out to your
farm and we did that late night uh you
guys were trimming and all the smells of
those incredible long flowering sativas
are just like I remember that night weed
still growing in January I mean that
never happens and H up here so you know
that's amazing bubble man what's
happening in on your land I know you
grew a lot of flowers and stuff last
year I'm we got to get you some flowers
we were lame last year but anyway for
you this year what's happening for you
this year
well we just had 75 centimeters of snow
fall on Whistler Mountain about four or
five days ago so uh am I
Frozen no we hear 75 cm 75 centimeters
fell yeah so like uh um I'm in the same
boat there's lots of water coming down
the mountain right now it's pretty
intense all my bulbs are up for sure we
have an acre here in Lion's Bay so we
have uh we have a pretty incredible
garden with all sorts of different wild
flowers and Edibles and and things like
that so yeah excited to uh see how the
season
goes not sure if I'm frozen
again sounds about
right in the northern Michigan
Appalachia and it's
basically lots of Lakes lots of water
it's all glacial tilt and uh they're
called Kettle holes so it's
basically um you know the glaciers
receding and scratching the Earth
leaving behind uh a bunch of lower areas
um so yeah I'm again on the same boat
with the the melting in the ton of water
um but the it seems like a lot of my
Mounds are kind of drying out faster the
sun's hitting them the water's kind of
pouring aside and there's some action
right at like you know the tip of those
points uh so it's going pretty well over
here awesome we've been seeing some
pictures and I know you're getting a lot
of seeds in and everything and you got
any uh favorite varieties that you're
putting in um I'm curious about I'm
running some stuff from turp Wizard
who's another Michigan uh organic farmer
and uh regen family I would say um so
I'm running a couple of his
varietal uh you know again stuff that I
saved from California from you know the
Swami days and everything like that from
hanging with Swami and all that um you
know but mostly I'm kind of open right
now I haven't really thought about
popping too much stuff because I'm a
little bit uh you know probably a month
out from that kind of time frame but uh
but yeah it's starting to come down the
pipeline and you traditionally did I say
traditional but like all you like to do
on your land uh start them a little
later and and have like a smaller depth
in the back SA correct are you gonna do
that again this year yep I do well I try
to dry farm so I don't irrigate my stuff
up there at all it's all rain waterer um
so I set up my hoop I plant small plants
a little bit later um into Hogle H they
holes I dig a hole and then bury a bunch
of carbon and plant inside there U and
that seems to hold enough water to keep
the plants happy throughout the year
they're small easy to manage and I don't
end up covering them until super late
into the season mostly just to keep the
rain off of like the finishing nugs um
so uh but this year I might try to do a
little bit different supplement with
extra water uh to try to get slightly
larger plants um yeah thanks but we'll
see how it goes nice when it's always it
seems like the whole state of Michigan
could be a dry Farm State because the
whole there so much water all around
easily yeah oh easily for sure and I
mean you know it's just it's one of
those things where it's as soon as you
kind of find out about it um you know
this was or three seasons ago was my
first season kind of doing hul cannabis
cultivation and it's it's remarkable how
well that works here specifically in
catching all that water and you know I
would walk up to my hoop houses past the
orchard everything's raging I turn the
corner thinking that they'd like you
know some water and and they just never
really asked for it so I was like fine
serious I'll tell a story later because
we're going to introduce people about
that but that's pretty amazing what what
water retention can happen in the hug
give thanks to
Noble and Tamara and the family and the
children and Sierra and everyone there
on the farm down making things happen on
the regen Camp so yall tell us where
you're from and what's going on there
what's your Appalachia tell us you go
ahead on all right well we're in Lake
County um in California
and
down we got little
[Music]
Emy yeah um down here it's really hot
like we are each like the last three
years I've started noticing it's just
gotten hotter and hotter where I've
started having to grow like in desert
conditions and because it just gets so
hot in the summer and um this last year
I planted a month like two behind when I
was like usually on my target goal
whereas like by the end of May all my
veggies and all my medicinals are in and
stuff it was too late it was so hot this
past year we're just kind of having to
speed up a lot of our planting and um
learning how to like really go
underneath
trees and any kind of shade that we can
do and creating more natural shade so
that's kind of like our appalation now
and we're excited to work with like um a
lot more sativas as well because we know
we can do those long term those you know
long flowering plants out here and um
I've had them go
until I think the longest one I ever mid
January and I finally cut it but it was
more rainy in that time and now we don't
have some of those rains so it's like
okay how do we adjust and I think we can
yeah we're going to try some more
long-term ones this year and uh but yeah
that's our that's our
appalation I'm just arriving here from
late as a lot of you guys know um we're
uh shutting down our farm up there in
lonville unfortunately due to you know
just Market
yeah we're regrouping yeah regrouping us
too because we've I've been in licensing
and trying to do this since 2016 when it
like first all like came about and I was
in talks with our County and this last
year I kind of had this like meltdown
cuz I was like I'm got TSD from thinking
about permits and Licensing and like I
just can't do it right now we when we're
going to do the hemp farm this year and
we just all decided you know what let's
just take a year and breathe and we're
building the medal Garden and we're
doing commercial herbs which we need for
the products for heal thyself Gardens
and uh we're excited about that she's uh
she's you know loves her coffee she's
you know the most intensive Barista you
know it's like hard to take her to
coffee shops because she's like you know
but she's amazing you know about like
the detail of like quality and making
sure the beans were you know sourced
properly and uh you know they're roasted
properly all those kind of things so she
had the idea of uh starting up a coffee
cart and we're going to do some trips
down Central and South America and go
and talk to some of these different
farms and do some sourcing and really
trying to help out some of these uh you
know more regenerative coffee farmers
and help push them in that Direction
maybe even do some Consulting and stuff
like that so we could be able to bring
back beans and start roasting here and
uh start setting up a a mobile coffee
truck a big 20 foot trailer with a big
deck on it and all kinds of reading
material and regenerative F push the
message of how important sourcing uh you
know products from the right people is
so uh yeah that's that's a whole new
mission that I think that she's going to
thrive at and you know so I've been
helping her out and we're getting that
going we have a buddy building a
beautiful trailer right now and uh and I
feel like we can integrate that with
like the events and really you know
plant that seed about true Organics you
know not just organic but true Organics
so and true
regenerative Styles which you know which
is great and we just had newly have a
regenerative pure pure farmer in
Argentina uh rod rod Rodrigo and all the
links to all the farmers are on demure
farms.com and we do keep that part uh up
to date but Rodrigo is really beautiful
and I just I just wanted yeah go ahead
yeah yeah I just wanted to say that here
we are you know cannabis Farmers we've
been playing these games we've been
playing a lot of papers we've been
pushing a tremendous amount of Licensing
we've been pushing a tremendous amount
of money you know there was a time when
Legacy farmers in California Oregon
Washington DC Colorado
Europe were able to feed their families
were able to keep Homestead were able to
put in crops every year and now through
legalization basically it's it's the
idea of legalization is to take out
those Legacy Farmers to take us out
right in front of our face and I and I
don't I don't want to you know sugarcoat
it or anything I don't want to make it
sound like oh well you know we've got
some place here and up here in in Canada
a lot of the micro Growers I know Shay
is going to be talking here he's on
Rosebud Farm talk about pushing papers
and everything that we're trying to do
for legalization up here but what we're
really starting to realize is that when
things become legalized with the federal
government When Things become legalized
with a province or a state that means
that it's more up for big corporate man
and the big corporate entity to take
over so the reason why Dem pure is Dem
pure is because we're here to support
each other we're all on the same page
with regenerative Community regenerative
values regenerative um you know uh
growing
practices and and here's a perfect
example it heal thyself and Noble and
Tamara Noble wasn't able to maybe keep
his farm and a lot of other people
aren't but we have this beautiful
connection of these people real people
real people in the world we're not just
marketing gimmicks you know we're the
actual blood behind you know the and a
lot of you all who are listening out
here on YouTube you're looking at the
faces of some Legacy Growers who have
been in this business for you know 30
plus years and counting and all of us
are have been bringing you all
what we're reaching out to you all and
consumers out there is to make sure to
be supporting these farms and these
Legacy Farms and and demure and people
that are getting out there and trying to
join together to continue the Legacy
Farm quality which is the quality is not
just in the flower the quality is in the
community and the quality is in the
education and then the quality is in the
kindness that we have and in the
reverence that we have to this plant and
this perfect segue Craig you've been
through so much having to do with all
this too let's hear from Craig where's
your app talk about your your beautiful
partner Melanie and the work that she's
been doing just you know we love you
alpen glow
Farms hey thank you good morning to
everybody and thank you Marcus for
opening up your house and sharing the
space with us yeah we sure appreciate
you and everything you've done to
support us through the process and um as
to where we are if you look between Rio
and Katie through that uh rectangle tall
window that is precisely where Katie is
pointing where my farm
is that mountain is called Reed mountain
and it is historically known locally as
weed Mountain it was it's one of the
taller Peaks right outside of
Garberville and has uh you know every
single one of those ridg lines has
Legacy historic Groves that have been up
there for you know 30 40 maybe even some
50 years uh you walk those ridg lines
you're going to find some water line
you're going to see some boards nailed
to trees where pots were grown in the
trees like it's it's pretty much ground
zero Southern humble you've got you know
Salmon Creek Reed mountain and some of
these other little uh micro communities
um but we are about 11 miles as a crow
flies from the
ocean and we are at the Confluence of
Two Rivers uh the South Fork of the eel
and the east branch of the South Fork uh
the Confluence is right there so we get
this really nice air exchange at least
twice a day um where the valleys will
pull in the ocean fog but we
and we kind of get this Oreo cookie
effect where we're the cream in the
middle because sometimes you know if
you're if you've been around mountains
at all they they get a little Cloud on
the peak too so it's really nice we get
a lot of beautiful sunrises and uh Rio's
Farm gets the beautiful sunset so we
have a nice little balance in our
ecosystem um but yeah we've been facing
a lot of challenges with uh legalization
and the county and over Taxation and and
uh that's where my partner Melanie has
been such a a rock and such a voice she
actually has a master's in communication
and has been delivering these amazing uh
three minute comments to the Board of
Supervisors and um just taking her
public speaking to really support the
the farmers and one of our last uh
rallies in front of the courthouse she
we delivered a very moving speech and we
were able to take our taxation from um
uh uh down 85% so we pay 15% of the tax
we did last year give you an idea so for
a farm of 10,000 square feet like ours
that went from 10,000
to legitimize our lives in in the in the
greater world right we we knew who we
were and we were legitimately conducting
good business and parts of our community
and um paying taxes um but but now with
legalization when it first happened at
least locally we were excited to pay for
our roads and pay for our schools
through that system we always did it on
a volunteer basis and we gave more than
our share and uh built schools and built
hospitals and did all
these F like it was just phenomenal like
and over overbearing and the way
California built out their supply chain
they built it such a fractured line so
no one could really participate in all
features and that fractured supply chain
is really part of the demise of the
entire California system you need a you
need a permit a separate permit to do
anything for me to drive a plant off my
property to move a plant from my light
depth to my full term that takes another
license like it's crazy so we're working
hard to push on that melan's been a big
help with all that and our entire
Community is is really working forward
to uh to with all that so I appreciate
everyone here today and you know
everyone has a unique skill and a unique
um strength and together we're really
able to pull something together that can
support each other so I appreciate you
all thank
you awesome Craig yeah you know I think
that inevitably we're going to get into
the conversation today on you know how
we can uh support each other a lot of
countries now are starting to come into
legalization they're going to be dealing
with a lot of this licensing they're
going to be looking at exactly what
we've been dealing with and they're
going to see the straight up takeover of
Legacy farmers of Legacy Growers as well
breeders so I feel like we can really be
offering them education forward on how
we can join together so that really
doesn't happen um and we're going to a
cannabis Summit in Colona um next
weekend I think it's next weekend and
it's going to be a really a policy type
Summit where we're going to be you know
creating
new laws and new verbage for maybe
creating a new license and just working
on the federal licensing up here in
Canada so I would say in Colona uh which
is in British Columbia for those of you
don't who don't know is a big cannabis
summer we're going to be speaking at and
involved in along with First Nations
groups from British Colombia
and Canada which they have the ability
to form their own laws which I think is
really powerful and so do they um just a
matter of education so these panels are
part of that education everyone talking
about what they're working on in their
jurisdiction uh you know big love to
Martin and Ireland there's people in
Ireland all over Europe having a lot of
you know hard times right now so we want
to big people up and make them feel like
they're on the right path and help you
know people know that you know there's
people behind you you know that that
that support you and then that really
leads us on to uh Shay you you're you're
you're fighting the good fight last
year's crop was totally unbelievable
Rose Bud Farms just becoming Dem pure
certified we're so excited love to hear
where you're at and your Appalachia and
a little bit about what's going on just
want to say also uh please mention
something about the Unicorn cup because
we're all super super stoked about the
Unicorn cup like Market on your calendar
is the Unicorn cups the bomb it is most
beautiful property ever go ahead sh is
our newest de pure farmer in British
Columbia in our area of the cies blessed
love thanks guys thanks for that nice
introduction a lot of love much love for
everybody on this panel I appreciate the
invite for the opportunity to learn from
a lot of you guys over the years so it's
pretty cool to be sitting here next to
you yeah we're um
regenerative cannabis producers near
Nelson not too far from arenta where you
guys are we're LP or a standard we're
probably the smallest standard is really
but here with a really small canopy for
micro it's 200 meters it's extremely
hard to be profitable at those numbers
so we felt we had not much choice but to
go LP or
standard yeah Rose Bud Lake as you
mentioned that's where we are we're this
magical beautiful
ecosystem sort of a Wildlife Reserve on
one side and uh Crown Land
surrounding it's a real Wildlife
corridor beautiful everything from loons
and Eagles and wolves and all that sort
of stuff so it's really balanced really
diversity healthy ecosystem so what a
great place to do regenerative cannabis
production I think if a synthetic
operation moved in here it would really
have a negative imp
than weed and Community mixed with music
and celebration we're just kind of like
up in the level of
Awesomeness it's August 13th to 14th uh
12 to 15th actually those are the main
days we got a whole bunch of really cool
artists coming uh some pretty big
Headliners that I can't quite tell you
about yet but uh I'm really excited for
you to to hear about them do a mix of
electronic music but not just that we
have like acoustic and vocal and a lot
of other
things um yeah we're really expanding
this year 500 people expected the judges
um we do a comparison there is not a
clear permit yet for a straightforward
Cannabis Cup in Canada yet so what we do
is a educational event and part of that
educational event is a cannabis
comparison where we'll rate cannabis and
have U people in the know like Kevin jod
and Josh and Kelly educate the consumer
humors on what makes good cannabis good
cannabis and then we just have a great
time a great party awesome camping all
on the lake it's a really really epic
thing so I hope to I hope to see
everybody there that can make it across
the border that is and if you're local
we hope to get you there
too yeah that's spectacular and I and
you know you're just in such a a a raw
mountainous area and really it's the the
beauty of just developing a new space
and creating you know what we want to
see or what you know the land is working
with is really exciting and and I love
the the wildness of it to where you
don't have like people breathing down
your neck you can really like express
yourself and and and I love that you
know and and take a morning dip in the
pond you know that Lake there it's it's
not a pond it's a lake and it is just so
amazing to be able to go to a festival
and have a beautiful Lake that you can
just dive into and we're really going to
be working on a whole Zone uh at unicorn
cup that's going to be a regenerative
Dem pure camping area zone and we're
going to be having just campfire
sessions going and education from demure
Farmers pretty you know morning break
for co cocoa and splits and and Bong
Hits and all of that until late into the
night and last year we had an incredible
time sh you really put on something
amazing for us and it was sort of the
last time that we had been social with
people so we've been holding it close to
our hearts and lots of demonstrations
everything for wild crafting to building
you know Forest Gardens to washing hash
to freeze drying to tinctures to
topicals like what how do you want to S
survive it's it's it's a
self-reliant cannabis plant medicine
Festival everything goes we're trying to
create an
open atmosphere one of the most
oppressive socities on Earth we live in
one of the most oppressive societies on
Earth
crazy but we're free because we live in
the mountains and we live on the land
that's the message consider moving out
to the country living on the land or
working on a community garden in the
city or a lot in your suburb or an area
where you can connect to the Earth
because that's where you're going to
have some some buffer from Madness and
it's also your point of health or if all
you can do is work and you can't do that
and you're really caught up in this
system and you're on a whole another
path you can go and spend all of your
money at the farmers markets where all
of those people are doing regenerative
stuff so then that is you supporting it
so whether you are planting your own
regenerative Garden or you're supporting
other regenerative Farmers you're still
part of the regenerative movement it
start starts from the very beginning so
and I guess you know here we are Tara
Lee here you you know it would be great
you've been starting your backyard
garden we've been talking to you a
little bit and uh love to know your
Appalachia and sort of what kind of
things have been going on you know in
your backyard and and in your Zone and
area what are you gonna put in this year
good morning everyone hello Josh Kelly
thanks for the invite today um has
Church hello everyone thanks for being
here my Appalachia I am in uh Washington
State Grand County area right in the
center of the state and we are in like a
dry Highland desert area and if it
wasn't for like the grand [ __ ] Dam and
all that this whole area would be like
serious drought like we wouldn't have
the A and the development that we have
here so we're lucky for the irrigation
that we have um but the Hugo culture
thing and being able to seek and doing
all of that stuff and being able to save
the water and all that I think that's
going to be an amazing um thing to be
able to add to this appalation area I
would say um I don't know I'm super
nervous today I need to dab my
gosh can can I just can I just say can I
just publicly announce my love for tery
right here
thanks everyone who doesn't know about
tar she is a people's person she has an
amazing YouTube page
and she
really blessing and so she lives every
day in that Spirit of being thankful for
life and and also been really up uh you
know talking up Community Gardens with
community making it really easy for
people to tackle a yard that only has
grass on it even if it's a 10 by 10 a
two by two even if it's just a pot so
she's in it every day trying to really
educate people the ways on really easy
gardening so that when they pick that
tomato and it may be the one and only
tomato that they grew in their backyard
it may be the highlight day of their
entire life and that is what it's all
about and that's what this education
from demer Farmers also to be a Dem pure
Farmer part of the agreements that we
agree upon is not only to to to to live
our moral C in our regenerative
practices on our own but that we're
continuously educating people you know
even like I can Duke you know you you
even when you have been not able able to
be a voice your voice has been carrying
on to people there's been an incredible
voice of yours that has been lasting in
education and people being having pure
respect for the plant your name coming
up so many times because of that
resonant love and that resonant
education that you give so freely I mean
Alexandra the same thing you know Terry
you and Terry have been bringing an
incredible spirituality to this plant so
and it brings UC your page is incredibly
informative too I love the way that you
share your gardening story uh along with
everyone and your uh your approach to it
I feel is what I'm really attracted to
it's really beautiful and I we would
just wanted to roll into just some
really amazing regenerative tips whether
it be Community tips whether it be
gardening tips anything that you all
have been doing that have been really
Making Waves and Rio and Katie I'd love
to every can talk about themselves like
and let's just roll this out now that
we've introduced everybody I would just
love to hear what's really working for
everybody and anybody who's on chat who
wants to uh ask some questions let's do
this should we start yeah um I'll start
uh this with the market collapse I just
had this Epiphany moment that I was just
done
and for me it's like keeping up with the
Joneses I was always like one foot in
one camp like trying to keep the farm
alive and one foot in the
region ideas of just the whole intention
of this land was to build a permaculture
Oasis and use cannabis to fund it when
that funding just got harder and harder
I was like I give up [ __ ] it and I had
this moment that just after harvest it
was kind of a shitty Harvest last year
and I was like all right I'm just doing
what I most care about I'm done was
always and Katie came on board and uh we
had a plan we Sorry Mario M your can you
your microphone Mario real quick and
also Daniel and Mario will'll get to you
right after uh Rio love you keep so this
winter I spent the whole winter working
and we just we had a plan we developed a
plan together and she's really into
plants which she has the Deep you know
knowledge of plants and so that was an
asset for me because I'm you know still
learning um so I we landscaped and came
up with some plans for a new market
Garden Katie we filled in a pond that
was never very useful and so now we have
a big flat with Market bed and a whole
Hillside that's sted with food and fruit
and nuts and berries and all hles with
an old uh the Windstorm blew over a um
Live Oak so that one tree built like a
100 by 100 square foot area of hles so
we're just making it super spongy and
absorbent so anything that flows down
just catches and then we have a big
cannabis patch under there where we get
to do a lot of
fun sativas and things it's a great spot
the cover crop is really abundant and
she we developed a yeah a nut and a
berry Hogle like a a hedro yeah with
service berries and Lizzie Richard's
girlfriend is becoming Elderberry queen
of
humble with elderberries Craig Craig
just came over and got some yesterday
and we're doing Elder berries as an
alternative crop
and everyone's committed to the right
thing right now it's and we've been
mixing our own soil for the nursery mix
instead of bringing in bags this year we
borrowed a cement mixer from Craig and
um have just making cacus Coots recipe
for soil and uh using soil blockers so
we don't have to use plastic um
containers so we're just soil blocking
everything
and getting in the jadm and and ferments
Katie's got imo3 now we're about to get
the im4 going LA and inoculations I know
our soil's lacking in a little bit of
fungal bacterial activity so the cover
crop looks good now we're bringing in
the compost and building the and spin
chiaki logs from our friend Mike who's
the mushroom cultivator and so he's just
got you know bringing the dump trailer
it's amazing amazing he's so beautiful
compost give thanks to mushroom Mike as
always yeah he just keeps providing for
so many people and any of you all out
there who are listening getting a hold
of anybody organic mushroom cultivator
in your zone or area because mushroom
blocks are just amazing St mushroom
blocks are great for soil building the
only public service announcement on
mushroom blocks is uh you know make sure
that the substrate was organic when it
started right because mushrooms are
smart they're not going to you know they
yeah they have the power to transform
but really do you want to support like
non organic substrate no you don't so it
always encourage you know your uh
mushroom farmer to start with Organic
glyphosate is not just used in the
agriculture industry or the cut flow
industry it's uh in the forests and
they're killing berries like service
berries which I like to call sarvice
berries because my
sarice but the the or the Saskatoon
Berry if you're in Canada superfood but
anyway it's the huckleberries all these
berries that supposedly get in the way
of tree growth and I have you know this
thing like everyone's you know with
anyway there's a lot to that but so big
love to you guys on on diversifying
we've been doing soil blockers too but
I've been just digging up the soil out
of my garden and mixing a little compost
in it and just using garden soil for the
soil blockers yeah just really I want
the seed to wake up and know my garden
right away rather than some foreign you
know like made soil type thing that's
just our thought process on it so we're
just like seed wakes up radical root
comes out they're like
whoa aren't doing regenerative they're
indoor their underlights or something
and it might not have that type of
intelligence and truly our microbiology
just eats it alive it never really gets
the opportunity to sprout so another
reason why you want to be getting seeds
from breeders like a lot of these people
that you see on here because we're
growing it
regeneratively to to to have that Gusto
Lala what kind of uh things oh oh wait
we're gonna move down here just super
quick because Daniel came on and best
friend best friend Farm maybe Mario is
still there Mario not sure but uh Daniel
it's nice to see you Rock Mountain where
are you what's your Appalachia and what
what's the weather like how are your
baby your baby your children beautiful
children yeah yeah um turn my phone
off um I can you hear
me think might have yeah so I'm in
eastern Potter Valley in the middle
Mountain appalachi
um I'm almost to Lake County we're in in
Potter Valley and and even in our little
region here we're in a little banana
belt at like seven between 23 and 2500
feet you go down 500 feet and it's it's
colder you go up 500 feet is
colder
um yeah it's uh you know my dad settled
there kind of the end of the road and it
turned out to be like a nice little
micro climate for growing breeding camp
anab you
know we also can you know get stuff to
go in a hoop in January I harvest like
my last seed run I I start Auto flowers
in the fall and harvest them in like the
middle of winter and occasionally have
to run like a couple nights of heat when
it gets down to like 20 for a couple
nights but that's that's rare where
we're at um the babies are doing good
yeah number three I'm I'm definitely
sleep
I'm not drinking I just have three small
children you know because the brain it
it definitely doesn't work like I want
it to work and uh I lose a lot of things
there um yeah what a and this is yeah
glyat [ __ ] you know that's like the the
DDT of Our Generation I see it around
the valley all the time and to some of
these farmers
and to change their their their
ways she told me to mind my own business
and I said I am minding my own business
you're spraying poison where my children
play and she stopped you know and and
it's like these things like these people
who do it because it's easy wouldn't
they wouldn't like be putting a small
little Drop of Poison into the water or
their kids food but they will put it
onto their farms and it's wild that
disconnect there you know that and it's
just it's just a matter of time you know
before it's not being used but
but it's
crazy I would say it almost seems like
it's getting like more common if you if
that sounds like even possible but yeah
they just to this
whole maybe maybe because it's like a
household's kind of stopped doing in Cal
because it's B so it's got to go
somewhere else you know there you go
there that's what it is what are we G to
do with all these War chemicals oh I
don't know that's s them to Farmers yeah
let's put it in the food and I guess
since the gly has come up a couple of
times we really encourage anyone
listening out there to find out where
glyphosate's being sprayed know that
when they're roads spraying the sides of
the roads or train tracks near you
glyphosate is being sprayed um really
get educated on glyphosate because the
real problems with gut glyphosate is not
necessarily in your soil yes it's huge
because soil is the very beginnings of
life and it holds the very valuable
microbiology which holds you know
valuable life forms for plants to be
able to grow but also for our own
microbiome to be able to be healthy or
our genome and our genome and the these
type of chemicals actually attack our
DNA along with our
microbiology which changes way that our
health and well-being is defined well
you know now and into the future so we
would recommend
important in in the ADV
and that's not including daa and all the
other defoliant there there's thousand
things but glyphosate is the easiest one
to talk about but there's many of them
so our recommendation is when building
indoor gardens either ask the company
that you're getting those leafy products
from
a or text it yourself and that's going
to be the way that you know that you're
intelligent
Dynamic accumulating sentient being
ganja isn't sucking up that stuff into
its body and into the classic the head
of the Tricom where which is what we all
are looking for in some cases we want
the roots and the seeds and everything
but anyway Big Love and uh best friend
Farms Brian out in Maine what's
happening you're getting to introduce
yourself and then we're gonna find out
more Tech from the fam and your
Appalachia where you at
we can't you
there can you hear me
now can you hear me
now he I'm up in the Foothills okay
sorry I'm in the foothills of main I'm
at about 600 feet um nestled between the
Atlantic and the the White Mountains I
guess and and yeah so plenty full water
I think there's 14 like 14 or 15 lakes
and ponds in this town so it's kind of
you know a lot of Hills among water and
yeah we're just starting to open up with
the Snows all gone and we get really
good Sun here so I get great exposure
it's more of a South Southeast sweep I
think which is really good for Maine I
bring up too because of the uh the Frost
potential in the late season and the Dew
so if you get an earlier burnoff and
exposure to the sunrise Southeast side
of the Hill kind of thing here
so that's where I
sit and uh you're making really
incredible hash you know too and what
are some of the uh maybe some of the new
varietal you're excited for this
year yeah actually we're we're making
hash all the time and I'm just like uh
been constantly breeding to try to find
the best hash making plants so we're
we're focused on traditional form but
we're getting some pretty greasy good
air dried traditional stuff out there
and you know kind of following in the
ways of Frenchie with the same form and
enjoying it and then uh yeah I've been
doing a ton of breeding I just went back
to uh my gas mask clone mom with a with
a bunch of more like fruit forward
uh gas back stuff here so some cherry
chem and some pineapple fields for
additions to the gas mask and I actually
cracked some uh Dominion seeds I I see
Duke Diamond so I got a friend gifted me
some Dominion G and some local skunk so
the local skunk went in first so yeah
I'm I'm stoked about those and I got
some AK Bean brains gear going too the
same friend gifted me some nice stuff
um yeah I got some super skunk over
there from you know Andross with a Black
Domina I'm really excited about I got
some cough bx1 with same with Dave fop's
help I believe right in with Relic I
believe was behind it so I've got some
cough which I've been really really
hoping to get back into um classic stuff
and kind of going for it with some
really cool genetic stuff this year I've
even been talking to Colin from vessel
life and we're planning some interesting
project uh breeding projects here on the
farm which will tie in some more I guess
land race types even some Moroccan and
some nepes have been brought up to to
bring back into some lines here in
theory that are producing really good
hash and go with some more land race
hash oriented uh genetics to see what it
kind of mixes up and yeah
so I love that that's just candy to the
ears just hearing about all this stuff
maybe you can tell us about your hash
here in a sec but because it's really
interesting what you've got going on
with some of your your
uh Mis connections and and I also wanted
to touch on some regenerative things
that we can talk about a lot of people
are dealing with toxic environments and
how can we help people in uh uptaking
some of that toxic material so that's
gonna that's people are asking those
questions microbiology eats toxicity
cover across microbiology more of it
Mario what's happening in your in your
neck of the woods tell us something
about your appach your Appalachia your
farm and some of
your hey guys nice to see you happy
spring can you hear
me hey can you hear
me cool
um well everything's kind of going well
here for some sheep I got a herd of
sheep coming in soon and a couple of
week weeks and uh so I'm building a
little
manger I got a a new flock of ducks that
I just reared up and today's their first
day free ranging it's really cool it
feels really good they were ready to get
out I got some M scovies if you guys
don't know about those they're
awesome and I kind of like read about
them and thought that they would be
awesome but now that I'm like actually
holding one compared to like other
domestic duck breeds their structure is
so much stronger like their bone
structure and muscular and their nails
are sharper they fly they forage better
they're like the ultimate Homestead duck
I'm so stoked on those so I feel like
all the Ducks here are going to be Movis
eventually are those the running
Ducks what's up are those the running
ducks that like don't need the water as
much no ducks they're a totally
different uh type of duck in fact it's
kind of like a horse and a a donkey like
if a if a horse and a donkey have have a
a baby it's a mule but it's infertile so
if a mcoi and a regular duck have babies
they're infertile too they're not
compatible that way so anyway you either
got the Movis or you got the other ones
I'm all about the Movis right now um
yeah the Farm's at, 1300
feet uh I'm here in in Willets right in
the middle mesino about 45 minutes from
the coast in the
Foothills
um uh flat land in the valley I've got
uh really nice exposure and great water
um I've been on this site for eight
years now and um from the moment I got
here I kind of like did a permaculture
design of a um like a a livestock
laneway around the whole place and then
planted accordingly to feed livestock as
they pass through and I haven't had
livock until except for like ducks uh
until until this season with the Sheep
coming in so I'm pretty excited it's a
huge transition happening right now I'm
thinking just as much about that kind of
stuff as I am of the herb because it's
really about like being able to like
sustain like uh certain lifestyle and um
and live in in in in this place that we
love to live and pay the bills so right
now the herb isn't really paying the
bills so I'm like staying is fluid and
flexible as possible um you know
diversifying and one of the things that
I'm really focused on is building
alternate income streams with
existing
infrastructure like like how many like
returns can I get from that 2inch line
that's running through my field or you
know what what kind what kind of
resources do I have on the land that I
can like
like kind of like do as little as
possible to get return from you know and
and and keep it all like fertile and
abundant and keep the fertility on site
as much as possible you know so I'm
giving a lot of thought to that kind of
stuff any question or I just I just like
to that emotion and say many DM farmers
are realizing and part of the demm
certification is other crops the whole
entire thing is to be that you don't buy
products and that you have a polyculture
and that polyculture is not just with
plants it's with people and seeds and so
lots of farmers are diversifying jaw
Gardens move had to move and he's
planting hundreds of fruit trees you
know and it's it's amazing you know to
see what people are doing I remember
Terry Willard telling me uh you know
that the the eonia farmers were making
tons of money you know back in the day
and then all of a sudden eonia just got
flooded from everywhere in the world and
all of a sudden eonia farmers were just
lost and the point is any one thing can
go away so the more that we have you
know
prodcts as tertiary products at quadri
products whatever squary I don't know
where I'm going but we're having a lot
whatever it is and we always have said
it isn't about you being in business for
two years about are you going to be here
with a brand that matters with an ed
educational force that matters in 10
that's something isn't making money
we're gonna go to something else so I'd
love to hear from everybody what are you
diversifying with that's gonna keep you
here what what's what's working for
you I would say I can go on
that I would say just on a short thing
perennial crops
just I like things that you can put in
that are going to keep giving you
returns with very little input that's
that's really what I'm focused
on I agree with that you could do things
like
blueberries or things like uh you know
fruits and stuff those never really I
mean people like the sugary sweets and
those things kind of return for years
and years and years which is pretty cool
but I've been diversifying I mean if you
look at my instagam
I post a lot of a decent amount of car
stuff from vws and Audi's and it's just
you know I've kind of had a knack for
automotive mechanics and the used car
Market's pretty hot right now so I've
been kind of saving these old uh you
know 20-year-old Volkswagens and Audi's
resurrecting them and then you know
moving them along to kind of um stay
afloat after you know kind of a hard
season and a hard winter um so I think
that like using any other skills you
know that we pick up from you know our
various experience throughout life you
know kind of taking taking a step back
and reflecting on those things and then
trying to um you know to to Pivot to
Pivot into a more diverse network of
like income streams or or or whatever
you
know and have you looked into electric
conversions for old VW I'm seeing a lot
about like how easy it is to to convert
like an old VW bus to Electric like
drive it in and then that day you come
out with an electric bus type thing have
you heard of is that interesting to you
I was just wondering what your thought
is and then we'll move on you can
definitely do that that is like that's
definitely doable but with my
infrastructure here at the cabin um you
know I have very rudimentary electricity
um and I don't have like a garage I have
one structure on my land and it's pretty
much the room that I'm sitting in right
now um so you know with but my thoughts
on the electric batteries it it's kind
of a hard thing to uh to balance in my
mind you know with like the Mind
minerals the cost um you know the
difficulty in wiring and different
servos and stuff like that I I'm just
you know I'm not I I wouldn't say I'm
familiar agreed we would have to go back
to what is everybody else more common
just yeah more products I want to hear
about what people are doing for
secondary things I bet there's a way to
you know create an alternative energy to
do the electrical in the cars I mean I
know I'm in Crest Creston is doing some
amazing work with um biofuels and like
there there must be a way to to do this
anyway that was a thought
excellent yeah it's super cool stuff I'm
really uh I'm really interested in that
engineering side of things because it's
kind of you know overshadowed with a lot
of stuff and I think it's also important
to get your engineer on uh as a farmer
as a you know as a human
being in talking to a lot of uh people
in the California market like canos
Market it's like manufactured products
seem to be
much more stable so our tinure product
is actually the one that's getting us
through this
spring because that's the only income
we're really that's Reliant um so we're
looking for
more ideas to develop on farm value
added you know with
Elderberry get package products and get
that
out yeah older berries are an amazing
crop to grow um they just produce and
they're so stable um we actually have
like six
differentopic farming years ago and ever
since he did I've been going down so
many rabbit holes on you know creating
these and you know it's Sim similar to
what we've all been talking about with
regenerative farming and all that but
it's really using biomimicry and you
know even before indigenous agriculture
just like the way that nature compiles
things and us being able to learn from
that and be able to create these
self-sufficient systems that are going
to just keep growing and evolving into
these beautiful things um and eventually
just become you know its own stable
source of everything that it needs needs
and uh we've actually been yeah that's
what we're we're kind of excited about
right now is that um where our medicine
Garden um had
under
stor and elderberries are a big part of
that elderberries and then some other um
just really easy ones to kind of things
that are drought resistant things that
be able to create shade layers so other
things could be able to get established
and grow through into you know more
stable canopy and where we just have
continuous different crops coming up and
and that's one of ours is like we're
looking of how like a permaculture
teacher told me like every Farm should
have seven different incomes seven
streams so I've been trying to work
towards that for a while and now with us
all like combining forces there's four
usdm Farmers out here I'm really excited
about you know we all have different
ideas and figuring out our um different
paths and we're all alined but it's like
what we really love is the Copic is
going to be able to provide all my
commercial herbs but then also we'll
either have hemp or cannabis in it this
next year we'll have tree layers berock
yeah yeah lots of berock ashas you know
these ones that I need a blot of um for
the products and then we also all
different kinds of pollinators and
copsis and dianis
and yeah you guys have a top three like
uh perennial
Berry list that you could kind of shout
out right now because I'm looking to
plant like three more different types
I've got the previous owner of this
Homestead had what's that Cape
Gooseberry it's more of a self- seater
it's not a perennial but you know you
grow one and it's going to keep coming
back and it's it just spreads and the
amount of berries that you get off of
just one plant is just it's absolutely
amazing and it's such a delicious thing
to be able to you know experience it's
such a unique flavor and it's fun to get
down there and kind of harvest every day
for your berries and whatnot and it's
very low-lying the way that it I mean it
could grow tall depending on if it's
reaching for light light or not but if
it has a nice open area the way that the
arm spread is just it's it's so unique
and beautiful the Goji I GOI because you
can use the leaves for teas you can also
use the berries and I just like how it
spreads and it can be done in many
different climates and if you have a
little bit of shade yeah I was going to
say Works in Michigan or not yeah
blueberries be depending on your you
know it grows here
I I know there's some folks in Ohio that
was doing that so has
anyone has anyone done aonia berries yet
are awesome for a system yeah oh my God
the me that comes from those I've read
done aronia it does really good here
yeah it's one of my favorites and it's
in col so Colorado is kind of rough on
some things but aonia berries do really
well here awesome yeah yeah so there's
so there's so many I mean it really just
depends on where you live right what
your news are raspberry for me is a
really big crop here because I use a lot
of raspberry leaf and our smoking Blends
and teas does really well and it's yeah
it's great and it's just like always
producing so my little one just always
goes and eats the berries and we're
harvesting all the leaves and chopping
and drop in it and it comes back so
vigorous so yeah it's also it always
depends on what your kind of user needs
are as well as what's going to grow
around that area yeah Alexandra I know
an other one which is called
jberry and that grows even in um Alberta
like uh Calgary area it's very tough um
a bush and uh you can always make
cutting so easily of it and it's a it's
a hybrid
between uh a black currant and um uh
Gooseberry and I and a really nice big
uh blueberries and you can freeze them
or whatever but I would recommend that
for wherever you
live especially for tough areas
absolutely great I'm really excited have
produced them over and over again I will
this year have SE already a whole bunch
of flowers on
it oh beautiful perfect well I have that
written down nice we should figure out a
way to share all these resources like
like little bit um you know we have
it
[Music]
have page and a private one for for de
and pure family the private one no one
uses anymore but it could always be
activate at any time one Barry I would
add would be the C Buckthorn C Buckthorn
has been really good for us and it's an
incredible uh you know one to make
medicine and products with it's super
spiky and weird and it like continues to
grow it like propagates itself
throughout the the ground uh we also you
know yeah and it can be put in a lot of
skin it's not it's not very tasty but it
can be put in skin care products and it
just is super beautiful for really high
vitamin C
so anybody out there who has the the
freeze dryers or they do dehydration at
all they're just really amazing to grind
up and put in for vitamin C and also I
would add one more the has cap Berry
which is I believe it's Japan I may be
wrong about that but uh uh it's like a
blueberry but it BL it blooms super
early it's actually it's actually from
the honeysuckle family there you go and
um it was created up here off of a
hybrid H suckle in the Calgary area so
it's actually Northern and it just
continues to go and go the only problem
with it birds love it birds love the
berries as well as deer love the leaves
so in the winter time if you have a lot
of uh snow you you have to cover it so
the deer don't get to it but they are
delicious and they're a true red fruit
and they are so plentiful you know how a
blueberry is not quite blue it's it's
just the skin is blue it's a white fruit
but this is red on the outside and red
all the way through so when you work
with it and you eat it it's just so red
really beautiful fruit and also the
dwarf cherries we have this medicinal
cherry tree that's like it tastes so
like weird and bitter but it's dark
red and so I think I've seen those in
Hawai somewhere maybe not though I don't
know Lala please put these in the chat
on the YouTube for people that would be
great because I know people are asking
and Marcus Bale to go bring his uh his
buddy to uh a friend's house little
Tanner for some skating you have to be a
moderator in YouTube like you have to
have a blue mod wrench to be able to put
links in that chat so the only one that
can do just have to write them down
Bingo Lombardi and 70s mama I think
you're
more you know those were some great
ideas with with perennials and with
berries because they're great on the
market anybody else has been doing some
amazing things for some secondary income
I wanted to also say like uh different
deer resistant crops and things like
that to be able to do bordering around
uh your plants and things that are
really uh you know drought resistant
that could like different allows and
things like that and being able to use
that as uh you know you could sell it as
an input or use it for your farm I mean
the amount of oxin that you're able to
get out of it is absolutely amazing um
if you're you know reproducing and you
s it's so beautiful the you know
biodiversity that you can create with
just within that you know species just
keep telling us really it's like we're
only limited by our imagination
you know because we can grow we can do
so much with what capable if you have a
piece of land and you really are it's
like it depends on your interest and you
really are only limited by what you can
really create and conceive and that's
when we smok in a joint really great it
comes in you can go sit in your garden
and ideas just come and flow and like
one of ours is right now our other
income source and that we are really
loving is teaching we are doing doing
some education we have a new CL another
class coming up um on April 16th have
fun weekend that we're going to do
because it's Easter weekend and so we're
going to do a depth um in-depth class of
like fullon going into all the inputs we
use for the year of liquid fertilizers
how to make them the herbal solutions
seed blocks biochar lab cultures and um
then we're going to end it with a lot of
DM farmer talks and then some
celebration with music and dancing and
getting up the next day doing some ganja
yoga and then we're going to do some
adult kid and adult and kid Easter egg
hunts but it's going to be a fun weekend
but this is one thing that we are really
enjoying doing is events and in may we
have a sesh coming up a private event
where we're able to do you know a lot of
different things underneath that and
allow people to gather and come together
and this is something that just really
to our hearts right now and that we're
really enjoying creating these fun
places for us all Gather in say in a
safe way and also be able to help
ourselves make money right now and our
Farms survive and so that that's yeah
that's one of our important fun things
that we're doing we have a lot like that
we are creating right now that we're
going to keep close but just know like
on our land here we're going to be open
it up soon to classes and workshops and
private events and healing courses and
you know whatever our imagination kind
of comes up with and that we all you
know are
aligned and and tomorrow has some
amazing products that she makes there I
have like a half a dozen of them on my
shelves and she was sweet enough to send
Molly some postpartum stuff and yeah she
does amazing value added products yeah I
mean and one agree with you Daniel I've
tried some of the skin care I love them
thank you or and that that Elixir that
oh the eonia one yeah it's it's CBD so
good I mean this is this is why I went
legal you know just genetics you know I
remember when prop 64 passed and I
looked at we could do I called my dad up
I like Dad we got to do it they're gonna
let us flower out 5K square foot for
seed production like we've been waiting
our whole lives for this the rest has
been a total [ __ ] show and you know the
whole
time um
and yeah that's my you know I've been
packing some seeds up right now I do it
at night I do it in the winter it's it's
definitely my part-time job that became
the only money that I really saw this
winter you know was from from seed sales
and it you know without that I would
have had to uh you know gone to for
somebody else uh to get get through the
winter and yeah it's been such a
blessing and I'm converting some of um
the farm to a little more seed
production
um expressing 25% autof flowering and
I'll be doing three types of Autos per
bed but one breeder and if I'm
successful I'll make aund 120 new
Autoflower hybrids
and uh I'm excited I'm growing some haze
from Noble from Golden fig Gardens
that's one of the ones that we're going
there and and yeah we're we've been
planting we have a lot of fruit trees a
lot of food but the drought's been so
hard on us as a mountain Farm you know
uh I don't have the rain catchment in
storage that I need to farm in a drought
so you know we look forward to in the
future to be able to increase that so
that I can really dial in you know more
of the poly culture and just I got a lot
of holes to to fill in for you know the
rest of my life once we get a little
more
water and this is
saraphina oh
baby Jay do you want to say something I
saw you coming in
sure yeah I'm I'm likeminded with you
all here about
diversity we do a lot of mushroom
production we got about 10,000 plugs
going right now uh Rishi Lions man
shitake and some big big hles U we did
some land clearing and so we made use of
that that Lumber it's about our big one
we call the the wall it's about 150 feet
and about 17 feet high it's sort of a
sep Holzer kind of takeoff massive hugle
bit we do a lot of food production in
that mostly for our staff and ourselves
at this point the big idea though is to
here in Canada if you can make 10,000 a
year in uh traditional agriculture
because of course cannabis isn't
considered agriculture for some crazy
reason then you can claim Farm status so
we've been working towards that every
year adding more and
more and just building more and more
gardens the the value added line the
product line that's super key so that's
where we make our profit the uh the
biomass market right now is is really a
tough situation so I think it's super
important to diversify into value added
products if it's possible because that's
see what's going to add stability to the
company Long
Term having that's something else we're
doing trying we're working with our
community here we got this thing called
The Rose buddy program we're finding
micros shutting down all over the place
right now because of that issue with
trying to sell biomass on a saturated
market and there's not a lot of interest
in small Lots because a processor takes
on more risk in that scenario theyd
rather just buy a Big Lot thousand kilos
so the people that are getting it the
harsh I are the micros and they're the
ones that need it the most because they
have such a small amount of biomass for
sale so what we're doing is we're
providing genetics one of our strains
are really excited about this really
climatized well to our region and
support we do a a regenerative Health
Canada Canada Revenue just support call
once a week or excuse me every second
week just to kind of navigate through
all these things and then the idea is
although we're still not quite there yet
is to buy the biomass back from these
farmers at a fair market value and we'll
put that into our own product line um we
can't of course we can't do this
regenerative on mass scale and so in
order to get into the stores we need
more biomass we've capped our site at a
fairly small footprint to keep that
regenerative and high quality craft and
in fact craft is a new category here in
Canada too are pretty excited to have a
lot of input on the creation of that
category but that's another opportunity
to help us uh survive in this market as
small
producers so yeah some of the other
things we're we really just keep looking
at stacking functions diversifying what
I'm actually excited about we're bit
away is um te we one of our Guild one of
our support species do a lot of mint do
a lot of
very cool man well
said thanks friends I love what you're
it's important what you're doing up here
Shay and and people really appreciate
you and all the rose buddies are all you
know part of our family and and
stuff and pure certified too and I think
that we'll probably do more of these
hash churches with other pure certified
Farms that you know aren't on here now
so they can tell their story as well but
I also think that some regen camps uh
would be good at your spot you know for
the for for this area for for British
Columbia because
to do something you know in our bio
region and I want to continue talking
about regenerative practices like
farming too oh I didn't want to cut you
off go ahead shade you had something to
say I just be all into that like this
diversity overlaps beyond our business
but into our community and that's really
the big like this plant is a power plant
it's super duper key and important but
it's just one plant but it's part of a
big closed loop system which is our
community small and large you know our
world community so if we can do things
here to support people to support
themselves and support their Community
uh just like regenerative classes but
food production and you know all of the
things all of the things and how they
all connect together body mind and soul
you know from meditation and how you
take care of yourself to how you take
care of your land and how you take care
of your community that's really what
this is all about and I'm super excited
that we're all joining together and we
have beautiful place like where we live
to demonstrate these things to actually
not just talk about them but demonstrate
them and collectively we all have our
niches we all have our powers and we can
show our one or two or five amazing
things we've done that the next Farm
hasn't but so collectively we can date a
better world pretty easy in my opinion
I'm stoked to be part of
that me and Craig were just talking
about that the other day how much you
know we've all vibed off each other over
all these years and I've Just Seen
everyone's Farm come up including our
own you know we've been doing this a
long time and all that 15 16 years now
on this Farm you know a lot of bounty um
but every single time I have a
conversation with someone I feel like I
pick up uh you know support so yeah
communication something I'd like to
address uh the chat there was someone
that said that they have a hard time
getting seeds well that would be a great
time to address this right now because
we do have a breeder on the panel lots
of breeders on this panel that I know
and they all ship seeds all over the
world I think um so Reach Out DM them um
they probably can't do it through
Instagram you probably have to do
through email there's different weird
things going on with that so you guys
reach out and get to know people like I
was just at an amazing seed swap Kush
Kirk put on this amazing vent with some
amazing hat
seed swaps uh the amazing deure family
was there just putting us event uh Joey
and Tamara they put on them all over
seeds are everywhere they're gifting
them you bring seeds you can gift them
to people you can sell them there's like
so much going on so seeds aren't hard to
find you just really have to make a
little bit of effort to get out there
and get to know people it takes a little
effort if you want things and you just
got to do it and literally um you know
Sierra's parents um the peach orchard
team they are literally selling packs of
beans for 20 bucks at the seed swap also
giving out free SN grass family genetics
yes yes giving out free uh lettuce seeds
and flour seeds like that's what it's
about it's about uniting and getting
together as a family and sharing I love
it thanks everyone for being here today
and you know like uh Duke said earlier
though watch out for the scammers
there's so many scammers out there like
you know if you're you're following
someone look at the tag section on
Instagram these scammers can't fake this
you know not very well it'll be maybe
one of their own other scam pages but
you you know I'm sure if you pulled up
Duke's page or my page like Pride line
seeds you would see people growing our
gear posting about that gear so you know
just be careful out there when you're
approaching someone Instagram to to get
seeds
watch for the
scammers yeah and
[Music]
do Fly by Night company just putting a
and b together and here you go here see
they don't really care about your garden
or anything else they just they just
want some money so do you do diligence
um you know stick to those ridable
people that are you know putting in the
work showing the love and um that that
really is going to translate to your
garden
because um you know from your soil your
inputs and everything your environment
that's that's part of it but you know um
you're going to be able to hit genetic
potential you know to the to the best of
your ability with with all those things
but you can have everything to the nines
you know but if the genetics aren't
there you're you're not going to you're
not going to do well you're going to
have a bad time and uh especially if
you're newer newer to Growing maybe it's
your first time um stuff like that kind
of sometimes it'll deter people away
from you know growing their own and
everything and that's that's that's kind
of sad too so just make sure that you do
your due diligence and uh go that route
and then um you know like where just
talking about like you know your
businesses you know and certain people
it's their livelihood like that's what
they do for a living it's not like you
know the guy's working wherever and that
night time he just Chuck seeds together
and cause it good um there's people like
myself like that's what I do for a
living you know I got other things I do
as well um I do a little bit of
engineering a little bit of design work
for people if if they need it solar
arrays you know smart controllers you
know for green houses like kind of like
custom stuff like that um also the
educational make your own you know
radiant green and you know your fat
flowers and like you can do this but you
know you got somebody living in the city
like they they can't do it it or some
people just don't have the time or
whatever so the products available you
can get it from you but yall never had a
problem with the the sharing of that you
know they all were like so awesome about
just uh teaching people and you know
just like you know it's awesome things
so uh I've always told people like okay
here's here's how you mix this so yada
yada but you know like I don't have room
for that man it seems like a lot of work
so I figured hey for those folks you
know take a from Josh and Kelly make it
available to people you know otherwise
you know they can just make their own so
that's kind of kind of what I'm doing uh
for my
multiple revenue streams like the sav
business folks
say um
I I um the the way how I grow I always
make sure that I'm collecting my own
seeds not just from the cannabis of
course but also from everything else of
the vegetables and of course I noticed
as you BBY did too your own seeds are
always much more full of life they come
up and like almost
100% um for me it's also super important
that people uh know how to grow their
own food it doesn't matter how whether
it's in a farm or in a small space um
years and years ago um I was told to
make sure to educate people that they
are growing their own food because we
will come to a point where that will be
uh not available anymore and we see that
already how it happened whether it's now
through the virus what happened but I
also know it from my family in Germany
uh because of whatever happened in in
the Ukraine um suppli or certainly not
happening anymore um but also the nature
itself tells already uh it's a diversity
it's not only one thing and uh in my
many years of growing gardens there's
always something that doesn't doesn't
turn out and something else that turns
out much better the way of nature saying
hey this year you need much more beads
or you need much more beans blah blah
blah uh but what I wanted to ask you um
do you have any uh experience of keeping
your seats a long terms are you uh
including the canabas of course but also
other seeds are you just put them into a
cold storage or do you have any
experience with
freezing freezing the the the seeds to
yeah absolutely uh one thing that like
it was like a common mistake was people
were starting to put things in a in a
freezer way too early right there's
still moisture there and
um eight weeks like extrem dry time I
don't uh I don't bundle things up like
I've seen some people put them all in a
jar right away that's that's no good so
like a turkey pan you know or whatever
you got uh something that's not going to
hold moisture and lay them all out nice
and uh nice and flat and making sure
that they got that good long dry time um
once you're once you're good and dry
um so from pollen to to seeds and
everything I personally I like to break
everything down into like what I'm going
to use so instead of putting you know 5
or 100 or whatever seeds together I'm
looking like what is a single use for me
like what would I be taking out to use
that way I'm not bringing the whole bulk
in and out of the freezer you know
condensation and everything can happen
too so um something freezer safe uh
container wise but within that I like to
break everything down into like what I
would use so uh individual pack of say
cannabis seeds you know I might have you
know 15 together or something like that
um and then I can break out exactly what
I need um so for your long-term storage
that's good uh if you know like you're
going to be using it you know
respectably in the near future uh I like
just the refrigerator uh refrigerator
does good for like what you know you're
going to be getting into and then the
freezer for long term and then you're
kind of like replicating that
stratification you would see out in
nature anyway with you know you know
summer going into fall winter and then
back to Spring and I've always had real
real good results like
that and how long do you think can seed
blast in a
freezer oh a really really long time um
I know uh somebody brought up uh AKA
Bean brains uh at the beginning of the
show he's a good friend of mine um you
know he's he had stuff in there well
over 20 years and broke them out and
germinated them and you know no problem
yeah definitely keeps them keeps them
keeps them well like I said the trick is
you know keeping it keeping it like that
you know so and like he hasn't moved you
know he's been living in the same place
forever so that makes it easy too but
once you got it frozen you know keep it
frozen till you need what you need and
when you're storing just make sure that
you're putting in there like sizable
like what you what you need and not
going you know back in and out and yeah
that's pretty much it in a nice
container you know something freezer
safe you know and uh yeah you're you're
good to go and uh label label everything
accordingly like to put dates on things
so you kind of you know have an
idea that's that's great thank you and I
think that's also a good information for
everyone else because um when I do like
carrot seeds I did my own carrot seeds
it was amazing but I have so much of
course from one little plant to get
abundance so to keep it because Kos
seeds also can be really quickly not be
viable so I will put all those um into
little packages and and then have your
own um seat um
security yeah absolutely and if you go
to like um a place that sells like beads
and things like that normally they uh
they have like little small containers
that are good or if you can find like
the vials or something like that that's
cool too um yeah you can find like
little small packages to keep your stuff
in y um and there was a place I used to
order my bags from my seed packs like
you can get like the the friendly
biodegradable bags too you know you take
it up a take it up a notch it's got the
little green seal on it and everything
um and they're like the same price as a
normal plastic baggie or whatever yeah
so yeah that are
def are going you know um it used to be
like so like my father he he grew up
through the Great Depression and
everything farmer and all and that was
always instilled from me early on um
growing you know vegetables and uh some
fruit trees and canning things for the
winter like that's just kind of like
what we did then when I traveled around
and got away from there it's like like
wow no body else really does this you
know so it's it's good and you know if
you're running a farm um hell man like
you if you can cut costs you know
because like you know bringing money's
in but saving money is even better and
you know if you can grow your own food
you know you're not you know spending
out canning things and you know go to
farmers market sell your jellies your
jams uh like people were talking about
your teas and everything
then you're you know cutting cost on you
know living in general so that's always
a great way to make some money that and
efficiency you know yeah I like things
mean you put my seats in there and write
it on uh that's the way how my recycle
works and maybe put a little something
into make sure it's not getting moist in
in that I understand that thank you nice
um Katie and Rio I saw you guys were
wanting to say something but Rio walked
out Katie did you want to jump
in so I have a question because someone
asked in chat in our chat here about
freeze drying seeds like maybe that's a
good topic to talk about does anybody
know about that or no don't freeze dry
seeds you can't freeze dry seeds no
makes them inv
spores I think is the only thing that
you can like fre freeze dry and it'll
live that I know of yeah you just want
to replicate what the plant is going to
do in its ultimate optimal conditions
and for it to come back year after year
just like Duke was saying you know you
really want to dry that out so um I know
for us we've been doing some secondary
things we just got involved in all the
Saturday markets we've done Saturday
markets in years past and uh this year
we deed Ed that we were going to jump in
and do all Saturday markets and get our
crew on making sure to get you know our
salads and and some secondary product
you know whatever we've got excess in
the garden because so much of it goes to
our chickens so much of it goes to our
compost that we really want to make a
really concerted effort because we also
put away a lot so because we have so
much abundance I also really want to
talk to people who have abundance on
their Farms is to let's start hooking up
with people who can take it to Market
because so much of it is is just being
composted and there's a lot of youthful
people that want to be involved in this
regenerative culture so you know people
who want to get a hold of people who are
growing foods and say hey if you all are
wasting any we'd like to come out once a
week and get that to Market or get it to
the homeless I know that everybody is is
seeing what's going on we have more
homeless people in North America in the
world than ever it is absolutely insane
and to know that regenerative Farms have
access this is also where licensing just
makes me so [ __ ] pissed off we used
to is that there's cannabis that's even
being like burned because it's
you can donate it for the maximum value
of that and it's a tax write
off so you can donate it and get it to
these people
yeah well that's people
who and can't even get it to a processor
to get it out or have I've seen I've
seen people like burning it on Instagram
just thr I think that's more just like
you know those people who burn sports
jerseys because someone got traded to
another team you know it's like I don't
quite yeah I don't know you know
honestly we've definitely composted a
tremendous amount you know in the past
maybe because you know
whatever and and just in years and years
and years you look at like our outdoor
crops from time ago and changes in
markets and changes in politics and just
you know when you're in the industry for
30 years all we're saying is of
different values in different medicines
there's different values like what Josh
had mentioned in eonia you know if you
put all of a sudden maybe everybody is
starting to grow blueberries well then
the price of blueberries in your area
grows goes down tremendously and then
you have to make a secondary product
with those blueberries so just really
thinking outside of the box and that's
mean vinegar
and alcohol are something that we could
really look into making more of I mean
vinegar is really easy to make and it's
a really useful extract for medicines
even psychedelic mushrooms can be
extracted with vinegars and um it's
really healthy for you um it's it's a
fermentation that lasts throughout the
winter you can clean with it um I think
having your own dis your own still what
legalities is whatever you know having
your own still makes all the sense in
the world you know you're making your
own alcohol you're making your own
tinctures now you're making your own
medicine there's a reason why it was
made illegal it's too useful anything
that's been made illegal start learning
about it that's what you should be
doing because there's the whole point is
it's empowering you and that's not what
they want so this is a
empowerment yeah learning how to make
alcohol is very useful and vinegar is
like now CNN's going to take that one
little clip amazing
like they already forgot about us don't
worry we talking about the ethers as
long as we're talking about the ethers I
want to bring in the way I've been
gardening the last year just to kind of
put a little bit of an icing on this
lovely cake that we're [ __ ] making
together oh no curing in church I'm
sorry um I have been so I just want to
say real quick this is not that kind of
church so you can do whatever you
want because I don't remember taking
hits at church either so let's take some
hits on that note go ahead
please oh my
God you guys I've been going super deep
on web 3 all right I've been I've got
this Inc like not only do we have to
shift value and and add value and build
and uh we don't have to go we don't have
to find our community we have to be able
to key in with the community that we
already have and really get you know
just
heartfelt established in that and
support each other three stuff is so
cool so anything you want to know about
it the nft stuff is amazing it's not
just about products it's about it's
about contracts it's about relationships
and it's about gaining our creativity
back so we can start articulate what it
is to own our own not only like data but
but like our own livelihood and to come
together in livelihood overlays like
there's just such Elegance out there
there's a lot of people doing amazing
work so just get in touch with me if you
want to know anything about it I'm about
to save my farm through this AR
ticulate contractual Beauty thing that's
going to help every other Farm in
trouble so anyone who wants to play with
me in that
field come play because we're going to
do festivals together we're GNA do all
this stuff that we're gonna know what
each other's doing we're going to be
able to travel to see each other I get
to have a meal train if I want and come
up to Canada and see
everybody that's all I have to
say weren't you uh did you go to the um
the hot springs for that uh seed
swap the other was it last weekend or
weekend before I haven't really haven't
really ventured out I've been stuck to
my screen for a year
but it's been you said like you were out
around
creststone I was do I know a lot of
people in creststone yeah we should talk
dude because you're in state let's let's
yeah I was over uh in mait and then the
next day I went a joyful journey and
they had a seat swap there oh I was
there that week though I oh that's
hilarious we were in crestone at the
same time yeah I actually lived in
crestone for or mfet for a little bit
too right on yeah I was literally like
just there and like I was like I know
this person like I've seen the seen the
face or whatever but uh
yeah
I Josh and Kelly did didn't you
Colorado too Josh and Kelly we did we
lived in Steamboat we lived in Steamboat
me and Kelly drove to Costa Rica and
back in a Volkswagen bus in
1994 and when we came back from Costa
Rica we took our stuff from Guatemala
and sold it in Boulder on the street and
got a house in Steam we got a sweet
condo the Bas but the weed wasn't good
enough at that time we had to bail we
had to go I couldn't work I couldn't
work Steamboat Springs because I had
earrings and long hair so at first at
first I tried putting my hair up
earrings out and I even passed the weed
test because I did the the I did the
niin and a bunch of golden seal and I I
I passed the weed test and then I was
like you know what [ __ ] this they're
gonna see me with long hair afterwards
hire me so I just did construction all
year in 25 below weather oh yeah but we
left because the we wasn't that great
then we had we had we used to call it
the Rocky Mountain High for some reason
it was all swag weed in in uh in a
steamboat at the time it was all
Mexicans so we were sending out this
purple kush at the time from Southern
Oregon which was like the craziest
purple like Tara's bright it was fuchsia
purple when it was I don't know if you
remembers the purple from like the late
80s and 90s it I don't know why purple
cush you don't really see it the real
purple same way no one goes like dude
check out my purple Cush back in the day
like that was some of the most skunky
gnarly [ __ ] in southern Oregon and we
were sending it out to Colorado you know
and then it was just getting too crazy
so but Craig were you in Steam wa where
were you at in Colorado yeah I was in
Steamboat uh in 9 like2 to 94 so I left
right before you guys got there and yeah
the the herb was all right there was a
couple folks that had a had a little
something something going on it produced
some decent herb but for the most part
it was garbage Steamboat was more about
blow back then it was kind of crazy what
type of town it was um and uh the the
kind of the the gray cloud that would
hang over it because of that right um
but yeah I'm glad Colorado got the herb
scene figured out a little bit better
for the sake of the the population in
all these rural mountain
towns it's not easy to grow cannabis
here it's not easy to grow anything
thing in Colorado to be perfectly honest
I mean unless you're going to dig up and
replace and do ridiculous things to make
it like limp along until suddenly you
hit such imbalances you're like oh my
God and then you have these
differentials in temperature that really
literally swing 60 degrees and you've
got no season like the next season and
I'm trying to naturalize of cannabis
here and I've been doing it for seven
years and I actually asked Duke a
question at one of his seed um panels
and he gave me such support and just
because I was scared of what I was doing
but I've got babies coming up there
every out there every year and every
year I get surprised by some little
anomaly and I just keep throwing
genetics at it um I Craig gave me a
little bag of something at the regen
conference so that's make making its way
out there so anyway that's my
crazy now I remember doing it now I
remember and
Expo yeah yep that's when it
was tomarrow did you have a thing to add
our I we were talking about tinctures
and alcohols and shrugs and vinegars and
self reliance and you wanted to talk
tomorrow did you want something to say
do you have something to
say I kind of don't remember
now but there's always something to say
on self-reliance and um I mean that's
definitely one thing um I have wanted to
achieve here is like the apple vinegars
and that's why like behind us we have
the apple tree and it's a few years old
you know I planted in 2017 we have
another and every year we're getting
more and more but it's like with those
fruit trees you have real abundance it's
like get your fruit trees in first
that's one tip that I always like to
tell people who are just getting land or
if you've had land for a while just like
the best time to plant a fruit tree is
now and you got any um more you got any
new products you're excited about
tomorrow oh uh I have a few let's see
I've got the herbal syrup which I
started doing and that's the one where
it's um I've got uh let's see it's
nettle horel rose hips eia berock root
and dandelion root and then I've mixed
that together with some local honey that
we have and the local honey has some of
our CBD infused into it and um that CBD
is coming from the RSO that we create
and so that's infused into the honey
then the honey gets infused into this
really strong decoction of all these
herbs and then in that goes an ounce of
um or half an ounce of like California
poppy I do the whole plant poppy
tincture and then I do a whole plant
dandelion Ure that goes in that as well
so those are like some of my favorite
things I've been creating lately that
and I do a two to one with THC to CBD
and then the high CBD of like 500
milligrams um and so and then I'm
working on a facial line right now where
it's like I have the exfoliant a nice um
sugar scrub and then you have your
facial oil cleanser then you have your
facial oil and also in between that you
have your rose hydrol and then there is
a cream on
those are um what I really enjoy playing
with and uh created heal thyself Gardens
product line to be able to expand as I
expand and grow and add products with it
and um the more abundance that we have
with our herbs as we keep growing our
Gardens here the more abundance we have
the more the product line can grow and
the more ideas come and uh
yeah thanks for asking
that and Craig you know we were talking
earlier about your farm and we were
wanting to know you didn't say uh when
you introduced what Vari Idol that
you're going to be running this year and
uh why I know that you're working with
some really amazing extracts and I just
wanted to know you know what are you
running yeah we uh we made a conscious
decision a few years back to really uh
with what we opened up the show with
with like
Appalachians and having that taste of
toar um really you have to really start
thinking about what your what your goal
is and that was for to grow resin and uh
and to and to produce um hash with that
and um not only produce hash but we also
wanted to keep the regenerative mindset
or regenerative practices moving forward
so we partnered with uh Nasha extracts
right here in in Humble County um Baron
uh Lutz is is the owner and operator of
that and and we wanted to bring forward
um nothing fresh frozen you know we
didn't want to have all these
regenerative practices to plug a
condenser into it until it's consumed um
and have it plugged into the grid so
Baron is so supportive of trying to push
this forward through the entire
California Market where we just released
a Black Box series and it is our farm
cured um
resin uh rosin and um that's been great
success and the cult we used was guava
gift um and and we worked with um uh
green Source Gardens and and one thing
with it with going with the guava gift
you know uh when you're producing for
resin you know you could go with a GMO
which would be like an industrial
standard and it's going to produce
amazing clear resin and it's going to
return it you know over 20% blah blah
blah but then you have these outliers
right and the guava GIF came through and
produced you know between 17 and 18% so
it still produces well um but it has the
tping profile the richness the depth
that some of these uh more mainstream
cultivars don't have so it's important
to support these breeders that are
pushing uh the the the boundaries and
trying to pull uh tricomes out of these
deeper lines and not just grab a GMO and
and you know do some pollen chucking
like uh Duke was saying here and and to
go deep into their vaults and pull some
of these land races out and and start
going for those waxier tricomes so we
can do some extraction around that and
and to be truthful that's really what
has been a differentiator for our farm
is number one going deep into our
regenerative practice uh not scaling we
we learned that scaling is really
failing and and finding that perfect
model for how many people actually live
on your farm and and that's kind of how
big of a footprint you can have close
that Loop within that we see that
happening on a couple of the Farms here
whether it's he heel thyself or lady
sativa I went to Lady sativa and you
know you've got three generations
running around that farm and and re's
trying to look at try to build minimal
minimal housing infrastructure to
support that because you have the farm
as your front yard and your living room
so there's no need to have all this
massive roof space and and you know
industrial footprint on the farm when
you can just utilize what's out your
front door um but I I think I think for
us like I said it's it's the choosing of
the cultivars and working within the
network um to find what really works and
the other thing that really surp
surprises a lot of folks when we talk
about uh our farm in particular and our
model is we're only 10,000 fet 75% of
that is all from seed sungrown you know
full season and then uh and from seed I
forgot if I mentioned that um and then
the uh the second component is 25% of
our farm the 2500 square feet is light
depth but I should say it's just Su
grown and we just use an occlusion loock
some of that sunlight so we get one
extra Harvest a year and it's not really
even a greenhouse it's just a structure
to support that occlusion tarp um to
block the Sun and then our second round
is a set it set it and forget it I call
it where we just put the plant straight
in do nothing and that one always goes
whole plant to to resin production
because we've learned with that second
second run that um and especially when
you start growing for resin you've got
enough going on especially with 75% of
our production being seed grown Sun
grown um
and that um takes up a lot of time that
time of year so we like having that last
or second round of depth even though
we're not depping it to be this uh
specifically for resin the the bud size
can be small we're not judging the flour
the infloresence of it we're just really
monitoring the resin and ready for the
peak production and the most flavor and
the the best for extraction so those
those are a little bit you know that
kind of ties into a little bit of what
we were talking about earlier on what we
can do on the farm um and I I want to
tie in one other piece to what we can do
on the farm to revenue stream you know I
I made brief mention that we did some
activism and activism brought you know
over $4 million four weeks of work $4
million didn't have to leave our pockets
in our Humble County you know farmer
Network and sometimes when we're dealing
with such a parasitic supply line and
Taxation how do we protect ourselves
from those parasites so the other thing
we're doing is we're doing a lot of just
self-education on how to do some of our
own um compliance work and maintenance
there's so many things we have to do
with the water board and all these
documents and websites and
and conserve and and work with each
other to get rid of a lot of the
parasites in the supply
line I just have to say Craig I just
love listening to you you always speak
so well and I had the privilege of going
to Craig's farm and it is a amazing
amazing and is that the hash that I got
to smoke the one that you're talking
about I think I think so I yeah yeah
fire fire I have smoked some amazing
fire and that was amazing fire thank you
for the privilege and the honor to visit
your farm and thank you Josh and Kelly
because through you I have met this
amazing family and continues it
continues to grow so thanks yeah thank
you so much for that Tara and really
want to shine light on on on Baron's
work at Nasha right like in a in the
California market right now when fresh
frozen is like it and it's got to be
purple gas and blah blah blah blah it's
not interested in that you know he's in
over 300 shops just doing this Farm
cured resin and and how important that
is if you guys check out our Instagram
at alpen glow Farm 707 you can see some
of these melt shots of the of the guava
gift and it's just this beautiful Amber
and one thing with you know uh res uh
Farm cured rosin and uh you do get down
the supply line as it goes out you will
get a little Haze over it and there's
nothing to fret there you know it it
gets a little buttered looking but the
flavor and the turps are
solid so as a regular hash smoker I only
dab um there is a big difference between
live and cured and what you're talking
about that cured all that really G
someone really has a hard time dabbing
and they're like constantly coughing and
that's the thing that they really hate
about it because I find as as I go
through the communities and I talk to
people about dabbing they're like God I
just hate that coughing and I feel like
I can't breathe and I'm like well first
of all you're taking too big of a dab
but you know bring that back but you
know that cured stuff that you're
talking about it's off gas all that
really really you know cost the mon
Turpin you're talking about mon what
give you the Harvest hack yeah thank you
and I I think so people if you if you
get a chance to try them both there
there definitely is different there's a
difference there so yeah Tara one thing
one thing that we actually just had the
conversation with Baron we're gonna be
doing a side by side so we're we're
actually gonna do a batch of fresh
Frozen um not to uplift that market so
much but to just really get some d of
points around a side by side here's the
same cultivar grown in the same Farm you
know kind of do our own chall and get
the data points from the testing and
consumers so um that's a really exciting
and it's going to be a white box so we
have the white box Black
Box yeah that's super sweet and I really
it's an amazing point that activism can
be something that adds to your profit at
the end of the year um you know
especially in Canada it's really it's
really hard Shane knows I mean there's a
lot of taxes everyone's there's some
something at everyone so yeah just stand
that's what we're going to do at this
cannabis Summit com coming up is talk
about you know ways that fars can
diversify through Farmgate sales and not
having to go through Distributors some
people like going through Distributors
and Distributors can make sense but in
other cases it's nice when you can
directly communicate with your cons
consumers and get products and and and
also getting rid of microbial testing
which we have here in Canada is an
invasive microbial testing system which
makes it to where you can't actually get
true herbal medicine to the market in
many cases um so we're trying to is
doing it Shay is doing it but it is very
difficult but he's doing it through this
in topicals and and always trying to
make the way through Market you know so
I just and I don't know if maybe someone
can speak about the California Market in
the sense of testing like just testing
for
human
path as opposed to just blanket testing
for all my cfms or whatever and it seems
ridiculous that we are still having this
convers how are we still
having this conversation well we're
still having this conversation because
the other side the corporate entity
doesn't want to grow good beautiful
healthy medicinal taste good make you
feel good make you be able to elevate
your mindscape all of these things are
what Legacy Farmers regenerative farmers
are creating inside of the secondary
metabolites which happen through the
microbiome of the plant when you have a
set microbiome of a plant that means
it's coming from the soil so when we're
talking about regeneratively growing a
plant we're talking about regenerative
soil growing a
plant to the people it
doesn't radiate your weed in order to
get it to the consumer my question to
you all what advice do you have to
Canada and Canadian policy makers having
to do with gamma
radiation micro testing um and you know
and get you know and and making it to
where people can sell to Consumers well
we don't even have the ability to put
you don't even have the ability to put
your like logo you can say where it's
from but say like Shay can't say all of
the different Farms that he gets his
biomass from and maybe he can we don't
know and you can tell us if we're wrong
about on the label it's too small so you
know you might they have these weird
foldout labels here in Canada and so you
know the thing is they took away the
Organic certification for indoor growing
in Canada and they have this invasive
microbial testing which makes it to
where you have to essentially mostly
radiate the weed to get it to the market
what advice do you have to to Canadian
policy makers we're GNA go
hand because we're going to go hand
toand and we're doing it anyway we're
going to be doing trade hand toand
through these relational
networks that blockchain makes Available
To Us by the way um we get to write our
own contracts and if I say that my I'm
going to be supported through my
ecosystem and then my ecosystem is going
to be nested within a larger ecosystem
and everything is linked by that and
it's relational and I do business with
you because I know you and I see you and
I love you we're doing it anyway so if
you all want to get on with the program
and be loving humans on this planet then
officials can you kindly with great
heart listen to us because we're
speaking the language of Earth and we
have good news we can feed each other
and have abundant thriving livs and
that's exactly what I would say to them
in the common sense approach but you
know having like you know white papers
and act like scientific stuff and back
it up and don't give them a dictionary
highlight excerpt parts put it together
well formulated for a DOI that works in
the government to understand because
you're not always the sharpest folks so
uh you make it easy spoonfed but you
site where you get it from where it's
from and everything and uh you know and
just show like uh maybe we're somehow it
would be cost effective to them to
eliminate that part so you're adding
like a benefit to them as well you know
so it's uh fullon reciprocal everybody's
kind of winning you can cite the facts
like yeah you're not hurting anybody in
fact you're helping people and uh you
know give it to them in a nice you know
nice little package that you can just
say here you go on your silver platter
okay and then uh you know it's hard to
fight you know people that are going
behind that you know from the heart and
you know just the common sense also
being backed up by
irrefutable you know just [ __ ] fact
so you give it to them like that you
know they they'd be hard pressed to tell
a group of people I mean we're talking
about the same people that cut weed
illegal right that were refuting facts
however um you know uh maybe uh maybe
they'll maybe they'll do the right thing
I don't know that's just my my two
cents well definitely one of the biggest
um hurdles that we have up here in
Canada and and it isn't a very good um
reflection for the for the rest of the
world as far as being federally legal is
that all of our legislation within the
Cannabis reality
and whole licensing is under Health
Canada that means Health Canada talks
about what we do with our plants so of
course all of those Reflections are
going to be more towards the
pharmaceutical Market because it's
Canada it's not Ministry of a they're
not treating the plants as if it should
be something coming out of the ground
we're actually having to fight to get
that type of education out that plants
come from the ground and that microbials
are something that actually helped the
plant
Thrive I I have no idea on this sort of
left turn that uh cannabis continues to
have as well as plant medicine to dumb
it down by isolating it and putting it
into pharmaceutical hands when we put it
into pharmaceutical hands it is no
longer medicine
and and and that is not at all what
regenerative practices are created the
legalization to begin with because what
created the legalization to begin with
was its medicinal
qualities and so when Craig is talking
about all of these
amazing uh values that you get from his
Sun grown purely dried gorgeous rosin
from his farm what you're getting is
you're getting secondary metabolite that
aren't even registered yet we don't even
have the scientific data and I loved
what you were saying over and over Craig
you know we're gonna get the data on
this and all I kept thinking was the
Dabba because you're gonna be like
dabbing to do it so you you guys are
gonna be taking the daa on that
one um but right now the data was a
grandma joke sorry about that um the
data on that right now is that it's all
taken from in
a lot of it is from Israel some of it is
from Canada all over the world it's not
sungrown it's not soil grown it's not a
full balanced
holistic um biome that the plant has to
even produce these incredible secondary
metabolites that haven't even been
studied yet so the data we're getting is
from a totally dumbed down source to
begin with there is new data coming out
though that I've SE seen from different
outdoor farm but we're having to force
that data it's not like run by
governments it's not run by these
Ministries that need to jump onward to
realize the value of putting it in the
hands of Department of Agriculture
because they have they're going to be
able to create more value in creating a
holistic plant that comes out of the
ground any thoughts on that D
centralized science Desi Desai Desi
d d
d I will hook you up with some
dii I was going to say um you know one
of the things our group is working on is
we we always evaluate the new bills
coming through and and wondering if they
make sense for our group to support or
not to support and
we don't need to look at Arizona we
don't need to look at these other states
and have some sort of pack to sell our
products there I think we need to First
work on our home state and move out from
there and that would be the one thing I
would
probably um share with the folks in
Canada is to start working with your
your you know I don't know your
government structure but your your
county or your Providence and then move
out from there because the other thing
that is going to happen here at least in
this country is you know New York is is
building out New Jersey's building out
they're going to have massive taxation
for my product to come into their state
right and then there'll be States like
Oregon and Nevada and Arizona that will
probably want to bring their prodcts
into
California you know that's not so
exciting for me um so I think there's
something to you know definitely want to
get the medicine out don't that's not
what I'm saying and we definitely want
to share but what's wrong with
experiential cannabis what's wrong with
having the experience when you come to
that home
state it's gonna be taxed somebody else
is going to try to figure out how to
make some more money on it but let's
come as close to the farm to to get
these products and and have these
experiences with us you know a lot of
the a lot of the conversation we have
with Soulful at the dispensary we're
partnered with is is the the dashboard
that people use to purchase cannabis
right now you're looking at a menu
you're looking at this percent that
tarpine that and if I was out front we
always joke about this if I was out
front 11 jars and rolling joints I'd
sell out every single time every single
time anywhere I went I could be the guy
selling you know the guy selling oranges
on the corner down at the bottom of my
Hill setting up my weed stand next to
him and I'd be
so arms I think that's where it's at
keep it in the hands of the farmers and
medical patient and affordable less
hands involved less money less
taxes AG
rainment go deep into
agrotain trade
route yeah more events too like I love
these farmers markets rather they're
legal whatever you know um it's all
about just bringing the the people to
the farmer and that's yet we all sell
our own stuff way better you know I can
sit there and tell you all the things
that my products do and my herb and I do
lots of oneto ones and different CBD ver
you know ratios but who else is going to
tell all that who else is going to tell
the story about how and the hell all
that happened gets deleted yeah it gets
diluted it just becomes false too if you
tell the same like big story over and
over and it's like all marketed and it's
like yeah they were supposed to give us
time as you know Legacy Farmers to
establish ourselves in this transitional
world that we've been going through and
they didn't you know they open up the
floodgates and now lenus Valley and
places like that are you know covered in
50 75 acre lots of you know subar
cannabis that's bottlenecking into the
industry and it's it makes it tough so
yeah things coming together more we all
tighten up if we have to go under we go
under but it's like we do have these
events we create it where we have people
can come direct to the farmer and get
their you know what they want and need
and know that it's grown in these
beautiful ways and then at the same time
having to keep fighting the fight of
like pushing regenerative farming and
what this does and the data and
collecting it and being like here you
know pushing that but at the same time
how are we going to make it so that's
that yeah I feel like there's a lot of
power in gathering together and creating
there too much of a barrier between the
farmer and the consumer you know way too
much talk to a lot of Bud tenders you
know unfortunately there's not as much
of a educational curve involved with it
um something that needs to be handled I
think a lot more um within you know the
the shop industry and retail industry
and whatnot but um I think that's what
DM's kind of really you know beautiful
for and what I really love about it how
it's you know a peer-to-peer Network
work of people that are on that same
wavelength that want to push that out
there and um it's What attracted me to
dragonfly Earth medicine in the first
place so educat and the people that are
directly to the consumers could be able
to help that until you know we figure
out where we're at between County and
state even you know um yeah that's
powerful like just like Craig said going
the tee out you know you walk in the
garden you're able to see where things
are growing that's so freaking important
it's so cool to be able to be able to
offer something like that too and it's
an
experience yeah yeah you use you use the
the
term also need call each other when
we're doing really well and and and not
be shy of that and and feel how we can
celebrate our successes as
well yeah absolutely and like I know
like when it comes to my dollar like I
would much rather go to like I said like
a farmers market or any any type of
popup where people are at and like I
said get like some SS and some lotions
and stuff like this last one I went to I
got like this really hand sanitizer it's
all natural and everything super cool
cheaper than what you get in the store
smells awesome works great um just like
I mean it could be anything but like I
would rather put my money in somebody's
hands like that because a lot of the
stuff like it is super quality you're
getting something better than what you
would you know see in like your typical
commercial [ __ ] store and also I
don't like going into stores man like
it's just weirds me out you know so like
farmers markets and stuff like I'm crazy
relaxing and if I got a question
normally I don't even have to ask it
people are willing to share their
passion their love and the information
and like that's super cool and like if I
was living like if we were all literally
living around each other right now and
you know you're growing like different
types of herbs and you're like you're
growing fruits and stuff like that I'd
be buying it up not just to eat but like
I I make little ferments and everything
and I'm trying to Source you know good
organically grown fruits and everything
and making little T juice and whatnot um
but you know every everything else that
surrounds it and I would tell you you
know like if you need you know seeds or
anything you know just holler at your
boy now unfortunately like we don't all
live around each other however like we
got this this internet thing right and
now I know you know n you know you yall
know me so you know don't hesitate like
we can still you know support one
another um so if you need some see
so if you need something just let me
know um one than happy like I said
donate it to you man like you know you
know money's whatever but you know um
you know there's plenty of people out
there that buy them just for whatever
and you know I'm more than happy to
share with y'all so uh if you ever need
anything just uh yeah just give me a
holler you
know can I say
something um we're almost like carrying
the torch of the back to the land
movement I mean we are carrying the
torch of the back to the land movement
and we talk a lot about Landscaping as a
garden you know we watch these French
gardening shows and uh and the the thing
that people
uh you know are transformed by seeing
these beautiful flower gardens and these
Estates and we're using this back to the
land movement values and regeneration as
this transformational
experience where people come here and
they come to Craig's farm and they see
the mycelium growing in the soil and
they're like totally blown away and
they're transformed
some you know it's a
values war in the Cannabis industry at
this point it's deep entrenched
values heartful Eco
gardening and I'm just saying it versus
this corporate Paradigm that impose
these mechanical overlays on our life
and [ __ ]
that and when people come visit us it
should be real and it should be like
emotional and it should be designed from
our heart that's the transformation I'm
going through it's like I'm over it you
know how can we be beneficial organisms
on Mother Earth exactly it's like
connection to the land is our message
and the land is an expression of where
we are Rio could you could you share you
you mentioned it's a values war and and
Rio actually took this huge Community
leadership role like five maybe six
years ago and actually performed uh a a
a work study um and came up with some
real data you could could you share that
just a snapshot of that yeah I mean I
was trained in mediation and and then my
job in the local government was uh
developing industry clusters for humble
I developed a whole process from my
trainings on how to you know get
everybody to write out sticky notes of
what their core values are and then I
got tables to come together with what
the table cons thought was the top 10
and then then we go and we put it up on
a board in front of the group and
everybody voted on their core values and
we came up with with like the top 10
core values of Southern humble and I
think there's a lot of movement right
now to do it again and kind of reassess
like hey are we living our core values
how are we doing compared to like what
we were 10 years ago and like every 10
years we could check in and see if we
have that Integrity of
like are we living according to what we
feel and you know to me that's happiness
it's like when my core values are
aligned I'm in in harmony but if I'm
broken and off of my core then I'm
stressed so I think that's an important
thing is to like reassess and uh and
stay
core with you know and not that comes
out come in
anyway but that was a beautiful process
and thank you every year I get better at
Living my core values a little bit I
would love to bring in something I'm
just I'm just now learning and I just
what you're talking about resonates so
deeply with this I don't know if
anyone's like the domination culture
versus partner ISM it's a have you heard
of the partner ISM thing yet oh my God
what a beautiful practice and what a
beautiful like lens to because I get
caught in Domination behavior all the
time and like to learn that conflict can
be redefined is when any two people get
together and that literally everything
we do is by terms of agreement and also
transparency like if we have tensions
with each other being able toj it in the
moment and have this kind of reciprocity
and like being real people together I I
can't wait to practice that in my own
community and have it with my neighbor
finally and to have it with my dearest
mother who I don't hug often enough you
know anyway I just love this community
building on this level thank you for
bringing that and I think what what
we're recognizing is that
um the structures that we were and have
been living under and we have been
looking for reciprocity we've been
looking for hey we're out here we are
now Rec recognizing that not only do
they not speak our language but they
don't want to speak our language they're
not interested in speaking our language
there was a pretend fraction of wanting
to speak our language so that we could
come
into you know uh their field of
sight so but the thing is that they
don't realize when they're dealing with
regenerative Farmers is that we've been
talking aot about seeds and we are seeds
so there's that old line you know when
they try to bury
us no problem that works for us like we
can deal with that because what you're
doing is you're showing
us how you're going to bury us and then
we're going to be figuring out as a
group in our mycelial Network where
we're going to repopulate and how we're
going to repopulate and everything that
we're talking about right now
is the most basic most
important
fraction of the
entire Vision like it's actually The Hub
of the wheel and then all of the spokes
go off of that like our happiness and
our health and our self-love comes from
Community it comes from the people
around us and that Community is also on
a microbial level and that microbial
level is balanced soil that we also come
from we are no different than that and
if we don't have a true running wheel
which means that every single spoke off
of it running true you know that Cog is
is definitely the soil and we're holding
that so what we're talking about here is
something that you can start
[Music]
everywhere everywhere it doesn't matter
if you're in downtown
you can get together a group of people
to say hey how can we get more beehives
at top all of the all of the different
buildings here how can we get more
farmers markets what is it that we can
do to uplift the frequency that is going
to hear us because that standardized
frequency the government no longer wants
to hear us they actually can't because
if language is frequency it's not words
it's frequency and the last two years
our frequency is Shifting then they
actually can no longer hear us and we
can no longer hear them so we have to go
where the frequency is the same and
that's going to happen from us
recreating the soil and nature Vibe as
mentor and no longer humans being the
mentorship we just commune around the
true the true Mentor which is nature
sorry I went off on that ramp but I
wanted to bring it together about all
this
potency that you all are talking about
here and please add anyone jump in and
our and it is a back to the land
movement and I love that our land may be
used for tourism in some cases you know
bringing people to our land you know
just
maybe uh JJ's got so much water he could
plant 27 different Willow species on the
property next thing you know JJ's a
basket Weaver making the most amazing
baskets you've ever seen you know or or
living fences still working on that
one
exactly when you're
done you put the canes in the ground and
they grow you know so shout out to
crestone shout out to crestone right
here and now just because I can say yes
to dope
goats
yes and and another thing too like don't
be afraid like spread the good word like
you know uplift your your friends and
everything you know so like you know any
post I'm making on IG like anything I'm
using to grow anybody ask me like what
to use what to grow you know I'm not
just like bullshitting because like all
the other friends of mine but you know I
don't have a problem telling a friend
like if they're giving me something to
use it didn't work good I I'll tell them
you know I'm not uh not shy about that
but um take like Nick risden you know
like um he was asking me uh you know how
to how to grow
organically um turned him on the
dragonfly and everything now he's he's
doing it up up in Michigan and
everything and like you know any people
that he talks to like you know it's it's
contagious you know what I mean um
you know when you do good for other
people's and like I said spread the good
word you know and anytime you have time
to like share some weed you know let
them know how you grow it let them know
what you use and um you know up uplift
your your friends and your you know the
people that are around you somebody
needs something you know like where I'm
from you know it's like ain't nobody
going to the Jiffy Lube or whatever like
oh yeah you got a problem with your car
yeah I got a guy for that you know he's
right around the corner you know you got
a nice you know something quality like
God's not going to jack you or whatever
you need some fruits yeah I got a guy
for that too you know you need some
moonshine yeah we got a guy for that as
well you know like we can we can still
uh we can we can still you know do that
same thing with what we're doing we
might not all be in the same local town
but you know you got you got a person
for that you know and we you know like I
said don't be afraid to you know spread
the good word you
know yeah that myum reaching out with
I really love that all of us are
connected and then also sharing
resources and things with your neighbors
we I love it at our Farmers Market how
we all trade a lot of things people come
and get my products I trade them for
different awesome foods and I just I
love that I love that so much I've got
many gifts that way of like being able
to get gifts for other PE family members
just by like trading and stuff I just I
love bartering and trading and it's
powerful and I really want to touch on
what you said Kelly with the health and
happiness and self-love and going back
to what R said about the about the the
core values all of that it's like we all
have our own core values and I feel like
once we are aligned with those core
values when we find what that is and
it's like then health happiness selflove
all that can happen and right now on
this time it just feels like a lot a lot
of us are getting shook up like I feel
for me my whole world is like kind of
falling apart but it's like Fallen back
together it's all fallen into place like
I'm realigning and re-remembering like
my purpose and I feel like that's
happening with a lot of us because it's
like so much [ __ ] happened it's like
wait a minute that this isn't me I'm not
happy this sucks and it's realigning and
finding those core values again and
going okay wait this is what feels good
because we are part of it and
reconnecting getting out of the Cities
getting out of the concrete getting out
of the pollution and getting back to
touching the soil to seeing color
therapy with our eyes of the plants to
being able to walk in a garden to even
touch a cannabis plant to touch a fruit
tree and taste it and it's like that
right there is like I feel like when
true like health and Harmony and balance
can start to happen and how it's so
important with growing your own food
growing your own medicine or sourcing it
at a place that it's grown with love and
loving and like this is evolve humans is
like we heal our we we shift you know
like we're doing telepathy soon
hopefully we'll be able to teleport to
each other soon you know these beautiful
things but all that has to happen as we
evolve this like Humanity like we have
to have more pure thought more you know
just things that can't be
hidden and uh yeah I feel like we're in
a good sense but it's realigning I feel
like all of us where we need to to be
again yeah it's like recreating
ourselves I just came up with something
which is the ego The evolutionary stacle
so I think that you know we can move you
know keep keep those parts that we need
but often it is the evolutionary Gateway
obstacle and what we've been taught in
this standardized sort of lifestyle that
we've been living is always look to
someone else for the answers and don't
share the answers with other people keep
them to yourselves everything in school
tells you don't cheat don't share only
get information from one person which is
the teacher all of this is like getting
our brain you know used to something
that is going to take us away from that
self-love and that self- happiness and I
wanted to mention too you know a as
human beings one of the things that
we're always running away from is pain
and I want to talk about like every
single one of the people that you're
seeing up here has either gone through
tremendous pain to be sitting
here whether they their Farm or whether
there's been incarceration for what it
is that they love and what they want to
do but also you know
cry having to dig up the money from
eight years ago that you never wanted to
dig up or or maybe having to risk your
children to still get medicine out into
the market and when you look at this
type of community we've come from a lot
of difficulties and in fact in the Dem
piure agreement we agree to get through
things that are difficult because we
want to delve into what is difficult and
we know that if we don't deal with
difficulty then we are not going to
arise
to you know reaching what we've always
been searching for it's like you've got
to have the compost that
reeks before you can have the soil that
you plant into so don't be afraid like
right now is a great day to compost
yourself and it's it's it's the it's
okay that it's the first day to come out
and say [ __ ] I need to re-evaluate where
I've come from from and start aligning
with those values and that frequency
that can hear me and that can that can
understand
me sorry another rant but isn't that
what we're here for rant and
[Music]
Rave I like I like to add to that first
I really love to be in that group it
really opens my heart but there is a I
think that um only in the midst of
stress or difficulty we are actually
growing when we are too comfortable what
we have uh we just sitting there and we
roding so to speak but the the the
challenges that come our life and
nothing is handed to us that we cannot
um handle then we are growing that's
that's
so uh in some way it's sometimes hard to
welcome the difficulties but if we can
shift our um way to look at it say okay
there is another thing that's
been similar
things and I have a lot of appreciation
respect for you because of you know
coming from East Germany and seeing
everything that you have
uh seeing everything that you've seen in
your life and
then possible for people because a lot
of people talk about what they can and
can't do or themelves being stuck and
all that and I get it like I don't know
what everyone's going through but it's
stories like yours and other people that
have overcome things and become such an
amazing Beacon you know in the community
I I really love and appreciate you and
those words mean a lot thank you maybe
before we end you can help maybe you uh
give us a little
visualization uh practice at the very
end of this which is coming up soon if
you're up for that we would be love to
hear to leave everybody yeah just to
leave us with a nice thought you can
think about that as we uh yeah you know
start wrapping up but there was somebody
else that wanted to say something there
Daniel you had a thought and I don't
know if you if it still pertains but
anyone else yeah you know like Kelly we
all been through pain and and having
just been witnessed to child birth
again it's incredible pain here to birth
life and you know when my wife is coming
on she goes oh we can't do this again
and on the it's so deep because on the
soul level we can't do this again we
need to keep moving forward in and what
I love about spirituality and physics is
they're very similar and like in you
know two points if you go from here to
here you're not going backwards you know
there's no going backwards there's only
going forwards but only if we learn the
lessons then you know because there is
when you start to repeat that progress
then you could say that's going
backwards but then again there's no
going
backwards and I see us moving forward
forwarding from what we've exchanged or
what was stolen what we replace clean
water in a healthy forest for and it's
crap it's utterly it's crazy if you go
into like a supermarket like a gas
station go it's all we traded this for
clean water and a healthy Forest like
to you know like they they but like the
rainbow prophecy the Hopey you know it's
we are here the the the the um the
rainbow children have grown older
they've become rainbow mothers and
rainbow fathers rainbow grandmothers and
grandfathers you know a home with talko
a we are here you know we are we have
come to you know but we find that here
this time we find the Garden of Eden
here but we're here we we love to do
stuff we you know we we want to work we
might never see those goals we might
never achieve those
dreams but we like to do stuff so we're
here in the garden we're going to clean
it up and i' like to leave my little bit
on one of the new poem I sent it to you
Josh and this is just a little
inspiration it's called mover of
mountains never let anyone tell you
you're not good enough that you can't do
it that you're never going to make it
that it is foolish to follow your dreams
after all you are an individualized drop
of the infinite Spirit a
microcosmos that through the law of
Miracles contains the very universe
itself the wave of the sea dissolves in
the sea and there is no obstacle that
can stop you no storm that can throw you
off course no matter how insurmountable
it may seem in time you will find there
is no peak too high for you are a mover
of
mountains yeah check him out uh there's
a poem called all the way that he wrote
and it's about uh overcoming uh you know
adversity and a lot of lot of a lot of
things that go along with like you know
your goal like what you what you really
want to do in life like what you truly
passionate about uh I'd highly advise uh
everybody to give that one a read super
super good and like I said you know
there's there's problems in life but
there's Solutions you know you just got
to figure it out and you know there's
mistakes and then there's successes and
understanding why the mistake was a
mistake and you know rectifying that and
you
know improving it and also understand
why you were successful like not living
and operating by happistance like
understanding why you know things are
doing what they're doing that way you
can you know become better
uh broken starving you know what I mean
uh sacrificing for what I do but like
like that poem says it you know but
you're going to do it because that's
what you really want that's what you
really love that's what you're really
passionate about and you'll keep going
and you know you might lose
relationships friends uh you know family
you know husbands wives whatever but
like you you're you're going to keep
going you're going to keep going you
might get locked up you're going to make
it through that [ __ ] too but eventually
like you know you're going to get there
and once you get there it's Priceless
it's the best thing best thing a person
can have you know so uh it just makes
you better makes you better person at
the end of the day and uh makes you
stronger and you know when something
pops up with a friend hey maybe you can
help them out have some input you know
maybe you going through something
similar you know you those that are
around you you can bring them up too you
know through experience and everything
maybe keep them from making the same
mistakes whether it's just you know
growing knowledge or business knowledge
or life knowledge or turn in a wrench or
whatever you know like just keep keep
passing it on you know we can all be
better for it you
know thanks for saying that
man um all of you you know it's been uh
been a rough couple years in this uh
world and uh I've had to make some
serious decisions in the last few months
and other decisions being made for me
and you know life um I've always you
know said like uh you know life doesn't
really get any easier we just just get
better at it try to understand the
little cues and the the messages and um
you know once I kind of
surrendered um you know I all these
opportunities came up and you know Joy
tomarrow asked me to come on out here I
was about to go you know do some farming
out in
Oklahoma and uh I was going to work with
this really cool lady that actually she
got in a car wreck when she was 16 she
lost her eyesight and some other things
happened to her and um and she uh came
to you know a place of healing through
cannabis and um it really changed her
life and uh she wanted to um you know
change the world with it and like find
people that wanted
to and um help her grow regeneratively
and poly cropping and all kinds of other
medicines were finished products and she
had some really good shops and um she
got taken advantage of by some people
out there and it really crushed her
business unfortunately you know she's
really nice person and you know
vulnerable but she could have done some
really amazing things and um but at the
same time I you know it it's hard for me
to move away from Cali you know this is
where I this where I grew up this is my
home this is my stomping grounds all
over Northern California I love this
place you know and the spirit and the
culture and the people that I've met
here people I know here it's um a really
unique place um it's changed my life but
to be able to kind of let go after so
much gone on over the last year and then
be able to come here and be able to
realize that now I get to kind of go
back to my source and grow cannabis
because I love it you know as like a
personal plant and work with all
different types of other medicines and
um I'm working with Mario from cosmic
Force Farms is helping him building the
house for his new sheep that he's
bringing in and you know he's setting up
this whole Silo pasture setup and you
know for rotational grazing and it's
just all all these beautiful things that
I you know I love so much and I you know
I dedicate so much time in knowing and
that I haven't had as much time as I
wanted last numerous years because I've
been distracted by things that don't
need to be as
important kind of took away a long time
from the point that I started doing this
in the first place um so I feel like
there's Beauty in the chaos and uh every
day I'm still learning more I'm trying
to be more perceptive of my surrounding
environment and you know and really
listen to the messages and the lessons
and um I appreciate all you guys for
what you shared today it's you know been
noteworthy and
mentionable so yeah I love you
guys I love you guys too and and I would
love to maybe uh it's get about 12:00
and I'm not sure if Marcus here back yet
but he had to go away for a little bit
but maybe we could talk one more thing
about what you're most excited about on
your farm from this last win like I I'll
just say from from from our perspective
we did a really good job of mulching
everything last year and we don't have
the opportunity to grow crops in the
winter um because it's freezing and tons
of snow had an extra amount of snow this
winter so we have to really focus on
mulching and so what we that's why we
say mulch love everything is mulch
without mulch in the dream it'll never
come true and when we're fancy we like
to say mche just because that's good
bone mche yeah but um you know we're
peeling the the garden's covered in
mulch right now like a blanket and so
now I'm just sort of using my hands and
ripping the mulch back it's just filled
everything's just moving all over and
it's like matted down so there's it's
matting like plastic wood matting weeds
down and now we're just planting new and
I just take a little pickaxe and I just
kind of pick like a pasty or a hodab and
I just pick that line just kind of fluff
up the soil a little bit take my hand go
like that and put seeds on it and then
we just cover it back up so most of the
garden stays mulched and then we just
have these little babies coming up and
everywhere around us is covered and
everything's wet right now every the
whole entire Earth is just just
everywhere you walk it's wet because of
the the snow melt um so um I'm really
excited looking at the the health of the
soil right now and in some cases we left
the greenhouse on uh Tina was talking
about how hard it is to grow in Colorado
it's extremely difficult to grow here in
the cies of British Columbia too and we
get early Frost and crazy temperatures
so we use green houses and that's why
we've dug Wall-E penies and things into
the Earth Earth and we have pipes going
into the ground six feet for like warm
air coming up and so we do have the
ability for Passive growth but we still
don't choose lights in the winter we
just go for Passive so right now as soon
as the snow melts even though it's
freezing it's time for us to plant our
seeds so I'm really excited right now
seeing the health and the crazy life in
our soil and the thing that we've gone
beyond making a compost pile now all the
aisle
and all of the gardens are the compost
any food scraps you can bury in the com
in the garden or feed to the chickens
any limbs off the trees get put in the
aisles any leaves everything the aisles
by by this time I'm looking at my aisles
from last year and it's an
incredible wealth of soil so now just F
if I want I can just fold that aisle
over onto the onto the thing and to me
that's what an IMO is that's what I want
I want my indigenous microorganisms to
grow in the garden from local materials
because that's what indigenous is
because there's life in the plants that
I'm using there's bacteria fungi and
nutrition in the plants and then that's
breaking down fusing and S sinking into
the soil and now the seeds
just pop through so I I want to tell you
guys I actually heard you talking about
this years years and years ago and I
modeled the last hle bed so it was 2500
square feet of uh you know three foot
deep and just you know like a really
nice lasagna Tech it was so Lush most
Lush Garden I ever grew and I love that
model of uh you know that that static
compost in the aisles and just keep on
taking all that brush and that over that
overgrowth and piling it in there and
stomping it down and the mushrooms and
the life that we'd get out of that space
would just explode you know and it was
so um so beautiful to see that Garden of
evolve off of you know a lot of your
guys' teachings and um you know I like
the IMO right there exactly gra that's
the easy Farm you know work that you
don't have to go out and capture
anything or add sugar to it and you can
see right there I just love it I love
this the Deep mulching so much and once
you have that you can still get those
organisms from that other environment
and you maybe may liquefy it and put it
all over all the mulch or you pack it in
just know it's going to grow so you're
always seeding
with certainly bringing white rice and
collecting things that
grow know imos can easily come from your
imos which is which is your indigenous
microorganisms which maybe you know you
can see back behind tomorrow like you
know in your farm there underneath some
of those trees and in some of those
zones they're going to be growing like
pristine plants or something and then
you would pick that little zone or that
little area you know a little tiny
handful of soil and then that's a IMO
for a billion trillion times
more I I just yeah just makes a more
sense so that's awesome I love that
fastest little with Chay and maybe Brian
did you want to say something yeah I was
gonna say that's interesting because um
what I found on this land after it was
post clearcut we came in and kind of
helped us to be that but it was really
messy and then I pushed like over a mile
of trails with help last year around the
property and even from the trails on off
the original clearcut the skitter Trails
there was a lot of deposited humus that
was turned over an humus and it opened
it up to exposure to the Sun so it was
drying out in portions but I've been
able to isolate Pockets that are kind of
getting worked but they're still fresh
and then I reintroduced like Leaf litter
and other you know microorganism based
natural litter and kind of try to
restore it naturally with fluffing it up
more and letting it grow but I've been
able to pull uh natural Forest humus out
locally here and we've shifted out of
any type of uh purchase bounty or any uh
ancient humus that's in a bag all the
way from Alaska or anywhere else so
we're actually like implementing that
that Forest humus of ours into the
compost tea that we're we know growing
our our melum flats from it and really
just having a great great turn off it so
want to share
that and Sh what were you are you doing
any new tech on the land this year and
and you you have an area of forest that
that's been cleared you're in you're
you're re re reinoculated and reworking
things what are some of the things
you're going to be doing this
year yeah we do hemp up here too it's
nice to have some high quality hemp but
really I think the bigger benefit is
actually like preparing the land
improving the land so we just harvest
the main colas and then chop and drop it
back in and spreading microbes this is
the first year that we won't have to
till you know that's a dirty word it's
something that I don't want to do but we
actually ended up on basically a glacial
till and sand for our our subsoil here
we got a couple inches of called so soil
or Forest findes maybe that we stripped
off the top but it's been hard to get
the soil structure and so we've been
turning back in organic matter a lot of
clover and Al Alpa and we're finally at
the point now we don't have to to till
anymore so I'm super excited about that
it's just a lasagna Tech from here
forward really really thick Guild or um
living mulch support species last year
and so it was nice to to see this spring
there's this heavy mat and the snow is
laid it all nice and down flat it's
decomposing super quickly because we are
pretty heavy on the microbes so it's
great to see the soil really coming
around it's gone from Sand to like this
black lomy crumb what we're what we're
looking for so that's uh that's the
biggest thing I think the most exciting
thing of all is to have the best soil
possible
because it all comes from
that and JJ what about you you
you're situation um so there's like
really especially on my spot there's
major
drainage so you know my main focus has
been and will continue to be uh bringing
organic
material um so it's just like anything
that I can grow like I've just set up a
couple gray water systems with comfrey
planted um so I can like get the uh
nitrogen from my sink for that uh
specific project um but you know I need
to get animals on the property still I
have some chickens but my chicken setup
through the harsh winter wasn't really
ideal so I had some deaths that in that
you know Department um but yeah like you
know my focus is definitely going to be
on organic material either sourcing it
from Neighbors or um you know finding a
way to either grow more things like
Alfalfa and and things like that
so on Down the Line Craig how about you
you had a spectacular Garden last year a
field of giant plants you know looked
like a field you know you know but still
it was just and I love the way you used
the straw bales and
every last year was our first year of
scaling the farm down Again by another
7,000 square feet um so we're down to
like 10,000 like I said earlier and that
was exponential difference you know we
grew 10 different cultivars nine are on
a menu at a a local shop and the 10th is
waiting to be released as our next uh
Farm cured extraction extracted rosin so
getting smaller was really beneficial um
but to answer your specifically Josh we
we took our our um cover cropping to
like the next level we wanted to uh
consider our cover crop or offseason
crop as as as the main goal of the farm
you know during the winter time here in
Humble County we get a lot of rain we
get really nice growing temperatures for
greens right so we're growing you know
fava Bell vetch um these types of plants
as and and we made due diligence at the
end of harvest last year to get in
immediately and um we grew out probably
one of the best cover crops we've ever
produced and and going into a drought
season um we feel the most uh the most
beneficial thing we could do and Dr Lane
Ingam was just here about uh the end of
January and she she really spoke to that
she gave a whole presentation about
organic material in your soil and
organic matter um will really help with
water preservation
you know that was kind of like one of
the models you keep hearing me talk
about through the whole process was not
what are we doing to make more money how
are we saving the money and how are we
saving the water how are we saving the
resource how are we working with our own
farm and our own way of keeping that all
here whether it's the water um and our
and we're really blessed to have uh
the uh I gu agriculture we have in
Humble County so I kind of look at
closing my Loops within the county um
we've got an ocean we've got the
farmlands we we're working with an
organic Dairy to get their compost uh
not even their compost it's it's their
uh raw
manure we're able to get loads of this
uh amazing alal Al now um so I our goal
one day would probably be to close the
loops like within our little region of
you know us and Rio and Lady sativa but
at the moment we're working within
Humble County we mentioned mushroom Mike
at the beginning he's growing in seeding
spawn of mushroom into the native tanos
and then those tanos are producing the
mushroom to go to culinary and Farmers
Market U mushrooms and medicinal reies
and then all those mushroom blocks are
coming back to the farm so we're
constantly taking these Forest Products
and and ocean products and and just
moving them around the county and kind
of doing what the salmon and the bear
and the rivers did um but at the moment
we're using a little bit of of uh you
know fuels but we're trying to be as
efficient as we can to move those
products around and and kind of keep
that Loop closed within our County and
and again it's like all this knowledge
share is is like so important and and I
appreciate everybody you know so many of
the things we're talking about whether
it's the genetics or or specific tip um
the biggest tip I would probably share
with everyone is um one of our ways of
terminating our cover crop is it's we
call it skier or grown Tech and I pull
out these old skis that I have and I
literally sidestep my cover crop down
and um some people are say well why
don't
terminate on my cover crop so having
that time for the beneficials and and
all my insects to move around is super
beneficial so I would say uh yeah take a
moment and think of other ways to
terminate your cover crop um even if you
have a bigger Farm sometimes just backd
dragging the the the loader bucket of
your tractor if you have that big of a
farm where you don't have the human
capacity to to do that but just get away
from tilling as as best you can and no
judgment you know every everybody takes
their own process to get to that we were
in smart pots for the first couple years
we tried taking smart pots to the next
level cardboard line cover crops
potatoes all that and then finally you
know we just dump those out onto Rosa
cardboard and
so everyone along the
process I really appreciate that Craig
so much that was very beautiful and I
love that your grown Tech where you just
take your skis and push it over and I
just want to you know say that that you
know that can be done on a thousand
acres you know like rolling and crimping
is what's you know that is what they
call it on a on a large scale and it's
just taking a tractor and putting a Big
Barrel in front of it and just running
the tractor over the the crop and just
pushing it over and that's like what no
till looks like on a thousand acres and
then there's a disc that goes behind it
and just splits the the cover crop and
then you plant in that spot so that's
nice to know that something that's so it
seems like a you know Grassroots Farm
level can be is also tech for you know
saving the whole entire world thousands
of Acres you know Josh I'm going to drop
just one little bit of information that
we've been doing too and that is um you
we brought a trencher on to to trench in
some some piping and some some
electrical lines and then I was
push up anywhere I was remember where
everything is but then I took it to the
next level and I started trenching like
the floor of my greenhouse and my
Pathways and filling it all with wood
chips and a little bit of compost and
building all these biological batteries
within my property and all these sinks
of biology so um just always think about
like when you're doing one task how you
can over overlap those systems and and
when you're going to put soil back in
the earth covering something up what
could you put back in its place as well
to to
buffer so good so good B I guess on Down
the Line maybe briy best friend fars
will go up that's what I'm seeing on my
screen go Bri what's up
newer pure farmer you've gone changes
you're transforming a clearcut
you excited about we know that you're
doing a lot of new stuff up and huge UPS
to all the main
Farmers yeah yeah really yeah thank you
and I same and like really proud of how
people are doing it here in Maine we've
been able to stay uh medical kind of
stubbornly but also you know by choice
so and we're approaching it like a small
craft and small batch mentality which
main kind of is anyway so really proud
of that but um I'm excited about always
about compost and after we're here for
our fifth year it's finally starting to
get uh to the point where it's got such
a good Continuum and the biomass that
just comes from the even the smaller
scale hemp and cannabis is so amazing it
seems like between like the carbon and
the nitrogen ratio and and the local
cultures or spores that are within back
to it so we got a great Continuum for
rebuffing the soil and I think that that
would be probably the easiest thing to
share maybe or that I don't know a lot
of in depth anyway scientific based info
but I know that we can all on any scale
compost back in the cities in the
country and really make our own compost
just from the circular Continuum of the
Cannabis and the hemp almost entirely
and we're introducing good like local
fruit bodies we had a great mushroom
year so we went out and collected stuff
that was like dying back and I got you
know multiple different sports to add in
it seems to be popping up fruit bodies
even into the organic indoor it's it's
working there and I would say that I'm
actually really excited to learn so much
today and thank all you guys for you
know paying it back to Mother Earth
because it's definitely it's needed it's
it's man or humans rather have have kind
of scarred the Earth in a way that has
allowed us to live here in subside so it
just feels like the most important task
that we're all taking pretty seriously
and um rejuvenating the Earth where
we've you know cleared to live to have
animals to farm so the regenerative
Mission just seems so uh needed more
than ever right now and I'm super happy
to be part of it and learned from all
you guys today I would say that thank
you Josh and Kelly like totally answered
a question or not question but like I
had motivation to fill my aisles after
we correct our hemp field more this year
for our rais beds and getting it to the
no tail point so I'm I'm GNA just fill
up the aisles with the with the local
biomass and you know scraps and and the
wood from the clean out of the stuff
that's already down and and rotting so
we're really going to try to just make
it not as much of the I guess aisle idea
with it or Rose maybe as much as it is
building so incredibly potent and uh one
last thing that I wanted to say before
we and Duke I don't know know I I sort
of had a feeling that you may know that
Bukowski poem by heart so if that's
something that you wanted to recite and
then we could end with Alexandra in a
thought that would be really awesome
because I'm feeling that from you that
you know that and I have I have a Vibe
on that but one thing I wanted to just
say in leaving with everybody is the
word legacy we've been talking about it
a lot tonight and like this idea of like
Legacy and like leaving a legacy and you
don't leave a legacy with things and
stuff you live you leave a legacy with
heart and soul you leave a legacy with
fruit trees and beautiful soil so that
your children have your seeds that they
can just go out and put them in the
ground so that they can be taken care of
you leave a legacy by supporting other
people who are leaving that same kind of
Legacy so you know the re-evaluation of
what that word is but uh and one one
thing just really quickly like to say
I'd like to just give thanks to the
birth of our granddaughter and I like to
say as a legacy Kelly as a midwife in
our home on the land on our own
terms having our children at home you
know these are the legacies you know
this is the this is nature this is
evolution this is regeneration it's it's
powerful and uh I just feel really
grateful and thankful giving the
opportunity for the ultimate optimal
outcome and that's what we're all doing
here is we're giving opportunity for the
ultimate outcome and I just appreciate
you all so much and I wanted to hand it
um over to Duke uh because I I'd love to
hear
it well I was too afraid to recite it
off the mind I was like running risk of
butchering it and then I'm going to have
like some angry Poet Society hunt me
down and beat me up
so definitely uh I'll just read
it Charles Bowski go all the way if
you're going to try go all the way
otherwise don't even start this could
mean losing girlfriends wives relatives
or maybe even your mind it could mean
not eating for 3 or 4 days it could mean
freezing on a park bench it could mean
jail it could mean derision it could
mean mockery isolation but isolation is
the gift all others are just a test of
your endurance and how much you really
want to do it and you'll do it despite
the rejection and the worst odds and it
will be better than anything you can
imagine if you're going to try go all
the way there is no other feeling like
that be alone with the gods and the
nights will flame with fire and you will
ride life straight to perfect laughter
it's the only good fight there
is want to give thanks to everyone out
in the world watching us take this and
make the world a better place in in your
in your world go do something good we
love you and last thoughts big thanks to
uh Marcus for continuing to hold this
space we may not be learning how to make
rosin right now for the first time but
we are feeling each other on a way that
we have never felt before which makes
better rosin in the
end it all it it it is a better hash
thank you
Alexandra
M I like to first of all
acknowledge the mod itself I like to
acknowledge the land that you are all
residing on with your physical
body the ones that are here on the
circle and the ones that are watching I
like to acknowledge the people of that
land that have walked and lived there
long before we came I like to to
acknowledge you here present and your
ancestors that have passed on the life
to you as you have passed on life to
your children I acknowledge life in the
macro as much in the micro life that we
are seeing and life that we are not
seeing I like to acknowledge the
uniqueness of life that comes through
all of you in such a beautiful
way and in our
heart space we shall connect to each
other we shall accept the light of the
Earth in our heart at the light of the
cosmic heart to mared with each other
victim and
victimizer the same so that we and they
can remember the light in the love that
exists in our heart and that they can
remember that they shall shall follow
disl
W thank
you I think we should just leave it at
that I love you guys so much love you
all love you all who are watching
everybody thank you all so much for
today peace
out never it's never too late much
love garden