got
it all right all right here we go about
to go live here talk about good timing
at CH GE if I hadn't sent it to you I'd
be in here alone right now welcome
everybody has Church 4.0 episode
6 potentially going to be a very small
intimate hash church today can you hear
me I
can yes can you hear me I can absolutely
I can hear you welcome welcome how are
you doing this
morning I'm doing good sir I just kind
of woke up and saw there was a hash
Church who was like oh
[Laughter]
I I I guess I must not have your email
because I used to do all the invitations
via that Facebook messenger and I just
sent out an email I to the same group I
sent out last week which I remembered I
or the week before which I spaced having
you on it and so um yeah it was kind of
last minute I think Colin said he'd try
to come in and the dragonfly Earth
Madison said they would try to come in
and I think Mark Mark sheldone also Dr
Mark said he would try to come in and
even Neo maybe it was Neo Mark too that
instead of Mark shalone I can't even
remember maybe I didn't even invite Mark
I can't even remember now
so anyway you know what we'll have a
little gathering here even if it's just
you and I we can chat for a little bit
and uh discuss what's kind of going on I
just like uh being available for the
good folks here that are waiting on the
regular for us to come on these Sundays
and it's kind of a nice uh
nice way to spend an hour or two on the
on a Sunday morning
so so how are things been going in your
neck of the woods it's uh fall coming in
it's harvest how is Harvest coming along
for
people well you know um I got to say
like from an outdoor uh situation I I
have just seven small plants on my deck
and uh I got to say they're um looking
phenomenal like it's surprising how
phenomenal they're looking my phone's
vibrating here but I don't know why oh
Angel he's calling me up but I can't
answer the phone because I'm on Hatch
turs right now sorry
dude I
know I know no the plants look
incredible we haven't had any rain I
don't know if it's the same all the way
down there but there's literally been
like
let me get to
my anybody else hear him
am I the only one that his mic go out
can you hear me
everybody
hello Marcus we can hear you there you
go there you go
back all right NOP you C your audio cut
in and cut out again
well hi everybody Welcome to Hash church
I'm not sure what's going on but we're
having some minor technical issues with
bubble
men um it comes in it comes out and then
it goes off and then comes back on I
cannot hear you at this time I think
people can hear me for a second I have
an
idea y there popped in there we go
all right so they can hear me you were
popping in and
out I think we're going to have to do a
bong bong
rip pretty sure y yeah he's he's going
out again everybody yeah you come in and
go out
no can I hear
you I don't know
why they can hear me Marcus
unfortunately they're blaming they say
it's the beard of knowledge that is
causing the issue
[Laughter]
I oh I got you back now there you go
yeah that was me getting a call from
skunkman Sam on Facebook messenger and
that just completely took my airpods
away it completely took my ability to
talk away and hear
any okay sorry about that guys little
technical difficulties there um where
was I I was talking about um
harvesting stuff on your deck yes stuff
on my deck so yeah they look amazing
dude they look better than anything I've
grown Outdoors I'm not a big outdoor
grower um I I always kind of grew
indoors but I gave these things a little
bit of sort of uh that was the medy one
sort of that organic Earth Juice type
food for maybe two or three
feedings I never measured it I never
phed the water or the you know the food
afterwards I just kind of like the
minimal amount and then um I give been
giving it water for the last like month
month and a half and the resin
production is absolutely phenomenal it's
shockingly phenomenal in fact I wish the
plants were bigger hey welcome Dr
Mark hey boys how are
you oh not too bad got my audio and my
my my yeah my audio back I I lost it
there for a second and was talking into
the into the ethers so that was kind of
fun I haven't had one of those moments
in a while where I was like
troubleshooting while we're completely
[Laughter]
live yeah well that's like live
television right you never know how it's
gonna
go yeah exactly you never know how it's
going to go not that I've ever really
done live television but uh I've
certainly done enough this this is this
this ver this today's version of live
television this is it Marcus we've been
living right yeah true enough and uh
someone told me the other day that we've
been doing this for like eight years is
that does that sound right have we' been
doing this for eight
years uh is that
right yeah I mean I think it was uh
2015 when Horatio first hit me up and
said you need to come out and straighten
out this Tony vzer guy who's talking all
kinds of chemistry and he goes I know
from talking with you on Facebook that
you know
what you're talking about so he he
wanted me to come into that discussion
guns blazing but I was like no I know
Tony I had I had been out to Colorado
once Mark and had hung out with Tony
because Pinsky made an introduction and
I think didn't we do a hash Church from
Tony's Place one time with Pinsky there
yeah definitely there was definitely I
seem to remember that because a AJ was
there
too I
Tony AJ me and Pinsky because me and
Pinsky were were rolling out west Y no I
do remember that absolutely that was
that's going back that's uh wow rest in
peace to Horatio for sure every time I
think about him it makes me a little sad
gone gone way too soon he was
instrumental in in in in introducing us
as as you know I mean I had developed an
online kind of interaction with him kind
of like on on the underside it was it
was before Facebook too I forget how he
had reached out to me but I think it was
through some kind of Internet exchange
on
chemistry yeah rest unbelievable
unbelievable how fast time goes by
welcome uh welcome Josh dragonfly Earth
medicon and I see Colin also punching in
here for a
little for a little Sunday morning half
Church oh maybe we're actually going to
hear him play music remember in eight
years we have not heard him play those
keyboards
[Music]
hell yeah how goes the Harvest
Josh a lot of background noise on my
computer for some reason but uh it's
going really well it's going really well
we're all really excited uh it's been
probably the most amazing fall you know
in British colia that you know let's say
anyone can remember so you know this is
our first chance that really seeing what
what strains do you know up here uh
without getting attacked by buritis or
whatnot you know we live in the mountain
valleys and they easily get clogged up
with moisture and stuff but yeah
spectacular Year all the flowers get to
really Express themselves show their
flavor show their colors we made amazing
seed this year so we're really excited
to go to these new Gatherings that are
happening the next ones the organic Cup
in
Michigan uh which Colin went to the one
out in New York and told us about a bit
about it and uh now it's happening in
Michigan so uh we're really excited to
go out to Michigan meet up with the
family there's some new demm pure
Farmers uh out there and in Maine and
hopefully a couple of them will join us
today Connor TP wizard
and uh hunter from Hidden Forest up in
Maine hopefully they join us today
they're also going through Harvest and
washing um yeah I haven't started
washing too much hash yet from this year
but I'm really excited to get into it
so yeah things are really good up here
other than the the bear and the deer
which we've already talked about have
really done a number on our farm
so hopefully it's been uh Been a Good
Year of like you know learning about
what the next season will bring for you
guys on the genetic side you know and
just kind of paying attention to the
things that are going on in the garden
and you know from the plant for
morphology to resistance and you know
just just understanding what the next
season will look like I think is you
know it's always a nice preview into the
you know previous years genetics you
know
so quite a bit with the heavy range that
just ensued but you know luckily I start
started covering things and and really
just making sure that the at least the
rain wasn't on top of the plants um you
have Heavy
Rain Man I was in California for it but
apparently yesterday or the day before
it was Thursday or something it was like
all day it just rained all day I we six
millimeters in like four
months wow yeah it was it was crazy I
mean the East Coast just a different
world but it just you know East Coast
man we can have like 20 inches of rain
the last month of your of your crop and
just it changes your world you know so
it's it's a very different environment
um you know everything could be going
perfect until August and September and
then October rolls around and it's just
you're you get beat up you know so it's
um it's really important to be proactive
I saw on Brian's uh best friend Farm's
Instagram yesterday that they got 4 Ines
of rain in 24 hours exactly
you know that's our whole and welcome
Connor I'd love to hear from you in in
just one second um I was just going to
say on the rain tip I mean we we we have
to prepare for Armageddon every fall
type thing too that's why we have seven
different green houses on our property
they're all different styles we keep we
sort of always keep the walls up every
really the greenhouse is just a roof in
the springtime it's a it's walls and an
end wall and all that we get the early
we don't even need that early start
because honestly starting in May or or
right in that and getting that late
spring window when it's really warm out
like the plants totally catch up you get
an incredible year so there really isn't
any need to rush it early in the season
so really our green houses are mainly
just a roof they're a roof just to keep
acid rain off the buds just kidding but
probably that too um but you know and
and also just rain in general and then
we have to be careful about humidity and
just flow through humidity but that's
the one thing you know that we we really
we start our light depths June 1 or
middle of June so that we can at least
have one good greenhouse that's probably
going to do well by be being done in the
middle of August Because by the end of
August we can plan on rain but this year
we did get rain in the end of August we
got a week weeks worth of rain in the
end of August here in the cies and it
did [ __ ] with some PLS but and and
honestly we've done so much soil
building on our property over the years
this is probably the first year we
didn't use any te's on any of our
property because it was totally
unnecessary plants had zero bugs zero
mold zero issues no trellising the odd
plant got tall and heavy and fell over
during some winds but we just put some
bamboo in it and St staked it up most of
our plants are just self they just hold
themselves up you know and and we let
them blow around all year so they
continue to be strong and it's sweet for
us so anyway that's that um but welcome
Connor turp wizard from Michigan how you
doing today
brother I'm doing great um just trying
to get some of my soil beds uh tucked in
for the winter and get everything
prepped um before it gets to too cold
out here we had a really nice season
this year um I picked some spots in the
woods that are a little bit more shady
so things started flowering sooner which
means they ended sooner as well and I've
been really uh enjoying growing in the
woods compared to um the
yard that's cool that's cool and and
also plant magic Homestead is the farm
that you just certified which is all the
outdoor the
genetics uh really enjoyed growing your
genetics this year just by the way we
had a lot of really good results from
the all the strains that we they got
from you and and even the GMO which we
told you in the spring was the one one
of the one plants in the greenhouse that
didn't get eaten by mice now I don't
know if you can put mice resistant on
the
label but it didn't get eaten by
mice so anyway yeah the strawberry jelly
the which I you can tell us the real
names but sometimes I just put the
actual cross on there because it's
easier for me to see what the plant is
while it's growing so that I can Vibe on
oh this is a a grape cream cake by
banana OG or this is a strawberry pie by
grape cream and then I just get the vibe
on what the plant's
expressing yeah thanks for making space
in your garden for um the SE that I made
last uh last year you guys knocked out
of the park I was uh super impressed
with all the Expressions that it um they
uh brought out in your space and it's
been fun to see people in different um
microclimates grow it here in our state
as well as others and see what
Expressions they're getting
um yeah it it just shows you know
breeding Under the Sun and growing It
Outdoors you get a little bit extra
Advantage when the the plants are made
in the environment they'll be grown
in make sense makes sense welcome by the
way TP wizard I don't think we've ever
met but uh nice to have you here on hash
church and Josh spoke highly of you and
uh yeah it's good to have you here I
also got to say shout out to Wade
laughter in the house and skunkman Sam
who both uh showed up here in the last
little bit sorry for so many mistakes
today guys I guess I don't know what
happened but some somehow I must have
started a different oh it's hand
speaking but I can't hear
him can everyone hear
me yes I hear I hear
you's having a conversation with
somebody in in his room yes yes that's
uh it freaked me out I've had so many
different glitches today that emails
aren't going I somehow started the a
different Zoom link than the zoom link I
sent to everyone so uh yeah I'm dropping
ball a little bit over here I'm not
going to lie a little bit of ball
dropping going on but uh we're all here
it's good welcome
everybody nice to see some some new
faces in the
room um uh also uh hunter from Hidden
Forest out in Maine might jump on he's
also harvesting and and doing some last
minute washes out there too as well
hopefully he jumps in um not sure what
everyone wants to talk about I know
Connor you were involved in the smoking
jacket did you go out to that that event
out in California and then you visited
Some Farms maybe tell us a little bit
about the entries of the smoking jacket
possibly if that sounds interesting to
everyone yeah it was a really cool event
to be a part of um I've never been or
competed at a uh event with that caliber
of people from all over the US usually I
only get the opportunity to um compete
here in Michigan if at all and it it was
nice to meet some of these people who
I've seen their work um online and man
it was hard choosing a a winner out of
that box there was a lot of good stuff
it was interesting to
see um where most of the profiles were
leaning in that box there's a lot of
fruit very little um gas um from knows
it seemed like there's like a lot of
papaya and and Skittles uh dominant
profiles in there and yeah I don't get
too many opportunities to go out to
California so it was a really great uh
trip for me and then you know spending
half my trip in LA and getting
experience that and then going up north
into um the humbled area and then into
Southern Oregon and visiting uh alpen
glow and Kush Kirk um it was a really
magical
trip to kind of have the yin and the
Yang of the city and the forest all in
one um week you know I wish I had more
time out there and uh yeah it was it was
a really magical experience for
me you got lots of people shouting you
out in the chat room dude people uh one
guy says he's super looking forward to
uh linking up with you in at cream asene
next
Saturday uh sticky flower farm says yo
Connor you're d Alona grown in Oklahoma
smells like Welch's grape
soda and there was a few others shouting
out so good to good to see you making uh
making some waves in the turp
steam yeah it's been really awesome to
see all these people who I sent seeds
out to and got to meet over the last
year um make space in their Garden for
some seeds that I made in my backyard
you know I don't really consider myself
a breeder I kind of like you know
working with the hash plants that I I
have available and then finding a male
that's interesting to me and you know
combining them and seeing what they do
um you know obviously there's certain
traits that I'd like but I don't know if
I'm quite as uh experienced as some
other people who
would uh you know call themselves a
breeder you know but I kind of just say
I'm a my my seed projects I'm making
seeds I I don't I don't know if I'm
quite ready for that but yeah it's been
really sweet to see everyone 's
um results and to see what the male was
bringing into the equation because I was
pretty familiar with the female stock of
everything and um yeah it's been some
Stellar
results be
beautiful what are some of the varieties
that you've made this
year so I uh selected a male from Kush
Kirk's blueberry watermelon uh times
melon bread and I slapped it too um a
couple different fenos of guava yogurt
which is frozen froo times uh Lucy's
diamonds and then uh pancakes from a
fishon sugarcoat from
schale uh choca colola and Sour Diesel
from skunk Tech
uh GMO which is a local um cut there's
like a couple GMO Cuts floating around
Michigan um and
then I've got a crder Gaya which was
selected from JJ Michigan regenerative
farmer so that's kind of like a little
Michigan Dem uh
collab um I think there's one or two
more that I'm drawing a blank on but got
like the male the male that you used
have have you is it uh alive I mean do
you keep the mail alive for the next
year no I'm going to be selecting uh a
mail probably from the F2 stock I made
um and then just keep finding new males
just you know I pop a lot of seeds so I
like to find something that's
interesting um that catches my eye and
that has some lineage that is more
towards um the half side like I'll grow
out some of the females see what the
Expressions I'm seeing from that and
kind of hope that some of those traits
get transferred over and um the reason I
was mentioning that was because you know
you can take a male clone and with Ethyl
on you can transform it to a
female and then you get a really good
idea of what trines and cannaboids it
has the ability to maybe pass on to its
projecty it's a lot more sophisticated
breeding what was the name of that
compound that you were saying Sam well
it's called ethelon but what it is it's
ethylene gas uh yeah I I think it's
ethelon is the is the technical name on
it but uh what I'll do is uh on hash
church I will post the name of the
chemical and the name of the paperwor
they talk about using it but what's nice
about it unlike SDS which you can use to
make uh uh mascul uh female clones and
uh the if you do that well that works
very good you make all female crops but
this is not dangerous so it's the same
thing that comes out of
bananas you know and if you want to
ripen up fruit faster you can put it in
a paper bag with rip bananas well this
does this same thing but wham bam thank
you ma'am the male will turn female uh I
think I've showed uh Marcus photos of
the work before and uh yeah it's it's
it's not so good for form because uh
some of the uh the the the female that
the the male that gets transformed into
a female doesn't look particularly
female form it has more of a masculine
wispy form but the flowers the resin the
Turpin they all uh show up and you can
get a really good idea what it has the
ability to give from that
female Sam is that um I feel like that's
a
diamond that you just
dropped it is you dropped what my my
question to you Sam is that similar to
you can smoke it is it a is it like
selfing but with a with ethylene correct
it's like selfing except for you're with
selfing what you're doing is you're
taking a a female and making male pollen
with this you're taking a male and
you're making a female from it got it so
it's the reverse of it yeah amazing that
is a Jem yeah and it's smokable unlike
anything you've done with STS you cannot
smoke it in fact you can't even really
handle STS it's dangerous right yeah
yeah that's for those that don't know
that is like the sage wisdom was just
cast upon
us join hurch Facebook grou did you P
also as well there
Sam what people have to do in the past
was you had to take a mail keep it alive
for a few years as a clone hit your
ladies with it and then grow those seeds
out and find out so it was a several
year process for you to find out when
you field tested the progyny seeds that
you actually produced with this one it
it can for example if you have 10 skunk
number one males this will immediately
show you which one has the most resin
which one is the you know it really
really points in the direction and when
I first did this about because I had
been using my skunk mail for maybe a
decade or longer then I I tried this on
it and I was shocked and surprised how
sweet the mail was in other words people
are always saying oh you breed the skunk
out of skunk you know but uh I did it
because I preferred the high the smells
The Taste the effects and uh it's my
creation of course of course I could do
what I want and uh but what what I found
out was that the mail I had been using
for the last decade was even sweeter
than the
[Laughter]
girl I think find that out too
right that's a serious gem you just
dropped there and for those of you that
want more information on that you would
be implored to join the Facebook hash
church group because that's where Sam's
going to post this information and uh
amazing that it uh like Sam has so much
information in his head that he can't
just put it all out there we have to
have conversations for now I think eight
years for that to get extracted so thank
you Sam thank you T
wiard of
Sam usually when I'm sitting in my chair
some of it sort of just leaks out my ear
247 it's awesome dude and and Josh
inviting uh turp wizard in because it
was really turp wizard who somehow
pulled that out of out out of you there
and uh man I'm glad we did this that
right there was worth past church today
that's that's like I don't know if
everyone understands how [ __ ] insane
and profound that information was and I
I'm not sure if you heard this what Sam
just said best friends but uh if you
didn't yeah when it's really really
important is let's say you have 10 or 20
males of the same variety and you don't
know which one is the best one to use
you can either use them all or you can
actually pre-screen them using this get
it down to two or three then use those
separately with your ladies and find out
which truly is the best of the two or
three or if all three of them are
good well I guess that's how church
like that's a
w the mic drop that's
yep it'll be seven years from now so
some G be like hey do you remember what
hash that was when Sam talked about that
chemical that he put on the bananas or
something like I don't remember exactly
can you tell me what number that was and
what time he said that I think the
chemicals name is ethelon but uh if I
you know my memory is a piece of switch
cheese
so I don't know we'll pull
it cv1 receptors yeah exactly did you
hear what he was saying though
Brian about gender bending yeah I just
CAU I just CAU that with out of the 10
males uh select the two to
three you know the top two before that
he's turning males into females to check
their tpine and and cannaboid profiles
with with this with this chemical that
yeah yeah yeah just say it one more time
Sam we need this twice oh okay basically
what it is it's using ethelon and you
spray it on a mail just as you're GNA
begin to flower it and it will turn
female it will produce you know 99%
female instead of male flowers if you
didn't spray one par particular area
maybe you might get a few male flowers
but uh then it allows you to test the
the uh with the gas chromatographer or
whatever you can test the turpine and
the cannabinoid profile and you get a
really good idea of what that
male uh can give as part of the
inheritance package that it's going to
get and Sam you could potentially clone
that male
beforehand right and then have a few of
those males around yeah I us on the
female from absolutely but you can't you
can't it's only a temporary
transformation doesn't permanently
change it's it's like if you use
SDS uh you know it's not a permanent
transort the DNA hasn't changed all
that's changed is the sex expression you
know in the case of STS you're making a
female produce male pollen in this case
using ethelon to produce a male that
produces female
flowers in
uh expression so you can analyze it and
see what it is not only that but you can
smoke it it's totally safe so would you
recommend that as opposed to we used to
use gilc acid back in the day to turn
the female to male is that what you
would use now but gabic acid is again is
female to male and I'm talking male to
female it's a it's a completely
different picture no no I understand I
was just wondering if there was a
different well Gill acid Gill rubic acid
didn't even particularly well turn uh
females to male because it also made
them stretch I mean it it it was [ __ ]
ation when I did that with Ed that's
what it happened it causes
a just compared TOS it's a growth
hormone so that makes sense that yeah
because that I got turned on a dilic
acid because when I was working on bonai
if you're trying to elongate a
particular Branch for like a Chinese uh
you know drop style or Japanese uh
cascading Etc you would use that chilc
acid and that's how I got turned onto it
and then started applying it to can
which we did get male pollen from but
the stretching and elongation made it
very challenging in smaller
rooms ex exactly uh I had a 20 foot tall
greenhouse and I find Gil ribic acid
unmanageable so don't you usually use
gibberelic acid with collodial silver if
you're going to use it for I don't use
codal silver I use STS it's much better
it it's just it's it's a toxic compound
where colloidal silver is not so some
people can still they could use collidal
silver if they want because you can
ingest collodial silver in your eyeballs
and in your body okay well I've never
used collodial well actually we did
about 25 years ago we tried every
different known method and collodial
silver was one of them so was gilic and
uh but what we found out was that STS
was absolutely the best the most
reliable
the only problem is if you're going to
transform a female to male you have to
make sure that female doesn't have the
Tendencies to express intersex because
then
you yeah yeah you enhance the
intersection yes
exactly um we just recently walked
through a hem field out in Colona and
there is a licensed cultivar called
Umpqua
that's up here and one more anyway and
it was it's Fe feminized seed and uh we
walked through the field and there's
probably like a good
four or five different fenos in that
field which I I thought was sort of
surprising and I didn't know if one of
the methods that of feminizing is less
stable than the other but I thought with
feminizing it would just be a little bit
more stable than that even though a lot
of it
was and it was it was actually a really
sweet CR they
wereing probably what they were doing
was using poly multi hybrids for either
their male pollen source and transformed
female to male pollen Source or they're
females and when you have poly hybrids
and you breed them poly
hybrids you're going to get multiple
phenotypes which can either be an
advantage or a disadvantage depending on
what your purpose is most people who
cultivate want to get a large crop of
Fairly identical stuff so that they can
you know do the cood and the analyzation
and everything else as a package rather
than each separate
plan yeah and so Josh you know I grew a
lot of those varietals in the states
here and I had a chance to do like super
hay you know couple different sour Thea
the lifter a bunch of them and what I
really noticed is what Sam just said is
that they're definitely using poly
hybrids and even probably Crossing those
poly hybrids with other groups of poly
hybrids and that in and of itself when
you looked at the field is like
different smells different you know
different structure different resistance
you know so it was really fascinating to
see that over 58 acres and just kind of
like look at it and be like okay
distinctively these rows are the same
but they're also very different you know
um so the like the CH profiles were you
know from lifter were like ranging from
sour to gassy you know like it just you
know and the oqua was like very spicy
and you know um very uh just reminded me
of older varietals from like the the
early 90s and late 80s yeah one of the
other handy things that you can do with
uh
ethalon is you can use it to create a
all male
variety from seed so uh the first year
you do you make the cross of uh uh a
male and a female that have been a trans
well the the male was transformed to a
female and then you use a straight male
on it 25% of the seeds will be
uh y y and uh if you select those one
you'll have to find which ones they are
because they're not all then uh you you
can easily produce crops which are 100%
male which uh most people there's no use
for that but for fiber in theory an all
male crop would be better because there
would be no problems with the police
because if there's no female plants then
you don't have a problem and uh if
they're all male male fibers actually
finer a little bit finer than female
fiber so it produces uh finer woven
fabrics if you're interested in that do
you recommend any kind of
decorticator uh any kind of small sort
of home style decorticator to where
people could put their hemp stocks in it
and make the fiber and the herd or they
could take Nettles nettle F how how many
plants well I've seen ones on Oli Baba
and different things for you know four
or $5,000 so some something like that
and plantwise I mean I don't know I'm
talking for the sustainable farmer where
maybe you're doing an acre or
three well then you you you you need a
real device not just a a toy because
I've done it by hand and uh that's what
I yeah Gardella out of Italy makes
larger machines I know domestically
there's only small producers I know John
lupian out of Oklahoma I mean pardon me
out of Nebraska uh was making one
because he took the old decorators uh
and kind of made one that was toad but I
know that back in the day Gardella made
the finest ones that you could just tow
to a
tractor and they would uh it would
basically separate the herds from the
wet fire F so the wet fiber would just
be hanging on a rod and then you could
just pull that off and then dry it um
are they still around Sam
Gardella uh I think so but you know I I
haven't been keeping in touch with the
the hemp industry the way I used to so I
I can't really say I mean i' I've seen
all kinds of sophisticated French
Italian Hungarian Etc uh Machin
Czechoslovakian polish
but uh I don't know which one is the
best and the most practical depending on
your crop size because also whether
you're going to do it like you say fresh
or dried because traditionally it was
done dried now uh it if you can do it
with wet it might be faster and easier
and what he's talking about is the
reading because uh back in the day you
used to field red I.E let it sit in the
field and let the bacteria eat the
ignant off of it the problem with would
cause it to to turn gray a lot of that
polar shmp would turn if you did that AB
absolutely all the French was gray even
the Italian was gray and so Eastern
Europe we would actually take large
baths which they had large concrete
baths and they would soak them and so we
would water R it so that the bacteria in
the water slowly did that and that way
we kept the golden color of the hemp so
that's how we did it by water reading um
whereas the Gardella machine it pulls it
off green so if you were able to dry
that properly it should come out golden
as well because you're no longer dealing
with the bacteria eating the agnostic uh
glues that hold the plant together
externally sorry to nerd out there
people oh no you're I love it I was just
gonna also just put in um Danny and her
father from the Colorado hemp project
they do amazing a lot of amazing workout
in Colorado with uh
industrializing uh you know
decortication and stuff and and fibers
and they do different things in the
world and I've been meaning to get in
touch with her she's really amazing
somebody is saying herd Master Hurd
Master uh comes up on Google looks like
they have some medium scale offerings
somebody is saying um um specifically
Tony neg in uh chat so thank you Tony
yeah if if you have a million dollars
and I know a lot of people don't have a
million dollars but if you do have Aon
million dollar or if you have Rich Uncle
who's got a million dollars go look at a
thing called The Hemp train hemp train
is very interesting uh Machinery that I
think was actually a Canadian company at
one time Marcus and then they were
purchased by a wealthy guy in
Pennsylvania in Red Lion PA and I know
he's got one of those hemp trains up and
running and yeah basically fractionates
the herd from the fiber from what I
guess is just like the biomass that's
just ground into a green powder which
could be extracted for CBD and
whatnot and some of that finer fiber can
be used for Plastics and and different
things like that but uh yeah I just like
the get on board the hemp train like we
all got on board the Soul Train remember
the Soul Train in the 70s everyone got
on board all these white people started
grooving to the to the music of of Black
America and it just became yeah this is
definitely the way to go well the hemp
train everyone get on board the hemp
train all you could be our new Don
Cornelius welcome to the H I saw I saw
video Mark scone I saw a video meme of
that the other day where it said when
the cocaine was so pure even white
people could dance and it had all these
all these Soul trained whes dancing it
was pretty pretty pretty
hilarious all right you know Soul Train
and roller skating and we're get we're
getting into a whole new realm but I
think uh really the to to just interject
for a second so it really speaks to
something called the economy of scale
which is that if you could afford one of
those big hemp train type machines those
scale then to to run this I mean it's
just the operating cost so the plant
itself it doesn't make sense to do hand
cortication on a small scale what does
make sense is to have like a processing
center local to your farm where you
could bring your your your stocks and or
they could come and pick it up in a
truck or something like that and then
return to you the material after it's
been after it's been processed because
again just the look at the it's really
cool I think they have a really um
interesting video that describes the
process and the overall mechanical feat
of separating the herd from the fiber
and Sam you've probably seen this at
industrial scale whenever you do
something and it's just that sort of
like garage or basement scale it's one
thing but when you do stuff at at really
tremendous scale the power that's needed
to turn those to turn those Motors is
really important to consider and just
that they can do it a lot cheaper down
the street if you have that sort of
investment to be able to put one of
those things even the really old
machines that I
saw they were they were run by steam so
they they it had like a small steam
engine attached to it and it was from
the like 18 20s 30s 40s 50s something
like that and I saw that in just outside
of uh it was at an Italian Museum a Hemp
Museum outside of ah [ __ ] I can't
remember the name of the city but it
isn't it true Sam that in the worldwide
Market of hemp and I don't know this
because China is a definitely a wild
card here that all of that Antiquated
equipment is still producing the
world's bulk of of what's what's
consumed and and and what's what's used
I'm not talking about CBD in particular
I'm talking about mostly fiber seed and
oil that's all made on very Antiquated
assets not stuck I think there's really
only a few countries that are even
producing fiber to be honest right right
Slovakia right I know Marcus had a had a
big you know early days of of hemp I
know you were like really heavily
involved in that stuff in Canada was
there were you guys using you know large
Machinery at that time to harvest that
material for hemp and you know what when
did that in 98 in 98 we had a hemp
pageant I remember that's what we called
it and we invited all these people over
all these different people that had
interest in the hemp industry and I
remember there was really wild like we
were just a bunch of kind of young dudes
from Winnipeg kind of like yeah let's do
this hemp thing and I remember these the
these guys the hack Brothers showed up
because they they like own diamond mines
in Africa and we were like what brought
them and then it was this like
billionaire guy from Germany named Peter
Steiner who had this piece of hemp metal
that was like lighter than aluminum but
stronger than titanium and it could cut
glass uh and it had been shipped around
the world eight or nine times and he
brought it I held it in my hand I put an
X into a glass asay because we still had
as at the hotels back then and um we
brought over a harvester from Holland
and we brought over the the guy who
basically ran it and we harvested about
5 to 10 acres uh at our H pageant with
all of these people present and I'll
never forget when he it had the two big
red Cutters in the front and he just
ripped through this 5 acre field this
thing was fast too it was it was Dutch
made so it was uh you know that it was
definitely like the Dutch definitely
know uh how to farm and how to build
equipment and so it was pretty
incredible machine I'll never forget
when they ran through this five acre
field the pollen that came off of the
field was like clouds of pollen I'd
never seen anything like it before and
some people got really nervous because
they had allergies and they were like oh
my God I'm I'm gonna die right now and
it didn't surprisingly set off many
people there were a few people that kind
of had to move away but um yeah I have
pictures of that somewhere I'm not
really sure where those pictures are but
I do have pictures of that Harvester oh
no how much did that how much did that
Harvester cost like would the average
farmer who's growing hemp today be able
to afford this this
Harvester well it was certainly not a
cheap machine I I can't remember back
then it might have been a quarter of a
million dollars I'm sure today it would
be five or six or
$700,000 I I I you know don't quote me
on that it could have been a little bit
less it could have been a little bit
more back then but it was not a cheap uh
piece of Machinery especially to bring
over uh and get to Canada but the work
that it did of the hemp and how fast it
harvested the hemp I certainly wouldn't
think anyone growing under you know 500
to 1,000 Acres would would be getting
one but um you could Harvest very
quickly um and it was it was profound
for us because we were just super young
this was like
19 no it would have been before 1998
because I moved in 96 so it probably
would have been 94 95 maybe
9596 when we when we had that done we
grew our we grew our first field in '95
so it wouldn't have been 95 that was an
experimental field there was only one
field grown before our field and that
was in '94 and that was by Jeff uh Jeff
Kim and Joe Strobel the tobacco Farmer
and the lawyer they got the first ever
license in Canada you know in the the
last 73 years or whatever it had been
since temp had been grown in Canada we
were one of the five or six groups that
got our five acre experimental field the
next year uh so it was pretty cool kind
of neat to be a part of that history and
uh you know I'll never forget inviting
my mentor Ron hickey who had served I
guess at that point he had served six
and a half years in jail for cannabis he
would end up serving another five plus
years in the federal penitentiary with
mass murders and rapists and
Psychopaths uh for being a habitual
florist albe it uh but we brought him in
my Volkswagen van to our first five acre
field and he definitely had tears in his
eyes I'll never forget the um just a
profound Revelation in his soul that was
occurring you know and I'll never forget
my partner Martin morovic at the time
either saying this is going to change
the way people think uh not necessarily
the smoking of it but the driving down
the highway and looking over here and
seeing like a five five acres was the
most any of us had ever seen and Ron
grew a lot of cannabis but five acres
just in one big field in
1995 uh was substantial and we were
surprised that the time because it
looked it was buds it was just like it
was it was herb you know it was you know
at the time we had convinced our
minister of uh f it was minister of
Agriculture and Minister of Finance that
uh you know hemp was a distant cousin of
of the Insidious marijuana and it really
wasn't the same thing but once we grew
it and we saw like holy [ __ ] this is
definitely very close to the same thing
big stinky Buds and you know 10 foot
tall PL well Marcus Marcus there's that
important distinction that important 3%
and and weren't you guys wasn't this
group the people who had kind of defined
3% and if I remember correctly I'm not
sure that this is true but I thought
it's because that was the limit to which
they could detect to so they said okay
we can detect to this limit so therefore
that will be the limit 3% and now look
at the ramification that that's had
since right it was the definition it was
on a document I thought it was the peace
treaty the
1962 or whatever the peace treaty was
for for growing hemp and it was it was I
remember it was Martin I think that
found it he was reading this very dry
document and it was like an amendment B
and it said if it's below 3% uh it is
deemed hemp while we had linked up with
John stall who was an expat he went to
the Amsterdam Cannabis Cup in
94 um and I guess he thought it was
going to be some hemp Gathering he was
living in the Ukraine in Kiev and he was
with you know Goro boto from The
Institute of b
f
conspiracy you just off for a
second say something important you froze
we we met this guy John stall in
Amsterdam uh who was who was living in
Kiev and was connected to goo Bosco from
the in now I froze again
on this listening you're all so amazing
and thank you for reaching out and
continuing to be
uh through enthusiastic about the plant
um I love you all thank you I've gotta
go col I need a battery send me a
battery oh yeah I got you I'll send you
yeah I got you brother I love you by
have a good one col
see all right Marcus you're froze again
so you're gonna have to try it again you
met with Mr stall and and he hooked us
up with these these farmers and and goo
botco at The Institute of bass fibers
and I guess he had been breeding this
zolotonosha I guess he got told some
years ago that if he didn't get rid of
THC he had to get rid of hemp and so he
figured out some litness test in the
field I'm frozen again [ __ ] insane
I'm done
no I I know um ladies and gentlemen
start your conspiracy theorist websites
now not it's not meant to be
shared apparently not another day
another day the Illuminati has said
no strange happenings on hash
church that's it
okay so really quickly we uh got we went
to Romania to look for CBD and hemp uh
probably close to eight or nine years
ago I forget what it was we went to
Bulgaria and Romania and drove around
and in the province of Mara
maramures outside of Transylvania on up
against the Ukraine border that's where
we really
found uh waddle fences and uh woven
fences and all the and but also hemp
here hold this side go and we found this
incredible hemp fiber that's like a
hundred years old it's a big long bag
and it's just everyone made their own
clothes back in the day and some of the
elders that were in the village even had
like hemp shoes they were like wearing
hemp shoes pants and jackets and they
were [ __ ] sweet I mean this is it's
like it's heavy fabric yeah it's super
durable for being a hundred years old
you would be so totally surprised and
the bag is even stitched up with thread
that's even more coarse that's also hemp
so the threading on it that they've
stitched the bag together outside of the
weaving is also hemp and it is like
incredible it's easily going to last
another many more hundreds of years so
also it's soft and would be really warm
yeah so they also grew flax because flax
gives you the the soft Linens in between
the hemp and the skin you know you got
the under under layers of flax but also
they had waddle and do natural building
so a lot of the walls were you know post
and then you just weave in and out this
the thinner sticks or uh whatever and
then you pack it with with uh whatever
you have so the best thing that you can
do if you're going to use like hemp
cream
or if you're going to use these small
decorators which we're talking about is
you can use the herd the inside part of
the hemp and if you mix oneir clay oneir
herd and I like it that it's oneir herd
you heard and then um and then water you
can mix it up in a in a in a concrete
mixer and then you can make forms or you
can just paste it up against the wall
and clay herd and water makes nearly
like a a concrete on your wall we saw we
saw buildings there that were fully
beautiful there wasn't like anything
coming off of them and they had been
done hundreds of years ago with this
hemp creete and waddle fences and all of
the buildings were just really beautiful
and really sturdy and fit right into the
land and I think also when you're
working with that kind of natural
building materials you can even see like
some of the buildings or some of the
homes even slumped with some of the
earth as the Earth slumped the house
would sort of slump too so yeah it
wasn't linear and there weren't straight
angles and everything but the house then
sort of became part of the landscape
really beautiful but yet incredibly
functional maybe even a thousand years
later and also they start you started
realizing oh wow so instead of fence
post they just plant trees like Willow
Chestnut
apple trees
Alder and then and then the tree is all
you what they they use a technique you
just cut it at tight every fall and then
in the springtime it sprouts up a bunch
of branches and a lot of times out in
the west you're like oh Jesus all these
branches we got to get rid of them we
don't know what to do let's burn them
but out there they're like you know what
we make them branch and then we cut them
off Copus yeah we cut the branches off
and then we use that for all of our
weaving for our walls we use that we
make rakes we' use waddle and do we do
raised beds waddle waddle beds waddle
fencing it's
spectacular uh it's it's amazing way to
live also when we were in Haiti we went
to Haiti after the earthquake and it was
two weeks after the earthquake and it
was just utter Devastation buildings
down dead bodies everywhere terrible
terrible thing and then uh we started a
birthing Clinic and to to to get food we
had to go in into the inside part of the
island and we started
taking all these uh small motorcycles
into the Inland and started going oh my
God there's all these houses are still
unaffected out here because they were
all waddle and and do they were all
woven houses and fencing and it seems
like oh these are primitive housing but
they didn't lose their house they didn't
lose their crops they had all the food
all the crops that they had before the
earthquake so you know sometimes the
simple methods you know are the smartest
methods and get you through so that's
why simple homesteading can be a really
effective tool for everyone you know to
inspire one another you know what all
this talk of hemp I want to shout out
git scogland uh Rob Clark sent me this
book recently a cannabis textiles book
and uh all sorts of cool pictures there
they are harvesting hemp in
Romania you know
Transylvania really really great
information if you want to go uh if you
want to learn more about hemp textiles
this is uh this is a cool book there's
Victoria in
Transylvania saying hemp has always been
growing there some really great uh all
the different cultures that have been
growing hemp and producing textiles are
uh are in this book and I would
definitely suggest uh checking it out
cannabis textiles
edited by Rob Clark
too and some quite a few photos in here
as well by Rob yeah it's a great book
highly recommend it and also am this
amazing fabric from hemp
Boutique this incredible fabric from
Turkey
right Amir Marcus Amir and Amir and Rob
Amir and Rob clar are doing this really
beautiful fabric textiles from Turkey
and it's nice that the pattern that you
see on that is not dyed it's the two
different colors of hemp um that are
interwoven there naturally it's it's
really
beautiful yeah it's really beautiful
stuff for
sure oh there's some from hemp to Hash I
was going to say we we made some really
good strains this year and I was going
to name off a few just to get it back
into like uh you know strains and maybe
we can hear some more but uh from from
Kush Kirk we got sour garlic sour cream
ice cream cake Lily papaya sour garlic
and the sour diesel lemons and we cross
that with uh the fire glue guava punch
that we made from last year um and where
really excited about that cuz all the
fire glue guava punches that we made
this year are spectacular amazing and
they have a deep blue and purple color
going through them and they have a a
grapey kind of essence to it but they
also have some of that fuy chem doggy
chem flavors in there which we think are
really really beautiful um we also made
some really good ones out of the new
zel's gift that we have and the Hindu
push and the royal purple and uh this uh
strawberry jelly again was really really
sweet uh with the Frenchie Force we made
last year we we created that string
called Frenchie force in honor of
Frenchie dying and passing on to the
next realm we talked with Kimberly and
we said hey Kimberly we have this really
beautiful strain that we made and she
and she said I well he was such a force
of nature that we just wanted to you
know we just just she she and we decided
to call it Frenchie's force and uh it
just it's very crystally uh very
florally um it grows really resistant to
um uh it has the guava punch in it as
well uh as some gak varieties um from
from H I definitely think that it was
the winner in our garden this year that
Frenchies Forest I think also you know
when you put intention like that into
something like we grew it for him we
crossed it for him we had a really deep
conversation with Kimberly and oen um
his daughter their daughter and we
wanted to call it Frenchie's Funk at
first because it was so funky you know
we really got like all these really
funky flavors in there and she said you
know he was such a force I think
Frenchie's force is good and wow you
know it's amazing you put in tension
into something like that and the plant
really feels it so that plant is
something and and hopefully will be able
to bring some down to share with people
and share across Canada too super stoked
for those asking about uh the hemp from
Amir and Rob there hemp Boutique
bouquet.com
um you I put the link up on the uh in
the in the chat
room there you go there you
go back to the turps
I like
turps if you were trapped with one
turpine on a desert island what turp
would that
be I like the combination of many turps
and THS and Esters and thoits I'm not uh
I'm not the uh the the uh the
monomolecular turpine guy um I want I
want the uh the the combination I like I
like so many of them I like gas I love
hate I love what would be the name of
the flavor of them all together
combined uh the swamp
[Laughter]
water take me back to when I was a
little kid at hockey practice and I'd go
and get all the pops put into one cup
right oh put I want a little bit of all
of them the swamp water who knows you
know I always thought um mushrooms can
tame so many tpin and try turpins and to
try to pull out all of the different
tpin that like a mushroom contains is
ores
andever quite complex so I always
wondered if all of the Tarpin mixed
together smelled like a mushroom kind of
like all the colors together are gray or
brown or brown yeah gray brown brown
right yeah that's an interesting way of
looking at it no I love the variety I
love the spice of life I love that
people have different oil factories and
have different preferences and that they
also have different environments to grow
things that tend to express things you
know differently and I I just love I
love the variety I I I get asked all the
time oh if you had one cultivar what
would you you know what would it be it's
like I don't know like if I had one
cultivar I'd for sure get bored of it
that's what I can tell you although I
will say I think the one that I had the
longest that I didn't get bored of was
probably the
which was very fruity and flavorful and
just you know it was like pot to get you
busted it stunk so bad uh so good it
just reaped through the bag you couldn't
steal the stuff uh but when you burned
it and exhaled it had a hazy smell to it
so it had these two varieties of this
fruity flavor that it tasted like and it
smelled like but on the exhale if you
exhaled a big puff of it of of bubble or
whatever and you walked out of the room
and you came back in you'd swear someone
was was puffing Haze so I I like that
that it had these very very different
groups the two groups that I that I
probably prefer the most I've never seen
them kind of together uh in a in a way
like that so I have a special place of
my heart for for Renee shout out to uh
Dr Renee and shout out to Muhammad who
turned me on to the Renee Way Way Back
when in the 90s much love to those guys
is the still around or has that been
bred into something else yeah I mean
great Gardener was breeding it into
stuff and you know I've I've heard
people say they have the Renee but it
it's like the Romulan you know the
Romulan was shortlived everyone thinks
they have it they don't um I used to get
it from Romulan Joe himself and he got
it from the group of guys it wasn't his
Cult of art it's just how he really
became well known that was a very
special plant in the 90s as well and
it just disappeared it was years later I
saw a cut from an overgrow guy that
white I think his name was White Rabbit
and he had this cultivar that was like
across of the Romulan and it had that it
it's like the shishka berry you know the
shishkaberry yeah you can taste it in
the Nicole you can taste it in the
Barbara it's definitely what makes those
two cultivars special but do you see the
pure shishkaberry like the yellow and
the red line anymore no not so much they
seem to be things of the past
maybe that's okay maybe that's what
builds that love that loss of not having
it anymore makes it makes you remember
it even maybe better than it really was
I I don't know but um I do know that the
people are making just just as good of
things nowadays with the with the new
cultivars that they're breeding and so
there's always excitement in cannabis
things may come and go but uh there's
always greatness around the next
Corner yeah Romulan
unfortunately we lost it in a bay just
due to white pottery Milo and champagne
I think also had Romulan in it same
problem one of those just very bright
expressive floral cultivars but
unfortunately uh nature and man didn't
necessarily combine too well on that
one go ahead Brian I've got a I've got a
Romulan bx4 going right now three fenos
I've still got one outside that's really
late it's a Romulan bx4 to a sour best
[ __ ]
ever and two of the fenos I'm learning
what the they've only run once for a
quick test and now one of them's outside
only and brought back in all three to
try again but this one I have in the
yard is really really unique uh I call
it like a seven up soda type of smell on
it so I don't know Romulan really well
the pure ROM but it uh you know a couple
of them come off like seven up lime type
of thing influence not sure where that
comes from or what the original Romulan
tasted like really so yeah the
old Piney to almost grapy a little bit
and most of tiny
lime and the Bud's double covered in
Crystal so that's the the one thing you
really got to look for it's just the
ridiculous content so that that probably
will just that's what I've heard yeah we
we yeah they're coated this one's called
candy coated from uh catsu seeds on that
one
actually and yeah candy coated so looks
triy for sure and then I had I was going
to say I tried this really unique uh
probably the best tasting resin out west
before I left that I couldn't place
again or find it the cultivar again but
it was Big Sir holy weed on a cook an OG
Big Sir holy OG and that was like the
most unique alien Spike ranges you know
like Marcus is talking about on the EXL
of the Irene where it came out hazy went
in a different way so that one was just
this really like reach to Hay skunk
Pine um classic kind of I guess later
90s into two early 2000s kind of thing
with it late 90s from the little bit I
know of that realm but yeah Big Sir holy
OG
if anyone knows where that we grew that
exact cross for a long time up here we
got it from down in Cali so I got from
Coastal seeds Michael Michael kagu from
Coastal seeds in Santa Cruz yeah Michael
probably still has check him out he's
amazing it also has like he just posted
Maui
woi um
Tai used he used that big sir holy weed
because it is so resistant and really
heavy weiter so like yielded really
heavy and it was almost like anything
that you crossed it with would just be
phenomenal that was a really fun cross
for us to have for a long time also
Bobby and Mary uh the Snodgrass family
genetics did more with that Big Sir holy
weed and also the coastal
Haze they did some work with the coastal
Haze and also the Puna butter cookies
which is the big island South Big Island
Puna buta yeah that that that bu was out
on dead tour in the in the early early
90s and that's you know my bag seed
story from uh summer tour 1991 was
getting a bag from my friend Ron from
Shasta hey Pizza Man Ron how are you so
uh yeah uh we planted it like several
years later and the plants actually they
never looked healthy because for some
reason they just looked just very
strange they grew next to plants that
look just fine and those those two seeds
the plants were like I don't know just
small runs of the litter and very
purpley buds there's lots of yellow and
purple and orange in there but yeah they
were just Big Sir holy is just yeah
grateful Deb
approved I'm sure they helped move it
around wow yeah they certainly did I
mean there was I mean I I we've talked
about aash church just the influence
that and I think you know Josh and Kelly
you guys got to agree right the
influence that the dead had in bringing
kind bud from I mean there was kind bud
always in NorCal and Oregon right and if
you think about it that was like the
Dead's home territory so when they went
on on tour all the hippies that followed
them brought really good nugget and
people were like in some arena in I
don't know Cincinnati
in the 70s and all of a sudden it's like
who stepped in dog [ __ ] it's like no man
that's the way weed smells when it's
proper you know and yeah I remember like
my friends well a lot of people would go
to the Grateful Dead shows by acid by
[ __ ] we bring back to their little
communities and they were you know oh
man you got that from deed tour let's
let's go back on dead tour and get some
more we're out right I'm sure many a
good bag seed was found
also so much fun back then to just you
when they were rolling around the
country it was like a traveling circus
it was so much fun I would encourage
people to look up on YouTube Grateful
Dead parking lot videos from the
1980s they're fun just look up parking
lot videos from the 1980s and just watch
people getting interviewed in the
parking lot 80s and 90s hilar I mean you
start realizing whoa everyone super
stoked they think they're on the tip of
some like Absolute Total great thing all
recycling all national parks save the
environment you know it seemed like all
food food the food good food just
Progressive thinking art you know
different ways ways of
life sh down street was was mindblowing
to people for me being baldheaded kid
that I was back day as a as a punk I
would go down there and there'd be
people just holding like 6 to 12 in
mushroom amonita mushrooms mushrooms
some some girls walking together one's
holding a bucket and they're like uh goo
balls goo balls and you look in and
there's just little hash goo balls swell
of the waft of marijuana outside right
on Shakedown Street and then if you go
inside there's a complete utter fog
inside right front and Stage that kind
of wafted it back cuz there were people
who sat there and blew smoke at Jerry
Garcia the entire freaking show so it
was incredible what they did regarding
cannabis and I have a they have not been
given their due for truly spreading kind
bud nationally a whole other also that's
why we're talking about it we're
talking acknowledging that right it's
weirdly still happening and I could
definitely say because it's been so long
ago I'm so thankful if it weren't for
Grateful Dead and kind bud and being
able to like move that around dead tour
I I mean I wouldn't have made it through
University I'm so thankful you know I
have all kinds of Majors it also
wouldn't have taken her so long to get
through
University hey eight years three Majors
all you know she she was on roller
skates with fairy wings and a fair wand
I IM it was a great front for kind bud I
was able to get through anything and
anyone and it totally and that's all
that I had the rain name I didn't know
people would say what do you got and I'd
say It's kind bud and I was getting it
from all the Eugene crew and bringing it
out on tour and then you know giving it
out to people who would come out to San
Francisco who were from New York and
they would pick it up from us and I mean
we thought thought that we were dealing
big stuff when we had a half a pound and
we were like you know breaking up a half
a pound of kind butt that was a big deal
and people would come all the way from
new it would affect the parking lot it
was just so different so different than
the little brown manila envelopes full
of seedy Mexican weed that you'd get
from like someone who'd be selling weed
in in New York City and it was easier
quite frankly to buy cocaine that's one
of the reasons why cocaine's popularity
and crack took off in the 80s is because
they didn't have good nugget but I think
when the Grateful Dead started reaching
their Echelon in the late 80s and good
nugget came East I think that helped
maybe with the crack epidemic because it
seemed like a lot of friends that I knew
just needed really really much better
weed than they were smoking a lot of
them went to Coke and Other Drugs but to
be quite honest I mean like even like if
you at like a Neil Young concert or like
an Al Brothers concert you'd be hassled
for smoking weed at the arena like if
you had like just a little one hitter
people be like oh put that [ __ ] out man
you're got to throw you out with the
dead people would bring in bongs and
glass and it was just an elaborate
ceremony that the you know Bill Graham
just paid off the promoters to say look
this is the dead traveling circus they
all smoke weed they're really peaceful
all they want to do is smoke weed and
spin as
Jerry noodles but I think a lot of the
other bands for some reason it seems
like didn't have that thing figured out
you
know they also brought mus you know and
the mushrooms are known to help with
addiction you know I mean you can say oh
it was just a party in the parking lot
well kind of but it also affected their
your ways of thinking it what were you
going to say Mar
C well I was just going to say there was
a dark side of things too because
because it was such an open Circus the
police really it was like shooting fish
in a barrel the amount of people that
went to jail for LSD and did 10year
sentences the people who got busted with
weed it was just it was kind of like
that bummer of prohibition and when when
people kind of hate on cannabis becoming
legal which tons of that sucks there's
all sorts of shitty things about legal
cannabis and and endless array of them
what's not on the list of of legal
cannabis is 10year prison sentences uh
for getting caught with a bag of weed in
Arkansas or whatever so there was that
that as well I mean I I I was more of of
the fish uh tour you know I I that's the
tour that I did more of my time on and
it was very much the same way I'll never
forget being at a show in Montana and
the police are up in the buildings on on
on walkie-talkies and they're looking
down in the parking lot and they're
announcing to the Undercovers that are
in the parking lot and I don't I'm sure
it existed during the Grateful Dead days
but on fish tour it was Go free for
three so they bust these poor kids and
then they get them to become narcs and
go out and bust three more people go
find ecstasy go find acid go find
whatever you can you get three people
you can go free and I I had a lot of
friends end up uh end up in jail uh
during that time as well so it was this
beautiful amazing important thing that
was happening and then there was this
real nasty underbelly that I'm that I'm
sure um a guy like Jerry Garcia was
conscious of and and probably you know
it probably gave them nightmares the the
idea of how many of these young people
were getting locked up in prison really
just for for tapping into this amazing
like the the police just suck to to hone
in and be and and to on the weakest on
the most vulnerable on the like just
these like beautiful loving people that
just wanted to have fun and and get
together and and enjoy you know
psychedelics and cannabis and amazing
music um there was that part of it as
well so it was it's hard to talk need to
look you need to look at it the way the
police do they were soft easy targets
and they weren't going to kill your mama
daddy and sister like the cartel
would true well and and and and to let
you know Marcus I mean just to give you
a report so on a recent fish tour uh
this recent tour I mean really incidents
with police are kind of few and far
between because fish tour now is kind of
like sophisticated audience it cost a
lot of money for tickets so people you
know they're kind of like destination
shows like people plan their vacations
around them so there's travel plans that
are being made but there was one
noticeable show this past run of fish
shows where there were a lot of bus in
the parking lot where basically cops
were going from car to car people are
tailgating I mean you know like you said
Marcus this is like it's like our tribe
we want to go go there turn off the keys
to the ignition we made it to the
parking lot open a nice frothy beer
smoke a joint eat some food you know
socialize with some friends go check out
Shake down street maybe have a balloon
or two if that's what suits you but I
mean the cool thing is that again most
venues where Place places where fish
plays these days
they got that figured out they're like
okay fish is Coming to Town there's
going to be this crazy group of people
they're going to need the setup you know
and there's going to be campers there's
going to be deep fat friers and Falafel
and there just it's just there's a whole
infrastructure that kind of organically
comes together and it's still so cool
because like if you're a teenager or
like a college Age kid and you got a
couple bucks in your pocket you could
still go on tour and have like an
adventure like you don't know like where
like you might have like a couple nights
tickets lined up like you don't have it
all figured out but because there's some
uncertainty in your future it's kind of
cool because you don't really know
what's gonna happen you'll probably just
end up going back home and working the
rest of the summer to pay your hotel
bills but yeah I mean there's like
there's nitrous Mafia at all the shows
now so wherever you go there's balloons
just everywhere you know and it's just
like you know I don't know I
mean you know admit I like to do ners
every now and then but you know I just
think it's just proliferated the scene
to where it's just just garbagey at L
leave all their balloons around and like
couple hours later you go down Seventh
Avenue after you know Madison Square
Garden is let out and there's just
balloon trash everywhere and it's just
couple guys down an alley still sucking
on one balloon like three guys sucking
on one balloon because that's all that's
left you know it's it's kind of it's
brought a little trashy element to the
scene but all in all I haven't really
seen the huge bus and organized bus that
like the DEA had a project called dead
end I think that was in 91 or something
like that and they intentionally sent
agents out on to lot to almost get like
information like infiltrate like try to
be cool and make a deal but not
necessarily bust somebody but try to
figure out like who their plug is and
try to figure [ __ ] out and I had a Frank
good close friend of mine who's our
keyboard player in our band who went
down on such a thing that it was just it
was horrible but you know yeah it was
just part of prohibition but a crazy
time to be alive and following the band
around so the Grateful Dead I think the
deading company are doing one more tour
supposedly uh next uh summer everybody
everybody who's interested I did post
that ethelon at hash church and the
article and I also posted uh uh it in
the chat so the all the people who are
on has church can also see
[Music]
it that's amazing I was gonna say uh you
know for for us in the late 80s like
everything is what you make it you know
but for us it was going to to Dead shows
and seeing super natural people you know
living a a nature life and then going
back home like to Oregon and then just
studying micology and studying herbalism
and just learning about Midwifery and
natural building and then you know going
back to the Dead shows and bringing like
tinctures and bringing medicines and
products and it really is I feel like
the origins of like the legalization of
cannabis came from those those areas and
that from that like sentiment and that
like sharing of medicine and it was like
we were learning about dosing and and
making you know medicated food at the
time and it was I think pretty
sophisticated if even if you want to
call it anecdotal or stuff that was just
happening on the parking lot but I know
that like with rock Med and um first
responder medicine um a lot of that and
Kelly still does that stuff with with
professional athletes nowadays you know
with you know falling on jumps and and
and everything but uh yeah no it's it's
amazing how it's
it's I I think it was and it also was
the beginning of and yeah Marcus you're
absolutely right I think whenever
there's a really bright
spark of some kind of a beginnings of
something you know it definitely shines
a light makes people interested in
what's going on there and I think that
cannabis you know is just that plant
that continues to move us forward and
now it's continuing to it moved us
forward then you know and it's
interesting there's not a lot of things
that we would do illegally like to put
ourselves at risk but why is it that we
continue to put ourselves at risk for
cannabis I know I did and I knew what
the risks were at that time I knew that
I could look at 25 years easily for what
I was doing or lose my kid I knew that
but it was still like there's some kind
of a relationship that you have with
that plant to continue to bring it
forward and that energy was on you know
Grateful Dead lot it is in the fish lot
or barter fairs and it and it and it
does plant a seed of of some kind of
collective consciousness of humanity for
some something to grow from that there's
something very like deeper I don't you
know I don't want to call it
spirituality or whatever but there's
something very essential about how hum
Humanity exists with each other and how
we communicate with each other and then
get together and then you know spread
that information something so beautiful
about it and take everything higher tour
was that for sure fish tour was that and
Country Fair was that
Country Fair is not that anymore but it
was that and it was the first time when
we saw Keith you know was at an Oregon
Country Fair lineup waiting for food
right or right when you yeah so let's
see
1990 I was in line for some pizza
somebody earlier had said to me he had
two spray bottles and he said electric
or not and I was like oh well I guess if
there's a choice and you know which one
I chose so then later I'm in the line
and this guy said oh I've got something
to share with you and out of this little
velvet box and then inside of another
little box there's a little silver box
he had this perfectly
pressed ke like Square oh maybe it was
89 anyway and he made it it wasn't he
made you know and he pressed it and I
had never seen anything like it and he
shared it with us in line in the pizza
lineup and he was probably in his 60s
and I was just like what is happening
and I just remember toking on that key
for the first time and it changed my
life yet another like change you know
like what was that and that was yeah and
that was back at a time we used to think
it took all these hoses and Contraptions
to make hash we just didn't know you
know what I mean we just didn't know we
thought it was a big deal turns out it's
not
was at the time for certain part of your
history Sam was probably puffing on the
99.999 back in
'89 absolutely I
was unbelievable I was uh you you're
when did you you fell in love with food
and did food help you fall in love with
hash and do you find there's like a
thing with preparing high-end food or to
like preparing the hash and make and
making the hash and creating that
space who are you asking there's oh
excuse me I was talking to Connor but
anyone could answer it if they
wanted just you know was was talking to
Connor in that in that moment because I
know he loves the two of
them yeah think there's a lot of a
crossover between uh kitchen prep and
hash prep you know there's
um oh there's a huge emphasis on being
cleanly in the kitchen which is
definitely crossover for making hash and
you know prepping your space and getting
everything in order beforehand there's a
French term called Mison plast which
means everything in its place
um yeah I kind of found hash right as my
culinary Journey had started and um I
think there's a lot of uh you know bleed
over from one the other I find too with
um my new hobby of beeping that there's
a lot of similar things as well like
you're sifting and using different
screens to separate your honey from your
your wax so I don't know there's there's
a lot of things that can be similar to
making hash in The Culinary
world I used to argue with a couple of
people who believed that
bees chased after cannabis plants
because that they want to get and I expl
to them bees do not have cannabinoid
receptors unlike humans so they're not
getting high from it they it may be a
great food source for them but it's not
getting them
high yeah they seem to really love the
male ganja pollen um last year I had a
pretty big mail and every single day
they were um going out to check out the
new sites that opened uh there's not too
many flowers that I can compare to that
will continuously release p over that
long period I'm sure some fruit trees
will or something like that but a lot of
like the flowers kind of just have like
that that initial burst maybe they get a
couple more later but ganja seems to
drop a lot of pollen over a a decent
amount of
time I've definitely noticed the
connection between a hash makers after
watching so many hash makers after
helping kind
of many hash makers on their journey I
hate to say help create hash makers
because I certainly didn't do that but I
helped inspire people to become hash
makers over the last 25 years or so and
I always found that the ones that had
traditional training in a kitchen that
understood kitchen
Sops and kitchen um cleanliness seem to
shine in the hash making um processes so
lots of my friends that were really
great chefs uh to No Surprise were also
great at producing nice hash and also
seem to also grow beautiful cannabis
which is a very important factor you
know it's it's great if you understand
how to make great hash but if you don't
have the material to make it uh all the
uh all the Sops in the world are not
going to produce any fire for you you
really really have to first understand
have that sort of old factory
relationship which I think you know ties
into that kitchen relationship where you
have to have a very a you know you have
to have a high level of awareness when
it comes to your old factory your sense
of taste your sense of of visualization
and your sense of creating synergistic
um Creation with Foods the way certain
foods go together so beautifully and
doing certain things with those Foods
can create these synergies that you know
produce more than 1+ 1+ 1 equal 3 but 1
plus 1+ 1 equals 9 and so yeah those
those translate very well and I would
implore anyone that's out there that is
a chef and that is good at what they do
if they enjoy cannabis uh you should dip
in a little bit into hash making because
you'll probably shine at it and uh like
you inspire people with your food uh
you'll also inspire people with your
with your extracts
I would like is next to
stoneless we're gonna um start um
organizing bior Regional Dem pure um
high-end food and hash experiences at uh
you know really nice either high-end
Airbnb or some kind of piece of land or
Resort in different areas and what we
want to do is just combine the hash with
with food with glazes is you know with
that Ola Factory experience not to get
super ripped but really just to Super
celebrate the the the aromatic
experience of really good food fresh
food from the area with awesome people
and then being able to offer some of the
products to the community that we might
not be able to and we can do that in a
private session in areas like Maine
Michigan Oregon California British
Columbia you know and if the borders
open up we can start hitting up South
America and Europe and and you know
maybe even Thailand if we if it you know
it starts coming open because that's
that's where that's yeah that's where
our families are and stuff so um look
for those Gatherings as we start get uh
getting together yeah we're gonna do dem
pure popup experience uh
nights days beauti that out here hey
Marcus I have a question Marcus on the
um in in the The Whistler technology
when you guys are making hash what does
that come out analyzing at you know the
reason why I'm asking is one of the
challenges here in Vermont is they have
we are we've just gone recreational or
adult use or whatever you want to call
it but they have a limit on uh THC which
is we all know really stupid but it's a
artificial limit I think with it
hopefully either be raised or go away
later but right now it's 60% THC so is
that around the ballpark that these
hashes come out
at yeah I mean depending on what you're
putting in there you can definitely get
hashes I mean listen I was running
Afghan Kush I ran God I feel like I ran
like 500 kilos of it I think we ran
about 500 kilos of Afghan Kush oh I
froze am I back
no okay now I'm back sorry it's
conspiracy against me today you were
freshly Frozen I saw cuz you guys all
freeze up for me so I I know when I'm
frozen because you guys are all
like and not moving so I totally get
that I'm there it is
again I'm telling you doesn't want to
give me the
doesn't want to give me the love you
know what yes 60% is right in the range
the highest stuff I made was close to 80
um the lowest that's come out and this
is with like a 15 or a 16% cultivar was
the 220 which is usually like you just
throw it away and it was
50% so you can certainly make hash in
that in that 60% range I mean you're
7390 and 120 could be a little higher um
what I'm finding for these legal markets
aside from from California and some of
the some of the US markets is that
because of the expensive licensing and
the expensive
testing people are mixing a lot of the
microns together which really hurts my
soul like badly but that will also you
know if you're putting your 45 through
160 Al together and most people now
they're making bubble to press into
rosin as well they don't they don't have
the at least here in Canada so you know
60% is is a pretty solid range um those
rins those rosins are much higher than
like in the in the 70s or 80s is right
yeah the rosins come in around 65 to to
80 or so depending on on the material I
mean you could always start with a much
lower Frozen again oh no I'm not frozen
when I used to when I used to make
99.9 out of my skunk number one which
was uh 177% THC manicured uh so it
wasn't enormously high it was just very
turpine rich so it was very enjoyable
but
uh when I would make
99.9 uh% resin heads out of it it was in
the low 80s like maybe 82 83 84%
THC what was the tpine the tpine
percentage Sam oh you know I didn't
measure it as a percentage I just did
the profiles to be honest so so so if it
was 80 let's just say 80% what do you
think the makeup of that other 20% is
in I wouldn't be surprised if the tpin
were you know 10% or more because even
if they were only three or something
like
that what I've got there is four or five
times stronger than the the weed he came
from so the tpine should be also four or
five times higher so I I wouldn't be
surprised if at all if a lot of what was
missing was
thines but also too that was dry SI so
there was also natural
wax the cuticle so yeah right that might
have been that other 10% so if it was
10% tpes 10% cuticle wax and 80%
canono that's a pretty canono was THC
because skunk really doesn't the amount
of T it's got thcb but at really really
really tiny amounts and the same thing
with CBD I mean it's got a CBD synthes
in it but it's mutated and it's
nonfunctional so it doesn't really
produce
CBD we produced rosin that was 84%
cannabinoids and 9% tpes and so that was
in the in the 90s that was but it had
like
77% thca and it had some CB like 8% cbga
and it had a little bit of CBC and
almost 2% of THC
VA um and that if you add Marcus if you
add up all those numbers What's the
total unknown it was like 7% unknown
M so that's your your your waxes and
your your you want to you know get that
number as small as you possibly can and
get your cannaboids and tpes both the
dry sift and water hash will have waxes
on it unless it's been you know uh you
know treated with cold winterized yes
exactly yeah but win winterization also
when in in that process you you you
dissolve it up in ethanol and then chill
it to precipitate out any fats waxes
when you strip off the ethanol you lose
a fair fraction of the light fraction of
your tpin in that in that ethanol
recovery when you grow them you're
losing tpin when you dry them when you
harvest them when you touch them when
you move them I mean it's yeah that's
the name of the game
yeah so if you're um you know making
rosin from 73 bags or isolating bags
making rosin from 90 if it's not you
know six star or seven star because me
and Kelly are on that seven star now and
we can talk about that later but I'm
just
saying
um uh what do you recommend like the
mushrooms the home
someone else M make rosin out of each of
the fractions and you'll see that the
rosin the difference will be less than
the resin because when you when you've
got a bunch of different resins are a
little bit different uh but the rosin
it's it sort of equalizes everything and
they all get really really pretty
high-end I I would just say that the
more the the more um uh undesir not
undesirable but the more um uh plant
cuticle and plant matter and just the
lower or your higher that that unknown
fra action the more suited towards
Edibles and topicals and full spec not
that there's no value in that full
spectrum oil treatment you know cancer
patients who need AKA Rick Simpson Oil
just full spectrum oil you're getting
you know a full spectrum extract there
and and people claim I don't know have
you guys seen this um these Ros and
gummies where I I guess again there's a
fair amount of flavor from the rosin
that actually goes into the gummy that
flavors the gummy so maybe you're not
you're using less sugar because it's you
know you don't need to flavor it because
you're using the extract itself to
flavor
it anyone experienced Rous and gummies
yet yeah there's a bunch of Rous and
gummies that are being made up and
around here
and they're also using alternative like
sweeteners a lot of stevia people trying
um a Tamarind paste or a mango paste
making some unbelievably gorgeous
gummies with rosin and you definitely
can taste the rosin in there but they're
pairing it really well like I just just
a few weeks ago we had like a mango
gummy that was paired with a beautiful
rosin it was delicious and we had the
rosin heads chocolate out um in Ontario
has really good rosin flavor in it their
chocolates amazing they have their
Buddha heads and all kinds of different
you know molds they're really really
sweet and they pair different are you
guys Al I mean again I'm not I I'm a
scientist so I always like to try to
figure things out and whenever you're
looking at the marketplace there's value
for you know considering you know the
way a consumer would think too and so I
always think that like in a infused
edible product the best flavor is
no flavor at all you shouldn't you
shouldn't be able to taste like the
cannabis extract or all the all the
stuff that kind of comes along for the
ride so is you know again people use
like CBD isolate yeah that's not full
spectrum but there are ways of basically
translating full spectrum medicine into
ways where the taste and flavor isn't
really impact but neutralized by I think
what you are saying the other components
in the formulation itself and now you
completely crossed from you know uh what
what is it recreational psychoactive
consumption to food and nutrition
because now you're really talking about
a food and nutrition product so where
you could use these plant extracts to
say okay well uh say I don't know I I
don't have time to uh to to do my dab to
smoke but I do have time to say eat this
Cliff bar well is there a you know again
a way to put that rosin into something
like a cliff bar or something that
somebody could eat on the go a gummy is
I guess the most convenient example but
you know like I think you were saying is
right is that you know gummies and yeah
I play around with melting lots of sugar
in my kitchen too I mean sugar just is
yeah I mean kind of like necessary evil
maybe but you know everybody likes to
jolly lancher and this this hard candy
is really cool because you suck on it
like a cough drop but um are ways to
approach using full spectrum extracts
like rosin but even the more plantier
extracts in food preparations where
you're not necessarily oh God that's
just so loaded with hemp or so loaded
with cannabis I could I could taste a
can of butter or I think really the best
best way of medicating is to pair it in
a food that's complimentary or somehow
it doesn't mask the flavor but uses its
own flavor profile to put like a
bitterness or a sweetness or a sourness
into it what do you guys think on
that My worry is the heating up of
volatile organic compound you know it's
it seems like I'm sure people have
figured it out and there must be a way
to you know translate that so you get
that flavor and taste
unchanged but I think if you're heating
up chocolate or you're heating up you
know gummies and it's it's quite a hot
temperature I just I worry that those
things will be changed uh particularly
in their in their flavor so I'm sure
someone will figure it out at the very
least they would certainly be let me
just finish by saying maybe the most
prominent example of that would be like
cough drop where cough drops basically
have I think it's like camper and Pine
and a few of the kind of like Menthol
yeah Menthol exactly and so like yeah so
you could put basically essential oils
into basically a candy right a cough
drop is candy right take it and then
when you as that cough drop dissolves
you really feel that turke rush and you
know I mean and I think with edial again
correct me from wrong I mean maybe some
people like the edial to taste like herb
I want my herb to taste like herb but I
want my you know Edibles I want my food
to taste like food I don't need my food
to taste like weed but I don't know
maybe other people feel differently I I
can remember when I was younger the more
potent the Cannabis product the more uh
bite there was to my tongue almost like
peppery uh so when I was if I would eat
herb dried herb uh it would be a little
bit spicy like that if I would eat dried
resin or a dri sifted resin it would be
quite peppery if you did a butter or
ghee extract of that it got I mean
pepper as hell to my tongue so when I
smoked my first pure
THC I assumed it was going to be peppery
as [ __ ] so I put a little tiny bit on my
tongue it had zero taste or smell I
couldn't believe it yeah maybe it's the
kopine you because kopine is one of the
turpins that's in black pepper maybe
there's that's one of the Turin that
well I haven't done any oral testing but
I wouldn't be surprised if uh marine
loline and a several other ones also
have a bittery peppery taste I would not
be surprised at
all I put some on my tongue but I I just
haven't done it there there's a whole
genre of cannabis chefs and a lot of
people are using cannabis preparations
and cannabis extracts and cooking and
kind of like the point that Marcus
raised which is that if you're cooking
if you're making like I don't know a
stew or a pudding or you're baking
something you're putting a a thermal
pressure on this very sensitive plant
material especially when you're talking
about the tpin right and the turine
ratio I mean everyone's tasted that
roasted weed smell you get if you take
just weed and put it in the oven and try
to decarb it I never understood that as
part of a uh a brownie recipe people are
like oh uh when you decarb the weed it's
much easier for the oil to extract it
but um you burn off all those tpes and
you have now this roasted weed smell
which is kind of like burnt tpping and
also just the baking itself will decarb
it so they're they're they're
stupid right so right right right but
but I I guess the point I'm bringing up
is kind of like what Marcus was saying
is that if you're using cannabis or
cannabis
preparations in a food a process to make
a food product or a dish and and it
involves heat it's going to either
destroy or somehow rearrange the turpins
and make like a off flavor in your food
and you you're thinking well you know
again kind of like what we were saying
with Josh and Kelly you're getting full
spectrum extract and you're getting
everything that you can the whole plant
goodness and everything that's in there
but what you're really getting is kind
of like a bunch of degradation products
you got from adding this full spectrum
extract which is not th normally stable
into a process where you basically yeah
turn it into had that problem I would
make no bake cookies out of haze so I'd
get like a half a pound of haze and then
I would put uh ghee on top of it and put
it over a double boiler and I would lose
a lot of tpping so what I started doing
was I did it inside of a pressure cooker
not at higher temperatures but just so
that I didn't lose anything and that
helped quite a bit they changed the
taste very slightly but uh I wasn't
losing it like I was before um I also
know that when people are using such a
beautiful high you know quality product
such as rosin and its full spectrum
they're definitely doing raw products
and the gummy that I'm talking about is
a raw product because when you work with
Tapioca And you work with other
different types of binders like that you
can definitely do raw products without
heating up and making sure that the
raw the THC be
thca yeah I guess so well no because
remember the rosin is is is being
pressed it's being heated up so it
depends on how high you know they're
heating it up but yeah if it's a low 10
rosin then it is gonna be a
thca we actually figured this out right
here on hash Church a couple years ago
it is thca that that basically comes out
through what we believe is somewhat of a
of a steam distillation process where
the moisture is somehow driving a the
the cannabinoids out out but um yeah so
so tapioca you mentioned uh Kelly oh my
gosh I had not previously worked with
tapioca and appreciated how viscous it
is at room temperature you definitely
need to heat tapioca to get that to move
it's an order magnitude to or two more
viscous than just corn syrup I mean it
is just very very viscous and what what
I also noticed is that if you heat it up
too much it begins to do this
crystallization reaction which totally
changes the morphology and the the the
tapioca that you you get out of that
that's what I use when I make my candy
too I use tap nice but you know what
tapioca does it takes a really long time
it takes a time to cool down before it
actually gels so there's a time in
between there that it's actually really
cool before it gels that you can add in
your rosin and for sure these gummies
that I'm talking about they don't
actually get you very high so there is
definitely some thca you know in there I
do think that there's some possibilities
for tapioca to still have you know
without overheating eating it or and
it's a magical thing I with it a lot too
what were you gonna say Brian can you
use raw Agave that would actually help
with the viscosity of it and then
something to bond it to harden you
know we use Stevia and you can also use
a little bit of some super highly
concentrated um fruit puree like you can
use mango is a puree that's often you
can buy and you can get it organic and
is super thick and really concentrated
the same with Tamarind that's another
one that's super thick and concentrated
so you can add small amounts of tapioca
to it that's not actually very hot and
it'll be nice to to look at you know the
lab studies on it because that I don't
have that's just something that you know
people are making around here in BC and
in the cies and they're delicious and
really beautiful and I know the maker of
them and she's doing some amazing work
with different types of sugar herbs too
going yeah she's putting herbs in it
she's been doing uh even some super
concentrated vinegar
shrugs um with different types of herbs
so the gummies like almost have like a
really Beau vinegar tell people what a
vinegar shrug is a vinegar shrug is is
just utilizing vinegar instead of
alcohol as a tincture so it's called a
shrug instead of a tincture
and they're really quite flavorful and
quite wonderful if you you know do
different compounded herbs and if you
you can cook down the vinegar like a lot
to where it has a little bit of a
vinegary flavor so the gummies are
almost like these beautiful fruity wine
gummies you know those yummy wine
gummies that they I'm sure they still
have them but I don't eat sugar so
they're delicious anyway Al also just
the whole anything slow cook slow heat
you know the whole slow food movement
you know that's a great place for the
for the ganja also um fermentation or
pickling if you have something that's
super spicy you know you could add it to
a Spicy Pickle or some kind of a little
sweet side dish so again it's maybe it's
not your whole meal but it's just a
little part of it you know to get you
kind
of spiced up or whatever chy or
something like that yeah good a good
talk though I do think that the
more any any glaze you know could could
also be a good
utilization pesto is a good
one Pine the pesto is a really good one
for like raw even into cooked where it's
that spicy element of the Cannabis that
burns your throat even or does mine a
bit and that part can be unpleasant even
if I like the taste so I know when it
goes in there with an oil or either like
the raw and the composition of it mixing
and how it tastes combined with like a
almost a piny Nutty spicy
pesto so yeah Savory and not just sugary
items where it's you know it's fun to
explore the TP and and the expressions
with food and I don't I try not to eat
sugar also so it's one of those when you
do
that when you do that you can make your
pesto instead of out of uh Pine nut you
can make them out of cannabis seeds I've
I've done that was
delicious great idea yeah it makes the
pesto really creamy and if you even
blend it with hemp seeds it makes a
beautiful pesto also I wanted to add
that even basil you know fresh basil can
have that super intense bite I found you
know certain varietals that actually you
know are really hot in the back of the
throat too when it's raw so yeah those
two are paired really well together
different kinds of chutneys too yum
we've been working with like fresh lime
and fresh um mint Chutney and adding a
little bit of flour in their raw and
that's been it's really delicious fire
cider a fire cider could be a good for
it yeah and that's raw as
well nice ranges and ranges in profile
where you have like the spice to the
Savory text and and the sweets come in
with it I like the spicy and the sweet
idea with chatney that sounds like a
good one and it's been really fun
putting the fresh flowers in the raw
honey and then you leave it in there for
a good
month um extraction and then you can use
that honey raw in all different types of
things so that's something that I give
to children for like a cough syrup and
they're just getting thca or CBD we
mostly use CBD in there but they would
be getting thca with those traces in
there and that's awesome to use that um
honey for different types of medicinal
extracts extracted other herbs Lavender
in Honey yeah you can put all kinds of
fresh flowers in honey and now you're
just using this flavored honey yeah we
did a Mendo breath raw honey with raw
roses in the in the honey and it was
like wow totally incredible so that's a
beautiful done a maple syrup we haven't
done maple syrup yet and I'm really
excited to try it I just I don't I'm
sure it would work because it would
probably erode the the tricomes for sure
but we're excited to try it have a
Quebec sugar maple growing here we also
can get water from birch trees so we can
boil down birch as well to get syrup and
then we have some yakon that we grew
this summer we can boil down yakone to
get syrup so those are the three things
that we would like to try in I think
maple syrup would be amazing the the
Birch syrup would make a great soda
right so delicious yeah that that would
be Co I'd be interested in that yum well
come see us have some
sassa we're here we're waiting for you
well there's a lot of maple syrup here
in Vermont and so I always wondered
about the intersection between Maple
sugaring and and cannabis and hemp and
where those two nutritional things come
together like you've mentioned I mean
some people are sugar adverse so syrup
is mostly sugar although I do see signs
for sugar-free syrup I don't know what
that
is I don't know maybe that's a dove or
something yeah cone syrup would be the
best syrup for a person that was
sensitive to to sugars so you know with
the maple extract so you could basically
make a synthetic maple syrup by adding
like a maple extract to that or
something absolutely and and and I use
that in our in our cooking all the time
I have an awesome organic maple extract
because you know I don't cook with sugar
so I'm always trying to think of
different things outside of the box and
there's some really beautiful Maple
extracts that are made up here in Quebec
like have all of the Essences and it's
really beautiful but you know the sugars
are extracted yeah if you're making can
of butter in general maple syrup is a
great little additive to add to give it
a little punch and you you you'll end up
seeing the water separate after your
butter pools but
it'll it'll leave a little bit of the
maple essds back in the
butter well in the cool thing the honey
when you put the when you put the fresh
flowers into the honey and then you
extract it for a couple of months it
would be the same as probably putting it
into maple syrup it extracts The Waters
from the Fresh flour now you don't have
to use fresh flour but when you do use
fresh flour it locks in tpin like
amazing when you open up the Honey Jar
it just smells like the fresh Tarpin of
the flow and honey yeah so but what
happens is when the waters are extracted
into that there's a tiny bit of and
you've got to watch it of fermentation
that might happen and personally I think
that is like so delicious and really
amazing but there is like something that
changes when those extracted wat yeah go
into the honey and I would think the
same thing for the maple syrup but an
incredible place to start dispersing and
talking about the acidic compounds of
canabo and using Birch you would get
the that's what is B
uh Papyrus
bolinus or anyway bolinus and then also
um uh piptoporus binus the mushrooms
that grow on it in aotus so anyway
there's a lot of the that you see that
name continuing to come up through the
medicinal mushrooms as well it's the
cambium layer the the the pulsing Waters
through the cambium later that's the
most
healthy why birches
why chaga is so powerful and it has the
most sods Super oxide dismutase sodd
it's a longevity enzyme and chaga has
more sods than any other herb on Earth
and uh one other thing that has a lot of
sods is turtles so they they're one
thing that lives a long time
and when you find Birch in the forest um
you'll see a whole entire tree you know
know decomposed on the inside but the
birch bark will look nearly perfect like
it was still growing because of that you
know s so and that that that that type
of betulinic acid is in there so making
tea from birch bark is super powerful
and potent for you just putting the bark
in into water and boiling it not boiling
more steeping or are simmering and then
steeping assuming people are herbalists
and understand what it takes to make you
know compounds yeah less
temperature and uh but anyway bark even
from other trees is powerful Larch you
know um anyway yeah healing from The
Forest of the of the too is really it's
pretty amazing they're really different
in flavor and I think that the Birch
water I think is even sweeter than the
sugar maple water somehow it has some
kind of a resonant like maybe it's like
even resinous sweetness that sticks with
you that where the sugar maple doesn't
have that but it is true that when you
do any type of tests on the
triglycerides or all of the different
polyphenols and things in mushrooms we
find that the ones growing on Birches
have much higher medicinal compounds
than the ones growing on other trees now
when you're starting to talk about old
growth now you know we can't really
necessarily do those comparisons because
old growth you know has
exponential um healing properties but
Birch really is a winner and and it's
one that's you know like in forestry
they they don't they don't utilize they
don't take care of it they think it's a
weed they cut it down burn it off it's
lame so there's a lot of areas you know
in BC and in and in Canada and I know
definitely in the Eastern us where the
Boreal forest and you know the the fur
Forest hits the Birch Forest a lot of
that area is just being degraded because
there's not a lot of value for the Birch
but if we started putting value in the
mushrooms and we started putting value
in the medicinal compounds of what's in
the forest it would even outweigh
monetarily what they're getting per
board feet of you know lumber sales but
I just think that it's just not as
creative I'm not saying that there's no
use for lumber there definitely is it's
just to see the forest as something more
than just board feet we really could use
more of that creativity as a human
species to you know upgrade us um and
our health and well-being there's so
much intelligence in the forest there
and also there's little lumps in The
Balsam fur and in the spruce in the in
the um bark and you can push out the the
sap out of the bark and collect all the
sap and that sap and that pitch is super
useful and topicals warming it up using
that in your um topicals and combining
that with cannabis is really good also
in the springtime the the trees
pollinate and they um sporulate and and
you'll see a whole entire Forest just
pollinating so Gathering pine pollen
from the flowers and the springtime is
incredibly useful to uh uh you know just
human health in general so big up this
is a red belted
conk the beauty
so I was going to bring up that is kind
of interesting here watching the the sun
grown fullterm
uh plants that are matching the colors
uh they're obviously all poly you know
hybrids at this point but you can see a
definite line between the later sativa
more green with no purple even into Cold
versus some of the really dark violet
red pink it's actually funny the the
drop leaves and the lower set leaves go
yellow and then kind of Fade up into an
orangey red into Violet so it actually
matches the tree line in the fall here
for the foliage so it's kind of bringing
up some interesting thoughts about the
sugar conversion that fits into the
Maple and the birch and and how this
Terre this region of the north all the
way across the board where you guys are
up there talking about it over to here
in Maine which is Big Maple Country here
to Vermont up into Quebec and I just
kind of watching the sugars FL flow high
and then dip low in this really big
binary Spike you know and dip and it
seems to have a lot to do with pushing
out smell bouquet for tpping loud loud
in the early morning when the Dew comes
in and it's the you know the DW points
hit and it's it's just popping off its
smell when it goes to bed at night even
seems like there's resin cluster and
shine with swelling that happens into
those plants those more colorful plants
this time of year so I just want to kind
of throw that out there as an
interesting aspect where again
interesting in different regions where
the different strains can shine and such
and I'm definitely seeing better results
with the indicia based poly with some of
the tpine profiles we talked about from
lemon um now over to Cherry showing even
the Cherry brought in some cherry Cam
that has amazing resistance factor out
here even tested some of the original
Cherry cam sister to the brother to let
go long and now and even through storm
everything I haven't seen any vrtis it
had a septoria hit late but not one
piece of betrus yet on the on the whole
row so seeing some interesting
stuff and then some you know talk about
this Northern Region for the sugar
spiking and dipping into this ripening
period just wanted to throw that out
there I think once you build up the
intelligence in your soil and you start
using that leaf from the forest and a
lot of those inputs from the forest in
your beds and then you start you know
doing more and more Mulch and the aisles
in between your beds sort of connecting
the forest and you and in the end you do
start getting that underground
connection going on where they will
communicate with each other they'll even
probably you know start
transferring sugars and and and even
trace minerals you know back and forth
to each other that's why I think it's
really valuable you know mulching into
the transitions out of your garden so
that you can get you know outside let's
say outside input into your garden but
the more indigenous layering and buildup
you're doing the more you're building up
that soil rizosphere
intelligence uh and then the atmosphere
and risos spere you know combination
through the gashes exchanges uh they
they start uh building the the cells and
everything to make that happen so yeah I
mean that's that's what you start
getting when you build your land over
and over like 10 years from now your
land will be even next year it'll be
more but you know what I mean is we're
we're here for six
Summers now so it's been 16 years of
building building the soil and it was
actually you really crazy this year each
year that we're building our soil more
and more uh you know we haven't really
been utilizing teas anymore we only
utilize teas on sort of our new beds or
on fruit trees because it's just o over
nutrify and the more that our beds
become mature we're just not really
seeing any pathogens you know we're
still seeing the aphid that bong aphid
it's around and about but with all of
the poly culture that we have around by
the time the plants ready to harvest
there's not really any aphids on at all
maybe little bits here and there we saw
it maybe in our later season but like
it's amazing if you are seeing your farm
or whatever your Gardens as you know a
whole system not just when you walk into
your garden that your garden is the
system but that your garden is the
center part or part of a whole system
then the whole system helps take care of
the garden and the plants and that's
really awesome to definitely know that
the endic system of the ganja plants are
just so full that the allocation of any
type of pathogen in there is almost like
nil and that's been pretty amazing to
see and that's definitely by bringing
more and more intelligence of the Zone
around us into our Gardens rather than
trying to create something different in
our Gardens let's just see what's around
us and that's why every Garden should be
different and we shouldn't all talk
about the same exact you know additions
and techniques and and yeah but we do
are what we are starting to lean towards
is making big ferments right now in the
fall as we har everything and then tea
in the mulch for the winter so then we
have this sort
recharge of nutrients and green and
sugars from the leaves and sugars from
you know the diey off and also the most
trace minerals and the most minerals
that the plant or the seeds and
everything have in it you can make a big
fermentation which we have right now and
then after we mulch everything we just
do a really big tea over it and then the
snow comes or if we have some green
houses that we keep covered for the
winter then we use uh sprinklers inside
of the greenhouse to just keep it really
wet on the inside of the greenhouse so
that the inside of the greenhouse can
sort of have that cleanliness of water
happening in it and break down
Wade did you have a hash event last
weekend that you were involved in uh yes
um and uh hello everyone uh yeah had a
really wonderful uh Gathering of about
12 folks I think is how many folks came
and
um yeah we got up to all kinds of fun
things one of the things that I wanted
to show you all is a a piece of uh dry
sift one of our local producers is going
to
be selling uh old
school uh dry sift solvent list etc etc
etc anyway he's very proud of it and
he's old school enough that uh the uh
his marketing thing is going to be a
little gold leaf lightning bolt on the
pieces that come out and I kind of like
that because if you um if you were
smoking hash back in the 70s and had
access to good Afghani or Pakistani or
it often came with a seal on on the uh
plaque you'd get uh typically Preston
gold leaf and whatnot anyway he's of
that era as am I and I we got into a
fascinating conversation about hash and
I raised my hand earlier because I
wanted to ask y all's opinion about this
um the hash that came back in the 60s
and
70s um came from Fields where male and
female plants grew together so all the
females were
fertilized and it's my experience with
analytical testing when you look at the
conoid profiles in cannabis that is
seeded uh it's significantly different
than that same plant might have made
wori
sensia uh but I really loved the hash
that was coming into this country back
in the 60s and 70s and so I'm I'm I'm
really wanting to throw open a
conversation and hear some expert
opinions on the fact that most of the
hash that's available in the legal
cannabis market today is made from CIA
it's not made from fertilized females
and so it's different hash than what was
happening back then and certainly we
have higher uh canono content in the in
the hashish that we're enjoying these
days
but I just wondered uh what the thinking
from a panel of informed folk is on that
uh the differences between the hash we
have today that comes you know really
beautiful hash yeah last weekend I got
very
stuned but
um but uh and I'm very St today as well
thank you um yeah I'm I'm just wondering
what's what's the opinion here amongst
This Crew what is you know there's a
real difference there and where where
where do we want to take that
conversation that's all I got thank you
for the moment I'm sure I'll have more
to say you know I don't have a lot of
experience smoking hash that was made
from male and female plants but what I
do have is in the last year or two when
I came up with this hash hits product uh
you know I'm so I'm like Sam I'm just so
used to like taking rocket ships to the
moon like just pu puffing this pure hash
it's 60 to 80% it's high tping contents
it's just this intense blast and that's
what I've loved and I've been almost
blindingly loving it without really
paying attention I I don't smoke joints
I don't smoke weed so what I found was
when I started the the hash hits which
was really you know the basis of the
idea was to create a product that would
build a bridge for people who had no
paraphilia other than a lighter they
don't even roll joints they buy
pre-rolled joints and I wanted to build
a product that allow owed people to kind
of have a bridge over to hash and
extracts and you know it's just a little
tube a little paper tube it's got a
little metal bowl with tiny little holes
in it that we pack a02 of a gram of hash
into and of course right away I knew I
wasn't going to be able to pack full
melt hash into this thing because the
hash would melt and plug these holes and
you'd suck it into the tube so I had and
and as well turning someone on who only
smokes pre-rolled joints uh to Hash the
best product is not the thing to turn
them on to it's just it's too potent and
it it's not going to be the experience
that they're looking for so I kind of
had to force my ego aside and smoke you
know what most people on this panel
would call mediocre hash but what I
found was and I've learned this from
smoking so many different you know
people ask me all the time do you prefer
the torch and nailed do you prefer the
electric nail do you like the puff Co do
you like all these different things and
or vape pens or any of these things and
what I found is as a cannabis lover that
there's a place for me to love those
things at different times in different
places and so um it what I had to do
with these hash hits was I had to start
r&amp; ding them and smoking them and I had
a smoke hash of of a non-melt quality in
you know in a couple of decades or
whatever and so here I am now going for
an electric skateboard and uh pulling
out a hash hit and and hitting and
burning as well I hadn't burned in like
15 years or something so what I did
notice when I was able to put aside my
judgments on oh it's not melting and it
tastes a little burnt and I don't like
it as much as I like this and I just put
all that aside what I did find was that
I Lov the lack of intensity in the high
it was almost like if it was a food
metaphor all I was doing was eating to
be stuffed and for the first time now I
was just eating a small amount just to
be like not completely satiated but like
oh that was a nice little treat like I'm
not you know I'm I'm still present I'm
not completely blasted out of my skull
uh not that getting blasted out of my
skull you know put limitations on me in
any way I'm a bit of an anomaly like
that as probably many of the people on
the panel are but what I found was I
really enjoyed the the lack of intensity
of the high that I also had an
appreciation for this for these subtle
nuances of the hash that I was now
experiencing that I knew that this is
what these people that I built this
product for were going to be
experiencing they were going to be able
to instead of smoke a joint with paper
and glue and and and matter I could get
them over to hash and they could smoke
this this hash hit and have a nice
experience without the paper and the
glue and the and the uh and the Cannabis
but have that nice experience that's not
that so many people have told me over
the years when I've given them a dab
they're just like I don't like that it's
way too intense I'm blasted out of my
skull uh I just you know there's certain
times that maybe that's not what you
want and there's lots of times where
maybe that is what you want so it was
interesting from my perspective to
remove myself from the bubble man way of
thinking and and smoke something that
I've almost been judging harshly for the
last 20 years and I got to stay Wade
like uh there were times that I I quite
enjoyed it you know when I'm out on my
electric skateboard particularly with my
son I don't want to pull out my rig and
all my gear and have a dab and then put
it all away and put it in the backpack
and clean the Banger and do all of this
stuff but to just pull a tube out and
hit it like two or three times and then
put it back in the case and shut it up
it really was a lovely subtle nuance and
and I don't know if it's because I'm
getting older or if I was just able to
put my ego aside for a short period of
time where you know we have to remember
there's so many different enjoyable
aspects of cannabis and one of the
things from my perspective that I've
always been trapped in is that I've you
know not anymore as much but for a long
time I thought that you know the best
was this and that everyone needed the
best and everyone should have the best
but um what I'm learning is is the best
is is what's best for you and uh we
should enjoy cannabis in all her glory
uh whether it's smoking a pin or joint
or whether it's smoking some some dry
sifted single screen hash or whether
it's smoking some six-star full mail
cash so that's my piece that's what I
have to say and anyone else that wants
to answer or Wade wants to reply now
it's your time if if you if it don't
bubble it ain't worth the trouble
well early I remember have we didn't
have that in the uh in the early 90s or
late 80s so I mean I had access to at
times to quote unquote Afghani hashish
that was black to Brown that did have a
gold seal on it but it is definitely I
think Mojave stated as well that you
know the the hash that we're seeing
today is you know is made from all of
these newer genetics as well as opposed
to you know those were old older land
races as well that we were ingesting and
I agree they were both males and females
they were pollinated uh plants so I did
not get sometimes as High um smoking
that hash I'd always sprinkle it or
break it down and put it on top of
something um you know to just kind of
add to it because of the nuances that it
gave it gave a depth that none of the
Cannabis that you had access to had
because I think of the you know the CBN
and all of that that are you know
inherent as depending on how it was sift
but also it had a lot of impurities as
well they were packing it with you know
wax lots of vegetable matter no seeds or
anything like that but the quality you
can I mean it's like when you go to
Amsterdam okay right you go to Amsterdam
for the hash you don't go for the flower
right so go sit there and you smoke a a
Temple ball there in Amsterdam now take
that same Temple ball and go vaporize
it it tastes like hand it tastes like
the essential oils it tastes like all of
that unfortunately that comes from the
hand rolling etc etc so I think also by
having things like bubble man's bags
sing technology has better because
remember they used to used to use right
you used to use particularly just one
seeve right from the books that I from
the the old book hashish Etc they all
tend to show just one particular screen
as opposed to a series of screens until
you know later but uh I sent this invite
specifically to Mojave because movei uh
is also a master of the older hashish
and understanding so move I'm going to
defer and tap head to you because uh
love you love you too man Moab hey there
D hey there Sam um yeah I I just came in
at just the right time man I love this
conversation about traditional hash I
think it's really important um you know
uh like Marcus you're you're everyone
like the average guy's just got a
lighter that that idea I just love the
concept of like let's really think about
who the consumer is because I think
we've really driven the market and the
industry so much because we're so deep
into the science and the tech and but
the average consumer just really needs
us to kind of like provide them with
what they need in the simplest and most
available form and traditional hashish
kind of really nailed that you know I
mean they really kind of came to this
like Middle Ground of potency and
portability and stability and yeah there
it is that's it man that's perfect give
the people what they need
yeah but the other thing that I think is
really interesting that I that
constantly can I ask Marcus question
quick yeah please how much is that
retail for
Marcus this is uh the five tubes are a
gram and it retails for around like 24
bucks 25 bucks Canadian okay okay cool
thank you I'm sorry Mojave no no problem
man um but the other thing I just one
thing I'd love to hear from from the
group here that constantly fascinates me
about traditional hashish
is the somewhat intentional degradation
of the whole plant profile before it was
pressed and the aging process and the
drying in the Sun and and not just with
hashish with a lot of different
traditional cannabis um cultures with
you know maloi corn cobs and all these
things people did to like take this
beautiful perfect plant that we're so
desperately trying to like achieve this
whole plant full aromatic profile and
destroyed a lot of that because the way
they ingested cannabis was different for
one they ingested large amounts you know
like when you think about hashish
cultures like Afghanistan I mean Sam
obviously knows this better than anybody
um they filled that Hubbly Bubbly with
what an ounce a half an
ounce anywhere from a few a few grams to
uh really yeah like an ounce uh when
when we used to do it uh here in
Amsterdam we we would put in two or
three grams sprinkled on top of the
glowing coals and just keep doing that
we could do it for like an hour or two
and uh yeah just keep making bong hit
those two or three grams was for each
person to make
they could do it better than me
maybe what's the what what's the
economics of a Hubbly Bubbly like so so
Marcus was sort of making a paradigm of
you know just you know the average guy
who wants to cons
or girl whoever you know just somebody
with a match or somebody with a lighter
I mean now you need this Hubbly Bubbly
thing and how much hash are you using in
a single sitting is it more than you
have to spend for what Marcus getting
but we were smoking it with large
amounts of people so it was what did we
smoke Marcus maybe an ounce or two or
three or four oh God I'm sure judging by
the pale pale pale color of everyone's
face I say that it was right right
around there for
certain but it's also that's that's a
culture of Growers you know that's a
culture of hash movers and you know I
remember when I was moving cannabis I
had pounds and pounds of free cannabis
my friends that were growing lots of
cannabis always had towns of cannabis so
it's it's very different from you know
Joe Blow who's just like I'm not
connected to this community I'm not
connected to this industry but I still
want to have an experience with cannabis
and so you know they're very different
things and there's very there's very
little Pathways and bridges from the one
to the other and so obviously you know
getting cannabis into legal stores here
in Canada has opened that up people have
access to drinks and creams and all
sorts of different things and you know
they don't know much better because it's
actually fairly easy Marcus if you're
willing to dedicate your time and life
and energy towards Perfection of
cannabis but few people are willing to
do that to be honest that's true and I
think for us what we want for cannabis
is that you know I don't necessarily
want everyone to do that you know what I
want everyone to do is have access to it
as an option over just alcohol that's
what I want
what I had said was what I had said was
I wanted people to have people that
don't dedicate their lives I want them
to have access to cannabis over just
alcohol and so that's what this getting
it into these stores and still fighting
this good fight of you know in Canada we
can't have Edibles over 10 milligrams
and there's all these limitations still
and it's you know I think someone wrote
I think it was Andrew D'Angelo wrote on
Twitter the other day if grocery stores
had to get expensive licenses and all
the vendors had to have super expensive
licenses and you had to test
rigorously uh we would probably all
starve in about three
weeks add tobacco to that list too
Markus or grow our own
food you could add forestry to the list
because the Foresters around here are
are able to have cops come and arrest
the community
to make sure they get to do their job
and it would be weird to think about
having a cannabis farm which is a
life-saving Herb Farm to have like that
kind of ability to go around and be like
hey these guys are growing weed around
here you understand don't do anything
about it but I think that um uh Mojave
what you were talking about with
different cultures in the world and
different ways of ingesting cannabis is
it's probably you know more than
anything a
microbial thing you know microbial
connection or it's creating some kind of
a different canabo through its
transformation that's more bioavailable
to them you know in their lifestyle or
maybe it's because it lasts longer you
know three or four months down the road
and that's when they really need it so
even though it may not be the best for
the moment you know four months down the
road it's going to have preserved and
still have been their form so I think
there's a lot of different techniqu that
go into making the extractions but I do
believe that you know the traditional
ways of making things are worth keeping
around because you know you get all
headyy about new things and it's fun to
do that too but you know there's reasons
why that whole plant traditional
medicine really was a better medicine
for the the healing and stuff which is
good for us to remember and to keep that
in our realm so we we do we still do a
good amount of air drying and Trad hash
making on on our farm personally um but
we also are doing you know the new St
freeze dryer yeah we have a freeze dryer
and a press doing well I also just
noticed that sorry U I also just noticed
like what what Marcus was saying earlier
that you know I always I was always
trying to make full melt the most potent
hash I could but I also found that I was
like not smoking it at every time that I
would want to consume I'd kind of save
it for the end of the day or for like
you know and it was maybe just a little
bit too potent for looking at
spreadsheets and doing business stuff
and kind of realized it just didn't fit
in my like daily life as well as kind of
lower potency hash did just closer to
flower you know um so I've been smoking
a lot of like 30
40% um hash that really just it feels
really good it might have a little
Sizzle to it but it's not full melt by
any stretch and just feels really good
and it also keeps me so that I don't get
so downregulated so at the end of the
day when everything is kind of eased and
life is chilled and the sun went down I
can go and pull out that full melt and
feel the full impact and it kind of
gives me you know I feel that there's
kind of an arc to every day to if you
are consuming cannabis throughout the
day that you want to keep it so you have
so you can get high and so that you're
functional and I think hash really did
that and I think that there's something
also to just the the tpine canabo ratio
being different on on Lower potency hash
you know you start to get tpine start to
degrade and cannaboids start to go up
per per volume that you're getting in
your body so you get a really different
effect that way
moabi but uh when you seed a crop then
you cut the Tarpin in about
half you cut you lower the canono also
you cut down the total yield of canono
and turpins but you the T it really
affects the tpin even stronger than the
canabo I will say the way the way it the
way it fits into the chain of custody
here in Canada not sure if I'm frozen
probably yeah no you're not I'm not well
everyone else is
notz okay great um the chain of custody
in Canada when you make an exceptional
product and you keep it at minus 20
degrees Celsius and then you send it out
to the to the government you know
warehouses and then to the stores they
don't keep it cold and it's drastically
affected so the more traditional hashes
are less affected in fact they tend to
almost get better with being at room
temperature and aging a little bit
whereas like I put out beautiful rosin I
put out a beautiful 65% like four to
five star hash it was it was very light
in color and it ended up like almost
black after sitting in a warehouse at 30
32 degrees Celsius in Toronto for three
days because there was a problem with
the barcode you know there's in our
country they're still I use the metaphor
they're still shipping spinach warm they
don't have a cold supply chain to move
these products and when you make a
specialized product like a high-end
rosin or a full Mount bubble it's very
difficult to put it out into the into
the world and have the people experience
it the way you put it out whereas these
more traditional hashes single screen
hashes they don't have that big of a
degreg the degreg isn't seen as a
negative you know for hashes like that
people want to Pres preserve them they
want to keep them cold they certainly
aren't curing them there's no curing
high-end hashes anymore there's just
preserving them whereas with these
traditional hash methods they fit more
into the current supply chain of you
know everyone not keeping it
cold well also too when you press it you
have a tendency to rock it in place I
mean you might squeeze out some of the
smell by the act of pressing but you're
also it's more stable stabilized as
pressed piece than it is loose but you
and I know I know we both prefer loose
resin yeah absolutely even the resin
that I'm putting into the hashit is is a
loose resin it's not we tried you can
put press hash in it burns very very
differently it almost simmers uh which
I'm sure we'll eventually do uh you know
because once again um what you think is
best for everyone isn't it's just what's
best for you and you really have to open
your mind and and and realize that
there's a whole variety of people out
there and for me in Canada in particular
I'm kind of done after 25 years of
preaching to the choir I want to turn
some new people on and I know that I'm
not going to turn them on with uh you
know like a 85% THC rosin that I made
from you know live hash or whatever
that's great I want to still make that
make it available as always but I also
want to turn on this big group of people
that are completely different uh they
don't have the experience with it at all
but I kind of want to move them away you
know at least have an experience of
moving away from just smoking pre-rolled
joints which are not considered to be
the highest quality cannabis in the
first place it's ground it's mil it ages
poorly compared to Hash especially in a
cold uh warm supply chain and so it's uh
yeah it took a long time to sort of
figure out that uh may maybe what you
need is a metered puffco so they can get
you know a vaporized small hit that's
equivalent of 10 or 20 milligrams
they're not going to spend $500 on that
they're going to spend 99 cents on this
this is the tool you have to make work
for them they all have this this is what
they have this is what we need to this
is what we need to supply for them a
product that they can oh I don't smoke
half because I don't have a pipe I don't
have a pipe I don't I can't smoke has
Well here here's a hash hit give this a
shot it's just a tube you can puff it
with a lighter and you can you can have
that experience and what I've found so
far you know we did a great uh uh thing
recently at Northshore cannabis uh with
the future of cannabis project London
and all these great guys they they were
pushing the envelope they said let's set
up a tent outside in the parking lot and
we'll have a little smoking session
outside of this this legal dispensary
which is pushing the envelope for sure
it's not really allowed although most of
us were medical patients smoking in an
environment that was legal to smoke in
um but we I met a woman she's not on
social media she barely you know she's
only buys pre-roll joints and she sat
with us for a bit and she said well I'll
I'll try your your product or whatever
she actually went and bought some Bubble
Man hash and I just gave her some hash
hit tubes and she sat there and she just
put a little dab in and she she smoked
it with her lighter she had a couple of
Puffs and I just said you know like
what's how how was that in comparison to
smoking joints and she's like well it
definitely was a clearer High than I get
from the joint and it was a little bit
stronger and and it was just neat to
hear her perspective of being like yeah
this was really nice it was like one
puff I didn't have to smoke a whole
joint sometimes the joints don't taste
that good and the hash tasted really
good so you know one by one if we help
educate these people that aren't
watching hash Church they're not on
social media and Instagram and looking
at all the photos you kind of got to get
out into the world and I've said this
before the importance of allowing us to
gather and smoke is so so very important
the conversation I froze of
course I
froze of those sticks are in that one
package ATN five five five so so Marcus
Ju Just for the uneducated user so do do
uh each one of those represents kind of
like a joint so like one session right
so it's five sessions and you said it
was $60 is that right
$25 um and it's it's more than five
sessions in the sense it's uh I get
about 10 rips from from this I get about
rips and people who don't smoke very
much get about 20 so you're getting
between 50 and 100 pop out of a pack for
bucks so it's it's pretty substantial
you know 18 18 that that would sell in
the US wouldn't
it companies have had meter dosage
vaporizers um unfortunately it just
didn't catch on to people or I don't
think the um the efficacy or the
expandability was there but uh we had
meter dosages back prior to Prior prop
64 I can't think of the exact were those
vaporizers or were
nebulizers uh they were vaporizers uh
the problem is is that they were
internalized batteries so the batteries
died depending on how long or the
production because they were made in Pre
they were not able to charge so there
were technical realities that were not
necessarily expressive at the time which
I think currently there are because
people were pushing for the latest in
medical efficacy right so by having a
small handheld metered
vaporizer it just didn't catch on with
people because the the the hit was so
small for people they were used to a
larger hit so I think it was multiple
things uh New newa Market it was uh uh
state-of-the-art at the time but
unfortunately then we had when they
would run out they were useless so
people wanted to then recycle them and
we couldn't recycle the batteries
because of the componentry Etc because
did you see
nebulizers I have seen nebulizers we did
not see them sold to us
yeah yeah that's what I'm saying you
need you need Simple
Technology a lighter that's simple
technology that's what this was designed
for if people don't want batteries
things that are going to fail they want
to pull out their lighter and have a
little pop This Is A specific group I'm
talking about I'm not talking about
everyone by any means but that's what
this was designed for and uh it's been
well received in Canada and we're in the
middle of making some deals to bring it
down to uh you know Washington and
Oregon and California uh and
Massachusetts and Colorado and Nevada so
there's there's there's deals on the
table do you print a label on them that
says perfect for law enforcement and
correction officers absolutely
100% no ATN made a good point is well
about like actual volume I think people
really enjoy taking larger hits and
feeling the full inhalation and their
lungs expansion and holding it for a
second and having even lower potency
cannabis I think would be really helpful
for that just like um instead of
downregulating yourself so you need to
take more just have lower potency so
you're kind of at your threshold already
and if you enjoy it not to create you
know addictive habits but people do like
like to do this and and um I find like
with hash it's kind of nice when you can
just keep packing the bowl and smoking
big bowls and same the flower like these
are repack too you know they they are
they're repack like I've repacked one
tube like four or five times if you
light them correctly they they don't
burn they don't like degrade like you
know ideally you're not going to smoke
it forever but it's a nice sort of free
I mean hash grams of hash are already 20
to $25 in Canada and the legal Market so
I thought let's come in at the same
price but like Pro provide the vessel
for smoking the hash out of and I think
that that you know convenience is the
thing that we don't talk about too much
in the in the Cannabis world you know
we're like oh what about a puff Co what
about a measured dose what about a
$4,000 Banger with a $10,000 pipe and a
blowtorch and
a dosist was the company I was trying to
think of that had done a meter dose of
small pen um that was spe specifically
toward medical patients so do s i s if I
A A A at and if you had to guess what
would that pack that Marcus showed us
retail for at
BPG
um it's it's five specific is it meter
dosages they're not metered it's point
two of a gr so it's not metered in the
sense that you could smoke half of it in
three puffs or you could smoke one tenth
of it in in one puff yeah a gram a half1
to $20 retail depending you know if if
you know it's it's all on the amount of
cannabis and of course in the packaging
but from the distributor Etc depending
on you know manufacturing and cost I
mean it could be 25 to 30 I don't know
uh but you know what do you sell them
for in uh
Canadian you mute you muted yourself
Mark 25 I 25 I think in the US it would
be 20 bucks $18 to $20 US 20 to 25 yeah
that sounds about
right and people are looking for that
they're looking for something that's
specific that's a an easier dosage they
don't like having to buy a big cone and
then having to burn a little of it
because as you know the flavors taste
everything about it really changes from
the tars and everything that's internal
so well are looking for smaller dosage
things it's again it's more that are
medical specific as opposed to the
recreational just to clarify is it isn't
a traditional 28 and that you know
pre-rolls are kind of like the Run
litter it's just kind of like the shake
at the bottom you know after you've
packaged up a bunch of stuff it's
basically what it can be that way if
you're specifically doing it the biggest
problem that I want to say to every
manufacturer out there is stop using
cones just just stop it doesn't work
you're all trying to to to cram too much
stuff into these cones whereas the most
successful ones are people like
connected that do a straight cigarette
style
one bought that are pre-made I think uh
it's they granulate it too much what
happens is the last inch an inch and a
half it clogs up and it's useless and
you're wasting a gram to two grams of
flour outright so I'm I'm imploring
every manufacturer who makes cones stop
just [ __ ] off with it raw all of you I
understand you you like it and it's
easier for consumers but every
manufacturer has gotten [ __ ] lazy and
what you're using is way too dried
product that burns up way too quickly
you're not using proper product for your
actual pre-rolls uh so please just stop
you're insulting us all you're doing it
wrong
and somebody get out there like
connected and show them how to do it
right because you're wasting consumer's
time you're wasting their money and
you're pissing off new consumers who are
like hey I got a cone and they're like
oh I'm halfway so who's got a bowl [ __ ]
off with that [ __ ] and [ __ ] grow some
real [ __ ] pot and put it in your
[ __ ] cone I mean in your actual
joints and stop with the cones unless
they're twice the size because it's just
gumming up way too much because the
quality of flour is higher than what it
used to be and if you're putting resin
in it you absolutely have to stop with
the coning so I'll get off my soap books
now but all you cone making
[ __ ] [ __ ] you go to hell I
[ __ ] hate you all save the cones for
the ice cream
right but CH what about what about the
gold con cones those are the best aren't
they the gold
cones and they can [ __ ] off with the
gold Co cones too sorry I I I hate to be
so so adamant passionate about my hate
and vitrail for them but I buy every
single one that comes through BPG and I
try them all i' I roll my own even I use
a machine that actually rolls them
evenly so they exist okay including that
you can roll but manufacturers who are
putting out these products are
absolutely crap they're too tightly
packed and you're just turning off
consumers to a product that when I was
in Amsterdam a decade ago plus they were
doing it right they were using cones but
they were packing them properly you're
you're you're packing them way too tight
and I've been to many different
manufacturing facilities and watched
your people do it as they sit there with
little tools to pack and Tamp that stuff
down you're doing it wrong go back to
how we used to roll and roll them evenly
across the board am I wrong here people
am I is my head my ass here you're
you're you're absolutely right but I
want to make one notable exception which
is uh and I'll point out to my friend
Josh here on the upper right the canar
that I got in the teepe was the canar
that changed my life so other than yet
rolling regular joints I'm totally with
you ATN if they look like a cigarette
that's cool but the canar I think for
The Connoisseur is kind of in a separate
category that it's okay to be nice and
big and obnoxiously big and well well we
met Cones were for sharing and and and
people don't share nearly as much as
they used to you know covid changed that
and it's like the little three dog
walkers are really popular because it's
like I can go smoke it and put it out
and I don't have to hide a stinky thing
and they taste like [ __ ] if you fire it
up again you know so you know I know
cones are a bummer and yeah it's it's a
mess it's crazy you know the the whole
pre-roll packaged Goods thing is just
nuts you know and and all the the um
infused pre-rolls and stuff everyone's
trying to to make a better pre-roll but
really it's all ATN it's it it's about
just like cigarettes cigarettes figured
out like here's a a a standard form that
every single cigarette company adopted
like overnight because the delivery
system was just better and more
convenient and everyone even the
government does it they spend their
actual joints out from a Paul mul
equally rolled machine and guess what
they burn evenly
they're they're actually rolled uh at
the El's laboratory
facilities and uh they use a bonac
cigarette rolling machine to do
it no doubt visit I visited their
facility and there's an old High Times
article I think from 78 that shows them
actually doing it too it shows the
machine one of those old cigarette
machines machines there there's a
company here in Canada called Ready can
that does it with this cigarette rolling
technology from the tobacco industry and
they just sold that company for like
$900
million there's a good amount of uh
small batch Farmers I'm seeing now with
little glass tip uh straight uh
pre-rolls and and things that are really
nice looking and and then some infused
and all that and so I'm starting to see
that and I agree with you that you know
an evenly rolled and a thicker joint
brings more
flavor and it allows the resin to kind
of caramelize and burn on itself as it's
burning through and really it should be
getting better as it's going down to the
bottom rather than getting hotter and
and more packed in and stuff so yeah
maybe it's like heads up to Future Rola
and all the different rolling companies
out there that are you know really
giving people these as options because I
think people would start taking the
option they're not giving you an option
that's the problem is that you're only
dealt cones you go to raw and everything
else I just saw today they even made an
actual little raw a a cone roller
attachment that goes on your keychain so
you can roll a nice little tight joint
and can perpetuate this [ __ ] so
sorry I'm it's just my anger don't don't
jump on the canar people who are making
I'm not dumping on the canar canar
continue to make those products Jos that
canar that you gave me at the at that at
the tee when I met when I met I brought
that to delest the Bluegrass Festival I
think a year later and changed a lot of
people's worlds with that single device
so thank you kind totally yeah big up to
you and big up to the makers out there
and that's that's what's up you know and
you remember that canar right oh yeah
definitely yeah for sure it was
spectacular definitely what is it with
the canar itself so it's actually using
leaves of LEF the sun leaf and and then
also often you know adding a lot of uh
rosin and uh bubble hash to the
inside and then having like a stick on
the inside so you know the chances you
know a lot of those things can be you
know have an ounce of hash inside of
them as well as I mean it burns so
slowly unlike just like a fatty like if
we had had a fatty the same size the
fatty would have been gone an hour ago
that thing took about seriously about
two hours to burn and I shared it down
at a a pit right in front of Del
mccurry's band playing up there and you
could just see
CLS there look good with the disco ball
too because it gets the lights going and
everything so I'm sure it was much
appreciated in the crowd that's sweet
canar producers Please keep those movies
coming the people who like those I mean
I I think it's a different product than
just a a a joint if you will or just a
fatty or something I have to say that I
I I do love still rolling my own and I
still love the idea of putting two
papers together and and making even like
what we used to call ungrateful dead to
are a fatty right so when you light a
fatty it's not like lighting that nail
cigarette because you light a fatty it's
like Whoa man that [ __ ] thing
just and you
draw have you guys seen the um perfect
pre-rolls perfect brand pre-rolls that
Michael bachus works with they're
they're pretty far out the the one thing
that's really cool about them is they
have two filters on either a filter on
either side so the concept is that you
can snap it right down the middle and
share it or you can cut one filter off
and have a full one gram joint to
yourself um it's just it's just a silly
little idea and the funny thing is they
he came over to our facility in in La a
couple years ago just as like a just
like hey I just rolled this up just for
us to share and he cut it and I was like
dude that's a product no one's done that
I mean it's silly and weird but it's a
total product and there really has an
interesting infusion technology so they
the flower actually does stay
um the tpine profile actually lasts a
lot longer and it's not just dumping a
bunch of um extract in there it's it's
pretty interesting um that as far as
pre-rolls that's one company that's done
something
different
again perfect perfect yeah
perfect yeah they do they do pre-rolls
and they do flower um like like Blended
or I don't know if it's all Blended but
it's um might be single variety but um
it's uh loose so it's broken up loose
flour in a jar for people to roll joints
or pack bowls it's another one of these
things of like everything that we do and
we Engage The Flower so much we engage
the product so much but there's a lot of
there's a lot involved and maybe people
just don't want to be that invol or
can't be that involved can't take the
time to crumble up or get stinky hands
and go back to work and be scrutinized
or something so they make a product
where it's like just loose
um flow it's really interesting it's
moabi we all know only god is
perfect say The Atheist the one high if
thanks everyone I want to get H show
appreciation acknowledgement and love to
all you and everyone in the crowd we're
going to take off for the day uh it's
been a
conversation it's beautiful to see you
all uh we're going to be heading over
the Border soon here and doing some
events for the first time heading down
to Michigan for the organic cup doing
some private event beforehand going down
to heal
thyself uh in Menino with the humble low
local Joey and Tamara down there um and
uh doing another Hive gathering at um
Hartwood so we're looking forward to
gathering with everyone getting ceremony
and sacred and giving hugs and love and
sharing does and doing you know what
humans do we're really excited for that
and uh thanks Tara Lee she was just here
visiting us we had a really good time
really special times uh being able to
see her again was really special thanks
everyone have a great day thanks for
making the world a better place and and
bringing some magic into your world we
love and appreciate you
thanks dragonfly Earth medicine I think
that's perfect time to close her down
we've been going for three full hours it
was nice to share time with all of you
I'll definitely try to do it again next
week and send out the emails and get
everyone invited and have more of a
wonderful conversation thanks for
popping in last minute Mojave that was
awesome uh Brian and Dr Mark and
skunkman Sam and aten of course Wade
laughter uh Connor the turp wizard who
was here but had to leave as well well
as uh um Colin uh and anyone else that
I'm forgetting you know thanks to all
the people who are watching I think we
had about 2 180 people watching live
today uh there's still 262 of them in
there right now so obviously uh you guys
are a huge part of this I try to engage
in the conversation in the chat room and
I implore the rest of the uh people on
the panel if you can open up the YouTube
channel and you know atan is always in
there there's a nice live chat there's a
lot of good topics and conversations and
the more we engage the Audi audience and
the people that we're talking to uh I
think it just makes it a better full
circle experience so you know as always
even though I was talking about the hash
hits I will end it with May the full
Mount bless your bowl sooner than later
and uh peace out everybody have a great
day marus