preparing the stream okay welcome
everybody look at that we are setting up
our meeting to go live here Sam give us
a second give us a second and then we
will say our piece which is welcome
everybody welcome everybody to hash
Church episode oh geez what is it 21
episode 2.0 21 Johnny B's in the house
already
lighten up a fatty pimp guys in the
house trying to figure out his camera
yeah you can't do it Johnny's muted but
I came in muted wait listen we better
walk mr. Sam through this or he's gonna
talk over us okay we need to see his
little doll so what can we do for you
Sam you need to figure out how to turn
your camera it's usually on the bottom
left where it says mute and stop video
or it might snow yeah it's off now
remember when you turn it on whew we
almost saw you there buddy we saw your
elbow good morning can hear me oh very
well in fact excellent very well in fact
oh man that's it's so different starting
this up in the morning from the Google
Hangouts that I have to admit I felt a
little bit of nervousness this morning
just trying to it's crazy how fast when
I send out that link how fast you guys
are in here so I got to kind of hit the
record button and hey how's it going
Debbie she's gotta figure it out
maybe her mic maybe her video for video
and microphone supposed to get awake I'm
supposed to change the link in YouTube
people wanted to know and Chuck therein
chattering
now I see them all how come I'm just
getting a scream I don't know you
probably only please everyone down
everyone let's help Debbie get her get
her mic microphone work in there
autumns working her this it is now
actually come well we've been trying to
get you on for a while haven't we I made
it are you guys very well doing very
well we got Johnny B and a Chance man
Sam in the house so far as well as you
know and myself put put the link out to
ash whack of people so oh they need the
link to share in the other chat well
what if you're in here
can't you just I'm sorry I'm confused
here you go
yeah I'm looking on YouTube and I'm not
seeing it playing that's because you're
not looking at the right one it doesn't
play out on the one that we that I have
to the one I start that tells everyone
there's gonna be a show tomorrow that
goes through YouTube and I used to just
push a button called Google Chat and I
could go live through there but now soom
doesn't hook up that way when I go live
on zoom it starts a new YouTube box
immediately so I just put that into the
link I put it in an OG brick like that
post there oh maybe I'll go over to the
other one and post it because yeah I'm
in in both right now I probably want to
switch to speak review - it's on
grid-view I like the grid view but I
could spit I could change it we could go
to speaker view how's it I have a
question posted of the exact same
something that's funny like Sam
okay I'm using a microphone I'm gonna
turn it off and see if you still hear me
still hear me we can't yet don't
it's my on and off switch and the
microphone is useless the mic works
great but it doesn't turn on and off
well as long as it turns on that's all
that's important Sam
because we need to hear you yes well you
don't need to hear me anymore because
you could just read everything I know in
my bibliography no oh so what's going on
in the world of cannabis this last week
geez I I saw some funny stuff the other
day I found an account on Instagram and
at first I thought it was going to be
one of these sort of trolling accounts
that just trolls any aspect of legal
corporate cannabis well it was these
guys had a whole bunch of information
about what's the name of this company
the James II Wagner cultivation
corporation and Ravin question the other
one you gotta check out this guy James
JW see you can't even believe the stuff
that he says it's so ridiculous he
forgot the word I guess he doesn't use
the term entourage he uses the he's like
well it's about the cohort effect you
know it's all of our cannabis is 2.5%
terpenes minimum and it's all about the
cohort effect and trying to listen to
this guy talk I was it what the hell is
this guy talking about sort of went in a
little deeper and realized that I mean
we all know this coming from the
industry for as long as we've been here
but there are absolute frauds entering
the industry who are now just going to
sort of you know fake it till they make
it I guess like some of the things that
you hear these these these people say
you're funny Marcus I'm really honest so
when I start my cannabis cup a I'm gonna
call it frog cannabis fraud cannabis
from skunkman Sam won't get you high but
hey know everything I say about it we'll
be alive I like it I think oh I think
you should do that brand I think we'll
we'll release it in California and we'll
see how it goes there and we'll go from
there it'll fit right into the market
here now what's goin on with your market
like seriously is it just the nightmare
now like is it didn't
it's recovering it's recovering you know
we took it like at my shop we lost
almost a fifth of our customers to the
underground market yeah for a whole year
a whole year
but it's starting to come back now you
know because I mean so many of our
friends couldn't get into dispensaries
or get legal licenses so what were we
supposed to say the underground market
stayed alive that's probably the way it
should be you know if make such
restrictive regulations and then our
friends turn to the underground market
to buy their cannabis but I think part
of the bounce-back is you know the
quality is really up raised it's
incredible I can hardly even believe it
myself and of course we've got all this
toxic products on the market now with
these vape pens and that thickener stuff
giving people pneumonia what a nightmare
so we're seeing the bounce-back we've
almost got all of our games back now so
that's good smoke cannabis yeah some of
those cheap vape pens that popcorn lung
and some of the other things you see
going on I mean oh yeah I saw an article
the other day and they were like it's an
epidemic and I'm like like more of an
epidemic than half a million people
being killed from tobacco every year in
the US and like more of an epidemic than
three million people being killed from
alcohol-related deaths like I mean sure
it's probably bad but it's gotta still
be harm reduction to smoking radioactive
tobacco not only that the newest
epidemic in America is the random mass
killers I mean it used to be once a year
now it's once a week or twice a week so
when it's you strong ammonia so yeah I
mean to the point no harm reduction now
that we grow I use that stuff anymore or
well this is why we started testing for
this simple fact we wanted to know what
we couldn't see and once we started
testing we started to find all kind of
unsavory not good things
and that's one reason you may people
were complaining oh you're we costs more
well yeah we have to test fit we have to
pay employees we have to do all these
realities that come with you know
staffing 60 some-odd people to be here
and actually deal with and handle
everyone from patients to retail so
definitely we're seeing it bounce back
from people because they realized that
they are getting safe product because
there is a a plethora of bad products
out there I'm not saying every legal
products out there bad look I used to
support the black market used to be part
of the black market used to purvey some
of the best stuff in the black market so
I hadn't in the black market
okay still they said it was a third it's
probably closer to half now or you know
the numbers are bigger than what they
anticipated originally that's just the
fact of the situation but we need to
test everything correctly CED I don't
want it exactly Sam does not want a CBD
where as so many people want it and on
top of that I'm getting calls I talked
to people weekly who are asking hey
where do I get a safe CBD part what's
the safe sea Beach product I could order
in the middle of Texas and somewhere and
I tell everybody buyer beware
you know caveat emptor that's the
reality I have no idea what's out there
you have no idea if it's tested ask if
it's tested and that's what we tell
people is you know as much as they don't
want to hear it it's safest still in the
dispensaries to purchase because it's
actually safe efficacious as well as
it's been approved as well as it has lot
numbers if there's a problem it can
actually be pulled from shelves etc etc
whereas in the black market same thing
happened before 64 happened oh you don't
want it okay we'll just take this
somewhere else which they do and that
cannabis goes somewhere else all
together and where it goes nobody knows
and nobody knows to ask these questions
about why does this taste funny because
they're just going with the one choice
their dealer has we need legalization in
every state and I'm tired of people in
its where it's not legal yet or going I
got arrested can I get a lawyer still
you know there's still a lot of fight
that we have to do from you know testing
to a state
you know in states where it's not even
considered legal yet you know look at
Kansas look at some of the other places
in middle America where you know people
are wallowing while watching everybody
else get successful or get sick from
this cannabis so they're watching the
full caveat of reality of what we're
experiencing and wondering how can they
bring it to their reality yeah well I'll
tell you me
all right we're Sam being worried about
not getting CBD you know it works even
crazier the other way around because I
know someone who's super sensitive just
to THC does not have an interest in
having it in their body purchased a CBD
product and I guess it ended up being
contaminated like vastly contaminated
with THC that's super cooked it was like
she's a mother she was like she told me
she was about to go to her kids like
play at the school and had to bring all
her other kids and it was not a good
vibe it was kind of like you know like
we need to make make sure that for
people like that that aren't really
cannabis users but they're now using
some of the you know maybe this person
was just using like a pure isolate and
it was working really nicely for them
until they got super stoned and now
they're like paranoid because it's like
they you know they took like an ml or
whatever it was it would be like the
equivalent of us eating like a strong
brownie or something she was she was lit
for a levy you have a poster on your
wall behind you from that hashish in no
it's funny
me and my wife stayed there for two
weeks in the hotel of course you did
yeah I found that poster out on dead
tour one time some guy had made a bunch
of them back in India and found him in a
garage was just sawing him on dead tour
so I think they're like real OG from
back in the day that place was really
ready yeah they had like a dozen
different kinds of cannabis and the
dozen different kinds of hashish and all
I had to do was knock on my floor and
somebody would come up and deliver me
yesterday I was thinking man
legalization is nice I can get all the
best flowers there's good concentrates
but I can't get any traditional hash I
mean that alone is probably worth the
trip to the Netherlands just to try or
you know where maybe the homeland where
it's sourced we were there in 71 72 when
marijuana and hashish was still illegal
it made it illegal a couple years later
in by a guy named Sharma but I don't
remember very well it was quite a while
ago resurrection that's what I say
that's an opportunity right there one
day when worldwide global legalization
hits was that your spots a motel room
that's incredible well there you go
people there's a idea and concept in a
legal area that you have seen in the
past that somebody who's watching is
like what could I do in the world of
cannabis well there you go that you can
go open up a hotel in one of these legal
states and provide it for a nice
comfortable place for people to be I
know there's air B&amp;B ease but I don't
really know of too many hotels at this
particular Junction unless I'm incorrect
you see the top there was only about
four or five six rooms in the hotel
check check out the top of the sign the
eden has she sent her what does it say
right on the top you're old and favorite
joint I think they used a pun there
that's awesome I like to think that Sam
and his wife are in that picture while
it was being taken because that picture
is definitely and that's old freak
Street that what you guys called it or
is that just what this authors called it
Sam it was called freak Street it was
also freak Street in was actually called
chicken Street in Kabul
alright freak Street Katmandu huh but
when you're full of Kabul
there's freak speed for those of you
that wanted to see the rest of freaks
that's so cool
Oh some of your old photo yeah like
Katmandu and some of your old travels
are I mean they're epic they're
literally like you you got to do a book
one day I know you hate to be
photographed and you hate to be in
pictures but do it when you're like gone
and passed because people need to see
those those images I feel blessed to
have been yeah after I die I will
definitely make a book yeah once you're
dead you should make a book did you got
to get on that but once you're dead yep
puffs - I'll puff - Sam being alive and
talking to them I'm testing the karmic
up I don't know so it was number two
everybody's opinion - compared to the
other one was called Google Hangouts in
my opinion is that I like it I like the
option of doing like grid view versus
speaker view I like the fact that first
for whatever reason on this technology
us not having headphones and all and
constantly muting each other causes less
of a problem feel like the audio and the
video is cleaner and I kind of miss
being able to post right through YouTube
the way we originally did it but I
figured out a way to work it so I'm not
I'm pretty stoked on it oh there we go
you called it Sam are you guys [ __ ]
back already about time we rolled we did
we rode 15 hours yesterday from Edmonton
awesome Creek through the [ __ ] pine
pass last night at midnight pitch-black
[ __ ] moose everywhere he was [ __ ]
unreal man I love it man that's amazing
I can't believe you're both sitting in
the room right now cuz I'm like listen
guys are supposed to be an Edmonton like
they can't
just saw you guys out on the road yep we
were we went to slay a nut Slayer so he
was last month Iron Maiden release the
Beast that's a good we've never seen
maiden bull I've never seen made before
and did you know you've never seen Iron
Maiden before that was your first
concert we've gone to [ __ ] every
Slayer concert this come to Canada
pretty much was Iron Maiden in 1984
it wasn't an amazing concert oh yes I'm
for the 88 for the power slave that was
amazing they put on great live shows if
you if you haven't got a chance did the
most amazing Late Show what do you think
Darren was it worth the way hey it was
[ __ ] awesome man and listen to this
you guys okay we're cruisin around there
you know we went to Slayer the weed
policy it Slayer was you guys go ahead
and smoke wherever there's people
drinking you're allowed to [ __ ] smoke
weed too right so we walked in with our
case of doobies and we smoked all day
well Maidan was inside so allowed to
smoke inside but we're allowed our
doobies so we cruise in there and
everything we didn't get caught with
them we're looking for a place to smoke
for more two hours and we're just like
because we because the VIP thing you
gotta go at four o'clock before the
concert starts
well this rigmarole right which is
really cool and fun and you miss lineups
to the merchant stuff but we're sitting
back looking okay well we should want a
joint here man we find a spot we go with
the way to the top of this Rogers place
and we go to the stand so we're gonna go
to the nosebleed section smoke there but
this [ __ ] it's like this steep it's
like it's almost [ __ ] it's scary
standing up there so we're just like
okay well we'll go back to the seats
whatever which will the concerts start
so we're sitting right in front of two
security guards so we can't get away
with this [ __ ] so we go to the top we
find a stairwell well we didn't know the
stairwell was there we were waiting for
the yacht we're going to find the
escalator
and then the guys like note the
escalators not go down you gotta take
the stairs of the elevator
as soon as you said stairs really yes we
go to the stairwell smoke [ __ ] there's
no one in there we smoke two three
[ __ ] joints right away went in sat
down again and then we did it then we
did it again but we're doing it real
sneaky on the other side actually you
get much higher if you sneak it in the
bathroom
that's my bad too
we were gonna do that but we didn't end
up doing it we smoked in the stairwell
and we're smoking we still work up a
joint week we're like Coach we could
hear someone so we're being real quiet
and we can hear me give up looking
around looking we come around the corner
and there's two people doing the same
thing we were doing looking over to
someone that we just started [ __ ]
laughing shared the joints together and
[ __ ] and carrying on the contraband
getting kicked out of potentially
getting kicked out when you're VIP you
got the Good Seats you just you've
traveled ten hours or more on your
motorcycle a super nice hotel it's like
dude don't get us kicked out of here
tonight
that's the added risk in front of it all
as Sam said it gets just a little bit
higher you know I only got kicked out of
one concert and that was because I took
a portable dat digital recorder with me
he just pocket-sized like a larger
walkman but he refused to let me in with
it and I refuse to let somebody watch
over it for me so I left hey Darren I'm
thinking about the concert you go to the
top so you can smoke weed to come down
that staircase where every step is a
different size like one's a foot one's
three foot then two foot it's like
you're holding on to the railing does
that happen to anyone else
like can't they just make standard steps
there so actually the steps were
standard you weren't
hey Sam check this out oh it's a bad
recorder for mark
oh yeah someplace tasty shows from the
early nineties anyone think and coughing
in the background master's bro masters
let me show you what's on my wall
hey Darren just for shits and giggles
real quick my my foxhole in the Gulf was
named 22 acacia Avenue which is a maiden
Sun oh yeah what Sam sure it does demel
development of indication specific
cannabis scheme of Arts to improve
efficacy and safety sorry
Rousseau and Mark Lewis yeah you're
gonna stick to brave that buddy is this
the poster that was in leiden that the
International cannabinoid Research
Society yeah sure that is hilarious dude
how about that study that just came out
about the cannabis flavonoid fights
pancreatic pancreatic cancer which is
absolutely terminal and they finally
found something that helps that cannabis
that's some flavonoid in campus science
everybody raves about flavonoids but if
you smoke them they're deactivated
you can't smoke flavor you gotta eat
them orally into the Z grade can you
suspend them so they won't degrade so
you can ingest them I don't know yeah
absolutely
yes go Candace go Candace go chemist yes
oh yeah they'll do great if you heat
them up the coughing like the the color
that you seen a lot of cannabis extract
has to deal with flavonoids flavonoids
are highly colored and they're very
sensitive to exposure to air and oxygen
so they little dope I think they're
somewhat responsible for that so-called
red ring of death that you often find in
distillate where you'll see the
distillate that's exposed to the air
often turns sort of like this
reddish color I think that there's a
flavonoid chemistry it's involved in
that I don't know that for sure but
they're very highly colored compounds
I'm sorry in the resin head and you know
eaten the whole recipe I don't think
they're orally deactivated I mean
certainly there's a lot of flavonoids in
the human diet I just don't know about
their bioavailability and what
prevalence you get just from like an
oral consumption of cannabis you know
has done some work on this
I think nei Pro has done some work on
this I think they have a bunch of
unreleased information on flavonoids
yeah I mean an interesting question for
Sam as has anyone ever bred cannabis for
flavonoid content yes there are people
we have discovered in about 2000 that
the terpenes had the power to modulate
and potentially cannabinoids I was going
to look at later no it's next and then
dr. Michelle Amanda portrayed a few
others told me if you smoke completely
deactivated potentiate
does that mean raw so you couldn't like
say bake them into a brownie or
something like that
my feeling is if it decarboxylate it
will deactivate it maybe night so as
fresh as possible I think they're
thermally degraded so I think that's the
issue so again maybe this is an option
for you know juicing or things that you
know just carried out at lower
temperatures to isolate the extract so
so long as the extracts not
thermally were subjected to any Heat it
shouldn't degrade the flavonoids now
again I know that they're highly
sensitive to air and they oxidize and
form very highly color compounds and so
certainly just exposure to air or shelf
life could be an issue with slides but I
think what they turn into our actually
degradation products that are also
cancer fighting compounds as well so
they're just sort of like metastable
compounds that yeah do have somewhat of
a half-life but certainly have a lot of
biological activity and flavonoids are
rich in in antioxidant properties and
all kinds of things like that because
they're they're at their phenols and
these things react with ultraviolet
light and air like antioxidants should
twenty years later
99% of the are still there I was I was
contacted this week by a gentleman whose
wife is going through for Stage three
attic cancer and I put him in touch with
that article and he was like well what
do I do
how do I get it now for her and of
course I immediately shrugged because I
don't is is the patient a cannabis user
how's the patient because she is
responding to cannabis I have her on
different ratios of she's trying to
different priority no SACEUR she is in
cannabis a casual user barely once or
twice a year at a concert or something
like that
yeah I mean so this again speaks to that
notion that all cannabis uses is medical
because you know the cannabinoids
especially a CBD analyte basically act
as antioxidants in the body and fight
reactive oxygenated species that end up
leading to mutations that cause cancer
and the great thing about cannabinoids
is they're fat soluble unlike a lot of
the antioxidants
human diet which are water-soluble so
they protect fatty tissues like the
pancreas and the brain and the liver
from oxidative damage might really help
her is to eat resin in other words dry
scepter water shift that has not
degraded at all and is basically still
THC a because she won't get very high
but she'll get a monoi effects
I wanted to welcome wade into the room
and Josh and Kelly as well snuck in
there I didn't I had to like move the
thing over it was it just showed like
five or six of us so welcome to you guys
as well Harris hey good morning I waited
yeah hi guys my video camera is not
working today so I'm just listening in
and I'll pop and occasionally thank you
nice to see you guys we appreciate in
all forms Wade we appreciate you in all
forms as long as we can hear your wisdom
we're good
there's something very soothing about
Wade's voice I think he could narrate
like a lot of good [ __ ] he has a gentle
timbre in his voice that is very
reassuring and calming it just puts me
at ease I'm like kind of at the end of
my seat kind of a guy and when Wade
starts talking I'm a little bit like
alright
that Wade talk just like Wade song Shh
tell the story he's don't have much to
say this morning that's what I was gonna
say but wait he'll he'll speak when he
has something to say and I like that as
well about you son
I'm the other way I'll just say anything
any time exactly I do want to throw out
there
I love the conversation around that
flavonoid and the pancreatic cancer
study and yeah it really brings me back
to cold ethanol extractions and or
things that preserve the acid forms
there's a whole area in these flavonoids
that likely are going to turn out to be
really interesting when we get out of
that thing of feeling like we have to
vaporize or smoke our cannabis in order
to get benefit from it so here's a
question to the panel what do you guys
think about different cannabinoid
profiles being present in the different
types of trichomes and the reason I say
this is I've noticed some difference in
I've noticed that the differentiator
between oil production and hash
production comes from the bulbous head
meaning when I do mechanical screen
separation or water extraction I can
isolate the glandular trichomes head
mostly off the capitate stocked in the
capitate sessile but the bulbous tend to
sit on that single Stipe cell and really
hug the leaf they don't snap off in the
water extraction process quite as easy
and they don't really even break off
when you make them extremely cold with
with screens and what I've noticed is
that cultivars that are high in CBD give
very very little hash from mechanical
screen separation and usually give them
much higher sometimes two times higher
like literally 50% of the yield is in
those bulbous heads and they're just one
resin that you get from CBD has a drier
feel to your hand yeah it's a totally
it's it's definitely different but I
just wonder like if we're ever going to
go deep into what's being produced in
those different types of profiles and is
it when you put the two together that
you get this full profile that's hash
and when you put the three together when
you make oil because I remember from
being the bubble guy and being all into
obsessive about isolating out the heads
into different micron sizes and
realizing that there were actually
different highs and different effects
present in those different sized heads
because I've seen it over and over again
that I started to tell my oil friends
listen like why not make some hash first
so when you make your oil you've got
like some 90 microns oil or some
seventy-three micron oil and the few
that did it were definitely like had the
profound revelation that yeah that's
quite different but I just wonder if
there's going to be a conversation if
we're ever going to get to a point where
we can really decipher you know
isolating those heads separately seeing
what profiles produce in those heads and
just seeing if you guys have noticed
anything you really want different
cannabinoids the best idea is to breed
it with those particular cannabinoids in
faces there it would be a great study to
do in the fact that there's so much more
testing of cannabis down and you know
labs that are you know looking at
different
different aspects of cannabinoid
chemistry it's it's perfectly a valid
study to do you know what's the impact
in terms of the chemical profile on on
screen size and and it would be a easy
study to do easy just mechanically if
you had all the instrumentation at your
access at a place that was growing
multiple cultivars you could generate
lots of data doing that study real quick
it's very a good study to do I think
it's gonna be any need to be studies
plural I think you'd need one on almost
every you know macron that available
currently and then you'd also need to
start to look at some other macron so
you could start to reach those so you
can isolate those even smaller ones
because as you know they're in all
different sizes and every different
genetic considering its growth cycle I
just want to say that I really
appreciate it the way he pronounced
micron macron I totally liked it I dug
it and I'm gonna smoke a bowl to it in
fact right now it's really mad
I wasn't even busted I was straight like
I appreciated it you know I'm just gonna
say is like from a patient perspective
and when I separate and then do all
different mark you've taught me
everything from separation from how to
refine my hash even to my my dryer set
there's stuff like that and I always
talk about the different levels like
even I have that three or four it's
really fine there's a press much but the
resin that comes from it is just by far
more relaxing and I'm always wondering
if those you know has anybody ever
tested the different microbes that say
I've seen different profiles it's not
all the same profile but just in the
cannabinoid levels from what I've seen I
mean I would point to the research of
palm albergue in the late 70s and early
80's from University of Indiana
Bloomington who had a schedule one
license and did a lot of his testing
just on hemp but did do some testing to
basically his publications got like 12
publications in a period of about 10
years on you know the generation
of cannabinoids in the trico and he did
you know these micro pipetting
experiments where he actually went in
underneath the microscope and sucked the
fluid right out of the trico and
analyzed that by GC you know this is
back in like the late 70s and I wouldn't
visited his lab at Bloomington Indiana
at the University and that's also where
Rob Clark went yes he was working under
license so borrowing off the further off
of just even the Mac Ron's then even the
just taking vets migrants taking each
individual each individual one and then
vaporizing it at different temperatures
to to also see the different variables
that come off of each you know the one
that I'm most interested in is the
difference between the capitate sessile
and stalk for yeah what he found is that
there's the the the what I think re
doing this off memory so if I don't get
this right just look up his papers but
there's these cells that are called the
Stipe cells which is kind of like the
transition spells between the stock and
the bulbous head right so it's like
right where that right where the
junction of that gland is that Stipe
cells and I think they identified that
as being the area that's basically
making cannabinoids which are then
excreted into these things called
plastids which are these things that
migrate toward the edge of the membrane
and create the oil on the plant so I
think if I remember correctly and this
is all for memories so don't get me on
this but if you're if you're getting the
plant at the right period of time you're
you're getting it as that cycle is
completed such that the biosynthetic
pathway that's leading to both the
terpenes and that cannabinoid
biosynthesis has kind of like completed
its shuttle of all of these compounds
from those type cells into this what's
called secretory cavity I believe it's
called and there's just a bunch of these
little vessels that basically have the
oil that are like ready to burst or
ready to migrate to the surface of the
membrane to release it you know to the
extracellular world so it's fascinating
stuff he did some incredible work he
really really did Paul Marburg that's ma
h lb ER g i believe his paper in the
hash church forum on facebook graduate
student from korea i think his name was
soon younger but he worked on all those
papers with dr. Mohler i also want to
mention how awesome i think that it was
of course and standard when you know
mark mentions this paper from like
decades ago that your that your reply
Sam is yeah i went to his lab i went to
his lab yeah i was there i just yeah he
was a contemporary they were
contemporaries they were doing this this
work at the same time and the beautiful
thing is again i think he obviously had
to have night of funding and I believe
his material did come from El Sol is
operation down in University of
Mississippi Carl Hill
hilly working for him but did some of
the first taxonomy papers using you know
DNA materials and he was growing seeds
I sent him legally from to dr. Mel
Burke's lab because dr. Mallard had a
DEA importation license yeah if you look
at the way that cannabis has evolved the
they can't cannabis has evolved to
produce terpenes terpenoids
and cannabinoids throughout its
lifecycle but it expresses the terpenes
at different points terpenes terpenoids
and cannabinoids at different part
it's life cycle and throughout its plant
so when you look at you even that you
know vegetative vegetating plants
they're gonna contain primarily the
sisal stock tert trichomes which are the
hairs without the bulbous right try
crumbs at the head
those sisal stalks contain primarily
monoterpenes that are that scientists
are kind of believing are exhibiting a
anti insecticidal and anti fungal
bacterial role but in order to actually
synthesize the precursors into the
cannabinoids because those cannabinoids
exhibit a anti bacterial fungal like and
microbial properties they have to be
produced in specialized cells the
glandular trichomes
so what you'll actually see is that in
vegetative stop and primarily sisal
stock you're gonna have those bond of
mono and die turbo noise whereas when
you start getting into the bulbous stock
and the glandular trichomes on the sisal
stock or yeah bulbous bulbous Hagen try
crumbs and sisal stock glandular
trichomes those are going to be the ones
that are actually exit ating that the
two precursors in the that are then
synthesized into the cannabinoids now we
know that there there has been some
studies produced recently that I are
showing tricyclic terpenoids even being
produced in the roots and one of the
more things I found it found learned
more recently is a lot of the precursor
terpenoids are translocated through
symbiotic relationships in the roots in
the in the root zones through symbiotic
relationships with micro by microbiome
in the soil that means the soil
microbiology that the fungi which are
which are bringing nutrients to the
roots and then the bacteria are our both
trading terpenes in exchange for sugar
from the blue from the roots because
obviously fungi don't produce sugars
sugars are produced by photosynthesis so
the plant will actually exude a - sugar
into the root zone in exchange for
minerals as well as
nutrients that are traded symbiotically
between bacteria and the cannabis roots
so as the cannabis absorbs those
minerals and transfers them up the stems
some of those trichomes are going to get
exited into the sisal stock the non
Colangelo trichomes
but it isn't until the dry trichomes
a exude the THC a synthase or CBD a
synthase in the glandular trichomes that
you actually get that conversion from
the precursor mono terpenoids into the
dye or tri trip annoyed cannabinoids and
to Tim I just want to drop the mic for
Mike because that was really really well
put and I loved listening to that and it
really was a beautiful scientific
explanation of why a cannabis planet
seems to for a fact express itself so
much more abundantly when it's got that
living soil that it's growing out of
when it's got that entire living you
know bacteria fungus all of those things
working together to like you say trade
terpenes in exchange for sugars I just
that was a really beautiful picture you
painted there man I appreciated that and
I also got what go ahead at ten
you succinctly broke it down you know
very eloquently actually because people
wonder the difference and always as well
what's the difference between soil in
hydroponics well right there alone is an
understanding on why the uptake and what
you're looking at scientifically at the
end so someone should write down at 42
minutes Mike West came in and started to
drop drop the knowledge I appreciate you
Mike I also search everybody thanks for
coming
using a lot of hash water on our plants
that are about three to four weeks into
flour right now and trading that terpene
rich water and those waxes and those
water-soluble terms and ends
that come off of the the trichome and go
into the water and then we spin it with
like a what do you call the plaster like
on a drill like you and we use that in
the water just to agitate just the water
and then we gravity feed it into our
greenhouses and I know that that goes
into the soil food web and I know I
trust that the microbiology knows what
to do that the plant knows what to do it
can take those that brought the raw
material from the plant before and
synthesize those compounds water it
don't want them it wants sugar that it
can trade from the dirt beet well it
hears them it's my personality I mean
here's the thing we can the plants gonna
produce sugar and exudate that sugar
into the soil
but humans culturing cannabis can
actually contribute to that soil
microbiome there's things you know fresh
grant plant juices or fermented plant
juices right now is actually a wonderful
time for everybody who's watching past
church if they have fruit fruits or
berries in their local environments they
can actually press those plant juices we
may not have time to ferment them but
obviously pressing a flank plant juice
incorporating that into your compost tea
or into your watering schedule for
example if you add blueberry choose to a
compost tea that's brewing today and
water it into your plants tomorrow that
may add some of those blueberry
blueberry terpenes to the soil that the
soil microbiome is going to absorb
potentially translocate the micro
bacteria will likely use the sugar you
know it'll consume it and turn it into
cita - before it even gets into the
plant that those terpene terpenes in
soil I don't think they have much of a
half-life if the bacteria is right you
know that bacteria will consume those
terpenes you're just feeding the
bacteria in the soil by putting that
organic matter in there now locating
terpenes into the plant plant doesn't
have any problem making terpenes it
makes the
yeah you don't need to move terpenes and
it's not not that you're taking terpenes
from the plan the staking is straight
into the root and getting turkeys out of
it that's not last not what we're
implying what we're implying is the
train speeding the soil web the
intelligence of the microbiome and the
micro flora with soil knows what to do
it exchanges the information with the
plant and then the plant says oh I have
nutrients and and you know hormones to
work with and that's where you just
trust in you know evolution and and I
just wanted to add really quickly to
what Mike was saying you know we've been
doing fruit ferments you know for 20
years plus because it's always the right
time and when the apples are right or
the plums are ripe on our property that
that's when we'll start to do ferments
and I just want to tell people at home
that it's really important that when
you're working with fruit and fruit
juices it can turn to alcohol incredibly
quickly especially with your fall
through because you've got a lot of wild
yeasts on the outer coating of that
fruit so it will change very quickly so
we always tell people that if you're
going to be doing any type of fruit
ferment that it's really just for a
couple of days and make sure that you're
testing it and really looking at it so
it just turns to alcohol super quickly
and that will definitely kill a lot of
the microbiology in your soil
st. Bernard's observation booth who is
seems to be a smart fellow in the chat
room is agreeing with mark he's saying
it's the microbial metabolites that the
plant up takes is what will increase
terpenes but who knows maybe we'll learn
something new about cannabis with the
way it operates and works I don't
pretend to think that we know everything
I'm sure that we think we do but there's
always breakthroughs every 10 years
seemingly there's some sort of a new
breakthrough where we understand a new I
don't want to put words in Marc's mouth
but what I think he was saying with it
if you put terpenes in the soil and
they're up taken by the roots that's not
going to make more terpenes in the resin
no but by feeding fight by providing the
precursors which are oftentimes degra
debts of what you feed to the roots and
by up by providing more of those
nutrients that can be absorbed yet be
symbiotically traded for sugar with the
roots you're essentially increasing the
fertility of the soil which then
increases the bioavailability rates to
the roots I I think all you're doing is
you're feeding the nitrogen fixating
bacteria that the plant relies on
because plant doesn't fix nitrogen right
and so the bacteria and the my chrome
and the biome and the soil is sort of
symbiotic with plant and so in order to
get soluble nitrogen to make the DNA and
the protein and the enzymes that
actually do the all those eith is it's
you know the the synthesis those are all
proteins and those proteins on the
nitrogen and needs to be soluble
nitrogen and so I think it's just yeah I
mean like you guys have already talked
about many times feeding the soil and
the symbiotic relationship that the soil
has with the plant has a lot I don't
know if you remember mark but in the
sixties people used to hang their plants
upside down when they dried them because
they thought all of the roots and drip
down into the flowers that was still
believed into the 90s for people there
Sam the rich don't produce THC they
produce tricyclic terpenes and bicycling
turkeys I I was just at a Amish tobacco
farm last week and there's some truth to
that in tobacco drying apparently is
that yeah they do hang the leaves upside
down and you start to actually see a
collection of oil kind of as the plant
dries and she dribbles up of tobacco oil
I guess or exude eight or whatever the
hell it is toxic [ __ ] and boy I tell you
what I've never been to its back
before it is intoxicating when you walk
up to one of those drying barns such as
chuck filled with tobacco
bread tobacco if you grow the medicinal
Indian varieties that they used to smoke
before white men came let me tell you
something if you even touch the plant
it's there's so much resin onto those
tobacco yes have no conception you know
a neurology in herbology whenever you're
drying or you're working with herbal
herbal remedies you're always drawing it
upside down because of those oils and
and and then at the very end of the
plant is where you know a lot of the
medicinal values are that particular
plant which is where it's gonna dry out
slower it's gonna have a slower dry
which makes you know a lot of herbal
plants you know more medicinal and
harvesting them at dawn you know is the
the most medicinal time to harvest your
herbs with the highest terpene content
and also I was just wanting to talk
about a little bit about the living soil
I think that people who are cultivating
in deep living soil you know we we are
preparing and and creating cannabinoids
that we don't even know about yet of
course there's an incredible
relationship that goes on within the
rhizosphere that's giving the medicinal
values within the trichomes of the plant
and when you have a beautiful soil than
you're giving ultimate potential to that
particular varietal or that particular
chemo VAR so I think that putting in its
most natural environment with the best
food possible for the proper
microbiology then you're definitely
gonna get the ultimate potential that
can out of that strain and you know it's
really hard to tell but we were showing
some of these hemp varietals that were
growing this year and they're just
unbelievably filled with trichomes
and we're really excited to see what's
gonna happen this year with the testing
and me I mean the trichomes are going
all the way out to the leaves and
like a cartoon filter from like an app
to anyone else because it looks super
tricky when you've only got up you can
tell it's frosty but it's it looks like
a like a trippy filter to me yeah right
now you know in the way that we're
breeding our hemp and the way we've been
hopping of CBD values and a lot of the
breeding here we can't actually tell the
difference at all now after working with
it for so long between our THC varietals
you know our hemp varietals and our high
CBD varietals are starting to create way
more you know smells the terpenes coming
out of the greenhouses are just really
phenomenal I branched between drug
varieties and we have both on the
property we have temporize that we've
collected from Colorado and Oregon that
are open to breed and we've been
breeding with those you analyze
varieties they have a whole different
suite of terpenes yeah we've just been
doing quite a bit of testing and we're
really noticing full-spectrum terpenes
really a whole bunch of them are present
whatever anon dia labs is is testing for
you know all of them but a couple are
not present so you know they're all
there which is really exciting so and
we're really being able to tell that so
we're mixing the drug cultivar cultivars
as well as CBD with CBD and I think
think that we're having a lot of success
in both of them but incredible yields
and the trichomes are just huge this
year I mean we have everything from
spectrum number five box Auto cherry
wines
we have Ringo's gift Carl azuz Ringo
Harless Aziz EC AB a kiss our healer
strain which is a one-to-one ACDC to
drug to 840 which is ours
a temple spice which is a THC variety
that got a lot of CBD in it recently in
the last couple years yeah we're
definitely noticing that a lot of our
high THC varietals as we're working with
them is is starting to show more full
spectrum cannabinoids our CBD production
is absolutely going up even in cultivars
that weren't showing CBD before are
showing CBD and I believe that this is
part of you know living soil and the
relationship within that rhizosphere
that brings out the ultimate potential
that I was talking about these I'd like
to give you skunk number one to grow
because when it has a non-functional CBD
synthase
interesting interesting yeah purpose
right yeah I mean you know it's what I
love about the cannabis plant it's like
fractal medicine you know it just sits
it comes out whatever you know it's it
doesn't have we're only able to test for
36 right now and we're showing pretty
much about 34 being present in a lot of
our varietals yeah yeah you know it's
just we don't have access to that type
of testing and you know the more that
we're learning and more scientific
knowledge and and and money is being
dumped into cannabis and people who are
home growers even and people that are
really trying to up their breeding
program will have more access to be able
to get better I need any grower would
want you know the best test that they
could get and isn't it not an issue that
all labs test a little bit differently I
mean can we speak to that like how do we
get all labs to create similar data yeah
the issue with lab variation comes from
because when you look at the way that
labs run their run their equipment a
they have to perform an extraction on
their equipment to make it into a
soluble form that they send to the
machine not all extractions are done the
same way secondarily the way that they
run their analytical equipment is not
using the same standardized formula and
then obviously there are standardized
samples that you can get from cerulean
or standards but not every lab you know
quantifies those standards this same way
so you know if you run a GC or HPLC on a
method that takes five minutes to run or
ten minutes to run or an hour to run
you're gonna have much better resolution
on the longer runs but it obviously has
a larger cost to run it for an hour
versus any lab that's testing
once the five minute and that's what we
see in the recreational market says you
know they're gonna try and run as short
of a lab as possible to get as not there
to get as accurate as possible but still
be within a new acceptable margin of
error and and then as long as possible
yes the consumers aren't complaining
they're not gonna not gonna read fast I
calibrated my machine they would show
around the six-minute mark littell the
eight minute work all the different
cannabinoids over that period and the
same thing at the GC that Paul used to
run to then they're also supposed to
calibrate that machine after each test
as well okay so that you actually you're
supposed to at least when I was
originally doing it and actually working
on the testing here in the US but prior
to everything I always showed a
calibrated machine before the test was
even done okay so this is how many how
many standards fifteen hundred
well you cuz you know when you do your
calibration curve right if you if you
run it once with one standard serial
dilution of a standardized sample you
know that's going to give you a good
standard but if you run it at a you know
six different dilutions yeah you don't
need to run that between every standard
you need to basically ISO certified labs
that do this in the non cannabis
industries basically have to do that
calibration maybe quarterly or maybe
three times a year
I'm just saying again if you're using if
you're using a standardized method where
you're talking about measuring
cannabinoid concentration yeah you're
gonna be probably looking at anywhere
between 20 to 30 minutes per test
and you have to do it in a way that you
know again just as reproducible from lab
to lab to lab to lab and you know
there's a lot of sort of hyping numbers
in the testing industry to make sellable
flowers and new markets because you know
it seems as though I can't imagine
cannabis flower being greater than 30%
in THC but I see it Margaret I'm mark
I'm from from labs that are basically
certified or running you know equipment
these are the labs they that sell
product in places like yours they attend
so I mean the point is is that yeah
do we need standardized testing methods
absolutely
but part of what hinders that is the
whole schedule one thing because some of
these companies are even still scared
that cell you know the equipment that's
required but the companies that are have
sold you know like shimasu and other
companies that are basically customized
their equipment to do cannabinoid
analysis you can basically get an HPLC
for well on the order of about 50,000
dollars u.s. that can basically measure
cannabinoid concentration to the degree
that the industry needs to buy a
standardized method I believe even their
analyzer has internal standards already
built into the machine don't quote me on
that but I think you have to still get
the standards you know every quarter and
just do a calibration curve
same thing with terpenes you're running
through GCMs yeah you do it once and
then yeah and then your DMS is also
going to give you a way of determining
whether there's trace other things like
solvents or other you know because the
the GCMs is a lot more sensitive and it
could basically sniff cocaine off of a
dollar bill that's in anyone's pocket so
it's a very very sensitive technique for
you know basically determining trace
amounts of contaminants that could
there but again now you're talking about
a piece of instrumentation that runs you
know north of about $150,000 and you
really need to have a trained you know
chemist or scientist to basically
operate this because it's not a trivial
piece of instrumentation all right to
clarify gentlemen to clarify what I was
talking about with the testing
in-between is when we're come up with
the actual standardization I'm not
saying what was there and to clarify
further I was gonna say it's falling now
more on human error and depending on
who's working in the lab currently now
more so than anything which is because
we've seen also an exponential it was
one thing when I was working one-on-one
with a lab now you're talking about
3,000 samples coming in and they're
being absolutely run and then trying to
find you know qualified people to do
anything from pipetting to you know
getting everything up and running it
happens to be the biggest problem
because I'm having people too
complaining and saying they're failing
because the calibration or the cleaning
machineries are off gassing is actually
on the actual test well you bring up a
good point and a lot of the error that's
introduced into these measurements is
the actual sample handling itself were
not only it runs the risk of having
contamination but there's just so many
places where error can can happen not
just the the mixing up of samples if
you're running hundreds of samples a day
in these labs but just the notion that
again there's a systemic error in the
SOP itself where you're constantly
getting either a higher or lower result
because of the way the sample is weighed
the way the sample is prepared as Mike
was saying you know cannabis is
insoluble so if you're sending in flour
it has to be dissolved so if you're
doing a weight determination for how
much percent of teeth seized in a sample
that's a weight determination so you
have the way material means you have to
have somebody who's competent that's
able to use a an analytical balance and
weigh down to the you know 0.1
milligrams I mean that's just anyone
and a proper representative sample as
well how do you get a proper
representative sample just imir gives
you a little bud for testing but well
yeah I mean it it's funny I mean just by
analogy we're kind of going through this
in Pennsylvania now with hem and so what
the state requires is a sample of the
have to basically certify it's below
point three percent THC and they don't
care and there's nothing in the
regulation that says when or where you
take that sample from so here we are you
know probably like a you know month will
forget a part of it you know and we're
we're basically just clipping leaves off
the plant and saying okay state here's
here's here's your here's your test
result you know you bring up a really
good point which is the sampling and how
do you how do you use a certificate of
analysis a laboratory result regardless
of how precise that result can be how do
you use that result to characterize a
bulk sample of cannabis or ham or
whatever and so I'll point to the the
Oregon folks seem to really think this
thing out pretty well I think the Oregon
Rea is the one that I've read bred the
California one I've looked at a couple
of the other ones in other states seems
like the Oregon folks gives us a lot of
good thought on how to basically
statistically represent a large bulk
sample of medical cannabis how many
samples individual samples and how it
like if you're looking at like a
five-gallon pail or a bin or whatever
you're storing your cannabis they
actually talked about dividing it up in
sectors and taking a sample from each
sector and going lower in the barrel and
you know I don't know who's got the time
to stack their barrels with you know PI
testing cannabis on the top low on the
bottom I've heard people who spray the
tops of their barrels or whatever with
with distillate so when the testing labs
come in they could try to get
a higher test result because boy that'll
make it through the the marketplace
quicker because it tests higher for some
reason again the consumer who walks into
the regulated market who feels that
again I'm in a dispensary so I'm already
paying top dollar I'm gonna make a
choice based on THC content when I make
my purchase so the test results have a
lot to do with what moves off the
shelves and so yeah I mean there's a lot
of moving parts here but to go back to
the original question and I'll shut up
which is that we do need a standard set
of tests but I would say that again if
you got either the schemata to cannabis
analyzer or any current form of HPLC
that's going to require again
calibration as long as you stick to the
SOPs for cannabinoid separations there's
really good analytical methods to give
you baseline separation of all the major
cannabinoids and so with that type of
you know testing available I'm sure that
this will be something that won't be
something that will be unknown in the
future people will be able to have
access to these results there will be
testing there's companies that take
out-of-state samples now that's a new
thing because with the hemp industry
opening up it was difficult say if you
weren't in California where SC labs is
how do you get a sample tested at SC
labs now there is mechanisms to send
state or samples across state lines so
it's becoming a hell a lot better I tell
you what it really is look at you know
how we can how we can set the example
what hat I guess CBD extractors or hash
extractors can look for I know that when
when I've built my labs and there's
especially the labs in Oregon for CBD
you know we were sourcing biomass from
various farms in and around our region
trying to minimize the distance from the
farms that we had
but we would always obviously the
farmers had to test it before it could
be sold to the processors to certify
that it was under 0.3 the minute we
started processing it we in Oregon for
example Oregon passed a rule in their
administrative rules committee that
allowed for the product to be sold after
tests below 0.3 percent THC so when the
processor processes that it may go above
0.3 percent THC as long as you have a
CoA independent third-party analytical
test result that certifies it below
point 3 percent THC that's with that CoA
you can then sell the lot that's yeah
yeah that's right and and you know
here's the interesting scenario now that
there's interstate commerce thanks to
the farm bill you know when those
tractor trailers or you know rent our
train cars get pulled over how do they
know they're based upon some piece of
paper but boy that stuff still smells
like cannabis back there and you're
looking at a huge tractor-trailer that's
just full of em you know pull over on
the road side of i-95 in between
Philadelphia and New York City it's just
going to be really interesting to see
about the transport and and how how this
is kept distinguished from babies gonna
figure out how to get it stacks out of
it know for sure oh yeah you know about
that have to be it's gonna have to be
detained it's gonna have to be tested
and it's gonna have to find a lab to
actually test it so you know it's the
reality is this time is gonna have to
happen and it's gonna be a long slow
process and somebody is gonna be the
test case and it's gonna be a very
expensive and a very sleepless night
situation for those people but it's
already ongoing there's been truck loads
seized in Oklahoma there's been truck
loads seized in southern Idaho no but
it's gonna have to be in between in each
individual state until that we have an
actual federal law right because as you
know something passing through Oklahoma
or Kansas is going to be different
compared to like Texas
watching sometimes I will watch live PD
and watch these cops now struggle
because it's a CBD pen we have to
actually feel tests that well you and I
know also those field tests would fail
you know saliva even you know there's
just terrible tests and you know you're
watching actual officers right now
struggling with that because Texas has
law that allows for tea CBD but no THC
whatsoever so you can still go to jail
and watch this girl get arrested for
actually having THC in her pen so she
was actually arrested and thrown in pen
where the cops are just like hmm you
know so it's still a conundrum even in
these states depending on the access of
the legal as well as in Texas is medical
medical CBD they don't even they don't
even allow CBD for hemp oh no cat no gas
stations to read either because there's
gas station CBD everywhere everywhere
else
ice ACM came out with a study that 14
percent of Americans are using a CBD
product yeah and it's that's critical I
mean that's it's the healing of the
nation's right it's yeah if anything
it's gonna open up the doors I mean I I
was surprised when I saw CBD in Kansas
but Kansas has a state program allowing
CBD and with within a month of Kansas
allowing a commercial CBD there was CBD
being sold in gas station and we're are
you familiar with the paper by Mark
Lewis from April I think it's called
development validation of a robust is
that the DeeZee paper isn't easy after
and yeah yeah yeah Ryan's tell me that
right we talked at a time area semi that
no that that's that's expensive superb
method and also Justin fish addict I
don't
we're Justin as Justin's at one of the
testing labs Justin's across the street
from me over here at IAS the original
lab I've worked with Justin published a
great paper on correlations between
different varieties and terpene profiles
he's coached a couple with Jeff raver
yeah I mean there's a few few good
methods that are out there in Sacramento
and it's the best map I ever saw working
with canvas yeah
dr. Brennan Eisen dr. L Saleh's I've
been yeah I mean the way that these G
CMS's works you used to use GC fi DFID
is just that the acronym for flame
ionization detector and so the way GC
works is it separates mixtures of
compounds based on their different
boiling points and different you know
temperatures at which they boil and so
the most volatile ones kind of come
through the column first then higher
boiling ones come through the column
later and and and and what the FI D was
was just a sniffer at the end of the
column that just smelled a compound
coming out and would burn it and the
intensity of the flame was correlated to
the peak height because the more intense
the flame was the more compound was
coming out so the higher the peak would
be so mass spec what you're doing is
you're putting that column now into a
mass spectrometer which fragments the
molecule and creates what's called a
mass spectrum so it's it's how the
molecule shatters when when it breaks
and so each molecule has a different
pattern each per beam each cannabinoid
the way that they shatter creates a
different mass spectrum and so those are
included in a library of compounds
that's maintained by ni St the National
Institutes for Standards and [ __ ] like
that and so these libraries are all
inside the software of this in
and so when they're looking at all these
compounds coming out they're able to
identify down to a gnats eyebrow
everything that's in the you know these
mixtures and this is just routine
analytical chemistry that just has have
been happening in the food and non
cannabis industries for it for years in
the chemical industry pharmaceutical
industry so it's great that you know
these instruments have now been applied
to looking at these terpene profiles and
so the point is Sam is that the paper
that you're recommending was actually
carried out I think by fi D right I
think that was a G C F ID method but you
could easily they they had mass spec
yeah so much so you can easily yeah so
you can easily apply that method which
just uses flame ionization detector mass
spec detection it's just a different
kind of detector you know the detector
glasses once you run a set of analytical
samples now you've got oh yeah yeah
absolutely like that yeah that's I mean
fact with the hydrogenated cannabinoids
that's how we knew we had something new
there is nothing in the library there
was like oh my god there's nothing in
the library well there's something in
the library now now that we've made it
you know but it becomes yeah a great
detective identification tool to
identify whatever is in a mixture or an
extract or formulated product and you
don't need analytical standards anymore
well it's not it's not like you don't
need analytical standards so the
analytical standards what those are used
and this is what Mike was talking about
earlier is to develop yeah develop a
calibration curve so you want to
understand so when you get one of these
chromatograms you get a bunch of Peaks
right which looks like a mountain range
and what you want to be able to do
is correlate the peak area underneath
the peak to the concentration of the
compound that gives rise to that peak
and the way you do that is you you run
that test on that pure analytical sample
at different concentrations and you plot
on one axis the concentration and you
plot the absorbance on the other and you
generate a line which is in optical
spectroscopy is referred to as beers law
so beers law is the law that you know
the the darker a solution is the more
there is of the analyte in the solution
absorbance is directly proportional to
the concentration of whatever you're
measuring and so those at those those
calibration curves it's very important
and again this speaks to how we get
consistent methods throughout the
cannabis industry is that the labs who
are doing the testing who are doing
routine testing and testing hundreds of
samples a week have to stop once a
quarter and basically show that their
calibration curves are giving a linear
relationship between the different
concentration of the samples and what
they're reading from the machine and
sometimes what you'll see is that as the
column begins to fail or if they have
problems with their peristaltic pump
which pumps the fluid through the column
as it runs you start to get variations
either at high or low concentrations and
deviations from linearity along that
curve and so it's important to be able
to show yeah you could run hundreds of
samples hundreds of samples but you have
to be able to maintain that linear
calibration curve and when you don't
alarm bells should go off and I think
there's even programs that as the
machine runs lets the user know that hey
hey we're starting to get something
that's deviating here you start to see
what's called a floating baseline where
the the baseline and the chromatogram
starts increasing and that just means
that more shits going in this case with
HPLC you're doing a detection by
ultraviolet visible light so you're
taking the ultraviolet visible light as
the fluid comes off of the column and
the different cannabinoids have
different ultraviolet spectrum so you're
able to determine which cannabinoid is
which and also by running standards the
other thing that standards provide is
that if you have an unknown peak and you
don't know what it is
you could Speight that sample say is
that thing THC well you could spike it
with Delta 9 THC and see if that peak
grows if that peak grows then you know
that you've you know identified the peak
but these from chromatography you know
methods or devices are very useful for
analyzing first testing lab there's
there's been testing on cannabis dating
dating back decades but obviously the
first available yeah yeah so but only
came under the time gentleman lays the
same time
go ahead very good no I was saying that
I built it only for in-house use or
because we were plant breeders cannabis
breeders and we used it we kept it for
we 50 to 100 samples a day yeah no I
meant and that's what that's what I
think a lot of because with because none
of the states started licensing cannabis
no no no commercial labs opened up tin
until after we started seeing medical
states opening up and off having having
that need so I think has progresses
worldwide we'll start to see more more
standards more validation on those thing
labs actually being held responsible to
validate their lab standard monthly or
quarterly and then that deviation from
those standards then we obviously labs
want to be able to earn heed to be able
to you know shut down and either replace
their column replace their pumps etc
make sure that they can fall within
those state mandated standards we
started in O eight and O nine with
testing here in California and so we we
didn't have any access to lab or in
formation we tried to reach out to the
Research Triangle that's a University of
Mississippi and they laughed at us so we
that was in like oh seven so no eight we
started to reach out to Ethan Rousseau
and some of the other people and trying
to find the right people to actually
find to bring to the United States
actually have the actual calibration
liquid and equipment so I didn't know
you back then Sam because I wish I would
have known you because it would have
made it a lot easier but in the aspect
and dr. Holloway they both helped me you
know they weren't so happy to help us we
would send the exact same sample to all
three of us and we didn't come out with
the same result was wrong but we did
exact same result
I longed in dream that you people
existed and apparently you did exist
it's just we didn't touch base back then
they also welcomed the dream catcher
we've been talking about labs for a bit
now I apologize I'm just making a
tracking out again and I appreciate that
that's awesome now we've been going deep
man testing with the Green Cross stay
with dr. Horne be back and it was oh six
just after my accident that's when I got
hurt and learned about decarboxylase and
how those brownies affected my pain
controller that's when I kind of really
found out about analytical testing and
started seeing all those all that great
wonders of cannabis at the beginning
there that was you know 607 then that
was uh was some exciting times without
labs with you as a breeder you don't
know what you're doing just guessing I
think it's really awesome we have the
ability to test the flour and we have
the ability to test the soil and and in
the cannabis industry really getting
good at both of those already together
and the thing that I'm really interested
in is the actual reaction from the soil
into the flour which is really test the
end acidic reaction that's going on
within the plant and I don't know if any
of you all know of any labs or anybody
who is testing and the fights within the
plant that really is super exciting like
for example tack salt from the yew tree
was people were getting bark wanting to
extract tax all to cure cancer but after
further testing years later they
realized there there was endo Finnick
fungi and endo Finnick bacteria that was
pulsing in the cambium between the birch
I mean authority you bark and the tree
and the handle fights were extremely
medicinal towards cancer and other
things so we started looking up
endophytes in cannabis and there's
minimal papers on it and the one where I
found located that there was you know up
to 30 and endo critic fungi in cannabis
some of the endo fights were good fight
powdery mildew and botrytis other
endophytes were impossible to fight
cancer area and and we're not talking to
endo mycorrhizal fungi and we're not
talking about that we're talking about
endo FIDIC fungi and bacteria that live
inside plant tissue and i feel like it
may be a whole new medicinal frontier
and i'm wondering if any of you all have
learned about that
and also under I just wanted to kind of
jump in on that that's I think that's
one of my most like passionate and
exciting kind of directions where I see
things are going you know in so many
ways your candidates now especially you
know kind of what we're seeing in
California with as much testing is being
required you know we're seeing so many
of the
you
did somebody freeze up on us
no it's Mike went dead for some reason
now he froze frozen so you know we'll
just build on that we can add
information make our hemp oil we as we
harvest the hemp we harvest the ribs
thanks to Ethan Rousseau and some of
those papers that have been written on
the roots and we also use parts of the
stock and seeds in our medicine because
we when you talk about whole plants like
Marcus's shirt you know or whole plant
medicine you know you were looking for
the full range so and it's really
awesome because you found papers you
know that back to the 50s that look at
him and they're finding up to 30
different varietals of Enda fitted fungi
within the cannabis plant and say like a
tomato or some of our other food plants
or maybe tobacco or corn you're really
only gonna have a couple different
varietals it's it's super interesting
that cannabis has so many and we know
that that's definitely playing in with
cannabinoid and and terpene production
so alyx not alex now there's not enough
to hear you thank you thank you no thank
you for your patience there i'm yeah i
just don't make it to Wi-Fi so I'm
golden um so so yeah one dumb what I was
kind of just wanting to kind of share
with share with everybody here kind of
be in response to the endo endo philic
is alright and acidic yeah yeah
cool so yeah so anyway so the way I was
going on that thought is like you know
in so many ways you know Saints a
cannabis testing you know we've been
doing deep in this is our tenth year is
their decade of doing it you know can we
started towards the end of 2009 and and
so being on this journey of analytical
chemistry with cannabis and the science
of cannabis has been you know one most
educational magical experiences in my
life and and in so many ways especially
said you know over the last few years
seeing a transition to this new space it
regulated contested you know these
minimum quality standards that people
have to meet to kind of you know get
product that we market you know in so
many ways now on you know you know we're
seeing the most fascinating trends
around all the fails right and so so my
job in such a big ways
compliance fail happens and some BS to
destroy product during mediate the
product that pretty much means they're
never gonna work with us again because
there's a fifty hundred thousand dollar
plus loss of a cure and so so what we
found really early on last year when
testing kicked in is you know the buck
doesn't stop there if you if you as a
lab or just delivering a fee-for-service
tests and the certificate analysis and
then bad news you know you know with
someone having to destroy a hundred
thousand dollars product and you know
sure that never probably gonna work with
you again but what else do you bring to
the table and so that's really where
we've drawn on our past decade worth of
experience of being in service to this
plant and knowing this plan as well as
we do both like you know on the you know
kind of cultivation manufacturing level
but also then on testing and so so one
of the things and this is I guess the
big point of what I was trying to make
it so cannabis this you know this great
bioaccumulate implant you know now that
we've tested it but to higher standards
than any other crop that's ever been
tested you know we're we're you know the
testing is almost like it's showing this
voice of the plant that's speaking about
the legacy of the toxicity and the
contamination that's happened in all
these major agricultural areas you know
that are you know and so in so many of
these areas where the microbiome has
been desertified you know and and now
it's just eroded you know soil that just
kind of gives super height or just like
a super low pH you know super root and
high levels of heavy metals and residual
pesticides from the environment from the
neighboring farms there yeah it's dirt
exactly it's no longer soil and and so
so so in so many ways like we're seeing
this in California we're seeing this
massive movement towards kind of the
this establishment of appellations of
origin and protected terms you know and
and I love this conversation I'm
actually gonna be speaking at a
Appalachian conference look at some pose
in at UC Berkeley in the next couple
months on but but basically you know
what we're seeing is you know
Appalachian is something in this new
world that you have to wear whether or
not you like it or not and and you know
in certain areas you know the
Appalachian that you're going is almost
going to be seen as like a Scarlet
Letter you know because I begin to
basically by the like five or six
different pesticides that will show up
either in flower or plant material or
annex
you know I've begun from the from the
routine I've had over a thousand of
these fail calls over the last year but
now I can begin to predict the
appellation it was grown in by the
pesticide signature that accompanies the
prop and that's one of those
mind-blowing things I've ever seen
because I can predict if it's grown by
the almonds in Stanislaus or by the
avocados in Carpinteria because this
appellation signatures following the
plant and so that's the worst case I
think of the appellation conversation of
where I'm seeing it go but on the other
side unlike with you know with you know
pale laning gum and soil food web and
all the like pioneering work of all the
you know cannabis legends that have been
trying to push the boundaries on organic
farming to regenerative farming to like
understanding the symbiosis that exists
in nature and how you know to really
talk terroir and appellations of origin
you know you're it's it's the
microclimate region of the area but it's
the soil microbiome that exists and I
think well and and and and real quick
just about the point and so so with with
that being said you know we're you know
I've been to several landing them
accomplish two workshops I we were
starting to do some of these trials but
you know they're showing whenever the
soil microbiomes ideal you know for the
crop being grown comparatively to say
hydroponically grown the tomatoes or
other types of fruits you know you can
track the doubling of a secondary
metabolites being produced in the plant
whenever the microbiomes ideal and they
probably has something to do these
endophyte or the certain types of fungi
but whenever you know those so if you
can so if something's going the perfect
microbiome in one of these real clean
areas that aren't they haven't been
bombed on for 40 50 years by AG you know
where their soil is actually rich and
flourishing then you know you can
actually be good we're starting to begin
to track the secondary metabolite
production being released in cannabis
which are tokine's in this case and
other you know minor compounds that
we're not even testing yet but i but in
so many ways i'm seeing that as one of
the biggest competitive advantages that
a cannabis farmer has in this new world
because if you were able to produce
quality fiber quality cannabis that has
you know these big mark Lee expressed
higher amounts of these secondary
metabolite sector beans as opposed to
some of this mono crop cannabis that's
going and AG
that doesn't have the secondary tab like
boost but instead has this pesticide
signature accompanying it you know it's
like it's a really fascinating way to
kind of look at the field in front of in
front of everybody and who really or
who's really out of damage you know even
if some reason is small-town more you're
a small farm side of things instead of
like thirty acres mono crop you know
who's really an advantage
that's where analytical testing really
aids the regenerative farmer or
different bioregions which are
essentially Appalachians because as
South Africa and Colombia and all these
countries come in with thousands and
thousands of hectares you know you got
to be like Oh am I gonna be able to sell
you know the weeds still you're like
yeah you're definitely going to because
of the certain bioregions that you live
in a certain terroir and through
analytical testing and soil testing
you'll be able to show the purity and
show maybe the unique chemo bars that
you have and I think that's extremely
valuable and people trying to flip them
on and people trying to just grow
Kennedy and now that it's make upgrade
again and this whole movement of you
know all the farmers just going for it
you know if you if you shift you know a
thousand acres GMO corn farm with glad
to save everything else in the soil you
know I mean like I think a lot of the
testing kind of eventually wants it you
know you knew people then have to either
go straight to isolating CBD to a single
molecule just to purify it to not fail
you know or they're gonna have to go
grow rope for ten years you know while
they sit this one out and figure it out
then clean up the environment and
involve all I would be else is able to
you know kind of show what they've done
I mean because it's almost like chickens
come home to roost moment you know
performing Appalachian in Los Angeles
indoors under bites in in container soil
is that what's your opinion on that
that's that's a silly proposition sucks
here with a conversation on California's
version of appellations of origin I was
with the work the Appalachians working
group in Sacramento with CDFA and Cal
cannabis this past year and
there's a there's an important
distinction to be made what what the
folks in Los Angeles would like is for
state law to change so that you can
designate a geographic area of origin
which fits right into what Alec was just
saying but it's not appellations of
origin appellations of origin are
different that has to do with standards
and practices and cultivars at least by
law here in California and there are two
different programs
there's the appellation of origin
program which is very exclusive if you
will and it requires creating a local
Appalachian group that then applies to
Cal cannabis for permission to have an
appellation of origin whereas the
geographic indicator system is what la
is after and state law allows a county
of origin designation on packaging and
what we'd like to see changed is it
could be and there is a bill in the
legislature to make this happen that it
would be a city or county of origin and
that would allow the LA indoor growers
and the San Francisco and Oakland indoor
growers nobody knows Alameda County as a
source of indoor cannabis but people
know Oakland and so yeah they're two
different programs it's really important
to distinguish between them the the the
geographic indicator county or city of
origin is a very inclusive it includes
everybody that's doing cannabis activity
in that geographic area an appellation
of origin is a very exclusive thing
that's all I got
thank you you have to you don't add
large fertilizer to grow more grapes
that's not the way they prefer like yes
dirt soil yeah France France is that
there's actually fair laughs at lap
aleshia
eppley Shinto origin a French term is
actually fairly well protected in France
just because of the wine industry and it
traces back to you know different types
of wine being
in different or different appellations
in in France that way they could produce
uniform wine that whether whether that
wine has distributed work throughout the
world if it if it says it's a burgundy
wine or says it's a champagne wine we
know that it's going to be produced in
in that region under the same soil with
the same weather that way
if you you know try one year versus a
different here you can see variation
within the year but the but if you try
two different wineries from the same
year they should have fairly uniform
grape then that's what I want with
cannabis yeah and you're that's a great
way for you know cuz there's everybody's
focusing on trying to grow a thousand
acres what they don't realize is that
you're gonna make way more money as a
craft farmer growing high quality for
high quality flavors in biodynamic soils
producing phenomenal flavors that that
are going to be either extracted or
smoked or even consumed for the
flavonoid profile because all those are
there other terpenes not the
cannabinoids are going to be what
increases the value of your CBDs or th
yeah I couldn't agree more and to that
point to you know I think um you know in
this in this world word like that big AG
approach towards mono cropping towards
moving it to conventional AG land has
happened I almost feel like the plants
trolling us in this way busy and this in
this great time of legalization where
everybody's coming in to you know take
their piece and to crush the competition
you know it's actually setting people up
for massive failures that we're walking
through every day you know around these
these unavoidable residual environmental
contaminants that have become legacy to
that land as a result of the Green
Revolution and as a result of you know
post-world war two practices around
petrochemicals and nerve agents being
now used on you know treating growing
plants and treating you know keeping
away pests and paths of the pathology
but you know but but now like I really
see from the analytical side of testing
on cannabis it's almost really it's
reinforcing the slow food moving
idealism know what the source of where
you're getting your products and your
ingredients and it's more about quality
of ingredients and it is just getting in
bunions and mass
biomass you know because one of us comes
to and could look on the bright side yes
sir yeah after a bunch of people have to
go go go ropes for ten years you know
because I mean a lot of these people
like they're like I'm watching it happen
they're being forced in these positions
where you know there's these certain
regions that are almost getting
blacklisted as a result of you know
these like in you know can consistent I
mean so many people are spinning their
wheels they have they're building out
these like twenty five million dollar
manufacturing facilities and then they
just have people on the road going to
all the mega farms looking you know
living for material they're taking
samples of it they're going they're
taking like a representative sample of
say about thousand pounds they're micro
extracting it so they can concentrate
anything all of it to see if it tests
clean and then they bring it to the lab
pass test dirty and you said and you
know just so on so forth you know so
people are just spinning their wheels in
this time and what we're seeing is so
many the small craft farms that have the
quality ingredients that are preserving
their terpenes that are diversifying the
terpenes you know people are starting to
like lock-in long term you know trend
contracts with these people for like
five to eight hundred dollars a pound
for Tran you know in this moment where
nobody can even get rid of their trim in
a lot of these other areas unless
they're going straight again to isolate
you know or remediation you know and so
it's in so many ways I feel like it's
not only creating this barrier of entry
to for people to come in and try to
pilfer this plant and it's giving this
massive you know in robust advantage
then to the people that have taken care
of this plant that I'm going to steward
this platform ins and you know and then
through that I think it's also helping
to raise awareness to you know the food
we eat and what's on the food and and
then you know I don't smoke coming back
to Seder and the other pesticide or
fungicide so why would I want eat it and
I really in in real time and see kind of
disaffection you know the plant exactly
if you're saying Sam it's like it's
going to you know how those effects I'm
shifting at its trolling trolling the
people that are wasting money trying to
you grow for money right is that a lot
of those people are gonna be planting in
contaminated soil it's gonna play dirty
all of that stuff in various different
parts of the plant we've we've seen you
know the plant will accumulate some of
the heavy metals in the seed husk the
seed shell but it actually will bio
accumulate other pesticides and other
parts to play it so I'd imagine
radioactive nucleotides yeah emulate it
but it's gonna by accumulated parts of
the plant so no matter what you your
crops gonna be you're gonna have to be
able to test and identify what those bio
as you're developing that process
obviously using those contaminated
biomass there's ways to clean it if you
have competent labs and then confident
analytical labs that can help you
develop to remove those contaminants but
you're gonna have to go through a
greater amount of refining so then you
know and there's going to me a market
for distillate nice loot because it's
easier to export to to the three percent
or 1 percent water but that said
everyone who watches has Church
obviously understands that higher
quality is more desirable than bulk so
being able to produce you know have your
having quality as well as you know as
trying to develop quality into scale
there's gonna end up having better
better results for the farmers and
better results for the hash makers and
Mike real quick a question for you you
know so so we we've recently started to
conduct a series of experiments because
we we have this hypothesis that a lot of
the bioaccumulation and metals and
pesticides you know it's we are seeing
and bioaccumulation you know through the
plant of it whatever the toxin is right
heavy metals we're really seeing kind of
on the flower whenever they're being
fully applied when water and combination
of foliar inputs are being fully applied
every five eight you know so the
accumulation metals we're seeing one
flower happening much more from fully up
against than from all beer soil coming
up three roots in the stock if your
loved one knows too
'i'm cadmium arsenic Latimer you know we
don't see well so that's that's kind of
it so so so with my second question is
are they watered overhead by pivot or
are they flood are the fields flooded
right because that pertains the delivery
on the planet sure Wilson well so it so
so we see we see a 2% fail rate in Flour
for heavy metals 1% for arsenic 1%
separately for cadmium and so well all
over the state and so when we see what's
the failure web so failure rate or
what's the what's the what's the
threshold they have to me my love 200
part per billion point 2 ppm yeah I mean
and this is just like redic isn't that
ridiculous like you think well anything
in the state of California below to
whatever people you build you know we
only see 2% fill so I mean 98 percents
passing right so so anyway so real quick
so the emanation from mining or lumber I
think a lot of its coming from folks who
are foyer feeding as versus flooding the
root zone yeah well that's and that's
what we found because like one of my
biggest parts of the biggest part of my
job isn't somebody feel happy
somebody's failing I engage in a root
cause analysis and we go through a
series of environmental assessment tests
such as testing water testing all the
individual foliar inputs that you're
adding to the mixes and in with you know
98 95 plus percent confidence we've
begun to identify the foliar inputs more
so than the water that you're feeding
into the roots because you could take
you know any you know really high level
arsenic guano's and all these other
things and they're gonna accumulate in
the plant but it's not gonna
bioaccumulate slip through and that's
having a series of conversations with
Roy Upton who's the executive director
of the American Herbal pharmacopoeia and
he wasn't actually surprised by the fact
that there was there was such a low fail
rate of flour two percent and and
wondered what he was getting into it he
was he was making the comparison of
American ginseng because with American
ginseng it's a Korean
a plant that grows year after year in
the soil and so so through the monograph
process they were actually able to
identify the doubling each year of heavy
metal accumulation in the plant as it's
growing in the soil year up a year but
but he was saying with cannabis since
cannabis is such a short flowering
annual plan you know maybe if it flower
another 1825 weeks or something maybe
they'll be more of an accumulation
further from the roots to the stock up
into the fruit right and so so so the
fact is we're not seeing the craziest
fail rates and flower you know but when
we are seeing it you know it's a it's
being kind of correlated back to the
water you know cuz it's like are you
filtering or I'm filtering your water
you know ro what you're the what you're
spraying on the plants you know so
that's the start and then it's like okay
well guano seaweed fish pH ups and downs
but you don't the very policy and we've
tested for part four million of cadmium
and like but Paragard you know it's just
a series of different kind of both
beneficial or biological pesticides or
foliar sprays and nutrients but but I
guess the big part of where I was kind
of going through this is you know in
mono crop farming cannabis you know we
have this hypothesis that whenever you
if your row crop in thirty acres of
cannabis you no longer you harvesting it
with the sanctity at which we've harvest
in this plant all our life you know
which is there you taking the
inflorescence of the plant the sugar
leaf the flower you're separating it
from the stock you know but whenever
you're talking about farming with
tractors on this level and you and
you're truly farming for biomass where
you chip in the stock back with the
flower so you can do these industrial
scale extractions on it you know we're
really curious as to whether there's
gonna be like multiple time increase in
metals and also potentially pesticides
because you're using the stock you're
almost it's almost again the plant
rolling mills you can't plate you can't
plant like broccoli or whatever you know
and and and whenever you if you're gonna
try to harvest it in this way that's not
your cherishing the flowers and all the
you know the part of the plant that
we're harvesting I'm gonna use the stack
is this talking to bring about like five
types contamination concentration on top
of the fact that you're already
contaminated in Baghdad absolutely
absolutely and it all has to do with you
know we can lurk in it to what they are
grape growing we
Larkin it - you know the way that you
jab some japanese gardeners will you
know cut down and only grow melons in
one specific way and they'll put them in
shape so that they grow a heart-shaped
melon that they and then in japan that
kind of craft melon production has
melons selling extreme attica lee higher
prices and that really boils down good
genetics of the plant good terroir it's
gonna be child grown how its culture
didn't et cetera but in many cases
they're taking much more care of the
plant than they are growing it on in
trying to grow it in mass it when when
we're growing monocultures of CBD you
have to take more you it's difficult to
have the labor that's incorporated in it
so that you're gonna see stratification
in the CBD industry where you a raft
grow craft grown see Wow reach a premium
whereas if you if you grow it in the
desert
for biomass it's not gonna it's not
going to produce as many of those
monitor but no it's because a lot of
those monitor fluids are gonna get flash
off during the drying for isolate
production there's there's use for that
and if you're but like like you said if
you're not removing those fan leaves
you're gonna be increasing the amount of
wax concentration that's in dependable
mass if you're not removing the stems
you're gonna you know be able to pull
whatever is potentially bioaccumulative
in those stems and if you're trying to
extract seeded bud you're not only going
to extract the oil that's in the seeds
but you're gonna make metals that are
found in the seed coat hold on somebody
somebody is asking but what about
chemtrails you know what's really funny
about chemtrails is i mean like what's
funny about chemtrails is everybody
always thought when heavy-metal testing
kicked in the areas were that are highly
sprayed we're gonna be the ones that
just had the craziest agreed as fail
rates for metals and I mean we're
testing for cadmium we're not test I
mean you know in the idea of what you
know the thought of what has been in
Cantrell's you know maybe we should we
test it for more metals would see but
we're not
seeing any cut type of insanely higher
rate of fail are you testing for
aluminum well so aluminum no where was
the california peñalosa art when we
tested with the full library we tested
we're building a bike a prop 65 metal
tusks - that's for you know however many
total metals are on that list right now
like you know the the kind of throughput
service we offer is primarily for these
four regulated metals LED at 500 parts
per billion mercury at 100 parts per
billion arsenic and cadmium each at 200
billion and so you know like it was it
was interesting because everybody one of
her face three kicked in at the
beginning of two you know this year 2019
and heavy metal testing was part of the
regimen everybody was thinking it was
gonna be this extinction level of that
and everybody's gonna be dead and just
it was gonna be the thing that killed
everybody's business but you know we'd
spend quite the opposite focusing you
know again it's you know these really
low percent fail rates like land were
almost exclusively saying as a part of
manufacturing process cartridges
particularly but also shitty cheap
chinese glass and other types of you
know leaching any shiny metal from from
china could potentially be he be
contaminated with either lead or cadmium
or nickel or i'm surprised just given
the whole erin brockovich thing that
kali hasn't also put chromium on that
list right chromium six is another bad
actor it's interesting because chromium
three is fine right you can buy chromium
three at GNC and pop a couple capsules
of it today but chromium six is that's
the Erin Brockovich chromium right
that's the bad chromium that's the
chromium that they use to code airplanes
and and and ships with and [ __ ] like
that that's what you and Mark you know
what's what's interesting about the
whole thing is because I mean California
from from what I see did didn't you
indeed learned and an advanced past kind
of all them you know this mistake
mistakes of the previous states that
regulated and so you know some say that
you went too far but again like you know
whenever you look at these like you know
Google California average fail rates
across all these different categories
it's not as gnarly as
you know everybody thought you know once
these minimum level is a quality hit you
know we've seen you know from before
regulation to after you know he was like
fifty sixty percent reduction in a lot
of these common pesticides making it
through to the final retail space but
anyway like with your the metals and
with pesticides though there there could
be more more compounds added like
chromium states like Nicola and I've
been hearing of nickel poisoning being
about breaking from mortgages and like
nickel-plated cartridges but then also
glyphosate how much glad to States
sprayed in California yeah we're seeing
kind of hemp farmers that are
desiccating thirty acres of their
Tomatoes so that they can kind of pull
it out and then replant it with hemp you
know is that gonna be poison I think so
I would never want I was like and
smoking reports that I'm seeing in the
news or what Mike blow cards macro cards
I mean it's it's it's unknown like I
mean that that's a whole other just will
do the e-juice thing is one of the
gnarliest things I've ever seen in my
life because I was puffing those tools
really really tough we started doing a
pretty quick pretty big assessment of
the e-juice you because somebody told me
that it's like the e that e-cigs and the
nicotine that come from me sings like I
was saying I'm just puffing one of these
jewels and my body was like you're
really smart I can't believe you're just
puffing up and he's like where do you
think that nicotine comes from and as I
what it's like synthesized nicotine so
he's like no dude it's the hot dog water
distillate of the tobacco crop and I was
like wow and so I immediately went back
to it's more isolated like like cocaine
would be because it's an alkaloid you
can crash out the hydrochloride saw of
my well so I'm sure I'm sure
because that's what's real quick because
Merck that's what we're seeing so we're
seeing if we test a bunch of tobacco
like Marlboro and all these other kind
of conventional graham-cracker crops we
see a series of pesticides right cat1
cat2 pesticides different concentrations
etc etc when we're testing a Jew
we're almost exclusively seeing Diamond
azide owl our uh our I know like say
diamond is because there's certain
compounds like even Mike would be
positive an example like that needs
Sampson Poseidon the extraction process
was separate with certain process he's
nonpolar polar you know with filtration
these different things but we're seeing
other ones you will kind of linearly
concentrate with the extraction and and
so what's what's really really weird
it's only twenty degrees off weight but
I don't know what's up in the diamond is
out into conversation but diamonds are
you know Foss belowed flower dragon this
plant growth retardant you know that was
part of the a lower scare of the
eighties you know where they're ours you
approve to use on Apple crops and you
know they're you know and on orchards
and they're make huge apples and they're
all going to baby food and then the
skeevy a report came out in like 1987 or
88 detailing the carcinogenic properties
of diamonds I'd and how it broke down
into a chemical called udmh which is in
the hydrogen family which is even more
toxic like a rocket fuel derivative
compound and from that point on it was
banned for use on any consumable crop
sense but then it was like really
popular you used you know in the you
know late 90s through kind of a lot of
the 2000s by various types of growers
growers going oh gee Kush you know
stretch your kind of plants and in
indoor environments and so it really
popularized you know I'm on cannabis but
now it's a category one pesticide so
anything detected at the detection limit
or above which is about 30 parts per
billion point zero three is a fail you
know and so we've seen the you the the
fail rates of it on cannabis go down
incredibly low
you know below way below 1% you know so
that's amazing but then for the fact
that a juice and the fact that
cigarettes are showing such consistent
amounts of diamonds at across all the
crop is really complying my mind you
know that that's that's and they because
we're testing these eg pins and there's
like 15 part per million of lead and
there's like two thousand times of a
limit for diamonds I don't and they
don't fail California guys look what
just came out with this week with you
know there's approximately 20 to 25
people now with actual home
issues due to illegal cartridge is that
have never been tested
usually product that would never as
people would know would never even go to
testing so they even send it to that so
they backward backyard blast it and or
very professionally blasted there's very
professional illegal setups nowadays
that's really the shadows it's causing
breathing problems to where people can't
you know basic oxygen transformation is
a [ __ ] problem right now that's a
problem people this is a gun right and
the whole thing you know all these comas
everything like it's really fascinating
time that this is always break out of
vape related issues are popping up and I
mean what is it coming from is it coming
from a Eve apes or you juices is it
coming partially from cannabis and the
contaminants that are in it it's
probably a combination of mission its
causal prohibition I couldn't agree more
and that's what's so awesome about this
whole story and I think it really that
much more you know kind of I guess
intensifies the the need for analytical
testing and these minimum quality
standards to hit for public health and
safety concerns because whenever you
have all the legacy toxic material from
California that is and and other states
that are then you know being filled in
cards and sent to the East Coast without
any regard to people sell their safety
and they're literally getting the
dirtiest stuff that's there that can't
hit the market and probably many others
regulate spaces you know this is it's a
there's people who are pirating
packaging of like the more successful
legitimate brands in established markets
like Colorado in California and now that
people doesn't people unsporting people
can buy this packaging now they can
basically rip that packaging off and put
some some quality product into what a
consumer might think is oh that's coming
from that vape company and powerful and
when actually it's not it's just coming
from someone who bought the packaging
that from the company who's ripping off
that company and hey just well I have
the floor just for clarification issues
because I saw this come up in the chat
yes arsenic is not
metal right but arsenate is a component
that's been used for for many years in
pressure-treated lumber and a lot of
that pressure-treated lumber that was
made like in the 50s 60s and 70s you
know that green lumber for picnic tables
and swing sets and stuff like that
a lot of that lumber is now coming out
of service coming out of useful service
that's ending up in landfills and and
when that yeah when that well wherever
it goes
our arsenate itself so it's not arsenic
the material arsenic it's actually
arsenate which is a s I think oh five or
something like that highly mobile in
ground water and so that just again
points to again human impact that a lot
of places like Florida for example where
there's been a lot of development on the
coast I don't believe that there's a
natural source for arsenic in Florida
but over the last several years and all
the development that goes on on the
coastline and marshy areas require what
pressure-treated lumber
to go into those you know sensitive
wetland areas where you know like what
would typically be put into a up here or
you know any wood that has to go into a
saltwater exposure has to be super super
loaded with all kinds of chemicals you
can see kinda like the green salts that
come spewing out of these well for a
long time that was something called CCA
which is chrome aided copper arsenate
CCA right and so this complex was used
to make you know telephone poles and
railroad ties and you've seen that
pressure-treated lumber right so that
lumber which again is part of like you
know coastal development say around
state like Florida which is about to get
hit by a huge [ __ ] hurricane has
basically imported all of this arsenic
into their water system and and and so
again there is no natural source of
arsenic in Florida and all the
development that's gone on over the last
70 years or so around the Florida
coastline has imported all this arsenic
so so as this lumber comes out of use it
definitely puts arsenic arsenate in the
soil it's kind of nothing we could do
about it it's kind of like this is just
the the price that we pay for using
chrome aided copper arsenic from I think
I was discovered by some Indian dude in
like the 30s and an AT&amp;T bought the
patent and that green lumber was
everywhere
well that green lumber actually replaced
in some cases creosote which was used to
treat railroad ties and telephone poles
that's that black tar II [ __ ] that's
cancerous as well but you know you're
trading one poison for another but
that's just I just wanted to mention
that about arsenic so in in areas like
California or other areas where wood
treatment was used and and arsenic was
used as part of that wood treatment as
that wood comes out of useful service
yeah it ends up getting leached into the
into the water system you can't help it
I would just remind the panel that I
have been posting questions from the
chat room into our own private chat room
here on Zoom so if you open it you'll
see there's some question just some
people are a little bit more intense
about getting their questions answered
than others
hey Mark what was that question about
CBD a couple couple questions ago what
was the I seem to have lost it now multi
soil zone I don't know it was before
that it was the first one was CBD
production Kent I heard CBD production
can be altered and distillate by
lengthening the carbon times and THC can
be converted to CBD in this process how
true is this that was the first question
now I posted that about an hour ago and
THC can be converted into CBD is that
what they said yes versa but that's what
he's won the question mark is what about
a version of CBD into THC via
isomerization during distillation
yeah that's contra thermodynamic right
so its THC is lower energy if given the
opportunity
CBD will will convert over to THC and
that's a that's a well-documented fact
by Rafael Michelin themselves yeah the
other way around he was asking if THC
can be converted to CBD so I suspect you
know I mean not not I think some people
are trying that there was a a guy who
had that idea who posted for some input
on one of the Facebook cannabis chat
rooms we're not chat rooms what groups
were we sometimes talk about these
things but yeah I mean it's it's going
you have to figure out a way to put it's
gonna take energy to do that but it's
gonna take a particular catalyst to do
that I mean believe me if you could
figure out a way to do that that's very
very valuable because certainly people
want to take hot CBD and turn it into
all CBD and take away that THC I think
what a lot of people are doing with
their so when you're doing hemp
extraction and you're getting a CBD
isolate from it the isolate comes from
the crystallization from a mother liquor
and that mother liquor still is enriched
with cannabinoids and in most cases
depending on what you're extracting you
can get multiple crops of CBD crystal
from a single mother liquor but one is
no longer when you've robbed it of all
the CBD that they can basically you can
get like that now the mother liquor is
beyond the SAP
or no more CBD of THC and other minor
cannabinoid enriched mixture that I
believe a lot of people are converting
over to CBN the cbn has incredible
market value right now and you're making
it into something that's not THC and
cool right so you're basically
destroying it but you're destroying it
into something that you can actually
sell and actually if you think about it
if you look at the economics it's
actually a production process to make
cbn that by the way makes a little bit
of CBD along the way because you'll make
a lot more money on your seen cannabis
pick up gold mill near the Sacramento
area pick up gold it's an interesting
experiment that it's gonna cost a lot of
money to figure out yeah so what you
need it has been shown to pick up the
heavier metals but I don't know if the
if gold would because you'd have to have
some it I I would come back on a soluble
version of it I mean and to solubilize
gold to size go on you're taking nice
expensive gold and you're dissolving
with hydrochloric acid or sulfuric acid
to make some gold solution guy that
exudates something that can solubilize
the gold in raw and then form have that
fungi then absorb it and translocated
into the plant but that's gonna be
that's gonna be a little bit of work
I'll say that's gonna be a project that
I don't think it's gonna be well
accepted because of the genetic
engineering involved hey mark I'd love
to kind of jump in on a part of that
thought of the pressure-treated wood you
know one of the another really really
fascinating trends that we've kind of
seen since the beginning last year with
regard to a couple different pesticides
is you know one of them's called
chlorine chlorine is a
an old kind of DDT like compound that
has been banned for use on I mean yeah
they used to spray that around they used
to spray that in the trench around
foundations when they built homes it's
okay
and the has [ __ ] insecticide that
lasts for hundreds of years
exactly it's got like hundred your
half-life and so so they also used to
pressure treated wood with it and so we
see in instant driving spaces if you're
drawing and kind of like say a barn or
some space where there's open on stomach
the wood where it was frustrated we're
seeing the off gassing of that pesticide
happened yeah - where was levels are you
seeing like ppm or ppb or what ppb
mainly but you know with with chlorine
since it's also category one pesticide
anything at or above the detection limit
of about thirty point handling well but
so we're seeing kind of right around
there showing up in flower that's
basically being dried in these spaces
and then and then in extract we're
seeing it kind of showing up in failing
amounts you know kind of at you know
maybe a couple few hundred part per
billion but but it's a trend that we've
seen and and and we've begin to also you
know kind of with I mean whether it's
just a certain trend but we see we've
you know a lot of these chlorine fails
we're seeing very kind of regionally
happen also areas like Watsonville and
you know berries and strawberries all
the things that you know and in you know
so there's a line you know whether it is
the foundational wood in greenhouses you
know that are kind of open and exposed
in the space that are off gassing when
temperature humidity kind of
differentials are happening or whether
it's in drying spaces cuz then on the on
the other side with drying spaces you
know one of the biggest fails trends
that we've seen with indoor cultivation
is around basically the use of air
assault bug bombs
you know because historically people
were taking these total release bombs
like attain which is bifenthrin and
Piper no peach oxide pylon TR which is
chlorophyll appear particulate I think
it's under Plex which is chlorophyll
chlorpyrifos
which is an organophosphate and then you
know pyrethrin bombs there's
but essentially you know people would
take these bombs that are meant intended
for 10,000 square foot greenhouse spaces
and and they wouldn't you know even
organic people because I you know before
we open it Bessie labs I was working
many years not japonic industry and you
know kind of century selling bombs and
pesticide options to people and you're
trying to train people to be on him
organic integrated pest management
prevention approach but but you know
kind of the others at may you know
everybody use these bombs and so even
organic people there don't claim never
spray pesticides or do anything negative
to the plant they would still in between
harvesting and indoor room they would
take a thousand square foot room they'd
light off a 10,000 square foot bomb you
know for one of these pesticide bombs
and essentially they're lighting off in
this indoor environment where it then
coats every surface area inside the
space whether it's drywall sheetrock and
just sucks in like pour like a sponge
and so essentially whenever you do that
harvest after harvest after harvest year
after year after year you know there
becomes this persistence build-up of
these compounds that are then
unavoidable and we're seeing years after
their last use we'd like particularly
for the CH compounds like chlorophyll
appearing for power flows both category
one you know pile on most particularly
because it was so ubiquitous and
available just over the counter in hydro
stores that people like and so so we
will be failing like years after it's
and and then we're helping in all this
environmental assessment work further
like how the f is this here I haven't
used this in two and a half year or year
and a half whatever and so so will then
send out like swabs and will take chunks
of drywall that will then run testing on
and we've seen like ten part per million
built up in drywall in the you know
certain really worst-case scenarios and
in those cases we're seeing the flowers
you know that like even whenever they're
grown fully organic you know and this
has happened when people have even just
purchased and end up like an existing la
and or you know warehouse and you know
where it was previously bombed on
forever you know now kind of even though
they're going all organic you know all
the new soil of predatory bugs you know
the first harvest out of this facility
we're saying like 700 parts per billion
point seven of in the flower and then
whenever it is turned into extract we're
saying over you know two
last part per million in it you know and
this is again like it's his build up
company place from these part per
billion determinations you're doing on
the on the mass spec right on the mass
spectrometer I would take it right Jesus
master OMS GCMs NL CMS both you know so
you need you need the sensitivity of the
mass spectrometer to be able to do yeah
I think this is just before you joined
today Alec we were talking about that
you know there's this n I st library of
all right different kinds of compounds
and you can basically match the mass
spectrum of what you think is
chlorpyrifos to know that that is
chlorpyrifos and is no question about it
that that peak in that material at that
ppm ppb level but again the sensitivity
of the mass spectrometer is such that
you know you are down at the at the ppb
level and I on news for you folks we
live in a [ __ ] contaminated world if
you start looking at everything that
humans come in contact with at the part
per billion level you'll be amazed I
always used to say it's like taking a
little rush to a New York City sidewalk
you're gonna find everything you're
gonna find all kinds of [ __ ] that you
never knew on food on your clothing and
then when you look at the part per
billion level think about it just for a
second what so you have percentage right
then you have pretends and then for
hundreds per thousand this is billion
okay part one part per billion so
imagine a whole railcar full of vodka
and one little shot of vermouth that's
like a part [ __ ] four billion it's
it's an incredible you know again
opportunity that we have to use
analytical chemistry to look at such
levels at cannabis but really I mean if
you were looking to go look at some
backwoods smokes or just get go buy some
produce for
Whole Foods would they hold up to this
part per billion scrutiny that you're
looking at I mean will we see any
residuals at the part per billion level
of stuff that's you know in current
commerce so are they artificially
holding cannabis to a new level of
purity when we live in a [ __ ]
contaminated world and the plant we love
sucks up everything from the from the
soil the poisoning of this supply chain
to Alec I know this is gonna be a big
case for you guys when you know edible
producers down in California they have
to make sure that all of their
ingredients of my chain are going to
pass the certified test so in a way the
plant rolls the industry again all of
our ingredients better for our consumers
nobody hold on but it actually adds a
caveat because you saw probably this
week to Alec of the study regarding how
chocolate actually affects the potent
testing regarding cannabis so we're
finding even food products actually can
throw off testing altogether so another
fact that we're learning as we're
dealing with more normalized products in
from the food chain coming into the ring
of our testing requirements well two
points on that one
so SEM on yours which is one percent
valid you know I mean we've been doing
analytical chemistry on cannabis now for
10 years and it has taken us about that
long to figure this plan out and all the
different matrices that are presented
with infused cannabis in it so chocolate
gummy bears gummy bears are like the
bane of my existence you know to resolve
a gummy bear matrix and then pull the
two and a half milligrams and accurately
repeatedly be able to test over time
kind of that those those are that you
know dentures you guys use catchers done
[ __ ] well well just different for
different steps I mean
I mean catchers we used to use on our
pesticide prep I don't know if we use it
on our gummy crab mm-hmm
but that's if that if you're
recommending that I'm definitely gonna
forget to me well are you so are you
doing like are you are you freezing the
the gummy with liquid nitrogen well what
are you doing am a serrated to or that
might be three constants I were these I
mean it where it's the whole because if
you if you blend I mean this is a bit of
a tension because I wanted to kind of
hit back on the this other side with
kind of is testing kind of a cannabis
too much to Mark's point but but yeah I
mean you know the truck we've we've
worked through all these different
matrices you know kind of end and and a
lot of that you know whenever you start
working with the manufacturer that's you
know kind of making infused products you
know such a big part of the job of a lab
that we bring to the table is to do a
bunch of upfront testing for one to be
able to you know demonstrate and prove
our worth and being able to accurately
and repeatedly test this particular type
of product whether it's chocolate or
gummy you know but then beyond that it's
us helping to identify all these pain
points in the other ingredients supply
chain that are going into this cannabis
formulation because we're seeing all
kinds of trends you know with like
people making orange mints you know
where they're taking orange essential
oil and then making a cannabis infused
mint with it you know we're finding the
claw repair dose is you know I mean one
of the most common organophosphate
sprayed on citrus so of course those
essential oil that is gonna have alter
concentration and then you take the
tiniest amount of that ingredient and
flavor your mints and you just failed
the entire batch you know and and this
goes to chocolate also chocolate is a
known bio accumulator of a vital you
mediator of Miam and and since we've
engaged so in with like many experts in
the cacao industry since we've seen this
issue because we know with a percentage
of cacao 35 percent forty seven percent
75 plus percent cacao will see a linear
increase in cadmium like up to multiple
part per million in various sources of
cacao with the percentage increase in
and so come to find out whenever
whenever cacao is grown in mountainous
regions of the world like the Andes it's
always going to have this known issue of
cadmium bioaccumulation and so so Kay
the cacao industry had to pivot whenever
they're trying to meet these European
Union standards that are really really
strict on metals in the product and the
final form product that are being sold
to the European Union markets and so
they've had to identify this whole kind
of issue and as an industry they came to
find out that it's whenever you're going
to count mountainous regions like Andes
this is it cadmium is always an issue
but whenever you're being just sourcing
it from other areas like Africa and kind
of the you know central Central America
and such then you know the cadmium is no
longer an issue but it's it's you know
this cannabis regulation in these ways
it's it's putting people up to the
highest kind of you know robust quality
standards that anything's ever had to be
applied to and ends and there's land
mines every which direction around us
mark because of what your point is
because we toxify the environment the
legacy of the Green Revolution has
destroyed the soil
it's like contaminated everything but is
that the answer we just you know kind of
just sink to that low or we set the new
the new high standard that that
eventually anything else that we are
gonna be consuming shouldn't meet you
know because it's like I mean are these
you know let me just with like diamonds
I don't know I could just go off from
the glyphosate thing but it's like I've
say kills the microbiome you know it
gives the you know curious leaky gut
which then creates all the food
allergies which they could solve the
autoimmune reactions that you know kind
of then create autoimmune conditions all
the cancer there's so much of all the
illness and suffering that humans are
now suffering from you know in so many
ways stems from this chemical revolution
that has now created this completely
ubiquitous part per billion part per
trillion level every contaminant pfl AAP
fos in the environment now in our bodies
but but you know from what we're seeing
in california one of the largest
agricultural states in the united states
you know kind of even with the most
robust pesticide heavy metal mycotoxin
Aspergillus standards that have ever
been a
you know across each of these categories
we don't see that I mean so pesticides
we see about 2 to 3% salary metals we
see about 3 percent fail rate microbial
impurities now that yeast and mold in
toll aerobic bacteria aren't the the
focus of regulations and it's just the
pathogenic Aspergillus Salmonella e.coli
species we see about 2% or less fail
rate across all products you know and so
and and and and I'll wrap the point with
this I don't mean just be all
sesquipedalian with it but essentially
whenever went you know back it back in
2015 to 2017 we weren't testing 466 of
the most common agricultural pesticides
that are in California we're testing for
12 of the most common pesticides things
like Eagle 20 or Michael beaten all by
feni's eight album album actin pack low
diamond azide you know a spear Memphis
and imidacloprid so we're testing for
these really common ones that were using
cannabis and in Flour 2015 to seven 2017
for these 12 pesticides and when we're
testing them we're seeing them way
higher part per billion if not part four
millionaire levels you know with our old
kind of mass effect systems they weren't
nearly as sensitive as our new and and
so even then whenever there's no
regulations and people were just doing
the damn thing you know we saw in flour
about 30 percent fail rate for one of
these 12 pesticides and then when it
came to extracts we saw anywhere from 50
to 75 percent fail rate and 50 percent
was more like butane extracts and co2
stuff like that but then when you've got
more refined distillate you went up to
75 percent fail rate now across now that
California put this minimum level of
quality standards in place that
everybody whether David or Goliath have
to hit just to get product and market
we've seen pretty much most compliance
testing we've seen all these failures go
down to less than 2% less than 3% you
know for pesticides you know and that's
across pepino concentrates and flowers
you know we seem obviously a much higher
failure rate on the R&amp;D and process
testing and as people are screening
their supply chain and ingredients
before they get their product for market
and what but but that's like Meg that's
that's mind blowing that yeah Alan can I
ask like can you tell
baitball obviously if the levels I'm
sure would make sense but can you
distinguish someone who is directly
applying these pesticides versus adrift
you know resolved that would so you
could come you basically see the people
who fail up here and then the people who
fail down here and this is drift and
these are the people who are applying
well because I mean with with simplicity
certain trends were across every batch
in there huh in the in you know of you
know in a greenhouse everything will
fail you know that we can trace back to
a clone that was dipped or maybe in the
early spray where they thought they'd be
able to kind of get away with it and the
residual isn't gonna be as long versus
you know in a lot of cases when we're
testing you know kind of these major
greenhouses and different AG areas you
know we're seeing kind of more regional
pesticide kind of exposure you know that
are real close to vents that you know
that were Aires being pulled in from
outside you know where happen we're
seeing kind of more you know kind of you
know kind of less systemic or I guess
across the entirety of the harvest and
more regionally kind of located and so
then we'll go in and send out swabs and
we'll swab de interiors exteriors of the
greenhouse you know in different
perimeters of the greenhouse so that we
can help to further narrow down because
the pesticide thing is a huge issue you
know because the you know the FIFRA you
know the federal insecticide fungicide
and rodenticide act you know it's you
know it's it's the foundation at which
you know we are in the in the world are
protected from the exposure of a lot of
these pesticides and it's really
stipulated and strongly on when you can
spray what can spray how you can spray
you know under what conditions wind
conditions but those things aren't
followed you know and so therefore kind
of you know when you see you when you
drive down california you see people
just midday bombing kind of carpet
dusting out of planes or helicopters you
know they're doing so in full willful
disregard to these regulations you know
this right there are no guidelines for
cannabis not talking about them spraying
AG crops though because now there's
there AG sprays are gonna drift and
affect a cannabis farm and so now that
the cannabis farm gets hit and fails a
batch of this really high price
modernity crop that's now legal now they
have a president for holding a count
holding accountable the farms because
farmers have crop insurance not if
they're they lose their crop do they
[ __ ] up it's a in case their their
practices overspray and drift and now
they get held liable and have to
basically get sued and money basically
is there from crop insurance to you know
so it's you know I don't know gonna
prevent overspray though from being
causing a lot of liability especially in
agricultural areas where it's it's a
tradition where agricultural spraying
predates cannabis that's unfortunate but
what we're gonna see is in the cannabis
in those areas that unfortunately have
that overspray we're just gonna have to
develop SOPs in the extraction lab to
scavenge no but but just one just and
I'm sorry I keep talking have you all
been following the crop protection
services issue in Carpinteria with the
avocado farmers yeah yes so so this is
revolutionary and this I think proves
the point to Mike with kind of just
cannabis changing AG because you know
now that you're so in awe in avocado
country most avocado farmers don't spray
their own pesticides they hired crop
protection services the biggest retailer
wholesaler of fuggin AG chemicals who
also has a department division that goes
out and sprays the pesticides for a
yearly fee they also crop protection
services as a result of cannabis now
being planted all around Carpinteria
where the you know in somebody are
December Academy where the avocados are
they now are scared shitless of getting
sued and held liable for further
spraying practices so they just they
just pulled out of every contract with
every avocado farm to not spray
pesticides this year as a result of like
you know the potential of being held
liable so now instead of them just
pulling up there like blasters within
midday without care of who's living in
their environment or what it helped
their overspray is gonna affect people
the way used to go blast in the drive
home you know now their pull not doing
it so now if the avocado farmers want to
spray
pesticides they spray them and now
they're the ones are gonna be held
liable so now I feel like this plant is
this you know beacon of progress being
planted it's yeah rather than spraying
the dangerous pesticides that aren't
approved for cannabis they're gonna
start spraying avocado plants with more
beneficial insects beneficial microbes
actually have a lot of those are gonna
be able to treat the same symptoms just
have less latency time and less hazard
in the community and then that's
cannabis forcing progress yeah totally
so and that's great right the same same
same on what I've seen a lot of wheat
farmers corn farmers and soybean farmers
are now rotating hemp in a because they
think they're gonna get that extra bonus
yeah a little little bit more growing
hemp than wheat or corn or soybeans
especially with this trade war going on
but that you know I think the bigger
benefit is growing growing polycultures
and then you know being able to you
rotate your paddocks rotate your fields
with multiple crops and incorporate you
know hemp
benefit for its herbicide so you don't
have to use those criticized or no
pressed no oh yeah
oh no we've we've seen people fail for
putting up the dichlorvos
like little insecticide traps because
you know you can get the sticky traps
which are chill or you could get the
ones that actually off-gas pesticide and
that and dichlorvos is is a DB I'm sorry
DD BP dichlorvos as a category one pest
site and and also dichlorvos breaks down
into naled or I'm sorry maybe nail it
nail it breaks down nailer which is an
organophosphate because I don't know
that many people that used to borrow
poison bombs nope it's the same thing
yeah it's the same things it's basically
you know cuz in areas where we see those
no pest rips with that are basically
gassing dichlorvos
I mean it's more or less the same thing
just different
of bombing right because they'll spread
our pyrethrum aren't pyrethrum bombs
used to like deal with sick infested
rooms oh yeah
yeah i bombs the bifenthrin bombs
chlorophyta pure bombs core you know
core Pyro's bombs we see all of them
used you know and it's been really big
cal products in california you know
before the testing rigs were in place
for what it's worth though pyrethrin and
bifenthrin we see kind of i guess let
you know they seem to break down quicker
over time but but a lot of these other
compounds like the piper no beach oxide
which is you know company depends on
that that's similar to the chlorpyrifos
em chlorophyll appear is seems to stay
persistent and you know some of the only
ways to get it out once you've been just
historically bombing is to rip down your
drywall to rebuild the whole room he
said like your kids because what happens
is the lights turn off the humidity
spikes in the time where the demon if i
was trying to catch up and bring the
humidity down and essentially it just
sweats from the walls and from the
environment there's the ceilings these
pesticides out in the in the humid air
and then just gets circulated and blown
around through the humidity ventilation
systems in the HVAC and to you and then
you got essentially sticky residue of
these pesticides spread through every
area of the space and you know and the
thing is it happens the same at those no
strip the little I mean no pest strips
with nail it depending on how many of
them you have spread across your room
you know you you it just this slow
gassing or this one-time bombing it just
starts to build persistence in the space
well the whole notion about using
pyrethrum though is that pyrethrum
actually is not stable and will break
down with time so pyrethrum itself is an
extract from a chrysanthemum daisy right
that is actually a natural insecticide
now you have to distinguish that from
pyrethroids which are kinda like there's
opiate and opioids so that pyrethroids
are all synthetic analogues and those
are all the active ingredients that
you're talking about which ya are
regulated for use in Paris well hi
wreath room itself is a naturally
occurring you know basically extract
that has what insect mostly insecticidal
activity right yeah when you give you a
pie Ganic and like an organic evergreen
version which are just chrysanthemum
extracts extracts but you know paper
which shows that cannabis can produce
Arabians no you know what that's that I
have to call I have to say you know
there was there I think there was a very
premature bad leave you know the
whenever so that there was a paper that
kind of put out about pyrethrins it was
and and correct me if I'm wrong Sam but
there was a pretty recent paper over the
last few years but there was there's
there was some faulty information that
was generated by a lab or two around
these because PI you know in in the mass
spectrum you know like you can you can
pretty easily if you don't validate your
run you can miss identify pyrethrin or
piracy of these pyrethrin Peaks or or
irritate me or molecular kind of weights
or whatever we know what I'm unless kind
of scientist more kind of on the you
know kind of front-end so I am NOT
foundational a lot of science but
essentially have the materials Jews
Caribbean yeah I so I I do I hear you on
that I do know that you cuz I know that
the lab was publishing data around it
and I know as a result there was this to
genetic testing company that published
it I would just I would personally want
to see a lot more reproducible data to
demonstrate that because from what I
know so much of that was some who has
false positives and from the lab one
variety of will that be interesting if
there was a certain specific plant or
chemo bar that had that property that
seems very interesting everybody will
immediately get it now and you've
already patented that right did hey Alec
Sam's Bram
I am definitely no longer going to be
hitting my Andean Cusco chocolate that
was left on my pillow in Colombia when I
was there recently well do test it send
it cadmium dude let me test it I'll send
it your way
yeah well that's Cusco chocolate well
and it's not to down to denigrate kind
of you know then I I love a lot of nd
and medicines you know but but to
understand this topic of cacao and this
whole phytoremediation of cadmium it's
really blowing my mind around these
various aspects and you know just like
the whole thing with jewel and testing
diamond nose I when I was puffing you
know once you know and you see the see
the results in front of you you then
have a choice you know to keep puffing
it or to keep eating that cacao or you
know to find a cleaner source and I
think that's one of the most magical
things about kind of you know what
analytical chemistry is bringing to the
you know science of cannabis it's really
helping to kind of bring these things to
the surface that are unknown Invisibles
and then giving us the opportunity to
choose quite a percent now it's it's a
wonderful thing I'm glad you were able
to make it in because it sure was a lot
of analytical and lab talk before you
came in and of course since you've come
as well it's been the real and oh and I
wanted to mention to you guys I am now I
through zoom I can record this so I
record it like in a video format it also
streams to YouTube and get saved but
then it also creates a audio file so
I've started to post at buzzsprout and
I'll post the link in hash Church it's
basically buzzsprout comm backslash and
then the code for all the hash church
will be five five two one nine six and
I'll post that in I'll post it in the
comments section of all the hash
churches from now on that are zoom and
I'll also post it in the hash Church
forum on Facebook just so people you
know some people have been asking me for
years to make hash church into a
podcasts
there you have it he did the podcast and
today it was a darn good one let me tell
you I say we still got 22 minutes to
rock till noon I sort of had till noon
put aside so let's continue our
conversation yeah I haven't been seen
too many people hitting bond rows I feel
like I've been hit in mind pretty tough
here but maybe I have sir smoking
rolling well thanks for doing this mark
it's good to get together with everybody
again it's good to talk to Alec and see
her eat in again and I think 18 just
celebrated a big milestone in his life
right a couple yeah a few right more
than one just banged out a couple in the
last like three months
but thanks for putting this back
together man this is good yeah thank you
so much mark as I must say it's it's
nice to be back on and to see everybody
as well as to learn I love learning I
love listening and hearing you know from
everyone you know I just yeah I may I
became 50 and I got married in Alaska so
half a century seven half-century Club
and looking forward to the next one so
did you hear what he said that yeah now
I he's been with his wife for 50 years
congratulations there Wow
Sam many blessings there I hope to be I
hope to reach that milestone myself with
my beautiful life do the math apply you
Sam
picture you have hanging near your
bathroom and you're in your kitchen
there of like you and your friends and
you and Diana and the picture I can't
remember exactly it looks like an album
cover or something that's definitely the
front page of your book because that is
the most unbelievable it looks like it's
like a Hollywood thing like it doesn't
even look real good a much cuter one
when I was about nine months old naked
no you got to bury that in the book deep
you can't you can't be putting that on
the front cover Sam come on
you get hey Mark you want to answer this
last question here
what's one that is it possible to
carboxylate TT dislike converting it
back into th CA Yeah right he would very
much like you to ask that question okay
so who asked that question well that
question you know they probably tell me
if I asked tell us who as bet yeah so
it's it's possible but it takes a whole
lot of energy because you've you've
basically THCA again has got higher
energy than THC and so one of the
carboxylates it goes downhill kind of
like a roller coaster and so you need to
put a lot of energy back in and can you
so when you lose the carboxylic acid in
th CA that's a decarboxylation to
carboxylate it it's a very old chemical
reaction called the Kobe Schmitt
reaction and the Colby Schmitt reaction
is a it's a way to make salicylic acid
from phenol so it's a way of carboxyl
eating phenol to make salicylic acid and
you can apply that to mate th CA but it
would probably tear up the rest of the
molecule because that reaction has done
it ungodly high-pressure I think in
molten sodium or some [ __ ] like that so
middle of the Sun kind of chemistry it's
gonna destroy the Terps it's gonna
destroy everything including probably
the person doing it you know someone
reporting the person doing it yeah
someone reported the use of a reagent
called MN n P which is magnesium mono
terephthalate to do the oxidation of THC
to make THC a they only did a few
milligrams in the paper they just showed
that it could be done
I think isolated to peak in the PC and
said look we can do this well thank you
for the focus who asked that question
and he just said this is so much better
than as
hang on reddit so yeah probably not
once you decarboxylate you know it's a
it's a downhill thermodynamic reaction
you lose co2 and that co2 needs a whole
lot of energy to go back and be the
cannabinoid acid again and it just would
again someone they used to make
industrially salicylic acid salicylic
acid you could actually isolate from
from the bark of willow tree I think is
where they used to get it from but you
can make it industrially in a Colby
Schmidt reaction Colby is spell k o lb e
Colby Schmidt man these are some badass
German chemists for you know a little
after turn of the century that were
[ __ ] taking molten sodium and doing
all kinds of synthesis with it these
[ __ ] man it just you know this
is the foundation the chemistry that
exists out there there's there are ways
so to answer the question yes you can do
it I think it would tear up the rest of
the molecule and I think would never be
economically viable to do so so but
interesting question nonetheless it's
inspired me actually and I just
mentioned it to the YouTube chat room
that I think a really good episode would
be you know a question and answer like
listen listen this is going to be the
panel this week we're specifically only
going to be answering your questions
maybe even over the course of a week or
two you know bring in 500 different
questions and pick like 20 or 30 or 40
or whatever it is we have time to answer
I think that would be pretty killer you
know we could answer five questions
every time we do a a hash search there
you go yeah exactly and I you know just
today being the last half an hour it
made sense to just be like they've got
lots of questions one thing I will say
about the chat the hash room hash search
chat
is that they're very engaged with what's
going on for the most part the odd time
someone gets to stick up their ass and
they try to like hijack the entire
conversation but they are pretty damn
engaged in the conversation which I
guess is part of the little bit of magic
why would they be watching if they
weren't yeah well you surprised man I go
into like like you know okay for a
perfect example couch to her
holy smokes have you ever you get to go
to the real show so you probably don't
have to do couch tour mark on my couch
tour now because Fischer's out in Denver
caliber of people in the chat room let's
just say are not ninety micron for the
rest of us laymen what are you talking
about I'm talking about fish does alive
they do their tour video live streamed
and so they have a video stream
sometimes it's on Ustream or whatever
and then they have a chatroom just like
us just like here and so I'll go into
the chatroom thinking man I bet there's
some good people in there and I'm just
like holy [ __ ] like it's like troll
central in there like you don't even
want to go in there for half a
maintainer everything here is really
engaged and really thoughtful there's a
lot of crazy questions in here I'm just
going through trying to find there's a
few that are really fascinating around
testing you know one of the ones
actually I see on your real quick I
think would be great to hit is uh
pesticides through white whitey
pesticides kind of concentrate more with
the essential oils and the red and the
resin glands than kind of on the biomass
or plant material because we see that
trend very specifically like if you if
you have pesticides fungicides anything
like that on the plant and if you do
fresh frozen extraction live resin
extraction on it and then in the process
of further kind of purifying and kind of
mining the diamonds whether the terpenes
separate up to the top you know in the
terpene layer like if you test the
crystalline THC a that's created from
that process you know it's 96 97 plus
percent THC a the remaining bits are you
know presence of kind of terpenes
what-have-you but you see in the
terpenes the terpene layers were what
fractions the pesticides were those
we see most all the pesticides or
whatever that whatever fungicide
contamination that's in the material we
see all that migrate with the terpenes
very good yeah that that's kind of yeah
that was got your father solvent and
most of those are hydrophobic molecules
a lot of them delivered by suspension in
water they're not very water soluble so
they want to be in a hydrophobic
environment so yeah it totally makes
sense sorry I'm bombs right would it be
great if the if the pest of all you know
that said there are water-soluble
pesticides that will stay in the water
and not go into the oil but
unfortunately most of these you know
insecticides of Michael butanone a lot
of these things are very hydrophobic and
we'll concentrate any well you guys
missed it the second I mentioned that we
had a good chat room a troll came in it
was like you guys need to stop smoking
weed and get your get your lives
together oh that's what I was missing my
life oh gosh yeah what the heck well if
he was just tell me exactly what I
should do right yeah exactly I'm gonna
finish it with a bond rip we got 12
minutes left before it's noon
I got all these tasty bootlegs in my dat
recorder from like I bought this in 1995
in Missoula Montana and I just decided
you know what I'm gonna become a tapir I
should be a [ __ ] tapir 95 I've been to
quite a few shows already and I had a
hard time acquiring them and I wasn't
sure fish shows how did I find that in
Missoula how did I I know right how did
I what mark well I was just you said he
had been to a bunch of shows dad shows
or fish shows no it was fish shows it
was it was nice and I think to be honest
Jerry had been had passed already by
this point yeah okay or I was soft
for the first time in 93 but yeah I just
have all these old shows from like you
know here's a David Grisman that I tape
know like all the ones I have Marcus or
the Milky Way or the parodies oh oh I
know Sam years are amazing this is the
Missoula Montana show this was the first
recording I ever did on this dad ha ha
that's an incredible show oh yeah right
there was a there's tracks from that
show that are on the alive one their
live release
I think the tweezer from that night
might be the tweezer no that was from
Bangor Maine I was at that show you know
that see you look at that so yeah I knew
that was in 94 in Bangor Maine and I
took too many psychedelics at that show
in fact I thought it was just like okay
the guys like you want to eat some
mushrooms I'm like I would love to eat
some mushrooms he's like it's they're
pretty strong I'm like well just give me
a gram so I eat a gram of these
mushrooms
well apparently pretty strong okay so
I'm standing in line to get into this
concert and the sound of everyone
talking slowly morphs into mechanical
like crazy like spaceship sounds of like
a giant spaceship gearing up to take off
it was totally blowing my mind at that
point I thought this [ __ ] must have been
dipped in a much stronger psychedelic
because like no gram of mushrooms could
get me this high I've eaten enough five
gram doses to know this is gonna be envy
so I'm getting high the lineups getting
closer and closer as we get to the door
I realize they are searching people
harshly
okay there's like all these cops lined
up against the wall and there's patting
people down and I'm like holy [ __ ] like
I have a lot of stuff so I started
stuffing everything into my socks and I
don't really realize it but I basically
stuffed my bag of weed into my sock and
it gets caught up on my pant leg so it's
really just sticking out of my pant leg
and I'm super high I go up there they
Pat me down and don't see this plastic
bag apparently sticking out of my my
pant leg and then I walk by this like
long
long row at this point I'm like I'm I'm
in a psychedelic State
I can't even exactly tell like
everything's different than it should be
and these cops are all just looking at
me with the most serious look and man I
walked past them about 20 feet and
looked down and realized the bag was
hanging out and it was the beginning of
a very intense show and that's 29 or 30
one minute long tweezer yeah
mind numbing let me tell you yeah why I
was hassled going into the Palace
Theatre on my birthday this would have
been December 29th 1992 and I just got
back from Colorado and I had I we were
growing skunk number one so I had a nice
fresh bag of skunk number one in my
pocket and gotta take it away going in
to the show that night and really just
bummed me out because we on the way out
of the show we grabbed the bag out of
the garbage can where they made me
through the weed and we got a bunch of
[ __ ] that was confiscated at the tour
that night and ran around the back of
the theater and we're back there Marcus
and Paige walks out pace from the band
walks down the stairs and we're all down
there going through our oh yeah what we
got you know one man gathers with
another man spill so we we got like a
bull we got a bag of mushrooms got
everything that was confiscated at the
door that night we got because we
grabbed the trash and to dial that up to
this year I was going to see fish at
we're going in with my family at
Merriweather Post Pavilion and the young
kid told me to empty my pockets and you
know I just I pulled in my pocket and I
had you know the couple pre-rolls you
know inside a raw you know the raw cone
cardboard thing that they have a
I just had one of those with like two
J's in it and he's like he pointed to
the trashcan he's like in the trash I'm
like are you kidding me and he's like in
the trash and he had some other older
dude behind him with a walkie-talkie and
I wasn't gonna be held down for two
joints walking into a Phish show so I we
threw it in the trash and then my son
was just in on the other side and he's
like dad do you got these like now I got
him thinking what he's like dad what the
[ __ ] was like so we went to the show and
on the way out of the show sure enough
we walked through the same exit there on
the garbage can and it is the thing we
grabbed that [ __ ] [ __ ] job where
you're searching people on the way into
a concert and you're not letting them
take their weed or hash or cannabis
products into said concert you my friend
are a dick and especially in a place
like you know where you know cannabis
laws are changing everyone's got a vape
pen these days you figure oh this guy's
just got to pre-rolled joints and a
[ __ ] rock you know the thing you know
let him go in you know it's like no they
got to take it away they feel like
they're doing their job yeah
but the cool thing is I went back out
through the thing grabbed him and there
they were no that's very cool that's
kind of like being told you can't smoke
at a reggae show what the [ __ ] is that
right that's not how it works we
absolutely do Pop Festival in England it
was called the ready Pop Festival in
1971 and they it was expensive I forget
what it was you know twenty bucks or 30
bucks at the time to go for a couple
days festival and then I noticed what
they were doing is they were taking
everybody's taking tearing it in half
giving half to the person the other half
been referring in the
crash so with nobody was looking I took
about a thousand of them out of the
trash and they just handed them out to
everybody that's awesome
Johnny ticket seed there's an OG ticket
call a miracle music crash
that's some serious miracles
distribution well think about it most
people like can say like I gave a
miracle away like I personally have an
eighteen person miracle story but Sam's
got like well I gave away like I don't I
was like eight hundred miracles that's
awesome
well played Sam well played I need a
miracle everyday yeah bump I had
something I was gonna stay but I kind of
spaced it oh I did the hashtag song the
other day
oh I listened to it the other day it was
pretty funny yeah I answered I Marcus
you know how to do is like update the
lyrics right yeah well then I want to go
through it I say it the other day I was
like it made me think about Horatio and
Tony and Nicki you know all the people
that we used to be on you know yeah no
time
yeah I've seen Horatio literally since
he came no one time I integrati oh right
I have otherwise he's like on the
down-low right now what about Andrea
have you heard from him at all from who
Indra Indra John yeah yeah yeah I talked
to Indra yeah no I have I mean I'm in I
haven't talked to him in the last maybe
couple weeks but I talked to him more
often than not for sure right so how is
this extractor air extraction business
going or is there anything to report
that you can report on her it's a lot of
work for sure but there's he's
definitely got something really quite
amazing there as well so we're hoping on
you know getting a
in a way that can even be more amazing
so he's definitely there's no doubt
about you know what he said in the early
days you know that he had created this
fairly special thing it's a it's a
pretty special thing like it's
definitely producing product in the seed
oil and protein world for us that we're
quite happy about it's just a matter of
R&amp;D at this point yeah Andrew will be
back on again I'm sure
and what about Tony what's the latest on
him do you know I still am in a company
with him but as far as I've heard I
really don't know like I heard he won a
cannabis cup recently I know that you
can still rocking and rolling I'm sure
he's probably down in California running
his labs well if you go to you can cite
that I don't think he's he's he's part
of the team anymore it sounds like he's
no longer with you can is that right oh
[ __ ] I don't know yeah I just I was
wondering about Tony the other day and I
just I went to you can cite and I see it
talks about Ernie and you know some of
the other folks but it doesn't I don't
think Tony's mentioning it's not but
what he is is he still has some shares
and some of the companies but he needs
to he's promised he was gonna sell back
right well shares we all know how that
plays out I remember at one point you
can had $11 shares and I checked the
other day it was 49 cents that's gotta
be a wicked yeah it's just tough to play
that game I mean and I don't know like
if you look at some of these other
bigger players like the multinationals
now in the canopies and and whatnot I
mean what's gonna ultimately happen in
that you know especially with the FDA's
position now on on CBD you know so a lot
of Canadian huge Canadian companies are
scooping up licenses left and right here
in the States
it'll be interesting to see where this
goes more people make more money selling
shares of their companies then it's true
massive massive insane amounts of wealth
have been produced in that very fraud I
guess you could call it kind of to me
because you know there's so many I mean
there's still I feel like just in the
candidate in there like the the
leadership of the cannabis community in
each of the spaces each of the state's
you know they're they're lies this kind
of you know this two degree of Kevin
Bacon
kind of you know of the connection and
interconnection I think of a lot of the
the leaders in the community you know
and and I think there's massive strength
and kind of the the Solidarity among
that community you know their cannabis
is so long then based on trust and and
respect and kind of integrity in your
word you know like you can you know
hustling weed kind of somebody can rip
you off to rob you it's there's this
code of conduct I think that's really
kind of fallen off you know in this
invasion effort of capitalism into
cannabis and you know I really pray and
hope you know on this task church today
that you know we as a community can kind
of come together more and less see you
know each other in ways as competition
and kind of more you know really because
I think the real competitors haven't
came in yet you know obviously and and
they're waiting for the infighting and
all the failures you know because the
lack of capital or the you know kind of
the the vulture fund kind effort to come
just take over and kind of you know
transform these good ideas and good
people's business and to you know he's
pumpin up [ __ ] efforts to kind of just
raise money and capital with quick exit
strategies but you know I feel like you
know lost us understanding that there's
there's more kind of culture and
richness and in our community than we
could ever then they could ever bring
money into to take over and as long as
we can you gather and and and organize
in that way and you know kind of keep
that code of conduct on that high level
of integrity then I think we can also
you know in a way all kind of all boats
rise with the hot with the tide you know
and and we can come up Walt
you know they make their efforts but I
think a lot of those efforts are gonna
fall short and gonna fail
you know deploying that much capital to
scale cannabis businesses across so many
states and so many places I mean it's so
hard to grow fire herb and and subdue so
it's hubris thinking you're just gonna
mono crop it bigger than you've ever
gone without even ever having to go
through the understanding and issues of
all the pests and although you know it's
it's a futile effort and I think again
ultimately the plants control us and you
know the people with integrity that have
taken care of it Altima to come up as
long as we you know or they'll do stay
resilient and that said I wanna offer
universal shares in my company Universal
cannabis you just sold 8 billion shares
I got a quarter right here and that's 25
mil mark I got an eighth oh wait no I
mean history doesn't not only repeat
itself
history rhymes right we're think about
the end of alcohol prohibition the eve
of the end of alcohol prohibition in in
the US right and when they realized that
prohibition wasn't going to work anymore
and yeah I became a regulated distal and
all that [ __ ] but ultimately look
what it washed up to now you know yeah
there's Budweiser and there's these huge
manufacturers of all this swill crappy
product but there's this great
incredible craft beer industry and craft
distiller industry that will come along
with cannabis I think as long as there's
a consumer for it and as long as there's
enthusiasts like us and the people who
watch has Church I mean certainly like
yeah
just think of it like tomatoes right you
can grow your own to me
but you can go to the place and buy
tomatoes and that place is regulated by
the Department of Health and there's got
to be ISO certified blah blah blah
whatever ultimately that's where we're
gone it's going to be unregulated
completely it's gonna be like a craft
beer industry for the connoisseurs
there'll always be good high-quality
artisan cannabis and cannabis products
available just like there are really
heavy beers when it'll be good to beat
like sort of geographically specific to
those areas just like the heady beers
from Pacific Northwest and Colorado and
the ones in Virginia and elsewhere I
mean it's just it's a great analogy and
I think that's how things are gonna roll
out
well I want to understand degree there
mark and I really appreciate I
appreciate the I'm so much am grateful
to be part of this and just the level of
thought and understanding among all all
the hash church elders I'm really
grateful to even be part of this
conversation but you know did one one
thought on that you know I've been
wrestling with this quite a bit you know
with especially this whole hemp movement
and the conversation of make him again
you know in the conversion of all these
mono crop kind of it you know cottage
super contaminated spaces you know now
growing kind of CBD for human
consumption ultimately that could it be
bombed over the counter it's you know
buy a new kind of EP outfit P DEP
pediatric epilepsy patient you know it's
like there's you know and and obviously
I said what I'm about to say - I say so
fully mindful that I have a vested
interest in a testing laboratory but but
where I'm coming from and speaking from
is you know passionate servant to this
plant and seeing you know the botany of
desire the whole this whole you know
coevolution that's taking place you know
from us cultivating this plant and this
plant ultimately cultivating us you know
I think a great purpose of this plant is
really you know again this
bioaccumulation story it's to help bring
to the surface you know these are
invisible unknowns that you know are
important for us to restore human health
and and wellness you know which kind of
is such a parrot of but food is even
bigger a part of you know it's a food
grown in America
what percentage
the people that eat the food eat organic
food sure I wonder what I understand
that and and I won't understand degree
but does that mean that those people
aren't being poisoned you know when I
think they are being poisoned but my
question is I think that we are a small
market yeah well okay yeah no I agree
but we have the chance with this plant
coevolving us to radically affect and
disrupt agriculture to begin a process
to make food medicine again even though
whereas medicine is lead me to organic
living living soil and biodynamic
organic growing I was a farmer like that
before a group sure but my just just
follow me though on this thought you
know because this is the big a big kind
of you know thought I've been working on
and in my mind and reconciling just you
know in the service I'm I'm working on
on behalf of this plant now yeah I feel
like this plants a storyteller you know
through these regulations you we've put
on it it's telling the story just a
great story about what's happens to
legacy what's happened to land legacy
what's happened to our food system you
know the legacy of like helping to you
know deal with all these lawsuits in
effect right now around Monsanto like
12,000 lawsuits or empire state creating
cancer in people's life you know there's
this moment of awakening that's taking
place and cannabis can help with it yeah
this is Ayurvedic quickly when when diet
is in order
medicine is not of no need when diet is
out of order
medicine is of no use so you no matter
how much this medicine of cannabis can
help heal our body in our life and
repent we don't first change our diet
and radically remove the chemicals and
the poisons that are destroying our
microbiome that are creating the
systemic inflammation that's creating
the all the illness you know then you
know we're you what are we doing on
behalf of this plant there's all this
place to innovate make money and and and
you know what else is it's it's to help
change the world you know and and part
of that is to through the transparency
of what now you know because the
cannabis is the first crop that's ever
been regulated on this level every other
AG crop has been fully deer
everything has been so deregulated to
the point where our entire food system
is compromised and is poisoning us
pointing our children is poisoning lives
and and and and then the people that are
making the pesticides are the same
people selling the medicines through the
pharmacy
Bayer you know that are then kind of
like healing the ill which is just this
like the aren't people being farmed you
know like from the poisons in the food
so the by going to the doctor taking the
pharmacy that's then making him sicker
and and it says it's an endless cycle
and I feel like with cannabis we're
disrupting that you know we bring this
to the service it's helping to set an
example of food and change but and and
here's my last chlorine then this is the
biggest thing I was actually just trying
to say it's like I think we we have to
have this eternal vigilance you know as
leadership and elders in the cannabis
community to uphold this minimum quality
standard that have been put in place so
that we can kind of not only have a
barrier of entry for like you know the
thousand million acres in the Midwest
that you know the mega farms with the
super tractors or harvesting all the GMO
wheat it's like for them to just be able
to shift and grow CBD but then
ultimately is gonna go to children or
autistic people and patients or any
other person that's looking for cannabis
to help them it's like if we don't
uphold this minimum level of quality and
set the example for national
conversations around legalization and
what anybody has to meet if they want to
participate in the drug market of
selling medicine all cannabis to people
and patients through you know over big
box stores and Whole Foods it's like if
we don't uphold and set the example you
know like I mean Canada went even
stricter than California but there's
this there's this integrity I think with
the testing model that's helping to not
only hold any and everybody accountable
that wants to come in and take their
piece of cannabis but it's also helping
to create the path for this radical
revolution of Agriculture and Riaan
small farming kind of you know back to
you know and then and that's the rant
and I apologize but I just wanted to
have a lot more faith in common sense
and people's goodness than I do I think
people are incredibly clumsy and stupid
don't lose the hope broke
now I appreciate the perspective for
sure I need to do a few things quick
because we're over the 12 o'clock thing
and I gotta go here soon but I needed to
ask Sam in regards to purchasing stream
out of the UK do you remember which one
the 43 T was in micron yeah
43 s were very small like a full size
like 40 50 micron or something or more
like 70 I don't remember if it was the
thread measurement per centimeter or
inch or person ask is wrong cuz we did
not she he wrote all that [ __ ] down and
me
all's I did I remembered that you know a
77 is what you wanted for collected
resin and a 43 is what you put on top on
top of when you learn to get rid of
everything that's too small to be good
right so it was probably a 70 micron 43
is 70 and then the 77 is like 150 or 160
microti or whatever that has to do with
the thickness of the thread yeah the
thread diameter exactly and that
determines the ratio of hole versus the
ratio of screen on the surface area mark
I believe it's lines LPI lines per inch
so the greater number the greater
threads per we have lines per inch and
mesh are the same LPI and mesh are the
same but the T's and the S is the 43 s
and the 77s from the UK is some other
Rando super like huh
I used to buy a twist 9 bolt and twist
poly Mon 77 either an S or a tea trees
okay well I just wanted to get that off
then I also wanted to say a shout out
and maybe a bong rip because this
probably be the last thing I say today
to one of our longtime like since the
beginning of hash Church she was there
in the chat room he went by a pot smoker
and I guess he pet he passed away
recently so he's we thought we would
give him a nice little send-off thanks
for being a part of the hash church
community bro sorry to see you go but I
guess we all have an expiry date so
let's puff a little bowl for a pot
smoker
r.i.p a pot smoker perfect it it is
there a better sound better on the zoom
as opposed to the other one with the
left he's gone
[Music]
[Applause]
thanks much mark that was the best
ending to a great Hastert thanks
everybody
peace out thank you Marcus
thank you now all right oh that was fun
thanks guys