recording in progress well you know what
that means everybody it means welcome to
Hash Church season
11 episode two yes today is episode two
I've got a room full of people that I'm
going to let in here today we got a bit
of a special episode today we're doing a
one of the suggestions from Caleb one of
our newest panelists who was uh studying
music in cannabis and he thought
wouldn't it be cool to do a music and
cannabis episode so look no further
we're here to do a music and cannabis
episode uh Caleb's invited a bunch of
different people from the water boys to
Mendo Dope to a bunch of other really
cool folks I invited only a few myself
but um for this particular conversation
I really wanted to invite some of my
Jamaican Breen and so uh Kazam Davis
who's in the room right now reached out
to me now Kazam hasn't really been
playing music a lot for the last few
years but he was deeply involved for a
very long time at a time when I was
spending a lot of time in Jamaica I feel
like I met Kazam through the LI Joe crew
which uh there was this guy Joe and he
was just amazing he was kind of taken
off his music was blowing up it's really
powerful music uh you know hair on the
back of the neck standing up and Joe
unfortunately had uh brain aneurysm and
he passed away I believe he was 26 or 27
years old um and there was this whole
crew of amazing musicians that I met
through through Joe's brother
CA and uh Kazam you would remember his
other brother's name Gideon Gideon and
CA so those were the two brothers I went
to their house that's where I met as
well as um Rebel salute I met a ton of
amazing people from uh gez I going
through the whole name I have a video
that I'll show maybe a little bit later
on but that's who Kazam Davis is so um I
want to welcome Christopher Carr into
the room as well and Dan who just showed
up as well as Caleb Chen how you doing
this morning
Caleb doing well excited for
today shout out to Kazam and Chris and
Dan for showing
up say GRE greetings family just fix my
Bluetooth here I'm having a little bit
of technical difficulty
days blessed love from Santa Cruz giving
thanks and Praises every time oh thanks
and Praises man
always H hash Church we're we're coming
correct on a on a very special day yeah
absolutely man and shout out to uh shout
out to everyone in La going through this
crazy scene is that you Kazam you
speaking what's up
brother enough love and respect you know
greetings everyone Caleb yeah mans my
family nice nice nice meeting everyone
you know yeah man nice to meet you as
well gez it's it's got to be it's got to
be 10 or 15 years since I met you I feel
like I met you through the that whole
Rebel salute I feel like I met your wife
before I met you actually yes you did
there she is yes Lorraine how are you
doing how are you oh you're remember my
name of course I remember listen I feel
like I met you before you were
mummy you did yeah I met you before you
were mummies so that's amazing I hope
you guys are doing wonderful and it's
nice to have you guys on the show today
and sharing this was yeah just you know
a little music a little cannabis a
little conversation I felt like to have
a conversation about music and cannabis
it would be difficult not to have
someone representing from
Jamaica thanks so yeah you know Caleb
has done some cool little um you know
deep Dives on cannabis we were talking
last week about uh C weed and how he
started looking for this you know term C
weed in music and how he found so many
different people using it in songs and
titles and he ended up saying that it
was um it was a lot had come from
Germany if I'm not mistaken Caleb that
you found the most songs were coming out
of Germany with that term and I thought
well the most songs that the most songs
that use ganja have to come out of
Jamaica there's just no I don't even
have to do the work I just know that uh
that the most songs have to be coming
out of Jamaica I have been so blessed so
blessed with my experience uh in Jamaica
over the years years ago a good friend
of mine by the name of Jose toku
he took over this
YouTube uh site called onair FM and he
said listen I've got this site these two
guys are from the Czech Republic they
wrote all the code and this was about
helping musicians monetize their music
on YouTube you can obviously do it
yourself which I monetize my YouTube and
it's done by myself but there's
companies that can do it and they can
kind of bring you in um and help
monetize your music so I my buddy was
like Hey do you think could help me I'm
going to go to Central and South America
I've got some other friends that are
going to be going to Europe I'm
wondering if you wouldn't mind going to
Jamaica and so we ended up renting a
booth I brought a a rosta friend of mine
uh from California with me to do the
interviews and we went to Rebel salute
in Jamaica in MO Bay and I'm telling you
we met everyone it really started that
was crazy it started with the nomads
with sheppy and and Evie
and bir these were the first these were
the first guys and they were different
you know they were not like they were
just different they stood out they had
these crazy suits on they had these real
pointy shoes and I would learn later
that they were really like an they were
like an acting troop this group of guys
more they were they were musicians but
also actors right Kazam yes we went to
to edner the same performing Heart
School not Edam but I went to said
performing arts school M for music and
Performing Arts and they would often
came come there to get couple of their
um their programs done at Edna at exed
yes exed and Edna they took me to Edna
Manley School of the the acting school
we went and saw Protege when he
performed his album from start to finish
and he brought all the artists out and
it was pretty cool to be at the school
with the Nom ads and they're introducing
me to all the teachers and all the
different people so really incredible
experience and then of course to meet up
with all of you guys through that whole
Li Joe group and there was so many of
you guys when we when we um we brought
these guys all over to the penthouse um
bar at this hotel in Kingston Jamaica
yeah in New Kingston so they all came
over and the video is on YouTube I'll
have to put it in the chat people could
see dude it was so good man like Dexter
maloi I mean can you Hess hempress
sativa was there you know Kazam micaa
was there micaa Shaman was there Shay
yeah I I so so many amazing musicians
and they just performed and they
performed from their soul and it was so
powerful I remember actually like
tearing up at that performance of uh
this jux toos of these real
yard folks you know Jamaican yardis like
real local you know Roots reggae people
we're at this hotel that's like where
all the business people stay in Kingston
like the suits you know but we're all
the roots representing and it was just
uh I'll tell you man I think about that
moment in time a lot it was uh it was
special to me man that was a real
special time trust me my brother it was
really a heaven send Vibes you know and
trust me how you guys because even you
talk about lorine at um re salute how we
went into re salute that was by with
with a camera none of us
paid we just knock in with a camera and
let I love
backstage we just take over backstage
like we are the main artist
performing well I'll tell you I saw
chronics that year and he really did
kind of become the main act that year
that was the year that was really the
year
chronics blew up he really blew up I
remember meeting him there he had that
little tiny backpack on and he was so
young I don't know how old he was but he
was
young so special and then to be able to
go over to Billy's place the surfing
place over over in Kingston there and
yeah Billy Mystic and there was like uh
the nomads brought me some places there
that's where I met kabaka pyramid and
abash and all of those Brethren just
amazing awesome people man yes holy [ __ ]
I'll tell you anyone that sings about
cannabis and is into music absolutely
needs to spend some time in Jamaica it
is musically I have never I mean one
time I was I was filming with CIP PE do
you know this Breen CIP PE sort of
artist c yeah c exactly so I was filming
with cie p and we were in some little
studio in Kingston you know one of
10,000 studios in Kingston Jamaica and
uh he's spitting and then you know
another guy standing there he's like oh
hey could I do could I spit something
and then this other guy spits and he was
amazing and then there's another guy
sitting in the shadows in the corner of
this you know kind of Outside Inside
studio just this guy was like invisible
and then he was like Hey man can I spit
something and then he popped up and just
it was like more Talent more Talent more
Talent the level of talent that you guys
have in Jamaica and I'm certain it's
connected to the suffering and it's
connected to the perspective of love and
abundance instead of fear and scarcity
it's dude I can't say enough about it
man I I I love you guys circumstances
make us who we are you know and and the
reality and the reality is that you know
Jamaica is like a open portal for for
creativity for it's like everybody in
Jamaica is a is a artist it's
so look at it that way you know it's so
true it's the first country I ever went
to when I was standing at the bus stop I
went in 1995 and I was standing on the
bus stop waiting to get on the bus which
was an amazing experience in its own I
remember the guy next to me had a little
piece of wood in his hand and I was like
I was like I wonder what he's going to
do with that like why is he just
carrying a little piece of wood uh
around with him but it he was put he put
it between two seats and made himself a
seat on this bus that we you know we put
like 30 people on this little bus that
fits like
11 but before we got on the bus you
would think that we were at a Sizzla
concert this guy had his his boom box
going and Sizzla was pounding and he's
singing every lyric and he's dancing
almost violently like and my wife was
like what is going on and I I was like I
think we're in Jamaica I think we're in
Jamaica sweetie this what's up like I
just love the energy and the you know in
North America sometimes we don't even
want to look at each other in the eye
when we walk by each other we don't want
to like we don't want to express our
love and our joy and you know we're
we're sometimes easier to express uh you
know dismay and and pain and anguish but
in Jamaica once again this place where
clearly you know people have less more
than more like Peter said some live in
big but most live in small is that what
Peter said yes sir BR cost of living is
is crazy here in Jamaica but we somehow
as a
people don't don't seem to make it
bother us I don't know how we do it when
the whole when the whole when the rest
of the world will Rebel if the prices of
gas gone up by one cent yeah say yeah
man we you know but make we nice but
trust me trust me you chopping up wood
weed right now right nor I
[Music]
can't I wish I had some real good herbs
y oh dude we should have got there's a
shortage here in Jamaica no there's a
short that is crazy
bro that is makes zero sense no good
herban it's like Jamaica in the past
10 years now has been into
into cush like you know indoor herbs and
oh you
know like crazy now more than ever yeah
well guys like Charlie or Archie guys
like
Archie for those of you that don't know
Archie Archie is one of the best indoor
growers in Jamaica he's uh he's he's the
man he's the first person to give me a
Pon a weed to BR hell yeah dude he's
such a good person man listen when I met
Archie years listen I don't know why I
meet everyone but I always meet everyone
and I met Archie and then maybe a year
later I met jaure and Kure was like oh
you got to meet my brethren nobody knows
him I keep them hidden and he brings
this guy to the table and I'm like
that's Archy man we know him for five
years and he was just like how how do
you know this
guy when everybody else was was dealing
with think the Archer was actually
learning about this right now cushion he
was ahead of the game way ahead of the
game listen he was the first person I
ever went into a grow in Jamaica inside
the house where he was just growing weed
inside his house and it was like
beautiful like OG Kush like he had
beautiful plants growing inside and it
was it might have been the weirdest
thing I've ever seen in Jamaica to be
honest it just seemed seemed so like
strange and off the the the charts and I
just remember his little daughter
walking around and this you know these
bright lights I was like wow man this
guy is like ahead of his time time bro
very cool because I check him couple
couple months ago I was with him when I
linked you couple months ago and tell
you that I wanted to start doing getting
get you know being educated about the
herb and I went to Archie of course he
I'd love to get link ups with Archie
again I lost his number if you give give
him yeah or just give him mine I think
he likes that better give him mine so he
can reach out to me but uh this is
important too so Kazam one of the
reasons I brought Kazam on here today
was that he's looking to do some interns
some mentorships he's looking to learn
more about cweed and plugging in and
gaining more access and I thought well
you know what this is a great panel of
people Santa Cruz come by Cruz build
bridge I'm gonna link you guys up I'm
gonna link you guys up so you all Chris
and Kazam and Dan and DJ Caleb I want
you guys to have access to Kazam he's
really really good people and anything
we can do to uh uh you know help
facilitate his inspiration
of yeah dude there there you
go there you go welcome welcome DJ hard
hitter how you doing my brothers how
y'all doing man coming to you live from
Houston Texas peace representing from
Houston that's I'm getting my right now
I'm in
the they know how to Puff in Houston let
me tell you yeah it's the largest city
in America that's still under the
prohibition you know yeah well listen to
this I'll tell you something about Texas
for years people would hit me up and
they'd be like oh man like there's no
good hash like I'm in Texas and I'd be
like listen there is so much good hash
in Texas the problem is these
[ __ ] protect that [ __ ] they're
not exposing themselves like maniacs
from California they're still living
under the they're still living under the
thumb of the man so you can't be like
bragging and showing pounds of hash and
big you got you got to be lowkey you
know even though lowkey you got to be a
little lowkey so I will say this about
Texas they are probably tied with New
York State for the state that I sent the
most bubble bag too so obviously
California's number one for hash bags
but the the second most bags that I ever
sent anywhere is like a tie between
Texas and New York and so Texas is is
certainly representing it's just uh yeah
they don't they don't [ __ ] around in
Texas I remember when it was really bad
years ago it was like 10 it was like
Alabama it was like 10e mandatory
minimums if you got caught with anything
in Texas it just like w bam 10 years
inis prison holy [ __ ] 10 years like what
a [ __ ] crime to put habitual florist
go ahead DJ check it out well this is
what you got to understand in the state
of Texas any it's been like this for
years because I got caught with some
weed before so anything under 50 pounds
can be reduced to a simple possession or
claimed as personal use so they might
they might initially charge you with
possession of marijuana with the intent
to distribute which is a felony but they
but if it's under 50 pounds they'll take
the with intent off and it's just simple
position which is a mystery damn that's
amazing that's like the best news I've
heard in a long time no doubt listen in
Canada when I got arrested with 16
pounds this was in
1998 my maximum
sentence was 25 years in prison
that's that's what I was facing now no
one had ever gotten that in Canada it
wasn't something that was like we were
handing out like free candy on Halloween
like they do in some states but it still
was on the book so when I got arrested
and charged and this that and the other
thing and then I asked my lawyer hey
like what's the worst that can happen
and he's like well don't freak out but
the worst that can happen is is 25 years
in prison I was just like don't freak
out listen if you think I'm white now
you should have seen how [ __ ] white I
was when he told me that I am talking
every drop of color fell from I was just
like 25 years but I thought we were in
Canada so it took him about a a week to
talk me off the ledge he was like listen
in the meantime Mark emer's facing the
death penalty in America and he's just
like this is how worried Mark was he's
like I'll go down there I'll sort this
out I'll figure it out I'll just go down
and and face the music and I was just
like dude listen I would run for the
rest of my life before I went down to
America and let them put me in prison
for like my entire life so Props to
Texas for changing that that's amazing
up to 50 pounds can be ruled simple
possession yeah personal use it's it's
been like that for quite a
while wow that is really crazy hey it's
crazy welcome go ahead Kazam I'm sorry
it's 2 O you can travel with those 2 o
no no
50 I wish I wish but like like like like
what I have not I have a sacramental
license right that allows me to grow
ganja for 5 years distribute it whatever
I want to do mm yeah but I'm affiliated
with a briging called
rager um and you know so whatever I do I
you know we communicate in a in a sense
okay okay that's good and so when you
talk about the sacramental use of
cannabis like uh maybe we'll get into
this conversation a little bit here you
know how important and I I mean I know
the answer but I kind of like to have
your words how important is the musical
component of the
sacramental use of cannabis because it
seems like no group of people
has
more you know music than Jamaica to sort
of represent and sing about the absolute
love of cannabis it seems like it goes
even deeper than a love of cannabis it's
a true spiritual connection yeah it is
it is B it's it's it's it's it's it's a
deep rooted thing within you know it's
like it's like Jamaicans not having herb
it's like not having life B and with
music it just goes hand in hand herb
food and music see see it's it's it's
way spiritual it's
way I mean you know bro you see me you
know comeing here in Jamaica and see you
you you have said it you know and every
household every every you 95% of make
SM yeah true
you that's that's a fact whether you're
Uptown you're downtown Rich poor you
know hey monkey monkey in the chat room
is asking if you were in The Humble
Jamaica sativa unicorn
video I think that's say it by dub
club might be I have to ask him you're
like I don't know I've been in a hundred
I mean
family you know so yeah well that was
the cool thing that you guys always did
when I linked up with you guys and that
whole chronics and kabaka and Protege
and Dexter maloi and Kazam and M all of
these people what I really thought was
cool was every time you guys filmed a
video you'd put it out into Kingston and
be like we're gonna film a video we're g
to be here doing the new Protege video
and everyone you remember those old days
where kabaka and chronics and everyone's
in
prot video I thought that was pretty
cool
man hold it together someone's asking
what's the dude's name with the blue
hole in Jamaica well that would be my
good friend Wabba Wabba that's who
you're thinking you know Waba Kazam in
where Portland yeah in West Morland West
mland no no no I Portland I think that's
brother Esau who has that
one oh the blue hole but you got to know
we got to link you up with Wabba cuz
Wabba has the fire herb and he's very
linked and connected and uh I'm
definitely going to link you up with
Wabba he is good people and you want to
go see the Blue Hole take your family
and go hang out in this blue hole it's
so good man that's is in West Morland
yeah it's in West Morland man it's in or
like close to Orange Hill know about
that I know I'm tell I'm telling you
dude it's crazy wob has been in my
videos he's linked up with uh gez with
with most people I'm hoping ktis is at a
birthday party today in Kingston I
believe he's with Chen and I'm hoping
they might come in just for a short
period of time for those of you that
don't know kitsi and China Earl chinna
Smith these guys are legendary China is
probably on like like 500 to a thousand
albums with his guitar he's literally
from another planet this guy and then
ktis is just ktis I I couldn't say
enough uh good about ktis he's just one
of my favorite people to hang out with
in Jamaica and shout out to Jeff I free
for linking me up with K is so many
years ago and I'd love to hear from some
of the other folks in the room man maybe
an introduction from Christopher Carr oh
and Sam has something to say real quick
what's I just wanted to say that
everybody knows
wobba yeah everybody knows
Waba
Christopher yeah yeah give thanks um I
was just thinking to what Kazam was
saying about like Urban Music is like
mother's milk for the soul and and and
feeding their soul good nutrients you
know good herb good music um and being
Muse worthy I think that's something
that's been connected throughout here in
Santa Cruz I play with a Roots group
called ancest tree tree tree tree
growing Roots here in rosta Cruz and
yeah I play bass and so getting in the
pocket and playing with the Rhythm
Section and getting into the drums in
the bass something that's really
important to me and and locking in
drummer than the heartbeat I think ganja
is one of the ways I can build that
connection even if it's jamming with
just new players new rhythms um it's
like a place you can go with herb and
and you know you could truly transport
your your Consciousness and that's
something I feel like we need to not
only feed our bodies like I loved what
you said food urb and music that for me
is like Mind Body
Spirit and yeah music and Herb that's
kind of that Spirit piece uh but herb is
also body and mind and and to continue
to create and be an instrument of
creation I think it takes really good
herb and music um and so we definitely
feel that connection here in Santa Cruz
we've been performing on the west coast
uh since 2010 we started on Bob Marley's
birthday in 2010 and Eight studio albums
and we love to facilitate um our
Brethren sister from Jamaica we had
yardcore come through during the
pandemic through a big yeah yardcore big
big party um and every Harvest it's uh
you know we just give thanks to to have
another year with the with the seasons
with the seeds and the and the flowers
here home in the hay here in in Santa
Cruz and skunk um awesome to see
skunkman Sam on the call but yeah I'm
just I'm just honored to not only
perform and create music but to be tied
to the community of music and working
with Ali and different nightclubs here
in in Santa Cruz it's a big honor to
continue to facilitate and same with um
ganja I think it's the in interwoven
piece to the ongoing uh evolution of of
the human Community is Urban Music
enough the
sh
SE I have I come at it from a different
aspect you know I'm a DJ so so when I
smoke weed it just puts me in a
different realm my song selection just
becomes so much greater it's like it's
like it enhances the moood for me and
and a lot of the party gos a lot of the
times I won't even take the gig if I
can't smoke in it you know but how
however weed is you know when you when
you when you when you smoke good weed
you know good weed it it it takes the
edge y it puts you in a euphoric State
and I could just go on playing music for
hours and hours and
hours yes sir that is so true DJ that's
so true bro that is so true
my especially the definition of good
herbs you know yeah if it's bump then my
sit is wet I can't do
it oh my God is why that is why I really
had to reach out to Bubba remember CU I
know he he really had some knowledge and
over the years I've been thinking about
doing this getting myself involved in
herb and cannabis but
musically I was thinking and tring a
different path
musically but I always in my back of my
mind say y I wanted to deal with I want
to deal with herbs I want to find way
how to you
know get it out there and plant it and
everything that I can learn and get it
done you know and so we can help myself
and have hollers and do what we're doing
there's a lot to learn about it I'll
tell you that much I have a question for
you what what was the first wide Leaf
herb that you saw in Jamaica in other
words a a Hindu Kush or Afghan or skunk
or
whatever skun definitely skunk
yeah oh I I gave skunk seeds to uh
aiman's crew pretty
early aaman remember aiman damn I
remember dude listen listen when I met
skunkman Sam Kazam who bred the skunk
number one who you're talking to right
now he had the most insane reggae
collection actually we rented a house
and went to Jamaica and spent some time
there and you know enjoyed all the
concerts went saw like tons of great
concerts made great hash just had these
wonderful experiences but yeah people at
first you know of all the people in
Jamaica like skunkman Sam like what
cultivar what strain have you heard
people say the name of more in Jamaica
than skunk it's
like crazy maybe maybe Hayes because uh
when I used to give skunk to the aimon
crew I did it a couple years in a row
they used to tell me that they called it
uh China weed because it was sort of
yellow and
short more like Most Wanted or something
like that Most Wanted
exactly dude I I grew up on skunk skunk
punk I see my father's
rolling like literally having weed in
them room and man WRA up B and
Bing I've
been I've seen I've seen all of it so
you know
and as kman is saying now really and
truly what I see people asking for now
is
runs runs yeah runs has a quite a quite
a strong uh flavor profile everybody's
asking for runs it it it is a hash
producer when you when I made the last
runs I
ran I got a 30% return dry you hear that
Dr Mark 30% without the use of solvents
from like that even when I get that
yield I feel like I'm lying to myself is
is that dry siip it no this was water
hash Kevin from Royal Harvest came over
to my house he brought this red velvet
runs was the cultivar and he brought a
bunch of ones and I would have never
picked this one to be the one that G I
ran 100 gram of his flour and in fact I
actually got a little over 30% but when
we weighed and it all was said there was
a little bit that we smoked that we
didn't weigh but we weighed and had 30
full grams and that was after it was
dried after the hash was dried exactly
yeah yeah I always like to make sure
that my U that is truly amazing whereas
with dry sift with skunk number one I
got 2% if I want to clean it up to
99.9 that's really
low it's really low but it's uh it's
worth it especially if you've got you
know Unlimited Supply of herb and you
want hash yeah exactly Caleb I want to
put sort of get bring it over to you I
know that we just sort of kind of uh got
into a long conversation I hadn't seen
Kazam in a while but we caught up a
little bit and if there's any sort of
Direction you had or some questions you
had maybe for some of the panelists or
maybe we want to do more introductions
whatever you guys want I'm super chill
I'm loving the Vibes yeah I think
introductions would be good we haven't
heard from Dan from Rebel grown yet I
saw people shouting out the uh double OG
pem in the chat and also haven't heard
from uh Dr Mark yet I think uh be cool
if everyone kind of introduced like when
they came to form a relationship with
the plant and you know maybe what music
they may have been listening to what
genre of music at that time I think we
have a pretty wide variety here of
people really dedicated to different uh
genres and we can find some commonality
with the weed here um so yeah Dan could
you give a little
intro yeah um just wanted to say I
appreciate the invite so my first time
getting to participate on uh hash church
and uh
yeah I mean I've been very passionate
about music since I was really
young I started getting into music when
I was probably five or six years old uh
Michael Jackson uh was the first big
influence in my life so when I was a kid
I used to dress up as Michael Jackson
and dance around and [ __ ] but what I
think about uh the connection between
cannabis and music is that I really look
at cannabis as an amplifier it amplifies
everything that's happening internally
emotionally spiritually um and so with
music which is already so important to
us you know when you're using good
cannabis it just amplifies that
experience it makes it such a a profound
connection and so when I was a kid I
wanted to be like a rock star and then
when I was eight years old I I heard
Easy E um and so like my big musical
influences when I was a kid was Michael
Jackson Axel Rose and e e and then I
discovered regate music and and Bob
Marley and um especially you know my
early you know before I was a teenager
teen AG you know mid 20s um you know
Jamaican culture was really inspiring to
me um so yeah I've had a long history of
Music in cannabis since I was like 12 13
years old and that's really what I've
committed a lot of my life to I don't
have a lot of other things in my life um
normal things like you know Vacations or
other things but uh you know I don't go
around saying that I'm good at a lot of
things but the two things that I think
that I can contribute is cannabis and
and music music um I I do hip-hop I
write and I rap um I've been doing that
29 years um just put out some new music
so first debut was put out in August um
it's on band camp if anybody wants to
check out my music uh there's like a
five song EP uh but I've got over 25
years worth of of recordings and so I'm
actually in my studio right here this
studio in 2015 uh 2014 when I was in
Humble still um and this was rented out
the space here was rented out to record
labels different like independent labels
this is on a a 200 acre off-grid
property in the Northeast Kingdom of
Vermont um and so it was meant to be an
artist Retreat uh where people from
Brooklyn and and the city could you know
these labels could book the space for a
month and send their artists and bands
here to you know decompress and get away
from cell service and so the studios had
a couple floods you know some issues but
everything here is still functional I've
actually got this really cool uh eight
track uh channel from a SSL that
apparently Legend man that part of the
SSL apparently came from a Prince's
studio um when he died and his Studio
was broken down so apparently that's
what I heard but anyway yeah so I I
appreciate being you know invited to
join the conversation I love to smoke
good herb um I've been um searching for
the best herb I can find my whole life
and have been making seeds and breeding
the last 15 years and have some cool
stuff and some great accolades like to
smoke good strong herb um my brand used
to be called ganja Rebel U because ganja
to me was such a powerful word I just
felt like the attachment and connection
between everything that that ganja and
the herb represented was really
important I took the the ganja out you
know when weed was becoming legal and
just made it Rebel grown so like this is
how you know us if you see this Leaf you
know us Rebel
grown nice dude I liked everything that
you said I was like dude this guy's like
my friend and I haven't met him yet
we haven't met no but I'm sure we have
several you know acquaintances mutual
acquaintances and happy to be in the in
the conversation with you guys and
looking forward to smoking some herb and
having a nice relaxing Sunday very cool
man very cool welcome gota
say very cool Dr
Mark what about you Mr Mark shalone what
hey I know how important music is in
your
life yeah yeah well it's
uh I said this before at hash church I
think you know music is my religion and
you know I was a kid who grew up uh
following the Grateful Dead around and
you know I when when I first started
smoking weed yeah it was you know I I
knew
some uh some of my friends who had older
siblings and they knew you know the
so-called weed dealers and it was was
mostly like yeah Brown Mexican weed or
we rarely had really you know s rarely
we had sensia but you know at the dead
show uh I would smell a different kind
of weed being smoked and it was all that
dank Bud from Northern California that
came out on Grateful Dead tour that I
think spread kind bud across the country
you know I really do think that the
Grateful Dead um would just this
traveling circus that we went to in the
late 70s and 80s it was so [ __ ] cool
man I was like I graduated high school
in
1981 and I lived in Suburban New York
City in northern New Jersey and it was
just so easy to go and see the Grateful
Dead um they would play in in New York
City they'd play in like Syracuse and
New Haven Connecticut and Binghamton New
York and down in Phil at the Spectrum so
it was just so easy to you know take a
two-hour ride and this was before cell
phones and before you know so many
things that you know we take for granted
now but yeah we would really just not
even have tickets and just show up at
the shows and somehow scramble get
tickets at the last minute and go see
the shows and you know for those of us
who were alive to see Jerry Garcia
perform it was just a real amazing
um almost religious experience
because every because because you were
on
acid no I I don't think so a lot of
people who were there who were straight
and there were a lot of people there who
were just smoking weed and not doing
psychedelics but there's just yeah an
incredible the Psychedelic aspect of it
was unbelievable would you not say that
that was like yeah but like I don't
think I've seen it since I mean the way
try describes it is like he remembers
when he first saw Bruce Springstein
right in 1978 at the Spectrum in Philly
and every person in that concert was
locked on to that one guy on stage and
that's the same way it was with with the
grateful Dad and Jerry Garcia he had
everyone's attention in that room and I
think the Grateful dad changed the way
live music is played and yeah I think
cannabis and psychedelics had a big
thing to do with it because they were
the you know the Pioneers from the San
Francisco sound that got involved with
key and the pranksters during the early
days of the acid tests and their
soundman you know bear the guy that they
named you know the dancing bear or the
marching Bears or you know Bears Choice
uh he was the you know Dropout chemist
who basically turned on a whole
generation on LSD by Purity LSD I think
they're still doing some of this Stash
from ousley's uh lab but you know I mean
make a long story short Marcus I don't
think weed I mean like like when I think
about it like even like hash even like
good high quality nugget I mean when you
were living in suburan New York uh you
can go more easily buy an eight Bott of
coke by some dealer just on the street
you know in Manhattan and come back to
your party in Suburban New Jersey and
completely uh
own the party but it was just difficult
to get good weed and you'd be able to
get these little $10 and $15 manila
envelopes of of mostly seeds and stems
and a little bit of brown weed you're
lucky if you could get a joint out of
like this little $10 dime bag so you
know the the Dead really were the ones
that brought good weed to the east coast
I don't think there's any question about
it there would not be the appetite for
deep
I mean uh chem dog has a Grateful Dead
um uh Genesis right so PUD and G first
met at a Grateful Dead show in 1991 in
Deer Creek they exchanged numbers they
exchanged weed next thing you know you
know Greg out in Massachusetts pops
these beans that end up becoming Cham
dog so I mean that's that's a Grateful
Dead uh connection I mean they connected
at a Grateful Dead show so yeah I mean I
so so that's my story I mean I think
that yeah there's probably a lot of
people with the same story but you'd be
able to go to a dead show Marcus and
hook up with acid and hook up with good
weed and then bring that back to your
town and they'll be like holy [ __ ] where
did you get all these good drugs and
it's like oh at the parking lot at the
Grateful Dead show you can get anything
right Shakedown Street right so down
street was responsible for some of the
best uh cannabis connections you know
some of the best genetic lines were as a
result of people having good times at
Shakedown Street for the whole country
it's is that's a really positive
connection with weed and music is how
music brings people together and same
with ganja right like you always have
that Circle the international
herb yeah for me it was just like I I
couldn't believe first of all that this
incredible weed existed and it seemed as
though again there was like this
cultural aspect tied to well it's
cultivated in Humble or in mesino you
got to be out there and so I had a lot
of friends who grew up in the east coast
in the midwest who migrated to Oregon
and Northern California because they
wanted to grow the weed that they smoked
on Grace dead tour and I I have a back
Seed story from summer tour in 1991 I
hooked up with my friend Ron the pizza
man from Shasta and he hooked me up with
a bag of Big Sir holy nug and it was
just these incredible buds man they were
so so dense and out of that came two
seeds which we popped like two years
later at a grow that I I first started
growing weed in the summer of 1992
Marcus right after fish tour um we were
growing some some weed in Fort Collins
and uh yeah we popped those seeds and
and yeah it was you know Grateful Dead
tour just a cultural phenomena we we
knew each other it was through the music
but it was through our appreciation of
psychedelic experiences and good weed
and good food so all those elements that
you guys were just talking about you
know the food the music the weed it was
just intersected in this lifestyle that
you know basically lived to the
soundtrack of the Grateful Dead I don't
know how else to describe
it hey what's up Dr Mark by the way you
remember me do you remember meeting me
yes Dan Dan we so we're kind of like at
a Vermont connection so uh well you
could are you back in Vermont or no you
were in Vermont but you're out or are
you in or you out I go back and forth
quite a bit but I'm here now and then
I'll be headed back to California in
February but come get some herb yeah
absolutely absolutely so Dan's a
producer here in our little uh economy
of Vermont here so how's it going Dan I
know it's stressed a lot of other people
out of the business what's that just the
Vermont Market how's it going here I
think it's getting it's getting better
man you know we're you know I I only
want to be judged by the the quality of
my herb and the character of my my
person you know and um so I think it's
going good we have really good exciting
herb to share and uh
yeah awesome well good to reconnect with
you
definitely and good to share great weed
definitely definitely definitely I want
to uh dive in there on like so Dr Mark
you were talking about how the Grateful
Dead Shakedown Street kind of spread the
knowledge of kind bud around the country
and like fast forward to like my first
time smoking in
2010 and um you know in Virginia kind
bud was like the top tier bud so what
was very common was we'd be receiving
the BC bud
you know the kind that was already
sifted had no trikes on it and then
people would sell it as kind bud the
Beast kind bud the beers exactly beers
were being sold as kind bud even though
they clearly weren't but no one really
knew the difference and there's been a
lot of I guess um you know name switches
that that could happen um and I guess
different tiers of weed that kind of uh
the information about the different
tiers of weed gets out through music so
kind bud is a great example um perhaps
some of the more uh perhaps people would
like to talk about like how did the
reputation of
Indo become like as a higher tier item
because over time right there was a
point in time when everyone was smoking
outdoor and then there becomes a point
in time when now I guess depending on
which Camp you're in indoor might be
considered the higher tier versus
outdoor love to get people's thoughts on
that and how music may or may not have
influenced that
okay I'll start you know my first time
smoking weed was like in
1994 I think I was about 15 years old
and we and Snoop Doggy Dog and Dr Dre
came out with the chronic Nothing But a
G thing and I'm telling you everybody
wanted to sip Jin Jin and juice and
smoke a blunt and then when they and
then they came out with with a song
called rolling down the street smoking
in
sing I listened to it
yesterday hey I'm telling you music
influences culture and that and that
definitely influenced our culture down
here in Houston because you know like it
seemed like everybody wanted to know
somebody from Texas so they could get
cheap weed or something like that or
other drugs you know but for us you know
I I think like uh the the the actual drw
the actual Kelly Kush I think it hit
Houston last I think it hit us about
2005 however we had this stuff called
red hair
SES and aapco gold and to get that down
here Houston was
like like something like like it was a
very
rare a very rare set of buds that you
could get and we would get and if you
were able to get a hold of that and jam
Snoop Doggy Dog doggy style or Dr J's
The Chronic you know
thing yeah a little bit of that too but
it was the it was the it was the Snoop
Doggy Dog man it was it was him he did
it he transed that one for us that's
true yeah it's Valour even before even
as you started
to hum the song I could hear the lyrics
so perfectly I was turning on my
10-year-old son yesterday to that very
song in fact uh because he had never
heard it before but I did want to
mention to Caleb before he went into his
kind bud speech he mentioned the BC Bud
that he was getting for that they were
getting from BC and that he actually
mentioned a part of the history that a
lot of people uh Miss they just blame
the shoddy BC Growers the low Integrity
BC Growers uh but he did mention that uh
it sifted that that flower was sifted
those buyers who were buying it who were
the the American folks were bouncing the
the flower like hundreds of pounds of it
and just collecting the sift and then
selling the
weed into like prohib prohibition Rich
States you know like V Virginia and
North Carolina and all Florida and
Alabama different places yeah so I I
came up on Canadian herb you know I'm
about 30 miles from the border right
here where I sit and um you know we used
to get small bats stuff I grew up in the
Boston area we got imported brick weed
you know and until we started getting
small batch kind bud but when Canadian
herbs started coming in um yeah I mean
those were that all organized crime
running that [ __ ] and I think I think we
can talk about it now it's it's it's
been a long time but uh when it first
started come because it was so dense and
compact we thought it was the kind bud
you know and in the beginning the
quality I think was okay but over time
as it was more and more mass produced it
was obvious that it was you know
harvested earlier you know not dried
right probably you know had been tossed
or keed or something all of the above
all all of the above I don't think I've
ever honestly experienced
the quality stuff that you guys have up
there I uh I I write for some weed
magazines and I um I write a column
called the breeder diaries for skunk and
I did this uh interview with breeder
Steve a couple years ago incredible
story uh that he told but you know he
gave me a lot of the background and
history of the evolution all the
Canadian genetics so I don't think us
Americans have had a fair share of your
stuff unless you're buying seeds in the
mid to late
90s yeah for sure well I met Steve right
when I moved here from Manitoba in like
96 I would have met Steve and let me
tell you in
96 Steve was all in like both feed in
just like going a 100 miles an hour it
was wild to be around actually I can
imagine I told his I did his whole life
story in the article I I spent like a
hundred hours on that article from like
a three four hour interview with him so
I I was blown away by how cool his story
was there's a lot more cool stuff in
there than did he talk about sending
like three or four doctors to the ER
room on the day of his wedding from weed
brownies he did not talk about that but
um I got the whole background story from
the very beginning of his first plants
and you know his experience with
Northern Lights to how he ended up in BC
and Vancouver to how the sweet pink
grapefruit was named to how he got
connected with Mark Emory and how all
that went down to um you know everything
in Switzerland so I I went pretty deep
nice yeah I spent a lot of time in
Switzerland with him as well in
Lugano so did
I yeah you were definitely around there
I went and spent like a month with him
just uh when he first moved
there did you stay at the tennis Resort
Sam at the cadro panoramica no I stayed
at the uh I think it was Hotel Splendid
on on Lake lagano oo fany yeah no it was
the best hotel around and uh I was with
my wife so I splurged I bet you she
would have liked the hotel cadro
panoramica
more he told me the whole story how he
had originally had this other farm and
had made the arrangements to move there
sold his vehicle his Hydro shop and
right before he headed out to the
airport was told the the place fell
apart and then at the last minute they
ended up finding a much better place
with a more Mediterranean climate
towards Italy and it ended up being a
way better grow climate um so it's it
was a cool story to to hear about very
cool very cool lake lagano has excellent
weather
yeah another uh thing that Dr Mark
mentioned was I guess the people
listening to the music that weren't
living in California Oregon time um you
know might be inspired to then move out
and you know I personally I guess feel
like around 2013 when I moved to
California um you know I was following a
similar Exodus but you know not because
of Grateful Dead music but because of
Hip Hop and um you know it came up a
little bit earlier when hardit and Kazam
were talking but you know I think in
certain parts of the country right like
they said it there Wu Tang's influence
wasn't as hard as for instance uh Snoop
Dog or Dr Dre or Cypress Hill and really
depending on where you are in the
country you know for whatever reasons
there's going to be different uh music
artists that are more popular and you
know that could have an influence on
what particular artist is smoking what
particular cultivar and what are they
bringing into town what is their crew
bringing into town come concert time or
come something else and I guess does
anyone have any stories about specific
Cult of ours associated with specific
artists in that
way yeah I mean in New York you mean
you're talking about wuang I mean
wuang in that whole breath of culture
from tribe really spawn the bedroom
producer and being in New York for me
artists like Travis Stewart machine drum
and flying Lotus and all these people
that I was connected to we're all just
making beats trying to figure out you
know how to blend our ourselves back
into this culture we were so inspired by
and I think through that strains like
sour diesel came up a lot um especially
in New York um there's definitely a lot
of chams a lot of super skunks at the
time um a lot of um just really gassy
fenos c99 was really around a lot in the
early early days um because a lot of
influence from Boston um there's a lot
of great Growers that were circling that
whole New England area than they you
know New York was the spot to drop it
you know Dan knows that well and I think
that what's up brother good to see you
man good to see everyone by the way I've
been absent um we'll get into that later
but I think the music scene for me it
even spawned into the Jazz downtown
jazine in New York for me because I was
around people like messie Martin wood
and JN zor and I was always selling
these people herb to be honest with
everyone and I I you know it was it was
very much
um a collective of individuals that were
all um looking for something for an
inspiring session that they were they
were trying to go into it wasn't um most
of these people I knew weren't daily or
even hourly users they were they were
looking for something that would Inspire
them to to further their creative
outlets and it wasn't the main event it
was a part of the room um much like a
new guitar or a new synthesizer rolls in
and it's like got this expression and
you're you're now writing a new song as
a result um and I think that's what I
saw from a young age and being around
these sessions and Studios of other
artists and I you know I think if if Jay
from Happy monkey was here he could tell
a great story too
about his studio and how that became a
Speak Easy and through that the wuang
and all these people were coming through
his Studio spawned a birth of of a new
revelation in in New York and I think
that's for me those are the varietals
that spoke the loudest and was on the
tip of everyone's tongue it was always a
gas and then you either had a Jack or
you had you had that and there was
really no sure you had your piff which I
believe is was more of a mango
influenced Haze um just my nose and my
my palette is really makes me believe
that um and then these muted tones were
really street corners that you know
didn't have the greatest herbs so they
sold what they had right and I think
those that's the the blend that I was
associated with as as a young kid
growing up around it um in my cousins in
Staten Island and my f extended family
in Staten Island that was what they
always had around um from from New York
so that that's that's my piece on on
association with with that that realm in
Brooklyn and uh in the
fibros well yo can I tell a cool Blu
Tang story
do yeah dude of course first first I'll
say the the two most influential songs
in terms of the herb that you smoke for
me when I was a kid was Cypress Hill
because hits from the bong just like
everyone that I knew we were obsessed
with bongs we're building bongs out of
everything we were trying to get bongs
um so big UPS to Bong Hits and then you
know the whole album of Ka and Bob
Marley was also the biggest to this
that's the most influential weed smoking
music of my life is the whole album Kaa
um I've smoked so much weed to that you
know album but anyway cool wuang story
um in Vermont we got to throw a New
Year's party with one of the
dispensaries that we work with that has
a um a music venue and so we did a show
with kaidon and inspected deck who are
arguably my two favorite you know wuang
artists or you know it's it's hard thing
so anyway we sponsored the show shout
shout him out hey Noah Noah right yeah
this place so um yeah we did a little it
was a little cheesy but it was cool we
did a pre-roll with my double OG Cam and
put the flyer for the show on the thing
and they came ins sign autograph I
didn't bother them with autographs but
when I got to meet them you know the
first time I ever wrapped in my life was
listening to 36 Chambers and people in a
room were freestyling so that's the very
first thing that really got me into
rapping and so I meet inspected deck and
kaidon and I give them my herb and I
show them this weed with the leaf on it
and I go to inspect the deck and I go
yes this is my [ __ ] Rebel grown and he's
like you know I'm the rebel right Rebel
ins I go yeah I know me too and so the
whole night they were just chiefing
blunts of my herb and to this day it was
one of the most amazing you know rap
performances I saw live and I got to
open up for them so I did a set and
opened up for them it was it was a cool
night but the cool story is I have a
couple producers in LA and one of them
is this dude Salam wreck um who is
Warren G's uh DJ and he's real tight
with the dog pound and um several other
people so I send uh mom my California
weed and I sent him a box of jars and I
told him you know if you're around
artists like you know Dazz and corrupt
and Easy E son I would really love it if
you could give them my herb and try to
get them turned on to it so he calls me
about a month after the wuang show he's
like you'll never believe who was in my
studio last night kaidon and um and um
killer priest and I was like yo did you
have the rebel herb he's like oh he saw
it right away and was like oh I was just
chilling with white boy in Vermont so
you know Wu Tang's really inspirational
and it's been cool to connect with those
guys through herb and get to share herb
on on both coasts with kidana and my my
hope is to pursue you know finding some
natural organic way of getting to collab
with them
more that's dear oh yeah shouts to the
woo witty
unpredictable uh I didn't ever really
meet them but I was in Amsterdam one
year at my hotel and it took me years to
find this hotel it was the cow rulsky it
was this big fancy Russian hotel in Dam
Square in the city center of Amsterdam
and um what I had learned and I can't
even remember who told me but it was
like a long time ago 25 years ago now
was that they had another building
attached to their hotel that was like
Apartments so they weren't rooms cu the
first time I went to this hotel it was
just like this two fancy red velvet
carpets and stuff and like you're in
this tiny little room that just has a
little bed and it's like 500 gilders
this was before the Euros but uh I found
these apartments eventually and it was
like the sickest deal they were like 250
bucks a night and it had a kitchen and
an upstairs with a bed and it was just
on the back end of the of the kapulsky
but it was their Apartments but they
would never tell you if you that they
had Apartments so I'm standing there
I've been going there for probably three
or four years at this point and I'm at
the desk and this dude is like kind of
flipping out he's like look I got all
these rooms they're way too small my
guys can't fit in these rooms like what
you do you have anything bigger and of
course she couldn't just say oh actually
sir yes we have these apartments right
they just don't do that in Holland for
whatever reason and so this guy's losing
his mind and I'm like this listen dude
like let me give you a tip you just need
to ask for the apartments and if you say
that she'll say Yes and she'll probably
rent you like four or five Apartments
anyway it ended up being the wuang cluh
this dude was their manager and uh yeah
they were stay it was a small apartment
where it was just like each floor had
like two of these apartments so it was
basically me staying in one of them with
like you know eight or nine uh of the
wuang uh members staying in the other
ones it was pretty cool pretty cool
experience shouts to the woo I got story
I got a quick yeah just one cvar that
comes to mind with music is purple
like I remember the first time I heard
Jimmy Hendrick on vinyl sitting down
like a toddler my Dad pulled out a vinyl
record and he said son I want you to
hear something and put
on it's the first time I heard that riff
it kind of changed something in my head
and it kind of reminds me the first time
I tried herb um they called me smiley
from Santa Cruz and when first time I
tried my first puff was actually purple
hayze so it was prophetic what happened
um and you know something changed in my
brain when I took a puff of Purple Haze
and we listened to that song it was in
an orchard in El Dorado County during a
snowstorm I I skipped fourth period when
I was 14 but that's actually pretty
profound because like these are key
moments in my life you know over over
your decades as you grow you remember
key Great Moments uh Great Moments in
your history and so that one cult ofar
that one song and that that that
beginning riff by Jimmy Hendrick is
something that I'll never forget and it
is amazing that cannabis connection to
music specifically and it kind of set me
on that path of like I want to you know
I want a jam um and that that specific
cultivar and living in Santa Cruz full
circle is kind of cool home of the haze
um you know since I was like a toddler
to high school to now being you know I
got my own toddlers I'll turn them on to
some purple hayze jimmi Hendricks after
the show what what year did you smoke
purple a
uh 2001 2000 it was it was early like
maybe 25 years ago okay because it was
not the haze Brothers growing that
purple haze because no it wasn't that
long ago I wish I really wish it was
they stopped growing the the the two
different Haze brothers were my
neighbors and one of them lived on one
side of me the other one lived on the
other side of me and they quit they both
quit growing the original Haze which I
thought was the finest weed in the world
uh including purple ha uh by I don't
know maybe
1980 or the mid 80s that they had quit
growing Haze and uh they both grew skunk
because it was so much faster and easier
D how crazy is it that hay skunk hay
like you had two Hayes Brothers living
next door to you on either side of your
house and your skunkman Sam now that in
Santa Cruz it was South County Santa
Cruz right skunkman Sam it was South
County well that's where I lived in
South County when I developed skunk
number one but the haze was grown in uh
uh both Santa Cruz just outside the city
and also in Aptos and also in Aromas and
uh I was growed in in
Watsonville yeah that's beautiful man
that's um when I was growing for Wham
for Val caral I was kind of feeling The
Vibes of oh I I think this is where
where things went down you know yeah
well wh the beginning Valerie and
Michael are still good friends of mine
it's a pleasure to connect with you it's
it's beautiful that music and can
brings us
together I'll give a short story and
that was the first it's kind of music
related the first seed I ever planted
was in
1965 in Hollywood at Sunset and Vine in
wck music City's uh flower box outside
there uh I don't know if anybody knows
of w Music City used to be before Tower
records the coolest place to buy music
uh at least in California and uh yeah I
I I just grew Mexican seeds I mean they
weren't nothing super special but uh
they got a put her Too Tall before
either the gardener cut him down or one
of the people that were hanging out on S
Boulevard spotted them and and harvested
them for the Revolution and uh
yeah and then after that the music I was
actually listening to at that time was
people like
uh Buffalo
Springfield uh Jefferson Airplane that
that's the music that I lik back then
but uh when I moved to Santa Cruz in uh
1972 uh a few years later we were able
to see
uh uh Bob Marley played at the Santa
Cruz Civic twice and we went and saw him
both times the second time we had our
daughter with us she was only uh uh two
or three years old I mean she was but
uh it was fantastic and the Santa Cruz
Civic used to be my favorite place to go
see music because it was small maybe at
the most 1 or 2,000 people fit in it and
uh man it it I saw so much good music
there you know uh lot of Ree and it's
the the first two times I saw Bob Marley
were there also which was pretty
nice I have a bootleg copy of that 1972
show in the Santa Cruz Civic uh uh
there's a local guy here on the West it
wasn't 72 I think it was 78 in July okay
in
79 in uh towards the end of the year and
by the when I saw him the second time he
was uh he did not have the energy left
and you could tell something was
wrong it's Legend a place a legend yeah
the Civic I saw Nelson there to this day
it's still going but I I don't know if
it was it's not quite where it used to
be in the late 70s that said though
there's there's a lot of uh good energy
in that space for
sure I I love Santa Cruz it was the only
reason I left was because uh the state
and federal government were flying
airplanes and looking for people and
I got a
Dodge I understand yeah Babylon sucks
yeah
1985 it was H getting pretty
bad yeah for sure is that the year that
they were doing all those uh those uh
what was it called the beaverland dam uh
P patches or artwork was done like too
damn close wasn't that like 84 85 886 uh
yes that was you you're talking about uh
yeah beaver brand uh Beaver brand yeah
yeah beaverland brand he he did it like
uh four five six years in a row and the
first one was damn good and the last one
was damn close yeah helicopter flight I
remember damn close it was it Sam has
the just most epic collection of [ __ ]
you don't even know exists that like uh
will be artifacts in the Cannabis world
one day like they are already like
they're just epic like and at first when
you look at it you're kind of like oh
what what's what what is this and then
as it hits you you're like oh oh my God
like you just have these like illegal
underground cannabis labels per ounces
and pounds and uh it's the equivalent of
orange crate art or vegetable crate art
but it was for illegal can
yeah but you had like the bags for the
for the Lebanese hash and you had like
tie stick yes I've got them all that's
what I'm saying you have it's it's a
part of History you guys for for most of
us that have only heard stories to be
able to touch the sort of like actual
like oh these are the little bags that
the hash was wrapped in this is the Tie
stick like it's just pretty cool and the
labels I knew all of the people who made
them and uh I I also made labels for my
seeds and uh so it was the we were all
using the same
artists Pat Ryan in the north down to uh
yeah local artists in Santa Cruz V were
actually quite great well shout them
out awesome I I I I can barely remember
the names of everybody but uh well you
still remember I'll make a list next
time
yeah exactly it' be cool to get a it'd
be cool to make a book um of some of
that
stuff yeah except for I I really
collected it for myself it it would be
nice to share them and I've considered
putting them online on the website but
uh yeah it's a lot of work and uh i'
I've got hundreds of them yeah you do
there's a Grateful Dead archive at the
Henry Miller or the the the library at
UCSC and I could see like a skunk man
Sam archive uh little mum thing um you
know giving some homage to the young
slugs going to school I think important
to document and have a little exhibit I
don't know if you know this but the
hatch Museum in amster D was actually
started by me and Bob Warren and cool
Ben drunkers bought the building and
took over the museum and actually he
ended up putting a lot more money in it
than I had and then he built that one in
Barcelona which is amazing it's insane
it's Bonkers actually that one in
Barcelona is
Bonkers so beautiful
I think I think we broadcast something
from there together I foret we did we
did for sure I think it might have been
a hash Church actually but yeah it's a
16th century building and instead of
restoring
it
he I don't know what the hell the well
he spent a few million dollars in in
four years restoring it first of all
yeah no exactly but it was like the way
he explained it it was like he dug he he
lifted all the dirt off and like exposed
what was there and just yeah it was just
incredible incredible building if you're
in Barcelona it's definitely worth
whatever even if it's 20 or30 EUR it's
well worth uh walking through it the
collection is ridiculous I mean what
yeah it's ridiculous it's worth seeing
anyway in
person yep that and Bugatti building and
Barcelona both of those I I I I really
like
Barcelona that's a pretty cool City I
like to rent a motorcycle when I'm in
Barcelona and boot around on a
motorcycle it's like the quickest way to
get around and it seems like they have
more of a motorcycle culture where the
cars aren't running them
over there's a lot of a lot of people in
Barcelona use metros too underground for
sure
y perfect do it
up uh I had some
other questions that I had created
here um oh we still didn't see
uh there's a couple people that never
ended up showing up yeah there a few uh
Nick said he's gonna hop on in 15 or so
minutes nice yeah yeah there's no rush
oh it's yeah I sent you the link my
friend but I will send it again
apologies for my tardiness I I've had uh
my father passed away uh December 17th
so I've been kind of dealing with all
the
post of that and
just just put in the rest yesterday so
it's been a been a
whirlwind I
bet that's uh I think
back back that might have been the
hardest time of my life when my father
died yeah I don't want to turn the show
under that but just want to you know
keep it it's organic what it is we
definitely wanted to uh you know we've
been thinking about you anyway each week
that we that you've been going through
all this stuff and haven't been here and
we're glad to have you back
dude thanks man yeah it's good to be
here good to be with y'all I fig
I was actually thinking yeah I was
thinking about you know
um as you were saying like what artists
like what varietals and I I've as the
older self coming up through all that I
don't think anyone could really call it
out because it took individuals like us
to come in the room to be like yo this
is this this is that try this try that
um because I musicians are largely their
heads space are occupying
Sonic territories and they're thinking
about other things than what herb is
right for them and I think it takes
experience through trying things for
them to find what works but it largely
takes a conduit and someone who is
obsessive with that that medium or art
form if you will and I think when you
bring that into the room it it lifts up
the room and then and only then can they
call those things out like Dan gave them
the jar right and then they were in the
studio and he cracks it open and that's
a to me that's an artist discovering
something something the Magic in the
mundane in a in a in a in a sense like
they're just like it's in a jar and I
open it and then there's the magic right
um yeah there's a name but I always find
that that comes after and I think from
an artist point of view I don't think
they're searching as much at least back
then maybe today it's more because
there's more information and we all know
more
um but I don't remember someone being
like can you give me this it was
never I don't remember going in as a
delivery being like only after time was
that that that relationship developed
and then can I see what else you have um
but largely it was what do you think I
should have um very very similar to
today in a lot of respect but um with a
Different Twist to it you know um
so would you characterize that kind of
like a relationship between the artist
and a specific grower or or you know
breeder and then like there's a trust
there and then really whatever yeah
varietal well we yeah well we had this
kid that was in with all the hip-hop
guys and he would take our work and
bring it in with them and he'd be like
yo Ro likes this this guy likes that
this guy like you know and and we would
then arm him with other stuff like that
um and he was a part of a management
team and and you know there was it was
you know he had the authority and
there's always someone with an authority
within the circle and I found that
largely how I got through to people was
utilizing the not only the assistants
but the managers and then the assistant
managers and all these people that got
us into the circles and then and then
you at least back this is talking like
early 2000s or way back in the early
days of this for me and that's how our
you know it kind of moved you know you
weren't just like invited into a room
with all these guys right it took time
to develop that relationship you know
and then the trust was born from that
and then it was just like creature haboc
like call the call the guy um so I think
that's a lot largely a lot of my
experience at least personal experience
with it um I don't know what anyone
else's had but you know I I said sour
and then I was like that was only after
I was like guys you should try this and
try that and try this you know and it
was more um
influencing them to to try stuff and
they then you know it's like music you
listen to it you're like I want more of
that can I listen to more of that um so
I think that was um if I'm very honest
about it I think that's really how A lot
of this was was done I don't know if
anyone could really call Things by name
because we didn't really we had like
four-way and like you know skunk and
Hydra you know it wasn't like it is now
like these names came in in really the
2000 for us as as you know Brokers and
stuff you know it was just we didn't
really have this vernacular like we have
today if I'm really really honest I mean
I don't know Mark you know SC scouton
like you even growing up in the 80s like
what what what were the terms like were
people really calling things by varietal
names like I don't I don't really
remember that
no
yeah I I I remember certain varieties
like I remember things like uh Matt nusa
[ __ ] and Y monkey paw and peab
Bud and yeah things just sort of had
like a slang in the vernacular right I
mean kind bud was sort of recognized as
being just dense
sensia could be fruity could be gassy I
don't think it was um it was strange
specific until like the 90s on fish tour
the first time I heard the word
bubblehash was right around the time
Marcus you started going to shows so I I
think bubble has entered the vernacular
during the fish at least during my you
you know what funny enough all of my
fish
activity like almost all of it was
pre-bubble
bubble would have hit like I started
going to seea fish in
93 well 99 was when I coined the term
bubble hash but that's an interesting
thing because you were talking about the
Grateful Dead earlier and we've been
talking about you know colins's talking
about like how you can influence
musicians with your herb and then if you
can get those cultivars liked by those M
musicians and then they sing it I mean
listen I wasn't a huge ludicrous fan but
when I heard that blueberry yum Y young
song when it first came out I was just
like cranking that thing I was like dude
I wanted blueberry I was like trying to
reach out to DJ Short and be like well I
got to get the blueberry again like this
blueberry then then my friend Kayla
started a company here in Canada and has
a cultivar called blueberry yum yum and
I don't know if she's growing it like
aquaponically or what it is but it it
literally looks like the weed from the
video like it's just fluffy big round
coated crystally lovely Buds and here's
the thing I don't even smoke flower like
flower is next to useless for me unless
I can somehow bounce the resin off of it
or if I can you know I can vaporize it
and get the get that flavor profile that
way but I kind of went about things a
little differently because you know I of
course I hooked up a gazillion musicians
over the years that had inspired me that
I was going to then
reinpuck herbs but um yeah starting
Bubble Bags was a little different
because you know the way Colin was like
you had to earn that trust for me I sold
bags I was transparent I taught people
how to do the process and then that was
it I had earned their trust like in a
very short period of time at a time
where it was very very illegal many many
many people would invite me right into
their home where they were making hash
like like completely exposed themselves
in a way that like I had earned a very
deep trust and everywhere I went like
every country every city wherever I went
I'd always meet someone that was like
wanted to just show me all their [ __ ]
and it was really like wrap your head
around it during a time where you could
get in a lot of trouble so I
somehow leapfrogged the trust earning
Thing by by releasing the bags being
transparent and just teaching people
something that they didn't know before
that was so sort of mind altering and
life altering like not only are you now
no longer throwing your trim away you
know of course years would go by and
we'd get to crops being grown
specifically just for hash making and it
created this incredible Community where
I just suddenly knew everywhere in the
world where the best hash was like I was
the conduit for that I knew I know where
all the best hash in the world is from
all of these incredible people people
ordering uh Bubble Bags over the years
and just uh and just making hash so it's
uh that's been my journey and it's been
an honor to walk these steps and just
travel around the world Johnny apple
seed style but Johnny uh Johnny Hash
Pipe Style just making hash and showing
people how to do it when reg to come
into
Amsterdam they would uh people like yoy
and aan the first thing they would do
when they landed would give me a call
and i' whip over and give giant handfuls
of skunk number one to everyone of the
band members and seeds to them and uh I
I I I had really a lot of herb at that
time and did not to am am I incorrect to
say that Joseph culture Hill was like in
Amsterdam maybe you guys were hanging
out and then he drove to Germany and
passed away like the next day um yes
that was true
and uh probably the one I was the
closest to uh I had known actually I Jam
On's crew longer but uh
yoy you yoy was a very very special and
close to
us well I'll tell you I have a few songs
with my uh name in it uh from all pretty
much ree artists there's uh Richie Spice
one called dabin that's that mentions me
a few times in there about vaporizing
some full melt with them um Luton fire
did one called sweet
Tricom uh John Mason did one called oh
what was his
called I can't even remember all the I
think there's about five or six of them
now so I I don't have hundreds but uh
I'm still working on it well don't
forget on hash church right oh on hash
church that's right dude that's a
classic song There It Is there it
is Jammy um yeah I mean Marcus you you
earned my trust like almost
immediately and thinking about that
because and then summer 90 a like that
whole summer 99 after I or that that
year I'd gotten the bags really and I
think I don't when did you put the bags
out December of 99 or spring of night I
can't remember uh it was
March so March so March yeah I remember
I remember in 99 I went to lot with like
these [ __ ] up wet balls of hash
basically like wrong like just wrong you
know what I mean and I was like bubble
hash you know trying to move you know
move moveing shake and um that was my
fault you know I mean it was it was our
everyone you can't it on you man well I
I sold you the B I sold you the bags and
then showed you how to dry it
incorrectly that's true you did yeah and
then well I kept I remember it kept on
like hit I remember yeah well I remember
hitting you up one time and I I remember
I used snow I like washed in with snow
and you're like dude don't do that the
all the trics are gonna get stuck in it
you know what I mean because I was like
just trying you know was cold out after
I gone through the the first few months
of having it and uh it took a while man
to really get it you know again no one
to talk to except you know a message
that you would send and hopefully you'd
be on overgrow and answer it through PM
you know um free DM which is funny to
say I when the word DM came out I was
like what is DM what happened to PM
private message you know what I
mean um but that's you know the Journey
of that I think I remember utilizing
that that and going to on tour with it
with my girlfriend at the time um and
you know it was it was a interesting
time in in I think everyone's lives at
that point in that band's career and our
our own lives um because it was mainly
um you know there was some hash but it
was it was very few and far between and
it wasn't very good when you found it um
it was usually imported um but it's um
yeah I think Mark you know the the
timeline is maybe a little bit into the
2000s when the bubble hat really truly
hit because I don't I think maybe 200000
2001 2003 it's really when it started to
really blow through the lot um down
Shakedown and stuff and then um from
there it just
grew first water hatch that I made was
1988 wow so Sam with that said like were
you pulling were you how which screens
were you using like I'm always curious
using screens we would use we would get
dry buds grinded up with like a coffee
bean grinder and dump it in big
tall uh like several liter glass
jars and the resin would sink down to
the bottom and you'd wash it once or
twice to get rid of the the the floating
crap and to make the water cleaner and
then you uh treated it like water has
but the yield wasn't quite as good as uh
uh with multiple bag system like Marcus
came up with a decade later but uh it it
absolutely did work but to be honest I
didn't make a whole lot of it because uh
even though the yield of dry sift was
much lower uh I preferred dry to me it
was the gold standard and uh so that's
what I
made yeah it makes sense because the the
one thing I was hanging out with Mojave
and Rob Clark and and one thing he said
that you would always say is that gold
sinks and [ __ ] floats and I just thought
it was the funniest thing that we were
just like sitting there and he just says
that all of a sudden I'm like that's
really funny you say that but how would
you get to that and then you just you
just saying what you just said made it
all make sense to me because you're
using jars and it the gold would sink
and the [ __ ] would float
yeah Rob took a lot of pictures of the
processing and uh yeah it was actually
showed to me in
1988 by Neville at cannabis castle and
uh some American guy I think his name
was Mike I I don't actually remember at
the moment he had showed him and a week
later me and Rob went over and visited
Neville and he showed us and uh I
thought it was really interesting but I
didn't do it a whole super lot because I
like dry
better was that because of the the the
chir preservation you know because when
it get I invented static neck and I
could clean up dryft to 99 9 now the Y
incredbly the yield was incredibly low
but uh got it when you make water hash
depending on the variety you're using uh
you will lose some of the turps ETC I
mean that's why the water you know
smells so
turpy right and did it matter that the
yield was so low when you had access to
a fair bid yeah I mean I I never never
never never ran out of herbal cannabis I
mean I had you know trust me dude I saw
it I saw the wall of 55 gallon barrel
drums blue ones
filled as far as uh the Bubble Bags go I
was thinking about you know re jogging
my memory these were the first bags that
I got I dug up a old picture for you but
I got my local hydro stores in Vermont
to order these from you probably in 2005
or
2006 and uh so that was my early hash
making Journey with your bubble bags
right here back in the day and then my
buddy and I who were my other buddy was
really more passionate about hash than I
was and he made us a custom press and
brought some gold leaf and so we just
you know would would take some nice
stuff and uh I also messed up drying it
the first couple times but we were smart
enough to put it in the freezer um but
so that's that's how long I've been back
with those bags would be probably
2006 that's awesome man that's early
days dude that's very early days that's
only you know six or seven years in and
it it did take really realistically like
around three three in a bit to pop and
take off right when did the eight bag
kit come in like round 2005 right I'm
remember no I think he had a six or a
seven there he just said seven I thought
seven it said it said made in Nepal and
it took over to convince my local hydro
store owner to get it because they were
so bugged out to even order Bubble Bags
you know like that was it was different
times I know it really was greting B
everyone yes yes it changed it's changed
the world Marcus because most people
weren't using my dry method even though
I publicized
it got to go to work Sam just give me
one second because I'm just going to say
goodbye and then you can finish yes Z
rude to just cut out like that you know
so it's nice meeting everyone I'm sorry
that I have to leave this important
conversation right now this is so
interesting like I can't I can't process
all that I'm
hearing right now so I'm talking to some
Legends right now you know so it's
really it's really great to invite me um
bbba man I'm really looking forward to
linking with each and every one of you
and see how best I can learn and
grow grow the best thing in Jamaica here
or you know what I
mean yeah it's really great you know
trust me and I mean for me I started
music by climbing trees and smoking
ganja that's my inspiration when I
started um smoking herbs and through um
a group called orthodox music there were
a group in a organization in 12 tribes
of Israel in Jamaica here so growing up
in a
family growing up with herbs every day
24/7 yard in your space it was only
evident that you know I ended up started
smoking weed um I started smoking herb
as I said climbing the AI trees and
finding inspiration and eventually I
started to write
notes which turned out to be music so
that is how my journey started 21 years
ago 22 years ago musically nice and
Trust herban music has never I've never
departed since so listen I'm just
impressed with your pre work joint like
he's on his way to work right now look
at hold up your
fatty I love for bref have three more
but I don't
know are
me those are for my wife
it's really fun it's really it's really
nice linking you guys and it's really
awesome trust me so hoping to
L as I said I gotta go to make that
paper B so all right all right good work
talk soon Kazam bye bye Loren bye bye
blessings everyone BL yeah man
[Music]
respect that's so good
one leaves and one comes we have Nick
Riley
here you want the best it's got to be
fire in and fire out
yeah agreed welcome welcome Nick where
where you at Nick thanks for having me
um I am in Humble County I'm in uh
outside so or Redway in so hell yeah
that's what's up humble repres
that yeah yeah just uh offg grading the
mountains here so oh my god dude that's
what's up we'll give us a little
introduction to you man for the people
who are watching that might not know you
or what you're up to uh well I'm sure no
one does know me um I uh I'm my name's
nick uh I run media and marketing and a
million other hats for Reggae on the
River um and I work with the matile
community center who's the nonprofit
that puts on the riveron um my wife is
actually vice president of the board um
my partner on the farm is also on the
board um you know I'm involved in
growing weed and cannabis on every level
you could think of um and yeah we just
uh as a community Matti Community Center
has kind of been like the the beacon of
both music and cannabis culture honestly
and reg on the river was always that
Pinnacle and so for me it was you know
kind of coming in I'm from Cleveland
Ohio originally moved out to Humble like
13 years ago now and uh it just I didn't
plan on staying and it sucked me in you
know the Cannabis was great but really
what sucked me in was the culture um you
know I come from kind of like an
underground punk rock Anarchist world
and you know the hippies that I knew in
the city were totally different and so I
came out here and it was like oh wow
this is this is a world I can get you
know into and and really kind of live in
and after a couple years just realized
like you know the mat is kind of
everything I've ever been looking for
and so my wife and I just dived head in
uh we've been trying to help keep it
alive you know I hate that kind of story
of like ah this thing's dying got to
keep it alive but that really is what
we're dealing with here um and then
through that you know spent a couple
years trying to bring back reg on the
river uh with some of the key people
that originally did it some new blood a
little bit of everything and last year
by the skin of our teeth we did it so um
yeah it's uh all about how to keep that
tradition going I guess so I'm more here
representing uh the matile and and Regan
on the river for the little bit that I
can but to me it's more about you know
the homage to that Legacy that I didn't
have a part of but now I'm so blessed to
be able to continue hey Nick I just
wanted to say uh big ups and appreciate
what do for the Matti I've got a a
property east of Garberville um I'm not
I'm not currently a full-time humble
resident but I get up there when I can
and and that's you know a big part of my
heart in that Community um so you know I
understand the challenges haven't met
you before but uh would love to find
ways to support you know when and where
I can I I work with Chris and Redwood
roots and a lot of those guys oh okay
yeah my neighborhood is the palde you
know new Harris Island mountain is where
my spot is uh has got a lot of old
history in in southern humbal so it's a
pleasure to to meet you thanks man uh
same yeah right back and you're Rebel
grown right that was the yeah so it's
actually I just remember you were my
favorite person in Booth to talk to at
the I can't even remember if it was the
golden tarp Awards or not it was some
real early
Matti thing that happened and you know I
came down out of the hills like I used
to work for an Oldtimer who was super
paranoid so to me even going to the
Matti and seeing stuff like out on
tables I was like what the hell but uh
it's funny I just found one of your
little burlap sacks that you had your
seeds in the rebel grown on the floor of
my house like three days ago so yeah
yeah nice to to meet you this way yeah
yeah definitely let me know if you're
back in town I'd love to catch up
absolutely for
sure yeah that's cool man regga on the
river I've uh never been myself but I've
been to some of the big ones in Jamaica
and it's uh it's just magical Vibes it's
definitely worth uh keeping that alive
and keeping it going it's uh it's too
bad you just missed Kazam who was he was
going I kind of wanted to be like uh
just come to Regan the river we'll take
care of you you know um but he could he
can link you up with an enormous amount
of people uh artists from that kind of
younger I don't know if you were
familiar with this guy
Joe um he's got a he he passed away some
years ago but he was if you ever if you
I mean anyone that listens to reggae if
you've ever heard them say
Jahova evil which chronics was quite
well known for but Protege said it and
kabaka said it and kind of all these
different artists that were a part of
this Uprising through Joe liel Joe is
what they called him he ended up having
a brain aneurysm and passing away um but
uh so they pay homage to him in the
songs Through Jova evil which is J
OE uh which is is his name so yeah I uh
I wish I could put my video onto the
screen um I mean I can but there's
there'd be no sound but this right here
it's called J over Evil part one and
that's Kazam in the Tam on the right
with the with the go uh green golden red
shirt playing the AC acoustic guitar
there's micaa Shaman next to him and
Hess sativa is there and Joe's brothers
in the blue shirt way over on the left
they just came and performed for me and
my buddy uh one year when we were
working for a an online YouTube platform
that monetized views and man what an
experience dude like I can't uh I
probably have 150 studio phone numbers
uh for Kingston and at least maybe 200
artists from like the old school Roots
guys to like from luchano and and Tony
Rebel and all those guys all and you
know Israel Vibes and all these guys and
then all the way way back to like the
chronics and the kakas and I've just uh
had a huge passion for reggae music a
big part of my life although funny
enough you know for me it started with
rock and roll my dad gave me the old
Beatles and Stones albums and CCR and I
was just like this is [ __ ] awesome
and then it kind of went into punk rock
for me because I was a skateboarder and
I was living in Winnipeg this kind of
pretty pretty awesome [ __ ] hole that uh
you know a [ __ ] hole sucks if you don't
make best of it but if you're living in
a [ __ ] whole like I guess kind of out of
rock before Cleveland's kind of a [ __ ]
old too so Winnipeg sounds very familiar
very similar we just had all the great
bands and so just like Cleveland prior
to the punk rock bands we had all the
metal bands so first I saw all the metal
bands you know from glamrock kisses to
like hardcore Sabbath and just the the
real the real rootsy metal [ __ ] even
like Venom and like you know some some
some obviously Slayer that kind of
turned into punk rock we had this dive
bar bar called the Albert that just had
like every punk rock band every punk
rock band like they were all just there
and I was buying vinyl at the time so I
still have all these punk rock records
on vinyl oh and that kind of grew for me
I don't know how it happened it must
have been psychedelics it must have been
psychedelics because somehow for me and
I don't think I'm missing anything I
went from punk rock back into that sort
of old school 60 psychedelic Rock and
then the Grateful Dead and fish and once
the Grateful Dead and fish although I
will say in that time that I was getting
into the Grateful Dead and fish reggae
was like at that like I was listening to
Peter Tosh like a crackhead like I would
just listen to Peter Tosh all and he had
so many albums it was just like pounding
Peter Tosh religiously into my head um
and then uh and then really jam bands
jam bands reggae and now more eclectic
from Hip Hop obviously there was hip-hop
in there a bit too in '95 uh when Biggie
and Tupac were kind of taken off and the
woo and you know obviously krs1 and some
of the classics that I like so I I feel
like I'm pretty eclectic in my music I
guess if there's any genre I've
certainly paid attention to World music
I was a huge faila ANUK kapo couti fan
massive fathala fan listen to so much of
that music for so long with Egypt 80 and
all his other different iterations even
his son FEI couti I got to meet and hang
out with those guys dude his son is
incredible dude I saw him Fe
unbelievable in central at the central
same energy I mean I never got to see
but fi I've seen many times and his
energy was incredible dude and they
speak French so I'm I'm bilingual being
a good old Canadian so I was able to uh
meet them in Amsterdam there was really
not a lot of people at the show that
were speaking French funny enough but uh
I could so they spent lots of time
hanging out with me so always happy to
spend time with musicians who are so
exceptional at the execution of their
Vision or tapping
into this just incredible I guess as Dan
would say amplifier well he was calling
cannabis an amplifier but music too can
be Amplified as we know from Bob Dylan
uh I guess it was what 1965 or 67 what
year did Bob Dylan do his Newport or
even yeah Newport was it earlier yeah I
think it was 65 65 yeah so that was a
big thing when he just like I think he
was getting booed there wasn't he when
he came out with the electric
guitar it goes to show you how much
humans fear change because I bet you 99%
of the people that booed at Dylan when
he came out with the electric guitar at
Newport are huge electric guitar fans
today if they're still
alive yeah yeah new is scary yeah same
thing happened to Miles man when you
made [ __ ] Brew they were like what
are you doing bro and he changed the
world I mean I had a conversation last
night where they're like miles is
underrated I was like actually he
created drum Loops so I'm not quite sure
I'm on board with that actually he just
doesn't give a [ __ ] about that yeah yeah
on the west coast it was a Monteray Pop
Festival right that was was that the
most important um like out Open Air
Festival in California Sam is that like
the bigest time yes
yeah yeah because I remember listening
to hris as or studying Hendrick as a
Young musician and that performance
always came up because of him lighting
his guitar on you know all the stuff all
the all the sensationalism that happened
during that and no one had ever seen
that it's incredible it's well I don't
know he was definitely influen I was
thinking about that where he was
definitely influenced by like The Who
and others like that because they were
already doing crazy stuff like that and
then he was like what am I gonna do to
up this and he's like I'm gonna L my
[ __ ] on
fire
well Guitar kind of good yeah he was
decent yeah just just kind of good he
inspired some people I remember seeing
dzel Zappa and him telling the story of
like finding like bits and pieces of a
guitar under his dad's stairs and his
dad being like Oh that was uh Jim that's
the one he burnt at the Monterey Pop
Festival and then I think he restored it
I he might have even been playing it the
night that he told the story I can't
imagine why he would tell the story if
he wasn't but I don't remember exactly
dzel Zappa definitely has that guitar
though the one that Jimmy uh set on fire
Frank was a a one block away neighbor of
mine in L Canyon course was his
babysitter was Miss
who was uh kind of a girlfriend of mine
at the
time ah the skunkman Sam history Frank's
a block away the Hayes brothers are even
closer Frank's probably telling his band
stay the [ __ ] away from those Hayes
Brothers in that skunk
guy well is it true I I hadn't run into
the haze when I was living in L Canyon
that was in the late
60s so it was a different time
La not Santa Cruz well hold on there's
like Sam just let me can I ask you a
really important question because that
scene that music scene Laurel Ken scene
at the time you were there was the most
important music scene in the world like
it was the center of I mean all I you
know pretty much most of the greatest
songs center of the uh Jefferson
Airplane and
uh Big Brother you know so I mean there
there was other important areas
too true but it felt at least it felt
like Fleetwood Mac and I you the beach I
mean so much American history has been
written in that Canyon it's kind of for
me at least as a nerd about music histo
historical moments I I look at that as a
very unique time almost like the Lowry
side in the mid to late 60s kind of had
its own Vision too there within five
miles of the current fire line of the
Palisades fire Palisades fire is right
on mandville Canyon which is just above
Brentwood which is just above mahalan
mahalan actually the old mahalan road is
the current current boundary of the
upper level of that fire so that fire is
getting up going north towards enino
which is
crazy it's terrible I mean I I have two
friends that are I had bandmate that
actually Marcus met in Amsterdam
Ross um he lost his whole home he lost
every his Studio his music equipment his
all his memories everything is just gone
um he sent me an image and he it's nine
blocks this way nine blocks that way
just gone and um you know for those that
are out there that can help just to say
this really fast to everybody please
help um don't go into corny narrative
about politics that's corny that's
ridiculous stop go help people talk
about all that later um just go help be
be actionable because right now is the
time and if you have n95 masks please
ship them out to people please help
because they they don't they're
breathing in super toxic like very toxic
air um and that's another issue that'll
be later uh in life and and that's you
know so a good example was two two house
away from uh Frank Zappa's house was
Joan Mitchell's
house yeah hey welcome to Morning Glory
who just popped in looks like he's
enjoying some outdoor action getting the
fresh air yes sir good morning
guys over here brother I'm in Menino
county has this East Coast look to it
with those trees poking out your back
left side over there
oh can you hear me absolutely awesome
I'm here in mesino county in
NorCal
welcome awesome and I jumped in at a at
a pretty sensitive time talking about
the fires because uh actually in 2020 I
myself became victim to the Oak fire and
I actually lost
everything so sorry man sorry to hear
about
that you know firsthand um yeah what it
what it means
um but yeah you know it really is so um
I'm hoping and I'm hoping they can
contain the fire it's at 11 or I think
11% and you know maybe someone can
correct me if I'm wrong here
but um it's not looking great so yeah
it's not for
sure can I River Story please do all
right so um in 2008 I moved to Santa
Cruz next to a green room on Beach Hill
and uh my roommates at the time were the
moon germs so kind of punk rock surf
rock it kind of ties in all this Bubble
Bags everything and they were like I was
18 didn't know anyone I actually took a
musician's room because he went on tour
and move I'm like now I'm living in
Santa Cruz and they take me to this band
practice in montere so there's a montere
pops there and uh they Jam hard and I'm
trying to keep up with all these college
kids and I'm 18 so I'm I'm puff and
tough and and I fall asleep on the couch
and I wake up and they're dumping black
and yellow bins and they said it's time
to chop your way to the top and so the
whole the whole house was triming weed
and Monterey um and we would get some of
the trim and make hash out of it and
that's how we like built our our studio
our little Jam Shack our first records
were paid for from crops later on I
started ancest tree which is a Santa
Cruz Roots ban so Nick it's a pleasure
to to meet you and our goal was to tour
a a circuit from Seattle to San Diego
and that's what we did we would chop our
way to the top it was all funded from
Cannabis and we would make the hash and
sell that at shows and one cool thing
about Weeden music is it was The Growers
in Oregon and NorCal that would take us
in we would play a show like the Jolly
Roger or something some you know dive
and we had nowhere to stay uh we were
sleeping in a little LAX short bus and
there's 11 of us and it was always like
a grower some iy head would be like yo
where you guys staying like we had no
idea like in our car you know in the bus
and so that's another cool thing is not
Not only was it the amplifier cannabis
was like the The Muse but it was the
Cannabis community that always took in
players and bands and acts in my
experience as a performing touring
musician from Seattle to San Diego we
always got love um so it's something
that I think you know
times have changed uh when it comes to
like you know depending on a crop to pay
for an album or a tour uh but hey it
really was the foundation that that that
built our group ancestry and one of our
ways one of the stops on the way was reg
on the river circuit like 2010 2012 it
was 20 2010 to 2014 that was our circuit
yeah you you nailed something though
like just being a musician and stuff
myself I mean whatever just the
traveling around in a van with like some
level of like weed or I used to ship
finger hash back to myself and hide it
in the you know guitar pedals and that
would be like smoking out of an apple on
the back of the van but you nailed it
every single time no matter where you
were if it was like a shitty ass sports
bar we ended up at if it was like the
randomst hardcore crusty house whoever
was smoking weed they were always it was
like oh let's huddle
up like what do you need like you guys
hungry like you guys want to go get some
food you need a place to crack every
single time it was always the stoner and
that just crossed every single boundary
uh which actually kind of like what you
were saying Mark it's like
every type of music you just described
you're like oh it's all over it's
eclectic it's all weed like that's the
one kind like you know it it really is
like and out here in Humble first thing
I realized when I moved that was all the
hills too it was like if you can imagine
a type of person into a type of music
smoking a kind of weed they had their
own little Hill or like part of a hill
or like they'd bring their little crew
up and that kind of thing and and
everyone still had that one common
denominator it's like oh man everyone's
so different around here weed yeah weed
yeah traveling in a van and just being
out there with that as the common
denominator I I couldn't agree with you
more man you just touched my heart on
that one so and uh yeah come back up to
Reg on the river say Hey you
know man d the LEL kindness you got to
have to be like oh how many are there of
you uh just like 11 oh yeah no problem
dude come come hang out I got like a
studio apartment uh just above the
hardware store we should be able to fit
if we all lay head to toe head to
toea yeah Missoula Montana some some
punk group let us in just to a co-op I
can't tell you how many like Punk
Anarchist Co-op we as like crusty you
know Santa Cruz heads would come through
and it was all weed we came through with
that bubble has we were chopping our way
to the top and um but it was also just
that the compassion you know head nose
ahead by the look of the eye and you
know you see someone smok in you're like
okay let's let's go let's go hang out
with them and and contribute to the
circle and it always works out we always
had a place to stay even in the cold wet
places uh it was always it was always
important to to keep the music and the
weed together listen back then bubble
has was like this like elevated version
of kind bud it opened all locked doors
if there was a puffer on the other
side yes
like your story actually reminds me of
like when I'm we I met Marcus in
Amsterdam with my band when we just got
off
tour and we just went there by chance to
just like they're like what do you want
to do go to like Belgium or France or I
was like let's go to Amsterdam and go
[ __ ] hang and they're like all right
let's go and then I get there and I I
walk into this shop and I see see the
bubble bags on the wall and I'm like oh
dude that's my friend's
bags and the guy literally goes oh yeah
Marcus he calls Marcus on his phone and
he's like hands me the phone to like
test if I actually knew Marcus I was
like Marcus it's lemon cake he's like
dude he's like come to this address and
we all end up rolling over there and we
had an incredible time and I feel like
that was at Adam's Place wasn't that
weren't you in Amsterdam at
hempworks I think so yeah I was at
Adam's yeah at H exactly HKS I saw the I
saw your stuff in the window I was like
oh my God I'm going in like I went in I
was I was like dude this I felt
connected I was like oh it's connected
here and uh yeah my you know and then we
ended up meeting you and then meeting
Sama and then we were asked to play the
Showcase with Cypress and all Cypress
hilling all those guys and uh we ended
up opening up for all them it was cool I
think it was Doug Adam's partner Adam
Dunn from th seeds that him and Doug had
a place called hemp works it was Doug
that called me yeah I remember it was
like it was yeah it was definitely Doug
for sure that's the best hey when you're
actually like I remember being backstage
at a String Cheese Incident concert once
and this dude was dropping a name to me
he's like oh yeah uh I know the bubble
man and I was like what and he said yeah
that hash guy and it no one first of all
nobody like I'm not a person like I my
my I have a very like very a very small
niche of people know who I am into his
eyes yeah he's looking right at me in
the end he did know my friend Kyle who
helped me with one of my earlier logos
so it was kind of an a an honest mistake
type of thing but uh hey I wanted to uh
uh welcome uh meno dopes in the house I
just saw him pop saw up my brother how's
it going dude good how you guys doing
doing it man up
brother smoking has tell stories
everyone's like everywhere right now my
bottom row is awesome got meno dope in
the car Kazam Davis in the middle he's
in the car on his way to work smoking
fat
taste and then morning glory is my
bottom left corner so right on guys oh
yeah how many people are in here right
now I'm still trying to figure it out 12
there's 12 of us I think on a phone you
have to like swipe to another page I
think on a phone okay I'm on my laptop
but uh oh you're on your laptop in the
corner and I can go down and up and down
through the through the list you can
also go up to the top right it should
say View and you can go to like Gallery
if you want to see everyone at once or
you can go to speaker and then only the
one person I see
12 okay
awesome yeah there's a double stack in
here how stoned are you
Sam me are you talking to me I am oh uh
well I'm sitting here smoking my uh I'll
give you a
demonstration oh a demonstration I'm
trying
to a skunkman s demonstration he's
focusing
hard Focus brother the focus it is the
focus I knew it dude did you know that
did you know that DJ hard before you
said that hey Che it out Che it out I
gave H one of those several years ago
okay okay word hey hey so check it check
it I just gotta say this I think every
important relationship that I've ever
made in my life has come from marijuana
I'm talking about I've smoked weed
everywhere I'm talking about when they
started legalizing it state by state I
used to jump on the plane and just fly
there like that's my vacation solo uh I
even djed at the first annual cannbis
cup the first second and third High
Times an annel canis Cup in Denver
Colorado now I'mma tell you something
when it as far as you know hash I hit
hash I'll do some dabs I like to roll up
myself personally however I went to
Amsterdam I was disappointed
I think that the Kelly weed is the
strongest weed I'm now I'm from Texas so
I I think that the Kelly weed is very
strong you know uh
Oregon I don't like it Washington I
don't like it Denver I don't like it
Oklahoma I damn sure don't like it but
Michigan michell yeah Michigan Michigan
is you [ __ ] with
Michigan Michigan is very very
underrated those calans up there those
those are like uh Arab Christians so you
know how you have Arab Muslims so you
got Arab Christians so they call
themselves calans and those calan people
up there they grow some good damn weed
I'm talking about Snoop Doggy Dog style
weed listen that that weed believe it or
not is all around the world and
sometimes if you're just looking for the
weed itself it's hard to find but if you
if you hunt the hash and you find the
six-star full melt like you just found
the weed you're looking
for
100% well peace everybody I gotta roll
Marcus I'll be back next week full force
people I love you all thank you thanks
for including me travel call and
wonderful really lovely to to talk with
everyone I love all of you very much
take care have a great day every send me
beat yeah dude Dan we'll l peace
brother I want to try some Vermont weed
what's up with that Vermont weed you
talking
about Dan knows D here in front of me
you know I've got this is the California
version and then I've got the Vermont
version here and I got them both rolled
up so I've been smoking back and forth
this is the California this is the
Vermont and then I've got some indoor
too but uh yeah you know it really
depends in my opinion on how it's stored
um there's things about my California
weed that I like better that I think it
has a deeper flavor and it's it's
probably a bit stronger in certain ways
the Vermont weed is easier to preserve
the turpins so it's really turpy and
it's easier to keep it uh fresh I think
um I'm I'm high so I like
both so what what what would you
preferred up like if you had a
preference would it be the California or
would it be the Vermont I'm I'm in love
with growing weed in both of these
places so I would never do that okay
okay
okay don't make them shoes
[Laughter]
call that's
awesome what I will say that Humble
County in theal triangle is probably the
ultimate in terms of potential climate
history culture
uh if I if someone put a gun to my head
and said you could only grow weed in
Humble or Vermont probably go back to
Humbolt but very tough call have you
been up to the cies in
Canada I haven't you should come check
out the cies I'm like 99% sure it was
like draft Dodgers from humbold who
bounced to the cies and started the
culture there so it's very much like our
version
of of Humbolt it's it's big it's
forested and it's just like uh maniac
[ __ ] characters living on acreages
just everywhere growing
weed when I
first is that where black bear was
living uh black bear was actually in the
Okanagan he wasn't quite but he would
have like he would have been the king of
the Cy faky would have been the king of
of humble for that matter that guy was
uh quite a
character so my first year in Humble the
farm that I was at had a bunch of
Vancouver Island purple crosses um and a
bunch of crosses so we actually had a
bunch of um you know Vancouver Island um
early finishing pures crossed into some
like old school neighborhood Northern
Lights crosses so that was actually the
first stuff I grew in California was you
know Canadian you know stuff and did
great it's beautiful herb that wasn't
from Legends was
it it was some people who had come and
worked on farms and they brought
genetics with them that they had been
working on um in the in Vancouver Island
and then those just made a impact you
know it's like they were living in the
neighborhood and brought genetics and
combined them with the old school
neighborhood stuff and some people still
had it yeah that's awesome go ahead
Caleb we cut you off there no worries
yeah let's uh um we get some intros from
our two newest guests here um L from
meno dope and also [ __ ] Glory our
mesino Representatives today
yeah good morning good morning good
morning morning
glory morning brother I guess I'll start
it off oh lost you one moment there you
go uh yep Morning Glory as I mentioned
I'm here in mesino County uh wow where
to begin I have a passion for the hashen
I also love to DJ on the side and lately
starting last year I decided what
happens if I wanted to combine both
passion both DJing and hash making by
which honestly I put it um me and a good
homie of mine who's been kind of doing
this thing for a while now put our
talents together and we've been on this
this little bit of a quest this last few
year uh myself I should say along with
him within this last year of finding the
right frequencies vibrations HTS and
honestly D dejing and using bass as the
agitation process
I was just going to say are you doing
that already right now yes we've been
talking about that for a while too it's
the coolest thing ever to make some Keef
with some Bas y yep actually I remember
sub subcool rest in peace was was using
a Bas key agitated Keef and then I
remember seeing that and honestly before
I started doing hash making back in the
day I was I remember watching
documentaries about Mor hash making in
Morocco in which you would see the uh
sticks and beat SI process happening so
I'm like all right if they're beating
the plant material they're using a
vibration so what happens if I as a
little R&amp;D what happens if I took a
bunch of my Grinders put them on my subs
and DJ to see what would happen and
little suc had great success and then
all right not just dry sifting but what
about ice waterer
sifting
Savage and yep it's been real positive
results you know what else works really
good is
Ultrasonics yes when you use Ultrasonics
either with alcohol uh for example you
can put ground up Buds and uh just do it
for like 30 45 seconds and the uh what
you get is gold the green doesn't come
out fast enough and beautiful it's it's
incredible
awesome actually um in terms of
Ultrasonics um I've been using
ultrasonic as a way of cleaning the
resin once it's sifted through the
microns and so I'll be honest like in
terms of cleaning that
resin um I'll I'll be real in this in
this little R&amp;D process I have not used
a hose or a or a sand a fan setting on
the hose to clean the resin at all it's
only been Ultrasonics and it's been
working and how clean does it get uh um
pretty uh honestly uh the market I have
with people interested it's that old
school hashes quality and it's a good
melt full melt bubble style if it don't
bubble it ain't worth the trouble and
it's been never trouble so far I I made
that
up yes sir hon to be in your
presence Savage that's a cool thing I
just wanted to jump in I actually just
got back from Morocco not that long ago
and what you mentioned Morning Glory
like I took note right away where
everyone was talking about like who was
beating the best hash and it was all
about what Rhythm they had and so like
in the family that I was like hanging
out with it was like the different sons
all had different rhythms and they'd all
argue no mine's the best mine's the best
and it'd be like oh listen to the
pattern and then smoke the hash and it
was like you could tell the difference
because it was how long they did it you
know what kind of thing I never thought
about the science behind it as much as
you but uh immediately that clicked to
my head is like Ah that's that's where
it's at being a drummer myself so the
only trouble with Moroccan hatch is it's
all made with seeded marijuana it's not
CIA so it's hard to be the best of the
best of the
best yeah that we could talk about yeah
quality issues there all day I think but
the the science behind like kind of the
culture of them beating was great
yeah oh yeah but I tell you what though
I was out there in Casablanca for three
days and I was hot as
[ __ ] that's what's up well you know what
you do you listen I've had to smoke
things of a much lower caliber in my
days depending on to me it's always what
you have whenever someone says what's
what's your favorite hash I'm like wow
the one that was
grown like perfectly I I I less I care
less about the aromatic profile then I
do care about how well has it expressed
itself because at that point in time I
can lean towards any flavor profile sure
I love the haze that's kind of my
all-time favorites and I have an
appreciation for Fruity and the gassy
and all these different varieties garlic
and Funk and but I really would choose
the one that was grown the best every
time there's no flavor profile that
would have me choose something that was
a little bit below something else just
because I preferred that flavor profile
that's how much my um focus is on the
caliber the Purity and the quality
that's my focus has always been on
effects so to be up clear High Speedy I
don't really like couch lock weed
although I understand how medical users
do like couch lock because they they're
in physical
pain I like I like cash back and it
ain't because of physical pain I like
the full
effect got it full effect so
uh speaking of very efficacious cultiv
ours um congrats to Mendo Dope on the
recent Emerald cup win yes thank you my
brother yeah that Hees is a it's very
special strain we've been liking for
quite a few years now we've been growing
more and more of it throughout the last
couple years that's since we found it
from the from the re Edge you know I
don't if did you see the story from the
Emerald Triangle thing they did a little
cartoon even about the little story was
pretty funny um but yeah it was found at
our homies garden and that was already
in full flower um a homie passed away
that year so we were going to his garden
to go check out what his plants look
like to help his dad kind of put strains
together because he had a lot of seed
start stuff so he's trying to pack
things to sell and what can mix together
and we found that one right there and
cut the Clone that's already you know
deep October so full eight nine weeks on
the flower of it and then slowly brought
it back the next year had a couple
clones tested it indoors next year was
perfect to do an outside test it did
pretty good and then we did a big
outside garden of it at the at the farm
we had with Cody and
um so yeah that one is it's just like a
straight old school gas but there's a
little something hiding in there too
it's like a 90 I'd say like
95% old school gas and it's a little bit
of every gas it's hard to even say which
OG it is it's like a it's just like a
really good OG of a little combo from
like the best ogs that we used to have
like not even ones that we ever grew cuz
we never really got a really good OG to
grow before we always would get cuts
from clubs and get us something that not
what we wanted we're always trying to
find these couple different ogs that we
would get eights of you know and be like
man if we could get this cut but we
never could find it so then after
finding this one it's like the gassiest
one we've ever had our favorite like
just Kush strain in our mother room and
our like selection and um it's uh super
super nice strain just super cool and uh
grows really badass and it's really cool
that the judges all liked it it was
funny too because like you know gas has
been uh a little bit on the back burner
now after all the Exotic candy gas
things that people are on and all of the
new hype stuff so for it to be like
catch the judges for like a just nice
pretty close to all traditional OG kind
of profile was really cool to see
how people like uh Emeral cut people are
a little different too than other people
too they're more old school and they're
very smart and they're not like a normal
other cups you know that they could be
tricked by the hype stuff so it's cool
to see like people that really took the
time to like it liked it like as much as
we like it so it's really cool to
see cool story
too Strain To Us yeah [ __ ] came together
yeah it's like well we're gonna have to
keep this forever you know like this
isn't we we we keep strains probably for
like we've had our we had a vanilla cush
strain we had for like 11 years as
longest we ever had one strain for and
then that strain kind of got maybe sick
or sad or H Latin virus or something it
stopped gr on to grow really vigorously
and we just got rid of it but besides
that one strain we kind of keep strains
for a few years maybe three four years
and then we'll we'll move on again and
kind of switch things the mother room
around and but that he strain in general
will be like a forever strain for us and
we've been Crossing strains to that now
for a little bit so we have all kinds of
strains with that lineage from it so
it's really cool to see new stuff that's
back dates to that
also you keep your clones clean
you can keep I've had them for more than
30 years and they were just as good as
they were 30 years ago but I used
Extreme Measures to keep them clean
including not taking any new plant into
my facilities until I had uh field Tri
trialed it for uh 6 months or so yeah I
bet that's probably how you have to be
real serious these days with everything
going on and all the strains that have
you know all the strains you can get
that are disease ridden and whatever and
really for our mother room our whole
life since we we started keeping that
vanilla strain we kept in like
200 in in 12 or 2011 when we first kept
like mothers and that was the first
clone we kept as like a forever like all
year long we keep it and all the next
year we have it and we have it and and
our mother sex like a lot of our mother
rooms we would just let them barely live
like sometimes during the winter they're
just like very dormant like in uh um
like I forget what the word would be
right now but it's like they're like in
limbo they're not really happy they're
not vigorous because we don't have a lot
of space to have like vigorous plants
the whole all winter and all year and
the amount of moms that we do have so we
for a long time we keep our moms in the
winter time really slow growing kind of
sad and then we'll boost them back up in
the in the season I had a a cold grow
refrigerator so I kept the temperature
at 4 or
5° and uh
you hardly had to water it at all and it
had grow lights fluoresence inside the
refrigerator that's just super smart
yeah that's it seems like keeping them
in that dormant slow motion grow is not
a problem to slow down things and be
able to
maintain U but with us like we that
vanilla mon we almost lost it like 10
different times throughout the 11 years
we had it like it just it got it would
get sick and then when russets hit that
year russets hit hard out here it got
russets bad and we we barely kept it
alive that year and then it's like that
thing went through hell and so it's like
not far-fetched that it would catch
something and it probably maybe someone
could have cleaned it we liked it a lot
but we also you know it was cool to have
it for as long as we had it we didn't
need to to force force at one time I had
360 mothers and a few fathers damn and
uh yeah my employees sort of rebelled
against me so I knocked it down to 120
so I've had happen a lot I've had people
rebel against my collections you know
like I've had I've had whole years where
we've you know cloned you know 750
plants and went through multiple rounds
of testing only for someone in the
winter to let stuff go without
permission because it's challenging to
manage with a you know when you're
limited with space or electricity
especially growing off great a lot in
Northern California um so I feel that I
for what's funny is as long as I've been
growing weed there's such a small
percentage of time that I had actual
control of a year round mom room where
someone wouldn't make mistakes you know
and now I you know even in in Humble you
know we play musical Grow rooms in the
winter we use our cloning room which is
you know small we have to you know you
know burn fuel which is very wasteful to
do that then we fire up the greenhouse
and put a bunch of propane in at a
certain point but it's it's a year round
evolving thing that's a challenge and
and not efficient with with cost or
anything uh when you're off- grid and
super Rural and then here on the East
Coast we Bank all my stuff so I have my
stuff banked here and have a pretty
decent collection and some of the the
males that we use so we can recreate not
have to re reselect and then the goal
for years is I've been trying to get my
you know my more special stuff banked
with tissue culture but I haven't
trusted any of the tissue culture people
that exist that are offering Services um
and I'm about to do some initiations and
then you know keeping them clean and
making sure that you have you know lab
testing that they pathogen and and vroid
free it's it's a big Challenge and a a
big challenge in in cultivating that
didn't you know exist when you go back
15 years ago um that's absolutely true
I've I've found 29 different viruses in
cannabis damn
D yeah whatever that Vanilla Kush had it
would like the Vanilla Kush was always a
[ __ ] to root too it was so hard to root
it take longer than any strain we've
ever had our whole life they'll always
be sad by the time they rooted so that
was a problem but that that was like we
would get them to root though and then
they would grow kind of good and veg and
we put them outside they look happy but
as soon as they start to get a little
bit of a teen mode and a little bit
where everything's starting to rip that
would just be dormant and slow down and
then as it went to flower it started
just dying like yellowing out and not
putting out the smallest buds ever it
was like a tricks for like two or three
years we thought we could like save it
and the mom would be good and we'd get
clones and they'd start to look good and
we' be like nice it's maybe it's back
but then no it just go to [ __ ] right by
the time it really need to start doing
something that's why I always try to
give stuff to other people I trust you
know it's hard to trust people but every
year before the winter I'd always try to
get the most important things to at
least a few people so hopefully if you
know if everybody made a mistake one
person would still have it you know very
smart yeah very very have our our heades
now we have a couple people with the
heades cuz we cannot lose that [ __ ]
strain so we had to make sure yeah it's
not on just one person I mean even when
the fires came through you know a couple
years ago those three years of fires
straight that was also a crazy hurdle
and pain in the ass to keep mothers
going it was like uh very dangerous you
know just having one of a kind plant one
unicorn in the world we could have it
somewhere like like sometimes we have
our homie now in Minnesota have some
cuts for like Minnesota nice hold some
things for us we're going to start
having him have like couple various rins
just like we the [ __ ] away from
California's fires first off fires would
be probably the one of the top 10 ways
you could lose your [ __ ] [ __ ]
nowadays I I would grow a one or two big
plants in the ground that would be 15 ft
tall and I would grow uh maybe five of
them in uh like a 5 10 L Pot and then I
would grow a couple of them in a
refrigerated uh uh cold refrigerator
with grow lights and uh I I never lost
one that's that's
badass the cold that was over a 30y year
period that's like with our mothers we
have we have a big like a 60x 4 like
metal shop for the last like quite a few
years now where our Grandpa's house was
that we took over and that's like where
our moms are and our studio is and we
have our little Hut for like our our
moms we don't have we only have we keep
we keep we've always we never gone hard
like you guys we keep like 31 like
masking Robins has always been like
something we like 31 Flavors like if we
have 31's I don't know how why we would
need more I know it's so [ __ ] easy to
hoard and keep everything but we would
try to once we get past that we try to
weed it back down so we can fit like our
moms in the dormant state in our little
Hut upstairs in the in the Machine Shop
so it's [ __ ] freezing in there too
like like your fridge technique and that
is how like it's been helpful for us to
not have just full-time vigorous plants
all year round constantly transplanting
and keeping them fed and happy and
cutting them cutting them cutting
them and we've always done lot smaller
Gardens Too than a lot of people
throughout the years once we got raided
in
2013 or whatever we uh we just started
filming our personal Gardens you know
like everyone's known like our our
YouTube stuff is like it's all like six
plants and 12 plants like we got rated
with the 25 because they were too big
and then instead of just going in the
hills and teaming up with people are
going and getting a property where we
were just going to blow it up we were so
focused in music we wanted to do music
so much not disappear and then then that
kind of made us like get into the and
subcool made us get into filming the
garden at the same time so we're filming
music stuff filming the garden stuff at
the same time but growing so much
smaller Gardens than so many people are
doing it's only the last couple years
we've been doing these bigger Gardens
where thousands of plants shout out to
sub cool and uh what a what a great
[ __ ] dude man like just knew the guy
for so long such a character such a
lover of of cannabis a true bubble
Ambassador truly turned so many people
onto bubble hash and uh created or
helped create some very well-known names
in the hash World from supplying such
great cannabis and if you had subcool in
your life you were like if and and you
were paying attention you also had great
weed oh yeah for sure he game he laced
our game up for sure a lot with the
indoor stuff and with hash and
solventless and clean clean weed in
general just like watering with just
water and super soil and not liquid
feeding every single watering and all
the stuff we were told like tricked by
in the beginning of the
times yeah and he lost his place in a
fire wasn't that right remember yeah
yeah that fire was like the 2017 fire I
think or something that's right he was
on hash church I think the following
week yeah tell that he got out with
nothing more than his backpack a
baseball hat and like a small little
bong and a small statue weed well I was
talking to him while it was happening
and he was trying to get back in his
truck to like this to to get back to his
property uh and that's why I invited him
on to Hash Church the next week that was
uh yeah that was shocking man fire that
just wiped out Santa Rosa right it wiped
out like a lion through Santa Rosa like
it came over the mountain right where
sub's house was kind of in towards the
start of that fire and it he was way up
in the mountains compared to the down
low Santa Rosa area it turned over the
hill wiped his house down almost like a
[ __ ] fire waterfall or a river or
some [ __ ] straight line through his
property through the people down him
straight to the bottom of where Santa
Rose the town is took out like a a big
hotel and a couple other trailer parks
crossed the [ __ ] freeway went through
skinny neighborhood down to this block
at the end that took out the entire
[ __ ] residential block that was
like it was a crazy crazy fire for sure
it was one of the biggest ones that's
ever been out here that burnt sub's
house down that [ __ ] was was like uh
probably like very similar to what's
going on in La like full tornadoes of
Fire full
like when sub would just explained it he
said it came over the hill and exploded
trees on the way down like when it hit
the fire would come like a waterfall he
said and then as it hit the next tree
the tree would explode and go down to
the next one it wasn't like the fire was
a normal fire you know it's it's just
exploding through the forest just
ripping down the hill like downhill too
you know it's not wasn't even going
uphill it's just going
downhill that's [ __ ] I was in Santa
Rosa when that one went down and that
was a crazy experience you know because
I I used to stay at those hotels on the
The Fountain Grove when I used to come
into town business those were like my
spots and I had actually just moved to
Santa Rosa and rented a house and it was
my first night in the rental house and
no nobody knew that I was there and I'd
moved for a business deal or whatever
and um I was about to move my my my
family out they were going to be there
like you know whatever but I woke up at
6:00 in the morning I went to bed and I
could smell smoke and I could hear what
I thought was gunshots and I was like
who'd be stupid enough to burn a wood
stove right now you know with the with
the wind and and how dry it was when I
woke up in the morning I found out that
what I thought was gunshots was the
propane tanks exploding in people's
homes like a mile and a half down the
road from where I was so I I went to go
check on my other friend's house and set
up sprinklers on people's houses in
downtown Santa Rosa and yeah I that I
mean the ones in La I think are a lot
even crazier and worse but yeah yeah
honestly that's that's of the reasons I
chose to leave California part-time was
like you know full-time was because my
kids kept being exposed to so much smoke
from so many fires so many weeks out of
the year and it was so intense you know
what I'm saying and um it's it's really
unfortunate difficult situation for
people out there yeah it's really bad it
sucks so bad because sub cool like we we
met sub through the Cannabis cups like
early on and right when he was moving
out of Oregon and he was finding a place
in California then he found the Santa
Rosa house and he was so close to us it
was it was right as we were starting to
become like super fans of his when we
met him and he moved closer to us then
we just clicked and he was able to drive
to our house and we could drive to his
house anytime and his house was super
sick and he was just starting to grow
outdoor like it was like his second or
third year doing like the man dope style
outdoor at his house and it was so
[ __ ] cool and as soon as that
happened it all went to [ __ ] like he was
already going through so much [ __ ] with
his health and with Jill and stuff and
then that just [ __ ] his rest of his
life up that fire [ __ ] it up so bad
it's so sad how many people have to go
through same some things similar to like
how sub did but sub had so much on top
of his plate already at the fire just
[ __ ] changed his life for the like
fully he was just it was so sad because
we just didn't get see him no more it
was only a couple weeks he was in Cali
after that and then it was gone and we
saw him in in Arizona once but it was uh
super shitty his house was really cool
and I mean just the seats he had his his
where the seed Vault was like on his
bottom uh downstairs of his house or
whatever like all that [ __ ] [ __ ] gone
we went up there to his house like a
month or so after the fires and walked
around and looked at it and we grabbed
one of the stocks that was left like it
all burnt one of his trees that he had
there was a nice stock we kept and we
have it in our in like our house and
stuff just like for a memory but it's
[ __ ] so sad dude so sad but sub was
he was yeah he had fire so long ago so
many fenos could have been kept as one
name it whatever the [ __ ] you want to
name he probably had a Lemon Cherry
gelato similar variety and his [ __ ]
pheno mixes and [ __ ] he made you know
what I mean he had so many cool strains
so with the people he was working with
too like in his circle of who was making
stuff with him and and I'll say this
about sub like his Cult of
ours obviously who grew it was fairly
important but it seemed like it was they
were somewhat more generous for some
people that maybe if you were had never
grown full melt resin before you might
have the best chance doing it with some
of his cultivars they were just like
everyone I ever tried was just slamming
like so good so tasty so strong he
always just had great hash and I listen
I go back with I don't even know what
year it would have been whatever year he
met Jill cuz I was on like like chat
rooms in the
90s with her Jill and this guy Jack they
were like Jack and Jill that's what they
went under this was her original like
boyfriend or husband or whatever he was
to her soon after Jack disappeared and
then sub popped in and that's how I met
sub was through Jill so really I I feel
like I met him before he made any I feel
like we were both really working on
making our marks
simultaneously and uh you know he was uh
he was a character had that uh certain
people were like whoa this guy's too
much and I was just like no man I'm from
Winnipeg like he's he's a perfect amount
for
me yep it would be times it was it was
the first dude I remember we went to
after we got ra he took us to uh to a
nice dinner and stuff we had a big talk
about everything that happened and um he
would be like going to like nice fancy
restaurants and telling the waiters like
he's like you know who we are we're
cannabis celebrities we're like famous
can like he's the only was like back a
long time ago dude he's like telling
random people like I'm a cannabis
celebrity like I am this is who the [ __ ]
I am you don't know who I am here take
some weed a hat pin or whatever I was
laughing so hard I'm like damn that
Savage just just be that ballsy dude
he's so ballsy to tell people and then
be filming like you're saying too like
the homie nick uh box who we got the
headiest from um he's the one who
introduced us to subcool and he was
following I think he was also following
you too I remember him talking about you
years ago I think now that you say that
he was on the forums and he was on the
[ __ ] before we ever were on YouTube and
these chats that you guys were doing
Nick was on that [ __ ] right that's
awesome very cool we had Zach G come in
we had Mojave come in and we've uh yeah
so welcome to those uh two welcome Zach
welcome Z how's going I like that both
you and Mojave at least appear to be
standing
outside I'm waiting for my kids a flag
football game to start so I'm kind of
tucked off in the side of this school
dude that's what's up on hash Church
waiting for a flag football to start I
like it I like
your this is real outside it's a it's
[ __ ] cold and wet and it's super
weird to be up here I'm in Oregon I like
drove out of La watched all the smoke
and [ __ ] and left my family and moved
into a bunch of came up here to a bunch
of rain and moisture
so hello everyone hold I couldn't tell
if you had a green screen going and you
were just really trying to sell that
[ __ ] so you had the hoodlum and the
[ __ ]
tuon hay Valley yo hay Valley e yeah
Santa Cruz hay Valley really good
genetics that's itth it's a Green Valley
Road you know it man on it's all about
bring the haze back Blue Halo that
flavor was so
good when I was going the Wham Garden
that was H Ryan would come through with
some genetics and we put them in the
Wham field so a lot of love for Hayes
Valley
beautiful I had some stuff in the field
as well go ahead Caleb yeah so uh Zach
runs a brand out in Sacramento called
Amplified farms and um we've gone to
some shows uh together and I know one of
my favorite Cult of ours from Amplified
is called Cypress OG and I was wondering
perhaps you could share the the story of
how yall got that um we that was just
basically gifted around our circle of
friends that were grew and it went by a
few different names over the years and
supposedly uh our one buddy that got it
first got it from I think DJ mugs or
something so when we wanted to like name
it for the brand we just kind of called
it Cypress OG just to give a nod to
those guys but uh it's one of my
favorite Cuts still to this day um just
hits every time and um it's kind of like
listening to you guys earlier about like
keeping moms alive for a long time and
that was the one that the group of
friends was always making sure somebody
had alive so um yeah I was uh people
called it the Tahoe G for a while and I
think it went under a few different
names over the years but um yeah great
great strain just great effect probably
still my favorite thing we
grow is that also known as that Ricky's
Brothers cush or whatever I'm not sure I
I mean I'm sure it's known as a few
things but I I I can't speak to that I
don't know uh know about that but um you
know it
grows it gets big you know when it's
healthy it does really well but um yeah
just just a solid OG it's got the nose
it's got the effect um love that
strain rbk is just reg is just old
school OG it's the same cut same cut
right it's all the same
cut most of them are the it's so badass
I've heard a lot of that about that
story any like whatever podcast I was
listening to also on the first smoke of
the day I got a little more info from
that I've always we've you know listened
to cyber seal so much and there like
knowing about that like hearing about
that [ __ ] for so long it's so cool to
keep a strain that long and share with
people and for you guys I got to get to
sack and get some of that [ __ ] I got I
got a Cypress Hill story that's kind of
relevant to keeping strains and all that
[ __ ] um in 93 when I moved to
Amsterdam um Adam Adam dun had just
gotten his um gotten the bubble gum
seats he had I think 13 fenos or so that
came out and this is like summer of 93
and Cypress Hill had just come into the
town you know they were just new I mean
they were just guys right like they're
just a new band and it was Cypress Hill
House of Pain and Funk dubus they were
doing this that tour and we were hanging
out with them at ciny seeds and stuff
and they're doing all their promotional
stuff there and anyway I think it was
maybe the first I'm not sure if it was
the first time we met yeah it was the
first time we met him and Adam had just
harvested this bubble gum and we he had
like one plant that was yielded really
low I mean it was like and this is like
Amsterdam closet grow imagine a closet
in Amsterdam right it's like it's like
the size of this chair right and there
was like these are the magic beans from
his homie back back in back East back in
Ro Island who got him from the guy and
you know the whole story anyway he pops
the beans and one of them was just like
the most to this day I know everyone's
got the stories of the memories because
it's a weird sense memory but to this
day it was just one of those holy [ __ ]
that's not really that's weed can't
taste like that it's just like crazy
like your mouth you kept chewing and
just like while you were smoking it it
was just like and the high wasn't that
great it wasn't that it wasn't that
insane but the taste was just like nuts
so we went after the show I think it was
at the Paradiso we went back to the
hotel room with with um with uh Cypress
Hill I mugs wasn't there I guess it was
just um be real and um anyway we smoked
them out they were blown away they were
just like dude I've never tried like
that and we gave them them all the wheat
right just like take it whatever gave
them like the 10 of the 13 grams that
there was or something like that you
know that was left and then um so we had
all of those set up at Adam's Place and
then Adam's place got robbed someone who
had smelled what was going on in town
did not like what was going on and they
br came in there and they stole all the
cuts and they went it was creepy man
they went and broke all the moms they
just snapped all their backs and left
them there like in the apartment like
walking in a crime scene just like a
bunch of dead plants and only one of all
the moms was able to
get reved out of all those dead plants
or dying plants a clone sorry a clone
that got off of those dying plants and
it wasn't Cypress Hill cut though it was
not and that bubble gum became the
parent to all the bubble gum of today
was what
from that that's what went to Serious
seeds and that's what went to you know
Saga mother and all that so the real
Bubblegum the Cypress Hill cut which was
just [ __ ] insane just insane so and
it was the only one that was and the one
that survived was yeah it was bubble gum
and it tastes like bubble gum it was a
good cut it was actually a good like
medium version to get a lot but the real
the Cypress Hill
cut
[ __ ] and that's few times I've ever seen
like uh you know that kind of weird
jealousy kind of thing where someone was
like your genetics need to die like and
then the weird part is like they took
them and we knew right away it's like
well you can never use it you can only
breed with it because can't grow it
amram's a small town you can't like
start pulling out bubble gum just like
where did you get it so such a weird
like history in the cannabis genetics of
how intense it can be when something new
pops up and who has it and who can have
it and who's jealous and who you know
weird is real ain't it the hate is real
oh yeah it's fear and scarcity man
people start getting insecure with fear
and scarcity they can do some silly
things I uh I prefer love and
abundance makes me a happier person yeah
I have a interesting I keep seeing uh DJ
Morning Glory there hitting his three-
hole Hash Pipe and um I'm reminded of
the time that I met him at Black Oak
Ranch at an event called the kind bud
camp out and you know he taught me how
to use that three hole um does anyone
have any stories about kind of that
correlation between glass and cannabis
and music and all these events that uh
may have seen each other at I well I I
got a good story my buddy uh Jamie from
uh heavy glass bong he's up in in uh
Oregon now but um a band I was playing
in in the early 2000s we used to
practice in his uh he had a couple
warehouses in I think Gardina or
something we used to rehearse there
while there was like a whole crew of
people uh blowing uh tubes and he had an
assembly line going and that was right
when like uh Jerome
Baker um got popped and then all of a
sudden he was like the biggest biggest
fish in the pond so then I think he he
got rid of his company but he used to go
on tour with our band and and we never
had any money but he he would always
just make sure we had a killer time and
was just just an awesome awesome like
inspirational dude that just lived life
his own way just uh total Savage and um
yeah it was it was really good I
remember taking a guitar and burning
part of it with the uh with the torch
from the uh from the glass making the
making the tubes and still got a burn
mark on it but yeah just those times
were pretty uh pretty awesome just like
when things were a little more
underground and a little more closeted
and uh and and just like uh just the way
he ran his whole operation you'd have a
couple non-descript Vans where he'd do
his runs to supply his uh you know head
shops and he'd book some of it around
some of our tours so we'd always have
someone fun to hang out with at the end
of the night but yeah that was a that
was pretty pretty cool scene back then
I don't know if anybody knows
Jamie yeah I'm trying to think if I do
i' I for whatever reason always had a
very strong connection to the glass
blowing World from pretty early on I
would say my
first pipe was I I want to say
94 I think I
bought a hug grass it was one of snod
grass's like students I got a little Hue
grass pipe and I went to Amsterdam that
year or no the next year and I ended up
selling it because someone apparently
needed it more than I needed it but I
ended up meeting marble Slinger before
he was marble Slinger uh at that
Cannabis Cup I it was super weird
because years later I actually met him
by picking him up hitchhiking on the way
to a fish show uh at the Gorge but he
was living in I'm I'm guessing close to
where Dan is right now he said he was 30
minutes from the border if he's on the
west coast anyway because he was in uh
uh
Bellingham I'm close to Quebec oh Quebec
okay on the East Coast right awesome um
Vermont right um yeah so these guys all
lived in Bellingham and there was a lot
of them there was Marcel braa who's this
just incredible glass blower like top of
his game he was he was like creating and
building tools to do things things that
no one had done with glass yet so he was
really going down the R&amp;D hole plus he
was just beyond talented Savant style
but then there was also you know Slinger
and and Zach and Pedro Smiley and d and
Max Poland got a little Max Poland piece
right here that uh sits on my side here
Jason Lee was a part of that group so
they had this huge contingency of these
glass blowers I'll be honest this was
really pre Bubble Man pre-bubble hash so
for me I was just chain smoking joints
like huge giant joints smoking insane
amounts of them I didn't really smoke
with pipes these guys [ __ ] put like
took Buds and like smashed them into
their bowl of their pipe and then just
hit it and I was like I was intrigued so
as I met them really because I met them
at 98 at the Gorge and you know within a
year later I was basically going to have
access to Bubble has so by the time I
really befriended them through email and
whatnot and invited them to come up it
was 45 minutes for them to come from
Bellingham right to my deck in Canada
here and literally that house is two
doors down for me that we used to have
all those meetings but uh they really
helped turn me on to the glass world uh
the the art form of it the the
awesomeness for flower I missed the boat
but for smoking hash purely like having
like the stain steel screen with the the
match or even better like the beline
wick and just like fading the flame over
the hash and boiling it and even though
there was no carb cap and it was
probably not the most efficient way to
do things it was still an
incredible time to be alive and be
exposed uh to these different things it
was part of my journey surely and so
yeah old full melt
Bubbles and Jason had a um before Jerome
Baker was Jerome Baker um he had a
little spot right next to Adam's CIA
spot in Amsterdam where he would blow
and it was a trip because I'd never seen
anyone you know i' never seen anyone
blowing glass before you know other than
that like a fair making a little
Trinkets and stuff and here's this kid
you know his long-hair young kid and
he's over there and he's just in this
old building like in the middle of this
kind of old Warehouse that looks like
it's an old like just Old Ship or
something and me and Rober buffing and
you know most of the bowls that you'd
get pull bowls you'd get were like
Graphics pull bowls that were like a
serious deep angle and we're puffing
bubbling hash you know and we're like
dude this this just clogs the bowl every
time and even to put a screen in there
you have to [ __ ] push it in so Jason
was like yeah he's like oh how would you
what what do you I'm like can you make
it a little more u-shaped and a little
flatter and he's like yeah I'll be right
back and he runs over and he's like
literally like 20 minutes later he comes
back and gives us the bowl and we start
puffing it's just like what just
happened did that just happen right now
and it's a trip because you know Jason
Harris everyone calls him Jerome Baker
because jome B his company and for I
didn't even know for like a couple years
and I used to sell their stuff at a shop
I used to run and I asked him one time I
was like dude why is it Jerome Baker
he's like dud Garcia
man he's like getting B because it's
like you know so glass and glass and and
the dead and music are just like like it
wouldn't have happened it's just that
was the first glass blowing I also saw
and I I met uh Jay in 95 when that I I
believe it was 95 that they that he had
that studio and Adam still had the CIA
because I think he closed it soon after
and then opened the KGB 94 it would have
by 95 I think was open yeah so by I
think it was just from like mid mid late
93 all the way through 94 and that would
have been it awesome yeah it was cool
yeah good times can I actually I gotta
roll man but I just because it's the
music thing I'll give you can I give you
a quick story on my cannabis music
relationship please that's what we want
right on um so I grew up you know with a
lot of musicians around and stuff and
music was always a part of it and
obviously cannabis is in music so I
actually moved to Amsterdam to do music
um one of my family friends was a guitar
player for Nina Simone and he lived in
France and he said like come on out and
I'll Mentor you and you do music you
know learn jazz guitar and I wanted to
take it to the next level I was like
yeah cool man I I basically came out
there got a one-way ticket and partied
in Amsterdam for a few months and
hitchhiked to France and like some dumb
kid with like a big bag of hash and a
guitar in a backpack I realized that my
mentor had moved back to the US like
four weeks earlier because we were
communicating on like postcards and
[ __ ] payones and [ __ ] right and I
literally stranded in Paris with no
money and nothing but hash um which was
better than money because whenever you
found people who needed hash right got
you that's how I survive got like a
place to stay and food anyway and I
called up Amsterdam and called up and
got Monica
at ciny seeds on the phone and Monica's
like why don't you you know come back up
here and we became a couple and I we end
up living with Monica and I started
growing and breeding and while I was in
Amsterdam this
band um and I fell in love with with
cannabis you know with with the whole
culture in Amsterdam and there was this
band that was an LA band that was local
band you know playing around and they
got signed and they were doing they
needed their guitar player quit and they
needed another guitar player and I was
like well I play guitar because I I
can't remember how I knew these guys and
they're like and and I'm from La they
like perfect it's like oh yeah dude and
so we're rehearsing and starting to do
some recording and then actually yeah
that's they got signed afterwards and
they had like this five record deal and
a tour and all this [ __ ] and they're
like all right we're goingon to go we're
going to start touring in Germany we're
going to go around the world blah blah
blah and I said you know what I I think
I'm just gonna stay in Amsterdam and
grow weed
like it's just I I couldn't feel it it
was just weird I was like the plant was
so like dude I'm here it's like right
here it's like if you can play music and
be with me then that'll work but if
you're going to go off in the world then
we're definitely going to part ways you
know what I mean because traveling in
the early 90s and cannabis was always
such a challenge so I decided just to
stay with the
plan and you know and that band went off
and they're like went crazy and they all
had all this crazy drama on their world
tour and you know following your passion
is like definitely important but for me
it was definitely sticking with weed it
was The Sage it was The Sage dude I
couldn't couldn't was it's like part of
my uh part of my DNA you know Sage
needed to
exist I I got a jump my kid game's about
ready to start but I really appreciate
you having me on thanks Zack enjoy guys
I will have a good day
manv I I see I seem to remember your
story having a exposure to the Grateful
Dead at a early early age right isn't
there a story there oh yeah no I my um
my dad's best friend was the road
manager for the grateful Dad before they
were the dad he was he old friend of
Jerry's and um he was like he was more
than my uncle he was like another dad to
me someone I grew up with my whole life
and he was a total character we had lots
of
musicians in you know in the scene in
Big Sir and yeah it we were very um my
dad was a Smuggler at one point and him
and his best buddy had all kinds of
strange uh relationships with the dead
around you know
um cannabis and but um but yeah it goes
way back and his family his his kids are
still good
friends and I I never really appreciated
growing up like what that meant like
being like you know it's like just the
Grateful Dead was just a kind of a
fixture you know of our family you know
Hell's Angels like my mom tells stories
about like you know hell Hell's Angels
showing up on a dirt road in Big Sir on
like Harley's like 30 bringing food for
us because you know they found out that
a bunch of hippies living on this out in
the woods didn't have food and so we had
this weird Bay Area um connection we
live my family lived in Moran too before
we moved to Big Sir um so yeah it goes
way back with the dead but then later in
life as a teenager when they reemerged
in you know I guess you know in the 80s
when it became a big thing then I you
know started going to shows again
and you know by then my uncle was no
longer involved because he got way
whacked out and drugs and all that stuff
but um he kind of reintroduced me to
that scene and he his kids as well got
reintroduced to the scene and started
going to shows backstage passes going
there and hanging out with the dead in
the back there you know just like a trip
just like a little kid on acid there
while the wives are making them
sandwiches and I'm just like wow
sandwiches look really good could I have
a sandwich like the [ __ ] are you like
I'm just I'm just here I've got this
pass and people say I can go places you
know are you amazed are are you amazed
like me like when you look back now like
here we are in 2025 and it was just kind
of like a flash in the pan that they
existed for the 30 years that they did
here we are and going to be the 60th
year of Grateful Dead music and man it
seems like their music is bigger today
than it was was when when Jerry checked
out right like there's Grateful Dead
cover bands in every you know part of
the country performing that music and
there's really famous musicians who
perform the music of Grateful Dead so I
think it has something to do with the
staying power of the music but does it
Amaze you Mojave like when you look back
like to think that oh my God here it is
like so many years after Jerry's gone
and the actual configuration that we
knew The Grateful Dead has been ceased
to exist for a while but that body of
Music exists and you know I think it has
to do with the taping you know they
allowed taping at their show and that
was a really smart move it didn't seem
like a smart move at the time but if you
think about it there's more recordings
of the Grateful Dead than any other band
on the planet if you think about like
all the tapes in everyone's Collections
and and the way it's the way it was
traded to me it's just it's it's
phenomenal just to think about I think
the music well the I think the music is
important and the music is beautiful and
that is definitely 100% true Mark but I
think more than the the to me the real
reason the dead is still relevant and
people listen to the music and the cover
bands and all the similar bands and jam
bands is because the spirit of what the
dead was and that connective tissue that
they were for
Humanity in as a community was so needed
right like what if the what would the
world be like like you can't take you
can like I love Jimmy Hendricks I love
Le Zeppelin I love the Beatles I love a
lot of classic rock but you could remove
all those people from those bands from
the world and the world would be
different but if you took the dead out
of the human history of the world man we
it'd be very different right they they
created this cultural movement that
branched off into all these different
facets into cannabis into glass into
culture into Tech into art into you know
whatever they're like a they're like a
anthropological phenomenon so it's
like what happened in and around that
scene especially as it relates to
cannabis and psychedelics and you I
guess having a good time in general is
you know like if you go to a billy
string so Billy strings again just like
incredible musician and he's got a scene
outside of his shows the proverbial
Shakedown Street right where there's
people who are vending all kinds of you
know wees and you could get good glass
pipes you could probably get good weed I
mean the thing is is that that that
business model of having a culture kind
of develop around your music I think the
dead were the first to do that right cuz
like you the great bands that you
mentioned and I I grew up listening to
Prague Rock ELP yes you know Genesis
great music and such a you know period
of time when you know when you got
records you had to go to the record
store The Day the album was released and
then you brought that album home and you
clean your weed on it and you put the
headphones on and you got lost in Pink
Floyd Animals or you know remember all
that great music that went kind like it
created and this goes back to this
episode right Caleb a connection between
The Human Experience of music and like
getting high like when you got home with
that Talking Heads album that was just
released and you're getting high and
you're listening to that album for the
first time like maybe you've heard a
couple of the songs on the radio but
like it's not like it is today I mean
you heard that song on the radio you had
to wait till the radio station plays it
again to hear it again I remember
listening to uh to uh wrapped up like a
douche another runner in the night I'm
like oh my god did they just say douche
holy [ __ ] I got to go back and listen I
didn't even know that that was a Bruce
Springsteen song right and we were
[ __ ] high as hell inside my friend's
uh sister's car we couldn't even finish
the joint that we started smoking but I
mean the connection that we had back in
the FM music days between you know
getting a record for the first time at
the record store and then going home and
smoking some weed and putting it on I
remember you know brothers and sisters
the Almond Brothers I remember the day
that terpin station came out the day
that Shakedown Street came out yeah you
went to the record store got the record
went home rolled a joint got high put
the headphones on and listened to that
music for the first time it was magical
experience such as trans roll the joint
on the
record on the record it was the same way
but I I had some different artists I was
like red man me man you know what I'm
saying some Snoop doll some Dr Dre
clonic
2001 explosives baby you know I was a
white kid living in the suburbs growing
up in the 70s so I was just I was
listening to wnw in New York and
whatever they played when I first heard
Elvis Costello first heard the Talking
Heads first heard squeeze all those
great bands and it doesn't seem like
music is that way anymore right like the
music that's today is just doesn't have
the substance that you know that music
of the 60s and the
70s I don't know Mark I think I think
the music is great even better in some
respects because it's everywhere in
performance it's just
the ability the record companies can't
present the art the way they used to and
so now record companies can only present
the most commercial fast food version of
it because it's been taken away from
them right music is now in the hands of
the internet so it's like there is no
like it's sad for kids not to have that
collective experience of of the way we
did but I think the music part's alive
it's just not the product the way it the
music is the weed right there's too many
people trying to go grow weed they're
not all deserving to be growing weed and
there's too many people trying to be
artists and maybe they're not all
talented and because the record labels
no longer invest heavily in artist
development and creative the same way
the stories aren't being told and
there's just a lot of there's just a lot
but of course I'm sure there's the same
amount of talent percentage wise in the
world it's just harder to dig through it
and find it you know I just think about
me searching on the internet from
something now compared to 10 15 can't
find anything I don't know where [ __ ] is
I don't know how you find out about
stuff but um I think that's that's what
it is is like it is all about the
internet and so many people trying to do
it similar to weed there's just so many
people who go oh weed's cool and I want
to be down with weed and um that's what
makes it hard you gota consumers have to
weed through all that themselves to find
out who the real weed people are yeah
well back then too it was you know more
like this like main component of where
the music was coming out from and they
were all listening to similar records
they were all inspired by similar bands
and they were all being inspired in very
similar they were moving to the same
places and going to each other's
concerts and so it was kind of like now
that's not how music is chosen like now
music is chosen through the infinite
high of the melum network it can come
from a billion different ways it does it
certainly does not need to be limited
through like the record label
which was pretty much the way music was
fed to us back in the day if the label
didn't get behind it it would be it
would have been very hard for you to
have been turned on to Leed
Zeppelin right I saw some artists
talking about what they would do to fix
it and they go super simple put CD
players in
cars start selling CDs put CD players
back in cars and get rid of all this
digital stuff I don't even have any
music on my phone I don't know how to
download anything but my own music so I
listen to music on YouTube cuz I don't
know how to use Spotify but put CD
players back in cars sell the CDs in
physical stores and no more
streaming I think that's again just
going back to like what the jam band
scene is now and like nugs.net you know
all the couch tour stuff and all the
broadcasts of live
performances I think the Grateful dad
changed the way live music is presented
and like yeah now anyone with an
Instagram or a YouTube channel can be an
artist and back then you needed to be
picked up by a major record label to be
distributed or else people wouldn't know
who you were but I think what the dead
did quietly all during the 80s is just
played night after night they played a
different show every night and they had
kids like me hooked because you know I
remember when I had to justify to my dad
who thought I was in college and I was
coming home for for dinner one Easter
and we had to change the time of the
dinner so I could make it to the
Hartford show that
night it was like an obsession you know
they thought that we were obsessed and I
had to kind of like rationalize the
Grateful Dead like baseball I'm like
well yeah it's different every time you
know it's like every night was different
and I don't think every band was like
that at the time and so now I think
again there's this whole scene of bands
who
can exist without having Mass popularity
and not being you know a you know a band
like Mo for example I think Mo is a
great example they have achieved a
certain level of success their you know
ban admin office is all family members
so they kind of keep it in the family
and they play small little venues uh
Daniel like this they just played stos
cider the other night and uh you know
like small venues kind of like Zen bar
like things that are nice in Vermont
that has you know cultural significance
in that when you go there you're
supporting a local venue so the money
you're spending behind the bar isn't
going to some Live Nation big venue it's
going to a small venue owner here in the
state and so things kind of stay
homegrown and I I think there's certain
levels of success that you could achieve
now without being you know Ariana Grande
or some you know big blown up back these
days you there's still a lot of great
music going on today but I don't think
that it's I I don't think it'll ever be
like it was in the 60s and 70s and well
they don't sell they don't sell records
to to dance point because that but they
they make their money performing so if
you're a good performer and that's kind
of what the dead did they also didn't
sell as nearly as many records as they
did performance put people in seats so
if you're a good band and you can
perform you know people do appreciate
live music and there is amazing music I
just lately like a like a couple months
ago Spotify took me on a thread that I
wouldn't have gone down and I've been
like listening to some really cool music
that I never would have selected and I
got but I got lucky because 90% of the
time I ever tried that before it took me
down this Commercial Avenue that I
didn't like so I'd always just play the
music that I wanted to listen to and
then I started letting it go and I was
like wow there wow you guys took me to
like 70s Ethiopian jazz
funk and I'm like this really [ __ ]
cool and now I'm like obsessed with
Ethiopian Jazz
fun well as long as there's people
smoking marijuana right I mean as we
used to say you know you get Five Guys
together you get them drink alcohol they
get into fight you get five people you
get them a joint next thing you know
they're starting a band so there's still
the
creativity out there it's just you know
we've seen a demographic I grew up
playing a traditional instrument right
about a decade ago I mean Guitar Center
and others said the number one selling
things are DJ equipment right it's it's
it's just changed its creativity and
perception what people were doing on a
fretboard they started doing with
turntables and sounds and and really
experimenting and taking things so it's
always going to be an EB and flow you
remember you know rock and roll was
going to be the devil's music but Jazz
was the devil's music then hip-hop was
the devil's music so just make music
you're always going to be accused of of
being on the side of the devil because
you're being creative so you know just
do it and whatever happens it's just as
as everybody's talk how I did it which
was making a mixtape and you know then
you know 45 then to you know going to
wax and stuff like that that went away
but now it's back back you know what I'm
saying so because when I grew up I was
only buying seven Ines right my first
7even inch was uh L freak uh you know
freak out you know back in the 70s
right right but that was again what was
it was an affordable medium right a 45
was you know less than a buck back then
right and it was two songs right you got
one song and then you got one song you
never heard on the other side right or
that you occasionally listen to right
but then that what changed into right
what how many of us belong to a music
service but like the old school where
you get 10 tapes and you know then you
have to buy them over series of time
right then it became CD and then
it's
Kel right Kel for sure and then we then
we all destroyed our computers with lime
wire right or our friends or our parents
computers right because I used kazah
kazah right because then way to burn
music so just it doesn't matter as long
as the music's there people will find a
way to get it out yeah it's different
the music industry is completely changed
and I'm glad that it's changed because
I've been a musician I was an artist I
was I was a music artist I wasn't a
music player in the sense that you're in
the music industry right that's a whole
other realm of reality is that you know
you have to be really good talented but
you got to also have some luck and love
and a way to get that music out so you
know cannabis spreads still by smoking
circles and the music will continue to
spread just in different ways shapes and
forms and something's going to evolve
from you know the turntables to
something else eventually that's
currently being made right now that
people are scoffing at and laughing at
will soon eventually become the dominant
parad in music that's just how it goes
cuz generation Alpha right the new
generation will reject our conventional
music and find something and create
something else and that's the beauty of
music right whatever they do create I do
hope to see a world where you can go to
a musical experience and have cannabis
be the drug of choice that's set up to
support your intake of cannabis it's not
all booze it's not all you come in
you're like oh welcome Mr DJ hard hit
we've got your table right over here
with your pre-rolled blunts as you
prequest that's the VIP service that's
what I'm looking
for I need that on the pull up on
command on demand always have my goddamn
We Roll is that in is that in your
writer I mean put it in your writer
others have well yo so what I do when I
do shows is I I have somebody go around
the crowd hand out a bunch of weed so
I'll usually do these gift bags with
lighters and pre-rolls and stickers and
I'm I'm not suppos in California it's
easier but I'll just pop a whole bunch
of pre-rolls and get everybody smoking
our herbs so I'll get the people
performing that I'm opening for smoking
the herb and then I get everybody in
there smoking the herb and then I throw
you know more off stage but yeah I'm
excited you know to talk talk music I've
been working on my music for a long time
and you know have kept it pretty private
and personal and like I mentioned
earlier I just you know debuted my first
release you know back in August and
what's cool is I've got decades worth of
of songs that I'm going to all start
putting out and so my my plan is to
start a label and you know have a whole
strategy of what I want to do with this
music you know I just want people to
hear it and you know hope maybe they
have a similar impact you know or enjoy
it the way I do but you know the balance
is running a a cannabis company and
having the the time to break away from
that so that's my hope in balance is to
start consistently releasing music you
know on a monthly basis so there's more
and more but you know I need to free up
the time to shoot theic music videos and
write the blogs and do the [ __ ] you
know other things to get it out there um
but I appreciate an opportunity to come
on and and and speak about it and uh be
interesting if people check it
out absolutely well I definitely want to
get links for everyone that has uh
whether it's your Spotify set list that
you like to listen to whether it's your
own music links to what you're doing uh
I spoke with Caleb earlier at the end of
the show I definitely want to have all
of your contacts uh and uh you know
links to uh in in the description of the
video soon after we're done so uh if
Caleb doesn't have those already make
sure you send him an email with those so
that the minute the show's done because
it the show will get like you know 5,000
views in the next five five or six days
but it'll be like uh we want those links
to be up right away you know it might go
up another 5,000 views in the next month
month or two so in that in a very short
period of time we'll get a lot of eyes
on it so it would be uh nice to give
everyone the uh proper exposure to to
what they're doing especially with
music hell yeah hell yeah oh yeah Tupac
made me smoke a lot of weed too though I
ain't gonna lie Tupac was a good one
yeah absolutely I you know what once
again through this bubble bag thing like
even some someone was mentioning bear I
was like I met bear like I met bear
because he saw bubble bag I met skunkman
Sam because he saw bubble bags online he
reached out to me he's like he's like if
it don't bubble in it worth of trouble
do you know who first said that and I
could even hear the like aggression in
his voice when he asked me on the email
and I was just like yeah I know who it
is dude like don't worry [ __ ] I'm I
respect you if you don't want me to use
it I won't if you do I will whatever he
was super cool about it we became
friends soon after I met bear the same
way he reached out to me about bub bags
and with some random like he's like I
think butter is better than than bubble
and I was like what who the [ __ ] is this
character he was in his like eating like
butter infused butter towards the end of
Oley Stanley's life he was all about the
infused butter it's probably how he
flipped his tracker honestly he was
eating a lot of this
butter yeah anyway big meat yeah it was
a super pro meat guy dude like forget
about it like he was all his consumption
of cannabis at the end was was through
butter which is fine I'm I'm Pro all
cannabis uh consumption use whatever it
is but uh yeah so met lots of characters
over the years with the uh with the
Bubble Bags a lot of different
characters that uh even we've mentioned
today
here uh but oh the Tupac one I was going
to say um didn't meet Tupac obviously
but I met Mike Dean who I guess produced
mik Dean that's my homeboy yeah dude
Mike Dean dude I Mike Dean reached out
to me years ago I had no idea who he was
but he's like a [ __ ] he's the the man
dude like he does a lot of work with a
lot of artists he's he's had a lot of
success a lot of work with these people
yeah these people dude he used to send
me he would send me unreleased Scarface
music that was like that no one had
heard yet that's right he worked on all
the Scarface music him in o
Joe Scarface him still actually they did
the tiny disc y should really check that
out the Scarface with the tiny desk with
Mike Dean oh I see now this now this guy
here he's he's an incredible musician he
should get an invite to the H totally
totally we do a whole show around Mike
Dean but yeah he was another one that
reached out about bubble bags and I
ended up getting him a set of bags and
just kind of a heady dude I was kind of
when Mike first reached out to me I was
like this is it this is where bubble
bags are going to get their first
mention we're going to get like bubble
hash something we're going to get a
mention in some some hip-hop song I know
Mike but it just uh you know what it it
leaned into the reggae and it was the
reggae that got a hold of it it's like
no no we we got this we got
this he even works with Trevis Scott and
all of those guys oh yeah Kanye Kanye he
was he was like posting pictures him up
with Madonna Like not too long
ago
yeah I was going to say you know it's
not just being in in in musicians to get
involved in cannabis I was with the
Cannabis Action Network back in the
early 90s and the uh laoa and The Horde
tour liked that we were Grassroots
cannabis people and we went out on tour
and then uh Primus and fishbone and
various others were like we like what
y'all are doing come out with us and
educate people on tours so you know you
can this you don't have to be a musician
to necessarily plug into the scene
because what we found is when we were
doing these tours the musicians were all
coming to us I met various musicians
scoring you know on the buses from the
the Bas Tech right is the was the actual
seller on the tour right so everybody
went and visited and you know uh you
know it's just the reality is cannabis
and music are at the hip they cannabis
doesn't travel without music and music
doesn't travel without cannabis that's
what I learn from the inside scene so
again you don't have to necessarily be
musically inclined to tap into the
culture if you're active and you're
genuinely working towards as we were
they will respond not only that they'll
invite you on the tour we weren't paid
to be on the tour we had to pay our way
through and sell our own t-shirts and do
that sort of thing
but those are ways that you can just
plug in if you're not or if you want to
get along for the scene become a roadie
you know learn how to plug in and play
and do all that stuff those are real
jobs I've done that myself and uh you
can get around and see a lot of the
world and in music just being behind the
scenes it's a tight-knit family that way
right
musicians you guys want to say DJ hard
hit what up man I just want to say
Scarface is really inspirational to me I
have big big Scarface fan and uh my home
boy well big brother I should say yeah
um see I work in the general manager's
office at Rapp a lot uh I just actually
my boss just passed away uh the
legendary Mike
Mack uh but he was um he he was he was
over well rap a lot for everything
having to do with all of the music the
catalog everything except for accounts
payable and receivable concerning raap a
lot records as a h so this is
distribution this is uh management
marketing uh getting the video shot uh
everything you know what I'm saying so
yeah uh Scarface man that's that's like
my favorite artist of all time know and
I know you know what I'm saying yeah
most people think it's scar
as you know and they hear his stuff that
kind of took off when he became more
mainstream but Scarface his early music
is he's he's considered your favorite
rapper's favorite rapper because the way
that he wrote and the way he did
storytelling it's on par with like a
Slick Rick I mean it's it's a very you
know unique you know standout artist
that was really inspirational to
me yeah especially the song Mery Mary
Mary Mary Mary you know what I'm saying
so good man listen imagine he's sending
me his [ __ ]
unreleased like it hasn't even G gotten
out yet and he said he's like here check
this one out and I'd I'd see it it would
say Scarface MP4 I'm like yes crack this
thing open and listen to it like 25
times in a row man I was like how did I
somehow hit the jackpot where this dude
reached out to me to buy my bags is now
sending me unreleased music bless you
Mike Dean I appreciate you
dude hell yeah hell
yeah yeah he's an incredible rapper dude
that guy is uh amazing narrative skills
and and Vivid often dark tales of life
in Houston
right struggles struggles of the
streets
introspection what's unique about scar
yeah go ahead he was probably one of the
first rappers to talk about struggles
with mental health you know hip hop is
so masul most hard but his early music
he would talk about the own battles that
he was having in his mind and some
pretty dark stuff for sure but you know
really really deep he's an interesting
dude just watching interviews of him you
know it kind of uh plays to today where
you see I don't know how many of you
guys have been exposed to
Ren but Ren was going to be uh Ren was
kind of going to be like some big big
thing in the UK I don't know if it was
he was supposed to be a pop star or
something but he had major major mental
health
breakdown and then just inwardly
converted his mental health breakdown
into a focus on executing
authentic music his authentic music and
uh if you don't know who he is I would
definitely implore you to go check it
out he's got some cool concepts for a
longest time all the videos I'd seen of
Ren were um him busking out uh in the
streets of whatever City I think there's
some Amsterdam ones and some London ones
but he'd just be busking and really
really crushing it and doing a wide
variety of music but um some of his more
non covers his own authentic music
there's uh he's he's he's basically
having a conversation with his his Dark
Passenger right his mental illness his
like the the voice in head and he's
wearing just a like hospital gown and
he's sitting in this sort of dark and
dingy room on an acoustic guitar and
it's it's really [ __ ] powerful if you
haven't seen it I would uh I would check
it out he's worth uh looking into uh
just you know from what Dan mentioned
about uh Scarface speaking about mental
health uh Ren is definitely picking up
that baton and going deep with
it really exposing the uh that the
nitty-gritty Dark Side of of mental
health that really everyone has suffered
from at at one point in time some worse
than others for sure but everyone's
tasted
it well we got about a half an hour left
today on the show if there's anything I
know I was going to end it I had a
concept that I was going to ask you guys
about I'll have to remember that I did
have kind of the last 10 or 15 minutes
of a of a of a question I was going to
ask everyone but in the meantime we have
about a half an hour if anyone wants to
speak to anything in particular or talk
about projects that they're up to that
uh maybe the people who are listening
would like to know about I think we have
three or 400 people watching live right
now yeah still 325
326 well I'm I'm always happy to talk
about stuff if there's any topic you
guys would like to discuss you know from
genetics and ongoing stuff with you know
breeding
cultivation
music one thing that came to mind
earlier that kind of resonated was like
cultivating and giving giving space for
the grow and I feel like in creating
music or or the creative process it's
good sometimes to be out in nature and
that disconnect I think that's a
connection with cannabis and music um
and would love to speak to that maybe a
little bit because I know in NorCal
Emerald Triangle in the Santa Cruz
mountains or where I grew up in uh Gold
Country um that connection
to getting to the roots and creation I
think is best paired cannabis and music
together but also taking that time you
know on the hill and taking that time in
the the wild the wild element to
cannabis and
music I feel that I um there's no human
beings within a half a mile of me in any
direction and um I I like it that way um
I really like my privacy and I think
that's because you know I've been trying
not to get busted for weed a lot of My
Life um and so you know both here in
Vermont and in California both both
properties are off grid solar and and
battery and so
so uh you know I I like to visit cities
and more populated areas to kick it and
do cool stuff and experience culture and
visit people but I I definitely prefer
to be um you know more you know in
natural surroundings and try to preserve
them as much as possible and that's
where I like to grow weed and that's
where I like to write and do
music very cool man I uh definitely have
a massive affinity for music music not
much of a creator of it you know played
drums and always enjoyed drum circles
and have a lovely collection of drums
and got an acoustic guitar eventually I
I play left-handed so there was never it
just was never convenient for me to
learn from anyone if someone knew guitar
and had a guitar it was strapped the
wrong way for me I was just I didn't I
didn't fit into that
unfortunately um but that's okay because
I was directed into uh nice hash so I
was happy with my pathway and I can
always still pick up my guitar today and
start playing it again which is a
beautiful thing about music but uh it's
definitely played an important role in
just my life uh and I can see it in my
kids too my daughter and particular how
important music is to her just that
connection it's nice to have a a track
to your to your different experiences of
your life you know where you hear music
and you can remember specific
times that's uh that's pretty cool yeah
music has I think got us all through
times of no pot right than anything else
right you know from the you know when I
went to combat when I was in in the Army
I made my own mixtapes I brought a uh an
Outback uh Sony Outback [ __ ] tape
player right cuz I needed something
heavy duty to survive and yeah I mean
all the toughest most hardest times in
my life the only thing that's pulled me
out is music right that is always been
my lifeline is that the same for
everybody
else absolutely through hard times and
um as mentioned when I first jumped on
that
uh losing everything in the fire U one
thing I was blessed about in the
community here in the Emerald
Triangle uh was that not only did
farmers see what happened to me bless me
with trusting getting their trust to
make hash for them but also I got to DJ
Harvest parties I djed a lot of parties
out in the Hills that helped help me
rebuild
myself sir
awesome beauty of community
here and I just want to learn to grow
the weed from scratch to everything
everything that I can learn about
growing
everything and I'm willing to learn well
there's no shortage man and let me tell
you there's a lot of good people sharing
information about such a thing plus you
live in a place where when you plant
seeds they
grow so
beautifully I think if somebody um
Legends could drop some of the links so
you know where we can read up or learn
couple things couple videos here some of
them are talking about some YouTube
links I can link you up with all sorts
of information Kazam including people
and uh even people in Jamaica like I
said the best way to learn in my opinion
in Jamaica you could go intern you know
you have to have time to be able to give
to it but you could go donate and
volunteer your time at different Grows
Where you know someone has a vast array
of knowledge that's sort of the person
running it right you want to work with
someone who's exceptional and who has a
good understanding there's definitely
certainly incredible Growers on hash
church that have been dropping really
good information for the last like 10
years on here but uh I don't know where
where where would you guys that are on
the panel suggest getting really good
you know grow cannabis knowledge like
where does one find such a thing at this
point in time I remember there used to
be key websites but now there just must
be a billion and one different sources
for
this it's a lot to sort through these
days so much dude plant some seeds man
hit hit me up if you want I'll give you
some seeds and um plant seeds and you
know gain experience and find the best
people you know who are growing weed and
try to look over their shoulders
and ask
questions and
um give me some seeds if you want some
seeds yeah I'd love to keep connected I
think it's good to build relationships a
lot of interviews a lot of talk a lot of
like podcasts are wonderful way I feel
like that's a there's a lot of knowledge
there and an actual growing is a is a
right of right a passage you have to be
humbled sometimes and keep growing and
learn from your mistakes that's
definitely something that I've been
humbled by this plant so much but I also
get so Fired Up When It's Time to
germinate and get the soil ready and get
back into it every season is uh every
seed is a prayer every breath is a
blessing every year is an honor to to to
walk with this plant so stay
connected well said appreciate that
you're outside again Kazam you're not I
thought you were at
work yes I'm outside
again gas
station of the
office all over the place right now all
right all
right well cool I'm definitely going to
link you guys all up make sure on the
email that I sent out that everyone like
replies back with their contact
information or I can get it all from
Caleb I just want to make sure you guys
all have access to each
other because that is always
convenient yeah give thanks man I did
send an
email oh wonderful awesome yeah we'll
make that happen for sure just uh
another what you'll you'll compile some
as well Caleb yep get you that list by
the end of the showroom oh yeah that's
great sat we smoke sat here and smoked
weed for a long time it's
fun yeah it's you know every Sunday we
do this for about four hours we go into
different levels of conversation it was
nice to have a kind of a different panel
today with some of the regulars as well
and sort of have this conversation I
think this conversation definitely has
the capability of going deeper it's just
a little bit of a harder one to crack
you know that that cannabis music
relationship and how absolutely inp like
how important it was in so many
different genres of music that came out
if you follow cannabis use back to
really like old jazz
music so
cool I have a really hard time doing
music and making music without weed um
there's one time in my life where I was
challenged where you know I was in a
position where I couldn't smoke um and I
wanted to write and so I had to really
challenge myself
as a writer to see what I was made of
and I I was able to write some stuff
that I thought was really special but
like I said about the amplifier when I
write I just I start smoking and uh what
it what it does is it you know I believe
that it connects you know it's also a a
a conduit a connector and so you know
they talk about your Consciousness and
when you use you know weed it can open
up a lot of things that otherwise you
wouldn't have access to and I think
that's where when I work on music
whatever is is coming from you know is
largely you know coming from the
influence that the herb has when I smoke
and then it's kind of like a wave that
you're trying to ride because like if
you hit it at the right way all this
[ __ ] is bursting out all this creative
stuff and then you'll put things down
that you you know can't go back later
and and understand where it came from
that all kind of connects and clicks and
then if there's too much or too little
you know that's that's what it's kind of
like for me as I as I use you know herb
when I when I write and stuff from my
own experience it's it's the key to your
door of creativity right it it unlocks
your door right we all have individual
doors of creativity that we don't know
how to unlock it just unlocks and when
it's there you best bathe in that [ __ ]
you know because if you don't you're
going to potentially miss lightning if
it's just a hum a beat a Melody a lyric
right you got to immediately jot it down
right and get you know capture that
otherwise it's gone to the ether if you
go to sleep and you don't jot it down
you're we're not waking up the next
morning and hearing it right so you know
when you're in that flow and I found
that's what I find with cannabis
cannabis is that key that unlocks that
door that creativity and that flow if
you're not ready for it you better be
ready for it because it's coming and
inside you it's exactly how I feel so a
lot of times I'll be driving and I'm
supposed to have phone calls and I'll
smoke I'll get really high and I'll hear
a beat and all of a sudden that's what I
have to do and I and I'll just I'll just
write while I drive a lot of my songs
are actually written on notes on my
phone hitting the the just repeat over
again on the instrumental on long drives
and stuff but you can't lose the
opportunity if you get that intense
energy of creation
coming especially if you're you know if
you're in a musical
collaboration like I've always said that
you can't you can't make music with
people that you can't communicate with
and like like think about just the sort
of like the situ sitation where like if
a guy is screwing your woman you can't
make music with that guy right because
you have to be in a place where You're
vulnerable and sometimes I think right
Dan sometimes cannabis gets you there if
you're in a group of musicians and
everyone's getting high and everyone's
kind of like on the same wavelength when
you lower those those guards you can
really start communicating
musically with other people in a
collaboration and that's where the the
gestal thing comes in the play because
what you're doing now is bigger than
just the individual players themselves
right and so there's this
communication that happens amongst
musicians when you're playing in a small
group and everyone's kind of on that
same kind of wavelength it's really
exciting when that happens and I think
think everyone in the Ensemble
recognizes it and it doesn't always
happen right but I think cannabis can
help you get there absolutely it can
also help you recognize it while you're
watching and it's
happening well it also can get you
together to synchronize right I've had
my band used to practice High used have
band called Norther kns number five so
that when we played High we were ready
for it right you can't practice then go
play high and you know no if you're
playing and you're doing it right you're
hitting a level sometimes right correct
me if I'm wrong musicians who has not
astral projected while they're playing
live literally left their body left
their being and you're just holding some
spiritual ground to be there but that
connection so solid anybody else if you
stud not everyone understands music it's
a spiritual thing yeah well closing my
eyes that is powerful that's well said
if you study for the test stoned you
better take the test high
right yes very true this is very
true I don't know what happened man I
really blew that taste well did you get
did you did you get super high before
you took
it oh that's what that was the problem I
have to admit I did take tests very high
and did fine on them but maybe not for
everyone me that's important
that amongst the players they they they
told us if you exactly what Mark said if
you study High you better take the test
high and that was my TA in my English
101 I was like oh this is a life hack I
had life hack how much it was a life
hack I was learning the probably the
most the best lesson I ever learned in
college
sh I like that dude I like that a lot
well I can't tell you how many times but
we would be like drummer would be off
bass player would be off thing let's get
take a break smoke a joint and next
thing you know you're back all in sync
have that happened especally recording
when you're in the studio trying to
record your music you guys got to be
it's like taking a test High you you you
jam High you create high you find you
know you find your verses and your
choruses you're you find the structure
sometimes High because you're open in
that in that realm that space that
cannabis can help take you um and
playing long enough you eventually can
communicate you know telepathically I've
also experienced this with with other
you know other teachers and that's
really important that when you build
that Rapport our our group has been
playing um every week and in weekends
since 2010 so going on 15 years and you
get to a point where there's such a
relationship you know cannabis kind of
keeps that um new and and listening to
music too I was thinking about that too
the DJs on the on the on the panel you
know ganjo can get you to to this place
where you can hear different things
almost every time you can listen to the
Same album same record and there's still
something kind of new there sometimes
and it's it's like there's that that
beautiful um you know Infinity of
possibilities and and Novelty
that ganja helps with sure as
appreciators of music lovers of music
and cannabis each and every one of you
have had the experience where you've
wanted to you've been turning someone
onto a song and you want them to focus
on it as much as you're focusing on it
and really hear what that song is so
what I would ask each and every one of
you will go through the list is to what
is that song that you would like to turn
on the people that are listening to the
podcast today for you and uh I don't
mind uh going first uh something that
you just it it it's it's like an
exciting Jam or it's an incredible
guitar riff or it's a an amazing bass or
drum beat or you know it could be vocals
it could be whatever it is that you
would just love for our audience to hear
if you had your one song I'm going to
say for
me um I'm going to go and this is mainly
because these are the most recent sort
of musical experiences I've been
happening I've gone down this Harry Mack
Rabbit Hole this freestyle rapper guy
that's just mindbending on every level
and I think I was going to say Omega 18
but what I will say is rap col train I
think it's his uh rap soliloquies it's
called rap col train and the two songs
are called well one is rap col train and
the other is snake eyes and it's just a
YouTube video go watch that after you
take a big rip maybe put the uh uh close
captions on even though he's very clear
you want to read the words while he's
saying them and uh let me know what you
think in the comments sections of the
video I'm going to pass it on to Dan and
he's going to let you know what song uh
does it for him and that he'd really
love you to listen to with intent Focus
go ahead Dan hey wow well there's a lot
of stuff I'm weird with music when I
hear something I like I like to listen
to it on repeat a lot because you do get
a different expression of it every time
but honestly I'm going to say I would
like for you to listen to my music um
you know everything that I that I put
out is it's a true story it's all
autobiographical um and it's pretty deep
and uh you know I've only shared it just
recently so if you wanted to check it
out you go to you know band camp and
just search rebel grown Danny hustle uh
mixtape volume one by Rebel grown it's
produced by my friend TSO who's an
incredible DJ an international DJ and
producers toured all over the world and
six continents tours half 2third out of
the year he's really uh influential in
the development of Juke or footwork
which is a whole kind of sub genre of
electronic music and Hip-Hop that comes
out of Chicago the whole Tech life thing
um and so it's it's dope um what song
would I would say is the illst one would
probably
be uh the fourth song but that would be
dope if anybody wants to check it out um
and I'm curious to see what people think
of
it awesome dude thank you how about
Christopher
Carr hey yeah give thanks this is my
first time on hash church it's a
pleasure to connect with all of you
especially on such a intimate and
inspiring topic um Dan I like that you
set the toad bro because I think yeah
we're we're here to Big Ups the the
fresh Originals thanks and Praises by
ancestry t r e uh it's the name of the
album 2024 release we have Natalie rise
on on wise humble and strong that's a
unique track and then the title track
thanks and Praises is an homage to ganja
ganja ma um so always always a pleasure
to to connect with uh like minds and
like spirits and um Big Ups Big Ups I
love uh CIA with black auru that's
another track that fires me up so thank
you
all skunkman Sam how about you buddy
uh well I think one of my favorite one
is positive her by n
naora uh I'm floating High can't you see
my eyes I'm red red red tap
Des a marijuana High my head head head
homie skur hit my
brain etc etc etc but they can listen to
it it's pretty cool I like it I think
from now on everyone else is going to
also have to perform their favorite song
so I think Sam just set the uh the tone
there thank you Sam for being you next
time I'll try and wrap it no problem man
we'll take it from you Dr Mark I know
you've got a whole swack of songs but
there's got to be one that's just like
is it like a standing on the moon is it
uh some old blues is it what what what
is it what is it some blue
grass uh well since this is Hash church
and it's all about smoking our favorite
thing why don't we use Blaze on right so
climb that Hill stay on your feet
scramble from your footing when it gets
too steep you're on the highway now with
higher
hopes while all around are rolling eggs
with living yolks you never get too sad
you never get too blue it must be all
those Chemtrails raining down on you you
the justice of the peace won't have it
anymore they just took the covers off
the justice of War you got your night
shades on and your first G now the band
plays on you got more light Blaze on so
Blaze on dude
fish that's awesome dude damn I was just
joking but [ __ ] way to like set the bar
even higher Dr Mark how about Nick
Riley uh yeah I don't know if I can live
up to that bar I'm I'm the drummer in
all the musical projects I'm in so I
don't know if you'll get some singing
out of me but um uh you can I don't know
um the uh I don't know I'm I'm trying to
think about one but just a song that's
really hit me you know kind of out of
nowhere uh is a song called change by
Big Thief I don't know it's one of those
like every year I go back to it you're
talking about like marking moments and
time and and things like that I'm a real
big fan of that same as Dan too just
like listening to something over and
over and over um I used to pick a record
of the year and every morning doing
tarps I would listen to that same record
over and over every morning uh kind of
like set this little moment in time for
the year so um but yeah that song has
become almost like a yearly Mark for me
to listen to and repeat for a while so
beautiful well thanks for sharing man
I'm going to check it out for sure how
about Morning
Glory oh boy as a DJ with ADHD I have so
many songs on my mind right
now well I'm gonna have to I've been
thinking about it as well as been
hearing everyone's inputs it's I'm not
gonna have any bars because it's a
little more modern but I'm gonna say a
song that I've probably choosen because
I've been playing it every time I've
been agitating the biomass to make hash
with this track it's called Uh Love
Rocket by LS
dream excellent I just wrote that down
I'm going to check that out for sure
little hash making music hey
yes absolutely okay so but as a DJ do
you
have are you playing songs as a DJ like
I guess it's really I I I'm not a
musician or a DJ but I I imagine there's
times where you're playing music for
yourself and that there's times where
you're playing music for your
audience exactly um one thing I love
about where I when I DJ a lot of like
quote unquote Underground scenes is
personally one of my favorite genres to
mix is house music but I Al also realize
that not everyone loves that type of
music so uh one thing I've been doing is
on my quest to find new tracks I love
finding like these Bay Area deep sty
deep house style tracks that have like
covers of 90 lyrics 90s hip-hop lyrics
or kind of like it's getting the vibe of
modern but bringing you back when you
hear these
voices nostalgic
Vibes right right okay cool awesome well
I love it how about uh are you are you
can you talk
Kazam in the middle of you got a tune
for us one that's special one that makes
the hair on the back of your neck stand
up special tune you want to share with
everyone could be a tune that you wrote
could be could be a tune that you just
like
there's one particular son I always go
back to it's called in their picture on
the
wall in my
house there's a picture on the wall far
I see up on
his yeah man by visionaires that is that
is I always go back to that tune you
know true thanks for sharing I'm going
to try to find all of these tunes and
then put put them in a link in the
description so that uh at the end of
this video the people that made it all
the way through can be like all right
now you get to hear kind of everyone's
little I'm going to create a little
playlist of this group of songs that we
have here uh we still have etan F and
Caleb Chen uh to go through so etan if
you want to go next tell us a
song well I like the instrumental
Muggles I'm from New Orleans so it's
from Louis Armstrong back in the 20s but
if I had to choose one that always gets
me up and going um C Callaway's reefer
man you know have you ever met that
funny reer
man yeah I love that song it's just it's
I've always loved upbeat songs and it
was one of those earlier jazz songs I
was like they're talking about weed you
know I understood what reefer meant you
know what I'm saying so that one for
when you're feeling up up and bumping
yeah that one is is definitely want to
put on the
party love it man well last but
certainly not least Caleb Chen what is
your song that you would love for people
to listen to here to finalize uh I guess
we missed Mojave mojave's in the chat so
I'll get him to give his just through
the chat uh and anyone else Colin and
anyone else that may have left already
but in the meantime Caleb hit us with
your song really quick Caleb sorry for
interrupting I want to change my answer
as my favorite song would be uh we are
the
world
team the world all right I added it I'll
put them both up uh Dan go
ahead um song I want to share with
everyone is called Hay by Jackie chain
my one of my favorite songs about a
specific cultivar um fun listen you know
uh musically some people might not uh
find it up to par but you know listen to
the
lyrics yeah dude that's what we'll be
doing we listening to the lyrics so I
may reach out to each and every one of
you depending on how well I did with the
uh spelling of your band's name or the
song's name or the artist's name uh
sometimes if you make a mistake suddenly
you can't find uh maybe Dr Mark you will
want a specific version of
Blaze uh up on because it's fish and I
don't know if you want the album version
or if you want some ridiculous like 2023
version I'll find the live version I
kind of figured you would so uh and
anyone else that has a very specific
version of the track that they just
mentioned I should also mention Stevie
rayon Texas flooding is just absolutely
insane if you just don't want to if you
want your brain to explode and and watch
this man play the guitar on a live
version find a live version but in the
meantime I want to thank everyone for
coming out as far
as as Jamaica to humbold to Vermont
to British Columbia where I am right now
um I appreciate everyone that's been
watching all morning we've had a big
group of people with us over 300 people
that have watched for the last four
hours as we've been uh hanging out and
shooting the [ __ ] and talking about
music and cannabis and the sort of
connection between those two things
which uh is the sort of theme for this
week's show all of us have a deep
appreciation for both cannabis and music
and I liked how there was sort of Reggae
and there was DJ music and there was you
know grateful Dad I want to shout out DJ
hard hit too he he bounced but we'll get
us a track from him as well I feel like
it might be a Scarface track but we'll
see what happens I'll throw one in there
anyway because we talked about it and uh
yeah hopefully we can do this again one
of these days soon catch up with all of
you I want to thank you for coming out
and Caleb for helping me organize the
show the show was his idea he is the
co-host today and we'll definitely get
him back as well uh in the meantime what
I would say as I always say May the full
melt bless your bowl sooner than later
and in the
meantime see you next Sunday everybody
peace out so