[Music]
do
hey guys what's up bubble man here i
have left my
lab a little early today and i have
headed out
up in smoke you may or may not recognize
it from the last video i put up but
apparently our hazel
all hash joints no paper no glue no
cannabis
pizza without the box if you will are
now available and
i wanted to support thc this time around
but they did not order them yet
so i am going to go back into
up and smoke support max and dom as
they've always done great things here in
vancouver
uh under their old uh legacy brand
um dispensary that they used to run now
they've transferred into the legal
market
and uh like uh you've seen in the video
from previous of the hank that i bought
uh they know what they're doing so uh
yeah let's go check out some hazel's
pure hash joints
first time on the canadian market first
time in
british columbia in the legal framework
of course my friends have been making
these joints for a very long time but
never been able to go into a store and
buy one so pretty excited
all right so here we are here's the
hazel yeah
right there
i'm doing really good man i mean i'm
pretty stoked to be uh buying these
hashtags right now i'll take two
two yeah yeah two for the bubble man
excellent accidents oh yeah
that's gonna do just fine gotta find
somewhere heady to smoke this
oh there's a nice bench we can find
sound will probably be messed up
yeah yeah exactly we'll do it we'll do
it we'll push through so listen
i'm here with dom from up and smoke aka
the meme dealer what's going on
and you know what you do with your hash
that's not dabbable
you [ __ ] roll hazel's with it so we
are look at that
boom there's a hazel right there this is
how it comes
got a little thc symbol on it i haven't
even seen this yet nope
we'll get to uh unwrap it here together
so we're just gonna smoke our own for
covid's safety probably not the safest
thing to do
pass joints around right now maybe a
little bit uh
uh irresponsible if you will so we're
gonna we've each bought our own
i was pretty stoked on the price i think
i paid
would you say about 27 bucks yeah yeah
so 27 bucks each this is this is within
the range in fact it's a little bit
cheaper than the price that these were
back in the day when they were available
through compassion clubs and legacy
markets you can confirm or not confirm
with me
in the comments section of this video to
let me know what you what you see
and i guess uh i'm gonna try and open
this bad boy up you had like the
just kind of wrapped up and these little
little tubes almost the tubers
all right now we gotta open up the
packaging it looks like where you push
the sides right
yeah these ones are really tough to open
i can do that for if you want well i
remembered you have to
pinch all three sides all right make
sure that's broken and then
yeah pinch the sides really hard for any
lps watching this
these are literally the worst containers
that you can use
uh gage i'm looking at you
these are not very friendly to people
with oops and issues
oops you know what for us this was
chosen to try and get the product to
market but i agree with dom
it's not the best best ideal packaging
but
it has secured the hash joint in a way
that the hash joint is not broken and so
that's kind of the key
and so i guess uh yeah you light yours
up shout out to
hayward and cheryl the creators of the
hazel
i'm uh really proud of you guys and
stoked to see you
having this product come to market it's
uh
pretty darn cool all right so we'll just
slide that one
out
really easy to light these just kind of
start
heating them up the lighter and they'll
just catch themselves and it looks like
it's just going to keep itself going
it's got a real nice nice cedrine how
about that for a terpene
beta caryophyllene beta-mercine
alpha said dream and beta that's
obviously
terpenes but it does smell good you
don't speak terpenes damn
dom i thought you were like legit
so there we go there's one for me the
cultivar
is the death bubba and i'm gonna borrow
your lighter
we do ask that you hold it in your hand
and light it just the way dom was
mentioning it holding in your mouth and
lighting it it is a fairly big hole down
the center
and if you hold it in your mouth and
light it you could suck the flame in and
it's not the most
ideal situation so i'm really excited i
don't
smoke joints very often but when i do
they are pure hash
no smoke nice
maybe a half gram is a lot for one
person but i think it's the perfect
amount for me and marcus here
full gram it's a full grammy it's a full
gram we're gonna we're gonna smoke the
whole
gram that's that's what's up right there
we're we're down in these things we
gotta sit here for at least 20 more
minutes and smoke this joint while
people honk while construction is going
on when people are trying to back into
their parking spots
right in the core of the city here good
idea on the shades dom
that's smoke
i like it it smells good yeah it's uh
it's doing the job i suspect by the end
of it will be pretty high
that's the mission right it's definitely
the mission but i'm more impressed with
just like the integrity of the actual
hash tube you know you'd think with the
heat passing through it it might soften
up
or start melting at the end but this
stays really nice and firm
and it smokes really well there's no
runs
oh yeah and although you may think the
majority of the
the hash is burning off on this joint
it's really not the case
uh when you smoke them you really get
the idea that you are indeed
inhaling a lot of it
for anyone who loves that old school
taste of hash and a joint this is this
is the way absolutely
with no paper and no glue and no
cannabis
i call it um pizza without the box
got that closed again it's as hard to
close as it was to open
they're tough they're tough
we're cannabis people and we did spend
enough time in the legacy
that of course we're going to be
critical this is just the natural way if
you've ever looked at new people who are
coming into the industry who are just so
gung-ho and excited and god bless their
hearts for that
we've lived for some decades in the
industry
and you get you get a little bit a bit
critical when you do that so we're going
to be honest with you you know like dom
said the packaging just isn't the best
packaging it did get us to market but
let's be a little bit more conscious in
the future
of people who have difficulty opening
things um and hopefully um
you know change things up a little bit
but yeah that is just burning
lovely i'll have to get this shirt
changed my hash melts
except when it's hazel
i always really enjoyed these at
concerts yeah
man i'll tell you when i stopped smoking
joints and it was like okay
like am i gonna do a vape
a pen yeah i'm like you know a pen's not
gonna hit you like a dab and then it's
like well am i gonna sneak in my torch
and my rig and my and all my dab i
remember actually i went to a michael
frontier concert
in uh stanley park at nalton bowl and i
had a big like at the time it was red
eye because
it was not heady at all i've just gone
out of high school i'm pretty sure was
this 2005
i think so yeah it was like it was
launched who opened up for them uh
the reggaetonius i believe i believe a
spanish reggae band
yeah um anyway i went there and i
brought my my like my two
two foot like red eye glass bong with me
through security
and then had to like bargain with them
to let me keep it as long as i didn't
smoke it inside
but you know that was that's who i was i
was bringing my bond to the concert i
was supposed to be at that concert
but i got the call the night before
that my father and his wife were killed
in a motorcycle accident
very suddenly it was one of the worst
moments of my life
and in fact the day that that concert
happened i ended up on a plane to go
back to winnipeg to deal with
you know the things that you have to
deal with as you get older when your
parents are dying or siblings or
you know heavy [ __ ] sometimes happens in
life but i knew the minute he mentioned
that michael frante concert i was like i
would have been there
i go to michael frante no matter where
he is whether it's whistler whether it's
at malcolm bowl whether it's in
in an indoor venue in in vancouver i
would be at that show
um that's the only one i missed it was a
powerful show
i heard i remember it was beautiful
sunny afternoon and
it started pouring down rain in the
middle of the set and they just started
covering up all the
all the electronics and everyone just
started dancing harder and he started
singing harder and it was just like it
was this
crazy crazy vibe like there's not many
concerts that had so many people really
all on the same level
what a great venue too like not very
many people know malcolm bowle
in stanley park if you've visited
stanley park you for sure won't know it
you could live in this city for many
many many years and not know that
malcolm bowle is literally smack dab in
the middle of this park and it's this
really cool kind of amphitheater
little field you know it's just that
when you walk in there you know that
like something special
could possibly happen it's just like
it's a great great spot for a venue
you're just like they're one with nature
it's a nice outdoor concert
wow i've been doing good on this i have
smoked this much faster than i normally
do
we're not even at 10 minutes dom i'm
pretty impressed they taste good you
know what i'm gonna be like honest like
i'm super super critical like if there's
anything that i can taste on the
on the inhale whether it's bitterness or
anything like i'll i'll be the first to
tell you and i
don't get much negative taste out of
this it's like a death bubba
it's smooth at the end i suggest not
squeezing it too hard
because you'll do what i just did yeah
yeah but but you can puff it back
throw it into a pipe and and hit it it
is now towards a roach mine is actually
still
completely perfect in every way it
hasn't uh it hasn't crushed out but that
right there happens a lot when you pass
them
if you get that one guy trust the
integrity don't squeeze it it's true
um but this is nice it tastes good you
know like it's got a clean burn like i'm
not really getting any bitterness
like there's nothing kind of foul there
like the input material
was decently clean for this bubble and
dry sift
yeah like you know what it's not it's
not melty because it doesn't need to be
melty right you wouldn't be able to make
a hashtag
no the first rip would be awesome and
then it would just you'd have to put it
in a pipe you want to put like melty
hash it put it on the inside of the
joint
yeah exactly and i have had some i have
had some people tell me that they're
putting things on the inside of these
joints and people in um
ontario the other day i was on a pk
session with one of the stores there and
they said yeah we filled it up with
keith
we just stuffed it full with a toothpick
and packed it full of keef and they were
like man that thing
burnt perfect so experiment play around
have fun
i'm really happy i'm uh really stoked
mostly for
for like the most for hayward and cheryl
the people who really made this product
and brought it to market
sure we brought it under our brand and
we brought it under our company name and
we partnered up with them but
they did the legwork on this they're the
coolest old-school couple from the
kootenays
and uh if you have time give a little
shout out in the comments section to
hayward and cheryl and i'll make sure i
show it to them
i'm officially burning my fingers and
it's still going dude
yeah oh they're nice let's see how small
i can get this one down
wow well there it is
the pure hash joint from hazel i want to
give big thanks to up and smoke
these guys have been doing it right here
in the city for a long time when i go
buy new products i want to make sure i
head over
to some of the shops that spent time in
the legacy market give them support
and uh yeah i just i've always
appreciated what you guys are doing
thanks always appreciated the uh you
know the fun videos we've done
and you know we've pressed a lot of hash
together now it's been a few years of
years it has yeah if you go through this
channel you'll definitely see more than
a few videos with uh with dom
and uh his partner max with preston
rosin at my house or just on the boat
without
sasquatch that was a lot that was a fun
day that was a fun one i almost forgot
about that one
we tried going out to bowling but the
water the weather wasn't letting us
we turned around didn't we once a day
instead that's right that's right
well awesome shout out to embark shout
out to hazel
and uh shout out to all of you guys i
just puffed a grandma hash
i think i'm gonna go buy another one
well i got it i gotta keep that stash
topped
i got my extra one but i want to buy
another one and maybe uh
give it away do a little giveaway so
listen everybody thanks for watching
that was the hazel hash joint review
if you want to get yours here in
vancouver i know that up in smoke still
has a few left so
uh head on down there 258 west broadway
west broadway
exactly thanks brother peace out
[Music]
everybody
well that one tasted like another one so
i'm going to buy one more
support you guys hear it up in the
smokes
[Music]
you