[Music]
hey guys bubble man here I'm here at the
Heavenly days medicinal Gardens in uh
beautiful Vancouver British Columbia and
uh we're about to walk into the garden
right now I'm just sort of uh standing
out in the sort of garden foyer where
they do a lot of their work I'm making
sure I'm keeping the camera nice and
close so you're not catching a glimpse
of anything that's on their boards I
like to keep people's privacy but the
guys at Heavenly days were nice enough
to let me come in and do a little
filming and a little macro photography
today and that's what I wanted to share
with you guys so uh why don't we head in
now all right so this crop is at the end
of its life uh inspired by Remo for
certain with the nice 20-gallon brw
uh pot right at the front and he's got
some other I'm guessing those are at
least 20 gallons right at the door here
we have uh a high press sodium let me
make sure I get the the lights proper
here for you so we don't have to go back
and do this again let's go to man there
it is turned green that's the color we
want so this is the congales right here
at the start uh this congales is under a
high press sodium light bulb which has
been turned off for now but an
interesting fact is that he's got this
Cong
uh plugged in under the HPS but then
he's got another congales right over
here and this one's over a metal Hy
which is uh literally burning right
above us right now and producing a fine
color light at least for film so you can
see this one uh is from The High Press
sodium and this one is from the uh metal
Hy the metal halide buds I'm not going
to lie look a little thicker look a
little frostier interesting how a plant
can just decide you know you know this
particular one congales in this
particular environment for this
particular situation preferred the metal
Halli light now I wouldn't go and say
scientifically that you've now
established a scientific Truth uh it
just happened to work out that way in
this particular situation so uh
interesting things that we see in the
grow room uh uh particularly with the
exact same strain same strain different
lights a little bit of a different
production
value all right so we'll come back
around this
[Music]
way and we'll check out an East Coast
Sour Diesel here I'm going to have to go
low real low cuz I don't want to touch
the
buds all right so we got an East Coast
Sour Diesel right here nice and
chunky This Is that real sort of fuy Tas
in Sour Diesel really nice little bit of
that PO and grab you by the by the uh
well I guess I'll say it grab you by the
nuts this particular one when Vaped or
turned into hash comes out a really
beautiful full melt the dry sift is
absolutely exceptional uh close to
Second To None when you really get the
Dank full flavors of that unadulterated
canabo High coming through with that
Sour Diesel East Coast Sour Diesel
tarpine profile I'm telling you it's
definitely very good very very good so
I'm just touching the stocks making sure
not to touch the buds you won't see me
squeezing the buds in here and I'm
really trying my best to not touch the
buds anywhere so um over on this side
let me get you under
here all right so over here we have a
sweet skunk this is just an absolute
beautiful plant killer resin production
uh one of my favorites to be honest so I
mean you don't really have to convince
me to love this this plant I love
everything about it and it is a monster
I can't even tell you where it begins
and where it ends but every nug on it is
is just beautiful looking it's got that
sativa uh kaix sort of stretching like a
fox tail and stacking on itself pretty
[ __ ] awesome you can see the size of
the nug uh against my forearm there
pretty big size nugs and uh
yeah what can I say about the sweet
skunk it's one of my all-time favorites
a breeder Steve special
uh this Cut's been floating around
Vancouver ever since Steve really
stopped producing it it never went away
uh the smell is extremely lemony with a
mix of that exotic sativa now not a
spicy exotic sativa but this
really sweet and perfumey exotic sativa
mixed in with the lemon scented you know
strong uh dmon and mercine and uh uh
Valencia those uh orangey Tarpin and and
citrus uh e Turpin that mix together and
produce the profile of the sweet scun is
really something to be experienced it is
spectacular and look at that bud how
nice that looks with the light shining
through the back
there I guess I'm shading myself
out
beautiful all right now the Le here
behind me and then we've got we've got
this big monster and this is the king
and the King this little bud got bent
but thank God it did because I found
these beautiful little pinkish hairs
pistolet hairs that I photographed for
you guys and uh I think you'll really be
quite happy with how those came out
really nice uh resin production on this
plant and to be honest it really just
smells to me like a God Bud it really
does smell like a God bud I think maybe
even Jordan uh put this together as a
God Bud cross and uh that's why there's
seeds available of it so nice resin
production um very photogenic not my
favorite profile um it looks like that
La weed that everyone wanted in the 9s
and uh I think it's just a left a
leftover remnant of that very time much
more impressed with these exotic sativas
these congales and sweet skunks and I'll
take you guys a little
deeper and in here we have the
Burmese two monster Burmese plants one
over here one over here I'll try to keep
the light on this side of thing so we
can get that greenish light uh from the
metal Hy this plant might not look that
great through the camera but let me tell
you it is absolutely spectacular I've
taken some beautiful photos a much more
thicker vegetative Bud uh this is that
sort of land race sort of style uh uh
cannabis plant that uh I am my a big fan
of
myself and uh it's it's potent it's uh
it does the body good I'll tell you you
can see that that is a nice looking
lady and so I think it's another uh King
in the background here and then these
three in the corner here the lightest so
terrible I won't really bother coming
too much in here are the train wrecks so
that's a train wreck right there uh and
another train rack right beside it I
could potentially uh use my flashlight
to kind of give you guys a little bit of
a a little bit of a light there we go so
that's the train rack you can see the
cush like uh uh structure of the bud
very different from uh these other
sativas that uh I've been showing you
can tell that it's quite uh quite a
substantial difference there very
different from the sativa buds that I've
been
showing and uh yeah just nice little
nice little Crystal content on
those all right so that was a nice
little tour of the Heavenly days Garden
great job that these guys are doing
they're growing proper they're not using
chemicals uh and they're producing
really really beautiful buds so a lot of
people are happy with their product if
you want to check them out uh this very
product will be available to the mm and
the mmpr p s that have licenses uh
permission in Canada to to purchase
cannabis uh you can go check out Eden at
any of their oh jeez they must be up to
like four or five locations now I'm not
exactly sure I'll try to put the link uh
for at least one of the locations in the
comment section of this video so you
guys can give them a call and ask them
uh when Heavenly days is stocked and uh
when you can go down there and grab some
of this so uh yeah thanks for watching
guys always enjoy your uh company here
when I'm on my little cannabis
Adventures uh I'm now going to go meet
up with d420 K and check out uh high
integrity glass art and we're going to
go and have some lunch so thanks for
watching Bubble man's
world they there will be
salvation I said there will be
[Music]
will be no salvation here and there
until
the the CES
[Music]
are so come now my brothers
all to the
call for one he one
[Music]
one my rich man cries are heard my
Hiding man cries are heard then why then
why why can't the poor hey hey now the
poor they've been crying out for these
many thousand years their vibrations are
traveling throughout this world oh yeah
so come now Brothers all and R to the
call for one he one unite the word one
word but you and I Cry out for Unity
that's what God
said that's what marus
said and now those of
you read the books of Prophecy that's
what the prophet
said that's what they all
said
and got I come now better have got you
come but it's only going to come
starting with you and you and you and
you yes better got to come now yes
better has got to come but it's only
going to come starting with you and you
and you and
[Music]
you oh yeah hey I am
doing do it doing
it what what what what you going to do
now with the Judgment so near at hand
what what you going to do tell me now
what going to do