hey guys welcome to bubble man's world I
am here today fresh after Christmas I
guess it's a couple of days after
Christmas the 27th hope you all had a
wonderful holidays and enjoyed your time
with your family I feel like a kid on
Christmas morning because I have a new
package from pure pressure in Colorado
my favorite rosin press company and I'm
hoping that this is either the helix or
the helix Pro manual rosin press so I
wanted to do an unboxing video with you
guys I'm not sure if you're familiar
with the helix Pro I can put the picture
up here real quick it's the helix Pro is
a 5 ton manual rosin press they are
expected January 2019 so they're doing
25 pre-orders for this particular thing
it's got bigger heat plates and more
force than the helix it's exclusive
preorder pricing as a thousand bucks
down and then you know three weeks
before shipping you can pay the rest of
the the price I think it's another
twenty nine hundred for this particular
unit every pre-order comes with a free
matching accessory kit and entry into
their contest where one is going to win
a second press for free for a friend or
for yourself so top features user
friendly and easy to twist press
operation no air compressor required
ultra accurate force measuring load cell
which displays bag pressure in real time
that's a market first for manual rosin
press super responsive pressure control
that allows for as little as 10 pound
force increments press up to 12 grams of
flowers or 20 grams of kefir hash at a
time with ease features our press wear
technology which offers a full-color LCD
touchscreen with custom software for
even more control you can save up to 29
preset recipes so once you dial in your
settings you can repeat your results
over and over and over again up to five
tons of force which is ten thousand
pounds of force output from our hundred
percent custom engineered lead screw
twist press technology these guys have
put a lot of time and energy
so trust me when I say these guys
understand engineering and they really
produce their rosin presses from an
engineer's perspective that's how the
machine is getting built even heat
distribution from zero Fahrenheit to 300
Fahrenheit from our in-house machined
aluminum plates each with its own
thermocouple which is great temperature
accuracy to less than one degree
Fahrenheit ultra durable powder coated
construction and of course their patent
pending so I say we get started right
away it was just such a pleasure when my
long Peaks showed up I loved the way
they shipped it I loved everything about
how they packaged it it was just really
quite a pleasure to open that package
and I kind of have a feeling this one's
not gonna be too too different crack off
this lid see see what's inside
just a little bit of papers so you've
got your invoice got your invoice right
there you've got rosin bag filters which
is quite nice I'll take a photo of it
and put it up on the screen so you can
see about their press moulds they're
specialized scraping tools you know the
funnel kit the quick flip the bag sizes
the screen sizes all of these different
things are pretty pretty important to
kind of know where you sit how rosin is
pressed they have a really nice little
folder which I will also photograph and
put up on the screen so you can look at
that and see the different screen sizes
and from flower to Keith to bubble hash
and the different tips for the different
things and the consistencies and the
textures these guys have really been
doing a great job I gotta say working
with them has
an absolute pleasure so they also have a
little card in there for the harvest
rate pharmaceutical freeze dryer all
right look at that here's the top right
there be careful with our knife so it's
gonna be somewhat careful when you're
using a knife especially when you're
opening a package that you don't know
exactly how it's been shipped all right
so these look like the little feet put
those down over here there's four of
them so that makes sense all right what
else we got here yes this is the beat of
the press I've seen these enough times
to know these go on the side of the
machine with the feet that screw into
them so that should be easy enough to do
while we're on the unboxing video let's
just screw these right into here we'll
go as much as we can I'm not sure how
much we should leave but probably
probably a little bit one two three four
threads one two three four threads one
two three four threads perfect that's
the right height
get the other one in here what I love
about peer pressure is just the quality
of the craftsmanship you know the idea
that this came from a real engineering
standpoint and they put a lot of thought
into into putting this this unit
together it is definitely not something
that is fly by the pants seat of your
pants construction they really do an
incredible job I might actually cut this
whole box away rather than try to lift
out the press I think that is what I'm
gonna do
yeah we're gonna give you a little show
on what's going on in here not sure
exactly what all these components are
because I've never seen this unit before
so you're seeing it really for the first
time with me here
not sure which these guys are for oh
yeah this is our little handle yeah that
that little guy right there for cranking
it on the top of the unit I like it I
like it a lot and on to this one right
here it's definitely not as heavy as I
thought it might meet which is really
nice this definitely goes down right on
top boom just like that your handle gets
inserted and then okay so the screws are
actually right in the unit which is
great I can take this off I like how
easy this goes on and off and it doesn't
seem to need to be locked in place which
is very nice okay so I suspect these are
gonna go like that there you can also
put this unit like this so you can
actually have it like this setup where
it's sort of horizontal versus vertical
so both options are there all right so I
already got the one leg on what are the
things with these guys that I make a bit
of a mistake is they'll have a tiny
little bend on their foot and naturally
I'll think that the feet go to the
outside this is actually the opposite of
how it goes you can see the feet go in
the unit builds up and there's three
little allen keys right here in the side
but are fairly easy to unscrew I could
be using a drill in making
easier but i'm using an allen key so be
it
and so i love the way the screws just
come in in place in the machine you
don't have to look for a little bag and
try and find the screws it's quite easy
you just go to where you're going to be
screwing them in and they're already
there so it's just a matter of removing
them and then screwing them in to secure
the feet and I guess that's done because
the feet can go on a variety of ways the
way they've got it set up you can put it
vertical or horizontal so all right just
get this up here threading is just
really done well it's not gonna be
problematic where your screws aren't
aren't screwing in nicely or the going
in sideways everything just lines up
really really well on these units and I
appreciate that about about them okay
there we go little make sure they're
tight on both sides yep yep yep boom
look at that there it is right there it
comes with a power cord got the same
great digital screen and really left the
little screen I like the look of this
little unit I'm pretty excited about it
alright so I figured we should do a
little press I've got a little bit of
canvas here it sounds like we can press
a solid 12 grams of flour at a time on
this little unit so we're gonna take the
little flip tool that they have I've got
the screen over top here this is a
hundred and fifteen micron screen we're
just gonna flip it inside out
that's gonna get that seam on the inside
for us and it will hold a lot less oil
as
you know contaminants capturing oil that
we really would rather have release I've
got my little funnel I'm going to put on
my gloves so we've got our little bag
we've got our little 12 grams of herb I
am of course pressing my all-time
favorite where is my bike just such a
great flower to press as it truly really
releases an incredible amount of resin
so we'll go into there nice I've gone
off about these tools before but I might
as well a little bit again I just love
the ease with which these tools operates
I've got quite a bit of extra room it's
definitely not going all the way to the
top I'll have a nice little bit of
screen I'll just be able to fold over
I brought my pure pressure template here
for pre pressing the pre press get that
in there much better over there so we've
got a nice flattened piece here this is
the older one that I took from and then
we have some papers so they sent me once
again with some screens all sorts of
varieties of screens here which I was
very happy I'll be doing some
experimenting including stainless steel
screens right there send me some
stickers which I will be giving away to
some folks
all right so oh man oh they even sent me
a new see that so let's get this opened
up and access some of this paper I
wondered why this paper was a little
smaller than the parchment that I'm used
to but I get
it makes very good sense in the sense
that we're using a much smaller press so
too will we be using much smaller paper
so I think first things first because
we're not ready to press yet let's hit
the switch on this little boy this bad
boy will see the screen line up probably
come over to the side here a little bit
and you turn it okay please remove force
from press then press okay all right
let's remove force from press okay ah
there we go so it opens up the same old
LED screen that I'm used to and know and
love
it's giving me my force it's got system
settings it's got recipes it's got a
quick press it's got run recipe it's
about last run data so I say we go into
recipes I have merely turned the heaters
on here and here I've got my settings at
220 Fahrenheit which for the you know
recipe that we're gonna be running is
gonna work fine for me let's go back to
home let's go back to recipes and let's
go back to this one so this one edit
recipe name set material type well
restarted it again that's interesting
well let's you know what let's do it so
we'll go select flour select bag size
okay so it's adding that the weight
based on bag side it's got the
temperatures it's got my pressures
alright so I'll just go run and then I
have to push start press when we're
actually ready to do this and I'll be
turning this little guy to to check out
how how well it works so very very cool
little unit these guys do such a great
job it's got a little drip tray for
those of you that didn't know what this
was
it's loose weight now
was playing around with it now I'm gonna
hold the camera but I love the idea of a
drip tray I have to admit there we go
because these sides I've had parchment
absolutely drip down inside the machine
on my long Peaks so this is a very nice
little unit right here this little drip
tray it comes in and out very easy you
can lift it right out if you don't want
to use it and it's just a matter of
actually opening up the press a little
bit which happens very easy with a
little bit of twisting and this just
pops right out so that's our little tray
right there I also found out that these
particular guys are obviously clamps and
what they are for is to clamp the unit
down to any table that you're working on
if need be if you're really cranking
away at this thing so I'm going to use
the drip tray you can put it down over
this way because that's where the wiring
is I'll fit that a nice and carefully
there you go perfect alright so we'll
wait for these to heat up it's already
at 105 degrees potentially oh look at
that it even came with magnets these
guys are on the ball you can keep that
on it's quite a bit of parchment coming
off the back which is never a problem
for me because I love when I have a real
squisher to be able to have that little
bit of back room for the oil to escape
into so very excited 12 gram runs
obviously this is a lot smaller than I'm
used to doing I'm used to doing 35 to 40
gram runs a flower and even high
- but who knows this is like a real nice
little small unit I can carry it around
with me and I suspect I could get this
thing to fit into a pelican case which
means adventures in rosin making how fun
would it be to take the bubble bags and
the dry set of screens and the rosin
press up to the ice cave on the parrots
and ice caps and bust out some high
quality and that is what's up so we are
at a hundred and thirty nine degrees
Fahrenheit not too bad both sixty to
eighty degrees away from the temperature
that we're looking at and as you can see
there are important components to
getting this you know to making this
easy to making it you know less
difficult and difficult and that's about
having all of the proper tools make sure
you have your bags okay what do I have
the bags I have some 90 microns I have
some 36 microns I have some 72 microns
and I have some hundred and fifteen
microns so for different sized bags
most of these bearings are used for
flour 36 micronized use for hash we've
got the template for pressing we've got
our funnels which I can put the dirty
ones in here as well as our flipper unit
which is very key and then we've got our
our bags our parchment paper so that's
also very important just kind of getting
all this stuff out of here that's pretty
cool the way you can the way you can you
know basically attach these two to a
table and it's it's not very difficult
to do is it you're just gonna try maybe
one while we're sitting here tables not
queue wide but definitely wide enough
that it's there's that
one other one of those little doctors
not sure this so that's actually a
really good idea I'm sure once you get
you know moving on this thing you could
get a little excited depending on who
you are
you could start moving the whole unit
and that's not really gonna be an ideal
situation so when the screen gets put in
properly and doesn't doesn't come out
because then we end up with with a fair
bit of screen contaminant and a plate
nice to be able to put my finger in
there or not worry about the whole press
squishing it and crushing it that's very
nice
okay so let's go start press stage one
yeah so we're at 729 pounds we're at a
thousand 1,100 forces at 2,800 okay
forces at 4600 let's see if we can
turn a little bit and I can start seeing
the oil coming out now I can see quite a
bit of oil coming up the sides here is
buttering up nicely here and it's that
it's that some good force right little
close up what we got going on here there
we go
without our percentage we got 8,000
pounds of force
I like the drip tray I do indeed like
the drip tray and you can also see
around back here that it's also starting
to push rosin up through the back and it
looks like it's wanting to butter up
right away and that generally is what
happens with very high THC product it
was only 12 grams so I'm hoping for at
least 3 grams of rosin that would be
maybe even a little bit more for this
particular strain cultivar cycle
complete let's stop the press and we'll
open this up it really only gets a
little bit tough at the end alright
let's go around and see what we got here
[Music]
here we go for our yield so I'm gonna
collect that up and I'll let you guys
know what it is in one second here
pretty exciting
alright so I have crushed out the first
and second press I did end up getting
just over 3 grams which I guess would
probably be around 26% 27% so I left up
a little bit behind from what I normally
get with my long Peaks keep in mind this
is my first press with this unit I
didn't really understand exactly how to
set it up so I'm pretty sure in the next
week or two I'll get that 2% back
certainly not upset with it that's for
sure three solid grams
really caramel beautiful where's my bike
flour rosin I gotta say so far the first
experience with the helix Pro has been
really cool I did also figure out both
of these how they actually go on as they
go between the wheel and the foot so
they go kind of like that underneath and
so that's why they don't need to be
different sides they both work perfectly
and I will set it up next time better
with the with the clamps because once
you get it listen the first when you're
closing it and opening it opens really
easy as you get to around 5 6,000 7,000
8,000 pounds per pressure it starts
getting a little bit harder and I can
see for sure how you could move the
whole press so I'm going to thank you
all for tuning in you're gonna see a lot
more happening with this press we're
gonna do a whole video and actually
using this press with flour dry sift and
bubble hash I just really wanted to do
an unboxing video today and I thought
what a great way to do an unboxing video
to also show a really quick press so
thank you to the people the the group
over at peer pressure the team if you
will I look forward to seeing you all at
lyft in January January 11th to 13th or
14th I believe here in Vancouver these
guys peer pressure coming out and we'll
have a booth you could probably find me
at their booth otherwise I would be
walking around with my team from embark
if you see me there definitely pull me
aside and say hello and great great
little unit super quality I mean once
you see this unit in person and you feel
the quality of the tools you really get
the idea very quickly this is a solid
unit so thanks a lot peer pressure
thanks everyone for watching and we'll
see you next time on
[Music]