[Music]
all right oh man here with Doug from
hemp hoodlum in Amsterdam welcome to
Amsterdam yeah you want to turn your
office come see our new office excellent
right in here
here's our new friends this photo was
taken in Ibiza
it looks like snow but it's actually a
salt mine so that worked for that and
this was actually done in Amsterdam when
the canals froze over
oh very where you take a canal boat but
on this situation you're a little it
doesn't happen every winter anymore does
it it happens about every eight years
five days or something come on in
examples beautiful Martha she's cutting
insulation for our entry the candidates
Carolyn - excellent which is a drop th
seeds not bombs so if we were just to
drop seeds instead of bombs the world
would be a better place especially if
their MKULTRA seems very true yes
excellent so one beam in each package
yes a feminized MKULTRA so you're gonna
get some good ganja out of that yeah
very nice yeah excellent
these are our hip art beautiful this is
George in jail because if he was alive
today he would be for the amount of hemp
he grew he would be behind bars for life
he'd be next to mark yeah it would be
horrible so this one here is here our
new drop seeds not bombs that's nice
came up with that and I think it was 95
the first time the logo was different
but that was I remember the they were
playing with the seeds yeah 95 was my
first cup yeah the head of booth yeah
yeah all right so office will review
Internet so beautiful and there's our
other slogan of course which is make him
not war that's the one we entered last
year love it excellent around this is
our winter jackets
our winter collection all of them are
beautiful love the hoodlum stuff this is
our summer range for 2014 next summer
excellent
and another thing we'd like to do is
support sea shepherd against killing the
whales absolutely a percentage of
everything that is made and sold goes
towards sea shepherd help stop the
whaling very cool and here you can see
the signature from Captain Paul Watson
and this is from captain Alex who was
captain of three different boats for sea
Shepherd he was just here last week and
we sent off for the next campaign which
is called no resistance I should know
the name of it but it's gonna be another
successful campaign to stop the whaling
awesome
and then over here more messy side
here's where we keep the these are
leftover hemp rolls which we used for
decoration and for sampling beautiful
and upstairs is where we work excellent
so am the hoodlum crew holding it down
the beginning of the canvas gonna fall
starting tomorrow thanks for having us
out of here you're welcome
awesome
okay