hey guys welcome to bubble man's world i
am here in beautiful squamish bc at an
undisclosed location uh i've been
invited by high integrity glass art
who's throwing a show for uh yoshinori
condo incredible glassblower
he's they've got some beautiful glass in
the house here so what i wanted to do
was just a quick little introduction
this is kind of a vip day for buyers
to come in uh rashaan has invited me in
prior uh to his good buddy's house who's
allowing him to throw this event i'm
super excited to check out the glass
uh you know
this gentleman is an absolute next level
glassblower i'm sure you guys recognize
the name i've i've
videoed him making glass in the past at
high integrity glass arts studio and now
we're here today uh october 20th 2021
checking out some of his latest work
let's go check it out
yes
incredible
glass
high integrity glass art
my goodness
obviously your favorite
yeah the cup for sure the tube's a tk
half a
yoshi colab
oh really stocky tube
oh this one yeah
oh my goodness
that's beautiful
this sake tube
i love the ode
to japanese culture
ready yeah
i'm ready oh
it's got the light
that is up look at that just in here
man that is subtle but beautiful
holy smokes
always excited to see
what these guys
are capable of doing i mean this is
this is really kind of the highest level
of glass production
for sure of all these years yeah of all
these years of
photographing and getting to experience
it it just seems like this is the
pinnacle right
here try to flip it over if you can flip
the marble over yeah
sure
i'll be surprised of course i
the will
oh my god
looks like europe 72.
jesus
the detail is absolutely astonishing
i might have to get the macro lens out
on that bad boy
you got a couple ships
it's the flower of life ballroom and uh
hive series uh four seed egg
with the ewok
uh terp elevators i think they're called
yes
so nothing but the best clearly
and then marbles from yoshi the man
himself yes
oh geez
yeah that's a little ewok uh marble set
oh beautiful
so pimp
even the carb caps are just perfection
been too too long
since we've done this
[Music]
man i'm glad that you're uh
you're back at it this is wonderful to
see little jerry bear
he's very dead inspired so is that
europe 72
uh
i would imagine
you know they are uh
heavy grateful dead fans and then as
they should be
that's beautiful
the girl i was shooting on and cali the
other day they were all dead heads on
the farm they had like the craziest
numbers
[Music]
now
[Applause]
[Music]
quickly sense media
[Applause]
[Music]
obligated to clarify
[Applause]
[Music]
is
and in turn showing off yeah
[Music]
yes
[Laughter]
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
the wisdom of the wise keep my eggs dead
i love the streets
[Music]
is
try
[Music]
i love the streets
you