[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome to the wonderful world of
high integrity glass art I have just
been so lucky as to take the most most
epic rip of chemo full melt bubble hash
out of this Fab Klein Taurus or Fab
Taurus Klein whatever you want to call
it it has 88 Opals on it I've really uh
never seen anything like it it is an
absolute work of art Flower of Life or
seed of Life along the bottom big giant
trippy perk in the bottom of the uh just
above below the uh Fab egg what an
unbelievable piece looks like it's got a
dose crushed opal Mothership honey
bucket on there and I've got a little
sweet skunk dry sift that we just
literally pressed out is this the one
here yeah so we just pressed out a
little uh of the sweet skunk dry sift
powder that is here and I guess it's
time to uh light this honey bucket up
because my
goodness it's time wa that's outrageous
I'm not a big torch fan I have to admit
they scare
me such a beautiful
piece really really really
incredible I would go as far as saying
it's the most beautiful piece I've ever
ripped to date in my life so here we go
[Music]
well not only is it one of the most
beautiful pieces I've ever hit cuz truly
I'm not sure if it's transferring onto
the video here this piece is absolutely
spectacular the opal work and how
perfectly uh encased in GL clear glass
that they are and the colors that are
accessible to us through the glass of
the Opals is absolutely above and beyond
anything I've ever seen in a glass piece
and uh yeah big up the mothership for
producing such an unbelievable piece of
glass Scott deppy and your and your team
of of talented artists and big up high
integrity glass art for for for for
having such an epic piece here in Canada
for me to be able to come and
rip very
cool thanks for watching guys hey
welcome to Bubble man's world and
welcome to the wonderful world of high
integrity glass art I'm here visiting
with high integrity glass art and they
have been so gracious as to allow me to
hit this I would call it a one-of aind
uh Fab Klein tourus or Fab Taurus Klein
I'm not going to argue with you guys
what it's called cuz I'm the one holding
it and about to hit it I'm just saying
that this is what it is there's 88 Opals
on this masterpiece it's just absolutely
stunning I've taken some beautiful
photos and I'll share those with you
during the video really nice pull on
it and uh the original honey bucket that
came with it I've shown you is not on it
this is a a Dosa that's on here and it
it hits beautiful and for whatever
reason that's the one we're going to be
using today with this 88 opal
Masterpiece so without further
Ado
let's heat it
up I've got some congales on the
titanium Dabber here the Highly
Educated so that'll be very nice to
taste it's always a pleasure to hit some
congales resin I have to admit
all
right what a beautiful piece of glass
really you can hold this piece of glass
with all these Opals on the bottom it is
solid
the optimized flavor zone is the zone
I'm currently
in check out high integrity glass art
you guys can find them on Facebook you
can find them on YouTube I'll have a
link to them in this comment
section where have you ever seen glass
this beautiful thanks for watching
guys sh the kind of real cloud like I
say cuz I bring about this
music man Roy alongside one
[Music]
SP stly s oh yes
againest head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke Co
that's why I don't grumble
Med oh
yeah must be burn like must be clean ra
vital for Spiritual a king Salon certify
the tree and he is the wisest manto we
so prop preach
her true speech so meanwhile the song
called lead us deceive man obligated to
clarify and teach you
[Music]
now marijana MEP just get a home from a
friend of the
highest just it from the higher
[Music]