[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm sitting here from with Martin from
rure and we're over at high integrity
glass Arts which uh you have to admit
some of the pieces we've seen up to date
have
been the best I ever seen yeah
completely Beyond stellar and right at
the end he's like oh did I show you my
wife's new piece and he pulls this out
and I'm like I don't know why I am so
impressed with this but man this is one
of my favorites that he show me and so
this is uh a Darby Nate Dizzle uh
collaboration uh this is uh the cactus
dcro that uh that um Darby is uh known
for smallest twiss perk I've ever seen
uh Dizzle Swiss Park I don't know what
the the red color is called and then of
course uh Rose slapped on an elite
Bucket from Mothership so it just fits
so beautifully I think uh I think I'm
going to maybe uh have a little
dab Let's see we got the torch right
here I really have this affinity for the
smaller piece I appreciate the smaller
and smaller pieces you know I know the
uh well the cups we were looking at
those are small pieces they're by no
means what I would call a large piece
but it's interesting to
see all right there we go kind what do
you got going on with this torch
here no more guas maybe out of gas it's
possible that's okay is this the only
other one right
here gas technical difficulties here
we're going to be getting some gas right
away I could move the phone and take
that other torch I'm balancing my phone
up against the other torch right now
which is quite ridiculous so here oh
look at this you've got torches man high
integrity glass doesn't mess around
so yep that's the
one all right we'll get that dab
prepared and we'll have the whole thing
uh all sorted out dab being held off
camera there you want to pass that dab
over
Martin I'll get high with a Little Help
from My
Friends hell
yeah I'm so excited to hit this little
guy someone was uh criticizing me today
on uh YouTube saying that I I was
hitting the hash too fast and that I
would get a better taste if I waited and
I don't think he understood that I was
hitting hash instead of oil but here we
go
guys
[Applause]
[Music]
yep that's a very cool little piece hats
off to Dizzle and Derby proper up bad
e