[Music]
hey guys what up bubble man here in
Whistler British Columbia and I thought
what a great opportunity Flav and Aaron
just buggered off to go get some uh
Samurai Sushi and I've got the Fab egg
the Marcel deppy air trapped ratachello
Fab egg with the drop down now uh this
drop down was blown by someone
completely different I cannot remember
who but when I do I will mention it and
I've got a nice rip of the Congo here so
you know what we're doing we're going to
take that Congo and drop it in the
Dil
absolutely spectacular on the mothership
rips thank you Flav uh for both the
Congo um Bubble that you've supplied
beautiful Congo bubble
and of course the Epic glass that uh
that you always seem to have my brother
so uh keep watching Bubble man's world
we're going to be puffing a ton more fat
glass up here in Whistler and uh we're
going to be doing a bunch of fun
adventures so keep watching