[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here in Kingston Jamaica got eggy
just off camera here the master grower
respect bless that and uh I'm going to a
little uh review today actually here in
Jamaica I'm lucky enough to find some
Bubble Man
brand lemon redy 3:1 tur rosin this won
first place at uh the emerald Cup this
year which I guess they kind of
announced after they had already
announced the first winners that ended
up getting disqualified uh so great job
on that Tony verzura killing it with the
half gram of lemon remedy really nice so
we're going to hit that we're also going
to hit some flow turp rosin we got a
half gram of dog walker flow turp rosin
so you can see that right there give you
a little stuff is just absolutely
beautiful make sure it focuses on the
right thing
there that's
it I put this on YouTube what's that
YouTube it's going up on YouTube
absolutely I got a little sour Tangi as
well from Blue River tpping so we might
be doing a little bit of a TP dip as
well um oh I have to find my Dabber I
will be right be right back all right
grabbed my Dabber I think I want to
start with some lemon remedy just looks
so ridiculous 3 to1 TP
rosin this stuff is
absolutely
stupendous did a really great job on
that trying to cut me out here and get
this into the nice closeup there we go
so yeah let's do a little dab here on
the 3:1 the lemon
remedy uh maybe Tony will be able to
come out as well and a little bit and
give you guys a little bit of background
on the lemon
remedy how he went about preparing it
and uh yeah for now I'm going to give
you my thoughts on it out of the Klein
Mothership here in Kingston
Jamaica wow
tast is so good yeah just incredible
smells nice in the air too doesn't it
yeah well if you were lucky enough to be
one of the people down in Cali that was
able to um Locate some of this as I
don't believe that there any drops were
actually made I think it just kind of
got traded out amongst uh close
people really really incredible taste on
this lemon
remedy three to
one 3 2
1 so it's getting a little dark out here
soon give you guys a little bit of view
just to show you what's going on there's
T man wow look at this so we're just
doing a little video I was just hitting
the lemon remedy oh yeah and I thought
maybe you could come on camera and tell
a little talk a little bit about it cuz
you know yeah you know what's going on
but feel free to take a couple
pictures and I am going to come back
over here and maybe hit the dog
walker and then if you want to come over
and just give us a few words on each one
that would be
amazing yes yes
yes all
right really nice headp space on that 3
to one unique
different definitely not what I'm
hitting on the
regular oo this dog
Walker Jesus I think the dog walker is
the chem the chem 91 with the uh Albert
Walker Kush okay right mhm that's from
the uh that was the last of the
uh Emerald Orchards right mhm get this
up b
o whole rip whole rip gone I won't even
go back there wow
yeah yeah that's how works sometimes
when you're trying to fix the camera you
Dro in dabs all right so dog walker dog
walker TP
oil I think that one was in the 70s 70
percentile with 15 15 plus 15 20% turbs
had you tried that one yet is that your
first time hitting oh
wow it's one of my favorites real
reminds me of California
oh
wow it's ranky yeah fueling
cush it's a nice little sunset here so
yeah I think you should just maybe take
yourself a little rip of uh let me take
a little rip of the dog walker dog
Walker's right here and then do lemon
remedy yeah lemon remedy and so the
lemon remedy was the one that ended up
going for first at the emerald cup sure
did right okay I wasn't 100% sure but
it's a delayed reaction you know like a
month or so right but uh you know they
were I guess you got to respect the fact
they'd go back and you know they're
trying to live to the standards of their
competition whether things were entered
under different uh understandings or not
but it was um distillates were
disqualified and anyone that failed
pesticides or
microbial was
also
disqualified and so our uh lemon remedy
flower oil y was a 3:1 uh SE dvda to
thca and
uh and also had like I think 11% tpine
so it was like kind of a 3 to one to one
right 3 to one: one it's delicious it's
amazing super nice headp space on it
we've of course
been uh driving around the city all day
in downtown Kingston going to Banks and
lawyers offices and all these different
things getting uh you know dotting uh
the eyes and crossing the te's for uh
conoid research and development and it's
our last night here tonight so we're
just going to enjoy just enjoyed the
sunset seeing the city slowly light up I
can hear our other partners just arrived
uh down by the pool we're up on the deck
right now but I figured I'd just do a
short little video today to one thing I
want to add on that the lemon remedy one
mhm um there's that patent that just
came out recently right that's kind of
actually fits the the mold for that one
that's a chemo type 2 drug cultivar that
is um High CBD low THC very very little
to low
mering but High lemoning high loning so
there's not that cherry traditional
Cherry taste and uh those that went to
the emerald cup that came by the harbor
side Booth was able to try that we were
I had people hitting me up that were
lucky enough to try it and saying wow
dude
superb which always good when it gets
back to you yeah absolutely that's what
you want to hear you want to hear people
are happy with the end product and uh
it's not uh you know know it's not one
of these it's not a brand that's easily
represented you can't just throw
anything together for the bubble man
brand it really has to be um that
special special so well I think that was
also 2016 it was good that we kind of
got some stuff out there and there's
definitely
some know people are like oh why don't
you make more of it and things and it's
it's just uh one of those things where
it's like you got to have a certain
facility in standard and thank God knock
on wood 2016 we got through in 2017 we
will have a
full-blown uh Bubble Man lab that will
be uh in Oakland and you'll probably see
a lot of collaborations white labels but
the tech itself and the facility uh
they'll kind of like your certification
and our CER our certification on it
absolutely I'm excited for that I'm
looking forward to it 2017's excited you
know there there's a saying big Tings
big Tings lots of people always like to
say that each time a new year starts I
haven't said it myself in a while but I
can definitely say that 17 has started
off pretty sweet and it's looking to be
um it's looking to be uh a good year
yeah absolutely let me get some of that
lemon remedy yeah hit the lemon remedy
puff us out on this short Kingston video
we end up being so busy we're not really
we don't have a lot of time to spend in
front of the camera and uh make videos
for you guys but I know you guys get to
get like to get a peek when and where
you can we went from 9:00 a.m. to 1:00
a.m. yeah non-stop every day every day
for meetings today's unique we had a
little time so figured we'd uh oh it's
the first time I hit these
gifts
yeah lemon remedy remedy and dog
walker that lemon remedy is just so
unique it's a true
blueberry afgh cross from a buddy named
Nick
really like I say it over and over you
know you can't make good resin
uh products extracts if you will from
bad no grown cuz for a while people
thought that extracting was creating
quality but then they slowly realize
that extracting is actually unveiling
whatever happens to be there you're just
unveiling it you don't um I mean in a
sense you you do make the appearance of
it to be better because you're smoking a
much Pur product and it affects you in a
more concentrated way but really all you
do as an extractor a hash maker is you
unveil the quality that the plant and
the grower have already um you know
spent months working on yeah and in the
beginning you know we were just kind of
pressing flowers but like you could see
the difference so when you take this
particular lemon remedy it almost grows
like a very naughty almost like an OG
mhm a little bit bigger it's got kind of
the pine cone uh shape to it and I asked
him you know don't trim it don't don't
touch it just hang it cure it and as
soon as it starts to bend you know and
just barely snap off then go ahead and
cut it right into a directly into a
turkey bag right so I got it that way
and then it was uh cured cold for a long
time um I would say a good month and a
half so the tricomes in a sense that
last bit of the curing mhm we did in the
freezer like in a a cold
dry uh environment so we did like kind
of a fresh cure kind of snapped off then
kept it really cold for a month what's
up gentlemen and then pressed that out
what's up e chill chill we're just
finishing up a little video for bubble
man's world that's Ernie who just walked
in one of our partners from United
cannabis Master grower and uh yeah how
was your day dude my day was great I saw
the pictures you bastard that that's I
knew it was going to be like that when
you come all the time and you're like
it's Kingston and it's Montego and you
get stuck in a little tur you never get
to enjoy like what dude so walking with
Miss Joy that owns the property was
super cool and uh I saw all kinds of
spots that I'm sure Dave would like
right on dude well I saw just a few
pictures that you took and it was
spectacular the waterfall the Blue Hole
the river the property like it was just
all completely ridiculous well that's
like the other property we we were uh we
were on helping these guys uh work on
there's uh what is that a two acre fish
pond yeah create the own fish emotion oh
each one is an acre yeah each one was an
acre and then that's a a 5year project
right right and then you just drain it
dig the fish Emulsion and put the fish
back
in W so the first crop in Jamaica with
crd yeah will be done that way I can't
imagine how much the plants would like
that blue water it was it looks so well
you know how much you like it well it
looks it looks so much like Disney World
that I had to walk out and touch the
rocks to see make sure they weren't C I
was like it looks like the British built
a built a dam here and I'm like no
that's real Rock wow yeah dude was there
a blue hole there was there a water hole
that went into I thought I sawal of them
those are the best every like 25 yards
was another waterf on another waterfall
oh my God yeah it was crazy she's like I
would love to do some Eco tourism here
like yeah we could build Dave one of
those tiny houses right here on this
right here the tiny house well that's
just a tease for you guys out there in
bubble man's world we will uh try to
give you better updates in the near
future we like to be quiet as we're
working on things you know Jamaica can
be chatty chatty place but uh you'll
hear more from us in 2017 so peace out
from the crd and you can team
[Music]