hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm over at Flav's place and about to
hit this beautiful Dosa condo uh collab
the condo is a marble on the bottom you
can see right there and you can kind of
see it in through the top there's not
really a window uh to see it but it is
absolutely beautiful the line work is
insane like I'm absolutely blown away
especially by this top uh neck of the
mouthpiece really incredible work Dosa
thumbs up on this piece uh I've got the
denail in with the silicon carbide nail
and we're going to hit a little bit of
bubble has out of this bad boy so uh
let's get her started shall
[Music]
we
turps that's what I'm talking about
right there two thumbs
[Music]
up