so this is um a fairly epic um piece by
Ghost and this particular piece has been
Electra formed it's got just I mean let
me get it off the stand it's it's not
your average piece just to pull off the
stand is uh is a bit of an experience
especially with the Bowl here probably
best to remove that first now you pull
it right out drop that bowl back in
which I have a Slinger Bowl in there
right now pull this off to the side and
I can kind of give you guys a little bit
of a show you can see it's got this
incredible brain marble up here it's got
uh just immaculate detail in the face uh
these are actual metal components that
have been uh electroformed right onto
the piece the base is completely metal
not glass at all and uh it's actually
quite a sturdy Place uh piece you just
wouldn't want to grab it around these
canes this would be a very delicate
place on the pipe and otherwise just
once again an absolutely Stellar piece
from uh Flav
so why don't we get to it and load up a
little sweet
skunk there we
go nice little fat bowl
there all
right going to use the matches from
HQ from the crew at
HQ all right I tell you a piece like
this really
really could throw you off if you didn't
know how to Puff it it really is a
Unique Piece in that sense I got the the
cut bowl by Slinger so it makes it nice
and easy to do the layback
rip
awesome thank you Flav thank you ghost
thank you Glass artists worldwide and
thank you cannabis Growers and hash
makers you all make this experience the
wonderful experience that it is meant to
be thanks for watching Bubble man's
world and we'll talk to you soon