that smells good Heavenly days sweet
skunk again cono sweet skunk sweet hey
what's going on everybody I'm here at
the Cannabis culture headquarters cchq
Lounge uh on Davy Street hanging out
with my buddy
Nate oh yeah and I guess uh I figured I
would share a bowl with you guys while
I'm here so got this beautiful Elite
Mothership whatever 3D Purple Rain
ridiculousness
I know you're enjoying that matin what
do you say [ __ ] yeah hell yeah welcome
everybody I hope it's a good day let's
Heat this thing
up so we could rip it hey you doing okay
over
there we've also got uh this little uh
Klein that used to be Addison deura in
the house right here with the nice
little oh welcome Mary G uh Mary Jane
green got the uh lemon drop ofz here as
well it just fits on there so
beautifully boom boom
boom boom 50 people in the house soon
it'll be soon it'll be 500 let me Heat
this up can you time me on this one
thank You Might Get Loud here in a
second I got to torch this
[Applause]
up bong rip John H Bell bong
rip hell
yes oh yeah dude I knew you would be
digging this mat team I know you have an
appreciation for mother
ships he's talking about the potential
of opening another melting point here in
Vancouver one day uh almost a bubble
man's world more than a melting point so
yeah that's good if you want to hit that
timer or you hit it already you're good
he's good really good hey what's going
on David what do you think of this bad
boy should we bring this to Spain this
year for spannabis I'll have to invite
Nathan you coming to Spain
Nathan March
it's going to be hella fun it might be
there if it's there it'll be at the
headquarters because trust me Nate will
want to be hanging out at uh HQ it's the
best place in Barcelona for chilling
welcome uh uh Ethan in the
house I should get my dad
ready don't you
thinky no I'm smoking on your
rosin and some of my rosin actually
let's go bigger so this is ready in 133
seconds sweet
oh yeah I do it because I have a
passport that's what I'm talking about
gorgeous nice yeah dude we'll try to get
you your uh Instagram photo David all
right here we go we're
good
[Music]
low temp
supremus oh yeah definitely when you're
puffing out of a a pipe like this with a
bowl on it this nice it's best to just
do those low temp dabs so when you clean
it out it cleans out real nice you don't
want to be leaving a bunch of dirt
behind it's just not cth
you ready for one yeah let do all
right all right all right the fine you
can heat that bad boy up get you one of
these ready little
rosin and some of this
too all right is it good yeah it's good
the mixture is great I mean you got the
cookies in there it's nice let's show
these guys what's going
on all right not bad
pipe a bowl hey whatever honey
bucket Call It Whatever you will just
don't call me late for dinner just don't
call me late for
dabs little Ziggy Marley in the
background hey welcome Debbie
southernland I haven't seen everyone
that's come in I haven't been paying
attention like I normally do so hello
everyone sorry for not mentioning you by
name when you first came in I know that
it's a a nice thing to hear when you
come into a new
chat is what it is that's it Mason
that's it it cheers
David favorite type of concentrate oh
well U my favorite would be 99.9%
glandular Tricom heads whether it's wet
washed or dry sifted as long as it's
99.9% microencapsulated resin glands
that's my favorite after that I love me
some rosin whether it's flower rosin or
um hash rosin I I I enjoy them both
quite quite
well
here we go gearing up waiting for the
one more second or nine more seconds one
more all right look at
that
betiful
boom very hazy that smell is just pure
sweet skunk you guys can't imagine it
just
reeks
thanks for sharing by the way I always
like tuning in to your
videos oh nice first bubble badge that's
awesome got a bunch of people watching
live right now while we're chilling out
at the cchq you can see the dab bar in
the
background pretty chill little Zone not
too bad I do have an IG it's BC bubbl
man
and and Nate is dab Vice is that
correct all right yeah he hit a a good
hit I'm coughing from his hit actually
actually got me pretty
good all right cool Maxim
salute Jared Scully asks what would it
take for you to open another
shop I don't know we were just saying we
were just talking about it it would
probably take uh a bunch of energy like
money connections a space
a rental or a purchase
agreement um probably quite a bit of
things but it's not like it's an
impossibility it could happen I know
Vancouver could really use a bubble
man's world a space for all things
bubble one day we'll see shout out from
Winnipeg from Sean Feldman anyway I'm
going to keep going we're going to go
eat some food I'll hit you guys up later
when we have another uh oh no problem
Maxim I figured you were talking to
someone named Jeff
oh I'll take extra hits for you Sean
Michael and Winnipeg always shouting out
Winnipeg my home toown where I have my
roots I saw it's supposed to be minus
215 in Winnipeg on uh on Wednesday I
think it must have been a typo on the
Weather Channel my mother sent it to me
made me laugh pretty hard - 27 - 26 -
215 exactly Patrick and Corey could use
it but I would also bring a lot of
well-known um artists I personally would
love to throw one of the first
Mothership shows in Vancouver and bring
up the whole crew from Bellingham how
[ __ ] sick would that be so close so
close anyway stay tuned for that guys
have a good one