hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here at my warehouse sloff space SL
storefront uh you can see all the
different Bubble Bags lined up in the
back here a couple of Jason King posters
and today I wanted to actually just show
you one of my prize possessions in my
glass collection which is one of my
Marcel bronze from uh 1999 so this is uh
one of the original sculpt sculptured
pieces it's got the uh incredible
octopus on there beautiful school of
fish fish with an angel fish that's
Hollow can actually fill him and the
octopus up and then of course it's got
the uh the Marcel 99 signed marble so
it's been a while since I hit this old
school
can yep I think it's going to be good
let's dump in a little bubs got myself a
little screen on there little bit of
Astro Boy
Bubble full melt for the wind
got myself a
beline all
right barely lit the beine but I got it
done and it's time to hit some
history
thanks for
watching