[Music]
because we've done this before one cake
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with Horatio Delbert and we are
at the CC HQ vapor lounge on the second
floor nice private place for us to shoot
today yeah you know I wanted to get
together and celebrate major victory in
Canada I mean it's for the most part
it's status quo NBC but for all of our
brethren around the country on they get
to explore something new it's he was
down it's huge what of course Horatio
was talking about is the Smith versus
Regina case Owen Smith and Ted Smith who
was the owner of the dispensary that the
bakery was working for at the time of
the initial bust a couple years ago the
judge struck down the word dried out of
dried marijuana and he changed the
definition of just us being allowed to
have cannabis into being able to have
anything cannabis so when you remove the
word dried in the novel sudden it stops
seeds resin leaves any part of the plant
whatsoever so that was two years ago for
BC the judge decided it was only for BC
guys like myself when I go back home to
Manitoba I was unable to bring hash back
there I was only allowed to travel with
herb in the vaporizer so when I leave to
go to Manito
the end of this month you've damn sure
I'm going to be bringing some extra is a
different world same thing with me
traveling to Ontario it stings for a lot
of people that move out to the west
coast but at the same time Ontario is
that East Coast hub and it's where you
are going to get to that crowd and it's
funny about what we take a stand in
medicine I saw a news article where it
was like someone was caught with four
grams of shatter this stuff is potent
bandits and it was made and to get just
with it turned it right back into crack
right and now I can see the you know
that person's case being overturned that
thumb got arrested for it and the whole
police division that was kind of gearing
up for um cracking heads on the subject
matter I mean the way to go it's a very
important decision nonetheless the best
analogy I've ever heard Kirk use was in
the what was the court case after the
fed the first one and and before the
Supreme there was three judges and it
was here that was art was in our
medieval Supreme Court yeah maybe that
was our provincial Supreme Court so at
that --cork a skirt to saw said
something absolutely brilliant and it
really I saw the sparkle in the judges
eye I'm sure it's where the dissent came
from and I'm sure it's how he got to the
Supreme Court and it's when he mentioned
that under the current regime we are
allowed to like an elder elderly woman
can acquire cannabis and it's legal for
her to have that but if she takes that
cannabis and steeps it in a cup of tea
she's now done an extraction and she's
now looking at potentially a mandatory
minimum of two years in prison she
became a manufacturer just by simply
getting closer to her passing and that's
how they had it worded but in reality
the judge didn't see that
as her becoming a manufacturer he saw
that as a flawed law that was written in
a way that had to be changed and so that
change has come we are now able to use
extracts right across the board in
Canada and unfortunately it's really
only for the 40,000 of patients under
the MMAR program and I suppose it'll be
their discomfort the MMPR patients but
it doesn't give them access it doesn't
give them access that's the key right
there the MMPR patients can take their
product and they can get who knows who
to make it I don't know if I'm legally
allowed to make it if for a sheõs are we
allowed to have a lab and make products
for people we don't know right now we're
allowed to make them for ourselves
horatio obviously goes out of his way
and makes them for people because he
believes that you know helping people
that are sick is the right thing to do
and I sort of I stand behind him that
firmly but at the same time we have
families we have wives and we have
children and we have things that we need
to protect while we're doing this sort
of good work yeah it's it's one of those
I mean even congratulations all the M&amp;P
are people who some of them pay the
price some of them use it to engage the
dispensaries so currently that's the
only model where dispensaries are
available that MMPR people have been
able to find access but again that
access is technically legal still
because there's no such thing as a
designated processor we're already other
type of term like that and we don't
exactly have that type of back and forth
infrastructure but for somebody in
Manitoba you can always get online maybe
it's time to order yourself a bubble bag
kit on you can start to convert your
stuff up but on a scale that actually
deals with you could almost say type 1
patients patients who are either
physically unable to actively do
anything um mr. Bay tries to keep
whether it's the fakirs fine or they're
in a condition of such terminology that
thumbed they can barely get justice or
something down they require to be make
they're gonna need help and eventually
somebody it's like I see this happening
all over again with somebody
reaching out getting caught and then we
end up in a challenge when it comes to
um the right to produce for someone else
because of that same eventually the
government become aware of the unique
talents that it takes degree of some of
these medicines absolutely some of those
unique talents are sitting right here at
this table right now one of the things I
wanted to mention while Horatio was
talking about the ability to make your
own hash bubble bags is going to be
offering a 25% discount to all MMAR and
MMPR
patients that would like to get into
water extraction you can go to bubble
bag comm and you can use the code health
canada that'll be the code for the 25%
discount off of bubble bank kits and
machines so we're always down with
giving discounts alright i guess to
start the commemoration of extracts
let's start with an extraction of our
main ingredient THC a so we're gonna
start with the main ingredient a ratio
has done a fine extraction here done
some pure THC a that's the THC acid it
has not been heated so this is the
carboxylic acid ring still intact and
it's very very very white and I'm
guessing
has pretty much knows no older give it a
go and see where breath that's kind of
why I said last time I'm not high purity
but I'm not going around thumping on any
chest but pretty close to odorless I
mean the tiniest little bit of that
University the limine valencian mm-hmm
but really like it's just funny because
I've seen so many people that all we've
got pure and they'll somebody 98 percent
and it's the yellow it's still got
discoloration so it seems as you get
closer and closer one percent I mean I
know this is a couple of notches
brighter than the previous incarnation
so on the next question is how much
stronger is it if you keep removing that
contaminated the adults all right
so okay here's the question did you want
to hear that hit that off of the
Sapphire insert on the shelf or do you
want to go right into the silicon
carbide bit well in this case it's not
really like we're going for flavor here
and one thing I noticed and it was a
definite notice is remember we made that
anecdote about it it kind of having a
slow kind of standardized melt to it it
got even slower with on that subtlety on
to find out so I've actually been
hitting it hotter oh so find I can't
finish now what time are you thinking on
my home nail they looked about 400
Celsius so I have a feeling if it's a
percent we're already good to go it's at
about 680 Fahrenheit right now yeah that
sir that should be fine did you want to
go direct into the cell
or put this afire additional because it
doesn't matter to me I don't mind going
to write come to the silicon I just kind
of want to see it yeah but are you down
with that you're up to your head
the hardest thing is the balance
No
interesting
I found it I mean I white them announcer
sitting in the Sun but it's not as bland
as historically described I guess maybe
they took sativas for granted but WBC I
don't get many upper aggressions that
aren't hybrids it's completely invisible
on the nail well that was interesting
hard to explain almost no taste
whatsoever effects are absolutely there
but they are very one-dimensional you
know as I sit here and feel the effects
trying to slowly curl up behind my eyes
and I feel the effects a little bit in
my body I definitely feel like
please would probably get too too
focused on hitting Pierre TFC all the
time might not a specific range for
something well the thing about it is
isn't it son amendment it is basically
in a way to rev it out because now let's
say we jump over and take it down about
some Sour Diesel how well that basically
we're bringing these terms to the THC in
their system right that's all because we
know that basically you never know what
the team she was genetically growing in
the potential of the Terps so I'm
throwing a little rosin sativa behind it
it might give it the final run of gas it
means but that how was this name on
that's rosin Oh rosin from dry sens
just a little rosin from dry sent us you
know how it goes rosin from dry said
that's who I am
the spirit boys I got this bear suit
well that's great that looks like a
potent stuff so yeah let's put that's
kind of why everyone Google wanna make
be super high on like well you still
need a turf either in your system before
or after but that whole recipe I mean my
analogies always been Terps in two
directions some directions can take you
know where some directions can take you
around the world but the THC is the gas
and we don't always have enough gas to
get to amazing
smells amazing but it didn't produce
that punch all those directions all
extended an amazing trip and it doesn't
yield the actual high so I'm looking at
ways to pretty much bring every straight
into its full potential the only thing I
can't do is make more tours right but I
can't bring well I'll tell you the pure
THC a is very almost just like I said
one dimensional heavy it sort of could
almost get you just staring and I love
the effects in the past when we've taken
the terpenes and modulated that THC and
really felt the uplifting of facts I'm
almost like the feeling of smelling a
flower are squeezing cement and psmith
and smelling some mint david malan
olivine and the house here guys can i
plug my new book please dinner mana free
copies for all potter activists and
otherwise it's 8 bucks it's the answer
to the question this cannabis inherently
harm young pieces developing minds the
answer the short answer is no one of the
reasons I know that is because when I
came to BC I came from London and like
everyone I had an internal instinct to
I'm to Burnaby Mountain and walked he
sings all the way to here and I only use
serve for some of the more life-changing
experiences of my life
oh thank then what you provided at the
herb school during that era did the
Hurstville was legit
upper level next-level [ __ ] it dung it
paid a critical point in many people's
development - you're looking at one of
them today I had some unique psychedelic
trips that I would never have safe
access to anything like it in any way I
could trust that changed my life in
significant ways that your mushrooms
play a major role in my luck we had some
fine fungi today yeah good positivity
that's how it goes I remember the year
at school back in the day and I remember
she's what was the place that you opened
after the Erb school where you were so
nervous we thought in Burnaby oh jeez
both the Burnaby operation was back in
97 yeah with the game Yogi's that was
yeah that was predate service going when
he's like oh that was close those Dutch
embassy flower and achievers yeah
because we figured well we're gonna get
arrested myself a funny medium and one
that makes people think at the same time
the embassy kind of you've always got
great names I only just recently before
the accident that you're spotted someone
told me that you opened this place
called stressed and stressed in two
breaths yeah great [ __ ] names about
it sorry I broke the national
perspective on what a dispensary or what
a place that yeah example medicine is
medicine can also be for the relatively
healthy so trends it I drove under the
retro box I even know the name I just
saw them I tell you what they can be
dedicated to remain high-quality dried
cannabis best cash in Vancouver please
concentrate safe animals books and
pamphlets it looks like I'm gonna have
to go and do a little review on the
stress and repressed your love for you
to check out our entire menu with Louis
vigilant and even an empirical
inspection we're actually just talking
about the wonderful news in the Smith
case Oh Smith yeah a win at The Supremes
finally the Supreme say yes to it kind
of a but what you're gonna do and this
is the biggest federal level acceptance
of medical marijuana in Canada
do any other federal levels that have
actually acknowledged extracts well they
terms I don't think yeah here he doesn't
know about your air quite either hasn't
done this extracts or hasn't legalized
extracts but yeah it is definitely
pioneering work and I've got to give a
tip of the hat to Mister to saw just
occurrences of - so long as he came up
with the win and that's all he came up
with a win and not only that I
congratulate you first for going on the
TV there and having to talk with that
woman who's a great I thought Daniel
Larson did great yeah I thought Kirk
slayed it he was like that when he
everything he said about because you
know it was important to hear from a
perspective of that person on the TV
wearing a suit intellectual articulate
on point and just saying and how it is
it's like man yeah I start I'll help for
Canadians this is our guy just watching
that that define our whole movement and
what would be dealing with and fighting
against that woman and that kind of
mentality the policy and the city all
hearings we've had some really talented
presenters we had Kirk we had Hillary
black yet Dana Larson I did my thing
Neil Magnussen knocked it out of Italy
are eating a great yes in more questions
they ask and real counters up first on
Saturday first or second snake
so 10 a.m. city hall Vancouver British
Columbia talking candy come here real
Catholic species also very particulate
yes else a red well knowledgeable person
I'm probably the most knowledgeable
person in Vancouver on policy for men pi
yeah I mean really that's her whole
thing I mean she's been involved
obviously compassionate Club for a long
time quite quite quite the early days
that Riel came on it wasn't too late
into the
yeah it was definitely the first four or
five years showing up and coming onto
the scene and it was great to have her
just show up in another really smart
intelligent articulate person that can
sort of push this forward motion on -
yeah just legitimize this subject that
we've been screaming at the wall for
20,000 years
yeah she's other people you know I spend
a week or two putting together she's got
her master's degree and she's getting
her doctorate yeah hello impressive yeah
she's got me out she can't be convicted
she's earned her degree
to quote Billy Joel I got a run but
you're welcome they come down to the
stressed and depressed association
anytime it's open 10 a.m. to 10 p.m.
seven days a week check out our website
stressed in the press box eh we're
located one block west each night Street
on one one three five three east 41st
these highlights that call it on that's
what does it take this is say East
Meadow okay next one we had yeah we have
to put that together in a rush job or
the for the city hall meeting but yeah
the next one I will say West tonight
awesome okay thanks Steve much of area
she is older too
for Malmo Levine cannabis activist here
in Vancouver we're coming at us like I
can say I can remember way back in like
96 97 you know no one all of these guys
Dana and Marg and David and Chris
Bennett and yeah just it's been a long
time that we've been actively promoting
this agenda here in Vancouver so what
I'm seeing with a lot of different
characters changing the rules as well
absolutely dave was a frontliner he's
always he's never been afraid to get
arrested he's always really been just
like Horatio said like he definitely
deserves that sort of level commands a
level of respect over the years for what
he's done and for the way he's held his
you know putting himself right on the
front lines
absolutely and often to figure out other
ways to sell herb get herb to the people
you know like the minute I saw the names
stressed and depressed I just thought
that's something different
that's not just your average that's not
recreational that's that's we need yeah
mine whatever one weed was called stress
because that's what you used it for and
then there was weed that was stress I
had a great hit on that Sour Diesel I
discovered that's why I feel like when
you pair it with more THC back to back
it creates you more some of the
experience in typical so it's really
something you shouldn't need a lot of to
take strains further and further so get
it again and then like then hit the tee
CA and see if the rush is the
one-dimensional orchids more like this
our diva I'm gonna throw this sapphire
do it I got the sapphire on the there's
a little shelf here that this thing goes
on if I can get it on without burning
myself there we go
I guess they should know what a nice
cold sapphire hit might be unique as
well go for well not all over the town
do it up inside well that's what I'm
saying
right are you a little change
oh you're getting another one of those
stretches see how we're just on the
second floor here of the cannabis
culture date for Lounge Jeremiah and
Jodie Emery are in the other room
they're setting up for Judge Jeremiah
show on pot TV which is the TV news
correct we have a court or a clock for
2421 yeah you can check that out on TV
on their YouTube channel and we're just
going to finish up here and have a
little bit more conversation a little
bit more bowls maybe hit some of this so
now I'll combine it with and see if you
experience it as Sour Diesel or a squat
because you've got those Terps actively
in your
[Music]
collecting the do I do a small bit and
then I'll hold it in for the full
duration and let it my system because
there's nothing priestess very little
contaminant and you get away with almost
because it's so smooth
I turned that's why I turn the heat up
and I kind of take it all in and I just
hold it and it seems to where do you
feel do you feel it more like flatlining
like the Saudis put more like the Sour
Diesel but something different
hmmm I can't even express its different
throttle yeah stir all it's definitely
behind my eyes and a sort of a more of
an it's you know even though I didn't
take added Terps many feels like it was
kind of this it's just like almost
surgery time I find it like a dry hit
like it's eased a bit but that's kind of
weird
back-to-back hits are interesting
because you're all so back-to-back
hitting it but it seems to do more or
because it you know you're not adding
anything new so if it's just THC what
does it do to this Sour Diesel
experiences at the mersin in the sour
diesel is that only mean that um I like
it when I have something to pair it's
not fun on its own because it's like
driving as fast as you can straight I
definitely agree with that I wouldn't be
hitting it all day long like that I
would hit it either with a variety of
terpenes or even safer and better I
usually bring a spring that you know has
a terpene profile i bets I actually I
prefer to ramp up every strata that's
kind of boards like I have it on deck
and I both
what happened it's not it's not
something to smoke on its own
nonetheless I guess this is kind of
where I wondered from a pain standpoint
is this refried beans in comparison to
this and is that why it hits you harder
because if these two hits should be
technically the same the only thing is
this is double activated because it's
active and then we double activated
refried beans is different than beans
sure so it is refried beans little bit
give you gas or dope
I don't like I mean that from a good
thing by honest there's a reason for
refried beans really it actually
ferments it then people seem to go that
way but I look at these two like this
should be like that on the go in of this
but it seems to be like this is this
this is the narrow leaf drug cultivar
this is a broad leaf drug cultivar from
the same cannabinoid well this is
something strict and this is something
comes with a profile so I mean this is
his terpenes are in their cannabinoids
are in their well in the end its goal is
to have his least amount of terpenes
impossible sure so I mean that's kind of
what standardized if I get two ravines
in there then then we got Sour Diesel in
it
yeah that's that's what takes it out of
the nutraceutical yeah I guess the one
term things thanks to last week's hash
search that I really enjoy is the fact
that these are components in the canal
bando Pathak library of medicine's
Lester yeah it loves it good enough can
a but no path a lot of that because I
mean this is a prescription this is the
prescription that is a balanced
prescription of making a murder scene
and what makes it sour diesel yeah and
all of them but these based
prescriptions seem to be the ones that
are most needed because of the quickest
to standardize I can make this and this
and um you know I was once a patient of
this store and have its person then
there's going to be access for a few and
in our country only there's access in
America but um these are whole packages
this is up and down I don't know what
the goers fit to it it's dope it still
contains more of the variables because
we're not a professional growing of
course where if I factored these out
it's not full cornucopia of medicines
that makes our days of Sour Diesel but
if this is the antidepressant and this
is the pain management even though
they're one dimension why I'm very happy
because something this is something we
could literally start making articles
and trials and you try you try are you
all finding an antidepressant
well then THC has a definite therapeutic
value outside of the antidepressant
Turkey which is me me and how can we use
it because clearly sativex
those guys tried something they thought
they could just simulate this and it
would do the trick
well I think that they might have not
had a close enough connection to the
puffers mm-hm
well even in a finger reel it is an
important factor that and I was just
talking to marijuana man in the other
room and he mentioned it we can go talk
to him about this afterwards just that
there's this connection with you know in
the new rules and how they are now I'm
gonna allow extracts he said they kind
of made a point on saying that because
smoking is bad and his says shoot and
and so what marijuana man is saying well
but that's what got us here it was
literally all these years of smoking
that led us the learning and the
knowledge came via that process of
smoking he also told me a story of going
and getting his lungs tested than the
doctor asked me if he was a swimmer
because he couldn't believe the hell his
lungs were in even though he admitted
that he was a smoker
hmm so it's an interesting factor the
the you can smoke to cough up bad things
yeah whoo that's the whole process of an
expectorant and opening of those
particular areas of the lung
to bring in aqsa Skyrim yeah you're
actually carrying weight that you didn't
know because you were so each breath was
slowly accumulating crowd you don't even
know how you got here then you cockpit
on that corner guy if I've been living
this way from all these years I like
this baggage in my lungs so sometimes
yeah smoking is the expector if you need
next Molly even in when you're getting a
cold
to cop it up and get that bacteria out
rather than holding on to it so it
develops and amongst well very cool well
maybe we'll end up having a quick talk
with marijuana man I'll see if Joey and
Jeremiah want to come in and throw their
five two cents out in regards to the new
laws and yeah see you guys there
all right so Mauricio is up Johnny fees
in just like that in just a second just
[ __ ] the second and you can see my you
can see it
Johnny be watch some some of this fresh
frozen rosin that looks clear yellowish
and maybe we were just talking about
sometimes when you make the buck the
rosin with some fresh frozen which
there's a little bit of water in there
be careful because sometimes when you
drop the hash onto the nail it can hurt
a little bit so I got my shades on just
in case I don't mind
this is Mehdi you say this was a
creature for I don't know
shir it's a smear
it's a smear all right here we go
hitting it on the sapphire with a
silicon carbide dish this is a holy [ __ ]
so that was my - because I've made this
actually in several different ways
I mean it was just buzz and then I made
was fresh frozen and just after swishing
it like flavor it's just so much more
intense it's gonna curious maybe that
water is
well no it's because you put you're
using fresh material that hasn't been
dry but with you so it has warm preserve
it's just an everyday understand yeah
most the reserve yeah you haven't dried
up those turkeys you're capturing
terpenes that are I'll tell you though
that's just like crazy it's me Rick so I
made this this morning about on the go
congratulations on the only the Smith
case by the way hashish all around
Canada yeah well the first thing I do is
make couch yeah Matt me too finding some
rosin I did some sift I'm gonna do some
bubble later on today right up right I'm
going even in the ribs here GCHQ
employee people's Jeannie it in your
ribs ribs we're just filming but please
bow on it alright
Pelican case Pellicano Pelecanos the
coop so these guys are getting ready to
do Jeremiah's show at 4 o'clock and I'm
gonna heading back to West Vancouver
myself a little peace
[Applause]
the Sapphire there on the ledge which
ones that is quite a bit darker let's
say so fast so what I've done with that
passionate ever man hash is always going
to be darker and it says he washes odors
once so with this with this was only the
7390 one time
well it just kind of slowly simmers off
there's not one very slow grip yeah I
love it myself females the newest every
time I mentioned email I feel that I
should tell you my cup my code for
purchasing don't denial products off
their website which is de natal calm and
it's tame LT although I am urging people
to use the code hash Church which is
available only on Sundays one word and
all the donate all the the money raised
for that code will go to Zack Gillis
legal fund for his RICO charges that
he's facing down in the US there's that
go ahead Johnny be there that and I
still support you might make no it's
like you told me one day when he's
beating at one you'll never
you need to need that because that
doesn't go over here this does something
it's okay this one is really the one
thing that carves this exceptionally
though it fits perfect and it's got a
nice little hole right on top if you can
get a nice nice milk factor out of the
Taurus there so well right on thanks for
sharing that Rick with us I might take
one more little rip myself and then head
off but thank you guys for watching as
always always a pleasure but you you
guys should just go check out plot TV
now if you want to see what Johnny had
to say and whichever I say aye
I will be soon nice to see you journey
Jody puffed a few bowls with us earlier
but I didn't want to do it on camera I
feel bad she's always founded by the
media I feel like when I see her the
last thing I want to do is try and stick
the camera interface and record what she
has to say so next time maybe anyway you
want to take us out with big awesome
guys oh man
[Music]