[Applause]
bub in action ice
reaction
satisfaction sck 73 night
M welcome to
[Music]
thealist herbalist
horiz herbalist
it was Tuesday night
in in
rental from
uu
[Music]
D search find
horiz man herbalist The canab
Specialist
[Music]
herbaliz over you search
a pull it up and give it a sff
turn I say yes and I also got
hash full m edes all that dry make you
cool and relax and if you get some you
must come
back
her man herbal the can
special herbalist
[Music]
reaction give me
you know
I you know I
[Music]
[Applause]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my a open wide the sun was up in my face
the wisdom of the wise keep my head
straight
with try to Perfection
smoke I love the
street from the we get the full m Dy the
ring I love
the when the rest consume the
meditation to CB1 and
CB2 can n receptors in the brain and
body happiness for me
[Music]
the to Perfection
smity I love the
stre we get the
full I love
to m e e i c a l medical canab with the
sick patient m a d i c a
[Music]
l make it I without