hey guys bubble man here and I'm back at
the house of the great Gardener and man
what a beautiful time to be here he's
just chopped down well not just chopped
down about 3 weeks ago he cut down this
Barb Bud that we have destocked got a
big tub of it right
here uh this is the last one that we're
going to run through and we've been
basically dry sifting it with some new
screens that I'm selling these large 5ft
by 3T screens we're breaking the butt up
over them gently
and then under that is a secondary
screen that we capture the resin on top
of and then a small amount of the resin
is making its way below the secondary
screen and this is it here so this is a
new method I've been teaching on my
YouTube channel and I just wanted to
give you a little teaser that we're
filming a show here at the great
Gardener's house and uh it's going to be
well worth watching so I'll talk to you
guys soon I got more Bud to break up and
more dry to make keep watching Bubble
Man's World
Peace