[Music]
with a message for
[Applause]
[Music]
El
topic of
[Music]
Med all right so we got a nice little
pile of sift sitting on our top screen
here screen this is the
250 the 60 LPI so the resin will be
mildly contaminated um we could give it
another
flick and collect resin underneath
that's one way of producing a nice
variety of head and of course we already
have collected over on this end the
extremely nice gentle light sift of pure
heads so I got some nice photos on the
macro lens I'm going to show you those
very enjoyable you know what you want to
do with it you want to cart it well
unless you want to flick it a couple
more times it's up it's totally up to
you you have so much I would just card
it up it's a killer grade and if not it
can be
cleaned yeah there's like literally one
or two stigma hairs in there and that's
it it's nice to see the uh Purity as
always oh man look at it on the card
yeah it's coming up want to be careful
you don't almost need a brush for that
ooh I would have kept that separate yeah
keep that separate just cuz it'll always
cause problems for
cleaning still perfect for puffing just
cause more problems for
cleaning let me see if I got a card
[Music]
on
let good the
push it's the high grade sift
man and a little brush obviously if you
had one you could you could clean this
all up much nicer you definitely don't
want to let it um sit well plug your
screen eventually it can sit as long as
you just get a card and and clean that
cuz you can see how that resin is
already creating a bit of a
thing that's what we call
qual
Sweet another day at the
house another day at the office with the
great
Gardener this is the house
some pictures of
that yeah I'm going to I'm going to
bring it down and take a few or I can
take it right here there's my camera
so basically Matt has a ridiculous
amount of Bud all binned up and he's
going to be playing with these screens
for a while and you guys can check them
out on his Facebook account uh the house
of the great Gardener and his Instagram
account and I'm going to be posting the
photos that we end up taking but there's
tons more sifting to do I think we will
show you that we're going to take that
herb down and put it in his large
tumbler for the uh 10-minute run the 1H
hour run and then finally the 24-hour
run and uh yeah I think that's about it
we'll uh we'll show you a few more
things here and
uh we'll be done with our visit to the
great gardeners put this shot up later
too yeah that nugget yeah that's
that that's
nice the bud is
[Music]
furry furry
nugget all right so we just lifted that
screen that we just sifted over and
basically have uh another level of sift
so this came
through the
180 so we've got our 250 Micron and our
180 this one came through so we'll card
it up
gently there's ridges this is so what
would you call this
one I mean it's seconds
from I guess this would be the it would
be the third the seconds from the 90
done the third time second the second
flick it looks flick it was more of a
yeah it was we carded up the res it was
more I would think it'd be more
contaminated than that other second
version
if I were a bon man but it does look
pretty
damn pretty damn good color
wise a little pile of the
Barb guaranteed it'll melt yeah lighter
than the stuff that's on
top
awesome have that sparkly effect
any yeah it sure does lost in the
cosmos what do you know about dirty
scissors
how's do the great Gardener
knows all
right great
Garder and Bubble
Man ready it
work we're just caring up the resin that
didn't go
through the the
990 LPI 180 Micron
screen little pile
of hash nuggets hash
[Music]
nuggets smoke that
later
[Music]
the other
one one thing I would definitely suggest
you getting in the future is a nice big
brush yeah it'll blow the card idea way
and it'll it with these ridges and stuff
it won't be an issue you'll be able to
brush all the resin up so much faster
than carding and you'll also be able to
clean this screen with a with a nice big
brush yeah good big static free brush
and'll be resin falling underneath the
big
screen just another way every time
you're uh using these
screens you're basically um making hash
so uh whether you're using the 250
Micron the 180 Micron or my regular size
screens which is the 150 and the 70
which you know always come in handy when
you want to clean the resin this is more
of a if you're going to do an initial
screening use a a few nice screens
and do it right my car gets smaller and
smaller the screens get bigger and
bigger yeah that's it hey see me with a
big huge scooper soon a giant like 8 1
12 by 12
card
special business cards that are like for
for commercial
Growers the size of an
album totally you know nice album little
handle on it dude I'm telling you
probably like a painter's palette more
like Oh I like
that you're thinking the drywall thing
again yeah that's what I pictured you
know those drywall finisher guys' be an
interesting technique definitely all
right you need me over there look you
can see how much resin is on top of this
of the uh 60 oh yeah there's definit I
just want to lift it up to see what's
going on underneath that's what I
thought
another pile of resin it's like a big
heart so yeah you want
to
it can also see it falling like rain
yeah yeah totally being in a pollen room
yeah I know a certain person that
wouldn't like this that's crazy uh yeah
I guess we're going to go on top here so
what we want to do here now is be
extremely gentle don't touch the screen
don't rub this St you can touch the
frame no problem but don't rub the the
bud on the screen all we're going to do
is a
bounce or we're going to break up a
yeah this is nice
CL once again the quality of this
herb is definitely on
par on
par cuz they don't [ __ ] around that the
uh House of the great
Gardener
daboo Dao
Dabo what a fun event you want the Dabo
to come to
Toronto yeah that's I think that's a
little bit
better just keep the stocks in a
pile oh
nice big nuggets flying here at the
house of the great gu look at that that
is definitely Afghan
dominant look at that thing this is
beautiful so this has been a strain
you've had for quite a while uh well we
have the Shish Berry for oh man since
they're early mid 990s I would say
awesome uh it was just it's my favorite
smoke it's not a heavy smoke it's a
social uh you know you smoke it with
your friends when you're having good
times it's just um great yeah it is
social weed marijuana uh so we had it
for a long time and then I came across
the Afghan strain and the Afghan strain
was by far are the best
painkiller that we had come across in
for a long
time some of break I'm breaking the rule
here some of the kushes and stuff now
that are better but is the best so look
at that bud big fat
nugget so yeah so we crossed had a a
really good Afghani mail fantastic just
for structure purposes just it was
unbelievable so we used it in the base
some cross and a bunch of things and the
uh shis Berry was on that list I'm glad
and then in the is it the 2004 raid of
the RCMP on the vitc facility that we
built no uh was lost it was one of the
strains one of the other strains was the
princess and the princess was like the
number one strain was that a c99 or no
the princess was uh
uh bubblegum
Romulan what else was in it there was
something else in it there's three
genetics in
it uh the seeds were given to us by one
of the old shop
owners what was it
bubblegum
Romulan I can't think of the third one
right now but it was it was the other
one
lost damn always hate hearing that so my
favorite Shish Berry she she lived on in
in the in the uh Shish Berry aghan cross
so we started those seeds and you know
just looking looking for the hash it
sure brought it back to me I mean I also
know the Shish Berry from the
mid90s and um I hadn't seen it in so
long and then coming here and seeing the
Barb I was just like that's there's
there sh Berry in there
yeah yeah it's a save and not just like
a smell or something but it's like the
structure of the bud the way the bud
kind of looked even the growing of it
it's super easy to grow and nothing
there's nothing crazy about it there's
no extremes on it it's you know anybody
can grow it yeah just like some of those
buds out there that you know you going
to do the whole thing let's do it sure
okay of course we're going to do the
whole thing we should like almost shift
this just fun
work the smell is so good to
continue Yeah well yeah we haven't even
we haven't talked much about that have
we no no about I guess the last time we
were here as many of the watch people
watching right now will will will be
thinking yeah wasn't weren't they
supposed to Clos down well obviously our
injunction uh was accepted and went
through the crown is of course appealing
it I'm a
grandfather yeah exactly grandfathered
in I guess um I was somewhat confused by
it it was something between as long as
your license went to at least March
21st yeah you were yeah well there's a
whole there's a whole bunch of things
that are wrong with the decision in
itself and that it limits
people so I think it's you had to have a
production license as of or a production
license as of September is it September
31st
2013 okay and a personal
license that was
active sometime in March March 21st or
something so there's a bunch of people
that because they're because they
production license especi I think more
dgs right that were affected by that
ruling because what happened was there
wasn't enough time they knew the program
was ending and then there wasn't enough
time or they had trouble and didn't you
know got delayed that they said I forget
it and then and then I think the people
didn't uh renew their license so they
got stuck in that little void but as
long as you had a valid
license uh as of
uh I believe it's September 31st I may
be
okay uh 2013 your grandfathered in and
that means as long as you got it before
then or yeah as long as it was valid as
of as of okay so if your your license
expired on September 30th it would
extremely suck to be that person yeah
mine just expired on March 31st so Mine
mine's actually written to expire
May 23rd or something because I got it I
got it the week
before Canada sent out uh the letter the
news about the ending of the program so
that's not the letter that exposed us
all to the mail people that was a
separate letter different letter they do
all sorts of offensive letters when
they're dealing with us which I'm not
sure I mean we are really the easiest
kind of people to deal with just let us
do what we want to do and we're we're
good to go we're not causing problems
we're not uh
totally
totally so it's a strange situation but
I'm very glad to say that that
injunction is happening for now and
injunction is happening for now the
crappy part is is that the government
came back and they're appealing the
injunction so everyone sort of sat back
and they're like oh awesome you know
trial Trials take forever no it take
years mine took six years right so
injunctions are awesome appeals not so
awesome so the government appealed it
and they could hear that
case within a month couple weeks y right
so here we go again so here we go again
the government's coming forward and
saying oh the oh the judge went too far
and it's like well I sit that I sit back
and I'm like what are you talking about
the judge went too far the judge didn't
do go far enough exactly right they put
150 g limit out there there's
individuals that have licenses that are
more than 150 g so what is that guy that
guy can't leave his house for the
weekend hey let's go skiing and Whistler
for the weekend I can't because that guy
would have to carry more he would have
to carry say two days 300 g yep he gets
caught by the police trou he's he's a
criminal yep that guy would be arrested
and charged under the criminal code of
Canada for and our criminal code now is
pretty bad for having two days supply of
cannabis there are I know they've
already got a list of over 200 people
that have moved because you can't move
your license anymore you're
grandfathered in but your license stays
to whatever whatever location it was
attached to oh did you move you know I
guess go make a deal with the people
that moved into your house
get home CU you can't move it all right
let's gently lift this before we get too
violent all right both of us it's our
nature to grab this butt and move it
around which there's you know what
there's nothing saying that you can't do
it afterwards when it's been moved over
there so I guess uh we'll put this over
the pile in the far
end
these are
good
MH um so yeah once again a good amount
of sift way better um distributed Now
you kind of see here where you see these
little black bits and stuff how they get
caught totally see them just come down
on a 45 see them all they're all there
right it's more than you can imagine do
you see them sticking straight up go
right down to the r isn't that nuts
that's the trick dude that's why now
here is what we don't want to bang this
screen this screen we want to lift very
gently and put over there and then we
know what we have underneath is going to
be of the utmost
quality
so this
here
[Music]
this is the top of the screen I'm not
sure if you guys can see if I get down
at the angle the way we were
looking but you can kind
of let's see if we can get some fancy
camera work happening
here cuz if we
can be good to show
you what's going on
here
yeah there we go you see that all those
little bits and pieces all those little
contaminants are lodged into the
screen and then underneath the big
screen we've got what I would say is
going to be probably 99 plus%
heads so it hurts me to card these up
but next time I come you're going to
have your brush and you're going to be
all about brushing at least for for this
grade carding everything else is not a
big problem my card is so gummed here I
have a clean one right
here
wow that's
nice that's the right quality right
there
there I'd say we're looking on boat peer
heads and not just a hit of it either
you know that's the cool thing about
coming to the great Gardener's place and
sifting it up with
Matt you know his genetics
just
rain sift they just produce
resin the hom The Afghani the J or is it
JT jt5 T15 and isn't there another one
jean G or something Jean Gan G skunk
Rene sweet skunk and Renee and now all
of his con of tonic I have to say what
I'm most excited about the high CBD is
to come is to come check out in the near
future of hash making is to come check
out the high CBD hybrids cuz I hear a
lot about CBD and high CBD markers and
how it's the best uh medicinal for a lot
of different people and I haven't really
experienced it for myself but I'd like
to uh start experimenting and and
hitting the high CBD uh strains that
you've developed yeah we got uh CBD hom
CBD Afghani
CBD uh sweet skunks CBD dig weed CBD
warlock CBD
Renee uh they'll be hitting the hitting
the club soon they'll be hitting you
know we got inquiries all the time for
the high CBD the CBD seeds
uh are going to be coming right behind
them uh we're just in the final
phenotype selecting as we were showing
Bubble Man uh a little earlier like the
one CBD Renee has flavor so the whole
project for us is about getting
flavorful CBD
strains and especially the
digweed uh and the
Renee are totally topnotch that category
have you guys produced uh CBD
Barb
no uh do I have it we will it'll be
it'll be on the list to to produce a CBD
Barb but it wasn't uh it wasn't in the
room of the of the initial cross at the
time yeah well that's uh we'll get on
that though for
sure I think you might have just given
me a project from the breeding room that
just became available
ailable
awesome bar
and what I'm doing right now is I'm I
fed the CBD Warlock and I'm crossing it
in with the Jean G nice joh G is a huge
heavy hitter yeah that's a potent strain
hey yeah oh yeah I don't smoke it it's
like it's like literally one of those
strains where I personally do not smoke
it it will it re my
day you just can't get anything done
well John Bell would probably love that
as a pain management oh yeah oh I I I
have no doubt that it works it works
right we got it from uh the Montreal
Club oh yeah as their number one
painkiller right so when we were
switching we not switching but uh
sharing strin in amongst the clubs that
was the one that uh when they sent they
sent us a whole bunch at the time
yep but that was the one when we put it
to the members here you know it's right
away you know you know when people are
coming back sort of the same day saying
yes I'll take some more of that you know
you're on something so awesome well
we're going to lift up this sift this is
our first grade um we'll probably give
this a quick flick which will give us
another second grade and I'll show you
that and uh otherwise we're going to
keep working here and get through these
tubs get this ready for the big machine
so see you guys back in a
bit
first do your thing
man it's funny to watch Matt do this
because uh I know in 20 years from now
he'll still be doing
this and this is the day he learned
it done all right really do see
it how's that b-grade looking
[Music]
blond as ever pretty good for
b-grade wispy it is right like you got
to be do it too fast and you like almost
create like a wave yeah you exactly
that's kind of the good way to do it too
you do it too slow and you melt the
resin put a brush future references a
brush a brush a
brush yeah I want to photograph this
PW
happening oh and she
goes so that's right on the top of the
screen so that's still fairly
contaminated but probably cleaner than
than 90% of most people
sift Barb doing it right since since
when what early '90s early '90s
just checking out we'll leave that we'll
leave that one on there yeah exactly cuz
now you got your
two terrible yeah but no not terrible
cuz once again each time you've done it
today it's been completely
saved so that's the other one though
right it's on the other side yeah to
push it over a bit there you go he's on
it
he knows what he's doing oh yeah how's
it looking yeah a little bit higher a
little
few uh a few more hairs yeah tiny little
bit more contaminant yeah that's all you
don't want to just
keep
one right here is
next too many gardening it
up so this was an empty room when I got
here today and the house has basically
half filled it the clones have a little
bit of droop right now but they looked
amaz amazing when they first went in
much like this guy right here and so uh
I have no doubt that these will become
beautiful big ass plants in the near
future oh yeah a little dppy though yeah
I just mentioned that but I mentioned
how good they looked when they first
went in look at this one
already some of these are standing up
[Applause]
now
that we didn't get as much seed as we
wanted to so we have to do it again
oh
perfect that'll
be time that for
November M Amsterdam Amsterdam the great
Gardener so we just keep collecting our
first and second grades and then we end
up being left with I
guess a secondary secondary grade which
is on top of the 250 screen
here you see the way we're carting right
now it it we're doing it purposely like
this because the resin moves nicer when
you almost blow it across the screen if
we start carting like this you'll see
instantly that the it's sticks to the
screen and it it becomes a little more
problematic Barb thirds so this is our
[Music]
thirds clicked it right on
them
boom so it's good when you're doing this
process that you clean your screens each
time I mentioned it before I'll mention
it again a brush is even better it'll
clean out all the holes and then of
course we have there'll be another level
underneath guaranteed what we just did
was we created another level of Si
underneath that one's that one that was
seconds well we called this seconds
before exactly because when we collect
it wasn't
first still have a little bit of
contamin yeah usually the only thing
that usually will hit down here is going
to be the first grade but that's only
off the first initial bounce on the two
screens when you move them both and
collect we've already collected that
moved the bud a secondary time on that
screen to get it to collect and then
collected the screen off this screen and
that's what we're collecting now so this
is a seconds for sure these sifts are
still much cleaner than what what most
people's siths would be considered I
mean we're calling it first and second
but really what they are is like this is
90 plus% heads and that other stuff that
we that we made was literally like
almost 100% I never like to say 100% I'd
call it
99.9 which is what I used to call uh
Sam's uh cleanest dry sift which carding
techniques will do uh this trick will do
Sam can do it with his technique there
there are ways to get resin to this
level of cleanliness if you really want
to just do it and not be worried about
um the cost go get yourself a rowap
machine Couple Grand for those you might
be able to get one for under a grand at
an auction what what's a rotap machine a
rotap machine it's one of those round
pharmaceutical grade separation vibrator
machines the stacks of screens that I
have I have one of those yeah they fit
into the rowap they they usually if it's
a good unit and you can dial it in
pretty yeah you can get small on at the
other place yeah you can usually get a
pretty good grade as well so there's all
these different ways um you know for
what what Matt's doing here big screens
like this make sense because he's
already using screens over this he's
already collecting the resin he's
already seeding out bud and growing bud
that needs to be destocked or trimmed
and so this is uh this is something he's
already doing now he just has a trick to
remove some of the nicest heads first
before he collects the rest of it uh
that hopefully I'll get to clean up
[Music]
later all right so we're back our last
tub of the
shishka pretty
ridicula the shishka ridicula the
barbola serious Barb in the house man
yeah the color
and really just everything about it I
kind of can't say enough about it I like
[Music]
it like this is reminiscent of I guess I
guess because this is what I had in the
9s yeah me too this was like when do you
get to see stuff you had in the '90s
I sort of went into a bubble right I
didn't for me it was just I was
developing my own flavors once in a
while you find something that's like wow
man I got add that to the
camp like I missed the whole sort of
cush era I don't know sweet stoked
stoked that you did like is great I
understand how potent it is but
everything but I don't know I'm not a
Kush fan well I've always been a bit
harsh on the Kush Vibes in the sense
that kush is a great productive um
commercial strain in the sense that
people that might not be able to grow
other things could come out successful
with growing the Kush I was always into
sativas that's why I damn near broke
into tears when you handed me the sweet
skunk earlier it was just uh I had it
years
ago that lost it and of course
everyone's always like oh you can have
anything you want right up until you ask
for
it not the great gardener
super stoked on bar share share why not
share that's it man especially if it's
good man people are there that could use
it it brings a whole new meaning to
Sunny and
share you ever uh interested in doing
some
Greenhouse oh sure I'm interested all
the time
interested in going to Denmark and
seeing some of those outdoor fields and
going to you know going to places in the
Middle East you're allowed to go to I
guess turkey and things seeing the hash
production that would be fantastic yeah
that would be pretty Dar fantastic it's
a big world out there and it seems like
with cannabis that
uh seems to be opening up I even had
friends of mine that are seed sellers
out of uh Amsterdam
tell me in just this last year that
they've been getting lots of people from
the Middle East coming and buying
seeds and they're you know they're kind
of like don't don't they like put you to
death there for that stuff and you know
I guess to a point they do but I guess
even there it's getting cooler yeah
because for people to even consider such
a
thing well why don't you start why don't
you start healing people not necessarily
even healing people why don't you bring
comfort of life
yeah for sure back to people right it's
hard to deny it's hard to deny the
grandma that you know is in pain and
someone gave her a tinure and she's not
obain anymore yeah it's a huge eye
opener I mean the big story for me was
always Lester grinspoon talking about
his son and how uh you know after he uh
he basically this was years ago decades
ago when he was using it medically and
I'm pretty sure he was quite young like
11 or 12 years old his son Lester's son
yeah don't quote me I think his son his
son's name would have been
Danny um he was sick getting
chemotherapy and every day after
chemotherapy every time they would go
back home and uh you know he would wret
for hours because it was harsh poisons
poisoning his body and
so when he finally broke down and
allowed you know to consider to use
cannabis as a medicine there weren't all
these fancy vapor izers or all these
things so he had smoked a joint I
believe just out in front of the
hospital and after chemotherapy that day
instead of going home and wretching for8
hours he was he asked his parents
excitingly in the car ride home you know
could could we stop for a submarine
sandwich which is like that's a pretty
huge quality of life change particularly
for a child cuz we never want I mean we
never want to see people suffer
generally but something about a child
suffering that is even more devastating
you know you just don't want children to
suffer
sure so I I was always found that to be
a very powerful story that Lester told
in a it must have been an interview
because I've heard it in his words him
telling the
story there's some pretty powerful
stories out there I remember a guy named
Ronald Ranger from at the Vicks and
Ronald Ranger he was just a regular guy
but he had glaucoma and he had glaucoma
he had a bunch of other things
uh wasn't you know wasn't the healthiest
guy but his glaucoma
would take a sight away and back in the
day he knew cannabis when he smoked it
he could see like he like he could
wouldn't be able to see you or I but he
could do shapes and he could maneuver
around and if he didn't have cannabis
and the pressure on his eye would build
up to the point where he couldn't see
and and in the scope of this guy's
life he in the in to find Cannabis you
had to go out on the street sometimes
blind looking for cannabis jeez and he
was dragged into an alley on numerous
times raped and
sodomized Jes because this guy wanted to
find weed so he could
see we came across that story like to
this day I can't tell the story without
you know feeling the emotion this dude
just wants to see do doesn't want to
smoke weed to get high or anything this
guy just wants to see yeah let and we we
came across that story and and we
supplied that guy weed for free for the
rest of his life until until Ronald
Ranger passed away he smoke weed for
free Wicked because he just wanted to
see that's worth
it I mean when it's your eyesight too
right it's easy for prohibition or
conservative government types who are
have great eyesight and whose family is
all healthy to not even consider things
like this yeah like what are you going
to what would you say to that
guy that's it you know you can't have it
or you can't grow your
own you know don't have the money to buy
the large production
licenses weed what's your option
took it
away we still have it we still have it
we can still
grow such a nice bite still gr
purpley almost blue there is a blue s
there's like a blue tinge to it that
especially on some of them that's as
your eyes yeah it's really nice nice
fall colors on that Canabis you get
those colors you want those colors like
that you got to learn to flush your weed
yeah this is definitely if you don't
flush your weed you won't see the crazy
colors get the plants to go yellow first
and then once they all go yellow that's
when your your Reds and your purples and
your oranges and all these amazing
colors that lie within these plants come
out and are you getting that in a two
three four week
flush four yeah five I have a room right
now that's on its eighth week of wa just
water awesome there's a John G room I
fed it for two it flowered fed it for 2
weeks and then now in then the last
eight weeks of its life we just gave it
we just gave it to water yeah I'm giving
my crop just water now it's in its last
4 and a half
weeks all right finishing up the last
few
be a nice
one well they all are we'll try not to
move the bud too
much coming out of the
bin back all right so we've lifted up
our our 180 Micron screen we put the
butt over there um you can see there's
resin on top of this screen we put it
over here this is our number one grade
this is our first grade this is the
light light light sifting that we got
from doing breaking up all that bud over
those two screams of course there's more
to get but this quality will
be near pure heads those ripples are
thrilling me
out keep hitting them and it's like a
car accident it's a dry sift accident oh
this is nice
quality so it's a great way for any one
who's already sifting or
growing to collect a really incredible
quality of sift I mean that is really a
nice
quality without too much uh really
without doing much different at all just
specific screen
sizes press that in your hand that fast
yeah
beautiful see drop it on there love to
see the
contrast oh yeah snaked right
up looks
good so that's basically the first thing
you want to do if you're dry sifting and
you want to collect the best heads
possible from there you can bash the
herb more and collect it under the
screens and then basically do what we're
about to do which is take that bin or
that tub full of the Barb that we've
destocked and done this light dry
sifting with and then I guess we'll be
taking it down to Matt's industrial size
machine and giving it a 10 minute a 1
hour and a 24hour I'm not going to be
here for all of those but I'll
definitely be here when it goes in for
the 10 minute and show you what we get
out of that as well so cool
awesome you can clearly see that
contaminant
yeah be cool to get that
[Music]
picture nice e second
season Mr Officer man what you want from
me
[Music]
come over
here don't no
[Music]
Fe I Wasing down
the and I up in Old BL and be ask on my
answer I say it's the good old green
and I know
[Music]
you see my like a
t got it
[Music]
TR a to the wise in Afghanistan Indian
and Pakistan not to mention Afric the
best
Riv
every because
same and I don't know going work with
the rest like
[Music]
I've been steaming
from my eyes got
real and I don't got
no can I do for
[Music]
myself
off don't you have no Fe off e out don't
you Jud by my
[Applause]
[Music]
head was walking down the street and I B
up in the old DC said that the smell of
the good old
trees man what can you do for
[Music]
here I
off
don't
off walk morning everything
[Music]
and one up the road with me and the old
blue all in get
d right how's it going everyone what was
that that is the Warlock canonic uh High
CBD
warlock wow okay sorry welcome back I
got hit in the face by this one actually
it was this one I smelled it and it was
awesome but then this one brushed up
against my shoulder and I could smell it
from over here this one right here any
fans of the Warlock out there we've
acquired a high CBD version of warlock
I'm a warlock fan up there high see high
CBD version of the aani over there high
CBD Renee uh no that's the rc7 it's the
only one it's the only phenotype out of
I don't know I must have started 500
seeds it's the only phenotype with that
we kept that doesn't have a high CBD
content but it's like it's it's a beast
it's such a beast that you know it we
were like we're keeping it excellent you
we have we have we you know cuz you can
only keep so many plants and stuff but
you don't get rid of one that's that
special that's one of those times you
want want run into a strain like that
you keep it and then there's another
that's the afgh that's Afghan but what
that one has the that was if everybody
remember is that was the one that had
the Afghani Ved structure remember we
like this is the one this is Afghan well
when it flowered It produced the catonic
bud it sure has the canonic and then the
other plant that had the the canonic
venge growth actually created like the
agh aghy bud so was like genetics the
Bea this is the beautiful thing about
genetics so all right so that's these
are our three tubs of Barb maybe should
yeah look at that this way I like how
that uh so just be sort of careful on
the side I don't pretty much stand up
against it sure I'll just mostly use my
hands and arm to block jeez I'm not a
big enough person to block
this this is a great
smell so this for us has two purposes
one obviously we get hash from it uh but
the other one is the tumbling action uh
breaks the buds apart and releases all
the seeds not all of them but a good
chunk a good chunk as anybody knows
that's clean SE seeds before
it's long and slow process sometimes ESP
you got one of those fancy
machines yeah there's some pretty fancy
ones for sure
so raining
glands oops
s getting dirty at the house of the
great Garden all right so that's a good
solid uh I don't know what but many
pounds of of weed just went in
there I'd I'd say two two lbs I don't
know probably only
two we'll call it two plus two plus yeah
you're right
there in
there you know what time it
is
442 442 jeez it's only been 22 minutes
since we hit our 420 rep
we'll plug this in so at uh
452 see what we
[Music]
get beautiful all right well 10 minutes
we'll be back in 10
minutes all right you know what I always
used to do is I always used to sort of
knock that off but now that we've sort
of done that double screen technique I'm
sort of thinking cuz if you look at this
it's the same right
like it's like hair and you can see them
poking
out now I used to rub it now I don't
want now I don't want to rub it I want
to like well maybe separ you know
collect it separately get it yeah get
everything out that's underneath it
first yeah pull the tub out all right
never a bad idea to be learning new
things and just if you don't really have
to change much and just be a little more
careful
perfect and that is a healthy pile of
red
present I brought a whole stack in but I
think I gave half
you not quite thick enough
yet 10
minutes morning everything and we just
yard put on rice
and up thead with me and the old
blue
get 10 minutes not bad no not bad at
all the container that
big think I
dos it take like four
medium
yeah this is one of those hyoma
Afghani oh Afghan katonic oh Afghani
katonic right right right right so it
had the Afghan structure but it grew out
to a h or a canonic style shape
but all of them look
great
I'm going to need another
one filled it
up a
10min I remember from the stuff that
I've cleaned in the past of yours 10
minutes was a a joy to
clean coming to torono bring this to
Toronto with
us I suspect if you were there that some
of it will be
there with like a hundred different
people have you tried this have you
tried this Barb from the great I'll be
like uh yeah where did you get it dude I
just met the guy in like an
elevator he just gave me this oh man
that's those are those are some of the
funniest stories of course meet the two
kids in Whistler and puff them out see
them later and thank you man
anything 10
minutes so listen it's been a great trip
to Vancouver Island but I got to head
back home we're going to go see Matt
he's just working in one of the far
rooms that they've been building up and
uh since we got here when I got here
earlier they were literally cleaning uh
the base of where the bases for his
tables for the draining of the water and
they were cleaning those the room was
completely cleaned and now they've
actually got plants you know some sever
several hundred plants transplanted uh
and planted into this room so let's go
check it out all right so I'm all packed
up it's been an amazing trip some great
hash was made I'm excited to see those
seeds in the future super stoked to be
leaving with sweet skunk um let's go say
goodbye to Matt he's just working in his
garden yeah buddy what going everybody
just finishing the uh transplants in
this room finishing up the transplants
for the day
[Music]
beautiful now that we can keep our
Gardens yeah that's what I'm talking
about plant another grow double high
five on that and this is a CBD room this
is a CBD room there's CBD Dy there and
CBD H over here beautiful little droopy
today couple RC's yeah a couple other
little
treats well they've picked up a mously
just from uh an hour ago yeah
yeah that whole table was drooped over
right drooped hard yeah it's com around
good'll be it'll be up in an
hour well as always it's been an
absolute pleasure man really thanks for
having me out once again awesome we're
uh the thanks to the screens man those
are fantastic that yeah well I know
we're going to see good things from you
in the future from those bad
boys awesome take care everybody till
the next time but on to the great
Gardener great
[Music]
G rebel music now give them some rebel
music now well it's a rebel music don't
you confuse it with that crap that the B
producing thisel music don't you confuse
it me at The Lyricist watch me prove it
used to we a lot start a lot
the syst US locked up in the prison
defeat Us in the street touch never
teach us nothing we afrian features now
we and div officers preachers doctors
and all
allance from from Jesus used to rock a
re no creep up
B but grab the microphone and tell the
pretty black for Bleach up no F
knowledge when them at the college when
leave out the
I I have a dream and it's not
beam is my name the
game