[Music]
hey guys bubble man here on a beautiful
British Columbia morning here I'm very
excited to tell you that I'm on my way
to see the great Gardener the last time
I was there I wasn't even sure if the
Great facility was going to be
continuing to function after March 31st
due to the
unknown um you know the injunction not
knowing whether or not it was going to
go through anyway I'm real excited I've
got my big screens loaded up for Matt he
has no idea we got the 250 and the 180
we're going to deed his um Barb today
and then we're going to sift it and
clean it um I brought all the different
size screens here I've also which I'm
quite excited about
yesterday um John and myself cut some
watermelon clones you remember these
little guys that we cut into the
Clones today we're bringing the great
Gardener one we know he does great work
we know he does great things so he
should have the TGA genetics the
watermelon and anything else that uh I
that comes across my plate I'm glad to
share with Matt cuz I know he's not
going to hoard it I know he's going to
share it and even more importantly I
know he's going to work with it and
potentially add High CBD markers and and
other cool sort of genetic things so
totally happy to support the great
Gardener and bring him a little
watermelon clone so we're pretty excited
here today we're going to get going here
jump in the truck and head down to the
ferry terminal and when we're down at
the fery terminal we'll have a little
wake and bake session I am running a
little bit behind today so not able to
hit the Bowl before we leave see you
there
[Music]
oh
call
G call me the
gon
come big stinking flow through the with
them call them call it we them never did
when we in water when weing fertilizer
yet out of this Sky Spitting Fire and
I'm ath man with a hot temper dig up
stinking rocket launcher
and
theop ganja
planter call me the Ganja Farmer keep
the
[Music]
meditation I so them could give it to
them sick patient make get
medication and so them could have BR new
medication Mi singers get some
inspiration and so them spread
message a
g call me the
G gja
planter call me the gja farmer on the
g g g g g want to call it call S if you
don't want to call it call it marijana
if you don't want to call it call it the
[Music]
IND hey guys just got to the ferry
terminal here and uh we got about 25
minutes to kill the cars are just
unloading but I think that's actually a
bow and Island fairy they're unloading
from so I think we're going to have a
little session here straighten this
camera a tiny little bit CU I'm
obsessive
compulsive there we go all right so I've
have brought
the product case with the Hitman rig
inside the little little baby case
really been loving this piece just to
keep the plastic bag and the kleenex in
there so it absorbs any little bit of
bong water that I've uh left over not
sure if I even brought any
extra water in here so we're going for
some dry hits
today dry hits are better than no hits I
always
say I always say so we got our
nail got to have
that we got our little creme brle torch
and then of course we have all sorts of
different
bubbles so we are going to see Matt from
the great Gardener today so I suspect we
start the day right with a rip of
some great Gardener dry sift look at
that I mean the guy knows what he's
doing when it comes to Growing the
Dank and even making
uh Wicked [ __ ] concentrates you know
he is definitely an inspiration I know
to many of of you and that's why I find
it so fun to go there and uh you know
bump into him and his and his whole crew
him and Sarah uh they're just all really
good Folks up there and they're doing
good work and I get super excited when I
get the opportunity to go up there so
once again that's what we're doing today
so might as well start this off right oh
this is so dry it's just perfect you
can't even believe how dry it is like
powder powder powder
dry all right so get that little guy
down got the baby cakes right
here guess we could give you a little
bit of a visual on
that little bit of a visual on the old
baby
cakes there we
go
so yeah it's good heading over there
today going to drop some clones off with
Matt and hopefully get a clone or two
looking forward to getting uh hopefully
the sweet skunk uh I'd also love to get
the Hom OR The
Afghani they're all just such beautiful
wonderful strains that uh I wouldn't say
no to any of
them probably getting myself another
tent here in the real near future after
hanging out with John yesterday at at my
green planet um just loved seeing all
the material all the tents all the
lights all set up
really nice all right here we
go got to love Afghani rips through the
baby cakes I got about 15 20 minutes
left I'm going to sit here and rip
bowls I suspect for a while probably the
whole time until um I realized the guy
in front of me is starting his car and
driving onto the
ferry that's usually my um my cue to
realize that hey Bal man if you're
getting on this fair you might want to
get on
now super stoked to go dry sift today
Matt always has the most incredible I
was talking to John about this today and
you know obviously it has a lot to do
with the resin that you grow when you
start sifting the majority of your resin
you really see what you're growing you
really get to see the resin uncovered uh
isolated and taken from the plant and
that really um with some strains
particularly when you're breeding
strains I think it's important to know
uh what ones are resin Productions
plants
oh my God it's tasty tasty treats on the
fo outelt dryp so we'll see you soon on
the
ferry ganja
planter call me the Ganja Farmer deep
down in the a
Bon well it's like 10,000 bon in one
blue
[Music]
g g
g
n n n n n n n n n n n
[Music]
dabbing in the morning dabbing in the
evening dabbing late at night
time take a dab right now and am feeling
so inclined W dabbing in the morning D
in the evening dabbing late at night
time come I take a dab right now and I
am feeling so
inclined take a trip to the hit mention
doggies got a piece for you hit man
glass wee got some for you shatters like
glass if you had enough you could I
always say that you pass can culture is
growing and it's growing real fast down
in Colorado even Cali most of the people
medically inclined defended by the
lawyer scripted by the doctor seems like
the people Spirit incline and if you
never on your mind Mr tell you one time
we'll be dabbing in the morning dabing
in the evening dabbing late at night
time say take d right now when I am
feeling so
inclined ding in the morning dabing in
the evening DB late at night
time see take a dab right now when I am
feeling so inclined tell them don't get
caught by scientifical medic ation the
side effects that is destroying this
nation decreasing population increasing
frustration it's okay to think about
your health now do it by relation or
broadcast to the nation the people need
to know a new time has come a time to
rejuvenate get it from the concentrate
some even seek to legalize it right now
so let me see by the show of your hand
this 42 years da da will be D in the
morning morning dabing in the evening
dabing late at night
time say take a dab right now when I am
feeling so
inclined dabbing in the morning dabbing
in the evening dabbing late at night
time cuz
Mr right now I am feeling so
inclined guys bubble man here I am on
the BC ferry heading over to beautiful
uh Vancouver Island you can see as I
step out of the frame and the camera
readjusts it's really beautiful out
there beautiful Skyline we've got the
Zodiac boat twin Mercury here on the
queen of cin just in case we need them
and uh yeah Vancouver Island in the
background sorry Vancouver the city of
Vancouver in the
background really sweet so yeah I
figured what better time than to do some
hit and rips with k with my Hitman baby
cakes got
my
torch my Dabber and my piece so should
be able to get this done as Vancouver
disappears in the
background the
city sure love to take this Mercury down
for a little whip this little zodiac f
with the doal mercur on it and without
really got to give it up to Hitman and
the glass that he's been releasing
lately I've only smoked a few of the
pieces but um from the ones that I have
I've been more than impressed so Props
douge really really digging what you're
do and stepping it up and uh it's just
nice to
see they're making some uh announcements
here on the
ferry all right well I said let's get to
D here we don't have time for
announcements all day long so we're
going to hit that beautiful Afghani from
the from the house of the great
Gardener just about lost it there
toight never lose house never lose
as all right so just a little smid on
there we'll
do then a
little torch action
staring out at the ocean while torching
my bowl my Hitman
Bowl can't wait till they make a
portable denail but until they
do I sure love a little Hit
Man baby
cakes baby cake rips
thanks for watching
hey guys bubble man back here at the
back of the ferry not sure if you
remember last time but uh we tried to do
this last time and I failed miserably so
I figured the only thing to do was to
come back and make another
attempt so with the dab loaded great
Gardener
Afghan we've uh got the piece in hand
and we got the Creme Brule torch in
hand so let's see if we can make this
work ooh the wind's brisk it's going to
be a
challenge we can get
this this could work guys
all right Dab's on the back of the ferry
it
worked I'm happy to say that I managed
to get a hit on the back of the ferry
it's been a while when you don't smoke
joints anymore you know you got to come
to the back and do what you need to do
but with a torch and a glass piece it's
not that easy but today it was so I
guess uh I'm going to continue to sit
here and rip bowls now that I've managed
to get this working and uh we'll see you
guys over on Vancouver
[Music]
Island
w
[Music]
w I've got some OG this morning and I'm
feeling real good the light you know me
load it on food a real ganja smoker and
I really love to burn the ganja
Community my first concern check me good
friend a
good sming
because smoke
weed
car me up
bless and I make re
[Music]
call take smoke take
daily want to arrest me them G not is
necessary
G when we're smoking smoking
s it should cause no B gja to the
world yes when we're smoking smoking
s shouldn't cause no B healing to the
world
[Music]
get a we call that
filter real
[Music]
smoke
maximum like the words come off so
try it open at the morning time light it
open at the evening time light it when
night time
[Music]
come we defend the maximum light it up
Anya it listen the M we're
smoking smoking
s and it shouldn't cause
no can do the
world yes we're smoking
smoking s minia it shouldn't cause no
B gja to the
world come G with the people give me the
make me light
[Music]
up yeah
child I love you I love you I love
you give thanks for the morning
rising SP Breath of Life
man it's all about your dab to relax and
free I want to take a DB with you
because I'm feeling good hey
it's all about your da to relax and free
mo see I want to Da to because I'm
feeling good
yeah guys up this morning feeling in the
mo to dve away
today dve away
today I saw my good friend he said to
me one will keep the the r
away it's all about your da you relax
and free you
move I want to take a dab with you
because I'm feeling
good it's all about your da relax and
free your
mood see I want to Da with you because
I'm feeling
good make way for the concentrate
and the glass makers of
today by a torch to the glass blades
your Tres away load it up load it up let
us burn one down and pass it
around it's all about your dab with you
relax and free
move I want to take a dab with you
because I'm feeling
good it's all about your D relax and
free fre your
mov see I want to dab with you because
I'm feeling good yeah so if you ever
take a before take it easy if you know
say one time
begin from the DJ
[Music]
seek is in the house everybody Welcome
backa oh man what a good time
congratulations again on the uh thank
you thank you
da Dabo bar for the win nonsolvent so uh
got a couple of gifts for you here today
sweet yes gifts gifts gifts as we arrive
most
importantly ah Astro Boy from TGA
genetics the watermelon yeah you know
what what is that the best gift ever to
give someone like uh bo the gift of
genetics well maybe the second gift ever
what we've got industrial screens yeah
look at these screens
let that
go so I figured with that beautiful Barb
we should get these bad boys these are
different than my other screens this is
a 250 Micron and a 180 so it's a bigger
size we're going to use the dry sift
Wizards trick we're going to put all the
herb gently and do a super light bounce
get like 99% pure heads and then you can
literally use the the bottom one the 180
for um uh for regular for regular
sifting oh oh yeah yeah yeah you C over
your 70 still so you've got a 90 which
is um 180 Micron and you've got a 60
Mash lines per inch which is 250 Micron
the smaller the number for lines per
inch or mesh the bigger the Micron
number the bigger the hole so yeah let's
bring these bad boys inside and uh you
need a hand go get those barbs um you
need this probably not no we don't need
it you've got the table so you know what
I'll I'll let you take one of these cuz
they really are heavy and I'll take
one we'll head on up
awesome all right
so what we got
here today we will be sifting Barbara
Bud oh yeah this Barber bud is this
Barber Bud was let go for a long time
just water you can see the color you can
see the purple you can see the yellow
you can see the crystals dude this is
and it's super dry beautiful
herb these two almost look like
completely separate
fenos it does look like a different Bud
hey if it wasn't for if it wasn't for
sort of down in here yeah as you get
lower you can tell it's exactly the same
TI it must have been close to the light
holy
Moes D I can only imagine how much dry
sift is inside
these bins so and this is a non seated
this is seated oh it is seated I can't
even see the seated feminized seed
beautiful yeah they're in there yeah you
got to crush them up to get them out do
you find it's because when all those
hair like all these leaves dry and
everything right like just prot it
totally protects the bud and when you
start you start taking off these little
leaves I do it over the bins and get
into just CED it is incredible you can
get really close on that too it's a
quite a quality little uh little
camera for showing the quality of uh the
resin it's unbelievable often too often
I'm uh working with people's material
and you just don't see that yeah the
bottom of this producer the bottom will
but you think you think if people are
trimming this wet that all all these
crystals a get smashed ruptured oh yeah
um all all these leaves and stuff I
don't know how many people out there
throw away their Leaf it's sort of a
more of a '90s thing where everybody
just threw away their Leaf the quality
of the resin on that leaf is really no
different than the quality of the resin
right inside the butt if you were to
turn it into hash you quickly realize
that that's uh that's what we're growing
here for particularly when we're calling
it
medicine really nice and what was give
us the background on the bar one more
time I there's Shish bar yeah it's an
old Shish Berry clone we got in uh
London uh and I've had it I've had it
since had I've had it since the mid 9s
would that have come via like NYPD yeah
okay so then that guaranteed that lets
me know that because it was uh NYPD that
had it um it would have come from
breeder Steve it would have been an
original shry either a red line a red
line Red Line okay cool there were two
lines the red line and the yellow line
that used the two afghanis that were
used in the creation of shisher and both
are exceptional slightly different but
still so always it's always been number
one if someone makes hash out of it it's
it's it's a star it is the first bubble
hash I ever made that let me know that
there was something special with these
bags that these bags could do something
that was special cuz before that I had
seen it done a few times and I was very
unimpressed with the wet sort of
substance that came out of the one
single the two single bags one work bag
and one catch bag and then breeder Steve
brought over it was the yellow line of
shishkaberry a pure sherberry and when
we made that into water
hash it was the first time I was like
okay there's something here this is a
real thing so so in Spain too the
reaction in Spain for the barber Bud was
oh yeah I was having I was having people
I respect come up to me and sort of tap
me on the shoulder and be like hey can I
try some of your dry sips and was just
like nice of course you can of course
you were so generous with your dry sip
so many I bumped into so many people
they'd be like hey do you have any of
that great Gardener dry SI I'm like no I
don't have any and they were like well
let me smoke a bowl cuz I have some and
I like that's amazing that's awesome it
was awesome I'd say honestly five or six
different people smoked me up with your
hash in
Barcelona like apart from you like you
weren't even around yeah very generous
of you it's nice to give your hash away
fun you know it's good to share so I
guess next up we're going to lay these
screens down and do a little bit of
breaking up this bud so we'll uh let's
do it catch up with you guys in a
bit be the best seed run was a little
late when I are you serious like best
for seeds or best for resin oh it's
great for resin but uh when I fmed it I
it was sort of last minute thing so the
right didn't work as good as it should
have all right well we're back you can
hear us yapping away here um we've got
the large 5 foot by 3ft screen setup and
that's going to uh break up some nugget
man does that powder up
amazing holy
Christ yeah there's some nice seeds
there's some seeds in there for sure
yeah absolutely feminized Barber bud so
we're doing the little light trick the
quick bounce we're um basically going to
break some nugs up over this quite quite
delicately because it's a very large
screen you don't want to really rub too
much on top of the screen because it's a
larger size we're working with a 250
Micron underneath here we have a 180
Micron and what we do is just the more
gentle we are we want to just get the
pure heads so if we can get the pure
heads we're
happy crappy bin you need a bin yeah I
need a crappy bin be right back all
right amazing resin content on these
plants like these guys uh are definitely
not messing
around it's just
beautiful reminiscent of that old school
shishka
[Music]
Berry so
nice it's nice to see you know special
genetics stay around but also be worked
and bred into into something more
special I would gladly help you but
without gloves I'm not going to even
attempt it I'll melt so much of this
resin onto my uh oh yeah you got some
over
there I don't know if there's any in
there no I don't think there is I think
this is like you I wouldn't even use
plastic gloves for stripping like this
yeah this is really only the heavy duty
I only wear the gloves cuz you'll just
you'll get crazy blisters oh yeah I've
been there I have been there so we're
just going to go through and break them
up because I'm I'm I'm destocking like
this because it's a seed run uh uh seeds
don't mind if buds are broken up people
do so yeah people definitely we can go
we can go through it fairly quickly and
my God is this ever just
perfect perfect perfect so we let this
just hang and dry and dry like it's
interesting cuz when you get the
opportunity to let things really dry out
uh wow you can you can play with it
right you can get it so so dry but then
you can close the door and just let it
sit and it's like you know gets a little
mo get that that sort of perfect butd
consistency no you can get too
dry you know well most people never find
out when they're just so damn worried of
selling it and getting it off the you
know and it's so much herb is just sold
wet that there's always extremely high
moisture content this has an extremely
low moisture content
yet you know some of the stocks can
still Bend yeah so that's definitely a
good
sign take that
off the stock is
reading man I'm excited to see what's
under this screen I got to say yeah so
we're going to do this for a
bin every time so you always want to
move move your product gently so then
when you're doing it you're always doing
it onto the screen cuz all of a sudden
you have a big pile of weed and you're
trimming buds onto the top of the weed
those triome heads even though they've
fallen off they have to now sort of
navigate yeah Plinko their way down
that's why we have a huge screen here
too so you you know if you've got a big
screen don't be afraid to use it if
you've got multiple people all using
their own this would literally be a
screen for four people you could have
two workers on that side two workers on
this side and just working over these
screens doing exactly he's doing this is
a good chunk of screen to do this work
or one worker
working yeah serious I'm not really
working am I I'm a talker come on I'm
here to talk no my work will be lifting
these screens and seeing what's
underneath them and then of course
dropping that onto the ceramic
uh little plate that Dil sent you what
do they call that little ceramic insert
I think that's what it's called you put
it inside the tie nail or you use it on
top oh no I just use it on top yeah yeah
I did that by accident and that's how
people are using them now they laughed
at me they were like what are you doing
with the thing and I'm like it didn't
fit in my tie cuz it's the original
titanium bowls and Nails it fits right
in but mine was ground down so that
little piece in the middle that was
keeping the screen from oh yeah I wanted
them to grind it down and it thickened
the walls anyway it's how that became to
be I think it's good for photography too
oh it makes great photos oh my God I put
too much on one the other day and I gave
it to a rookie you I don't believe it no
I gave it to one of the one of the the
king of putting too much on and he like
the guy just like and just like right
down
the slowly yeah that's that's where the
drop down comes in
handy right the that little yeah there's
a little piece it's a little glass piece
that goes up and then goes down and then
points up again and you put your bowl
and the D nail down there that way
things that drop through don't go into
the pipe they sit down in this little
chamber at which you could literally
just torch later for a
rip and it's hard to watch him do this
and not just be like but my hands are
just from touching one the amount of
resin on those gloves even has got to be
oh totally just since I've started look
at it oh my god oh no that's a rip oh
you're freaking me out there man I was
like
just this Patty of hash on
his oh my God award-winning Barb right
here well you got some more uh you're
going to be entering some more things
with Barb aren't you are you not I think
so I think we should yeah well
absolutely I mean look at it dude look
at it we got the champ show coming up
it's just Toronto [ __ ] ridiculous
dude it's happy weed this weed makes me
happy we're coming for the Legends title
No we're leg leg we're coming for the
experience and the good times dude this
will be a welcome welcome welcome
addition to
Legends I've been thinking about it ever
since the last Legends dinner I know you
know how many people go to Legends of
hash dinner and while they're sitting
there they say to themselves why didn't
I bring my best hash why am iend the
allall of next year making my peace hey
if you haven't started making your
Legends entry for next year this might
be a good reminder for you that if
you're coming and you want to show off
man I'm telling you like 48 hours is
what you have to come to my booth and
show me a piece to acquire a ticket
because there's not enough tickets
there's 15 to 20 that become available
um maybe if more people in the scene
that weren't entering you know dedicated
their tickets more new people could come
because there are at least 25 people
that just come to the Legends dinner
every
year but don't really enter hash so most
of them are legends though yeah well you
know what the Legends dinner was always
about ancient legends they're Legends in
people you know it's like it's fun going
to the Legends dinner and having Legends
Smoke your pipe absolutely we have a
pipe around here like that that the
Legends Legend dinner pipe yeah I've got
I had a few I I ended up selling my few
every year I I'll bring one and then as
I'm leaving a friend will be like you
have to sell me that pipe everyone at
Legends hit that pipe and I'm like uh
okay sure great like you can you can
only keep so many pipes in this world
right we got that done yeah I'm just
going to clear the
screen we notice how I said we yeah me
and Matt working hard's put I assure you
I have my
place this is uh going to be going into
your tumbler tumbler after this and
we'll do so you'll do a 10 minute we'll
do a 10 minute then 1 Hour 1 hour and
then we'll do the 24h hour 24 hour well
we'll do the 1 hour and then we'll go
and uh get the seed out 24 hours when
Matt first said that to me I was like
this guy is insane that he's spinning
his material for 24 hours he's not
actually insane his herb is just so much
better than most people's herb that his
24 hour which you couldn't even run the
majority of people's herb you could not
run for 24 hours it would be like uh
lawn clippings at the end of it but
you've seen what we pull out on his
24hour big bag of golden sift that still
slightly sticks to to itself sure it's
contaminated it's been spinning for 24
hours but the fact that you get the
amount that you get after already doing
the 10 and the one hour it blows my mind
man like it really does this is
um THC ladened herb unadulterated canabo
been collecting them for years well you
know you know go through hundreds of
strains to find that one that's just
like oh my God it's so different right
there there's only a few strains like
the sweet skunk is one of those strains
for me the the Warlock is one of those
strains for me the Warlock has a unique
smell both of those totally the ha which
sort of comes from the old pers and the
perss is you know smells are
extraordinary I mean it really is just
about a profile you know there's of
course visual things that show us
different structures and genetics in the
plants but it's in those profiles the
ratios of cannabinoids versus THC versus
the tpin and terpenoids and
monoterpenoids and sesquiterpenoids and
you can read about all these cool things
uh Google it up this is uh this is the
the next the next level of cannabis
learning people are not just growing
herb uh this is the messenger well you
think because of prohibition right
people grew plants for size sure no
smell you know canot smell you know
these are sort of before carbon cans and
you search for houses with high chimneys
and oh yeah or you search for a house
the best house we ever found was on the
train tracks and right where the train
came around on this property it it shot
it's it gave it a big boost of power and
shot out a huge amount of diesel out the
top of the the stack so it was just
perfect for the um for the diesel
generator that was also 24/7 pumping out
diesel smoke to just have this train
doing it like six times a day or
something and I remember grower so mad
because you gave him a stinky stinky
strain oh of course my God man that
plant is so the [ __ ] your problem man
it's like oh sorry that's so true here
you go and then it was and then it's why
it's probably one of the reasons why
only the few seem to have the ability
and it's funny that this would even
still be connected you know the Barb has
Shish Berry in it that Shish came from
Steve Steve and Matt to me remind me of
one another in one sense that they both
recognize quality they both don't just
smoke joints they know what full melt
resin is they know the grades and the
levels and from all the Breeders I've
met over the years the ones that
recognize the qualities of the resin to
me seem to be the ones that have better
luck in producing strains go figure that
produce melty resin for sure you know
you just can't figure that out sming
because of the CL and then you get to
see you to see that those same smelly
plants are the same plants that people
in the
clubs are using to feel better right cuz
there's something
to the the
synergistic smells and flavors that go
along with the high or the pain relief
or
the
so oh I just accidentally dropped that
big oops I Did It Again so there well
let's do that that's one oh no we're not
done one bin we're not done one bin we
didn't empty it out
man all
right there you
go it's so reminiscent to of that old
school lime bud you know the light
colored herb it's
just puts a smile on my face I'm
definitely going to do some macro
photography for you guys here get a
little bit of
um uh the the resin on the plant I
pulled a few buds aside here that I'll
shoot for you to show you the quality of
the resin and how intact it is this dry
uh still on the on the plant so how long
did you hang and dry this for two weeks
I think three weeks but at least at
least two at for a week hung for a week
it sat in a bin or it hung for two weeks
uh and then it sat in a bin for a couple
days and then uh we open the lid and
just uh and we stuck it in one room that
was warm I would suggest also just to uh
crisp it up right before we uh the fact
that you're leaving the stock on is is
huge that people think that they can do
this by taking the buds off the stock
your bud will get way drier so realize
that if you're going to copy him and uh
come out with the same results make sure
that you leave your plant on the stick
the stock is super Super Key cuz it
holds moisture just the right amount in
the inside the cellulose of the stock
and just hold that perfect amount of
moisture so that your buds don't uh
don't literally turn to dust cuz as
violent as he's being there's still Bud
here in the end
yeah and many many seeds so these seeds
will be available at the house of theeg
great gardner.com no sell seeds on our
site but you can get them at uh
Vancouver Seed
[Applause]
sacred herb which just just started
carrying our seeds which is a which is a
huge thing really cool Victor Ian Hunter
back in the day he he opened that store
to sell seeds and yeah absolutely he got
he got busted for it and they haven't
and they haven't sold seeds since so wow
it's good to uh yeah very nice know that
the old school so sacred herb Vancouver
Seed Bank two perfect options if you're
looking for uh we're working on the
house of the great Gardener Dot
uh UK exellent so we're going to and
what oh did we enter into the European
scene they like the barber bun there it
is shout outs to my Spanish crew at the
HQ yeah right on guys David and edu
those guys are awesome guys definitely
um where I'm hanging out when I'm in
Barcelona that place is nice uh did you
play Russian pool uh I did not play
Russian pool but what happened to me is
I got I sucked into the back room and
photographed Buds and hash for and2 yeah
so all my friends were like where did
you go I was like I was in the back room
there uh we were playing Russian pool oh
it's a beautiful table beautiful table
right you want to kick those underneath
you got a card or something yeah I got a
couple cards under here first we'll uh
these clean this
up room two let's make sure there's no
one in there meet the family asro boy
[Music]
you want to see something crazy uh
no I came here one day I was checking on
the phes one sec let me get my white
balance here we're all blue they're not
so bad most of them I've left by now but
I went to check I was like oh see how
the roots are doing right and I came in
under here and it was like man I got an
entire air Colony W setup shop look it
down in there all the little eggs and
stuff holy [ __ ]
dude that's
gnarly look at that they're like yeah
are they crushed there are those all
eggs I can't tell if those ants are all
crushed right here yeah they might
be no no no they're not okay well that's
officially hilarious dude so and what
which one are these sugar well these are
just all different cuts uh I got the
Sour Diesel the Warlock oh look at that
t came out oh nice dude little dig weed
in there
dude khaniis what do we got in here we
got the jt15 Jack herrer the Renee The
Afghani dude and all these are all CBD
what about this guy B weed that's a CBD
sweet skunk dude that's nice looking
yeah everything that you love about the
sweet skunk but has a CBD element to it
beautiful Jack rare
[ __ ] perss perss right here this thing's
such a pain but uh people love it people
love it right it's super hard to grow
though because it's buds get so heavy it
just Falls over digweed warlock
Renee Sour Diesel
Afghan CBD Afghan CBD sweet skunk
oh Barb hello there Barb how are you
girl I think I got a couple of those
don't I I just one
bar Barbara Bud very cool awesome nice
to see I don't think these plants were
in here just like a little while
ago here you go bubble man oh there we
go what's that barber Bud for you oh
Barber Bud for me dude look at that
wouldn't that be awesome look at
that I'm so
happy the
Rene oh
[Music]
yeah see the Dig weed
Afghani
beautiful I wanted to get this on video
cuz Matt is about to gift me something I
was gifted years ago but uh was unable
to hold on to it uh gave it to a friend
who ended up losing it due to the law
dude there you go man oh man so happy to
be receiving this this is the infamous
sweet skunk uh a favorite by many people
that don't even know it it's a favorite
people that don't even smoke cannabis
will have a hit of sweet skunk it's
literally like the salmon of herb you
know how people don't like fish but
they'll eat salmon that's what this is
this is the sweet skunk it's such a
great um just unique profile oh it's
unbelievable I used to be I I I I have
an island sweet skunk that I sort of
have like three generations of it it had
it and I and it had it he could find it
and uh but it's nothing like this does
and this one was gifted to me by a good
friend and and uh so keeping it in the
family and making sure everybody has it
because it's got to stay
alive and uh preserving genetics that's
what it's all about DC Legends yeah that
is really cool it's incredible how it is
literally like a bonsai plant you know
it almost looks like a bamboo or
something the cut is yeah perfect yeah
we just kept it under fluorescence and
just kept it on the back burner so it
was like this tall and you just to cut
it back yeah totally keep all Bon eyed
up dudk keep for a long time I really
appreciate it yeah yeah no worries House
of the great Garder man preserving
genetics breeding growing and supporting
the community in a way that uh I can
only give uh two thumbs up too so two
thumbs up okay we're back um it's been
hard getting Matt to not like touch the
resin on the screen cuz he's so like on
autopilot he wants to card up all the
resin this is a different uh process
we're doing we can card that up later so
we're going to take this we're going to
gently put it over
there rotate a my way
yeah put it down gently cuz there's
obviously
still resin to fall through there yeah
like look at that dude I've never seen
anything like that that's ridiculous
okay so now we need to lift this yeah
and put it right
here this whole thing SW look at this I
just want to look look at that it's
already like here bring the camera over
here and we'll show the
um your the
dang yeah absolutely good call I'm going
to take mine
off that's incredible the quality of
that so much fell breaking it up yeah so
let's see uh what managed to fall
through below that
uh put your end
down all
right so this right
here should be very very very very very
pure another card pure than normal I I
had you give you one yeah I have some
other harder different ones oh okay yeah
this looks like it's uh the right
texture as
well always doing things on a different
level with the great
Gardener I card that resin up slower you
can see just in the corner here how I I
gummed a little bit of it
[Applause]
up beautiful color on this dry sift it's
absolutely golden I'm suspecting under
the macro lens it's going to be uh damn
near pure heads
so that's a nice amount to get for a
first little
run quality
looks really high it's uh melts right
into a liquid just in your fingers I got
just a little piece there and it's
uh it's gummy and
melty looks to be I'd say 99% pure heads
just from the way it's glistening and
Diamond like but I'll get my macro lens
out and I'll photograph this and um we
still have one more trick to do to get a
second grade and then I guess really
we're going to get a third grade what's
left on top of this screen or we could
card it through as well it's uh always a
pleasure working with the great Gardener
wow yeah look at that quality even
what's sitting on top here is
incredible there's like random little
red hairs and then that's it everything
else is just
gold
well great to know when you use the
right genetics and you use the right
tools that you can get uh some pretty
great
results so we'll wait for the great
Gardener to get back up here we'll show
them this last little second grade trick
that we're going to
do just for a quick quick run you know
look at that even look at this though I
know that's I bet you that's 99% heads
I'm going to photograph it with my macro
lens but even the quality on this is
unbelievable so you want to do the
second trick 99% heads we'll do it
together you going to click it yeah
we'll give it a one two three I usually
do one in the middle but I would suggest
we don't all you ready
yeah perfect it almost didn't even move
in the middle I know now so let's bring
this back over to our original pile put
it gently over there holy moly that was
from a flick a
flick this is the flick number
one we're going to have too many jars in
the fridge and freezer you already
microplane SIV dry
sift Micron
size yeah it's true on top of this
screen underneath the
screen look at it move it almost like if
you do it too hard it catches
there he it's
[Music]
nice it's catching a little bit of the
uh I have a room that uh we're going to
put a AC unit in I'm going to make like
a super cold room I think that's a
pretty darn good idea and I'm going to
make it with these put these in there
somehow we should get a hinge on it or
something that'd be cool hydraulic
hinge
well I'm sure whatever you do with them
be oh you're going to leave them here oh
yeah dude oh man I brought those for you
dude last time I brought you bubble bags
this time I felt like for the quality of
resin that you're producing and stuff I
mean I love the idea that you home make
your screens and stuff but you need a
professional version of screens these
screens are oh they're just so tight
that's what I'm saying it's a special
machine ours are
like we can never get it tight but yeah
the machine the stretch it out it' be
interesting to see the process quality
from from just a
flick and I mean it's not like we're
done now we've gotten a first grade over
there a second grade over here here
wherever we decide to card this up is a
third grade and I would suspect whatever
falls through will once again be another
at what point does it stop melting yeah
exactly with a barber butt never no
exactly and then you know that's why you
always want to double stack the screens
cuz it'll it'll collect this this is
what you would have collected like on
here like it's almost like you know but
you managed to pull these little like a
couple of grams of heads out on either
pile you pull out it's almost like you
further refined you don't have to
clean it doesn't have to this has to be
cleaned but now you can literally get
like quality of resin like what I was
cleaning for you with just like a single
bounce without the secret without the
secret it's a different secret secret
Sam secret recipe or secret technique
stays a
secret well I mean until he allow still
make it yeah well caring's allowed us to
do that um this allows us to do that and
of course you know Sam's technique still
will always have its place cuz you know
when guys have like large amounts of it
that they want cleaned uh that's it I
was just had a conversation about sort
of dry sift and getting dry sift to the
point where it's like this and then
they're saying like how much is that
worth and you're
like you know what are you comparing it
to are you comparing it to the 20% that
the 20 25% that the BHO guys are getting
or the 10 to 15% that the ice guys are
doing when you get to this stuff yeah
and you're pulling out like a 1% it's
one like 1% pulling 1% out of all the SI
to put a value on it is really where
prohibition comes into play because
because of prohibition you can't grow
enough of it to make the true quality
medicine that is deserved like this is
the stuff people should be smok of
course not the plants well the plants it
has their place well the plants bring us
to the resin you know and they're
definitely like I would never want to
take away whole plant medicine from
anyone but I would hope that anyone
would never try to keep you
know to have this on a daily available
basis would take an enormous amount of
cannabis well did you just see the
amount of cannabis we used to break up
over that screen I'm sure many of you
were like oh my God
and you know it's not like we've wasted
it there's still a ton of resin still on
that bud still on the screens but when
you break it down to the small pile of
the pure
heads it is beyond rare it's it's the
Holy Grail let's go try the seconds yeah
absolutely you want to lift up and bring
the First with us as well of course I
mean I can't just you can't just grab
the seconds put
this good
call we're going to go back yeah
you could probably get away with
flicking it multiple times because you
have so much resin on there and it's
yeah you can tell this is a different
grade yeah oh for sure for sure you know
what I'm saying it's a tinge of green
that we're not getting here now it's not
that this is contaminated they're
different
heads you know which definitely makes
them a little less uh
picks up nice off of the uh poly
head nice fresh poly fresh
poly got a little snake ready for the
Dil Ren like this you can put it on the
card and leave it for all of a
minute and it gums up and it'll gum up
and harden up and make it a lot safer
for us to move that from here to
downstairs where we're going to go hit
that D now because after all that time
of growing beautiful cannabis and
hanging it and putting it in the drum
the bins and flipping it and then
bringing it over to the screen and deep
stalking it and collecting the resin the
way we collected it to drop it is an ABS
[ __ ] loot no go you can't you can't
do that that's like uh I don't know
that's a faux paaw Beyond faux paw that
was amazing you just dropped a tiny
little drop of it and it exploded when
it landed as we're talking about
dropping it but hey you dropped it where
you're supposed to drop it t yeah that's
listen dropping it on the table is one
thing dropping it on the wood stairs
that's a nogo so uh yeah let's head
downstairs we're going to hit some of
these
bowls might have
to uhuh
child I love you I love you I love
you give thanks for the morning rising
sun SP Breath of Life of
man it's all about your da relax and
free I want to take a dab with you
because I'm feeling
good it's all about your D relax and
free and
move see I want to Da because I'm
feeling good
yeah rise up this morning feeling in the
moon to dive away
today di away
today I saw my good friend he said to
me one D will keep the doctor away
it's all about your dab with you relax
and free and
move I want to take a dab with you
because I'm feeling
good it's all about your D relax and
Free Your
Move see I want to D with you because
I'm feeling good
yeah make way for the concentrate
[Music]