[Music]
now we're going to have to mute that
right off the bat how's that okay
make sure that's
available welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here today with uh my good buddy
John and uh we were thinking today that
we were going to share with you uh we
don't want to say you know the proper
way to hit a bowl of full melt but I
guess our proper way the way we feel
like we feel like a lot of people are
not hitting full melt and bubble
properly they're they're torching it
exactly John's noticing this as he's
making dry sift and wet wash these days
that is of full m quality and he's
sharing it with a lot of people I go to
the Cannabis Cup every year which I will
be at uh in a couple weeks November 24th
to 29th with John if you want to come
see us at the booth we'll be around
walking around and having a good time um
that's in Amsterdam but uh a lot of
people just they just don't know how to
hit the bong they'll especially with a
beeline they'll either suck out the
flame and then they get a taste from the
Smoke Off the end of the Bee Line and
they say they don't like Bee Line cuz it
leaves a flavor you're not really
supposed to burn the Bee Line out and
inhale the the smoke from the beon you
just want to use the flame as your sort
of wafting tool so we're going to do a
little video for you today I got my
macro lens so I'll do some sort of
showing you what we're doing from a
distance and then I'll try to put it in
as well clips of us closeup of just
gently the process of what we're doing
to hit the bong properly so first of all
I would begin with depending on what
bong you're hitting there's going to be
a learning curve cuz every bong perks
differently some bongs it's almost like
a horsepower of a car it's just really
strong and you're trying to take off
very slowly without screeching the
wheels some bongs are just like that you
know you give them the tiniest little
bit of suction and they just the water
goes up to your mouth it'll suck the
flame out so before taking a hit
sometimes it's not a bad idea to just
feel the perk when we were talking about
that feel the perk of the bong step one
you know just sus it out before you hold
a flame he's hitting a rure treating
yourself addition I'm hitting a
Mothership straight Fab and they both
perk quite differently I would not hit
his bong the same way I would hit this
one anyway smaller we sler yeah it's a
lot slower deeper CH it's a deeper so
with that one there I know I love that
bong this is what I use whenever I puff
Med cush mhm excellent all right so well
we've got uh a giant jar here of some uh
full melt cush bubble uh there's
probably about 30 G here and uh of
course John's got his uh superb quality
that we made on our our last video that
we posted making a fresh Frozen whole
plant extract and so yeah let me have to
smell that what do we got 120 90 oh
that's a 73 73 you know how it works so
well for me it's absolutely all right
well let's load ourselves a bowl
here we'll do a little a little
bage and and and when puff on something
like that you can see how small that's
all I ever really use I'm not doing a
big rip yeah no exactly and it's uh yeah
it gets right down to it that's the
quality is so good that you don't really
need to put like 300 uh there's a hair
right there we don't want that no that's
okay we'll do
we throw the lid back on that using our
Skillet tools here they can come in
handy sometimes it's a little bit
difficult to just big fingers kind of
trying to grab little pieces of hat
perfect little tools when dealing with
this perfect little to there's so many
different ones I got about 15 of them
actually so I never run out of two when
it comes in all right let's see if we
can find out Li that lighter sitting
right here I got one too a nice so let
us light our beines we're both hitting
with beine today we're not going to say
this is the only way to hit a bowl but
this is what we're doing today um
there's there's cordless units like the
amberber ceramic uh heater that is also
a great way to hit a bowl and there's
electric nails and there's sublimator
and all these different things we'll
talk about over time but today we're
talking
beine and uh I think John and I both
have a similar technique when it comes
to the beine which is uh wafting the
flame gently over the bubble allowing it
to melt uh hitting it and then letting
it melt for a while if you hold the
flame too long those volatile turpins in
my opinion are just destroyed they're
never really appreciated so uh here we
go
[Music]
that was just so tasty I could even pull
it all the way through cuz I was really
nice gently so nice and of course the
more gently you waft your flame over the
resin and the Less Direct
contact the more flavor and taste is
going to come through in that hit and I
think the the guys who are doing a lot
of dabbing with sublimator and enails
and den nails and
such are also finding the same thing
that when you bring those temperatures
down uh it's a world of difference
compared to the the young guy who's just
first time torching the nail orange hot
and then droing bubble in an orange hot
nail I used to do that many people used
to do that so thanks for joining us
today short video we're going to we're
going to sit here and do some more
puffing actually but um you know what we
were uh definitely talking about this I
had a little chat with jod about it
yesterday too about just not proper way
to hit
just to kind of gently and when we say
proper it's the way that seems to be the
most efficient and effective for what it
is it's such a valuable thing we just
did bubble we should do some full melt
dry sift too yeah we might do a walk the
dry sift you know so this here is
actually that product sitting right
there oh yes and this is medy this would
be U well that's an O
cross um unknown uh it's uh definitely
some Bag oh my goodness yeah yeah not
going to be able to really show it to
you guys but I'll take a picture and
I'll add it into the video so you can
see the quality of uh what we're ready
to puff and the same thing applies um I
find with the dry sift it's a little bit
quicker than the
Buttle yeah absolutely another thing I
would talk about as I'm watching uh John
load the just most awesomely huge Bowl
uh the guy who grew the herb and the guy
who made the dry sift is the guy who can
load huge bowls don't take someone
else's dry sift and load a big bowl for
yourself it's just not the best
etiquette I just you know it's not the
best etiquette I love I give it I love
handling it out to people who truly need
some nice little hint of some nice F
medicine and they're really afraid of
smoking a big joint smelling I try to
explain how this is a proper way of just
a nice little mhm Perfect all right full
melt dryft following um yeah this was
another video we made on the tumble now
you can see that video as well check out
check them out share them with your
friends and here we go here we go same
thing same app but this one's
quicker and that's what you don't
do that's a prime example that even
someone who hits a lot sometimes gets a
little excited and uh pulls it on that's
much much easier to do in the RAR cuz
it's a deep juggling
perk the mother ship is almost a gentle
perk even though you can pick it up and
get it really going
it's got a really
incredible uh learning curve to it for
sure thanks for joining us thanks for
watching leave us some comments and uh
we'll talk to you soon