[Music]
hey how's it going guys I'm Marcus
Richardson aka the bubble man help
popularized a Pioneer waterash back
about 25 years been in the industry for
a very long time hemp activism medical
cannabis and of course recreational
Cannabis I've been coming to ICBC pretty
much since the beginning uh Alex is a
good friend of mine I've known him since
back in the days of Amsterdam uh 25 plus
years ago and I've always found that
Alex has done an amazing job with ICBC
bringing together the corporates and the
Legacy you know helping push regulations
helping uh inform and educate
governments and different groups that
are going to you know obviously be
requiring to understand what this
industry requires and what this industry
could look like if we all sort of got
behind and and pushed it through the way
it needs to be pushed through very
different from shows in Canada um in the
sense that you know Berlin is you know
second to none for a cannabis show the
amount of companies and people that that
arrive from both the corporate entities
the Pharma companies but also from
Legacy seed readers and Growers and uh
without ICBC there would really be no
platform for so many of us to gather uh
and it is truly the conversations that
happen at ICBC are the conversations
that will shape the future of the
Cannabis world that we
[Music]
know
oh
yes oh
[Music]
yes let me know if y'all had a good time
tonight make some
d bless
y'all
up