welcome to Bubble man's world uh here we
are with part three of the tip
installment for water hash or ice water
extracted bubble hash tips with bubble
man call it what you want basically I'm
trying to give you guys some tips
for um getting through the process
without overthinking it it's quite a
simple process really one of the biggest
places people have problems is the place
that I'm going to be helping you with
today and that's in the property drying
of the water extracted hash that you've
extracted okay so there are two schools
of thought when it comes to the drying
um everyone agrees that we powderize
basically the people that are considered
the experts I guess which is somewhat
laughable if you just go out and do the
the experiments if you just go and make
the the water hash and you realize after
a while that if you're not using a
desicant if you're not wicking out the
moisture from the water hash you're
going to be left with a process where
your hash lookss really great for a
while and then it does this thing where
it Butters out and it no longer holds
its form it no longer is sticky it kind
of starts crumbling and falling apart
this is resin degradation it's the wax
membrane is being degradated by the
solvent use of the water because it's
hanging out for longer than it should
it's breaking that head down and
eventually you're left with this sort of
sort of a less than product you know you
hear people say all the time oh it used
to be so nice so how we can avoid this
is following one of the two schools of
thought you've got your stainless steel
strainer so you can take your fresh
Bubble Patty when it's right in the
pressing screen and depending on the
quality this is where it becomes a bit
tricky you want to gently dab some of
the water out of that bubble Patty some
of the water I say because leaving some
of the water present will allow you to
put it in the strainer and with the back
of a spoon you can gently push it
through the metal screen and what
happens is it it falls out as a powder
now don't make the mistake on allowing
this powder to pull up on the cardboard
what you want to do is as you're pushing
uh gently with the spoon the you know
rubbing on the inside of the screen
between the hash and the spoon and it's
falling you want to be moving it over
your thick cardboard I know a lot of you
are cringing out there right now and you
think it's uh old school method but the
cardboard is a desicant if you don't
want to use cardboard um my good buddy
Kake K uh he puts it on a screen and
then under the screen he packs paper
towels and those paper towels Wick the
moisture out of the bubble you cannot
just put the bubble okay the water hash
ice wax solventless whatever you want to
call it you can't just put this um on a
parchment paper or on a piece of glass
or on a plate because that will not Wick
the moisture out and air drying is not
going to be good
enough unless you're in an extremely dry
dry place and even still the resin will
bond itself so make sure you powder it
up the more exposure to surface area the
better the cardboard will Wick more
moisture out that way so this is one
school of thought our second school of
thought is a microplane now this is a V
Syndicate card it's not your average
micro microplane but I couldn't find
mine I think I might have left it at
Remos the last time I was there but so
this is a little card with holes in it
and you can literally freeze the bubble
patties uh you also want to allow some
of the moisture to come out before you
freeze it I like the idea of uh allowing
the the resin Patty to sit for a short
period of time on um some paper towel or
on towel below the screen that it's
sitting on so you're not getting fibers
in your in your hash and it can Wick
that moisture out and at that point when
it gets to a certain point you can
freeze it the freezing will remove more
moisture but it'll get it ready for
microplaning so you take those freeze
Frozen patties if it's a really high
quality resin I suggest breaking off
small pieces of the Frozen Pat Patty
like a gram at a time and microplaning
them and allowing as it falls out
allowing it to fall spread thin on the
cardboard always use plenty of cardboard
don't use little pieces that are this
big use giant pieces you can fit them
into trays if you don't want to use
cardboard you can use 4x4 screens like
these ones here you can use these metal
frame screens um that sit um you can
basically get them built into um
uh frames that they sit above one
another and you can basically put the
hash on the top and then underneath you
can put the paper towel as a moisture uh
as a desicant to Wick the moisture out
so those are our two schools of thought
um our microplane and our stainless
steel Seer whichever way you're going
about doing it you'll learn the way
that's best for you unfortunately by
making a mistake here and there but
hopefully these tips can help you get
your bubble broken into powder very F
powder spread very thin on a thick
cardboard or using a lot of good uh
desicant like paper towel that's stuffed
under the screen it has to be in direct
contact to really allow gravity to pull
that water out so we've gone to so much
trouble in the growing of this cannabis
plant all the variables to get it to the
point where the resin is mature and the
glandular triome head is thin and the
profile inside is
abundant then we've extracted the res
and we've done uh the right job on using
all the bags and isolating the heads
into their Micron size increments this
is the last most important thing and I
urge all of you to really learn how to
dry your water hash okay I hope that's
helpful um I'm going to finish it off
with a little dab of the fiveyear Cure
I've got right here do a quick little
dab a dooodle of that got the Dil right
here so all right here we
go
[Music]
great taste on that 5year cure and you
can never keep hash for this long
without drying it first
properly it'll never last for 5 years
and taste this good so there's one more
reason to dry your hash properly I hope
the tips have helped we'll see you soon
on Bubble man's world