hey welcome to Bubble man's world uh
we're here with tip four in the
installment of water extraction tips um
I've covered uh a few different things
from Ice to um curing and drying
processes but today I wanted to address
a question that I get a 100 or so times
a day and it's the infamous is the
bubble dabbable is it dabbable is your
bubble dabbable does it dab I get this
question over and over and over again so
I wanted to answer it for all of you
okay um the dab ability of a of a water
hash or a dry sift is really dependent
upon the quality of that resin now a dry
sifter and a wet washer what we do as
hash makers we isolate the glandular
Tricom head and we do that by various
means uh water and ice extract ction
which is the easy no-brainer way and of
course um uh we also do dry sifting
methods so when we isolate the gland
head to a 99% pure gland head you get
what we call Purity now Purity will not
give you a dabbable product but Purity
plus quality will and unfortunately the
quality of hash is never decided by the
hash maker unless of course he is also
the grower so it's really the grower and
the genetics of that strain that are
going to decide the quality How well was
the resin grown was it was it grown to
mature the resin head out and the wax
membrane to be very thin upon Harvest or
was the grower focused on vegetative
yields and flowering periods these
prohibition based mindsets that how much
can I get and how fast can I get it are
detrimental to the cannabinoid profile
and the hash maker so is your product
appable well if your product is a 5year
cured Master cush then absolutely it is
dabbable this stuff's been curing um I
had it in a freezer for the last 2 and 1
half years to preserve Tarpin but for 2
and 1/2 years I had it out in a various
of ways and I basically cured it up uh
to a real nice incredible flavor and
taste and uh yeah going to take a little
dab with you right now just to see uh is
it dabbable the question I get all the
time
so we'll put a little Marlin Asher on in
the background we'll get the denail
out with the Swiss perk I put my denail
in my Swiss perk
today and there's Nate right over my
shoulder chilling with Rob Clark two
very good friends of mine who I can
thank for both hashish knowledge and
beautiful glass
blessed
[Music]
we'll talk
soon
do