I've got a question for Assam. We've got
a passionate audience here at Hash
Church that's uh paying attention right
now. What's one piece of advice you'd
give to cultivators big or small who
want to use nutrients to elevate their
game inspired by what Canera is doing? I
think you've kind of answered this
question, but I wanted to be specific
because I want to make a nice clip of it
after the show is over. Yeah. So, as I
mentioned, you hear me guys? Absolutely.
True. So yeah, as I mentioned earlier, I
think the main two criterias when
talking about nutrients and its
correlation with plants is to look at
the uh the gaining weight as referring
to the human nutrition and the the
quality and quantity of excrements,
right? Unfortunately in in in cannabis,
we can't look at the gain of in in
weight because that's the yield. And uh
if we wait to look at that, it's too
late, right? Uh so the main criteria is
the quality and quantity of runoff we
generate. Uh so that makes the the uh in
the substrate the main aspect to assess
if we are fitting well our plants or
not. Right? So in in term of quantity uh
I think we better we we we have to
target a 10 to 20% runoff uh during the
vegetative uh watering and no more than
15%
in in in the generative uh in term of DC
and this is the according to my
experience I mean it's it's not nothing
in the book but it's my own experience
my own point of view is unlike uh other
substrates like soil and cocoa uh when
growing your rock wall I recommend
monitoring the EC uh at the root zone
and not at the uh the runoff level uh
for better accuracy uh because it's
different theuh it's inert the the the
rock wall it doesn't have the same
criteria as the cocoa or or the soil. So
that's why this may maybe have an an
additional cost like you have to invest
in sensors that are able to give you
real time readings of the uh EC at the
root zone but I guarantee that the ROI
is is is evident there especially for
large large scale growers. Uh the other
point is the uh weekly weekly leaf
analysis. It's a it's a I mean it's a
good
practice but I I recommend not making
drastic change uh based on the results
of these analysis. The reason is that
the standard nutrient branch that labs
the labs are are using as a reference
are very general and they are not
genetic specific and I think they need
it needs further studies to be specific
to group
of because you get your report for you
send samples leave samples you get a
report oh you have you're overfeeding on
nitrogen or calcium magnesium but what
is the reference what is your your
standard curve in in there it's are we
taking a general one for all the
genetics but we know they don't behave
all the same so that's why I mean I
would take just the general uh when it
turns to red phytotoxicity you have to
intervene and reduce your uh your
nutrient concentration but don't we
shouldn't go in the into the the details
and and and do drastic changes just
based on the uh leaf analysis
Well, it's good advice. Uh doing it at
the root zone and not the runoff. That's
uh geez, if your levels are high at
runoff, then uh it's going to be much
worse right on the plant.