yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
[Music]
yeah I can see the wicked in a great
spreading themselves like the Green Bay
Tree
don't don't the me not even
though who sleep on the
street treat people like some trash on
the street singing in that Feel Complete
but
wor up
from my up
from if you all
[Music]
know themselves like the Green Bay Tre
no they don't the they don't
me
even sleep on the street
[Music]
we building the DAV
Monarch standing
for living in perfect love
andity
why and
the the Conquering lion loose the seven
SE
[Music]
themselves like the
green not
even sleep the street
[Music]
never
suffer never
[Music]
know we get the
call
call call you're the call of the youth
when suffering
[Music]
group one the knowled what the
rules
withing life I could never
exclude shine
[Music]
fure well theno I know I've got faith in
me and so there will be no breaking me
we are TR through the mountains the
sings across the r SE de King is always
there with we he never left we out he
always stayed with
we
couldn't we are
full
withy every we see
strv every day we coner the be we SE
well blessed is the blessed is the me
more time for years and for months and
for weeks we've got to wait
patiently because patience is the
key the way he likes the way and he's
going to fly the gates for we and so we
wait
patiently because of patience is the key
light the way light the way and he's
going to
shine all right and we are all our
righteous
and
[Music]
man
the we righte
you it seems like a dream to achieve
something real something Heavenly when
live they get to be
lifeo
like f and all the energy some of them
they just looking for an enemy
with
and waiting
patiently
[Music]
patience he the and he's going the gates
for and so we
Pati because patience is the key
light the way he the way he
[Music]
the
come
[Music]
maest with the trip we say oh
over evil
infite
[Music]
oh the and he's going to slide the gates
for we see like we wait
patiently because of patience the J
lights the way he lights the way and
he's going
the
[Music]
gates up
it's when I
up the Seas the mountain and the trees
Mother Earth F me
with so and to me INSP me to teach
that's why we are clean street right me
[Music]
I
up when I wake up
[Music]
in alls singing fight against the
practices that they are bringing in my
brother did me wrong but I am forgiving
him let my soul be the game that Jack is
winning in wi from the beginning this is
the earth man is living in I am dressed
in my robe of cotton and
in thees that the of to are in they want
to get me out like a bat
anded concluding that we are intruding
by bringing the knowledge which are
the IAL never rush
adrenaline
to I must never chemically reduce my
skin melanin never Envy stretches out
like a Gard but on the am calling to
cover me like
the the evening afternoon or the early
morning while the sun shine or the rain
is falling falling I will drive over the
hill without
stalling womaning at yard in that are
this is the situation that we are in
[Music]
iake up in the
[Applause]
[Music]
morning bless me
work must
be I'm tell
[Music]
when I wake up in
morning it's amaz
[Music]
you don't have to ask I'm going for the
best
as far as the sea and the land go but as
far as I can see
I
[Music]
so we must like
like
the TV
andow we have different type of wepe
show take one
[Music]
bring to you
be care
this is what I want
to brother brother brother this is what
I want to say to my sisters s s this is
what I want to say to
Jamaica Jama this is what I want to say
to not
America America this is what I want I
want to say to Mama Africa Mama afria
which is the land the land of fora
[Music]
all
the could come together together
together I wish you and I could obey the
laws of
nature I wish
everyone could listen to The Creator
Creator creator all of us could learn to
love each
other I wish
everyone one could live
for
TR for some it won't be possible
be
[Music]
there