[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world guys I am
so happy to announce that out of those
20-year-old seeds that I cracked and I
I'll give you a little breakdown how I
did it I looked online I got all nervous
I thought I better do you know I called
uh the great Gardener I I asked
different friends I found a really good
seed germinating page and I haven't been
able to refind it I've been trying to
find it so I can link it to one of the
guys who asked about the other video
anyway I just went my old school method
that I knew was tried and true a couple
of plates um paper
towel Mo moistened the paper towel and
um basically covered it up I put this um
just like this under my office table and
I turned on my radiant heat floors just
to about
75° and so underneath the plate is a
nice kind of warm temperature um I the
paper towel has not moistened out and
the the water isn't like super cold to
touch it's about you know a a little
warmer than room temperature 75° or so
and this morning I opened it up and had
a seed crack so I'm going to show you a
couple of macro pictures of that look
how beautiful that is with the the old
outer shell cracking open and this just
perfectly beautiful New Life coming out
of that seed I'm very excited about that
so what I've done is um I've already
taken it it was literally just cracked
with a tiny little bit pointing out
which you could see and I I dug the
little hole with a pen I just pushed the
pen in a tiny little bit maybe about uh
jeez you know not a qu of an inch or
something and then I dropped it in tip
up so so um we'll see what happens it's
now in the the cocoa and the Pete Moss
and the the
promix sitting in the pot I've moistened
the pot and uh yeah I guess we'll wait
and see what happens we've got about
nine more seeds that are in here right
now not to expose them too too much but
uh none of these seem to have the crack
happening on them yet I try not to touch
them with my fingers
it's just amazing that one of those
seeds cracked and I'm really excited
this is basically just a short update
that I wanted to share with you letting
you know that the Jamaican hybrid of
Lamb's bread Eugene strain is growing at
bubble man's house so this will be
something fun to watch and I'm just
going to leave you now with um some
photos from Jamaica that I took over the
years um a lot of these photos are from
the early 2000s but some of them are
from a little bit more recent so more
recent but basically uh enjoy keep
watching watching Bubble man's world and
we'll talk to you soon
peace just an additional thing to add
guys when you're cracking your seeds
make sure the light is extremely close
to the top of your container we don't
want those seeds
stretching all right peace
[Music]
he ooh
oh in theard s Andre Park music a bubble
steam a bubble bun a bubble from dark
and the fire B the just
BL in a theard s and Park music a bubble
Steamers a bubble bunch a bubble from
morning to dark and the fire on the for
just one thing to over us about Jamaica
we are the confidence of the African
continent in our I no influence is
greater and the state of the nation this
test why the people suffer from disase
of the mind of enemy as de so them
worship the blind but the real black
Madonna is the rightful Divine and the
king and queen crown say
Time theard
s music bubble Ste bubble BN chice of
bubble from morning into dark and the
fire on the for just BL up in a theard s
Andra Park music a bubble Steamers a
bubble m a
bubble dark and the fire B the for just
the fire just a blaze
up burning out the
evil while the music free the
people
oh the herb I bring the
healing and the word I bring the
knowledge where would take up Wicked get
shake up when the Consciousness wake up
in theard sent Park music a bubble
Steamers a bubble bun chice a bubble
from morning to dark and the fire B the
for
just in theard s Park music bubble steam
a bubble pun a bubble from morning to
dark and the fire upon the FL just a
blaz up from generation to generation
the tradition of righteousness is passed
on
from the
ancient setting up precedence of
Excellence ritual Devotion to the
Mastery of the instrument strings with
percussion and vocal bingy vibration one
to other the most high meditation with a
high gr marijuana in a
sent music a bubble Steamers a bubble
bun chice a bubble from morning to dark
and the fire upon the for
[Music]
just the fire just a
Blazer burning out the
evil while the music free the
[Music]
people
oh the her I bring the
healing and the word I bring the
knowledge what would take up we keep get
shake up when the Consciousness wake up
[Music]
he