[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world I have been doing all sorts of fun
things and I haven't been filming it so
I figured I'd give you guys another
little sort of short intro into what
we're looking forward to
uh while I take a nice dab of rosin I
did have some nice little nugget past my
way this is uh I don't know if I can get
you guys the closeup but it's very nice
Jamaican butt I'm going to take pictures
of it with the macro lens it's got a
beautiful smell to it real exotic it was
this spice that I love in certain
Jamaican herbs and this has it uh this
was given to me by my buddy
sham shamrock no
uh so this herb was given to me by my
buddy shadrock and shadrock runs the
vegan uh restaurant side side of the
road kind of restaurant called Ras Ries
and it was funny cuz when I walked up to
him and I told him who I was he said man
he said if it don't bubble it ain't
worth the trouble and I said how do you
know that and he said you showed my
father Ras roie how to make bubble has
like 12 or 13 years ago and I I couldn't
believe it it was quite a trip to now
realize how old I am that the people
that are recognizing me here are the
sons and the daughters of the men and
the women that I shared my knowledge
with uh almost 15 years ago today so why
don't we have a big old raw monster
Rosen hit got a nice little blob of gold
here and uh we're heated up we're using
the quartz Halo now so I've now shifted
from the uh Sapphire which obviously I
broke in the last uh pre
video quartz Halo is really I have to
say it's right on par with the with the
sapphire I've noticed very little
difference so far so Props to those guys
for pulling it off um going to do an
interview with uh shadrock and we're
going to uh go over and show you his
kitchen and show you a little bit of his
ital food and kind of try to promote his
business a little bit because right now
he's one of very few people producing
true ital uh food here in uh N Grill
which I think is a fairly important
thing when you're coming on a vacation
to be able to have access to the good
food not all this burger and crap and
pizza stuff that uh you know most of the
places are trying to trying to make here
we
go there's people out there trying to
find a Dabber carb cap that fits their
Halo this unit from ID daab damn near
here fits it perfectly out of all the
ones I
have I use this one the most often even
though I sort of broke the top of it a
while back I love it for its carbing
abilities a quick
Zamboni and there we go next time we
kind of cloud like I say I bring about
this music
[Music]
man Royal alongside one
SP oh
yes again
and highest the
highest yes looking at me eyes so
because head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke Co
that's why I
don't yeah
[Music]
must be burned like a tee must be
cleaned rather vital for Spiritual hene
a king Salon certify the tree and he is
the wisest man to we so sh propanda the
preach her never Sound True speech so
meanwhile the song called leaders
deceive man obligated to clarify and
teach you now
[Music]
theit open up
Jamaica and this G you want to taste
Jamaica come Jamaica you hear me real
thing R blessed in the name of the most
high King C see the ashes from the earth
from the Earth to the finger and from
the finger to the joint and to the bra R
Powers give thanks and
praise over there blue hole blue the
[Music]
still where are you
[Applause]
oh yeah there he
is there he
is some parrots right there
[Applause]
that
go look good
[Music]
PR
check them out Tosh I got him on my
camera it's right in the
middle oh yeah it's green yellow there
two of them they're nipping at each
other
[Music]