[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
we are heading to West Morland today
we're up bright and early because of
it's summertime the heat is pretty good
here in Jamaica right now
we're going to be heading to see some
field today Fields I don't know one two
half we'll give we'll let you know we've
got the camera you guys looking forward
to see some Fields can't wait yeah
dude this is definitely uh what we're
looking to do some fresh frozen field
runs we got the 20- gon bags we got our
micr planer and we're able to uh we're
looking forward to seeing what we can
find today on the stick so uh stay tuned
[Music]
oh
now I use the hers for more than one
reason I use the herbs throughout every
season I I use the Earth for medicinal
purpose I use the Earth to maintain my
focusing we got many different kind of
hers ar gluc ar brontis the
cancer King Jamaica we got many
different kind of her I'm s nurse I'm s
doctor I'm s PRI I'm s
preacher and it's a
[Music]
reality go do your research and see as I
use more than one
reason I used
the throughout the
season I use the H for medicinal
purpose I use the her to maintain my
Focus use the hers for more than one
reason use the herbs to maintain my
Focus use the hers for medicinal
purpose I use the herbs to maintain my
focus relieve
depression anxiety
relief treat breathing dis like
Asma strengthen the body's immune system
it produce longevity and long life and
long life and long life
[Music]
and well we just got to West Morland we
just drove over the border
from which one St Elizabeth so St
Elizabeth Paris borders with West
Morland and West Morland is of course
famous in Jamaica or it's ganja you've
heard it in many or song some of the
best scents comes from West West
[Music]
Morland I use the Earth to maintain my
focus
the arms fighting pain treating
circulate through
disorders and announce
memory elevate your mood and anounce
your wellbeing and your
contentment and produce a feeling of
relaxation the for more than one
reason I used
the seasons
[Music]
to main
focus all right guys we made it to the
hills in West Morland sure did respect
Johnny's got the blueberry skunk that
he's taking a big sniff of I just uh
would say it's definitely a grade really
nice and covered in red had the
microscope out we were looking at it
intact glandular Tricom heads which is a
rare thing in this heat they tend to
melt but uh we figured we'd smoke a
little bit of this hash while we're here
before we go visit the ganja
plants so what do you guys say you ready
for a little bowl or what let's do it oh
I'm ready for some great stuff here this
is what we came
for absolutely this 73 right uh yes this
is the hit the 73 that's what we uh CED
up last night and I figured out you got
the lighter Johnny I
actually we just have the r yeah it was
blue I threw it to
you maybe in your pocket or
something it is under your
phone under the old phone which is
turned on and it's on your
camera it might drain your battery but
just letting you know cuz I know you
like to take pictures with your phone
I'm going to take a picture of this weed
right now you want to go first oh it's
all yours hit that up full melt bubble
full melt
bubble my first picture of Jamaican
grown resid it'll it'll look a lot nicer
if you take it in the sun when we're
done this
video definitely
beautiful so there good job there's
still some in there light that
up man it's great to be back in West
Morland
definitely the proper Vibes up
here it's great to First be in West
Morland yeah I guess a couple of you
both of you guys this is your first time
right very
cool we drove from Kingston
and took us about 2 and a half hours
from
Kingston driving through to
claron there you go want me to reload
you that was just kind of the end that
was kind of like a I need a
rip so this is awesome yeah man just
wait this is the this is the beginning
of awesome I think you're going to
realize you're going to be saying a lot
of
Yaman there could be you'll be hearing a
lot of it for sure you hearing a lot of
it absolutely it's a very
popular everybody says it all right okay
thanks for the nice rep Rock The Hitman
Micron and it's about 32° in the shade
or as third world would say 98° in the
shade classic
song oh
yeah on all right well I'm definitely
ready for one of those that's what I
needed that looked great thank
you nice oh and there's that little
way of
sunshine excellent excellent let me get
that beine for you nice to have the
little travel hit man you know we're
definitely not rocking the mother ship
and the denail up here right now
um don't see the power
lines oh
yeah lighter
please thank you sir
well it's going to be good getting out
into the field it's going to be hot as
all very hot I would say I'm going to be
uh photographing the plants and I'm
going to be stuck under the sun
definitely going to be taking breaks in
the shade oh we got the 50 sun block me
and Ashley yeah up to 50 yeah but you
know what all that does is potentially
protect your skin from burning that's it
won't protect you from sunstroke it
won't protect you from no it really
won't I know got water to me to me
that's the staying out of the Sun is key
if you stay if you get in there too much
and you're not used to the heat
especially here in Jamaica in the summer
man it can be Devastator so we're
prepared definitely we got
hash that awesome you've been dying for
that hit haven't you oh yeah it was nice
I mean we hit that one little
hit on the way here yeah which was nice
but uh
well I guess we're going to continue to
Puff a few bowls here and uh we're going
to make our way up to the field so we'll
uh bring you guys along when we get
there let's uh go chase some
rein a
aome hey guys bubble man
here just been hiking up the mountain
here for about 10
minutes not too long of a hike by any
means but it's definitely got a little
bit of a grade to it heading up into the
hills to see a grower friend's crop here
in West Marland says it's pretty much
ready to go he tells us uh he grows
about 400
lb in this
field I'm not sure if that's per year if
he's pumping out 100 lb four times a
year or what but we'll see I guess when
we get up there first sign of water it's
extremely dry season in Jamaica right
now he said the plants haven't been
watered for a few days and they're
absolutely leaking resin just dripping
um he showed me a couple of buds on the
way in classic pineapple skunk sorry
blueberry skunk very popular names I
recognize the smell from my friend jono
the
docta and
uh yeah pretty stoked can't wait to get
up there it's wicked hot it is June
almost 30th so we've got uh very warm
weather 30 plus de every day and it's a
hot sun I'll tell you a real hot sun
plantains sizzling them up on the
fire the real way to make food right
there all right
so here we are in the Hills about to go
and explore one of these ganja Fields so
come check it out with
us really stinky I can smell it
here on the finger just touch it just
touch it oh dude I I'm covered in it all
right I accidentally touched one all
right man you plant nice amount of herbs
here look here have a next feel over
there okay a young feel
nice scientist
[Music]
so what kind of
chees
H oh yeah
what kind of tree is that what strand
you know oh which one the tell T one
right here oh careful be knocking over
plants oh yeah call this is a nice tall
one it's hard to
say definitely has some sativa in it man
we should buy that
one
yeah that's a nice plan man
just feel my skin burning right you
touch it you know oh I know it's thick
so
nice oh [ __ ] look at my finger right
look look here oh yeah I just touch it
you know you see it out there you see it
out there man you see it you got a
sticky
finger right on them weed are just four
just eight weed now 8 weeks yeah here we
go we got some nice purpling effect here
yeah yeah it's full of purple right here
also purple yeah purple purple purple
enough purple it's full of purple look
this one has some pink hairs
yeah well I've made it here to the
beautiful ganja field in West Morland
Jamaica and I can't say that I could
ever be happier the smell is absolutely
beautiful it was beautiful 500 ft before
we even approached the garden
it's really nicely dense we've got uh
you know you've got plants that are one
and 2T tall many three and four feet
talls and and a few five and six feet
talls
one look at that one down there that is
the
one and even this little guy look at
these FX tail fox tails on this
guy woo tell you that sungrown resin
really reeks just produces turpins you
know I hear a lot of people with the
turp you know TP Rich tppy well this
right here is extremely
tppy the wonderful thing about this is
we're able to buy whole plants and uh
run them through the Bubble Bags there's
another one over here I wanted to show
you
guys really big tall guy here this one's
over 6 feet tall taller than
me it's got a very different smell to it
how's it going Johnny B this place is
crazy yeah you're happy
man
nice I got a little held up over there
with some killer purple strains one yeah
there's some purple right there come see
that one come see this all right we come
see of
course oh
yeah oh yeah look at that
a little piece of it is good that's good
to bring the water in yeah and taste the
resin on the end of the thing yeah make
your mouth numb a
[Laughter]
little what are you saying Ash much man
you digging this this your first time in
Jamaica yes ma'am you've been here for
what 48 Hours yeah you're in a ganja
field like a real ganja field not like
at this look at this all
right I'm just
[Music]
like oh my
God that is some crazy we got to wash
that one dude there's a couple I want to
wash we got seven Footers back there
look at these ones over
here I'm sweating with joy yeah manw
how's this for a little mutant I just
found this thing has crazy dark almost
black but buds on it I might want to
wash this one you get such unique herbs
here in Jamaica the Jean Pool is
incredible because all the heads from
all over the world have brought their
genetics here to share with the
locals and then of course the locals
have been breeding cannabis for
decades by using the seeds and the
strains that they have access to look at
this one all single leaves check out
that mutant single leaves the whole
thing all it is growing is
KX oh
man and of course it's always nice to
see real cannabis plants a real
height oh
W that one's also
beautiful and then we got the big one
how's that for a queen that's pretty big
over there about 7 feet tall
that it's cannabis John that's beautiful
how's it going over there I'm just
loving it over I see you have a same
camera too sir yeah brother yeah
brother oh man we're having fun we are
having
fun as that sun goes away for that
second that's the coolest Breeze talk
about appreciating that hey oh man give
thanks for the
cloud this is it
ready I mean really this
PL is is as far as I can
reach
oh M man is that nice too this one looks
very Afghan big
beast right next to it we have a very
different style plant with a single Cola
and a very light fan Leaf
structure this is some more afghanica
over here you can see the features of
the big large indicia style leaves
drooping in the hot
sun we should have tags John we should
be tagging plants
dude here
today dude there are millions of
tricomes in here
dude you happy dude dude dude dude dude
you're in a Jamaican field I've never
hey let's just say John's
happy s's a very happy man
o here's some beautiful fall
colors got some nice purpling
effects quite a different look to this
plant looks
somes oh yeah got some really nice pink
hairs
we need to
BU yeah
man
what this field we need toy whoa look at
this one now
definitely well you know what
delicious Miss the20 Mark that's
okay all right so I just found something
that I wanted to share with you guys
here look at the leaf structure on this
guy here you see the difference in the
plant you see the thin little leaves now
this here this here is a
sativa this here is a SAA IA Jamaican
grown tropical sungrown resin here in
Jamaica I wish I could explain to you
guys how unbelievable the smell of this
ganja field is this is no joke it is a
wonderful beautiful thing and I love the
fact that Jamaica has decriminalized
cannabis for up to 2 ounces you do not
get um any jail or any court it's a
ticketable offense in fact and uh it's
the start of a great thing here in
Jamaica I look forward to the day when a
field like this can be 100% legal
extracted
isolated and and turned into wonderful
medicine for the people that although
this one isn't the healthiest looking
plant wow is it ever the darkest one
I've ever seen this thing is almost
black dark purple yeah that must leave
that I'm not care what it so many
different colors hey look at the color
on this one we've got purple Taco
Happening Here the leaf is tacoing and
bending up like a taco
shell look at this one oh
yeah real
nice this
one oh yeah this one also most of see
just the different strain hey well to
how you know what this this okay see the
more it R the more you make it R more it
show you the best mhm yeah it's true the
more you stress it yeah the more it
thinks it's dying and the more resin it
produces all right so this is a young
field be careful The Way We Walk four
weeks old than four
weeks and planted from seed yeah got the
seed in the dirt and it's grow yeah
so what kind of harvest would you get
off of this little
field when Harvest
I
yeah well we have to see take the season
yeah how it get the season mhm it's all
depends on the season right yeah
sometime all depends on the rainfall
yeah this is a MTH yeah this is a m up
so he'll be taking out yeah I saw this
one oh yeah so that's what we do with
the males right there
guys we yank them
out you can't say yet how much you're
going to get out if you have St the beer
yeah when it's beer right so this is a
young field that we're in right now it's
about 4 weeks old he's planted it right
from seed there are males and females as
cannabis is a dious plant um they'll be
pulled over the next uh couple of weeks
as they are starting to all flower and
show they look amazing
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world we're here with Esco and Johnny B
and we're in West Morland Jamaica
brother yeah straight up thanks man good
thanks for having us here so we're in
this beautiful ganja field um I would
say it's ready this this is ready to cut
down yeah yeah any time in the time as
you can see everything is already ripe
and you know excellent so you're going
to put work how much time do you think
it'll take and how many people will be
working on this to harvest it well going
to be like about 10 of us 10 people and
normally it's going to be like taking
like maybe two days two days you guys
work hard yeah hard hard work guys are
working 10 to 15 hour days whole days
whole day whole days whole day see
that's what we're talking about ganja
farming is not the work for the lazy
this is extremely difficult and hard
work and if you could feel the sun
beating down on us right now it's a very
hot sun sun right now here in Jamaica so
it's uh I think the plants are loving it
I can smell the resin hundreds of feet
away from the field definitely amazing
and you guys have been breeding and
growing these strains for many years
yeah many years many years you know
excellent lot lots of different types
yeah there are I mean that's one thing I
say about Jamaica all the time how you
can smell all these flavors and and
strains and strains I mean these are all
from the same bag of seed yeah and
awesome there's so much variation and
nice variation not a lot of like I
really saw very little that wasn't good
okay everything like 95% of what I saw
was really nice you know like I mean
everything but everything is like is say
Jamaica is like a blessing still you
know it's like from the father above you
know differentation towards the even the
the farmers you know it's a current it's
a current I just say see a whole
globalization of different energy
towards her you know well I mean it's
been a long time that they've been um
you know Prosecuting and jailing us for
this plan I look forward to the day when
you know guys like you that are doing
this hard work can be a lot more
respected by your community instead of
uh bashed on and fighted with because
you guys are doing the good work of
course you know this is this is this is
a medicine that can cure disease that
can improve the quality of life and the
rasta Community the Jamaican Community
has known this for decades exactly and
uh the they've been singing about it in
their music I mean most of the the
people here that farm ganja they have a
in depth knowledge about yeah yeah and
it's not like the knowledge comes from
experience and from inhaling the resins
it's not learned in a book and you don't
go to school for it yeah this is real
experience exactly nice the catas are
joining us yeah I was going to ask when
harvesting do you cut or you just pull
the whole thing right out normally we
just pull it right out pull it right out
right out that's what I was wondering I
don't see anything I was looking cuz we
have other ones over here and you got
the starter fields and I'm like they
just rip these things right out the
ground listen that's normally when you
pull it out it's it's normally stay
alive for us I don't really know it's a
different but for us to to the
impression of seeing it right when you
put it out alive it's like it stay alive
compared to if you cut compar with you
cut the life so cut the life it's like
you cut him like that so when you put
you put him with the main rout and the
lat road so it come when you hang it now
it automatically just dry slowly fall
slowly but when it when when it is cut
groups before you get there yeah and it
start getting interesting this is this
is farmer knowledge he's laying on you
right now red soil exactly you know and
it's very hot so hot it's hot and so
easy it's just like wow that's why the
plants pull out so nicely so nicely I
can just grab a handful and it's just I
mean this is literally stain your hand
orange yeah
to Johnny Johnny Johnny John exactly man
is okay yeah for real man it's good man
it's good yeah as you see this is a lot
of medicine as you see you guys teach
you lot of things more cuz at first the
microscope yes yes the first time I I
really saw never seen it before I never
seen it before man the first thing I
ever seen that's it was only about like
I watch Discovery I like watched a
couple documentaries about the herbs and
all of that and I could see the weed
like the herbs like really close yeah
they was it Geographic doc those are my
photos you're you that's my
photos first they show a bud and then
they go closer closer purple my photo
tell man one love
one what a small world we are living in
right now he's telling me the first time
he ever saw a glandular Tricom on a
National Geographic documentary which
was on the Discovery Channel in fact it
was a TV show called taboo yeah and they
did a show on cannabis and they they
hired me to to take three photos tell
now I'm here with you man my D is the
best thing man it's the greatest thing
man I'm telling you cuz telling you
awesome it's first I really see
something like that man well listen what
we're going to do is we're going to take
a little break cuz the sun is beating
down on us we're going to go hang out
under the Hut where the herb is uh they
have some herbs dry right now maybe eat
a little food drink a little water I'm
going to make my way out here take some
macro photographs and then we're going
to get working John going to pull we're
going to get the buckets we're going to
tag the pl plants that we want to get
we're doing fresh frozen field run today
um unfortunately the 20 gallon bags
aren't working out for us but you know
what 5 gallons are great I don't mind
running two or three batches exactly and
just uh extracting the resin off of
these plants and showing these guys with
a purity the incredible work that
they've been doing all these years so
thanks for watching Bubble man's world
all right respect respect okay let's do
this planting yeah some bread fruit and
planting yeah more oh with the
Aki there we are look at these
guys this is real food food that was
never packaged yeah no need to spend
expensive money on trucks and gasoline
to move the food around and package it
right off the tree right off the tree
livity that's real livity right there
okay so here we are and um we're showing
these uh these ganja Farmers exactly
what they've been growing in something
they've never seen before for a second
we do
teamwork do it
together I
think we're Team working it teamw
working
it smoking and loving the resin
fresh frozen field or field fresh frozen
oops
I'm
going good to
[Music]
me bubbling all right guys we're finally
getting down to business Johnny B3
shirt I like it um we've got an
oversized bucket we went and picked a
bunch of plants you saw out in the field
we cut them all down well we pulled them
all out actually the roots are still
attached here's the first one that John
found and we sort of pulled out together
I think it was a joint effort on this
one it was like check this one out a
joint effort no pun
intended um so yeah we're going to strip
this guy down real quick so it's all you
have to do when're frozen in the field
here takes pretty quick just nice cuz it
just came
out of the field it's still got Roots it
just snaps off so quickly yeah they're
definitely you can tell too that it
hasn't been uh getting you know it's
been a
whilea since it had uh that's actually
some pretty good natural stuff there get
your greens are good for you feed your
endoc canabo system that's what I'm
doing right now and you know what that's
like all right well what we're going to
do is we're while John's doing this I'm
going to we got an oversized bucket this
time so we don't have as much of a spill
I'm going to put all the buckets all the
bags sorry inside of one another I've
got them hanging right here with the
beautiful ganja field in the
background love
Jamaica all right so we know the order
of the bags we go purple number 25
micron this is the smallest of the
screens tightest of the
scre so this is a seeve stack for those
of you that want to understand what's
going on here these screens are all
different
sizes and the the purple bag is the
smallest screen it's 25 microns okay
it's very very small much smaller than
even those little heads that I was
showing you on the plant those are
between 160 and like 45 microns the
majority of them so microns is just a
measurement uh a method of measurement
so we start with 25 we go next with the
white bag is the 45
after the
45 and gone it's the gold we love the
gold it's one of my favorite bags right
here and you guys will see why when uh
when we
release the the bags from the water
after mixing and we show you what we've
caught so to give you an idea of the
process give you an idea of the process
what we're doing is we're
we're freezing those little triome
glands those little microscopic glands
we're freezing
them because they're brittle they're
encased in
wax right basically we freeze the little
Micron uh the wax membranes of the
tricomes by freezing them they become
brittle and once we put the water in the
ice in and we start mixing it all up
what's going to happen is those little
resin glands are going to break free
from the triome body and they will sink
in the water due to their gravity uh due
to their density they're they're still
affected by gravity every most things
float in the water all this plant matter
will float in the water the resin heads
will drop off break and sink and they'll
fall through these series of screens and
simply put we will pull the screens
up and collect the resin so one of the
things we're going to need I'll get one
of our audience members to possibly grab
is a nice straight kind of clean stick
that I can mix
with it's coming it's
coming got machete there CAU way that's
how you do it man yeah all right
so happening okay 60 bag I'm hold
this nice I like it I like it we going
to have to do the thing
first
um and then we'll put them we we'll let
this sit for a little bit and get
cold cuz I think that uh right now it's
probably pretty warm
resin I'm going to have to show you guys
this there you go that's so nice isn't
it that beautiful can't you see that I
mean I know I can cuz it's
like just want to give you a little
closeup
all right here we go CH it's always a
good idea too to look at your bags when
you're about to use them and make sure
they're clean if you have a bunch of
dirt on the outside of the screen it's
going to go to the top of the next
screen and and all the way down so
always make sure the outsides of the
bags are clean you can also see there's
a band of fabric that goes around the
bottom when they're inside out that band
of fabric isn't there so this is how we
know what the right side is for the bags
also the label on the inside so when you
fold them over you can read it
properly and these bags are from Nepal
Catman do
Nepal home of some of the original
dreads in fact the holy man of India
sados really cool guys go figure they
smoke a lot of
hash okay so we'll just get these fit
tight usually they fit a little tighter
in the bucket but I don't think we're
going to have too much of a problem
these bags are stiff enough I think so
there we've got our seeve I'm going to
pull the blue one
out just a little bit and I'm going to
wrap the rest of the bags good job
around the
top and what this is going to do for us
is it's going to ensure that when we're
mixing and when we mix this whole thing
is going to spin I can tell you right
now hold it the resin or the leaf matter
I should say won't go in between the
bags and contaminate our hash
so that's
proper we got some
water we'll top this
up and then I want to get a bunch of
ice which is directly behind you in a
big bag I'm just U being so quiet here
because I'm I'm I'm hypnotized by the
smell of this resin smells great
amazing all right so
ice we go
hey's the stick coming
in ice picks work
well when you know how to use them they
do otherwise they go right through your
hand
hence I'm not doing this because there's
no first a station
CL and once again here we are our second
run of fresh actually this is fresh
frozen first one was uh some bubble has
and if well you can't see but there's
like you know 15 people behind us all
got the cell phones out they're filming
and we're educating them at the same
time we're educating you again it's
awesome isn't it h love
start cutting in here I'm going to cut
here can I start cutting you got the H
bu
um nice for some big chunks to fall in
there don't need to break them all down
to nothing
perfect I'm smacking it with some R
whack that was nice I like that it's
like a whole good
stick all sticked up all right so this
is cold now John this is real cold we
got a nice temperature here so you can
start pushing uh cutting those nuggets
down on there
I will join
you man we do this everywhere hey it's
pretty much we just fly all around the
world and hang out with cool ganja
oriented people and
uh make the good hash make the good
hash yeah I'm being a little rough with
it just getting it in there it's
okay want to get her done
it's the whole purpose you can feel the
cool air coming off of this bucket
incredibly it's already creating a
thermal clim it feels like air
conditioning we're in air conditioning
right now it's
nice this is some nice fresh herbs man
I'm just don't want to get all the stock
off of here they're just such nice
buns now we do see a few seeds in here
not much not many at all but um is
always a good sign you know a plant can
still produce melty bubble with seed but
generally we know this about the
cannabis plant um once it starts
producing seeds that it puts an enormous
amount of its energy into the production
of those seeds and I think that uh it's
pretty much factual that the THC
production goes
down so what he said so what he said
that's what he said oh what he said oh
yes
so yeah I'm um I'm not cutting anymore
all right we'll dump that bucket in
there so as you can see it's a hinin
bucket we were going to fill not full of
beer full of resin that was a whole idea
there's only actually a few more buds on
here but uh it's got to go in maybe
we'll bring a few buds home dry for for
Mr rare dankness Scott actually asked me
to pull aside four to six of the nicest
buds we found and uh well obviously the
nicest buds we found are in this bucket
right now but the next nicest buds we've
put aside for you Scott so I hope that I
hope that's okay and for me by the way
I'll be smoking those nice all right
let's get some ice on top of that yeah
please so what I'm doing here is I'm
just kind of stripping it off of the the
stock here I'm pulling some stock on so
Bud like that and get this in here you
expose more resin we don't really want
to cut it up it doesn't hurt to pull a
littleit all the stock out of there you
know don't need it in there anyways it
doesn't have any resin on it
oh I want it to sit right on
top and that way we'll get it into the
water uh this is something that's
important too when you're using the
fresh material it'll float up it won't
want to go down so you can put a layer
of ice and a layer of herb and then put
more ice on top and then another layer
of herb and you just layer it and uh
what it's going to do is right now those
crystals those tiny little resin glands
are freezing solid right now and so this
is uh this is the magic of the
process the magic comes from out there
we finish it off in
here that's real magic Magic's right
there growing out in that beautiful sun
good stuff I mean I don't think I've
ever made bub I don't think anybody's
made bubble house with a field of uh
fresh weed in the background I have
nice I've done it in Switzerland next to
five football fields of outdoor cannabis
in the north of Switzerland in volosen
near Zurich um literally whatever the
size of a football field is picture six
of them right next to each other and it
was just cannabis as far as the eye
could see I've also done it in gra Hill
West Morland uh Orange
Hill where was the other place I did
that was a ganja
field I'll remember there's three places
in Jamaica this is my fourth one I've
done it in a field and it's always in
this Hut with uh well you guys have seen
the photos on uh on my Instagram and
Facebook all right Johnny that's
probably pretty good I'm just freezing
the resin off my hands cuz it's just so
sticky right now it's
like awesome yeah I've got that going on
too I know so I fig the ice might do a
good job but no apparently not app I'm
high no come on of course you're high
actually why don't we have a
bowl yeah there's a a bowl sitting over
there I'm going to grab the pipe and
have some hash or what I'm going to go
grab it um we're going to let this sit
for a few minutes generally one of the
things about water has although you guys
probably won't have this problem but in
the rest of the world the Turing content
is sometimes well almost always never as
strong as the tropical grown Sun that
you can get in environments like
Jamaica so this
resin generally in water can leech out
some of those smells and tastes so we
don't want to leave it in water for a
long time so that's something always to
keep in mind that
it's unnecessary to leave the resin in
the water too long right now we're
cooling it so that's important we're
kind of trading in one for the other but
you wouldn't want to forget about this
for a long period of time and go do a
bunch of stuff and then come back and
mix it and then leave it for a much
longer period and come back the water is
going to start acting like a solvent CU
of course water is a solvent it breaks
things down however this is a
solventless process which my good friend
Nic I don't know if you guys know about
selecta Nic he's a Colorado DJ pretty
good guy does the uh he call calls his
he does water hatch like this but he
calls it solventless and he gets into it
with people cuz they say actually water
is a solvent and then he has has to
explain to them that this is a
mechanical separation we're not actually
using water as a solvent however because
the water is going to be a different
color every single time you run um water
hash there is a process being done that
is like a solvent the water is leeching
things out so with that said what do you
think Johnny should I start mixing up
the medicine start mixing up some
medicine I get the to on and uh someone
want to maybe just check the
clock and mark down the time and we'll
uh
start 128 130 128 CL 130 okay perfect so
we're going to do this for about 10
[Music]
minutes and that's doing that I'm going
get a half ready and
[Music]
oop
see put a little bit more water in it's
a bit thick bring up that level a
bit Yeah thin it out a bit Ah you feel
that now yeah now it's moving better it
was too
thick more ice though when it's too
thick like it was you need to put a
little bit more water in that'll melt
the ice so then it gets too thin then
you got to put a little bit more ice in
you'll find it's a fine line on sort of
learning these subtle nuances of of
these variables that will change the
game for you depending on the
temperature your environment the
humidity the
herb all right well we're going to mix
this up for another 15 minutes I'm going
to turn the camera off so some of my
friends can help me but we'll catch up
with you in a few minutes once we've got
this batch mixed
up all right so bong break we got to hit
some hash we've been working hard here
we've got the materials all sitting it's
ready to pull we' got our small clean
bag this is something that you might not
be aware of but when you're making uh
bubble hash out in the middle of the
hills you're going to be required to
clean your bags so what we've got is a
bucket and the bucket has
um ice in it and clean water so once we
pull the bags immediately we're going to
rinse them really well washing them
almost with our hand and we're going to
keep the ice mixture in here high so it
doesn't melt away that's going to ensure
the resin stays cold and breaks off the
screen easily and goes into the bag we
don't want that resin dehydrating and
melting to the screen thank you Johnny
oh no problem oh I I did it you got the
the lighter wet I got the Flint wet I'll
let you light the next lighter got one
too right here every
agent thank you oh yeah
so this is a little bit of a bubble hash
we made the first day we were
here third day here now and uh we're on
our second
run all right so let's do this let's so
we start with the 220 bag this is how we
separate the Chafe from the
resin and I'm just going to reinsure by
holding here that nothing gets pulled
apart
wow there's that color that we talk
about it's
creamy yeah it's creamy golden it's a
beautiful gold and you can tell we
definitely ran about a half PB yeah
that's awesome um that's what fits in
these bags generally when you've got a
big most of this is ice nice I got res
dripping perfect oh excellent you want
some more oh please that Cool
Breeze it is the
73 so how often do you get washed with
resin and I take a bath in this stuff
that's
beautiful M and I can definitely smell
it okay so can you hand that off to one
of our friends and we'll get that either
poured into a plastic bag or wherever
you want to it has to get cleaned out of
the bag right away that's the that's the
key so we need what it could be thrown
away literally we could throw that right
into the bush or if you want to save it
and try to make coconut oil use the
resin you can save it as well but if you
don't want to I understand all right so
that's the bag that bag will need to be
flipped inside out and then rinsed maybe
with a bottle of water to get all the
herb off and then it can just be
hung all right so
160 this water's clean John very little
contaminant got through that's
beautiful all right so first bag
red color on that that's pretty cool
it's 190 I
know all
right
so generally this bag is what we call
the contaminant catch it's not what
we're looking for but at the same
time have to spoon it's important to use
the bag in order to get this out of the
hash that we're going to collect
later John I think you need to wash this
in the pool water here we go so cleaning
the first bag right now oh no don't wash
that in here it's dirty it'll stick to
all the we have to rinse that with a
small bottle of water someone can rinse
this with a small bottle of water just
regular water all right this is cleaning
great want to hang that one
Johnny just go right there and we go
right
across all right so 160 next next
up not expecting much in this bag either
this is a very large size Micron I
suspect due to the sungrown nature of
this resin we're going to find smaller
heads and uh that doesn't surprise me
too much once again this is really more
of a contaminant bag than anything so
when you see hash that looks pretty
decent you're happy about it I already
going to be very happy to see I already
know what we got on the first day and
this is definitely
substantially nicer
herb substantially nicer herb however of
course the herb always looks the best
when it's
fresh growing in the sunlight oh my God
those plants were so
nice so listen if you're thinking of
going on a vacation anytime soon I
suggest you get yourself a set of Bubble
Bags a
medtainer and get yourself a ticket to
Jamaica this place is growing the fire
and all you people that come here and
say you can't find good resin that's on
you don't blame
Jamaica so is that cold enough you like
more ice
[Music]
that still lots of ice which we always
say keep it cold the colder it breaks it
off so that's how we're cleaning the bag
leing that at the at the last little
place we visited there uh the other day
that's uh rubbing the ice on the bottom
of the bag actually well oh
yeah like
that know it's
G perfect perfect that made my hand so
cool look at the color of that water
John look at
this it's got a tiny little green in it
too from the Fresh that we ran you know
so you got some gold we got another
little pile of
120 after this bag is the bag we expect
to start seeing some resin in now keep
in mind we ran fresh herb the other day
we ran dry herb and we ran a lot of it
so that dry herb I suspect was more than
what we ran this time but we'll see when
we get the next few bags
no did more
weed
more
okay it's
a maybe we'll see when we pull it all
out did you see the herb
herb was K yeah but you know what it
like we have a lot five plants lives
like that is
probably even by what I would say about
was in the bag is probably about i'
say really you
say all
right try andang that
one getting into 90 the 90 didn't really
pull much the other day though the 73
was amazing this one's pull look at that
there's this this 90 has nothing in it
no joke pulled right out makes me want
to pull the microscope out and make sure
the bag itself is accurately 90 however
the 73 is going to be epic it should be
cuz it's we did the same thing the other
day this is way less 90 than the other
day well half weight PL that's in
there
see one two three four
wash that in
there in there can you wash that one my
hand is cold it is cold in here guys and
I'm going to step over here instead of
not being in front of the camera and uh
yes that always is good for
sure all right so this one's feeling
heavy we already know it is so this is
what we're looking for now the other
ones I pulled them out immediately right
so remember yesterday and the last time
how much resin we got on the 73 well we
already know it's here I'm always happy
with 73 hey I'm wearing 73 you know
that's going to be the best bet
right definitely going to be one of the
best must have a puck of bubble has in
there too because this is slow draining
I can see it
smell it
too we want try to stretch that over
this maybe try and collect a little bit
better pull out a little leaf
I just a little
one all right so in here
as the wind kicks
in so we're going to show you this
bag see how much resin there look at the
quality of this resin and now the 45 and
the 25 what we're seeing with the these
tropical sativas is just so much more
that's what we're popping on is the 45
and it's killer so and and and like
killer and the 25 because we haven't
microplan it yet even looks better than
the 45 and we' been talking about can't
wait to smoke on that 25 and when we're
back at home with the indas the 25 isn't
anything that's that great but um that's
what we're looking for right there
that's beautiful
we can get another drawing screen and
close that one up if you
like I'm put top
[Music]
all right a little bit of resin on that
73 but not too
much yeah
but put the last one on the hook and
I'll tie each bag if they're touching
they're not drying if they're not
touching they're drying so this right
here don't do this so why you call
Yellow 7 Tre what do I call them why you
call it the 7 Tre why did I call it the
73 yeah born in
1973 it's my year okay
I not and it just happened to be the
best I don't know how it happened but
truly for the longest time the 73 was
the one we all wanted I personally at
home love the 73 and the 90 the black
bag is one of my
favorites all right so the 45's coming
down it actually pained out pretty fast
John well I know there's a lot of hash
in there but
so as you can hear everybody in the
background is really enjoying
this here's our next poll
guys it's
breing once again
all right this little pile of
45 now we could have stayed here all day
and ran literally I didn't realize how
little or how much the plants would be
weighing but I bet you this was less
than a half pound that we ran just from
the resin
[Music]
really important that you clean your
bags good when you're in the hot humid
tropical environment the resin can stay
on the screen and each time it'll build
up that resin will start acting as a
solvent potentially break down your uh
screen and make it a little more brittle
what I've seen in Jamaica when people
have given bags to haven't taken care of
them uh they let them get wet they dry
them in piles like this so the water
never really dries out the wind needs to
go all around and dry it out if they're
stuck together like this you'll get a
little bit of moisture stay in there
what happens over time is it degrades
the qu quality of the material and the
bags become uh you know less effective
in their use you know you had them it's
hard to keep keep care of them here keep
clean yeah hold them
black got to what we got to hurry up
okay any we're hurrying
up well we only have one bag left so
it's easy to hurry up now I was like
this is the one I watch your
this one's big so you know there's some
resin in this
one a lot more
[Music]
than ganja
class ganja class yeah well the reason
why this bag is having such a hard time
is whoa how's that for a little
explosion sometimes you got a massage at
the bottom of the screen
there we go that should be enough to
start now that was actually a really
good example if this just has resin in
it but if you let your screens get dirty
this is what they'll do they won't un
they won't release the
waterly so this is releasing now which
just means it was a lot of
water and hopefully a lot of
resin right if
[Music]
any it'll go right
into the other ones are in nice and cool
yeah
awesome so yeah we've taken I don't know
if John mentioned it but we took the one
pressing screen full of most of the
bubble we pulled already and we put it
inside the cooler box our cooler that we
have uh the ice packs in so that'll
ensure that this doesn't get too warm
also this stuff would stink so bad
they'd smell it like 20 ft before you
got to the
roadblock so good to put it in there and
make it cold so they can't smell
it freeze cuz let's be honest we don't
need to be buying them breakfast
nice little pile 25 nice and
dark you open it right now
e
CLE right you can put that in the
uh in the styrofoam
anything really nice actually yeah
perfect last but not
least all right so that was great little
fresh frozen field run the first of many
this is just our first little example we
just did a five gallon batch we weren't
sure if we were pulling a pound we
weren't sure if we were pulling a half
pound I suspect it was just a half pound
or a little less but we'll really be
able to figure it out by the amounts of
resin and uh oh we can show you that
right now what we got there you
go so of course what we just pulled on
top give it a little little show here's
the 45 and
25 nice little pile it's about 3 G of
resin there lift that let me do this for
you
perfect there you go all right and then
our other two piles
which uh you can see the 73 is that
monster pile right there and uh that's
really what this is all about this 45
and this 73 is really what we came here
to get today so I think maybe put this
underneath of that there do whatever you
like brother there we go so anything you
like set this up for you all right
so I guess now all there is really to do
is to dump the water that we've that
we've already used clean up the pales in
the environment and we'll take this
basically now the unfortunate part of
this process is it's really hard to do
anything with this now in the
environment that we're in we need to get
it into a colder air conditioned room
and what we'll be doing is we'll be
microplaning it with this tool right
here there you go and so this is a
microplane right here it's just like a
little grater type tool most of you in
the audience probably know and we just
grate that down the same way you would
grate Ginger or cheese you're going to
grate that hash and that hash is going
to fall all in a powder and rain down on
top of your cardboard we use parchment
paper upon the cardboard so it doesn't
stick to the cardboard and you don't
lose any resin and it's just a matter of
kind
of you see it fall like a dust and you
just allow it to collect and spread out
everywhere like you're painting on the
parchment paper so you cover everything
uh that from that point here in Jamaica
it doesn't take very long before the
heat of the day um just evaporates any
moisture that's left in that resin and
it really uh dries the hash pretty fast
so I won't be surprised if we're smoking
quite a bit of it later tonight but
definitely by tomorrow and the next
night when Tony uh and Scott arrive uh
they'll be puffing some nicely dried um
full Mount bubble hash that's fresh
frozen field fresh frozen field dude
always a pleasure
Johnny keep watching Bubble man's
world all right guys well we were just
on our way out we saw another field on
the right side of the original field we
were in so we thought we'd just sort of
do our final goodbye here at this
beautiful West Morland ganja field how
you feeling about your first ganja field
visit
John wow and how's that joint this is
right from this field and it's um it's a
blueberry skunk 10 12 years of it
breeding in this little area it's just
amazing like I can't can't say anything
else other than wow if you were here you
would understand the Goosebumps and how
I feel and and this beautiful look at
the ocean in the background you just
can't get over it's just gorgeous yeah
the waves slapping up against the coast
behind us we've got some fresh vegged
plants deep in the back and then forward
here in this little patch we've got some
plants that to me look like they're
going to be pulled in the next couple of
weeks tops yeah no it looks like a
couple weeks they're definitely rocking
it here so I guess we're going to uh
take off we're going to head back to
Kingston it was a nice day in West
Morland I wish I could have said hello
to Negril but next time and uh let's
head home man actually let's head into
this field let's head into this field
5 fo 6 foot tall
there for
all right make our way home
[Music]
see they
you look at this one right here straight
like aist
this is like amazing you know that
we'll never
leave I'm sleeping here tonight
it's time we
go as we leave the Field of
Dreams goodbye Field of Dreams this is
the Field of
Dreams right
there going to do our last
moment thanks for watching Bubble man's
world
peace all right do
it yeah he got the one that you put on
the table that cuz you thought everyone
had
one no no no
a gja
planter call me the gja
farmer
[Music]
gja big stinking helicopter flow through
the with them call call we never did
when me was in water when we didly
fertilizer yet out of the sky Spitting
Fire and I'm ath man with a hot temper
dig up stinking rocket launcher and
theop
G call me the G
yes I'm a
G call me the
g
g make get
meditation give it to sick patient make
get no medication and so them could have
BR new medication mixing
get some inspiration and so them could
spread
message a
g call me the
g
g call me
the
G come
g g g if you don't want to call it call
it s if you don't want to call it call
it
marijuana
g
g call me the gja
yes I'm a gja
plan call me the gja
farmer
G it's
10,000
one
[Music]
one call me the f
G
[Music]
g g