[Music]
how's it going po TV viewers this is the
bubble man here live in negro Jamaica
hanging out at the new Royal itall
Kitchen that is actually yet to be
opened this going to be the juice bar
back here and we're hanging out with uh
with Buffalo and red a Rastafarian Elder
who's lived in Negril for jeez as long
as he can remember we'll let him tell
you how long it's been but uh he's going
to be making a Jamaican steam pipe for
us today what we're doing is we're
trying to get to the uh The Roots origin
of the vaporizer pipe vaporizers are
quite popular these days amongst medical
users but also gaining popularity with
recreational users as well and uh the
some of the most efficient vaporizers
are hot air Delivery Systems that blow
blow hot air over the Cannabis
vaporizing the resins allowing you to
inhale them as a vapor rather than a
smoke so as far as I'm concerned I've
yet to find a more original vaporizer
than the steam pipe in Jamaica as the
history goes I heard that a friend of
the skunk man's came here in the 70s and
was turned on possibly even by Red to
the Jamaican steam pipe and he went back
home to California to try and sort of uh
figure things out and see if he could
make his own version uh with with the
help of technology and the skunkman
offered him uh the idea of using a heat
gun and thus the vaporizer heat gun idea
was born and so many ideas have sort of
branched off from that idea I thought
wouldn't it be a great uh great thing if
we could show the viewers at pot TV the
original vaporizer so we're going to
introduce you to Red here who's hard at
work already and he's uh he's making the
steam pipe what's up love all right how
are you doing good doing good say hey to
everyone at pot
TV thousands of people from all over the
world who have access to a computer will
be watching
this yes we are now doing one of
the steam pipes as U my my good
friend B man says right now I'm
doing I'm making a
clip and this clip it's like a
um we use this for um for taking up the
fire the hot
cold so we put the bamboo
together but hello you want to work with
me find the end of this please come on
and get yourself a picture here you come
on Buffalo you find it in okay
so I'm making this
clip
than Nic
see what I'm trying to do now is to get
this
together all
[Applause]
right that's
it natural clip for picking up the coals
huh
sweet as you can see we're in Full
Construction here they're leveling
leveling the ground as we speak starting
to look
[Music]
good all
right so this is the
clip you take your hard the hot so hot
Hots that's they call it cold but cold
it don't get cold it get hot it get hot
nice we say fire cold but it's really
not cold it's fire hot fire liquor it's
hot red red hard okay
Wicked all
right I know what we need we need to hit
the Chalice we will eventually one sec
that's that's from cool liquid the glass
blower
yeah he blew this chalice hoping that
someone very much like yourself would
get to take a lick give thanks and
praise to bless the fight before we hit
it absolutely so give thanks and praise
for the hands that provide the herbs or
the as that we use in this [ __ ] and that
we will continually be prosperous Absol
thanks R give thanks bless so
here
bless
any hole yeah one right
there
boom nice
bubbles full power that's all right I'll
grab a little hit
myself all right here we
[Music]
go left
in I fill it up for you my man
right ready for
another that hole is silly huh it's for
a left-handed
person
bubbling doesn't want to go try this
side yes doing the bubble right before
the
steam all right give thanks bless yes
the steam piping
so we are making the main
ball you said this is the maale piece
yes this is the bowl the bowl
okay this is
that collects the water oh
okay
exactly
yeah
okay so this is a
steam this is a steamer a steamer it's a
common different of
bamboo one joint so we're going to make
a hole in here through right through
right through here yeah I noticed it
wasn't the hole on the bottom was all
the way through but not the top
no
there nice strong blade yeah good blade
make a
[Music]
hole so when's the first time you
yourself saw a Jamaican steam pipe red
the first time I saw a steam pipe
uh first time I saw a steam pipe
was H 19
uh
7 I
7475 nice a friend of yours showed it to
you no they have uh original
um give is the
original give is the
original
raster a rter camp used to be in Harbor
View in Kingston
mhm and
um so that's where I got the idea from
of the steam pipe he was making them
Elder Asters used to to they used to use
the steam pipes wow because the average
people on the street did not know about
steam pipe yeah even still even still
and even most of the young RS and
otherwise didn't know steam p
right but the Elder rers knew of steam
pipes okay so they used to use their
steam
pipes well I had known of the of the of
the uh the other pipe that we call the
chill out right but I did not know about
the steam pipe
until about
19 75 7 between 74 to
75 then I got the friend of
mine
rer by the name of um
[Music]
Batman
he taught
me he was the first
one who taught you how who taught
me about this steam pipe how to make it
and how to smoke
[Music]
it's interesting it would be neat it
would be interesting to find out you
know from some of these people that you
learned it from if they if they uh you
know where they themselves learned it
from you know whether it was developed
here in Jamaica or whether it was no no
I have
seen I have
seen I've seen photographs of steam
pipes in magazines African magazines
really I've seen steam steam pipes in it
and um Ash I've seen Ash um Ash pipes
several tubes around where they have
they have steam pipes that are being
made that these have five or six tubes
that you can can draw from Wow right
interesting right so it's an African
thing beautiful you know in Africa they
really don't
smoke well no that's why I would have
guessed it was from India or something
it's it's a it's it's a Indian African
thing oh whatever it is it's a beautiful
thing it's really um in a sense
it's it's harm reduction yes it's very
isent it it reduces
smoke but Steed it's a nice
thing so this part that you're making
here is is the main
part this the bottom part of this
consumes
water right mhm which that's where we
put the um the stem in from the
bone oh this is great for me cuz I
really have to say I've never seen an
original style bamboo Jamaican steam
pipe it's Hardy anyone it's mostly
resters that know
about mhm have people does it and and
the young rers go all I'm
one in NE that show even my my um my
neews and things like that right they
make Steam
P right and steam
p
i
[Music]
so now this got to get a hole in it
mhm getting closer down
mhm so your family's been here in the
grill for quite some
time I I was born
here was I was born right by by the
Royal Kitchen here nice
that this all that land my parents
land even where you are over on the
other side my parents saw that they sold
it we own the whole thing up up to
berville and you were saying when the
hippies came in the late 60s and the
early '70s it was here in NE grill that
was the first and only place in Jamaica
to at the time to
welcome them yes because um when when
when the hippie start coming here you
know it's like they most of them landed
like M if they even land at Kingston
there was some vibration that draw them
to
NE right which was a small fishing
Village at the time just a small fishing
Village and but and we were young
wresters at that
time right right and the thing about it
there wasn't so much other people
here that means when they came
here we were the first first ones that
they met and we were very honest and
start showing about we used to be
cooking itel food beautiful right so
they were interested in
um in learning how to to do it you know
and then and those days the hippie had
us to
hide I us to hide really from the cops
because they'll be here and over stay
and things like that mhm so we were the
one to help them to help them
hide from the cops and the mountains and
things like that some of them run out of
money uh resters
were very generous more in those days I
think you know sure so we cook and
we or maybe there were just back in
those days there were less um divisions
and less wolves and sheep's clothing
there was there was there was no W yeah
this was a very small group of of rasers
w right red you know there was no Woods
that at that time
um yeah let me R
[Music]
it cutting a little hole in
there yeah yes has to receive the
stem but it's a way to do it if you
don't know what you're doing it doesn't
work properly I can believe it I'm
looking at watching you do it I can see
the way the bamboo splits
lengthwise right you don't want it to
split too
much and after you have it on an and
roof and it apparently seems
like you want me to find you a stick or
something to stick in there not
right
[Applause]
all
right so you've made a few of these
haven't you R oh [ __ ] once a guy let us
made about
600 I didn't give a
[ __ ] he stole all the
money what you do
sp well we're going to put this one to
good use I said we'll put this to good
use we'll get it fired up and we'll
stick a few sticks of uh of ganja in
there and
away will
go find a
[Music]
bambo
see
[Music]
it whittles down nice doesn't it
yes doing a nice even
job should fit right
in
okay put the hole yes it's on a slant it
is yeah you see this I doesn't cut it
down that way I give it that slant that
we could get it in and down that it
could go down in the Water right all
right sure if you don't get it down into
the water you're not going to get any
water filter all right
but you see here you got to cut
it like
that
ah have it opened up ah so when you
bubble when you dry it doesn't go up it
bubbles it bubbles around right right if
you put it there you going to pull all
the water up in the p b you understand L
of them lot of people pipe doesn't look
draw good because they don't know about
this a simple little procedure is quite
important okay that's the down stem but
now we has a um this will be the
bow that the ash goes in ah that'll go
on top of the down top so I should do
this first to fit that okay sure so we
did this both these two pieces
mhm now we're working on the
bowl we're going to work on the bowl
okay
well you're working on that bowl over
there I'll work on this bowl over here
that's
right maybe I need that little head for
you I think so come here
okaye no problem what's
up
[Music]
put the hot
World said
the after
[Music]
the careful
you
be careful how
you smoke pretty much
[Music]
every the should make a point on getting
information people
on up
right no no you need me over there yeah
do that one more for me
mind even all your
mind
okay you need me over
here
fire be careful how you
jump
[Music]
uhr
now you building from
the I
know now your sleep at a
night while your handsome do
we I tell you now
now
fire
care fire
[Music]
fire
enjoying yourselves now that's how you
been
T and while you
jumping
[Applause]
you I just play you
play I tell you now
now fire
fire be careful how you
jump fire bu
[Music]
JP
don't
like they might
your that's
great
[Music]
don't like
noar
[Music]
careful be careful making that piece
nice and
[Music]
smooth you want that pulled over block a
block half a
[Music]
block
okay
[Music]
[Applause]
got to be
smooth
[Music]
Randy can still hear his
music got SM a little H you know just a
little bit huh and what is this piece
you're working on here the bow this is
the
[Music]
bowl
b you never see that so hold that
up see that little
dead dead years ago
huh dead people
there
[Music]
okay so we do this get it really smooth
ah makes
sense so okay say you're using the bow
sometimes right yes sometime it is made
from real tough bamboo this is tough so
sometimes when you use the fire on top
of the bow it eventually Burns and
crystallizes and have some little olds
and doesn't draw good okay because the
pan is on top and ear is getting in okay
yeah so you then you take it off and and
you rub it back smoothly smooth it up
right so the stone is your friend
yeah bamboo the
stone so the draw is
good
[Music]
yeah steam gets you there than that cuz
steam is the
hash unadulterated with not no
contaminants it's in the
Purity St for okay so we can put a hole
in this all the way through yeah all the
way through
[Music]
okay nice sh we're bubbled
yeah
everyone done that
[Music]
before it's a nice thick blade though
sometimes the thin blades they cut you
worse These are
nice
yeah it was a gift years ago 10 years
ago now more than that
[Music]
yeah those lead seed up
we there
they want it
all
up down stem into the
Tube Man Too F too F and you too
[Music]
fat F get and to
thide and knock and knock and knock
knock knock knock knocking at your
door and they won't stop oh
no until they get some
your
back won't
stop won't
[Music]
stop
won't you stop you SE up in
your acting like
you don't know you don't know you don't
know what out the clock
justu I chat you are
chat chat chat
[Music]
chat
and knock and knock knock knock knock at
door and they won't
stop
making it fit
[Music]
tight
there
[Music]
the down
set if you don't do the
[Music]
all right
just smoothing out the bowl
piece nice and smooth soon we're going
to get a
[Music]
pan hey you want to be on PO
TV all
right I love days like
this get by the candle the candle I've
got the candle okay okay
now I'm making the holes in the pan
yes to put on the
bow to put on this right so you got to
watch
this make sure it's centered yes on the
circumference that you don't B over the
H
right
I'm starting to understand now this is
brilliant the original vaporizer right
here you you're are over understanding
now you now I'm over understanding and
this is true I used to understand right
you used to understand but now I
overand
okay all
right I'm F okay explain it to
me um I'm in
between I'm going to go take a shower
when exposed to my
uniform right
there fit into the water
piece got your Stam I wasn't aware that
there were so many pieces involved in
the steam pipe it's actually four pieces
yeah
what four one two three four and then
the pan five right and the clip six oh
yeah the
clip don't forget about the
clips or you'll have burnt
hands okay Mo
[Applause]
on all right all right so we going get
the candle see these SE yes I did get
the
candle brought you a
candle let's go get the ear
so explain to the people what you're
doing M I'm try to see it properly so we
can putting what oh tissue I see a
little tissue so it can hold against the
candle on the on the
band okay
[Applause]
yes
[Music]
[Applause]
light fire I got a light put one of
those guys
out every day that you rise up you know
that you're
trying
trying you're trying and trying
[Music]
that's why they call them
Elders cuz they no stuff and the
[Music]
problem
it so much problem facing the wax just
making it
airtight
[Music]
talk at you
latery Andy and trying to pay the
[Music]
be
get wax on you
no what was it
saying the good day
sometime good day when you
[Music]
make you got the f f
yeah now it's
gentleman every day that you rise up you
keep
[Music]
ony
andyy
[Music]
Andy
have patience and hold on hold on hold
on hold
on days are
long
when nothing comes
along the day he's
alone when nothing comes
[Music]
along have
patience
[Music]
use a lot just to make sure
huh every day that you rise up
you you're
trying I'm trying I'm trying I'm trying
I'm trying
[Music]
yeah
so now we're going to build a little
fire to heat it to heat up the pan so
it's clean fire clean fire
burn
[Music]
see how easy it is to start a
fire and the pan sits on top to get
fired
[Applause]
got his
clips
all right so any worry of any chemical
residue would be long gone from being
fired Burns Out you going to set the
coconut Embers up FL yes so what am I
saying um you could use up here what
would you use to make your heat you guys
Co um you could still use coals from
wood maybe cedar or Birch or one of the
woods Birch is it's not good it's a wood
yeah cedar cedar one of the
hardwoods any hard wood you could
it you got those Co you make Co yeah hey
you
can yeah absolutely just coals I like
the the Eyal way
though saying but sometime maybe you
know
absolutely some water in there yeah see
what's
happening the me are
r
I hear it
shouling little bit of leak or
noit
hold
you
doing feels good you fling yeah it's
bubbling up nice you
this what's that putting the coal in the
pan ah Coal's in the pan of course I'm
filming
it
now B man is going to steal yes
ma' I
bet
okay you can let him handle the camera
and watch his oh yeah if he know what
he's [ __ ] doing it's on this one's
on you don't have to do nothing all you
have to do is hold the camera
right you got give me that this lean
bubble this one straight put it put it
straight you all right now bub
man bubbling and that's bubble man and
reds there smoking the steam pipe not
smoking steam steaming steam Pipe smoke
is when the fire catch the herb but this
one the Fire doesn't touch the herb the
fire goes on top in the pan and the
herbs in in in the CI and he
steams this is
hot and you can see we got the purple
pineapple skunk there that's what's
going in the pie smells very
uh and we have um doggy around there and
Dogg is going to come and get the heat
off the steam
P that pipe there tough so you hold it
with the clips when you take your head
hold that no you put it down he's going
to put it down on the bamb bo watch
what's happening he going to sit it yeah
he's just going to sit
it that good
Reds by they
neat get
my for
side
[Music]
one
you less
up yeah
think
that's Vapor right so don't try
just nice and
slow
that was a beautiful
beautiful but that was a vapor that was
the beginning of a nice Vapor
head very nice and
thin I know it's going to get
thicker two hits feeling
good
mhm
mhm mhm come get
ready
mhm
Patience name
bless put through your nost and come
again get a good
one you got you
got the first one that that we got I
call that the king's hit cuz it's just
it's so light and just the essence you
know so this
take nice I'm feeling steamed
already Sweet Jamaica
afternoon which girl is
that you know that little girl there I
know that little girl yeah I know that
she's hiding she's hiding
away bye little
girl
this is some old school herb this is
like this this herb is the herb that
when I first came to Jamaica in 95 you
have to break up the her a little bit no
no man you just put him in man you have
to break him up you just put him
in put in I wasn't ring it
just bble you can steam the green herb
that you just cut yeah the green herb
that you just
cut I like to make bubble with fresh cut
yeah man the fresh one I'm feeling
Hy
right come doggy your
time fire bur cool for
fire what you mean in
man
[Music]
I think it's time for pass the steam
pipe to Doggy
now which little girl is that that Ste I
know that little girl this one taste
this one let me know what you think the
flavor is very different I know that
little girl can I have a
piece oh very
ni
sh no no
okay all
right so the Jamaican uh steam pipe is a
success to me the afro Jamaican steam
pipe as red calls
it what's
up looking
good
all right we ran out of
shells so we went and got a
coconut little a bit of coconut water
dripping out should we collect that in
the cup red that's that's a raw foodist
stream coconut water
fresh
yeah
all right good
thanks oh
[Applause]
man
yes the bamboo
yes no well this steam pipe's going
really good right now it's it's
borderline almost almost smoking but it
is actually still just steam you
just really
[Music]
intense definitely don't want to hit
this too hard kicks like a
mule no an elephant an
elephant clean it
out
yo
yes
[Music]
yeah Spirit you
unw our on the
mission showing the world
our spiritual un Warriers trting from
behind
ding forward at this
[Music]
time fre the mindset of the people chaa
children true true children seeking for
the via the way part to go through I am
I come to freedom freedom with a light
in the
[Music]
C Spirit you
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world of a
spiritual Warriors tring from
behind tring forward at this time
spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors tring from
behind tring for forward at this
[Music]
time