[Music]
overcoded C no interest by the media no
interest by
human no middle class person is there
some that perspective but where are we
today we been talking talking talking I
because a on why I'm actually here
because I respect the work and Comm and
what he has supported the group that we
work with but I really want to
contribute to another talk shop and I
for one don't believe that going to jica
is AC with any sense of urgency on this
matter I don't believe that
[Applause]
exec and I said this to many of them
there's nothing I'm saying their
back understand the vast
potential the magnitude of the potential
that this industry is about in people's
minds unfortunately it's about more
people just
and that is just the least of it the jur
of as to
what
what G people smoking under habit much J
I'm going to get into that today I had
my few Puffs while I was in JC 64 I'm
not more probably J
1970 I didn't see any negative impact on
me I was noted right
and I won't call the something
this they hold some very serious
positions in the society who used to go
upstairs and SC
her but talking about the the farming
implications I think all of us not just
the parli all of us have to be
Guardians that this industry is
protected for
Jamaicans and protected for Jamaican
Farmers I don't think everybody should
be excluded but I am just amazed by some
who call me and I welcome their Interest
Who
want about 500 Acres willing and wanting
when this thing going fre up when the
gate going fly I have
just who I would never have thought
of in growing this
product
so as you know we have the Cannabis
commercial medicinal research task force
and we spawn the gang of future girls
and producer Association I hear the word
future won't be with it too long but
what are the farming
implications all we going to make sure
it is protected for the Jamaican
farm and remnant conted final decision
but certainly in my mind in the first 3
years it has to be restricted to strict
the Jamaican farmers and it has to be
restricted in s otherwise those who want
to grow 200 Acres 300 ACR 400 Acres will
take over the industry they too must be
allow to grow their 5 ACR
[Music]
[Applause]
the Jamaican farmer understands the
industry from a international legal
understand from an international
perspective but from a legal
International perspective it can't be
that people should be allowed big
farmers should be allowed to grow 100
200 300 acres of this certainly the
people who need the product must
contract Jamaican Farm to grow their
product put their quality control
experts give them the kind of seeds they
want but they should not be allowed to
grow more than their own research era
and then they contract Jamaican
Farmers the farmers who Supply must be
able to through a Cooperative own part
of that Enterprise so that we're not
just producers and suppliers but we earn
from the finished product so if
hire is that valuable that up to a month
ago I was told by Dr law at is law was
selling more an ounce of hempire for
sending more than an ounce of
gold we want our Farmers not just
provide the raw material but we want
them to benefit from the finished prod
certainly the workers we have to dust
off ESOP employee share ownership Pro
programs that they get preferential
shares so it is not for foreign
companies to come in and say Yes grow
the crop for us and we make the finished
product and and not we they make the
finished product and the finished
product leaves Jamaica 20 times value
added 40 50 times and all we are doing
is producing the raw cannabis GI them we
have done that all house as we have seen
so this has to be
how should the money be used I certainly
support that has to go to public
education some it has to subsidize
development and research and some it has
make some people still grow food for to
eat I say to
you it is not that threat everybody's
just to go there in the same way you
have the farmers in s having Tomatoes Ro
you got D so it's not what you want to
grow it's what people want to
buy so
the the future grows Association is very
is a very important group and they have
excellent leadership and they have a
collective leadership and they have
people who are not restricted back in
political
conserns right uh because as I said
before very day when I became sure that
I would have a chair for more than 3 4
months and they have put a Le in place
that they are really studying the
implications of this
industry we also want to make sure
that most of things leave in Jamaica is
finished
products not the raw cannabis but there
a market for raw cannabis yes and in
many countries right now they are
selling their own stock as make on her
CU I call used to sell things as Blue
Mountain Coffee right and people are
marketing and branding all kind of
strong as jamaan which is not authentic
jamaan so there's a Marketplace for that
now the oversight
committee the criteria so clean and
straight for those who want to grow that
once you meet 1 2 3 4 five you get your
license
nobody must feel that to know somebody
nor a politician nor a good man it must
be open that the average jamaan the man
that use te blows and the lips right can
grow his strong
finally
finally I believe if the Jamaican people
are not mobilized to push this and you
believe that announcements our victories
as sincere as they may be and this is
what has caused some of the passive
thing that we just believe is going to
come but let me tell you my last
story in 1978 Dr Kim M shared a
committee and of that and we just
learned the other day there a 197i study
done and Louis found that study which
showed clinical evidence that the a lot
of the myths that gandja was universally
dangerous that once you use gandja you
were going to go man and all those
things and that has been univers Landing
for many years and know many people and
it's just last week has been coming out
again there's a lot of information about
that but in 198 in
1978 the the the Jamaica Council of
churches was opposed the medical
asso so that parliamentary committee you
could appreciate when 1980 n the two
political parties
wanted to take on in charge the Medical
Associate Jamaica United States of
America all of
that an inside story I made a
fundamental mistake in
1999 I was in a different room a
different time about to move a
resolution for a certain party to
legalize call for the legalize from G
and the members of that party were very
interested and very militant and we're
going to pass that
resolution and I was told don't do that
because and the shabans committee was
set and that committee did some good
work fell short but many of us who were
there R silver
that was a good first thing but as deiz
was a half step like when gave the
slaves apprenticeship not the real thing
yet but still move the thing forward so
I wouldn't accept it and that sat down
for 10 years nothing
happed I am saying to you if you
understand and appreciate how important
this thing is it's one of the pl
of the National Economic recovery
program and of Local Economic
Development thousands of jobs Commerce
distribution allow people to grow their
own plants for their own own use that we
must not wait until the government is
ready right we must agitate we must
Advocate we must
insist and then we can start F and then
family will have reputation for
thank you very
much I like the idea of of protecting
our intellectual property rights because
that is s important if it's high grade
gandering our next speaker will expand
these issues you look at the economic
implications of a ganja industry because
if in fact if in fact it is as high
as 140 billion US doar I can't even put
that in
J if it's that our future is in
Gant but we would need to have an
economic framework what kind of
incentives would we need to put in place
to have fair play I mean what sort of
incentives we need to have to get people
involved in the industry and what kind
of regulations would we need to put in
place to have Fair place so everybody
can come and sit at the table and what
kind of financing mechanisms would you
need because from all that we have heard
today it's good business but it is
expensive business it's not easy for you
to get into the market well uh Mr Tony
vura Who currently runs the day-to-day
operations of the act now program will
tell us will give us some thoughts as to
how we can or or what are the economic
implications of the gandra industry he
he runs the day-to-day operations of the
ATO program patient care programs
product development accredited training
protocols quality insurance continued
education and overseas all marketing
efforts Mr vuro is the founder of river
rock Wellness with sever medical retail
cannabis licenses in Denver Colorado
that's the place to be if you love ganja
but this is where it began this is where
the real this is not where began I never
cor that but this is where the good
stuff is
as a former general contractor he has
managed projects in excess of $100
million with an emphasis on state
tostate operations Tony will be working
hand inhand with our Affiliated Partners
to Ure a smooth transition into the
United cannabis family and will be
coordinating efforts to optimize their
Global operations Mr gra has been
featured on CNBC mon talk Washington
Post and Publications in Culture
magazine Tage magazine and High Times
ladies and gentlemen it is our pleasure
to have Mr
Turley who has been on CNBC and other
places to tell us today about the
economic implications of
[Applause]
[Music]
the well I was checking my notes in it
it didn't say anything about liido or
the female plant I wish I had that
subject my mine is a little more cut and
dry I think it comes down to a few
things and I wrote some notes down
here it comes down to awareness it comes
down to timing it comes down to
standards regulations Brands and
Community what do I mean by that is how
is how aware is your community how aware
are you
about medical cannabis hemp social
aspects social responsibility of using
cannabis in a recreational way it's your
awareness which is what's going to
expand the economical impact how where
are you and how willing are you to
accept the entire plant and its full
spectrum capability of helping people
and and having a place for industry and
also having a place for responsible
recreational
use so the uh timing is also an
important important issue because the
rest of the world is changing around you
so depending on how fast you act and
this particular time and I mean timing
within 90 days to 6 months and I know
that's very very very fast for everyone
in Jamaica but you have to look at what
some of the other professors and
principles from UI talked about in
timing of what's going on in the United
States what's going on in Guam what's
going on in Canada Uruguay
every country around the world and at
one point Jamaica had the ball and they
weren't first we all knew that that's
what the Rosses talked about that's what
music talked about then there became
prohibition a Prohibition spread in the
United States and spread around the
world many people went to jail many
people sacrificed their lives and so
today is that opportunity of that timing
so you can stand up as an entire nation
and not fight among yourselves and and
find those solutions to to where you can
help every aspect of life in every
department so that starts with standards
so if everybody wants to be part of
these products and everybody wants to be
a part of what's going on you have to
stand within a community and you have to
build that like uh Paul Burke had said
before I came up here so that's simple
that's creating a standard a standard of
waying to grow a standard of your
cultivation a standard of your resin a
standard of processing and creating
local branded products by the people
that are here through a regulation and
Regulatory system that also opens up
more economical impacts once you're able
to do that then you can have localized
branded products that are actually made
here like you have your Blue Mountain
Coffee not the raw not raw cannabis but
actually products that are finished and
made here and branded here and then
exported to the rest of the world that
has vast huge Community impacts not in
not in the billions but in the
trillions that's the truth because if
you accept it and you're aware of it and
you understand that there's industrial
medical and social aspects of this plan
and you embrace it and you turn the rest
of the world on to you and you
understand that you have to study it in
a scientific aspect and debunk all of
the different myths or the different
solutions or the different things that
you've seen you have to find the most
effective way to use the plant possible
for all three of those categories so
that's going to affect your economical
impact so those are pretty big
statements and why do I say that I say
that is because I started on the floor 6
years ago like anyone else less than
$200 six lights and six
plants that's how I started so I had no
economy I had zero and so I was a
patient and an activist and somebody
that had a mission to help myself and to
help the other around me so I also been
through opiates I've been through
painkillers I've been through car
accidents I've been yelled at I've been
told I'll never make it I've been
disowned by my family all of which did
not come true I just kept pushing
through so that's how I started River
Rock and in 5 years we we developed uh
both indoor and outdoor cultivation 300
different strains in house and we've
created actually I've created a program
and that's what she was talking about
with the acel program which is utilizing
all full spectrum of all the cannaboids
85 medical of that in its raw and Live
Form not utilizing activated THC so I
eliminate THC in the entire program but
I use the acid forms of T andc this
developed into a widespread medicinal
outbreak if you will in Colorado so what
ended up happening was we didn't help 3%
of the nation we started helping 8 80%
of our population with effective
effectiveness of 90% so the list of
immune autoimmune and Central Nervous
dysfunctions we are able to address
without any psychoactive experience
whatsoever utilizing the full plant and
it in its full
Integrity we also legalized cannabis so
I need a round of applause for
that so in that process I also went
public and I took all of these products
and all these inventions and these
things and these ideas and decided to
implement them in state by state since
we weren't allowed to cross borders so
we still have prohibition going on and
in doing so this allowed us to
infiltrate into different territories to
set up this information and use part
terms and localized growth and
sustainable Community projects that
allow us to grow within this is massive
in massive economic impact and this all
comes from how much do you want to
accept this do you just want H do you
just want medical ganja do you want to
accept the social and the recreational
aspect in my opinion having all three of
those and taking your time with that and
understanding how to actually create
those regulations and standards and
following the lead of everyone that's up
here that saying those things is the
most appropriate way so you have to
think of this as an industry with
training farming education testing
careers banking it's humongous it's not
in the billions it's what's going to
save multiple Nations and multiple
places but what makes Jamaica
unique it's not just the vibe it's not
the high
grade it's the people that want to make
it you actually want to do it that's
different today I spoke to Children
about wanting to get involved in
cannabis I don't get to speak to
Children about cannabis the United
States so this starts early and it
starts with
[Applause]
you uh thank you very much Tony for your
very inspirational talk on the value of
Gand well Paul said that nearly well
several years ago that the jamaic
Council of churches opposed the whole
business of gandra they didn't say lick
them Jud Jud lick them Lord they would
have said that polite church group but
the Bible says that herbs are for the
healing of the
Nations um so I wonder then what with Dr
Gary harot who is the secretary of the
Jamaica um Council of churches say on
the matter of of gandra what are the
biblical and moral issues well Tony gave
us a clue Tony says we must have social
responsibility when it's our
children Dr Winston de says if my young
son who is 10 smokes it it will affect
his memory and his learning that's what
he says his research is showing are
there is that true is is is his research
right well he says yes we have done real
studies and that's what he showing well
Dr Gary Harriot will tell us what what
are the biblical and moral issues
related to gja he is a minister of
religion of course he is or was ordained
in 1991 and he has served the United
Church in Jamaica and the Cayman Islands
in a variety of capacities both in
Jamaica and the and the grand kman since
September 2006 Reverend haret has been
serving as general secretary for the
Jamaica Council of churches an
ecumenical body of 11 Christian
denominations it doesn't include the the
independent churches but nonetheless it
cares the Catholics the Baptists the
Methodist the angri Reverend har you're
a family counsel and family counselor
and the broadcaster you should tell my
child whether you should really have it
or whether my nephew should be smoking
gandra at 20 as he goes to University or
whether this country should embark on a
process of change where real poverty
could be solved if we could harness the
resources from Gano and make several
products and make real Income At Last
please join us at the podium to tell us
about the B and
[Applause]
more thank you very much um good evening
everyone it's really good to be here and
to be part of participating in this
[Music]
conversation I am not going to present
an official position of
JCC and I must say that it is not likely
that what I will say will represent the
view of the church in
Jamaica but I have in preparation for
coming and sharing with you I did
reflect with some of my colleagues in
JCC to hear their thoughts um on this
matter and
if those responses that I've gotten well
they seem to be indicating Paul that
some conversion is taking
[Music]
[Applause]
place yes and I suppose the church like
many
others
um lack of full information and
knowledge when you do not know something
it creates it has a way of creating
anxiety and fear and so forth and I
don't think the church is is is
uh is perfect and therefore you'll find
that happening as well but I I shared
some thoughts with some of my colleagues
or got some of their input as I prepared
to share with you and I want to begin
by where we
call creation
Theology and that is based on our
understanding of the creation narrative
where in Genesis God created the heavens
and the Earth and he said it is
good and the psalmist in chapter 24
captures it very well when he says the
Earth is the
Lords and
everything that is in
it so from a faith
perspective we believe that the universe
is
created by God and that God has
entrusted the
stewardship of its resources to
humanity and since
Humanity or human beings are God's
stewards we are accountable to God for
what we do with God's creation amen and
therefore we should not abuse God's
creation we must use it in ways that
enable
life in ways that Empower human beings
and the rest of the creative
order marijuana then is one of the
[Music]
resources and our
scientists and their Knowledge and
Skills are among the gifts that God has
given to
creation and to us human beings and they
too like the rest of us must Endeavor to
be good stewards of the resources that
God has given to us
so it is
appropriate to give thanks to God for
our scientists the discoveries that are
been
made and that all of us together must
work at protecting
Health well-being and the economic
empowerment of our
people love and
neighborliness are important principles
of the Christian faith
as such we must be
concerned about those who are anxious
about what decriminalization and
legalization May mean and the negative
impact it could have on families Society
in general and especially people who are
able to speak from their own experience
of how it has affected them or how it
has affected their families so we must
do all that we can
to protect the vulnerable while making
good of the resources that God has given
to us in fact for us that is a moral
issue that you must protect the
vulnerable and Dr Le has raised some of
the
concerns Justice and I hear Paul
speaking to some of this but Justice is
another important principle um for us as
Christians um we consider it unjust
where the negative side of the story is
what is
highlighted and has prevented the
scientific exploration over these many
years to advance in the ways that it
could have
advanced
and what we see is
that our greatest critics if we're not
careful will deprive us from the
benefits and if we allow that to happen
if we allow others to
manipulate the
possibilities and like other things
where we export and then have to turn
around and import that would be
irresponsible another Justice question
surounds and again I hear Paul raising
that the fact that over the years it is
mostly our poor black males who have
been dragged before the courts for the
use of marijuana
now if we're going the route of
embracing a more liberalized approach we
should ensure that the wealthy in our
land are not the only ones to experience
the significant benefits from the
industry Hallelujah we should
ensure that it is so
structured that the
ordinary organized Dominican people can
also benefit
from
it there's issue of greed that we need
to watch and that's a moral issue as
well that sometimes there's a tendency
to want to get the most out of it and
put the least in it and so we would need
to
ensure that greed does not allow us to
sacrifice standard and quality and so we
need to ensure that all the necessary
inputs are made
so that we maintain proper standards um
of the product thank you very
much when I must say all I can say is
amen really I think this was an
extremely balanced presentation
[Applause]
on our final presenter is Mr Courtney
Betty who will tell us about the
medicinal tourism
implications currently Betty is a lawyer
but it's a law he's a lawyer with a
conscience he's a lawyer that has a
social has some kind of social
responsibility he he has gained an
excellent understanding of the legal and
Regulatory frame at the Department of
Justice in Canada he has also had a
successful track record of contributing
to the development of Jamaica having
served as a former senior legal council
of Affair of trading commission and he
helped to pave the way um to have the
deregulation of telecommunications in
Jamaica Mr
Betty will is has played a key role in
advancing the development of medical
marijuana industry in Jamaica and his
model of the green gold triangle he tell
us what that means the green gold
triangle maximizes the opportunities for
Jamaica by creating Partnerships which
ensures participation from all sectors
his vision for Jamaica is to utilize our
natural herbal resources to create
health and wealth for our nation ladies
and gentlemen let us invite Mr Courtney
Betty to tell us about
the thank you
good evening um as I heard Paul speak
and I was just reminding him how long
ago we actually started this battle not
as long long as Paul Chang I got to
recognize Paul please stand up Paul
Chang and uh for the work that Paul has
done really on the on the whole issue of
social justice and uh that work has been
going on for many years with you Tom
about Peter Tosh or many of the others
that are really being at the Forefront
um as a lawyer uh sitting um and looking
at the opportunities here in Jamaica was
very interesting because as a lawyer you
start off first with your legal mind and
what I discovered um was that in
1974 the laws of Jamaica actually have a
provision that excluded medical
marijuana from the definition of ganja
it's a really interesting situation
because we're actually one of the first
countries that I'm aware of in the world
that actually has a medical marijuana
provision from back in
1974 and it was a result of that that
you have individuals such as Dr lockart
that presented this morning and Dr West
that were able to develop amazing
products canol and
asmol know so it was quite a surprise as
we're now going through many years later
trying to put in place a illegal and
Regulatory framework I've been fortunate
in working along with Haw Thorne from
the initial
process looking at the type of
submissions that would go to
Cabinet um working on with the Minister
of Justice who in his presentation of
the first document that was tabled
recognized the work that uh that time
has sit down in trying to look at a
potential legal and Regulatory framework
and what I saw was a couple of things
when I started on this I saw
Israel started after Jamaica but they
had moved this so far Advanced they put
place a legal and Regulatory framework
they began all the scientific and
research development that was required
they own the vast majority of patents if
you go and you search marijuana patent
you're going to be shocked how many
Israeli companies actually own those
patents I mean they're very far ahead so
my vision which we launched here in
Jamaica on May 22nd was to really
combine the the research the technology
that has been developed the common
practices from Israel with the greatness
of Jamaica or actual goods and products
that we're able to grow here and bring
it to the international market and we
called it the green gold triangle and so
as I looked today we didn't P we didn't
trademark that one but I'm glad to see
that we're here at uh at the green gold
green gold conference and so we move
farther because we had a particular
Vision having worked here in Jamaica
having worked on the community level on
many different projects I don't need to
to mention them specifically what we
wanted to do was to create first and
foremost a common
infrastructure that all Industries and
all people in Jamaica could actually tap
into so some of the things that Tony
mentioned for example testing facilities
and ha had mentioned as well being able
to um distinguish the amount of C CBD
versus THD all of those infrastructures
actually now in place at the University
of the West Indies through a partnership
that timeus has put together to form a
herbal medicine Research Center at the
University of the West Indies the next
partnership that we went to we look
forward because we really thought it was
important to ground ourself in some
history was the Maroons and colonel
colonel lumson is here with us today now
looking at setting up colon Lon you
stand up please as best I can as best as
we can and col Lon came to us with the
project with a project aimed at tourism
for the Maroons community in Portland
and so we've been assistant working with
them in terms of getting that rural Echo
System uh tourism project going the next
initiative that we look at we'll talk um
was tourism outside of mono Bay and with
Dr William Courtney and his wife
Christine and others we're looking at a
medical Utopia where people can come in
from all across the world particular
senior citizens and be able to get the
type of treatment that they're not going
to get in the North American environment
the type of medicines the type of herbs
if you look at Dr Janice fiser one of
the leading experts on medical tourism
and St stem cell research and the work
that she's been doing in mono Bay we're
now looking to enhance that so the
opportunities from a tourism standpoint
again you know it's a challenging
situation because we're trying to
separate recreational and all these
other elements the medical tourism side
internationally is one that has
tremendous potential and people will
come to the shores of Jamaica people are
now coming to the shores of Jamaica uh
as Dr lockart may have said people are
coming here and importing canisa into 23
countries so there are things that we're
already doing the goal is not to
reinvent the wheel the goal is to see
how we can build put the proper
infrastructure in place to be able to
move this ahead thank
you to the point but effective
thank you so much Mr Betty for your
excellent presentation on the medicinal
tourism
implications aong is such an interesting
place Charles is
too Charles well all of those areas
because you have such a rich history a a
rich Heritage Rich knowledge that now
can be used in a in a very sensible kind
of way ladies and gentlemen we' have
heard from the panelists they've given
us some idea of the medicinal and health
implications the scientific implications
farming economic biblical and moral
implications and finally the medicinal
tourism
possibilities what have we heard that
203 million users use ganu G 203 million
persons use
gandu um currently I see that it's $140
billion it's that's a business with bed
products but
Tony Zur says no you're looking at what
is today you're not looking at the
possibilities you're not looking at the
future and if you look at the future
you're talking trillions when he said
trillions my eyes saw dollar signs and I
thought about the health of the people I
got so excited about Simon and the
health implications on all of this but I
people like
uh Dr Harriet and Courtney Betty says we
need regulations we need to have an even
and careful playing field we need to
make certain that we can have what we
want and minimize the negative impacts
because Dr Winston de was not afraid to
say there are possibilities you know but
let me caution you about some of the
negative impacts you don't want to hear
about it you think I'm a Dooms but I'm
going to tell you anyway and so he told
us what are the possibilities what you
call cannabis induced
psychosis you see things you pretend you
see you think you're hallucinating your
out of body experiences I say wow and he
said you don't want to have that and if
you're a kid you don't want to take it
but still the P said we need to have B
let us see how we can eradicate poverty
develop viable business bu and move on
while minimizing the negative
impact and then again the possibility of
medicinal tourism in Jamaica well I'm
sure you have a lot of questions so I'm
going to open the floor now for you to
ask the panelist and to share your ideas
on the possibilities of simia caner
cannabis hemp Mar or whatever you call
it is it really Jamaica's green gold
okay the floor is open I see someone
waving
here vanity prevented me from putting on
my glasses so I can see you in the
black can you me I think there's a
mic oh there you go night everybody um
it Mr Tony
vse okay I'm just going to call him Tony
um he mentioned something about timing
in his presentation I just wanted to
find out if anyone can shine some light
on where we are in terms of Regulation
getting all of these things up cuz what
was it 6 weeks to 6 months he said um
can we meet that kind of T do you know
anybody um can we get some assistance
here might is the mic
on you want to come to the podium
started that
problem so yeah and timing is everything
I can't speak to your regulations cuz I
don't I don't like to take political or
government involvement in any type of
political stuff or regulations I just
lay out my opinion and what I think
people should do and how it could impact
people on all
levels but I will be on uh USA Today and
then later on on Vice um that's on TV
talking about what will happen when the
United States reschedules cannabis to a
2 three four or even five and they will
they will reschedule it eventually so
there's elections that are coming up
what ends up happening is when the
United States makes that move and it's
no longer a class one so THC would not
be up there with Heroin would not be up
there with cocaine or acid as everyone
in this room knows it shouldn't be not
even smok in a spliff should be even
anywhere near that so when they change
that that has drastic implications on
what can happen in the United States
currently clinical trials are very very
difficult to start
universities uh professors and and
science communities don't integrate as
they do here and no one's all for that
so therefore even someone in in my
position can't actually take
um the products that we're using to help
for cancer and epilepsy and seizures
chronic pain opiate dependency things
like this we can't just go test them we
can't just go to the local University
and ask them to get involved and help us
with that so the moment they change that
is when the opportunity changes so if
you if you don't act as a as as a
country upon that in the
next I said 90 days to 6 months then
that window starts to shrink so I think
you have 6 months and then that window
starts to go away now do I still would I
still uh think that the economy would
still boost if even if you made the
changes absolutely because people want
to come to Jamaica I want to come to
Jamaica I don't want to right right now
it's 17 where I
live if I could if I could take part in
medicinal herbs and all kinds of
plant-based medicine and integrate this
with canav oids I would be here so
people want to come here even patients
want to come here this is Paradise this
is going to open up tremendous amount so
you want to act upon it in a very smart
and intelligent way as soon as
possible no no
no no
[Applause]
just just to add to what um Tony just
said and um in relation to the question
that you raised uh unfortunately you
missed the earlier session of the the
the presentations but uh we had somebody
who made a presentation regarding the
status of the dangerous drugs act and uh
we were told that hopefully by December
of this year it should be in Parliament
and you know we're moving on track to
get it sort to go as quickly as
possible okay next person uh the
okay good night night everybody just
before you answer May invite persons who
want to ask questions to do exactly what
you did to come the island and use the
mic in
the go
ahead I I would like to ask the the
creators of this conference the the
theme of the conference is medical G and
I would like to know what level of
consultation there has been with the
medical fraternity considering that
neutrals are not necessarily traditional
medicine and as such but canol is not a
neutraceutical so there is spere for the
use of carabids in terms of as a
medicine what is the level of
consultation in terms of this kind of
conference with the medical fraternity
or the Ministry of Health or whoever
there is that controls medicine in this
country is there anybody who wants to
take a
question
um there really has not been any level
of consultation with the medical
fraternity conference such as this is
really designed to get ideas rather than
Consulting a particular group you s it
open to get ideas like yours and
everybody's that is put into the Melting
Pot and recommendations are put forward
so the conference is really designed to
get information and to give
[Music]
information okay Dr de do you want to
say anything oh all right good evening
everybody I have been
noticing with all that is going on that
the manufacturing part of it is already
set we have been asking the question how
are we going to get the government to
work faster to
make production legal because
the manufacturers are right them set
right medicinal ganja is already on the
team but we need the farmers cuz you
need the produce you need you need a
product to work for and to work with
right you need the ganja to do your
extracts you need a ganja to do whatever
you need to to to to make your
products our problem is if there is no
farmer then you're going to have a
problem in getting your stuff you're WR
material right right so what I am
suggesting is all
the producers of the various
products come together with us as a
farmers and press the case along with us
make the government know that if you
Don't Legalize the farming no we won't
be able to produce anything to export
from Jamaica
so if that doesn't happen we are still
going to be here talking
talking right so this is the suggestion
to you and I'm sure all the farmers are
in agreement with this that all these
people who are producing the products
should come into the game with us or put
some petition to the government saying
if we You Don't Legalize the farmers no
then we are going to shut down CU we
won't be getting any raw material to
make our
products that's
why really interesting comment I must
say but I think the government kind of
is a little interested in it the days of
resistance are over as I understand it
I'm going to ask you young man if you be
kind of enough have Kel speak before you
yes you in the blue blue jacket or black
jacket
I I asked I requested that I I sign
until I I I speak because I I have
beyond what the country needs and
sometimes you have to think about
yourself because I do have a personal
problem situation but what I want to
speak about is uh uh uh uh uh Mr bet is
uh talk about um uh
tourism medicinal tourism or tourism
that could generate from uh uh uh uh
medical marijuana marijuana uh uh period
we have a uh a tournament a wrestling
tournament with the former own
communities in Charleston on the 6th of
December now we have a magazine out of
uh America that said that they would
fund
this
tournament and would
guarantee a certain number of people
coming to the uh tournament the the size
that would make Portland as a tourism
destination get a significant boost
however one of the things that they are
are requesting is that there be
some
something that says that when these
people come to uh Jamaica within the
boundaries of char ST which is clearly
demarked that they would not
be
harassed the 6th of December now aong
aong gets the same thing on the 6th of
January 6 might be something you know
the ancestors what but the 6th of
December and I'm wondering if
the government can't give us that money
to put on that
[Music]
tournament and we are suggesting that we
are trying to find our own and we're
wondering if the government would help
us in this in in some way shape or form
to to to to to to
satisfy uh these people
that
indeed we could get a away just for that
one day nothing just one day get a
waiver of a waer that we not the people
that come to char for the uh uh
Tournament Wrestling
[Music]
Tournament can can can can smoke within
the defined boundaries of
char I'm not so sure if there's anyone
at the table who can speak to me but any
take we will note
request but I'm not sure anybody can
give a commitment at this
time
suggestion next next um person good
evening to the panel good evening ladies
and gentlemen um I want to preface what
I'm about to say first by saying that I
only heard about this Gathering the
conference on the radio Nationwide
I have absolutely no interest no
business interest in it um I am
completely and totally against
recreational use of marijuana having
seen what it has done to a few persons I
just want to start here having said that
though in Jamaica we have a way of
blocking the road when our roads not
getting looked after by the MP I think
this is a good cause to block the road
because if half of what you all said is
really so with the type of money that is
waiting for Jamaica to exploit then this
is a really good cause to block Hope
Road tomorrow
morning I'm going to ask let me preface
the rest of what I'm about to say first
by saying I'm also a
Christian no but at the end of the day
at the end of the day the lord gave us
as the Reverend said all these things
for our own betterment so as I said I am
completely and totally against the
recreational use of this
drug having two young daughters myself
now
question when has Jamaica
ever um taken and held with both hands
an opportunity like this when the people
did not intervene and get radical about
demanding that the government does it so
if we go by our history us sitting down
discussing it as you all said earlier
where these things have been done from
10 15 20 years ago will change very
little I listen carefully to um my
brother from up North who said that the
window closes or or starts to shrink in
about 6 months that means we have to act
now Mr Burke I think you are uniquely
placed and positioned considering the
governing Administration to hang on to a
few persons and say here ye here ye this
is the chance and the window is closing
so I would really love and know sorry
for preaching so long I'm I'm I'd really
love at the end of all that is said that
a very clear course is charted as to
tomorrow morning what is it a person
like me who just interested in Jamaica's
betterment because it is not is not a
business interest for me it's only about
what can how can Jamaica benefit in the
long run so I would want to hear over
the radio tomorrow morning if I must
show up down half Tre to help block the
road I'm willing to
[Applause]
come and so say all of us but I should
tell you brother I'm not just in it for
the health reason in to I'm in of
[Music]
the thank you very much um good evening
brothers and
sisters um my question is for Paul I
don't know if I heard you
right when you spoke about the size of
the fs are you saying that we should
limit the production in terms of the
size of the
Farms are allowing people to have
production just up a certain size I
would like you to explain
that I have been very
consistent that in the first years of
the
industry that you have to allow the
small
farmers they place on the plane field so
they not go home because if the problem
is to make manufactured production or to
go abroad then scales of economy dictate
that those that own 200 Acres 50 acres
100 acres 500 Acres would be the person
engaged in the contract if you force a
situation where only small farmers can
grow in the first 3 years it means that
who wants to come in the industry has to
engage a small farmer and not a big
farmer so that the big farm and the
small farm on the same platform can only
grow one acre 5 Acres whatever the
amount is for the first 3 years then we
can review and decide what is if we ever
make the
mistake of allowing those who have money
to buy a license pay by acreage you're
going to find that this industry is
going to end up for the big big Farmer
and the traditional farmer is going to
out what people are going to tell us is
that we're going to lose some economic
Advantage so be it economic Advantage
for who the big farm was never
involved I
believe honestly that unless you protect
this small Farmer at the outset he or
she is going to be a c to
um let me just say this that I been in
farming for a long time very poor person
coming from
Grassroots and I do not think we should
limit the productivity in any area in
agriculture listen to me
carefully I was president of the Jamaica
be Farmers Association B fun be and a
lady came here from New York and she
said
let me see the kind of honey that you
have and we say okay we know that to
make a l honey is the best so we gave
her a sample to take you know what she
said to us how many trailer loads can
you supply after she tested it we have
not replied
yet you can't so you see 3 years is a
number of hours we we talking about we
cannot limit productivity for 3 years we
are a country of samples we have to get
out of the idea of saying we are going
to produce this into our home we have to
expand and begin from the beginning if a
big person has a th000 Acres what we
have to do is to make sure he pays tax
like everybody else for the benefit of
the country we cannot small farmers have
to be protect it cuz I am one to you
have to protect the person regulation to
protect but in terms of production if we
are going to limit it to this small
amount but if the market outside wants
to take the rest of it we have to
produce for the market and the market
wants it here we are Jamaica we I I
agree with you and I believe in
cooperatives 100% I farmed a few so that
is important we have to protect the
small farm
but in terms of productivity we have to
make sure that we maximize our efforts
and there a simple way is to allow
everybody at the same time to increase
the acreage they can grow that is all so
when you decide it goes from 5 to 10 to
15 is for
everybody right so as the production
grows you study the market and you say
well everybody know instead of having
one acre 2 acre 3 ACR whatever it is you
can now go up to five you can now go up
to 10 but it can't be that a big man
because he owns a land and I'm not
against anybody a big farmer uh can grow
50 acres 100 acres when a small farm
doesn't have that capacity allow
everybody to grow allow them to get land
from the government that is Idle small
farmers and encourage and Empower that
group to grow so we can debating it and
I'm sure we can find a Middle Road
solution okay but there is much cicis in
and I've heard it that small is going to
be sold
out and let me tell you it is going to
be a major
backlash if people in the communities
and across jica feel that now that the
industry is open that is not open and
fair
term again FS
well might very well be cooperatives but
then that's another Point ton you wanted
to respond I wanted to add to that so
when we talk about he said that we might
be uh limited economically I actually
don't think so I I I think that you can
do this with a happy medium and they did
this in Colorado too so people that are
in the industry in Colorado actually had
had to live there and they had to be
residents for many years so you can't be
an owner you can't work in the industry
without have residency so in this
situation when you when and who writes
regulations it's very simple and you say
that you can only hire
local farmers that are certified and
registered through whatever local
program you would have so therefore
anyone that has whatever size land has
to use local farmers so therefore
everyone that works in farming has a job
so if somebody has a market demand for
something that demands more than 5 Acres
well you have to expand that within the
community so part of what our program
was about was utilizing 5 10 and 15
acreage and the smaller farmers and
giving them guidance and giving them
things for free and supplying them with
the tools the genetics and the
information of how to do it better and
so forth that increases the value of the
medicine that increases with the demand
and that increases with the actual
income which that local farmer will make
which will then turn around and spend
that back on the community so I think
you can do it you just have to all
however the system works come together
and figure out how to keep the community
locked and involved some other companies
that will come here and we're what he's
talking about is company's bigger than
what I would be considered and I don't
really consider myself very big big but
somebody like fizer or somebody that
would come in here they would bring
their own uh system their own labor and
that could happen and you can get
extorted out of a lot of things and you
want to prevent that and so you have to
figure out mechanisms very simple with
labor and with the
farmers okay we take the next person yes
Gan this is um ganja juice raw ganja
juice and I am SS
help people anyway but
anyway farmers and protect the farmers
big farmers and
this they have lied
am something like
that think sometime say the citizens
have limited amount of tree where them
can plant one two or tree tree they have
something like
that no so the citizens can't plant any
amount of tree all citizens no no no
what what what Mr B was saying Paul get
want get it before in fact in fact
instead of telling Mr B story I Paul B
say what he wanted
to there are two situations there are
people who want to go into it for bus
yeah and therefore there must be some
regulatory system how they enter the
business yeah but I believe also that
each and every individual yeah who wants
to grow for their own personal use uhhuh
not for commercial purposes should be
allowed to grow a certain number of PL
and for his her her own personal use I
don't see why somebody who wants to use
it must be forced to go and buy it
perfect so
what is that limited amount you have any
idea I don't know I would let me I heard
rumors talking about five can I tell
have a view even for the start to allow
people without any license without any
regulation within the confine of their
home boundaries to be able to go at
least five trees I'm not five trees hold
on hold on hold
on hold on
I am
not the number the bigger point is I
don't believe
yeah we're not talking about those who
want to grow
commercially so if you want to grow
commercially for
business that's a different
situation I am talking about un
license that people should not have to
go and get a license yeah to grow for
their own personal know
that I don't want to debate no we not
debate want the
principle established yes Ma and that's
the principle I have pushed we get it
clear but you hear me say all right
going say going say the five tree
business I am I'm a ra food c times I go
extreme raw depends on how the man play
Flow you know what I'm saying but right
now say I make a juice called raw herbal
Cell Anti-aging anti- cancer Gand juice
been working on the ground through
tourism for I have people come from the
state we pay 3,000 us you know what I'm
saying to get that 21 day anti- cancer
activation right now in Jamaica we're
doing it you know I take it to the
street right now you know what I'm
saying so anyway what going tell you now
and if you don't go like this it ain't
going to work
medical gja this what I'm saying can't
have five treat reason why medic G
have with the citizens each citizens
Jamaica need at least three pound of kja
fresh each day to make G salad what me
make you know what I'm saying and furing
at least so you don't want hold on hold
on I don't say it all I'm
saying
in the G what going be selling it ain't
going no difference from going to the
pharmacy you're going to have to have ch
I'm telling you with this juice right
here we don't need nothing more and if
we have three pound of ganja each day
three lound of fresh ganja will lick
away any cancer cells no no no hold on
so hold
on hold
on um first of all want that's number
one not no number two number two I get
your ideas no it's not ideas it's law
it's not ideas what I'm telling you as a
as a professional three pound of gja for
each citizens you know what I'm saying
from all of that the reason why
a pound of G when you Dice it up if you
don't chew it to make
a yeah hold on when you cut up you going
make a salad a ganja salad you need a
pound of ganja you going tread it before
chop it you know what I'm saying if you
want to do that you do
that listen this is the foundation you
going have to establish forid Tre pound
of gja for each citizens it ain't going
to work all right I take your point I
take your point you're right you're
right okay next speaker please next
speaker
please next speaker please yeah I don't
to that long I just I just think that
culturally we I like I like deal with
principl
people we ought to know Atlantis the
people who built Atlantis in Bahamas
they came to Jamaica first we really
have a serious problem with putting off
an almost anti
business we we need to have a culture of
I know it's nice to you know soon come
but everything we seem to do is always
just seem to put up and I think that
somebody suggested block the road that
you know that's one thing but the point
is that I would really like us as a
culture to get to to to the stage where
we we demand of our leaders we demand
performance and not talk talk talk talk
talk you know and and and um I I I feel
that what wherever the opportunities
come up the Avenues we need to do that
we need as a culture maybe doing things
on time and just and just put and just
said to them you have have you have
spoken
enough we away um too many we away too
many opportunities and I see every day
anyway that's I agree with you that
there's a fierce urgency of now but I
must suggest that two things one 10
years ago you and have a scientific
research Council having a meeting like
this where all ideas can contain and the
second thing is that remember that
minister paulw is the patron of the
Cannabis task force so it seems to me
we're in good hands he's the minister of
science technology energy and Mining
we're making progress but we have to get
it right and we're moving in my view as
fast as we can I see where courtly Betty
wants to say
something I don't want to be defending
government but the work that's been done
by Minister Golding in coming forward in
starting it's been
slow it has been slow but here's the
other part of it if we don't get it
right then all of this is lost that's
that's that's my view that's one point
doesn't mean that they haven't been slow
the other part of it is Jamaica
Jamaica from a legal standpoint is
different from many other places in the
world
because whether we like to admit it or
not ganja is de facto legal in Jamaica
there is a according to the United
States government there's 35,000
hectares of ganja that's being grown in
Jamaica right now so how do you how do
you try and impose a legal system on
something that's ingrained in the
society so there are some cultural in
sensitive years I'm not justifying I'm
not saying that there are not things
that they could have done but it's not
as simple as many of us would like to
think from a strictly legal standpoint
from the political standpoint I'll leave
that to others um I'm sorry Courtney and
I are friends colleagues but I have to
disagree fundamentally about getting it
right you can get interm legislation in
place and you can review it in two Fe
time you can allow the growing right now
for research and development you can a
number of this thing can be done if
there is the political will in less than
a
month the gun Court was put up in seven
days this thing can be done in less than
a month if you're going to wait to cross
every teeth and D every eye and go to
and you're going to wait another another
a year or two to get that legislation up
what you need to do is to put in
something interim and have the
consultations with the stakeholders and
you make it you upgrade the law and you
you add whatever it is but I am totally
opposed to this concept of getting it
right because it will by can we get a
grad wrong
under any law we the difficult easy part
is you can make regulation say listen
not withstanding section so and so we're
allowing so the minister to give
permission blah blah blah can I say one
thing two on that just want to add to it
had some experience with this so United
States moves really slow as well and the
way they're getting it done is they're
issuing little pieces of paper that are
provisional licenses and they take years
to dot all dot all the eyes and cross
all all the te's it took them 5 years to
give me not seven licenses I have 19
licenses 5 Years From the time I started
on the floor with three lights they gave
me a little piece of paper that said go
in the fifth year they finally caught up
to me and they said well how much
business did you do