[Music]
all right so we're heading into the
property
here heading into the neutral conference
I guess this is on the zoo property
is that correct no HK Gardens is on the
zoo is on the H Gardens oh okay and it's
just like right next door or something
yeah this is botanical gardens oh
okay botanical
gardens are you going to dance what song
was that show you my money is that your
song no that's a song from whiz kid
afria okay I it reminded me the first
verse of it reminded me of Desiree you
know Desiree with midnight Desiree is
killing it yeah she is that's a good
thing oh yeah my f favorite Desiree song
is fire yeah that's a good wake up song
Fire so good
absolutely no
vending you dare say
vending must prit these premises will be
subject to a
search all right we're cool with
that and R up for the
h I guess she didn't want to search
us she just couldn't be
bothered I needed this SE yeah just take
a quick spin around spin
around this is a nice place
eh yes he's my great
friend then bring a
new cheat on me well they brought they
brought her but you know kind of warming
up to
our yeah getting to know him this guy
look at this guy I'm off a drive like
this to the plant
nursery that
beautiful you know we won't be complete
in this cycle until we have some ganja
growing here in the hopal gardens and
the botanical
gardens here what's that iy
scam over
here been two years two years over it's
been 41 years and 9 months for me it was
Chinese look at the Chinese constructing
this over
here ni beautiful they got the
architecture down P live over here you
know they've been doing it for thousands
of years they got a longer history than
uh than a
lot it's serious
history right so we just got to the zoo
here hanging out with the zebras we're
going to head into this neutral
conference with our crew and see what
our booth looks
like the
Lioness no way this is where our booth
is Ash come on this is awesome that's
why I trying to tell you that man yeah
right where the land is right [ __ ] ly
by the booth what where's the lion there
that's the lion and this is our booth
yeah this oh nice little corner Booth
right by the
lion oh we could you know what we could
have brought the pop up yeah I didn't I
didn't think you we still could yeah
because it might do we want to do better
or worse it's all up to us we could stay
we
could we do a little walk through
here R Body and Spirits all right this
is good I'm just doing a little walks on
the grounds we going to go tops and we
drink tops Elsa's blend
teas ET
tennial pretty sweet
eh skin hair body starfish oils oil of
life I wonder what the oil of life
is we call tap let me take you take us
over there go over there
yeah all right
actually sing
right all right you got like you got
stable gun right yeah um actually has I
mean not actually
all right so here watch
right is this how you go
[Applause]
land a lizardy
I don't think I've ever even seen a
lion I feel bad for these
guys well there's a couple of dudes
there's a
bobcat that's no good Northern Bobcat
I'm not a big fan of
zoos I feel they're a little bit like a
well not even a little bit I feel like
they're a lot like a jail and it's my
whole life I've never really been big
supporters of zoos feel a little bit
weird at this
Zoo
wondering why people
see the need to lock up
animals but there's no doubt about the
fact that it's beautiful grounds really
nice
and what have we
here
hey what have we here
oh birdies pink
ones what's up
bird I'm not tripping you
out well mixed emotions here for the
bubble man mixed emotions I'm not a big
fan of zoos I just feel I'm not a big
fan of jails I mean maybe if there were
some bastard animals out there just
being real douchebags and then you put
them in jail then it wouldn't feel so
bad but just good animals that that
aren't doing anything just like getting
put into a prison it's depressing to say
the
least well I'm not going to let that get
to me too much we're going to head back
up to the conference and maybe maybe
I'll just stop visiting the zoo here
cuz well it's not a happy
place animals are bummed
who wants to be in
jail not
I some string
[Music]
[Applause]
want to lift it a little bit just cuz
it's low if you're going to stand in the
booth it's low right takes your side of
line of sight away needs to go up more
we can put we could put a crd one here
and a crd here we need a crd here crd I
need yeah we're going to have to go back
and get that no it's here but we have a
big stand we could put that would cover
the whole back of this and say you can
right
right look a lot
[Music]
better let's see what we got
sunspice Mark yeah go back now what's
that I'll go now and get it okay and
then um come back all right you want to
grab my laptop too yeah sweet I think
it'll be fine without the power cable
just the laptop so I can just open it
and show people the photos and stuff
just bring just bring a laptop right
just bring a laptop put it into its case
which is a zipper case and be fun
I'm com in I'm com
in and that is one tall
[Music]
woman hi how you doy how's it going I'm
good hi I'm Ariel and I'm
representing Sun spice seasonings here
hope Zoo today uh we're here with the
Bobcats not very friendly right now cuz
they're sleeping and stuff but yeah
they're pretty cool come on let's
go see I want one as a pet little
buddy he like twitched his leg you know
he's like yeah I'm here I don't want to
say hi but I'm
here very cool yeah sleeping well they
sleep during the day and they they're
basically up and about in the night
nocturnal so you guys have a booth just
behind uh just behind this just behind
yours right setting up sharing sharing
it with crd I like that yeah we pretty
cool people yeah not bad aome people
well I like sunspice seasonings cuz one
of the things that mauricea has in his
future is that he wanted to one day
potentially produce spices that are in
infused used with cannabinoids you know
like the resins taken off of cannabis
and then put into some of his spices so
I think that's pretty much one of his
basic futuristic ideas where he can you
know not just be doing just spices but
doing you know phyto
canabo yeah exactly no GMOs no MSG none
of that crap it's a minimal amount of
salt minimal very
itol this is your thing so this is a
pretty good place for a little like a
wake and bake for the herbalist yeah oh
yeah yeah oh yeah can see there's a big
sign behind here and I have it in my
hand that's it m well I'm uh I'm in the
same boat although I have to say I
appreciate the um Simplicity of the The
Joint the spliff you got to use the gum
yeah I'm over here and it seems a little
bit
ridiculous what I have to do but uh I
wish I had the camera filming when the
zoo guy came in earlier and saw saw me
with the Taurus in my hand and the
blowtorch
lit that was
uh that was kind of
fun there we
go and a quick
light I can't really show them with the
camera but you see what's on top of the
camera stuck to the top of my camera
right there by my thumb it's the Hat oh
yeah so yeah a little
he's going to heat that up and then he's
going to put it inside that's it dabbing
I remember last time we were here right
before we went to the Little Joe we were
at uh Chen's Place mhm and we went to
his backyard which was very quiet there
just around the back of the house yeah
and uh we decided well we're just going
to have a little a little
session hold this yeah I'll let you hold
this take a look at
this take a look take a look we're
dunking here at the uh
Zoo look at
[Music]
that
amazing can't say enough about the
mothership and the
tourus super pleasure to be here at the
uh zoo near the Hope Gardens the
Botanical Garden and uh you'll be seeing
much more from
us throughout the day throughout the day
throughout the
day see you in a bit
mhm
awesome what a small world I used to
work with him really like this what if
she Roars can she
Roar I've never heard like females say
anything it reminds me of a song by fa
anapo
CTI the Caged Bird
Sings look at him checking out her ass
just look just look at that oh wow look
at this
guy oh I'm focused on the CH oh her ass
is so
fine he just definitely is staring at
her hi remember me your
[Music]
wife this is incredibly you found
another woman in the two years that I
went
away he's like 2 years not one visit 2
years you couldn't pick up a phone send
a letter what do you want St for a visit
can't touch you don't answer your phone
you always goes to voicemail he's like I
want what everyone wants repatriation I
want back to
Africa yes
freedom
freedom oh my God you know what I'm
remembering that at the Museum What's
that Night at the Museum oh
yes you are so adorable what's up what's
up he was laughing with us he heard us
laughing it's like you're so funny I
think I'm going to spend most of my time
[Music]
here
awesome very cool we're going to talk to
these guys later too technosol look at
that they extracted the 100% extra
extraction of
lemass yeah essential oils this is the
no this is the extraction man right here
right yeah I do extractions as but what
I extract you know ganja what it grows
the medicine on ganja is an essential
oil we call it hash but it's not that's
just a madeup word to make it illegal
now that it's becoming legal really the
hash from Cannabis is just the essential
oil of cannabis and they have many of
the same oils present in cannabis oil as
they do in many other plants so it's
pretty interesting okay but um like
caropine I read something somewhere that
they don't necessarily
steam
nool exract well there's many there's
many ways we can extract um with
cannabis because the essential oils are
secreted out of glandular tricomes small
microscopic glands crystals that grow on
the plant and so we know through
different um knowledges that we learned
over the years
that we can um I use water and ice I
freeze those little glands I'm going to
show it later today and basically they
they when I mix them in cold water and
ice like just plant matter the resins
will break off and because of their
density they'll sink in the water now
that's how you separate the resin from
the plant matter in a whole
unadulterated form without using steam
cuz here's the one thing about steam
that you'll learn eventually it has its
place for sure but heat destroys the
tpin the the the the volatile oils that
make up the composition of the essential
oil those are affected greatly by heat
and how we know that is when you smell a
flower you can smell it at room
temperature it it smells really nice
those are volatile tpin evaporating out
of the flow that's why you can smell it
so when you heat anything you're going
to change the structure of the oil and
so that's why they use cold pressing I
use uh water and ice and dry sifting
methods and uh I think we'll see new
methods in the future that are involve
cold like a cryogenic process or
something that can preserve the oils as
much as possible but this is really cool
what you guys have set up
here so we have Lemon Grass bitter
orange you know Cil orange
yep bit orange very nice that's
[Music]
great all right all right I many need to
one of these thanks guys
[Music]
okay well I think it's time to set this
up Ash definitely a few so I believe we
should be coming to each of the booth to
distribute the launches in addition to
that um Minister paulwell who was
scheduled to be on the ceremony uh this
the at the ceremony today is unable to
make it so he's popping in at 1:00 um
for our breakout session and we should
be anticipating him in a few so we'll be
inviting persons to come around and
participate in
that right so just listen out for more
announcements and just we'll soon get
you refreshed in a few all right
[Music]
would have been nice
this looks good
SRC how you guys
doing right on uh you're from SRC oh
okay I'm from crd and you can have with
you guys
have the booth set up all
nice Hydro
distillation can you tell us a little
bit about Hydro distillation oh okay
it's actually the process by which one
of the processes by which you extract
essential oils from plants so it's Hydra
you're using water M and um you're
distilling the oils which are volatile
so what happens is that you immerse your
plant and it can be either fresh or it
can be either dried material you immerse
it in the water you have a heat Source
when that boils the um essential oils
come off as a vapor they condense they
in the coil yeah right they and they
collect in the bottom jar right this is
a Ultra so this is lemongrass it's
lighter than the water so it floats on
top I see I see so that's great and so
what about I'm I'm not a scientist but I
know that anytime we heat something
particularly volatile oils like tpin and
terpenoids that potentially were
changing their structures and producing
artifacts of their true molecules right
so it's the heat source is controlled
it's controlled heating you can actually
adjust the temperature so we we um we
get the oils off at very low temperature
and is this done under a vacuum as well
no it's not it's there's no need to be
it's all just open right okay and you
can always check the quality of your oil
when you're finished using DC
um or even the proton hnmr I believe
that they have at UI that be amazing
well that's really cool thank you for
explaining that I know the viewers on my
channel will really appreciate that cuz
right now there's a few people in the
community that I live in which is the
Cannabis Community um people are
desperately trying to figure out how to
uh extract the tpin from the plant
matter obviously this is a great way to
start the ball rolling and then start
using your head to figure out okay how
can I protect these volatile oils that
are evaporating at room temperature and
now I'm going to apply heat it would be
great if we could do it under a vacuum
under a much colder uh conditions and
still get the same job done that'd be
awesome
[Music]