welcome to bubbleman's world everybody
we are in st. Catharines Jamaica and I
don't know if Joe and I could be any
happier
I'm eat fresh fruit you've got a
breadfruit right behind you you've got
mangoes I see tomatoes down there
it's the yard is covered in beautiful
fruit trees this is definitely a good
buy place and we're happy to have about
a pound of some beautiful Sun grown
Jamaican ganja that's Sun grown tropical
grown glandular trichomes heads for the
bubble man and John to isolate using our
water and ice extraction methods so
John's been helping me for the last year
so and he's a good assistant and then
even better friend so and I can tell you
right now I'd be puffing on this hers
and it is killer I got a great buzz from
it wait to get this resin in this we
brought the originals nice yeah
we brought the original bags most of you
out there know that we have three levels
of bags we got our lights our
inexpensive model to get the the new
beam on hash maker perhaps the guy
that's kind of lost his way and he's
gone towards this making oil with
chemical solvents the exposure is
negative the potential of blowing
yourself up and burning your skin off
your body is definitely there and this
is I top this is in Jamaica this is item
there's no chemicals there's this is
just water and ice so this is what we're
here to do today isolate some resin
glass I'm gonna put the bat the the bags
in the bucket and get this started I
still wish I could be joining you right
I know but it seems in the best
I haven't smoked cannabis for 13 years
because I smoked exclusively hash I only
smoked the active ingredients in the
plant and every once in a while like in
this particular situation where I have
no hash I'm feeling it a little bit are
you feeling a little bit oh you know
what I'm definitely feeling that you
very fancy dad smells great so we're
gonna start with the 25 micron bag we've
got a bunch of people here and behind
the camera they're gonna stay off camera
but I'm basically time kind of talking
to them while I'm talking to you guys
we're actually milk yeah we're educating
them and then we're also learning
ourselves because we're out of our
normal environment so we're in a high
humidity high heat warm water
environment the herb everything's
different of a couple months ago oh is
it yeah okay so a couple months ago John
and I were at Barcelona Spain and we
were making some hash there you guys
probably remember we met with Xavier for
medical seeds we met from dahveed from
Ripper seeds we went inside the guys at
hemp quarters and we made hash all over
the place I mean so I think we're gonna
break that record here in Jamaica
oh we're breaking records we've been
here for half half the day and we're
already running our first first batch
which I have to say I come quite often
and it's always you know you're not just
gonna land and just go make hash and
land and then you kind of go get like
you don't go eat some I tell food and
then you
and you look for buckets and everyone's
got a bucket but not so much available
for you to have so we took this a couple
hours to find the buckets and we got
those so that's great we're five hours
in and we're making out yeah exactly so
the herb was completely easy I've never
had that be easier I usually have to go
out and really sort of put my nose to
the ground I have a bit of an olfactory
that's very sensitive to cannabis and
terpenes and smells and so I'm able to
find extremely good cannabis wherever I
go using those tools at my disposal so
when I hear people say oh I went to
Jamaica and the herb was so terrible
what I say to those people is that's
just what you could find that was what
your personality brought to you you
didn't put the right vibe out there so
you didn't get the right herb you know I
don't know what to say try to find the
right vibes you'll find the right herb
in Jamaica it's about that simple when
the vibes here are amazing
yeah well I don't know how you'd find it
all right here's a 45 micron bag for you
Johnny what we're doing here for
everyone watching because they
potentially never seen this procedure
before us we're stacking a sieve stack
this is like mining for gold this is
like if you think of these are screens
and they have holes in them and the
smallest screen the bottom the purple is
a 25 micron at a micron is a measurement
increment that is extremely small your
hair for instance is 7 microns in
diameter it's very very small smaller
than we can see with our eyes so we
start with a 25 and we go up with a 45
and each screen size from here on out is
going to get bigger and why that makes
sense is because the holes need to be
big and then small and then smaller and
then smaller and what that does is it
allows us once we've separated off the
material once we've mixed all the ganja
and the resin has broken free and sunk
in the water all we're going to do is
pull these bags one
i won and clean out the hash that's left
on the bottom of the screen there are
variables to pay attention to we want to
make sure our water is extremely cold
this would have been better if we even
left it in the freezer if you have a
freezer and it's sitting right there or
a fridge of course have it in there
right up until the moment that you put
everything in the buckets and you start
mixing that's going to be helpful when
you understand the process and I've sort
of given these guys a little bit of a
low-down on the glandular trichomes
glandular trichomes of course is is the
little part of the cannabis plant that
we all love it's why they sing songs
about it it's why we promote it it's
what it's why we wear ganja leaves it's
why we gather it's why people go to
Amsterdam people come to Jamaica I mean
really that is the reason this is an
incredible plant don't get me wrong the
industrial properties of hemp we know
have 50,000 commercial products from
anything from plastics to hempcrete to
have metals the amino acid rich
essential oil secreting seeds are second
to none they contain all eight essential
amino acids that our bodies need but
can't produce including the three for
children so this is basically a whole
food hemp is the perfect food they say
actually that it's second only to breast
milk I'm not sure about you but I'm done
with breast milk I'm sticking to hemp
seed oil hemp seed I love yeah you can't
get you know I mean they were good
enough for Buddha right how long did the
Buddha survive on hemp seeds one hemp
see today yeah for like a very very very
long time check out the story I'm not a
Buddhist but Buddha seemed like a pretty
cool guy I have to admit you read into
what he was all about and I mean it's
hard to kind of be anti Buddha
alright so 73 this is the gold bag and
this is just what you guys would think
what do you think about gold we love the
gold not the gold is in gold from the
ground but the Sun and the gold the red
gold and green the gold does not
represent gold in the red gold and green
we all know that so this gold I made at
the 73 micron bag this is the year that
I was born in
1973 and when I first made these bags
the 73 bag was the favorite
it was the favorite it still is to
appoint the favorite but I got the black
bag and the black bag is superior in my
opinion in every way this is my favorite
bag this is the bag this is the resin
that I personally prefer almost out of
any strains aside from perhaps a
landrace sativa a tropical Sun growing
sativa that isn't gonna grow short and
stout but it's gonna grow very tall with
a very thin leaf as opposed to a broad
indica leaf and it's gonna produce heads
that produce a different cannabinoid
profile now what a cannabinoid profile
is for the gentleman all sitting here is
the cannabinoid profile is the profile
of everything we love about ganja inside
that glandular trichomes head that I was
showing you guys earlier on that
glandular trichomes head has terpenes
which are smells terpenoids which are
taste so I mean obviously those are the
things we love those everyone loves
squeezing the herb and giving it a smell
I mean that's that's like the precursor
to smoking it to smoking and getting I
read is to smell your ganja you know
walking through the forest if you've
ever approached a big ganja field
getting hit with that the smell of that
is is a potentially spiritual event I'll
say that much about it
so let's get our black bag in there with
the yellow and we're gonna go from that
I don't think think I'm gonna bend them
over the bucket John oh you shouldn't be
looking at some beauty I'm looking at
how beautiful these try cones look elect
mark was talking about with what the
sudden growing tropical sativas these
resin heads are so small but just so
amazing yeah once again look at that
plant so I definitely very different
here grown
different soil different environment
different humidity it's something that
I've never seen a pulse like this I'm
used to growing in because of course
indoors we live in that Canada but I
mean definitely when we take a look at
this resin you can tell the difference
between night and day by just looking at
a Bowie outdoor and indoor in Canada
growing here on the equator yeah this
that the two joints I just spoke to big
fatties I feel great unloaded dated
right in that pain I don't think any of
you guys have ever seen me do this but
you know the best part of both is is we
take a look at the minute little effects
and I pretty much experiencing so of
course we're gonna try and break all of
this off of the stuff how does that feel
we are gonna break it down it yeah
that's the course quick question in
regards cuz I know you use indica that's
so we have indica and we have sativa and
of course Rob Clark the author of
marijuana botany as well as a wonderful
book called hashish one of my mentors
he's actually now talking about cannabis
Afghan ago
so you can look up that on Google if you
want to learn a little bit more about
that and yeah I guess we'll get we've
now put our 120 bag in and our 160 bag
and I'll explain to you why we're using
all these bags imagine that some of the
glandular trichomes heads are the best
and if we can separate them out and if
we can use these larger hold bags in the
beginning is often people say why do I
need all these bags can I do it with one
this particular bag in in particular
will filter out contamination things
that are still small they're gonna break
down a little smaller than they shut up
and they're still gonna sink whereas
everything else as long as it has a
surface area it'll float in the water
when things get too small they sink down
this is why I have this bag it's also
why I have this bag just to filter out
so generally these two bags will be a
medical quality although you know here
in
make it theirs they still actually
produce some some decent resin the real
magic will be in the orange the black
and the yellow and sometimes the white
and the purple can can really surprise
you so really these three bags are the
ones we're gonna pay attention to so
imagine we're gonna isolate all the
resin glands off the plants so taking a
pound we could be left with as little as
you know 20 grams of resin that's how
much active ingredient is on an actual
pound is cannabis when you extract those
20 grams we're going to get 20 grams
through all the different bags so if I
get a gram and a half here that's that's
no good I don't count that and if I get
another two grams here well I don't like
that either I don't count that either so
my 20 grams can shrink down incredibly
so once we explain this to the
prohibition based mentality of how much
can I get and how fast can I get it
which is where we've kind of been locked
with ganja for the last 40 to 50 years
at least the North America and Europe
parts of Asia it's a how much can I get
and how fast can I get it and we've seen
it happen here in Jamaica when I was
coming here in the 90s it was nothing
for me to find the lam spread it was
nothing for me to find the landmass to
Tevas it was very easy for me to do and
nowadays it's a lot harder you really
have to you almost have to seek out an
elder you know
you need to go to like Bobo camp for
anion thingy camp and find an elder
who's had his strain and he's kept it he
still has it because of all the growers
I mean and it's not their fault that
they fell into this because everyone
falls into this they grow these short
little sticky stock plants they're still
very powerful and amazing they do grow a
wonderful grade of medicine but if you
can imagine when Babylon had their way
and decided we'd make cannabis illegal
part of their trip was to make it how
much can I get and how fast can I get it
thing and what they did is they turned
us the people that believed in this plan
the people that believe in the
righteousness and the spirituality of
this planet they turned us into
modern-day how much can I get how fast
can I get it and I can't tell you how
many people have this mentality in the
cannabis daily and the unfortunate part
is is that when you shrink down your
flowering period to six to eight weeks
as opposed to a sativa which could
easily flower for three months you know
20-plus weeks you could flower a sativa
so you understand the prohibition of
space mindset how much can I get and how
fast can I get it is gonna be like oh
man I don't want to wear that's a team
that takes me 22 weeks to grow that plan
from start to finish I can bang out
these indicas in seven to eight weeks
boom boom boom boom while you're doing
one crop I've pulled out three that's
great but what you're growing is resin
and in that resin is a profile and that
profile is gonna offer you a medicinal
benefit and if you can imagine the
prohibitionist as brilliant as they were
and they're evil they cut us out from
our land race genetics the land race
genetics if you can only understand that
this is the equivalent of the world
population and when we took those and we
got rid of them and we started getting
smaller and smaller and smaller it's
basically inbreeding it would be the
equivalent of going and having a kid
with your sister don't do it you won't
get good gene structure you won't
produce strong plants and you won't
produce a good medicine you need to
bring traits and fee knows in from the G
Poole and this is where landrace comes
in this is where these African sativas
and these in Indian plants where they've
been making hashish for 8,000 years
these guys have a serious ganja culture
I have been to India I can and I can
attest these guys they don't even smoke
on that if you were to smoke ganja they
would just be so confused by it because
they smoke only the hash that's off the
ganja now they still have archaic
methods in fact they have the most
archaic method because they have the
longest history with this plant in any
culture on our planet and what they do
is they hand rub the resin if you can
imagine here in Jamaica they do it to an
extent but it's a lot more I mean back
in the day I seen it off of
sledgehammers that they were hammering
into tires and it would the GaN Jet the
the gum that you could pull off that
sledgehammer was incredible of course
here in Jamaica they don't trim with
scissors scissors are hard to find most
Jamaicans will use a knife and their
thumb and they'll curl that leaf in and
they'll pinch it against their their
their thumb and it's actually quite
impressive is the first time I thought I
saw it I thought wow that's gonna take
so much time
personally John and I don't even trim
our plants if you can imagine we only
make hash of it we go into our grow room
we cut down fresh beautiful grown plants
and then we throw them in this bucket
and we mix it then we make water hatch
which is I guess what we're gonna do
right now excellent last two bags and
before we yes please do that I haven't
seen eyes it of course I brought a bunch
of dozen to get a gift
let alone a supercool ganja oriented
gift they can a keep the police from
from harassing you because the police
know it you know they're not the
smartest but they have noses and this is
the problem we love our stinky cannabis
and it makes it so easy for the police
to realize we have it right they smell
it on us and even when they don't smell
it on us they they lie and they say
there's no Ames
all right so get ready yeah we got the
220 in here but we could start doing is
I'm gonna pour this into here part of it
Chuck about half and then we'll break
the bud into the top of the ice and then
we'll pour more ice or water on top just
like we would do in a bubble bag so can
we put the ice on the bottom you should
not pick this up too I'm not going to so
what we're saying
so once again we're trying to keep it as
cold as possible on more ice to better
itself can you grab me that cooler in
the back of the car
yeah thanks just thinking out loud with
that yeah once once we make the hash
this is basically this process is pretty
darn simple to break your butt down not
too much to break your butt down in let
me go back a little bit
this process is counterintuitive even
every person here is gonna watch it
they'll have a certain understanding of
it but immediately they'll start
thinking of ways they can do it better
based on what they think is happening
and I just I did the same thing and
everyone's done the same thing and in
North America particularly in America
because Americans are just so gung-ho
and like let's do it babe let's do it
large let's go as strong as you can and
so I'm showing people how to mix with it
with a stick and the Americans are
getting like outboard motors from their
boat and literally like running it in
kiddie pools and unfortunately what that
does is it turns the canvas to mulch and
it doesn't really I mean when you see
that these are microscopic glands we
don't need a vortex mixer you don't need
like an extremely powerful drill today
we're gonna make this with a stick I'm
just gonna mix it with a stick I've got
machines that I sell that you can use
and it's easier even to use a cake mixer
I used to use a cake mixer here in
Jamaica all the time which was great
just a little handheld tool with the two
little prongs it would spin it around
quite nice your your stock also has a
use of course cannabis stocks can make
paper you can make hempcrete from this
stuff basically what we're sitting on
right here can be made out of hemp grown
on the back mountain no problem
it's actually quite simple I think it's
just a lot it's like yeah you mix lye
you mix water you mix hemp fibers I
think they take the stalks and they chop
them up together so it's a whole process
you can look into it if you don't know
about it it's definitely cool of course
cannabis stock is just biomass so of
course you can make concrete out of it
do this up Johnny love to get that gun
down my fingers so this is how I get the
extra medicated because of course it
goes through your skin because the oils
absolutely you know rub a little coconut
oil on your hands while you're doing
this or do it after you've got gum on
your hands and rub coconut oil on well
that's a transdermal effect that will
actually bring those cannabinoids into
your skin and of course your skin is an
organ
it's the largest organ in your body it's
called the epidermis and the epidermis
of course is where we find quite a few
cb2 receptors so a quick little science
breakdown so you know not to confuse
anyone but we discovered in the 80s and
the 90s cb1 receptors I'm sure you guys
heard about this this is when they says
they found receptors for THC in the
brain that we had receptors that bond
that that the cannabis would bond to
these receptors so these were called cb1
receptors and they were found in a high
concentration in the brain then about
eight years later I think it was 1992 or
signee 192 cb2 and was it the Spanish
woman who discovered this Cristina okay
so Cristina basically came up with cb2
receptors and these cb2 receptors are
located throughout the rest of the body
and organs and your lymphatic system and
so there's also receptors for
cannabinoids in in in those organs so
what that really means is is that this
system called the endocannabinoid system
that regulates all of our biological
function you know well not all but I'd
say 90% of it of an extremely high
amount you know eating and sleeping and
remembering and forgetting all these
things are are based on your
endocannabinoid system for instance pts
tea you know postpartum stress disorder
people go to war they do things they
don't want to do they come back all that
stuff
they have messed up their
endocannabinoids system they can't
forget they can't forget what they did
maybe they shouldn't forget what they
did
either way cannabis is very helpful for
them to release that energy release that
tortured energy that they basically you
know some of them did it on their own
but a lot of those guys aren't bad
people they just got thrown into the
army and the next thing you know they're
in another country doing crazy things so
we know cannabis is extremely well for
that and that can be worked either
through smoking vaporizing transdermal
patches decarboxylation of the cannabis
and then eating it and we can discuss
all these things a little later on you
want to tell them a little bit about
decarboxylate enjoy decarboxylated so
it's basically activating the TT
molecules of the cannabinoids so the
bindery stuff is in your brain so well
smoke because they will not bind they
will not find if you just need the
answer I hate it if you can get that a
for confessed and if we eat bud we're
getting THC a we're getting CBD a we're
getting all these cannabinoids and th
C's in the A's the acid so when we
decarboxylate all it is simply is we
heat to a certain temperature 200 and
200 you long once again what's my
temperature
I go 320 degrees Fahrenheit just under
200 Celsius what you're going to do is
scientifically you're going to lose a
carboxylic acid ring on those molecules
and what that does is they turn all
those th CAS and CBD A's in the THC and
CBD and now when you consume those
products
or some heat generated when drawing us
let's make sure lose this I mean it is
only the 160 bag but let's just do this
so I can we're a little bit messy okay
this will just alleviate that problem of
us losing any and that's one more reason
why you have those extra bags in there I
mean the thought of plant matter going
into my 90 micron hash so actually going
back to when they discovered the east
yes he had a cannabinoid system for
those you know no it was discovered in
1977 they found the receptors in pigs
you know that's where the research
started when they talked about this [ __ ]
going on actually after working fella
just under 12 new at 11 years then they
found it in the human brain so it's
interesting that they knew it was there
but then they made it illegal knowing
that we actually need it and things are
changing and you know this is an
interesting thing because the
endocannabinoid system in my opinion is
just you know it's something straight
people have never known about it I'll
tell you dr. David Allen had a really
good point he said that people with
massive endocannabinoid deficiencies
that are like beyond and above on normal
endocannabinoid deficiency these people
basically get a type of brain damage
against cannabis these are the cannabis
prohibitionists that will throw you away
in jail they'll ruin your life they'll
shoot your dog they'll take all your
things they don't care if your kids are
crying they don't care about any of that
because they're completely not tuned in
to their own system so I really like
when David Allen said that it makes so
much sense why our prohibitionists why
are the people that don't use cannabis
why do they care if we use it
silly all right so we keep the gun in
here right now Johnny doesn't want to
run a whole town that's underground I'd
say we got to make our general breaking
this up so these five gallon bags
generally will fit 200 grams of dried
bud if you stuff too much bud into the
bucket the resin won't be able to filter
down it'll get caught in the plant
matter and so it's key that we do the
right amounts I oft in a way but we also
don't dry our bud anymore we we run it
fresh frozen so if you've got fresh bud
you got a freezer right besides it
thrown into it well the next we get
better result the next bubble we make
will be in a ganja field and we'll be
cutting those plants down fresh and
going right into the bucket that's
definitely the way I remember hiking for
forty minutes into the hills here in
Jamaica back in 2002 when I came out
with international cata graphic and
gypsy Nirvana who's now in Milano prison
awaiting extradition from the
Philippines to the US let's hope they
don't get him guys they already got Marc
Emery we shouldn't give them gypsy
nirvana
and once we get into her into the ice
it's breaking oh yeah well it's nice to
break the herb down you don't like I
said you don't want to break it into
powder but you definitely want to get it
you know broken down so that it's a it's
gonna release those trichomes and one
thing I did see when I looked at this
bug with what the lid you see definitely
how the trichomes release in there
because what the sativa is they're not
as tight as the indica buds that I'm
used to rock hard wood you always see on
my videos what I talk about is how dense
and how we rock are those in the Khazar
this is not that type of but it's um yes
this is the kind of but I love this is
participate it is I said all the time
and I guess banyumas
I'm constantly defending the herb in
Jamaica because you can't you get like
touristy people come here and it's like
listen man like just because you came
here and didn't find anything worth
finding but certainly isn't to say that
something worth people constantly say
when they can't find something that it
doesn't exist
oh there's no good weed in Jamaica but
is like the most insane statements that
you could ever possibly make and really
it's ignorant to say it because it shows
that you must have stayed at sandals
never visited any real people on the
island and literally just like bought I
don't know like swaggy moldy brown baby
from from the local hotel guy
don't stay in hotels when you come to
Jamaica if you can help it get out of
those all-inclusive those those hotels
don't leave any money on this island
they take it all off and they don't pay
employees properly it's all a pretty
pretty bad scene in general so I've
always prided myself the first time I
came to Jamaica I stayed in a tent and
everyone was like you can't stay in a
tent I was like why not I'm bringing it
who's gonna stop me
well the army did actually at one point
in time tried to stop me but I found one
I bribed those guys with a big buck
knife that I had they just buggered
right off it was awesome
it was amazing actually the middle Bush
is going back into like the early
nineties yes a long time ago guaranteed
things have changed here so yeah
absolutely
that I'm talking about so who knows I
sure look forward to the
decriminalization here in Jamaica
happening beautiful pretty big steps for
Jamaica to take to decriminalize two
ounces for personal I think even more
importantly than the decriminalization
of two ounces is to let everyone that's
in jail out if they're in for cannabis
crimes potentially we re proud part
reiations
and boy felony you know clean clean the
charges you can't you can't those people
can't be charged for something that was
simply you know unknown unreasonable
government towed line from the 1937
drugging piece of narcotics treaty that
the united states of course look bigger
put into got all the other countries to
sign up and that's basically what's been
holding everything up why for so long
nobody's been able to grow cannabis
legally and and actually experiment and
do and do good work with it we could
show it up yeah i mean it's just a
little bucket of ice a little bucket of
a but in here if you guys want to check
it out i'm gonna get more we're gonna
put more ice in we're gonna put more
about this resin coming in here there
you go
hey smart john there i'm gonna come in
here with this nice beautiful spear and
you can take a better look at that there
you go so that's what we're washing
right now put a bunch more
I'm down about here okay so I'm pretty
good we're gonna yeah what'd that say
well maybe not actually there's a pretty
[Music]
you'll never use enough ice in this
process don't ever think you're using
too much I think that every video we say
keep it cold keep it cold cold keep it
cool keep it cool and at this point in
time you guys have seen me and John make
cash out on the Pacific Ocean on a boat
I made it with DJ short once and Marc
Emery actually on a school bus driving
around Vancouver that was trippy there
were no school kids on it though we had
just rented it for our own sort of
tokers gold party that we were having
yeah made it in Jamaica bunch made it
all over the world Switzerland Germany
Italy France London India Thailand Korea
I made hash all over the world so I'm
happy to be here doing it Suns gonna
start mixing up the medicine always get
a rhythm going you be getting water
pouring out of the sides don't be
worried because the resin is trapped
inside the screens
kind of you guys anybody there
that right there is a good mix if we can
get that for five to ten minutes we're
going to assure glandular trichomes
isolation and decontamination
[Applause]
got this great drink here real Jamaican
around so I'll juice yeah that's nice so
back at home I have washing machines
they're very small washing machines I
get them out of China they're about this
big I have bigger ones as well but these
are an incredible product they're fairly
inexpensive they'll actually wash your
clothes but they'll also wash the resin
off of your plants so this is one of the
variables that a lot of people can make
mistakes in like I said earlier the
majority of the time people try to over
mix they try to put too much mix into
the material with dry material what can
happen is you can break it up more than
you want to and create contamination and
basically it's it's a fine line of
mixing and that's why I started selling
the machine not because I thought people
need of another machine and you can
totally do this with a stick but it took
out the variables of people worrying
about ruining their product I mean it's
for John and I it's nothing to throw
kilos and kilos and kilos into water and
ice and just mix it up I personally run
hundreds of pounds of bug into hash
eight to ten pounds of hash at a time
with this process every three to four
days this is something that I've done in
the past now I'm doing a lot less these
days I'm not really isolating on those
levels anymore I mostly I mostly isolate
myself and for John for our own personal
medicinal reasons why can't you make
your own resin that's it you can give a
man a fish and he'll be happy but you
teach a man to fish and that is a whole
different ballgame and that's what we're
doing right here we're not coming in and
saying we have all the secret
proprietary knowledge and we know how to
do a bunch of stuff that you don't know
how to do our whole trip is beautif
people how to do this I won't be leaving
Jamaica with these bags I'll be leaving
them here with the person that got the
most excited about learning and the
person that's the most gung-ho I'm
getting this started and turned into a
not a business but a journey it's a
journey to the unadulterated cannabinoid
high and when you experience that pure
essence of job through just the resin
with out that contamination
it is either what do you want to call it
a religious I personally call it a
spiritual experience and I am lucky
enough to have it every day some people
call it ritual but every day for me and
John
its original
[Applause]
get that fall
I need a friend
I've made a lot of John's water hatch
with and for him over the course of the
last year
happily John has done a lot for me John
helps a lot of people selflessly on a
regular basis so if you want to know how
to find happiness in your life it's not
going to be by collecting baubles and
gold chains for yourself it's actually
gonna be going out and doing something
for someone not necessarily that has
less but maybe just a person that needs
a little bit of help or a smile or a
nice word or two
so on the machine when I'm mixing like
this I'll generally mix for six minutes
with my machine because I'm hand mixing
and the mixing is going to be a little
less standard yeah I'd say about 15
working it
so a marketing company sorrell to me
from us and I have my first one if you
didn't see the expression on my face
pretty nice eh it's great and apparently
they're available in Canada so hey I'm
buying two pieces of these oh yeah what
I'm making bubble hash in Jamaica make
sure you I drink so Rael juice I'm just
joking one of the things about John and
I you'll notice is we don't promote
anything that we don't love we actually
have this thing called integrity which
lowers profits immensely but it creates
better vibes so when you see us on our
show when we're promoting a certain type
of product or tool or whatever it's not
because a company has approached us and
said hey listen you know if you just
tell everyone my product is the best
I'll pay you someone so money we don't
do any of that we don't take money from
companies we just promote the products
with a high integrity that we believe in
that you should you know in the least
check out if you are you know along the
same path
well that's it and that's why with the
LED light people are asking me already
do you like the LED do you like the lush
well I'm only starting to grow my first
crop with it so I can't really tell you
if I like it yet and I can't really
promote it in a way that says yeah you
should go buy one because I haven't
actually grown any resin with it once
I've grown my cannabis and I've
extracted the resin and I've actually
smoked the resin with John then we'll
have an idea you're gonna set us up with
the pressing strings I'm getting
pressing screens and they're there at
the Karno right in there so this is the
final part once you've done your mixing
I'm not done yet I'm gonna mix for about
five more minutes once you've done your
mixing we settled for about five minutes
right now as I talk little trichomes
have been broken off as cannabis and
they're actually sinking in this bucket
for me as a cannabis aficionado and
lover I always get so excited about
sharing this information with people
that I know love cannabis but they don't
know about this I mean imagine all your
life all you ever had was grape juice
and then one day someone that just came
over to you and said have you ever seen
these and you they showed you grapes you
know that's the equivalent to what we're
doing here when we when we lift these
bags and you just see this sandy kind of
product you'll you'll get the the idea
and of course I'm talking to my Jamaican
friends here not so much the people back
at home cuz I know you guys have been
watching these videos for a long time
and I know you guys pretty much know
this process inside and out
if you guys have any questions at all
feel free to shout them out don't worry
about it you're not interrupting I'll
edit this video and I can pause and cut
things out and make I don't want you to
be lost at any point in this process
there's ever a point where you're like
why did you do that what is it you're
doing right now just interrupt and ask
me so these bags define little story are
made in Nepal Nepal Kathmandu huge
shivay Bubba group in Nepal Shivaratri
of course which is Shiva's birthday
Shiva in my opinion is the most rascal
like of the Hindu gods
you know Shiva's pretty damn cool Shiva
puffs top and even drinks bang he was
got long-ass hair and a huge ass beard
and every celebration I've ever been
involved in and every saw do cuz there's
many many types of holy men in India
many type of sadhu and they're not all
she bites
there's Brahmins and there's Krishna's
and there she bites so you have a bunch
of different schools it doesn't take
long to figure out when you go to India
that the she bites or the poppers so of
course the whole time I was there I was
hanging out with shivay Bubba's
and here's an interesting fact that the
Jamaicans will love these guys are
revered in India they're dreads they're
bearded they're holy men and walk around
in bare feet they don't own things but
they're revered by the people because
they live a hard life belief system in
India with karma and how karma works is
that the Saudis are living this life to
work through the Karma of the people not
just for themselves a lot of the North
American mentality when it comes to
karma is a selfish
Oh as long as I'm nice I'll have good
karma well that's not really how it
works
bad karma can be trapped by good people
and good karma can be trapped by bad
people we're all one people on this
earth and our Karma's are all
interconnected they're not separating a
[Music]
couple more minutes don't it
[Applause]
I'm getting the
a little herb water in that in the
either
I've got two pieces of cardboard here
when I was just explaining the cardboard
to the guys behind us is gonna soak the
moisture that we leave within that is in
the hash of the moisture out of my gosh
very important for here in Jamaica a
desiccant a desiccant is something that
will absorb moisture with the help of
gravity so cardboard is a desiccant it's
any paper you can see if I put paper
down right here right now obviously it
would absorb the water off of the
concrete so cardboard is the same idea
we like to get a triple applied
cardboard we used pizza boxes because we
can close them wrap them in parchment
paper and when we grade our bubble over
top of it it's going to be safe from any
contaminant like hair or debris or dust
what I mean by grading it or receiving
it or micro planing it once we pulled
this resin out of here it's going to be
wet and it's very important that we I'm
probably the most important thing that
we will do in this whole process is that
will break that bubble hash up so it's
powder and the greater the surface area
of powder that we can spread the more
efficient the cardboard will be with its
desiccant action I mean if you put a
little paddy one little paddy on a big
piece of cardboard yeah that cardboard
is gonna pull right under that paddy
it'll never dry properly now what if I
broke that paddy into powder and spread
it all over the cardboard well in a
place like Jamaica it doesn't take very
long before that moisture is absorbed
and then the resin is is able to cure so
a small explanation of that is that the
wax membrane cuticle that holds in the
cannabinoid profile and glandular
trichomes becomes brittle and we break
it off and we separate the hash however
if it's fresh or herb it's going to
maintain hydration inside that wax
number and there's moisture in it okay
so when you add more water to an already
moist membrane you saturated and it
becomes harder to dry so in Jamaica in a
place like this using dry herb can be
beneficial however I still love to do
fresh frozen my fresh frozen okay way to
do fresh frozen filled
fresh frozen field they say we pulled
these bags pretty soon
the beds I think so pretty soon so we've
got my water right here John it's nice
and cold we'll be able to do our rinses
I think what we'll do because it's very
important
potentially Ashley or someone what we
require is the hose these turned on down
there okay and then as we pull the bags
and I clean the hash out someone's gonna
have to take the bags as us I'm gonna
clean the hash out John's gonna flip the
bag inside out inside this bucket rinse
McClure it's the majority and the resin
off of the screen but because of this
heat and this moisture we need to ensure
that those that the the resin is cleaned
off the screen properly so really pay
attention with your eyes look at the
screen is there resin all over that hose
down there is unfortunately very warm
water if you put your thumb over the
hose and create a real jet you should be
able to clean the bags and we're gonna
give you the bags wrapped inside out
over this bucket so they'll be already
stretched so you won't have to hold a
floppy bag there'll be a nice open
screen right here you can hold the bag
underneath you know cinched and just
hold this sideways and John can go down
with you the first time definitely
alright
[Music]
I think you did 15 John I think we're
good yes clean if you can that wasn't
there a second ago you gotta keep it
clean
oh yeah and you know what little blood
particles aren't really what we're
worried about
right it's the resin exactly so just
think I think we're gonna have to dump
this lovely plants yeah well we'll see
what happens yep and here we go guys
well embed bags when our first bags in
Jamaica so we did you know make a little
bit of a mess on our first we've got a
little vs. LV bag is very good to have
it is even though still I'm gonna clean
it as much as I can rather than let this
get into the final product
a great thing about water hash as well
is that you know often when people see
it for the first time they're surprised
that there's you know there's that you
took all this herb and only got this
small amount of resin well that's the
fact of canvas there's a small amount of
resin and all these people you know
people when I got caught with my
cannabis I have a cannabis felony I got
caught with 16 and a half pounds at a
roadblock and the police just thought it
was the greatest thing ever and I you
know luckily they didn't catch me
earlier that day when I had 100 pounds
that's a whole other story but the 16
and a half pounds got taken my cash got
taken it was actually being held for the
BC compassion club it was herb for
terminally sick people it wasn't going
to high school students and it wasn't
even a recreational thing so the judge
in Canada was really cool about it he
judged in a way that gave me no fine no
time no probation and he ordered the
prosecutor give me my money back
and while I was being charged the
prosecutor asked my lawyer if I could
get their friend who was dying of cancer
in the hospital a bag of weed did you
get that the prosecutor who was
prosecuting me for trial
Cannabis asked my lawyer to get his
friend a bag of weed who was dying it in
the hospital of cancer of course I did
it of course I'm gonna show the guy that
just because you're under bullying you
have such a shitty job you have to
prosecute people for you know cannabis
in fact the most righteous level of
cannabis distribution you're
distributing to terminally ill people
you know these people these people were
really sick back then now luckily today
in Canada there's a variety of us John
and I are clearly not terminally ill but
we're still allowed to use cannabis as a
medicine which is fairly important to
the two of us so the best part about
pulling this bag is how much of Isis in
there it's creamy it's like and when we
see it creamy we're happy
yeah we're happy when we see I'm almost
happy of all the colors aside from clear
clear states that you know this looks
like sour sap juice it really does is
what this looks like in here soursop
juice so you know we did something and
we didn't only do a mechanical
separation which is the process but
we've also leached water-soluble
terpenes into this water and that's why
we've got this color definitely keeping
this ice
quick thinking Johnny Johnny quick
thinker so I'm just grabbing little bits
and pieces just because the quality of
this you never know it could be good why
would I want to this is our contaminant
bag a little bit of ice cubes cuz John
and I got a little overzealous on our
mixing um it's a lot of contaminant but
you can tell that we filtered something
out all right this isn't what it's what
we don't want and people often ask why
do you why didn't want to use that bag
because we need to get this out of our
smoker this isn't something that that's
that we were going to be wanting to
inhale now there are medicinal
properties in this you could cook it
into a banana bread you could literally
collect this stuff by the kilo and give
it to someone who makes Mehta bowls and
those Mehta Bulls would be unbelievable
and of course John we know that because
when we eat THC what does it do in our
body we feed a Rango cannabinoid system
and it metabolizes in our liver so when
you eat cannabis it's different from
smoking and it actually will go through
your liver and it metabolizes and what
it does is it turns tetrahydrocannabinol
which is THC into eleven hydroxy
metabolites and anyone that's ever eaten
cannabis that stuff will lick you good
like it will put you down it isn't very
different from smoking cannabis and sure
you can get people who smoked a bunch
and have
minor anxiety attack and return a very
intense it's nothing compared to the
power of eating or overeating cannabis I
eat a lot of cannabis and I haven't the
last 24 hours X 2 3 days so of course
I'm eating this canvas yeah well you
need a lot of cannabis it's not you I'm
talking about that's for sure I know
so this is our 190 you just pull that
ice cube oh if you get a chance there
all right so so 190 so once again feel
the resin on there over here stretch
that right over the top
pull cinch it on the bottom and then
we'll just stick it in the water and get
that this is an extremely important
about this is a very important part use
your eyes use a microscope if you have
food there's stuff on the street and if
you leave it there each time it's gonna
dry and it's gonna fill the holes and
once you've eventually filled the holes
on the screen you're gonna be throwing
pounds of weed and and getting very very
very small returns because it's not
making it through the screens you can
fix this by taking some you know over
proof alcohol clear alcohol and rubbing
gently I use a toothbrush I flip the bag
over a screen and make it tight and then
I just use this toothbrush with the
smallest amount of solvents as you guys
know I am NOT a solvent fan I I say it
all the time
water sustains life and solvents end
like it's as simple as that there's no
ifs ands or buts about it
water sustains life on Earth and
solvents end life on Earth
next bag 161 3000 we got a pile Dhoni
yeah and right away it's this oranjee
ready lie bed awesome like beautiful
hash like that's nice 160 a little bit
the process that I use almost panning
I'm gonna balance it around and I'm
gonna pick itself up off the screen and
get these little shaking processes
anticipated because we were this is the
160 so by no means is this what we want
but I'll tell you to get that quality is
a good sign it only means that our 120
bag that I'm about to go pull right now
is only gonna be better this is
basically nicer than any gun you could
find on the entire island because I
washed it it's not an ego thing it's
just that they're smashing resins with
knives and I washed the resin we have
the microscope because we could really
show these guys
well yeah I'm seeing if you go over on
this side you'll see contaminant you'll
see systole pairs stigmas kappa pick
stocks
not so much actual plant matter but
trichome contamination why don't we get
it off and I'm gonna use a little bit of
this water just to kind of rehydrate
that resin that I allowed to in this
heat it's drawing me this resin will dry
so you can always rehydrate it by adding
more water on to the screen to get it
off once again movies on ice cold water
underneath now after this bag we wash
the other bags back into the other bags
we want to keep collecting that residue
after this bag this bag is not a good
enough resin for us yet I looked at it
under the microscope it's probably only
40% gland heads every sixty to seventy
percent contaminant great for eating
great for your 100% right that is great
whatever you know that's something we're
gonna put in our pocket cannot be snobs
are the purest it's just like you say
the same thing with a good piece of
fruit as opposed to a bad piece of fruit
you know I'm grateful that's right
perfectly ripe bananas it's the one
that's like overly ripe and almost
rotten I prefer that to give that to my
wife and she makes banana bread out of
it you know there's different levels of
qualities and the fruit that we're
looking for is the highest quality
getting that slow drip on the 120 is
never of that and now I need to show you
guys each time because you're gonna see
the different quality and you're gonna
see that the resin it moves around
different and it cleans different and as
it gets better as it gets better I'll be
able to basically
I need a spray bottle if I had a little
spray bottle let's clear it all into the
center make it easier to collect you
know all right I know and you know a
balla resin like this could easily be 2
to 3 grams it looks very small but resin
is extremely dense I have a feeling
microscope
so of course we're now looking at it
which you guys haven't seen and now it's
heads and now it's all the fresh heavies
hence his company yeah that's nice
yeah that's a good start I came here in
2002 and my friend from Seaford town
he's a German descent the white Jamaican
guy born and bred his whole family's
friend yep yep and uh he had a pound of
herb that he was selling to an expat in
Negril who was the coin man he used to
cut coins and make that look like it you
know someone was smoking a joint inside
a coin and Chris would sell him a pound
to herb for 50 bucks he'd bring it down
from the hills well the day that I came
to Jamaica and met Chris the coin man
told him that the herb was no good and
that he wouldn't pay him the $50 but
Chris had already invested his own money
to get that herb and he had bought it
for maybe 30 bucks or something but 30
bucks was a lot of money to christen him
he's gonna he was gonna mess him up for
about a week and a half if he didn't get
it taken care of you was really bummed
out or not the herb wasn't very nice but
I took the herb and I turned it into 11
grams of hash and he sold it to the coin
man for $220 u.s. the same pound to herb
the coin man wouldn't buy for 50 US
dollars so we took it we made hash out
of it
it took us 30 minutes and Chris went
from losing 30 dollars to making a
hundred and ninety dollars let me tell
you if Chris was pretty happy and so was
the coin mine until he found out
rehydrating because it wasn't super
happy good job that's that's a great
that's the Jamaicans spritzer is it yeah
absolutely
[ __ ] I'm gonna something I know you're
not learning something you just created
something this is how it happens get
your hands dirty make cash with your
friends I swear to god you'll earn this
haven't done me for actually I just
that's a great idea worked perfect it
worked
we're great see we learn something new
every day
I might have to just borrow that okay so
now at this point we're gonna wash this
Bank into the best rent exactly this is
one of harvest us this is a big change
now we're we're not putting Dresden that
was 90 percent heads and that looks like
something we all want to smoke into this
bucket which is clearly going to be
washed into the garden we're gonna wash
it right back in to the 90 micron bag
what that's gonna do for us is it's
gonna trap those resin heads that were
on this screen in our next we want to
keep this bag is always just great this
is something that will happen sometimes
with bubble hash you get foam and you
can't you won't be kind of can't tell
what you have to give it a little blow
some small amount of 19 years we're
gonna get a big poll in the 73 I was
expecting at least twice this much of 90
I think it all went into the 73 John
I'll say this as well if we were dealing
with sativas here if there were sativas
in the bunch we're gonna find a large
amount of heads in this white bag the 45
micron bag and that's due to the fact
that the tropical Sun beats such
powerful UVB rays down on this resin
that it produces almost a smaller
trichome rather than the large bulbous
ones that John and I are used to pulling
off of we're indoor grown cannabis the
sativas particularly the outdoor ones
will tend to pull much smaller just like
that just because it'll it'll self press
itself less normally when I'm doing this
as well these right here would be in a
cold environment like if this was full
of ice we would have it open and we
would have this down inside of the ice
mixture and it would just keep a sort of
thermal Klein from I mean it's gotta be
27 26 degrees out here right now so it's
definitely nice and warm something that
the resin doesn't always appreciate so I
like freezing
so actually brought this all right here
you go you want to clean this bag up get
it down there's a little trick we
learned in Spain yeah we do that I have
done that before Spain but he just had
the perfect size pocket and filled
actually even before I went to Spain we
made hash with the bucket on the side of
the river that she could miss river up
in Whistler British Columbia raging
glacier-fed River behind me and John and
what do we do well we bring a bunch of
his fresh frozen buds and some bubble
bags and ice and we make hash down by
the river it's quite nice oh yeah look
at this
the water came right out of the 90
micron bag why is the water not falling
through this screen right now what
possible reasons could it be full of
breath it's full of resin so you could
stand here like an idiot for 20 minutes
and let it drain or you could simply go
from jerking the resin with a quick jerk
up off of the screen and the water is
rushing down through the screen I
literally had customers who with this
bag one guy in particular he said it
took him thirty two hours to drain the
bag and I was just like Oh what did you
do for 30
he's a claw huh I hung it on the
bathroom doorknob and with the bucket
underneath it and then when I showed him
that I could drain any bag in ten
seconds he actually did not believe me
and when I finally showed him how to do
it well the guy just felt so stupid and
you shouldn't feel stupid man in my
opinion the only way you can learn is to
put yourself out there look like an
idiot make mistakes I learn from them I
mean holy [ __ ] how do we learn we make
mistakes that's how I learned anyway
holy [ __ ] how about that that's all I'm
gonna say
bad got the biggest yield I've seen of
anything that's a really nice 73 Pole
right there this is what I was talking
about for that is what we're talking
about your bumps here when you get goose
bumps you guys look at that goose bumps
from that resin see the hair standing up
that's amazing you can't see we're gonna
get the microscope out once the cameras
off and we'll all get to look at it for
now I want to pull it off it's always
nice to pull a really nice bag to show I
know I just thought my arm yeah this is
this is 10 grams I would say there's a
10 gram pull and we didn't even use all
about oh how do you know this graceless
cuz you know that 45 that's gonna be the
same
I had to show the goose and the hair is
standing up I was like that's amazing
that's what we came here to show you all
right clean that off into the 45 we only
have two bags left so we'll be getting
down to the fun stuff here pretty soon a
lot of people make mistakes when they do
this for the first time it's so exciting
when you see what John and I just saw
for the first time especially that
sometimes the bags don't get cleans fast
enough sometimes they get put down and
everyone's like just do me a favor look
at the hash once you've cleaned your bag
so I'm gonna clean your bags and then
look at the hash it's not going anywhere
on the 7390 by the 45 because it's so
small it's gonna get stuck in those
screens and yeah I gotta get it clean
right away most important parts I mean
they're all important but really pay
attention to your ninety or seventy
three because paper bags all right so
this one's gonna be heavy
45s always hold in the water nice
chance yeah this is probably like twice
as much as the 73 and learn he's just
all water but it's definitely the same
size once this water drips that's why I
had to give him a depressing screen I
hoxsey haven't changed my game right
away
okay I mean that screen okay we're
adaptable John
so as he started doing that I was well
ready to the same thing you can actually
blow the foam off to the side one at a
time no no no yeah I know I got stomped
all right so nice little 45 Pole
this one's gonna drive him faster so
this is the one these are the two bags
I'm not gonna walk around and show you
all but you guys are all gonna be able
to see it on the pressing screen once
we've got to collect it so this is a
nice pile it's it's actually not quite
as much as the 73 but it's pretty pretty
chunky clean - this is this is what the
water offers us the water offers us the
ability to clean the resin in a way that
we've never been able to before and I'll
tell ya Jamaica was one of the first
countries I came to to show this process
- and I went to a lot of countries like
99 mm I came in 2000 2001 2002 3 4 &amp; 5
and I think some of those first bags
were posted on your Facebook page by
someone from here yes yeah I got I got
good friends in Orange Hills Diggy I got
good friends in Grange Hill that we've
made bubble hash with over the years yes
and maybe people really growers these
guys aren't there's lots of different
kinds of growers in Jamaica just like
there's lots of different kind of
growers everywhere in the world but to
find the real root see growers to find
the real you know the the guys that are
really focused on the effects of the
plant not on how much they're gonna get
from the tourist market which there's
nothing wrong with that I mean if I
lived in Jamaica I'd be selling the [ __ ]
out of hash to tourists we need to be
funny yeah so when I tour here I mean it
would be great honestly when I arrived
here the first thing I had to do is go
find ganja and turn it into hash how
happy would I have been if someone met
me at the airport and said oh man we've
been making hash with your berry what
are you talking about here's a piece oh
my god here's a couple hundred dollars
thank you hey Vic really I mean before
Steve Newlin's came we gotta get back
you have to keep in mind John and I have
licenses for this I personally have a
license to have ten pounds of hash at my
house I'm allowed ten pounds of hash
what do you allow 15 15
fifteen point five pounds over here ten
pounds over here between the two of us
we rock a 25 pack of hash how sweet is
that we don't the world you know I
personally consider myself an Earthling
I'm not really a big proponent of
borders and division of human culture I
love the fact that we have other
cultures but they're all of our
culture's to share we're not separated
in any way one more bag Johnny then this
is the bag everyone hates I want to get
us some cups and we're all gonna have a
drink of this liquid and you're gonna
protein-rich cannabis liquid it's not
gonna get any of you high it's just
gonna be like drinking cannabis tea and
I know a few of you are gonna be
inspired by it at least and as everybody
knows you always see me during the night
yeah it's a nice thing to do you know I
feed it to my plants personally I mean
these are these are flavors and terpenes
and whatnot and it just seems like a
good idea to just put them right back
into you know what you don't drink
because I mean obviously John's not
gonna drink five gallons of bubble hash
water because he makes bubble hash
almost every day yeah for it's the last
little tip on this and you guys have
already seen me doing it these bags are
a little harder to finish off I don't
want you squeezing the fruit I don't
want you know we don't want to bruise
the resin we don't want to damage it so
what we're gonna do is we're gonna
create we just open the bag all right
and we create air in the bag
and then we use the air to force the
rest of the water and the foam out of
the bag this is very helpful and it
allow you here's the thing when you have
your resin soaking in water let's get it
out as soon as possible we're teaching
and educating here today so we're going
real slow but generally you'd see me I'd
already have this over here this would
have been in the house and microplane
like we would have already done a lot of
this but we're going slow because we're
in Jamaica and when teaching we're gonna
rush some people yeah all right five
this is our last bag and I'm gonna get a
really good bucket with a bed this is
how we do it we used to pull up only the
[ __ ] and exposes it right there marks
really experience so we hold in his hand
just cars it off with this and with what
the spoon but really reality to make
life a lot easier for you guys as you
see what he's doing here right now he
pulls it over a bucket and then you have
access to that resin
[Music]
all right so we get a real nice almost
artistic resin mixed with the white foam
that I created and because I gave it a
little bit of a blow I created these
psychedelic patterns inside the resin
you can see here in here how easy it is
to see the contaminant when you get rid
of all the contaminant even if you have
1% generally nothing will get through
these bags but the way John and I the
way I didn't fold the bag is over
themselves right away and we were
stripping the herb it was falling
between the bags so we had a little bit
of there but that's a major major so
we're gonna see we're gonna look at all
of these under the microscope I'll
actually photograph them all right now
with my camera so you know it's a little
bit easier than looking through that
tiny little eye hole and we'll be able
to fudge I've been smoking hash for a
long time over 15 years probably close
to 20 I've been smoking it almost
exclusively for 13 years but I'm here to
tell you right now
the Jamaican sun-grown resin is some of
the best quality resin I've ever inhaled
in my life and that's saying something
you guys all know who I am you know that
I'm not smoking anything less than what
I would consider the best everywhere I
go but for whatever reason and John's
gonna be on this man I'm so excited for
you to join us here soon
oh I have something to do making bubble
uh yeah that too but I mean I got to
smoke Jamaican bud before we actually
did this and like you guys some be
working here hard going solid and you
know I did I tweaked my neck a little
bit but otherwise not you know
definitely and that's the difference
between you know when we have what I
love having John here with me is because
we're not really just promoting you for
values of cannabis which I have 100% of
proponent on I believe in using cannabis
spiritually and in in the sense that the
same way it is the discipline for your
body it is medicinal for your brain and
for your soul and the synergy of those
three things the Holy Trinity you have
my only Trinity anyway I'm gonna what do
you think do a little a little bit a
little bit now you can do a second run
from that and I can guarantee we get
more from that right it's true we could
literally take this put it back into the
bags mix it again for 10 or 15 minutes
and we could get more I would not tell
you to throw that away
oh no however as you do this as you
start making this especially here in
Jamaica I can easily see with the way my
mind works that I would set up a thing
where all the firsts is like one team of
people and then this is the second team
it's not run by the first team you have
a you have a team of people who are
doing the jobs that John and I did and
then you have specific experts who will
deal with this product right here
because let's be honest no many people
you're not taking care of that well okay
big job the big job is breaking up the
hash into powder and drying it properly
this is like a foreman job this is a
supervisor this guy's getting paid more
than everyone else trust me these are
believers the laborers they're just
anyone any laborer I mean you just saw
what we did it's just really simple
labor you're moving around water and ice
you're moving you're mixing with a stick
or you've got washing machines if you've
got washing machines you're using a bag
like this that's all screened the whole
bag is screen and it zips closed I throw
the ice and the urban you throw it in
the washing machine you turn the button
ten minutes later another guy washes
that drains that washing machine into a
set of buckets and starts doing what we
did you could have one machine and run
three 20 gallon sets of bag so three
machines nine 20 gallon sets of
eggs you might have four people
constantly making ice breaking it up and
filling bags in these all screen bags
and then putting them in the freezer
then you have your second crew coming
along opening the freezer opening those
putting them into the washing machine
and turning them on that's all they do
the third crew is pulling bags this is a
crew you want to
they're not just laborers these are
people you've trained and these are
people who know what they're doing
and they're going to get to this and
this part right here this is where guys
like John and I come in to Train
specific people you need a hyper aware
individual you need someone that is
aware of their surroundings in a hyper
aware way not someone that's kind of
like just doing the job and all cut it
up it has to be done specifically so any
for this particular job you got to hire
someone that's OCD you know or like anal
like they're just like I want this to be
it has to be perfect because if you
don't have that person this is gonna
mold
you're gonna leave moisture in your hash
and you're basically they may turn it to
garbage especially if you start making
it all large-scale especially if you
start producing pounds of it so we've
got this what I want to do now is we're
gonna have a little sip of this water
we're going to take this inside and
we're gonna I guess we can break it up
into cardboard and that'll start the
drying process we'll probably leave it
on the cardboard for two to three days
you know although tonight in the next 20
to 30 minutes I will hand press a piece
India style and I will get as much of
the moisture out as we can and then
we're gonna plug in the female and we're
gonna do Jamaican milk bubbles you're
making doves yeah all right let's get
some cups and drink some of this water
camera grab a seat join me
oh when the music just came on sorry we
didn't film us drinking the juice guys
it was delicious everyone was pretty
blown away by the process good happy
times here in Jamaica we sell pressed
out a little tiny bit cuz I mean come on
how are we not gonna try some so wait
for it to making bummed out joy this is
a 73 that's what I call my Madison
that's what I say every day and this 73
is by far the best seven who ever saw he
saw the goosebumps I'm a little excited
you know you know yeah this is exciting
though there's a little bit difference
between always being happy and being
excited to try something amazing first
time first rip yeah thanks guys
to me this is something I'll never
forget
[Music]
its moist so we're gonna get through
that little bit of water hit first and
there we go now it's that's what we're
looking for that's what we came here we
are resident chasers
definitely needs to be dry but you know
what like we always say we got right now
and you just nail down boom we can
actually put the bombs right right
here's something we do quite event we
get excited John get excited we've even
hit it with water so you know what the
first water anyone that wants to hit it
we can hit it off camera so John and I
are gonna keep at it here we're gonna
keep smoking the full melt you're making
bubble and stay one guys all right well
Wow we wrapped it up we just popped a
bunch of that fresh 73 amazing dabbed it
up on the DL super nice everyone loved
it we gave them all nice little doses
they fed us this wonderful soup that
they actually put breadfruit in from the
tree behind us out I want you to cut it
Simon cooker excellent very nice very
special first day in Jamaica has been
absolutely top-notch it was just
completely off the charts you know
having rich of spices pick us up at the
airport that was and then just coming
and hooking up with these other guys
it's been a good day let's just say and
we're gonna see you guys tomorrow on
bubble man's world so keep watching
[Music]
hey how's it going guys yeah man I'm
Johnny de Gama in the hizzy we're just
chilling out now at the Spanish Court
Hotel this is one of the pretty nice
hotels in downtown Kingston I guess it
was up this way and it's sort of with a
nicer houses already drive up the
mountain
turn the music down crapping out on me a
little bit probably hear us a little
better if we don't have that going on
so and Johnny I came up here to do a
little bit of video editing we puffed a
few bowls out of the kit man that's
always fun
he found it I thought I spilt it even
though I didn't see anything new but
yeah we have one screen so we can't
really mess around with it in the way
using it would be fairly detrimental we
do have the mothership in the D mail
here which is upstairs in the room we
are hitting that earlier after we made
some bubble you've got a nice group of
guys that we've never met before
after we got picked up at the airport we
went and met some other guys and we made
some some nice bubble we got about a
pound and herb that we ran through the
five gallon bucket and we got an
incredible return that we need three
baby
the 73 kicked ass I'm not gonna lie I'm
on the 90 shirt if it was a contest I
lost the game tonight
73 one is toke on Festivus 73 was ever
the 73 who is and was epic so we're
gonna be I photograph the whole thing
I'll show you guys what it looks like
now what a great first night in Kingston
it's past great
[ __ ] like this just doesn't happen in
jump fellow's it seems to happen all the
time it's it's what's going on it's the
people who were looking for the
education with what's going on and
trying to better look at medicine for
patients I'd say that and and its really
really really into is that everybody and
they're really curious because they're
and the best part about it is yeah smoke
the herb feed your endo cannabinoid
system John and I are gonna be at it
well John actually told me today which I
was really stoked on he was like you
know we landed at the airport at one
o'clock 1:30 by the time we cleared the
airport and we're actually could say we
were in Jamaica and cleared customs and
we were
we had it was a great experience so we
land we get picked up within how many
hours where we smoking how much they let
me at 6:40 so you know once again sure I
don't have to promote hitting the super
wet bubble but I'll tell you when you
fly your ass to Kingston Jamaica and you
link up with some IRA dudes that want to
make it some kind bud turned into
isolated resin glands and it turns out
as well as it turned out for us I mean
right after finishing the Mushaf made us
breadfruit stew from plants I watched
him go outside cut down thing what's bad
with a breadfruit walked away he's
picking on some other things sort of
like a dumpling or a potato really
delicious Wow I haven't had it check it
out
one more cold thing I'm gonna try I've
been in Jamaica many many times John's
first trip so I'm kind of trying to like
every day I want John to like you know
tomorrow for breakfast John's gonna have
a key which is you know a very popular
client here to make a huge tree pink
fruit that opens up splits with his
three black seeds and within those you
get this yellowish egg like looking subs
like scrambled eggs
okay it's just delicious
so we're gonna check it out tomorrow
check it I'm excited everywhere I go
this fruit mangoes
and then all these different flew higher
a pie a couple nice berries it's amazing
so you know what I mean
mark said when I got here I was gonna
say I was gonna live here I'm not gonna
eat fruit here every day absolutely we
haven't even barely tapped into the epic
fruit we're gonna be on that for sure
tomorrow I don't think we're gonna waste
any time we're probably gonna get out to
a ganja field
no problem your art yeah I'm gonna
create a new term for you guys out there
it's the F F F which is fresh frozen
field run program yeah we're gonna be
doing fresh frozen field runs and I hope
you guys can join us I hope you guys
keep watching bubble man's world check
out John's channel John H for fellow on
YouTube thanks for watching guys we
appreciate
[Music]
you