[Music]
welcome you to our panel discussion on
ganja marijuana Sensa hemp cannabis is
it really Jamaica's green
gold I should tell you and I see my
beloved friend and colleague Professor
Morrison across the world I I must tell
you that my first and early recollection
of
gandra
is being about 9 years old and my
brother being found with a
sliff and my my parents were so
aggravated and agitated that my brother
could be turning raster and smokeing
this SP that they ship him off to the
United States was a very pleasant
recollection I must say and then the the
the other recollection I have is of a
woman drinking some strong gja tea and
screaming and shouting and speaking very
loudly and I thought this gja thing is
just not on but today I spent the
morning looking at ganja and I thought
to myself but this thing can't make
money ganja and and other medicinal
plants have the ability to generate
revenues for Jamaica let me give you the
numbers I like the
numbers the worldwide market for ganja
products is up to 140 to150 billion
us but if you look at natural products
well that that that those numbers just
baffle my mind .5 trillion is what Henry
L told us this morning and so for the
first time at last I'm sure that there
are some of you in the audience that are
saying to yourself but this G thing not
so bad enough perhaps it's something
that we should look
at and
so if you were someone who is 80 years
old in Jamaica suppose You' be ask said
should we really be making gandra
products making products from gandra
does it have harmful effects on human
health do people lose their mind do they
go crazy when they drink some Gadget you
have gja products or does it have
medicinal
benefits because today we heard that it
it it can help you with nausea after
chemotherapy you know I have a friend
you know she's a boy I had a chick be
for just one day guy is a soap in some
grum and when I drink it it gone forever
so thisen man have to try this chick be
thing put but the for foreigners chick
be is a virus that when you get it you
pray to die CU it's so so many pains and
so much no I'm serious it's pains and
high fever and arthritis has a new
meaning when she had it she tell me Bon
this Gand thing
works um the second question I think
that we would ask if we are going to go
into this gandra business can we produce
enough of it and what are the standards
do we we would need to meet to grow and
use it for medicinal
purposes should we register G for
grows whether they're growing it using
green houses or they're using growing it
um in the soil should we should we be
doing that sort of thing um or should we
just syn synthesize it in the lab just
make it in the lab as every says we can
do um and if we are to maintain our
competitive and comparative
advantage shouldn't we be preserving the
good stuff H told us what today so we
have the good stuff
remember being on my farm and somebody
says they were growing Gand on my farm I
said no God not today but today I said
to them come let me a little G you
understand me because you said we have
the best stuff as
usual but should we yes man this thing
is real truth I just keeping it real
should should we be preserving the
original germ plas that's a big word for
making certain the real Stu Still
Remains and or and should we be
developing new products so we can
maintain our competitive advantage we're
ahead of the
competition um there are the
issues one of our colleagues one of our
panelists will look at the economics of
of Gano but if we're going to do this
thing properly we need to have an
economic framework we need to look at
what incentives are we going to put in
place how we're going to help smmes we
have to look at how do we find financing
for do we use the regular um dbj funding
to to finance but I hear this thing is
business big business it's not small
money so how will we Finance it how will
we move from research and development to
products how we going to get that
Innovation into something that is
bankable and which people want to
finance so these are the questions that
we will be looking at in this discussion
this
afternoon we'll have Dr Winston de who
will look at the medicinal and health
implications he's a psychiatrist I'll
tell you a little bit more about it so
you can tell whether when you smoke when
you drink the good Gand tea whether you
do better or not and Mr haon Watson we
look at the scientific implications he's
the one is going to tell us how we're
going to preserve the good stuff and Mr
Paul B when he joins us will tell us
about the farming
implications Mr Tony vura I hope I
pronounced it right Tony we look at the
economic implications and the Reverend G
harot we talk about the biblical and
moral them Li them Lord you know that
kind of thing but you know if you're
religious it says the herbs the good
herbs are for the healing of the
Nations a feel of Prayer of R har but
he's going to look at the moral and
biblical um issues I said to my friend
but why would he care for Hy what is
wrong with us is we not smoking the good
deed um Dr we are drinking it we are
making ointments for arthritis finally I
can get over my chick symptoms you
understand so why would he care if there
are how could there possibly be some
biblical and moral issues related to it
but he'll tell us he'll explain it to us
and Dr William Corney who was scheduled
to speak will will be replaced by Mr
courney Betty from Timeless herbal care
that will tell us about the medicinal
tourism implications how can we get
tourists in when I looked at San G on
and I looked at the various persons that
were being um having some kind of
positive um uh relief from their
epilepsy or serious pain probably we
could get people to come in now Mr Betty
to to somewhere neutral else or up in up
in M or near to a compound and they have
the cool bre and everything is fine we
can just we won't smoke it we'll just
drink it we'll have a pill we'll eat it
but these are not the issues is what we
will discuss in this panel discussion we
want you after that after they have
given the opening each person will spend
5 10 minutes we want to have the
vibrancy we want to hear from you and
let and you tell us whether you agree
with them and whether you have other
perspective that we can look at well let
me tell you a little bit about our
panelists and the first one that will be
speaking is Dr Winston de Dr Winston de
is a
lecturer in
patry De at the University of the West
IND this mon Jamaica he's a consultant
psychiatrist and a Clinical Director of
the addiction treatment services unit at
the University Hospital of the West
Indies he completed his MD at the
University of pet Hungary his
postgraduate degree in Psychiatry at the
University of the West Indies he Masters
in public health specializing in
Substance Abuse and Mental Health at the
John Hopkins University and a full
bright hum Hubert humford Fellowship in
substance abuse education prevention and
treatment at the John Hopkins
University I find this particularly
interesting that he's the chairman of
the Bell hospital so if you think we're
all going to go Ludy he'll be able to
talk to you about it understand me and
treat you but I don't think that's what
he plans to say he's the deputy chairman
of the Jamaican National Council on drug
abuse chairman of the national homeless
committee amongst other things and past
president of the Jamaica Psychiatric
association ladies and gentlemen help me
to welcome Dr Winston de
[Applause]
thank you very much uh evening friends
all want to thank the organizers for
inviting me I I didn't know too much
about the format and so on but uh
because I do these lectures every at the
University it was difficult to get
something together for you but uh a very
important matter that we're discussing
here today uh as a psychiatrist I'm
affiliated with all aspects of of
cannabis as an addiction psychiatrist as
a specialty I certainly see the other
end of things where persons who are not
so lucky as others are uh succumb to the
ill effects of cannabis uh and in the
same breath as The Clinical Director of
medican limited and the chairman of the
a clinical committee I'm involved
currently at a very Advanced stage with
clinical trials using cannabis for
treating a wide range of illnesses and
so uh certainly recognize the positives
uh in terms of cabus use uh for
medicinal purposes and support that and
in the same breath give my specialty I
recognize the negatives and treat the
patients including a while ago which is
why I was almost need uh youngster of
age 16 with canus in psychosis so a
certain am Expos to both ends and have
to share with you uh that aspect I've
been asked of uh comment on the effects
of cannabis some of you may or may not
know uh persons who are pro cannabis are
more likely to be associated with what
for them are positive effects uh which
is necessarily on good balance and so I
certainly will speak to all aspects uh
very briefly this evening and it's been
a lot of debate around the whole uh
issue of decriminalization which I'm
also actively involved in recognizing
the challenges that we Face uh as a
country in terms of the management of
any substance related disorder in fact
I'll share with you the most recent
National school's drug survey of
November last year where and this is
really alarming so I've been with
national C on drug abuse for the past 10
to 12 years and I've seen the amount of
work theyve been doing in The Last 5
Years this has doubl tripled in terms of
their efforts and the number of man
hours for lack of a better work that
they're putting in educating youngsters
in particular about J despite of that in
the last November survey 60 to 70% of
youngsters reported not having heard a
single World about a prevention message
that clearly tells you that the funding
available for these messages is just not
where it should be uh the National
Council of drug abuse in spite of its
efforts needs more resources to do more
to reach persons who may not be as lucky
as others are and so uh I'm very happy
and I tell patients who come to me if
you see positives in what you do that's
fine with me very happy uh and in the
same breath if you're experiencing
negatives I'm able to identify them and
and and help you a lot so my talk isn't
necessarily for our gces as it comes as
the need arises uh and I'm sure
Professor low spoke spoke to this slide
in terms of the number of areas that
internationally were seen uh ganja being
used uh that includes uh as an analgesic
as an anti-inflammatory drug
antispasmodic and so on large range I'm
pretty sure recover this this morning
probably use the exact slide I'm looking
at because we work together uh the point
is at medic limited we determined that
we'll start our clinical trials with
pain Related Disorders chronic colant
pain postoperative pain uh acute pain uh
pain in the gynecological area and so on
large area with the potential to help
persons this why we are Physicians
because we want to to help people uh and
the potential to help Jamaicans do
better with the illnesses that they have
in terms of the social economic
development potential development which
others are here are far more versed in
what I'll just share with you uh that
globally currently it's a 2.5 billion US
business that's a medicinal cannabis uh
component discussing and it's expected
to be doubled in the next 3 years and so
many developing countries like ours uh
with uh economic challenges covers could
use the industry to help grow their
economies but is it all positive and
that's a resounding know uh and I'll
just now real quickly share with you the
negative effects uh and so the main
psychoactive ingredient meaning the
ingredient leading to the potential
problems with cannabis I treat every day
is Delta 9 trans THC I hen to say though
we support medicinal cannabis and we
recognize that Delta 9 trans THC is the
main psychoactive ingredient we also
recognize that where you separate the
products and use only the canab thees
for treatment they don't work as
effectively as when you have all
components present in the products that
you're using we appreciate and recognize
that and so the attempt is to reduce the
the Del 9 THC component to a tolerable
level in products so obviously in our
clinical trials we therefore need to
exclude persons with schizophrenia
because we recognize that they will be
worse potentially if they are exposed to
any amount of th so these are all the
challenges that we have in spite of that
the potential gain is far more than the
loss and so we proceed and and press
along but to look at the potential
negatives I start with uh addiction to
cannabis very well established that 9%
of adults using cannabis May develop an
add an addiction to cannabis the number
uh increases significantly for
adolescent so for children it's 50% of
those and hence the focus on the
National Council on drug abuse and
preventing any drug use and in this case
we're discussing cannabis in adolesence
because that's one in two and if you
have two children it's likely one of
them if the both use who may succumb to
some of the negative effects so that's
what we call the drug use disorder the
cannabis use disorder meaning the
addiction the DSM 5 which is the
diagnostic statistical manual mental
diseases which we use as our B for laal
better work for illnesses that we treat
and recognize specific illnesses
associated with cannabis the dsm5 came
about in March of
2013 and the illnesses they recognized
include I was you cannabis intoxication
uh cannabis withdrawal well refer well
established I've had a couple of
patients with that it's not the most
common ince it is present Canabis
intoxication delum and usually in my
presentations I have this one
highlighted in red because people my
specialty I see these patients every day
can of just Inu psychotic disorder so
people do get mad from smoking and canab
scan meing we need to be very clear
about that in persons with an underlying
vulnerability and susceptibility and so
just real quickly because this is so
important because we're on sure the
genes coding for psychiatric illnesses
we cannot today through genetic mapping
determine that you are at risk because I
found the gene in your system and so you
might not want to use we're not sure and
so you're taking a chance we're sure
though that if you are mentally fit
today but your cousin is schizophrenic
your mother is schizophrenic your aunt
is schizophrenic it's highly probable
that you have the for psychosis and
probably will Su up to use it that's why
two if today you in Utch or the
University of West Indies and whatever
discipline you're in you think you want
to finish with a good enough grade
because we are clear on the impact of
cannabis on memory and learning we can
categorically state that you might not
want to use Canabis uh but just to list
then some of the effects and I close
with my most recent resarch arch with my
team on cannabis and memory which the
findings of which was very alarming uh
the findings were alarming to us but the
common physiological effects I just lift
out a few decrease liido
constipation uh mild gr constriction
followed by
gradation uh axum and that is normal
gate in fact I used to be in the Army
was a milary officer as a medical
officer you could easily detect who was
using cannabis because of the gate as
assciated and so Military Officers
usually walk pride and so on so the
person see kind of leave a little bit
and so on you can rest assur uh if
there's no NE neurological condition
then they would test positive which is
one of the things not allowed in the so
that's what my job at the time uh but
just to lift a few more uh restlessness
depersonalization these are the
psychotic features now and these are
features which users of recreational
Cannabis enjoy but to others it's an
illness so dep personaliz is where
another term would be an out of Body
Experience where you're all seeing
yourself move around but you're not in
yourself if you follow what I'm saying
der realization you feel unreal you
don't feel a part of the world uh Panic
reactions paranoid ideation and of
course the the the main uh and most
negative of the illness is the Cannabis
indu psychotic disorder which
unfortunately for some present is an
acute psychotic State a briefy I episode
you treat they discontinue their use and
they may recover and be well but some
and we don't know cuz we're not magici
have to wait on AOW time even with and
after treatment Stills hypo that's an
unfortunate thing and you never know
before if that would be us taking a
chance I'll close now with cannabis and
its impact on neurocognitive performance
that's my most recent research for the
prob shortly uh we looked at the impact
of Canabis on neuroptic performance of
Jamaican adolesence we had a sample of
youngsters in Jamaican schools who smoke
we uh at least three SPS per week we had
a sample of youngsters who were not re
users and we confirmed that using
testing and so on and we looked at their
performance in various ways and so
learning can be broken down into a
number of areas to get into the the
intricacies of that but the most
important is that our findings show that
in all aspects that we looked at all
that was what was so we know there is
impact if we looked at 10 things we
expected maybe six or seven would be
impacted all 10 were impacted negatively
in terms of learning by E cannabists so
that's food for thought for our country
where our children are not doing very
well in things like mathematics English
they known uh throughout the Caribbean
and in Jamaica and so with those kinds
of challenges and given the monetary
resources or lack there off we really
need to stand back a little and though
we recognize the potential gain from the
medicinal cannabis not move too much
ahead of ourselves but keep it real and
ensure that should there be any changes
that we have the funds available to step
up the prevention messages at this time
I'm not so sure those funds are
available thank you very
[Applause]
much thank you very much Dr Von it's
really interesting because all morning I
heard about how good Gand is and how it
helps learning but
only um well should we drink it no
should we drink it or should we eat it
should we rub it on our knees that that
we can ask him in a little while but he
did say that the main psychoactive
element that affects you negatively I
mean correct is Delta 9
txc and the rest of us don't know what
that means I'm correct okay but I must
tell you that a man is coming
immediately after Dr Winston de that
will tell us about Delta and everything
else am I correct he's going to look at
the scientific implications of ganja
marijuana
s you hand again no you won't cannabis
is it really Jamaica's green gold
because nothing in life comes with it
being perfect am I correct so when
law told me today that CBDs and he'll
explain all what that means CBDs are
more valuable than gold than an ounce of
gold I thought good Lord you tell me
there problems but by all that money I'm
sure that there some people who are
saying that and he will look at the
scientific implications of of of Gant so
we're going to ask Mr hathon Watson who
is the acting executive director of the
scientific research Council and I'm sure
your St said the acting executive
director of the scientific research
Council believes in yes he does he's one
of the persons one of the persons who
isolated s of critical compounds early
in 1969 he Leed at the College of Arts
Science and Technology now Utch where
among his several achievements he
founded the chemical Technology Program
he was the first to establish and
publish the structure of a unique
compound found in minute quantities in a
plant of worldwide forensic and
medicinal interest we know what that is
that's gandra
right that's gandra let us not deny the
fact that gandra has tremendous
medicinal practice and I'm so excited to
hear about this that there's a whole
long blurb about him and his experience
at se and his experience here and his
work on science technology and
Innovation but iare you all of that so
Mr hon want please we invite you to
speak to us now about the scientific
implications of
[Applause]
G I will speak as soon as I can get over
the part about G reduced liido
[Applause]
about
that seriously after he lectures this
morning I said I was going to give it a
try um colleagues um we scientists have
yet to find a way to make science and
technology
sexy so I won't be very
long in terms of the scientific
implications of
G what we
SRC are really interested in
one Jamaica is known to have a high
grade
stuff originally so but over these past
years they have been a dilution of the
breed by various strains if not species
which have been brought into the
island we will be interested in
preserving the original ganja the
original germ plasm as the moderator
said and one of the reasons why we are
interested in preserving the original
plaz it's a science is very funny you
know today you vilify something and the
next day you find out is your savior
because though we vilify THC and I'm not
making a case before
THC in a recent study one out of Spain
and one out of France it has been shown
that THC
suppresses the growth of cancer cells in
the liver and the brain so we don't know
whether 10 years down the road CHC will
TC will be a drug in demand in any case
part of the Mandate of the scientific
research council is to preserve the
original plant whether it be ganja
whether it be Aki whether it be nury or
what have you so that is one of the
first thing that we will do with Gan
working of course with um university of
the West Indies you heard from B mlin
this morning of the wonderful work that
they are doing in identifying the differ
strength ganja in westand and St
Elizabeth
[Music]
the other aspect of the science that we
are interested in you heard mention that
we
isolated and you can
denno um way back some
time um it was isolated and
characterized so we know exactly what it
is but no further work has been done on
it maybe because it's one of those
components in ganja that is present in
very minute quantities I remember
getting you to get the ganja from the
police and a 50 of compressed G might
give you lesson and O of the stuff that
we
isolated and so we are going to go back
there you're going to look at whether or
not it has any
beneficial um property or if in fact it
is harmful to to to mankind because
sometimes um we don't have the charts of
the compound here sometimes there just a
slight difference between one compound
and another that makes a difference well
if you even take say t THC there are two
different thcs in the plant one with a
certain feature going this way and one
with the same feature going this way the
one which is going this way is a cytic
one the one which is going that way has
been shown to have no CYO active effect
at all so sometimes the features found
in the compound can influence the the
property and we believe that in the case
of canab trial which is the one that we
isolated
there are is feature there are features
present that give us um hope that we
could have something good um so we want
to go through with clinical trials with
those who see to have an effect first
and nice and if the results are positive
then we will move to human trials that
is going to take some time because it's
a slow process maybe year maybe two and
this can also be very costly but we
believe that is an Avenue that should be
pursued also at the same time we
isolated another true canab o c21
h304 um we know what the molecular
structure is but we don't know exactly
how the is arranged we know that Mel is
a clean compound because the melting
point is 107 218 so it is a very pure
compound what you need to do now is
going in back and isolate structure of
that compound and much the same as CDT
you want to look at clinical trials with
mice and then man so there are two
aspect of study
there um simultaneously while we going
back into the plan for these compounds
we are also going to look if um if there
are other compound here that might be
new and not so far known you know
interesting when I started working on
ganja the purpose for the for the
research was that at the
time it was said that it is a female
plant I don't know why they say all
things about me it's a female plant that
gave you the height true they SP it the
female plant has more of the resin than
the male um so we could distinguish
physically what they are but what the
Govern of the day wanted was the
chemical differentiation can you find
the chemicals in there that
differentiate the male from the female
but before about 6 months into the
research um the government of changed
his mind and just say gja is gja if you
pH with gja male or female you get
lock fortunately by then some very
interesting compounds started to drop
out of G and we want to I just say that
to say that while we go back for t for
CDT and this other compound we'll be
looking to see if any other new compound
will drop out
G if you listen to the various talks
this morning you will see that there's a
strong case there for neutrals and
cosmical already there are several under
the market and I know my visiting
friends from the north do have samples
of various um canabo products Henry L as
you know launched seven new products the
other day and Dr lard in addition to his
two asmal and kenol is launching TOS so
is a fledging industry but we feel that
the the the the the it has enormous
potential and so we will continue to
look at developing um those
cosmical and those neuticals
the other area that we SRC would be
concerned with is that we need to
provide robust Backup Service in terms
of analytical support because if we are
going to
establish an
industry we have to establish an
industry that can meet International
standard we can't grow G and make money
here in Jamaica yes we can make two
shill but we don't want to make two
shill want to make a couple pounds well
and the only way we're going to do that
we have to export and if you are going
to export you have to make sure that it
needs the standard that is required by
the by the World Market certainly um
people are going to want to know whether
or not the the ganza they are importing
as any insecticidal residue on it they
want to know if any soil residue on it
and one of the things that we would hope
from SRC that we could do
is to provide certificate of of analys
in that if you bring your G and we test
it we should be able to say this
particular sample of gja has x% THC y%
CBD and so this is one area again in
which we are hoping that we can provide
service and when the industry will have
enlarged and got real big you we can
employ a lot of analysts and Chemists in
our lives thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you very much Mr Watson our next
speaker is not unfamiliar to anybody in
Jamaica and I told you in my opening
remarks that in the good old days when I
was a kid which wasn't such a long time
ago I told you that um my parents
shipped off my brother because he was
found with a spliff and they said Lord
God is going to get into this ra Affair
and gja smoking thing and Paul Burke is
one of those Visionaries you know who in
the period that people did not find
ganja useful and and the thing to do he
believed in something else and he said I
I I once when I think of Paul Burke I
think of the phrase vision is the art of
seem The Impossible because 20 years ago
you just couldn't think that one day a
group of nice middle class people would
be sitting in the Pegasus or wherever um
talking about
Gand
uh Paul started his campaign some time
ago asking the Jamaican people to Rally
around the idea of the decriminalization
of of ganja and the use of ganja for
medicinal purposes but I said before if
we're going to do this if we going to
start a ganja based um industry can we
grow enough of it or do we need to
synthesize it and if we grow it how will
we grow it what are the standards we
must meet how we're going to trace it
from start to finish how are we going to
do life cycle analysis well Paul Burke
is going to explain that to us he's
going to tell us the farming
implications of a viable productive and
profitable ganja industry Mr
[Applause]
hi good afternoon
everybody you know today is a strange
day I've never put my key inion and the
car has not started until this evening
and that's why I'm for some inexplicable
reason it just would not stop it's not a
about problem so I to I I apologize
for
my and will take what I minute
my entropy
was really one human rights first K
growing up in Rockport and just seeing
the brutality being
unleash by members of the train of
conary fors against young people young
Ras parents anybody in general for
having a SP and people seem to forget
that up to
1972 it was a 18 Monon mandatory
sentence for a s of young
see anything at all there's no
discretion of the court so really from
that point of time we a CR Wicked
terrible law putting your people primary
into