so I just got here to the grounds where
the uh Roots rest the fari Fest and the
High Times Cannabis Cup is happening we
got niab bingy drummers going on over
here and we got to get some of this on
the camera this is
[Music]
legit
[Applause]
I'm
[Music]
the
mighty
to
[Music]
tr to
our we love
[Applause]
[Music]
by
I
[Applause]
[Music]
you Sil
Fallen
God RS up
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
be and th
children
I
from Over
[Music]
the one
another our Sid and our
tears
[Music]
our the
high
[Music]
[Applause]
of be
one
our
[Applause]
God
[Music]
might to
and oh
and with
[Music]
[Applause]
and
[Music]
i
[Applause]
i i my God
[Music]
[Applause]
I
[Music]
[Applause]
you
[Music]
you can't just give what to
[Applause]
you
[Music]
[Applause]
for
joh the angel
[Applause]
with
[Music]
[Applause]
I
[Music]
you you hear the pr I am
my
[Music]
B let the
words
meditation
[Music]
of
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
so let the
[Music]
word
his Imperial Majesty Emperor highis the
last of the first so we say princes and
princesses must out of Babylon
Ethiopians now stretch for irans
ohop Divine
Majesty into Towell in the parts of
righteousness lead help to forgive that
must be forgiven teach
love
it
wise to th blessing to let the H the
naked
protect and the
INF from the of
enemies must Pro fruitful in these
perilous days enemies are andc
the in the of the
earth
Liv the King of Kings
and the Conquering line of the tribe of
Judah himself in the light of this world
Divine Majesty
Emperor
[Applause]
Emperor again I I should give thanks to
everyone is
here I know some of you might be
experiencing this for the first time but
this is
R yeah and we said that to black and
white don't presses see now I ask you to
just put your hands together for sister
MIT she's the person that will take over
the ceremon from here and introduce the
speaker so could I put your hands
together for sister
M yeah she has been here she had been
here cannabis Heather she has been a
among going on through all type of
tribulation and persecution because you
know the history that rap has gone
through in
Jamaica so um if Sister m is not here
I'm going to ask forward Oh Sister
MIT we said give thanks
sister yeah greetings greetings everyone
we give than to be here give thanks to
my RAR family who brought such a
beautiful welcome to this occasion and I
welcome you warmly as rasa fari what
you're seeing and witnessing here is our
daily lives it's our Liberty this was
not a performance in any home in Jamaica
you can go and experience this on a
daily basis because this is how we share
our meditation with our father his
Imperial m day so we say
welcome again this is RAR Roots fest and
we're hosting the High Times Cannabis
Cup I've met some new friends today Fern
hi yes so you know we have a very
special we have to say brother because
um we are brother within Humanities we
are brothers and sisters and this is
somebody who has developed a very close
relationship with us we we don't agree
on everything but um we know that this
is a journey as far
as marijuana Gan is concern this is
something that we have paid the price
for as rasa fari we have suffered a lot
of persecution marginalization
tribulation and um we are now
experiencing a moment of Celebration
towards greater Liberation and we say
give thanks for that
so for all the ones amongst us from
every nation race and Creed who has been
a part of the advocacy for the
liberation of this plant that we know as
the healing of the nation we say one
more Applause and we say give thanks
again especially to our elders of the
rasa fari Community who as we said have
made so much sacrifice and have paid the
price for it we don't ever forget them
whether they're in the ancestral realm
or they're still with
us so at this time I want to welcome on
stage to share a few words with us
someone who has you know started opening
the gates who has helped to relax things
a little bit for us and to help us as
RAR to feel a little bit more at ease we
know there's still a journey in front of
us Danny in the house he's with us we
know that and um we'll just take some
higher steps from here after after this
occasion we're going to be moving
forward very very positively so I want
to welcome without further Ado the
Minister of Justice himself Senator Mark
golden to come and share a few
[Music]
words thank you so this is the Min
Justice here he's going to
be liing de man all other
distinguished and hello ladies and
gentlemen who are
here I um just want to say how much of
an honor it is for me to be standing
here before you this afternoon in
beautiful
nigil we really have a fantastic venue
here for this event and God is blessing
us J is blessing us with a nice gentle
rain and we and we in Jamaica have to
give thanks for rain because we don't
always have it so when we get it we very
appreciate it preacher love
it ladies and gentlemen this is a
historic occasion for us here in Jamaica
this is the first such event to be put
on in this country in April of this year
the parliament here passed um a law
which made a number of changes to the
way in which ganja is treated in this
country um and did a number of things
I'm not going to go into the details of
that at this stage Maybe on another
occasion during the festival however one
important thing living and living at one
with
nature so all of us I think should take
advantage of the opportunities to learn
more about this religion about the
spirituality and when we leave here
eventually we will I think have a much
more fullsome understanding of that it
is also been an opportunity for High
Times magazine to partner with the
organizers of this event Ras V is the
conceptualized and Main driving force
behind this event um and rasa far in
along with his team um and I want to Big
up the team big up RAS a for having
brought this thing
together I want to thank High Times for
partnering with the with the Jamaican
rasa farai Community to have Jamaican
High Times Cannabis Cup in the rasa far
Roots fest and that of course has been
the Catalyst that has brought many
people from outside of Jamaica to come
to N Grill to experience this unique
Festival One of a Kind it will not be
like any other that has gone before it
is my hope that this Festival will help
to provide economic opportunities for
the rasa farai Community as well and um
Can will grow from strength to strength
I would love to see this to be uh an
event that is enjoyed by all with mutual
respect and love
and that we pay we leave here feeling
uplifted and we leave here looking
forward to this event being repeated
again in the future and becoming um
something that is very very meaningful
for for Jamaica and its economy as well
so ladies and gentlemen i w going to
talk for any longer I just want to thank
you all for being here and I urge you
all to enjoy what we have to offer here
good
time
[Applause]
set up in Jamaica he deserves everything
in terms of Honor that he receives in
relation to his work and we're going to
continue to give him that strength as a
family and we're going to want to one
strengthen each other so Ras
I yes R and give thanks for creating
this cross but R it is with great honor
that I welcome you to the microphone my
brother yeah good than yeah really my
sister you know really my sister you see
how we look
alike I'm pretty one though yeah yeah
yeah I was about to say that you didn't
have to say that all right anyway again
I to give thanks and greeting as usual
again in the name of
his Empress
ESS really a pleasure for man to be here
and like sister n say yes I have been
there on the Forefront but this could
not have been done without individuals
like sister
ni Marcus
goth um Ras ivi B Jo you name the
team and it could not have been done
again without the honorable Mark Wy want
to give thanks
for um
Steve I want to give thanks for KY
because after we started this in West
and it was a domino reaction and
parishes all over groups came up all
over because they
realized that with the
amendment within the laws as it regard
to her ganza
marijuana it opened the
door for people foreign investors and
other people to come into
Jamaica and we REM do not have any
problem with
investors where we have a
problem I do not want to see this
industry being
manipulated by people with money foreign
investors are local
Jamaicans there are certain people Rari
and grassroot people who have gone to
prison who have paid a heavy price to
keep this industry alive and if there's
money to be made out of this this
industry I am saying that these people
should also benefit
[Applause]
economically and
again while we are here I hope that we
learn we'll be
having um we have already have Utch we
have UI we have the dsj that will be
coming through so a lot of different
agencies and entities governmental and
otherwise that will be coming through so
the A and objective is to really make
this like I've said before into a real
educational
program learning in different
ways now why I took the stand as a
youth as a youth growing up I have I'm
from a grad
background working class background
and being a youth who I had a
privilege I got a common entrance
examination at at the age of 11 plus at
end live to go to Manning High School
the second oldest educational
institution in the
isand and as such it has helped I to
develop my educational
ability but as a youth I never feel
satisfied watching police coming amongst
my grassroot people my working class
people and harassing them in any way
whatsoever so the fact that I had the
educational ability I took it as a
pleasure to confront police to confront
the government and as such like sister M
said we have arranged marches marches
upon marches letters upon letters until
today give thanks we are here we can
bring we can travel with herb we get
permit that we can go and pick up herb
we can travel with even 10 pound of herb
I mean those who have the permit but
again I have to give thanks for the work
of The Honorable Mark Golding because
there
are I remember we had written to a prime
minister seeking an audience with him to
discuss the issue of marijuana the
educational system the issue of
reparation and repatriation we never got
an
A but honorable marking is a man like
that like anytime calling he's
there the only way this minister is not
there if is if he cannot be
there and I think that is a good sign
because if you are a leader you must be
prepared to sit with your people and
talk with
[Music]
them A House Is Never built from the top
go down is always built from from the
bottom up and the people of this
country descendants of enslaved African
people we know what it is to
suffer the chain were on our hands and
our feet the chain has been moved it has
been placed
psychologically but more so it has been
placed
economically because even when we
liberate ourselves mentally like Bob
sing the song in man at yourself from
mental slavery nothing but ourselves can
change our
mind even with that we still have the
economic situation to face so this is an
opportunity that we can utilize this
product to help uplift the economic
condition of
Jamaica we know that the United States
is there and they are there with a big
stick over our head but for years they
have sent helicopters come to Jamaica to
cut down the marijuana that was grown
here they have sent they it has been
spread with chemical such as paraquat
now the US Affair is doing what more
than half the states have now legalized
and decriminalized ganja not only for
medical uses but also for recreational
uses and I think that's very
hypocritical of the United States of
America if we cannot do
what we think is
right and if we cannot be
allowed to plant her to utilize it
medically and economically then the
United States of America should not be
allowed to do that
[Music]
either now the United States of America
is doing that because they realize the
medicinal potential and the economic
potential of her
and I think we as black people and as a
nation in Jamaica should also be allowed
to use marijuana to develop our
economy it is a fact that for years
research and research has been carried
out not only in the United States but
other places of the world and when I and
I rest fire I used to say her to the
healing of the
nation when I and I used to tell them
about veget and we life when I and I
used to tell them that Africa is the
Cradle of mankind and the cradle of
civilization we were laugh at we were
mocked we were sconed but today it is
all been proven so if the rest of man
was right in saying those things it will
be proven that the rights of man is
right in everything that he
said we are we hope to use this Avenue
we hope to use this space again to
educate our people about his Imperial
Majesty is last about the empress
Empress V men we just celebrated the
85th Anniversary of the coronation of
his majesty and her majesty so we want
our people to realize that we do have a
base a historical a theological
anthropological archaeological un name
any Al or any alley that you go down the
r man is there so once again I say give
thanks to the here hope that you will
learn a lot and that when you leave here
here the You'
done well look who I just bumped into
Tony V is in the house here at the
Jamaica Cannabis Cup Roots R the farai
festival that's right only uh 36 hours
of traveling through ice storms and
floods and not bad that's pretty
reasonable some people didn't make it
exact same time that it took to get
answer be you got here before my product
which I sent 9 days ago so that's also
interesting so what uh we're going to
have a quick dab here yeah got some uh
some of this stuff that you might have
saw on Instagram hey why
you
Giant and butter I got bigger ones at
[Music]
home oh yeah I don't know want to stand
[Applause]
there just in the corner even so she's
not affecting so perfect cool all right
moving out the turps oh my God TS oh
here's a little for you there some lemon
pie a little lemon pie
tping lemon pie T right there got to be
like 25 to 40
[Music]
drops oh my
God
that is
ridiculous oh I wish you guys had smell
a vision for this but you don't have it
so it's just like you'll just have to
trust me on that
one no no no this
is tile
out
oh my
God yeah that's just
like that's wrangles so that's first and
foremost you have two gifts lenon pie
gorilla gr beautiful now those are the
gifts that keep on
giving lemon pie and Gorilla
Glue don't put it in a pocket that has a
hole oh my God so nice it's been raining
here most of the day we did catch a
little bit of of the uh the ceremony of
the rasa far chanting and singing which
is beautiful drumming as well but I got
to say Tony V is in the house with the
turs you know people talk about turs and
i' I've smelled a variety of them and I
got to say that Tony's definitely doing
something very unique in the sense that
they're bang on to the strain that they
are when you smell them if you if you
know the strain you will say what from
Devil's harvest seeds just said that is
bang on he smell the Gill glue number
four bang
on beautiful here I got a dab for you
some of my uh Linds OG
Ros and it's just
no
myet
snow
dog this is lemon it's crazy lemon a
good lemon though not that
F the best [ __ ] I possibly have you
don't even need to add
any that's why I
called in
[Music]
there here I'll take that one and you
can have this one there's a carb at the
top right no right here I guess it's not
really the top it's just like the
necken yeah da sent to me very shout out
to ID daab for sending that out I I
broke it very early when it fell over
but
uh it's a good unit man there's tons of
spiders on this thing not just one like
four or five little
dudes you're so going to create a line
in no lineups right no lineups no
lineups hey give thanks to the Tweet
guys for letting us hang out in their
boo right now and share the
turs justb
like no that was in Amsterdam like 2
years ago modified we started with like
these
excessive right
we don't do that anymore you should
check out some of these turs
kimb you smell
that
never yeah let me
get
line it's almost almost a little bit
better to
smell 73 just
get there's a pause
button let it
run bang on holy [ __ ] wow that's
diesel that's cool because especially in
the Diesels um this is the sour diesel
oh yeah yeah
yeah no the Caps you can try the jar
dropping the jar is like you are this
one's really
good Tony drop the jar you don't get to
hold now can you can you have that yeah
that's Point all right cool oh yeah
yeah so I this is the best way I explain
remember folk music and then somebody
came around with a grude tu electric
guitar and turned it all the way up and
his name was HRI that's like what we did
with all music all
that's the best way to explain what
happen it just
went that's what it does to like
response the
modulator that's ridiculous come
together
lovely all right that was goal one 36
hours hanging on to this and not smoking
it it's really hard have way more left
to rip
oh yeah 36 hours yeah but it took my
stuff 9 days so far and it's still not
bring well this is going in the the pipe
this pip yeah
the but a natural dab not a b dab it's
not made with chemicals this is the ital
version of the
dabs it
da I
dab yeah just tiny little pieces exactly
so yeah you do so this so this is a
little chain I've been
doing wow that was why I was wondering
how you would
go the
[Music]
medicine but it's not really like
[Applause]
it's different what's
going my halo
shattered that was
amazing The Taste on that was so [ __ ]
ridiculous wow TP flavor all around the
lips my trip just got better I was
having a bad day not going to lie having
a bit of a bad day but Tony tpine rolled
through and he modulated my entire
day
[Music]
TS smell that
yeah if you can feel it from here it's
pretty
good that gosh no these are pure uh tpin
and then we're smoking rosin and bubble
has
[Applause]
[Music]
break
an hour 45
minutes was like
okay
you a burn burn popcorn never get
the well you affect it drastically
so test you go to and
[Music]
then all right well this is going to go
on for hours so I'm going to take a
break I think I'm going to be speaking
really soon we'll get back to you guys
in a
bit holding that forever oh no cool so
in this table we have Tony tpine and bu
man birdy's in the house
birdie dude we're here we're in the
grill we're at the roots R the fary
festival dude so many hash churches
we're waiting for this moment right I
know it's here yeah man respect over
here we got someone selling herbs at
this
table so what we going the herbalist
nice the
herbalist see what you
got going in on those turs you want to
give
one
oh my God you put a giant dab of turps
on there that's a lot wellow it's a
whole yeah that's a lot man that's like
a that's uh that's a lot that's a
lot
show oh smell
it tpps would have been fun back in the
day to prank straight people with you
just like dump some t on some straight
people and then like watch them get
pulled over and
harassed Tony
turpy well it won't be going in
there I said it won't be going in there
why well because that's like a $3,000
pipe with an electric nail and that's
like a Chinese uh you know
uh they're different yeah yeah it'll
taste like a million bucks this like a
million bucks plus through that everyone
gets to hit it if it goes in there he
just gets to hit it
yeah people you got to make your own
it's like
uh so good drop drop on the catch yeah
Tony doesn't drop that was nuts I was
feeling your pain there though
man oh
my but it's true you
know I don't
know you got me man you got me wrong you
got me wrong I was looking from to Qui
in
my
came he he'll definitely let you hit it
out of here I didn't want to follow that
I didn't want to hit see you know you're
talking to son of Peter tou this guy you
talk about the
pict any he's not saying that any way
want you to taste this no we don't want
to taste that we I just got me a pen so
I need a supply to go with my pen to go
with my pen
what what I can do for you this I can
make some hash tomorrow I'll give you
some hash to put in yeah I'll go make
some Give It Away what I do that's why I
came over here want to follow this this
is this is all I'm bigger than this I
didn't want to follow up this no trust
me I know you're Bigg but you really
should try it for
real
put clean it clean it
alcohol no problem BR it's nothing
personal so don't feel that okay see you
tomorrow all right in fact I have a
respect for Peter Tosh probably in a way
that he would really never
understand
you with before she passed away on her
sto I po down back in the day and puffed
him down with bubble hat went to there
and gave him bubble
hat and I even named my firstborn
son so I have a deep
respect and I can feel my
trth and all we'll do the whole time
we're here me and him is we will give
away everything
take anyone we're just here
[Applause]
[Music]
to man man I
respect best
than so so so after like after Festival
is over really you come to
I hope so yeah i' looking out for you
all right yeah absolutely that be
awesome what's your name t tough good to
meet you yeah blessed and Steve Steve
the
first so tomorrow I come and get Ash I
will we see you
tomorrow I'll make it actually so it's
ready for
tomorrow
respect all right how we doing guys
awesome
awesome yeah just within like the
last we've been talking about it on hash
for about a
[Music]
year has Church panelist Tony verzura
tping out Jama
tping him
[Music]
out
sh all right so uh Tony is still here
hitting people up T how are the tpin
guys Prett pretty impressive
right don't see that every
day serious
hey that sh what you say Tony how many
people steady anyway it's not going to
stop for a while so we'll catch up to
you guys in a
bit this is like five tpen with three
types of full mounts and rosin one I
mean it's just soapy so
greasy
greasy that
greasy feel like you guys aren't really
pulling let me see what's going
on getting a real hit I saw him
exhale we're having a t
party T party Jack Frost Golden Goat
feel free to keep talking Sour Diesel
Sour Diesel Jack Frost g gold goat Lem
talking about your icy plane dude we're
talking about the iy plane yeah the icy
plane so the captain though here's what
he did he goes so uh we're finally going
to get taken off over here and
uh you know you only have a couple
options we're definitely going to be
late and um he like puts out this app
application like for your phone so
everyone's downloading this app get this
app and it's like you're supposed to
look at other flights so it can help you
book it and he was like we're sorry this
app isn't working
and everybody's like holding up the
phone right like mad chaos going on oh
my God and the bathrooms are plugged and
there'll be no movies on the way you
know and I had like this really good
seat like all the way to the far right
of where was an exit row seat and there
was no seat oh you can't stretch I was
stretch out like this stretch and the
guy next to me was like had the door no
he was like right here next to me this
way and my legs were perfectly stretched
out and it was like you know no good
hour just with no AC and everybody's so
agitated and like the third D icing on
the plane oh my go looks like we can
hold the power we're ready to take off
let's go have a tur party tur party
party guys I've been forgetting to turn
the camera on but I am here now at the
boardwalk uh Village uh Mr Kyle kushman
who's talking to Tony was married today
a little after 420 on the beach in the
grill at the uh Roots rasa farai times
Cannabis Cup really cool and we're here
now celebrating the
app's there's suie su's on the other
side of the table
there and I'm hanging out with birdeye
Cam Austin and Ross and the new dude
with some Ros
totally no in
terms
chicken you'll
beward just
like yeah we want you Ted out who here
who here is willing to do a shot with me
for my wedding me grab a shot
congratulations I didn't get to tell you
earlier
I don't know Tequila and
Corona came for the Canabis you guys got
married
here everyone's taking
shots here we I'm going to film this
this come on who's missing
one come on one
more there we
go I'm taking a
[Laughter]
than you all right all right so so you
know this is a most auspicious cont this
is a most auspicious this is a most
auspicious
[Music]
occasion and I am so so proud and
thankful to be
here experiencing history with all of
you um
the first Cannabis Cup in Amsterdam was
certainly fun and it was momentous and
it was historic but this is real life
this is changing people's lives right
here and we're all a part of this is
what we've all been dreaming of and
fighting for and I got to get married
here with my
love and we got to take part in that
wonderful ceremony and now you're here
with me and I just want to thank you all
and say that this is for Everlasting
friendship and what legalization of
cannabis is going to do for
humankind
Salle boom
bam yeah buddy love you awesome dude
I've always loved you so good to hang
out with you bro I've loved you since
the moment I met
c p on the
Chalice
up
roing so I just want to let you know I
promise it's all I
tell yeah promise he let you put those
drops in his mouth at Bob Marley's house
so I'm sure
he's it's going to fall off nice or what
not it'll be going for a while this will
keep you from sucking too much oxygen in
and give you a nice carbed hit oh the
flavor what do you have to say about the
flavor on that bird eye excellent
excellent right
Wicked so
nice that's the real deal right there
thank you
Tony always hitting this
up I might over I might have had my
camera on Paw that whole
time I must have not said anything
worthwhile
that there's good conversations going on
over here
Suzy
awesome the crew right there is the best
man there's Cameron and Austin
Kyle Junior Jun
Jr my own nutrients I my own
nutrients it or not I see a
collaboration in the
future people who grew that for me first
time they ever grew pop
I I mean I'm legal all over Dude Wicked
way to
do there's my
card it
in dude that's no that's not your that's
medicine card yeah
oh get this is a
federal no that's my bubble bag
uh
everybody like it's not
sand nice catch on the
[Music]
water easy on this one go ahead Tony
that's okay what's that
I got it running
[Music]
yeah slow and steady on that it'll melt
real slow you'll have to drop it in
there and then we'll cover
[Music]
it cuz I want them to get like the full
flavor of all of it melting that melt
that's awesome yeah it's
delicious oh yeah there we go I can
smell
it smells very
Island smells kind of like green
crack Shish
shry want to hold that
Tony you could probably turn that up a
little
bit oh yeah what is it
593 it's going to be a super slow tury
hit
how was
it how was
[Music]
it