[Music]
which are chemical compounds now they
express that for a reason the plants
themselves are threatened either by a
disease or by sometimes by a predator or
for whatever environmental reason these
plants Express secondary metabolites
secondary metabolites are nothing but
chemical
compounds if you actually isolate them
and take them out they are as chemical
as much as a drunk can be a
chemical so we need to understand that
even though their origin and their
source is natural they are expressing
chemic
inside them and those chemical compounds
are the ones that we are actually
benefiting from when we're using it as a
neutraceutical so for whatever reason
that they've been there by Nature that
is really what we are trying to
capture and I said to you before that
for a neutraceutical for this um added
nutritional added health benefit that
knowledge is key where do we get get
that Knowledge from there are two
sources that we can get that Knowledge
from one is what I have described as
ethnomedicine and that is knowledge that
has come down from
Millennium and there are ethnomedical
practitioners or traditional medicine
practices from around the world there is
um AA and Nani type of traditional
medicines in India there are are African
medicines there are European medical um
systems there's traditional Chinese
medicines that's coming from
Millennia knowledge that particular herb
or plant is very good for a particular
ailment or as a
tonic that's not the only source of
knowledge there is the scientific way of
actually going and looking for plants
that may not necessarily have had that
history so there are many natural
sources that we don't use as medicinal
or neutraceutical does that mean that
they don't have that value no they have
they they also Express that same
secondary metabolites which might be of
benefit to human
health Marine sources are a perfect
example Jamaica has um our Waters of
marine Al algae and um various other
sponges and so on have not been yet
tapped we have our own plants 23% of our
endemic plants um are only found in
Jamaica not all of them are actually
used as
neutral if you don't eat it does that
mean that they don't have a benefit well
actually they might and that's where
science comes in we can actually test
them and see if they have um medicinal
value so whichever the two sources
that's one has captured whether you're
using traditional knowledge or whether
you're using a scientific route and have
discovered that there is a value in a
particular uh plant or or a a source of
um water or whatever then can we just
bottle it can we Market it can we take
it and put it into the market and call
it a
neutral that's really the question that
we're trying to answer in launching a
neutraceutical industry well my answer
to that is
no one should not do that if you are
talking about launching an industry that
is to last a long time and it's of
global
standards those products ought to have
two very very important facets to them
and that is safety proof of safety for
human
consumption and if possible proof of
efficacy um for whatever that product is
is it effic is for the claim that you're
making it to
be and what are some of those things
that you must have and how does it tie
in with
science so if a product is to have is to
be known as safe then it must let's
let's take a Agricultural
Product then we must know we must be
able to have good agricultural practices
associated with it we must have good
manufacturing processes associated with
it we must must be able to standardize
it and we must also show that it is safe
for human consumption and then of course
efficacy is to be able to
link whatever you're taking to show that
it has that added benefit to
it this Pro process here which I think
most of you might see is actually takes
you through a small process step it
actually shows you the value addition in
partnering with science so if you are
simply taking taking a plant that is
grown then you need to be able to
understand how agricultural processes
impact what's what the plant is
producing and remember we had discussed
about secondary metabolites these
secondary metabolites how are they
expressed as you change Seasons how are
they express how they varied as you
change the growing conditions and what
about if if you use organic versus
non-organic how are these secondary
metabolites
expressed and therefore we must have a
good understanding of those conditions
in order to have an industry that is
based purely on being able to reproduce
every time we need be to be able to
understand those
quantities the other thing that we must
be able to have is
sustainability for for that same
industry to be able to grow we need to
have all of these factors fully
understood
okay um and then the second step is
being able to take those plants if you
want to make an extract then being able
to take the extract using sence as much
as possible to to take those met ensure
that those secondary metabolites are
coming with you as you extract them and
being able to every single time being
able to link back and say what the
quantities are so those standardizations
are extremely important it's also
important to be able to have
traceability to be able to say what what
what your batch being able to trace to
where it came
from and then after that for proof of
efficacy to to go into the lab if you're
saying that a particular plant is is
very good as an antioxidant then you
need to prove it and then last of all to
be able to take it to the clinic now
clinical um evaluations are not
necessarily not necessary for all all
neutral products but if you go down that
route then we add value to your
product so where can we get all of this
done here in Jamaica at a laboratory
scale level there's UWI that engages in
both safety and efficacy um as well as
chemistry Department that does
quantifications biotechnology Center has
engaged in both production at a invitro
level as well as product development um
and there's Utch and ncu there's your
tertiary institutes that engage in this
kind of res that you can partner with
and then once you develop at the lab
scale of course we need to be able to
take it to the pilot scale and that's
where SRC comes
in last of all I'm going to leave you
with three types of products there could
be three types of nutriceutical
one sort of a product that doesn't
necessarily claim a
nutritional or that doesn't claim a
medicinal value and you can put that out
without necessarily claiming in your
label that it isn't that has that added
value and then of course you can have
the second type which claims a medicinal
value and the third time which claims a
full um health benefit and medicinal
claim that has gone through the clinical
route and that brings us to the
regulations that Jamaica needs to to
undertake and our panelists hopefully
will also touch on some of those
regulations I know Ministry of Health is
here and they are are working on
amending some of the laws to to fit the
neutraceutical industry so I'm going to
leave you thank you for your
patience thank you very much we'll hold
all questions until later I'm also going
to ask our panelists to try and stick
within the 5 minute time frame as we
must commence official closing opening
ceremony at 2:30 Rupa alluded to the SED
research Council serving a primary
function in moving your products from
the lab stage with that of the
Industrial Level or to the Shelf we at
the S research Council has a long
history in developing interical related
products we formulated a number of te's
and number of other um products with and
know well established therapeutic
benefits and so forth I advise you to
just take a look at the S research
council's booth and get a clear idea in
terms of some of the stuff we are doing
also for most of the practitioners here
you'll find a line of products of to 10
major practitioners there in products on
display were actually developed by the
scien research Council so we have the
capacity we have the Know It All We Have
the technical expertise to move your
products from the exporter level to
actual products on the market with the
hope of it eliciting that part benefit
that you have planned at the onset so I
encourage you have a chat with your SRC
team and have a have some discussions
with our practitioners and exhibitors so
you be more aware of our capabilities
and competence
I am now going to move to a very
critical component and it has been a
vexed issue in Jamaica for years as
relates to protecting the intellectual
property at this point I'd like to
invite Mrs Bam to just give us
a m b to give you an overview in terms
of the services offered by Ja and how
they can assist you in protecting your
Innovations thank you so much Mr
chairman good afternoon ladies and
gentlemen members of the head table I'd
like to thank you for inviting me this
afternoon to do a very brief
presentation I have 5 minutes and I'm
very tall so I usually speak for a short
time because you can see me so I have to
talk long but I just want you to
remember two things I like you to visit
our website so everybody should be
writing now
wou do j i po o okay I see you getting
your pen I'll wait for
you okay it's double double
jip
[Music]
o.gov dojm and if you want any questions
answered you can write us at
info I nfo at
j.g. JM this is an area that we have
been doing work in at the international
and the local level we actually um we
have we're far advanced in our work in
the Caribbean and in Jamaica in the area
of finding protection for our
traditional knowledge traditional
cultural expressions and our genetic
resources which deals with our subject
area today we actually have a draft
Regional treaty which is to be
considered by the heads with
responsibility for intellectual property
and then to be transferred to the heads
of government for them to give their
sign off on it which would mean that we
would be able to put local legislation
in place that looks at protecting from
the point of view of intellectual
property your rights associated with
traditional knowledge traditional
cultural expressions and genetic
resources this is a new area in terms of
intellectual property rights because
traditionally this area was looked at as
the common Heritage of
mankind but there has been a Thrust
internationally from local communities
and we have our local community that is
represented here today and we are all
aware of the recent passage of of the
amendment of the dangerous drugs act
which deals with one of our critical
genetic resources in Jamaica which is
one that can be protected under this
piece of legislation that will come into
be there are the other usual areas of
industrial property and intellectual
property which is trademarks patents
designs and copyright and related rights
which most persons in Jamaica are aware
of which deals with all forms of
literary works but in a nutshell that's
what intellectual property is about but
if you send me an email at that address
which I gave you we will respond to it
and if you visit our website there's
also further information on how to
contact us and our phone number just in
case you don't want to go to the website
is
946 you can save it directly on the
phone if you don't want pay
946 130
or 946
0789 and I also brought some brur when I
heard I had 5 minutes I brought brur so
if you're interested you can check me
and I'll give you a brochure thank you
so
much thank you very much all right we'll
move right along thank you very much for
respecting the time uh Dian Edwards
present of jam Pro um she'll give us an
idea in terms of the business
opportunities that exist locally
internationally can you join me
welcoming m
good afternoon everyone thanks so much
Mr chairman and thanks for inviting
jamro to be a part of the launch of this
really exciting
industry essentially jamro is all about
business what are we here for is how do
we develop this industry into an export
industry a sustainable industry as you
heard from Dr Delora essentially the
global neutri ceuticals Market is valued
at over 207 billion US by 2016 that's
where it's supposed to grow to so it's a
huge Market I don't need to stress that
point the market is being driven by
Rising health care costs in Metropolitan
countries aging population growing
interest in Healthy Lifestyles and
natural products Beauty the whole beauty
industry and the desire to be younger
and healthier and live longer so that's
essentially what driving this industry
and I think Jamaica has a really
exciting opportunity here um
particularly in the R&amp;D that we have
behind the industry in The Innovation
and intellectual property as we've just
heard but most importantly I think in
establishing a total value chain from
field to Consumer which is the
opportunity that we really have here if
we seize it properly and if we develop
the proper Frameworks and legislative
structures that will allow us to grow
this industry internationally we think
there's opportunity for creation of new
Jamaican brands in healthcare and
branding is hugely important I think
because this is a heavily branded
industry this is an industry that big
farma has not really taken on big
pharmaceutical companies haven't really
taken on big time but there there are
very structured distribution change and
there's a very professional industry
internationally that we we need to tap
into particularly new channels like
health food
stores um we think there are growing
synergies by creating our own Jamaican
branded synergies with health and
wellness tourism which is an area that
we are developing at jamro so what can
jamro do for you essentially well as I
said jamro is all about business helping
businesses to grow and to thrive so
we're involved in capacity building for
exporters explaining to supporters how
to access International markets actually
finding those markets and finding those
proper roots to Market because we need
to go down Niche routes to Market that
can give us opportunities for value
added products that's what we're all
about it's also about advising exporters
on packaging on labeling on how to
comply with International agreements
trade agreements on Market access um Dr
Del go spoke about quality standards and
traceability I think this is absolutely
CR critical to the development of this
industry because if we don't Implement
Hass ISO and good manufacturing
practices we cannot access the
international market so yes um we we are
very involved jamro in developing the
regulatory framework that has to govern
this industry if we are to achieve
world-class standards so exciting
business exciting opportunity but we've
got to focus on developing the proper
Frameworks for us to develop so jambro
is here to help you we have a website
www.jan invest.com if you don't know
I'll give you my card after I'm very
happy to be here we're very excited at
the launch of this industry and um we
look forward to developing and building
a sustainable industry thank
you thank you very much Mr I just want
to shift things up a bit before we move
to to the business and the financing
aspect of the N industry or the sustain
development component I would like to
invite my dear friend Dr n gam he's a
managing director of Winchester Surgical
Center Caribbean School of medical
Sciences Jama and also a professor at
the University of Technology to speak
briefly On Healing Waters and then we
move into the business aspect Dr gan
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you Cliff um good evening everyone
um like to recognize um The Diplomatic
core here as well as the mayor and um
the mayor is talked in her little corner
she's so so important without her we
can't stop this thing but um I'd like to
just say when you look at the health and
wellness industry
and when you look at
neutraceutical our Healing Waters and
our mineral B they're very important and
um they are part of the whole question
of wellness and neutral industry and our
Healing Waters the most famous three
there are mil River Rock for mineral
bath and um St Thomas bath um mineral
spa and it's very important to recognize
them because um from from a scientific
point of view um they are really healing
and a lot of people under remember um
the history that both him St Thomas and
and mil were being discovered because
slaves were beaten and then they went to
these um Waters and they got healed and
therefore their bosses took it up from
there but importantly what is it that
they carry Milk River bath um has
ionizing radiation and it has about 16
CES million parts per liter and it's one
of the most um has the most
concentration of ionizing radiation um
in the world it is 54 times that of
France and Switzerland and about 16
times out of bath in England in terms of
ionizing radiation
and what it does to us is important
because ionizing radiation is
anti-inflammatory so what you find is
that for example people who have been to
Milk River have been noted to have their
um arthritis and their back pains and
their swellings and in in infections
healed because um the the ionizing
radiation is anti-inflammatory but it's
also anti-cancer ant cancerous it helps
pain and apart from that it is
antimicrobial so those people with
infections and so on when they go to for
example um bath which has a high Sol for
Content you find that um they their
infection would have been subsided or or
heal and so you find that Healing Waters
are very important another aspect of
Healing Waters is that and they have
they they have nutrients they have minor
minerals like cadmium um potassium
chloride and so on that are very
important for the body and so they
always argue that when you go to um St
Thomas if you drink the water and get
the hot bath at the same time and at
massage it helps and so it's very
important so so we don't know exactly
what we have and how we can Market this
industry and become part of that $2.5
billion um and and recognize that mil
River and B and Thomas are so important
from a scientific point of view as well
we have to look at partnering with the
scientific research Council the
University of the West Indies University
of Technology ncu and other academic in
institution as well as Ministry of
Health and so on because for example the
sulfur in the
centas um fountain at bath Fountain can
be very important because suppose you
are allergic to sulfur then it it may be
important that if you go there and you
have some little bumps on your body and
so on allergic reactions it may be that
so we have to look at in terms of the
contents and con constituents of our
Healing Waters and recognize the
benefits as well as sometimes the little
dangers and I must say that even though
Milk River has such ionizing radiation
Rock for too has some minerals that are
very important and um they don't Rec
they don't recommend that you stay in
these bath more than 15 to 45 minutes at
a time but and they are not as bad as
the cautions that are there but the
precautions must be important and
therefore it's so important that we
recognize the values the healing values
and the neutral and nutritional values
of our Healing Waters here in Jamaica
thank
you thank you very much Le so ladies we
heard it we are we are not short of
healing plant healing water in Jamaica
we have quite a bit of research a number
of research entities in Jamaica which
have been doing extensive work in
developing products determine the
scientific um principles online their
therapeutic properties of our natural
plants some of our invertebrates as well
as our Waters however of key importance
to us also is how do we start up these
businesses where do we seek the
financing and how do we ensure that we
do it in a sustainable way at this point
i' like to invite Mr Porter to give us
an idea in terms of the support services
in place on the JBC in the startup of
newal Industry Industries Mr
P me give of Applause
please thank you Mr chairman good
afternoon everyone all protocols
observed um well just spend my five
minutes to tell you a little bit about
what we do at jbd and how we fit into
this puzzle um support in the tical
industry now for us is about business
and doing business the right way um
starting from the start point we we we
have this Mantra JBC from concept to
Market and it is about how do you know
take these ideas and make them into
sustainable businesses um how do you
convert your ideas into products how do
you um ensure that they are competitive
that they meet International standards
and so on now at JD we are we we like to
consider ourselves a role of the sleeve
organization we're implementers and we
work directly with entrepreneurs and
other creative persons and you know
other business um
to to concretize um these business ideas
so and we work in certain pillars we
have our business pillar where it is
about business assessment looking at um
at the viability of your business idea
um putting together your business um
strategies and so on our coaching
program and mentoring program takes you
through the the steps to ensure that
your business whether you're startup or
existing business that you um concretize
your ideas and you're doing it to
International standards and meeting
Market
requirements we also have a technical
arm which I'm a part of and that is
about the product development and the
packaging and branding side you have
heard jro mention the importance of
building your brand and pack packaging
and for us that's very important it is
about how do you package your product to
meet International standards to meet
consumer needs right how do you make
your packaging attractive um but to do
it in a way which calls up on available
resources um look at constraints that we
may have on how we can come for the best
and most creative packaging solution
that we have so we have a team of
graphic designers for example who work
on creating the most suitable and
attractive packaging solution um for you
and it is about understanding now what
the industry is about tapping into the
whole natural Vibe of the industry and
give your packaging solution we're also
about bridging and um crossing over into
other Industries for example we work
quite a bit with the natural cyber
industry and how can natural fibers be a
part of this um a lot of neutral product
are generated from Plants what are the
other spin-off products that can be
created from other parts of the plant
which may contribute to the packaging it
may contribute to a new product and um
so it's about doing that all other the
other side that we're heavily involved
in is on the marketing where um through
our in Jamaican stores we actually get
it into the hands of the consumer and it
is about pitching brand Jamaica
authentic Jamaican products quality
products and we use that to get the
productss out into the market of course
we also have our engineering team
where conversion the Valu aspect of it
how do we convert that raw material into
natural product in a very efficient way
about your plant layout about your
Quality Control Systems production
management so whether you are a micro
producer or small or medium siiz
producer we work with you depending on
the scale you are to implement the
appropriate measures that can make you
successful and this is in a nutshell
time is limited this a nutshell what we
do at JBC you can also visit our website
which is
jbcn um we have we're on Facebook and
under social media and you can visit the
website find out our contact information
get more information about us we're
located at 14 Camp Road and we have our
incubator and Resource Center Marcus D
drive on
gar fre Zone Complex so we are open to
working with persons in the industry to
make it quite a success thank
you thank you very much Mr I would like
to invite Miss OK from first Global um
Bank in terms of giving us an idea of
the financial resources that can be made
available for small and medium
Enterprises um I know having the science
behind everything and the engineers to
facilitate do of of a business you
really need a financing to support in
that industry
[Music]
M good afternoon ladies and
gentlemen like jamro and jbbc who want
to say that first global bank is all
about business that's what we're here
for and we really want to we're very
happy to be a part of this this launch
uh you know I find it very I find it
amazing that despite being the home of
over 50% of the medicinal plants in the
world Jamaica today has not been able to
harness his resources to tap into this
very lucrative Market not withstanding
the fact that many of us have benefited
from some Bush te or some home remedies
that have helped us with diseases and
sicknesses that have healed Us in the
past
and first global bank is saying today
just by our May presence that hey we are
in support of this big business we are
in support of the launch and the
development of this industry we want to
see its success we are expecting great
stories to come out of it and we are
saying we want to partner with you to
help you to achieve this over the years
we
have partnered with the dbj to provide
financing for the smmes the group and we
are saying that today we want to partner
with the smmes who will be operating in
this new industry and how we're going to
do it recently first global bank
launched a new product called the easy
business loan and I want to talk about
that for a little bit now smmes have
always has had some challenges over the
year one of the big challenges that
smmes have is presenting financial
information um for their loans to ACC
loan facility what first global bank has
done in presenting this easy business
loan is saying hey we will look at your
business we will look at what financial
information you have even though it may
not be audited financials so we are
saying we are finding ways to come up
with products that will assist you that
will meet your need because you have a
very you have peculiar needs and we're
saying we want to help you to meet those
needs another product that we have
developed recently is our unsecured
financing unsecured
loans and we are saying to you
collateral has been a challenge for you
in the past we're willing to look at
your business despite the fact that you
may not be able to support a loan with
collateral one of our big Partnerships
first global bank is the dbj now the dbj
over the years have always supported
smes and micro businesses unfortunately
not a lot of smes take up the um
facilities that the dbj have out there
and first go bank has always pushed it
now one of the major issues for for is
the whole thing about capacity building
and so dbg and in assisting the to come
up to put together to build capacity and
to develop their their programs and
their products have come up with what
this thing is called voucher technical
assistant the BT program and what it
does for you is that it it helps you to
get the necessary financing that you
need to put together your financial
documents your marketing plans and your
business plans because as you seek
financing for your small neutraceutical
business or your mediumsized
neutraceutical business you will be
seeking investor Partners you'll be
seeking um loans from financial
institutions or other lending agencies
and you will need to present certain
documents for example a business plan
that very all important business plan
that is your guide and your road map to
the development of your business what
the dbj will do through the AFI through
first global bank is provide you with
financing to access that help to access
the help from Consultants to put
together your financial statement or
your marketing plan or your business
plan and they will fund it up to 70% of
the cost another thing that they will do
for you is to provide security up to 50%
of the value of the loan that you will
be seeking out from a bank dbj will give
you 50 % of that to a maximum of $15
million now we we consider this
partnership with dbg very important
because it allows us to meet your need
it allows first global bank to meet your
need and we want to do business with you
so as we launch this industry together
I'm here to say that first global bank
is here to help you we have a booth
Under the Tent and we are welcoming you
to come and speak with us to get more
information thank you
thank you very much people okay ladies
gentlemen our last presentation from our
panelists but not least Professor
Anthony clay we been looking on what the
future holds for the neutraceutical
industry in terms of exploiting the
industry in a sustainable manner ladies
and gentlemen
of good
afternoon should I try this again
good afternoon
everybody thank you very much for
turning out today I'm going to be
talking a little bit this afternoon
about some of the extraordinary changes
that we've been living
through as um I'm know this is a truism
but we live through we're living in a
time of unprecedented social economic
demographic and technological
change and some of these changes do
present challenges es and threats to the
economies of the Caribbean but there are
far more opportunities than threats so
let's just look at a couple of them and
see what they mean for us and for the
development of this potential new
industry today there are about 7 billion
people living in the world that number
is going to increase a lot over the
course of the century by the time we get
to the end of this Century the world's
population will somewhere in the range 9
and 1/2 to 12 1/2 billion
people so they're going to be 2 and 1/2
to 5 1/2 billion more people than there
are
today and the distribution is going to
change dramatically as well by the time
we get halfway through this Century
about half of the population of the
planet will be
Asian and about a quarter will be
African and all of the other nations of
the world will only add up to qu of the
world's population so the distribution
of the world's population will change
really
markedly but an even more significant
change is going to be the age
distribution by the time we get the the
median age in the world today is about
29 but the time we get to 2050 the
median age will be
41 and about by the time we get halfway
through the century about a third of
humanity will be over the age of 60
there will be at least three billion
people in the world over the age of 60
can you just imagine today if half of
all of the people in the world were
retirees that's the number we're talking
about we're talking about half of
today's global population as retirees by
the time we get to
2050 so by the time we get halfway
through the century if you look at
Europe for example there will be two
people over the age of 60 for every
child for every child under the age of
15 the population of places like Europe
will be predominantly elderly Japan will
be an even more extreme case and China
is about to undergo the world's most
rapid transition into becoming an
elderly population of of uh in history
and it's going to start in just a 2 3
years from
now so by the time we get partway
through the century there's going to be
a lot more people than there are now
most of them will live in Asia and
Africa and they'll be a lot older on
average than they are
now we're already seeing dramatic
changes in the world causes of death and
we're going to see even more dramatic
changes as we go through this
demographic
transition as I'm sure everybody
remembers there was a lot of upset a lot
of concern about ebola and chicken
virus so it's important to remember that
in fact these are not typical of what's
Happening
Now over the course of the last 15 years
the global burden of disease and we
measure this in terms of numbers of
lives lost has been falling dramatically
over the last 15 years the number of
lives lost due to disease has fallen by
about
1/3 and we think that even further
reductions lie ahead this is because
people are richer they're eating better
diets we've got better sanitation and
we've got better Medical Care and people
are living much longer over the course
of the last 100 years World average life
expectancy has doubled the rate of
increase is continuing and by the time
we get halfway through the century
people will be living on average at
least 10 years longer than they're doing
now it used to be the case within living
memory that most people died of
infectious disease that is no longer
true the leading causes of death now are
the age related degenerative and
non-communicable diseases including for
example cardiovascular disease and some
of the major kinds of cancer just to
give you one indicator in the UK today
not just a little under half of all
deaths are due to cardiovascular disease
which which costs the UK economy about
$45 billion equivalent US Dollars
equivalent in healthc care expenditure
and lost
productivity and this is going to be the
norm increasingly in the years ahead
it's already the case in Latin America
and the Caribbean that the leading
causes of death are not the infectious
diseases anymore they're age related
degenerative diseases we're actually
living long enough now to die of
degenerative
disease so what we have to do now this
is the next Frontier in medical research
is we have to find a cost effective way
to reduce the burden of the age related
degenerative diseases but we have to be
able to do this for a far greater number
of people than ever
before and this is the single most
important driver behind the development
of the new industry for neutraceuticals
and functional foods because these are
food stuffs and medical uh I ingredients
in a medical
format that contain actives and
micronutrients most of them plant
extracts that give us a cost effective
way just by changing people's diet to
reduce the burden of age related
degenerative
diseases by in about
2010 the global market for these product
was estimated at about $40 billion
US by the time we get to the the end of
this decade most projections show it
going over 200 billion US a year about a
third of the global market is the in the
United States Europe represents about a
quarter but the real growth
opportunities are in fact in the
developing economies the the new
industrial economies the market in India
is growing at nearly 20% per ano so
these are really the markets that we
should be looking to
now some not all but some of the uh
ingredients needed for this new industry
can be produced in
Jamaica now as many people here know I
did I was the first to identify the
potential of the neutral and functional
Foods Market for Jamaica back in the
late
1990s and at the time I did that
research the market for neutraceuticals
and functionals Foods was just one tenth
of the size it is now so over that
period this Market has grown tfold now
we have lost out on a lot of the um a
lot of that growth
opportunity but the good news is that
all the projections show that this rate
of growth is going to continue for many
years yet to come so it is not too late
we can still get into this Global Market
and we can still build a globally
competitive industry in this
country but as several people have
already pointed out the fact that the
industry the market is there the fact
that we have have products that we can
manufacture and export from here in
Jamaica does not automatically mean it
will
happen there are a number of things we
have to get right and if we cannot get
them right this industry will not work
for
us and we have to be absolutely clear
about this this is not about traditional
herbalism this is not what the market
now
requires we have to focus on product
quality on proven efficacy we have to
have standards controls in place we have
to be able
to trace any problems with contamination
back to source and deal with them in
other words everything that you now need
to run a modern food or pharmaceutical
export industry there are no shortcuts
we have to be willing to do the work to
put all of the foundations and the
prerequisites for this new industry in
place but if we do so this is a market
that is projected to grow for the rest
of this century and by the time we get
to the century it will be many times
bigger than it is now it's still early
days there's still everything to play
for so provided we do the work now and
I'm hoping that today will be the start
of a new commitment to build this
industry in Jamaica provided we do that
then this country could build a major
future on the strength of this industry
ladies and gentlemen thank you very
much thank you very much
can we give our panelist a big round of
[Music]
applause thank you I'd like first to
recognize mayor bronberg welcome and
thank you for his support we have a
number of distinguished guests in our
audience today if I begin a start
calling names I know I'm going to get
myself in trouble so I want to thank you
all for your kind support and thanks for
joining us here today this is a clear
indication of your commitment to the
development as well as the
sustainability of a National neutal
Industry
at this point we get to the me of the
matter we have just about 15 20 minutes
we're going to open the floor for
questions you can throw questions at to
our
panelists can you please join us so the
floor is not open to um our participants
can ask as many questions as you want to
we'll try our best to address them in an
amicable manner you can show by raise up
hand and I'll run to you one second
please also indicate the person to whom
you are direction of
question I'm Paul Chang with the ganja
future grows and producers Association
of Jamaica and the president director
and the professor who just spoke from
the United Kingdom um does the inputs
the
[Music]
plant Professor does it does the plant
inputs for this neutral industry require
certified organic plant inputs
uh let me just correct one point I'm
actually from Jamaica at the University
of the West
Indies very proud of
that uh no thank you well welcome I'll
take that okay thank you um no or it's
it is not about Organics okay except
possibly as a marketing point but no the
key is to identify the active now again
if you remember I said we're not talking
about traditional herbalism what you
actually have to do is identify the
complex molecular compound that actually
has the identifiable health benefits and
really over what we have to aim for is
to actually understand the molecular
pathway so that we can be uh very
precise about what it is we're
addressing and how it is we can address
it and then what you have to do is you
have to do the
extraction because when you take a
traditional herbal product you are
getting some of the active that maybe
does you some good but you are also
getting typically hundreds of other
molecular compounds some of which may in
fact be bad for you and as I'm sure you
know there was a big Scandal a few years
ago with some Chinese heral medicine
which it turned out was actually uh
quite toxic and and caused permanent
liver damage and some of the people who
took it so no that's just a stage we
came through the next stage is we have
to identify the compounds that actually
do people good and extract them and then
package them and that may mean for
example uh microencapsulation and starch
which we have to do with um the
flavonoids for example because to get
the dose that actually does you good you
have to actually be consuming so much
that it would be unpalatable so there we
need to look at coating these products
in starch so that when you consume them
they actually don't break down until
they're in your intestine and that way
you get the health benefits but the the
key to a lot of this industry is to look
at lowcost delivery mechanisms and
that's why functional foods is actually
probably got the potential rather than
neutrals neutrals you put it in a
conventional medical format but
functional foods you just put it in a
standard food or Bakery product or a
drink or a spread which means that
people can actually adopt a much much
healthier diet without having to make
fun fundamental CH changes to their
lifestyle and this it looks very much um
to me is the way to go so if you take
for example the flavonoids from turmeric
that we believe act as um uh
to the flavonoids in turmeric can take
block something called tumor necrosis
Factor Alpha which is a cancer precursor
so if you um introduce a higher level of
these compounds in people's diet you can
reduce the incidence of certain cats of
cancer so so this is the way we have to
go next but this has to be a
science-based industry we can start by
looking at traditional herble remedies
that's a very good place to start but to
go to the next level we have to do the
uh scientific
assessment any further yes further
questions we can only take one more
question we're out of 10 so I ask you to
just have discussion to the p
just the the I understand that you know
the the growing of uh uh uh uh marijuana
you could go um inh housee with lights
or um outside with with sunlight does
the
property of the uh uh plant changes
depending on what um how it is gr
sunlight or
artificial light because I I I I fear
that if we concentrate just on um one
particular type of uh uh growing we may
lose
um another aspect because of what is
natural and more um a cheaper energy
cost for us all right I don't know
enough about the specifics of producing
T hydr can Abol but
I think it is quite clear that um as
part of the demographic change I talked
about
earlier uh we have to look at much more
uh intensive ways of producing food and
fiber because we're going into a world
where we're going to have to feed
another 5 and a half billion people over
and above the 7 billion who are alive
today and that means we have to find
ways to produce more food
more fuel more fiber and more
pharmaceutical Products off a smaller
area of land than ever before so another
one of the key directions of scientific
research is how do we do that and it's
clear we have to look at production in
intensive conditions in Hydroponics we
we simply cannot we we'll no longer be
able to afford the kind of extensive
agricultural inefficient agricultural
systems we have now so I think that
however it's going to work we have to
find ways to produce more intensively in
[Music]
future thank you very much um Professor
we are deeply sorry for The Rush it's
just that the next session of prime
minister should be starting any time now
and as you understand the protocols with
the security details of the Prime
Minister we have to close out this
session with immediate effect I want to
thank you all for being with us and
thanks for joining us and we implore you
to have discussion with our
distinguished panelist I'm sure they'll
be able to guide you as much as they can
and if not we'll direct you to the
respected agencies that will be of
guidance to you can you please join me
in giving our panelists a big round of
applause thank you very
much and we thank you so much for
joining us thank you for sticking with
us and we hope that you'll stay with us
for the official home years from all the
best
ask
seats getting ready for the
official your seats
[Music]
Miss James can you report to the
entrance right now Kimberly
James James can you report the entrance
right now I waiting for
[Music]
stand FR my camera that's okay
a wonderful occasion to be here I don't
know for those of you who've just
arrived you've missed the opportunity to
look around at the research at the
people who are supporting the research
and at the practitioners of the research
I am Fay Ellington and I'll be guiding
you through this
program I had some yam
spread they had jerk and they had yam
spread with cinnamon and I had some
Moringa nuts so if I go a little off you
know then you know it's the moringa nuts
that send me off but it's really very
good the work that's being done here let
me acknowledge all our ministers here uh
Minister Anthony Hilton Minister Julian
Robinson I want to acknowledge Professor
Errol Morrison Professor Henry L all the
scientists who have gathered here all
the persons who are involved in support
of one way shape or form this is such an
important project we're very happy oh
Professor Morrison yeah I just mentioned
you but you're just making sure that
everything is in order yes I know never
mind right all those who have come from
overseas we want to welcome you as well
there are some changes and I think I
might as well just handle those at this
time on your program and explain why
some of those changes have occurred your
PS wondering where's the Prime Minister
well not only did she have to attend a
funeral Dr Fenton Ferguson's mother's
funeral this morning but there was an
emergency meeting that she has had to
attend to but she will be coming you are
perhaps wondering about uh Minister
paulwell you haven't seen him well he
has been called away on an emergency
meeting off iseland I won't say too much
more on that uh so he won't be here but
of course we have Minister Julian
Robinson with us uh The Honorable Derek
Kell is unable to be here as well and Dr
Lisa Myers will be Dr Lisa Myers Morgan
will be representing the honorable Derek
kello and representing the honorable
Fenton Ferguson's Dr Kevin Harvey the
permanent secretary in the Ministry of
Health let me just welcome you all and
tell you that this is indeed a historic
occasion and you are just very special
to be a part of it but before I go any
further it is my pleasure to ask
Reverend Dr Steven Jennings the pastor
of the Moa Circuit of Baptist Churches
to come forward and ask for God's
blessings on the
occasion let us
pray almighty
God you are maker of heaven and
Earth and you have given us all things
freely to
enjoy we thank you for making us
stewards managers of the earth and
giving us the Great respon
responsibility not only to take care of
the Earth but to produce food and
medicines for the healing of the
Nations we ask you now for your blessing
upon this launch of the National
neutraceutical
Industry in this way we thank you for
all who have been working hard in their
various
ways to produce health and wealth from
the land
and we pray that you'll give continued
wisdom understanding and knowledge so
that people might be better and their
lives might be transformed in positive
ways we pray that you might teach us not
to be
greedy but rather to support legitimate
needs we pray that you might help us to
be people of
sustainability that we will keep the
crop
going and that whatever Industries we
produce might be able not only to
satisfy individual needs but the common
good so hear our prayers today we ask
for your blessing your guidance and your
strength this we pray in your name and
for your sake
amen thank you you very much perhaps
it's is a good time to ask you to make
sure that your phones are on vibrate or
silent thank you so much Reverend Steven
Dr Steven Jennings when I was growing up
in the hills of
Clarendon I think most of our medical
needs were taken care of by the plants
we had around our home there was Leaf of
life and all we were required to do was
wash it and chew it to get rid of a cold
there was fever grass there was Cy St
some people call it I enjoyed my Lime
Leaf Tea yes Lime Leaf Tea enjoy that
not the lime you know but the Lime Leaf
Tea but if you don't have the lime tree
just make a little cup of hot lemonade
it is so good I grew up with six
different kind of flour in a my y of my
country rather for the non Jamaicans at
my home in rural Jamaica there were six
different kinds of flour there I had
banana flour i casava flour i araro
flour I had bread fruit flour I had FL
and then we regular counter FL the look
like not a me look good this age of my
life because me eat all of the proper
things right you see all that doctor on
the back there the one who have the
baritone him have all of those things as
a young man to you know but we tell him
more about it but the point I'm making
is these things have always existed but
we have used them in our homes for
domestic purposes it is now time to get
the real value and
explode this industry to the rest of the
world and what is really interesting you
know of the 160 plants declared as
having medicinal properties worldwide
there are over 80 80 that are endemic to
Jamaica may I hear an amen may I tell
you we are blessed indeed uh it is now
time to ask some people who have been
working in this area to talk about what
they do and Mr Norman Wright CEO
perishables could you come forward I
know you were here earlier on I Norman
gone where is M Norman ah could you just
welcome him very warmly if you are
coming to the zoo for the first time
since it's been done over I hope you
realize how much effort and work has
been put into this place and you need to
really visit and take the children along
this is Mr Norman R listen
keenly thank you very much
fa good afternoon ladies and
gentlemen I am a
promise good afternoon and uh the good
book says every moving thing that liveth
shall be meat for you even as the green
herb have I given you all
things should we invest in Moringa a
long-term crop or ganja a shortterm cash
crop there are
idle lands and hry hle ants and hungry
BS to be
fed in
1980 at the age of 24 when many
Jamaicans were migrating I made a choice
to stay in
Jama and create employment and domestic
Capital
formation I started perishables Jamaica
Limited with $300 Jamaican dollars
at that time it was
$175 us at today's rate of exchange it's
$2,000
fortunately in
1980 there was not a
$60,000 penalty for starting a
business if so I dare say I would not be
standing here talking to you today as a
small farmer and
businessman our
mission is to efficiently produce and
aggressively Market indigenous
agricultural products and byproducts at
a reasonable price to the
consumer let's think back could we make
that
$60,000 an incentive for people who are
wanting to get into business instead of
a
disincentive the first indigenous herb
we developed in to an industry was sat
VI minia also known as Jamaican
peppermint and we are the only Tea
Company in Jamaica that produces
indigenous Jamaican peppermint all
others are
important today we have over 500 Farmers
supplying supplying us this commodity we
have commercialized 13 traditional
Jamaican medicinal plants
with small farmers and wild Crafters
some of whom are members of the South
Manchester herbs and spices
multi-purpose Cooperative society and we
are currently developing another 20
plants under various Brands including
our own tops and sip a copper itle
Jamaican Brands forgive me the
commercial we export our products to the
USA Canada the UK and the Caribbean our
products are competitively priced in
terms of quality and reliability of
supplies our business
strengths are our human resources both
external and internal the development of
unique medicinal plants we use 96% local
raw materials in our processing we are
net earners of Foreign
Exchange we solar generate our daily
electricity needs and sell a little
excess to the grid each
day what are the threat store business
inconsistent and inferior quality
contaminated materials Rees and pests I
dare say the additional 100% increase in
asset tax is a threat to our
business lack of
water water is life based on the example
of the Yas water pipeline I hope that
the government of Jamaica and the bside
companies will in the near future find
it possible to convert some of the
craters that are created in the
highlands of our country into water
reservoirs this water could be gravity
fed yes not pumped using electricity to
Farmers Downstream to provide
sustainable water supplies for the
production of our herbs and spices we
need to harvest store distribute this
precious commodity more
intelligently for our long-term
development I'm
closing my mission is to share as much
knowledge technology resources and
skills with my brothers and sisters so
we can build and develop a long-term
sustainable neutraceutical industry
while contributing to keeping the
Jamaican social fabric
together God has been my
guide and he deter is my destiny my
mission I came into this world with
nothing I will leave the same way with
nothing but Jamaica will be
different should we invest in Moringa or
ganja the resolution might yet be to
develop paba dog blood donkey weed rang
dashal Stevia or Lam V to this end it is
understood that our human resources will
determine the success of our
industry we just go search my
heart to find the
answer I'm a promise I'm a
possibility I'm tempted to bur into Mama
L which is a song a folk song aboutum VY
yes and the powers of the ly thank you
Norman you are a promise and you've been
a possibility and uh friends it is now
my pleasure to ask a chief research
officer of sking USA Reverend Dr kimron
the Caesar to come forward and bring his
testimony could you welcome him good
Jamaican
welcome um I'm Reverend Dr kimr Caesar
Ste louds in
California first I would like to thank
this
community your ministers UT and all you
folks for allowing to be here and
participate in this amazing thing you're
doing um and I'm very grateful for
that um a little bit of background I'm
I'm a chemist I've been a Healer a
chemist and an ordained minister for 40
years I've been in herbalist for nearly
50 um says enough about
that I I think an important thing that
we need to look at here and what we're
trying to accomplish is and what I hope
steel brings is the ability to bring you
answers through
testing uh answers as to to a great
degree what you have so you can better
decide what you can do with it uh
answers to what hidden Potentials in the
way of different canabo in the plant
that can help different
illnesses um we're here to help where we
can to educate your University we're
here to help in any way we can with the
science we have to move the
Jamaican projects
forward and I want to tell you why that
is and I made little emotional because
it's near dear to my heart I work with a
tremendous number of very very six
children and we don't always win those
situations sometimes we
lose currently in the United States one
of the most important drugs we need that
comes from Mother Earth in this plant is
a compound called CBD to stop the
seizures and
epilepsy we have very little in the
United States we're working hard to
create it but when you create it from
the ground up because Mother Nature
didn't have it there takes a lot
longer um um currently when these
children are incredibly sick and we're
just trying to keep them from dying we
give them terrible drugs that keep them
alive but destroy their
bodies when that
happens we not only are creating
Devastation of the patient we're
devastating their families if they live
in tight group communities we're
devastating those
communities and it's extremely
frustrating to me
that wonderful medicinals like CBD and
th
see don't kill anyone they have no
capacity to stop you from breathing they
have no capacity crack much to cause a
lethal dose without eating and consuming
massive amounts far beyond what anybody
would do they rarely have major allergic
reactions or
intolerances I can't say that about any
drugs we're using and it's a pretty hard
thing to know that as a Healer when
you've got to make that difficult
decision am I going to give this patient
this young patient these terrible
drugs you know am I really certain
they're likely to die if I don't give
them to them it's a real tough position
to put any healer any physician any
herbalist into and so for me part of
coming here is hoping that you will let
me assist you in leading the way in the
world to understanding why these sort of
treatments are much more Humane why
these treatments have greater dignity to
them why these treatments have a
tremendous amount of compassion to them
now the reason why I'm extremely hopeful
about Jamaica is as a very spiritual
person I know a spiritual Nation when I
see one and when you have a spiritual
nation that was basically created out of
a demand for dignity and a strong
compassionate feeling you can make these
things happen in a very wonderful way in
the United States we're up against all
sorts of walls where that's concerned
because people close their Shades at
night rather than opening their window
at night to look across the street and
say is my is my neighbor okay okay we're
losing that but in a highly spiritual
Nation based on compassion there's
almost nothing you can can't do and
you've been given you may think in some
ways I I know the world sees some of
your resources poor resources I don't
believe it first off you have a huge
resource in spirituality in your entire
community secondly Mother Nature has
given you a rainforce that's filled with
herbals and yes cannabis is important
but there are many important drugs that
are better to give to patients than the
drugs we're using and you have a great
number of them here um you have a desire
to improve your situation and again it's
not just at the individual level it's
the entire Community that's phenomenal I
mean I don't see that in the United
States the degree I see it here except
in the small Mountain col
the small Mountain communities like
where I come from but in the big cities
that kind of spirit is gone it's just
it's it's asleep I don't know so what I
will tell you is if you allow us to help
you if you allow me to do what I can to
assist you I will happily come back and
work at University teaching your people
up I will give you every medicinal
remedy I have uh I will help you develop
others I will go out in your Forest like
I've been doing the four I didn't go to
a beach when I got here first time J
make I didn't go to a beach I'm not here
for
recreation um I asked Olivia the person
planning all this for me fil up my
calendar let me talk to as many
communities and as many people as I can
and that's what we've been doing and if
you allow me to do this I will be
immensely thankful and I think if you're
patient with your program and if you're
encouraged to build your program I think
in a very short amount of time the rest
of the world is going to be looking
towards de and saying what is going down
there
and I'll tell you what I have patients
in States like Florida on the far other
side of of our of our country who
because they can't get what they need
but they can get it from me and get it
from California every month they have to
make a pilgrimage all the way across the
country to get the medicines and
treatments their children need if they
need it you know how strong parents are
and how much courage they have and they
will go anywhere if you come up with a
medical program here that is the best
medical program people will come you
know every father every mother will
bring their children here and if they're
sick they'll come here because this is
where they know to get safe reliable
spiritual
medicine I I don't know what else I can
tell you other than I'm incredibly
grateful for this opportunity thank you
[Music]