[Music]
said 23 million they said you did 23
million I said yeah can I have a real
piece of paper finally so I'm not a
criminal so things can't get done and it
and and I think you need to stand and
push forward and take
something thank you next speaker yeah I
just want to um maybe put a little shed
a little light on hanana that just was
up speaking I think there was a little
Mis understanding so let's let's go back
and understand a little bit of what he
was explaining to you um Mr dir what he
was trying to explain and I think he was
coming a little too hard at you if you
will but what he was trying to explain
to you is that in in the United States
in 2008 there was a court case it was
called The Kelly decision and that
decision was in California what that
helped us out as far as patients in
California was to identify I.E with the
doctor and the doctor would be like a
William Courtney which he does
juicy and the example would be that as
hosana was presenting to you that the 3
lb is really only minimal of what a
person would actually need so and that
is the fact that that is the truth and
if you did a little research you would
see that that is really what is needed
now it's not everyone that will be juicy
but if you set the limits at 5 and that
the example will be this if I went to
the doctor and I had a pain and then he
gave me oxycoton we started at 100 mg
for that and of course everyone in this
room would understand that oxycotton are
heroin so of course you will getting
addicted and then your addiction will go
up what a coincidence and when it goes
up you will take more Hairway and by the
time you're done you're a junkie so what
I really would like to help and really
applo to you if you're the one that's
making these decisions or someone that's
going to go in and at least work for the
people is that the five plan is for the
dumb people uh we really need to
understand that the plan itself
depending on who or what is going on
it's your situation it is again the
doctor and the patient that decide on
what they need to take not the country
not the laws and not the police so it's
you the people that need to stand up and
take charge of your your land and your
rights because at the end of the day
it's your right to be able to medicate
and I don't care what country you're in
it's your right if you're sick and I'll
end it with you had a young lady
yesterday that I know our company
Timeless was going to go out and see and
just get give our our two cents if you
will and and to understand her pain and
her what she was going through and for
all you that don't know she was in uh
one of your m one of your newspapers and
unfortunately while uh we were planning
to go out she passed away yesterday so
again it's the laws that are prohibiting
the health and the movement while we sit
around and we have all these people
talking you guys have to understand
Antony you made the point we are and it
will be legal I have friends that are in
the White House and it will be a
schedule to by 2016 I guarantee you that
and if you don't step up now and get in
the game you're not you are going to the
money that you think you're going to
make or that you want to make the United
States will just take that right away
because you people and and I employ you
that's gentleman over here that says to
walk out and stand with you it's time to
walk out and stand you need to get up
and get busy and that's what I want to
see from the people that are here that's
the excitement of the Jamaican people
and if you don't understand you need to
understand that you have a chance to
change the way the world looks at ganja
you do but it's a matter of when and
will how the government can actually
change this and again we can keep
talking and we could keep going back and
forth but that's not going to solve the
problems that you guys have right now
and it's really catching right now if
you don't move this Peg fast and really
fast you're going to see the united
states legalize and they're going to
capture the movement it it it will just
be done it will be over so thank you
again for letting me speak and thank you
what passion what enthusiasm we have let
me see there only three persons in the
line we I suggest it's the last three
and can we limit a 2 minute
hi
Paul Paul this is for you um I know we a
forum that Jus serve to flesh out ideas
as you go along but your idea of small
soal small farmers making up the bulk
for for the three years where the thing
is legalized I'd love to ask you if
there is a demand for the product in in
3 years even before 3 years what is
wrong with the big and small producing
is it is this principle any different
from how the sugar operate sugar
industry operated in the past where by
was there any discrimination between the
small man came going to dayon line money
and big properties came going on was
there difference in the price structure
I understand maybe I have not because I
was guarded for
time I have tried to be very
conside what I'm trying to say that's a
when you
start you're going to be a certain
amount of demand for a product I'm
hoping that re insist that most our
products must be most of our raw
material must be converted into products
in
Jamaica if there's a need for you allow
all Farmers to go up
at the smaller level first before you go
into the big Fs in other
words if somebody has 5
AC and you have thousands of farmers
with 5 Acres thousands of farmers with
three acres you go up and allow as many
of the small farmers to get involved
then you need more you say okay we had
start limited to one AC in the first
year that us go up to 2 Acres then you
go up to 3 acres but you do that only
for a certain amount of whether it is
three or five years it is when when you
study the industry when you study the
demand then you talk to the
stakeholders and if they agree look here
we need to increase the m and it will
protect the small Farmer and the small
farmer is part of that decision to
increase them out I have no problem in
the same way I am saying in the first 3
years it could first 5 years allow
individuals a certain number of plants I
know you see the figure 2034 say Yes man
this is what you want to do from the
beginning so I think we have to be very
practical as to how we grow the industry
and protect the small farm but in
growing the industry it is about
protecting the small farm but you
understand I'm going it's just basically
saying we'll have equity I'm trying to
wrap up and so I'm going to give to the
last three the fellow in the African
outfit that young young man in the
African outfit yes you
yes go ahead yes I also want to um
refocus on those first two Works
medicinal G I mean we have been talking
about money i' been talking about the
logistics of getting the thing right and
all of that um the next term is wealth
um and it's G and but I want to more say
health instead
of um I saw as everybody else I'm sure
did the um the Expo by sanj Gupta and it
really struck the for of a lot of
Jamaicans to see that the research in
medical marijuana could be applicable to
things like epilepsy and all of those
things and um I think we need to refocus
s research Council all of those guys who
did the chal stuff we have a lot of
genuses in Jamaica and um there's a lot
of um research that has gone in to where
the the medical marijuana can actually
Aid to heal the nation and I think that
is what I always really want to focus on
um the
products that are already out there how
can we bring their them in study them
those that can help
to heal our children with epilepsy
artism all kind of other diseases um I
kind of want to hear some more about um
Mr Tony I don't know if you have any
information or if there's anybody else
who can actually give us some
information sure we could go back and
forth on this one you
want so um the actual uh plan that I had
in place if if and when and hopefully
the government will do it if medical
gandulas were on the books and we were
able to do that um there's products
besides the ones that we focused on with
our capsules and sublinguals we take
Blended strains and we we take we start
with genetics so you have to understand
I'm a breeder manufacturer processor and
products so I do everything from seed to
sale as well as Implement those products
into other territories so I'm actually
the reason why I'm actually here is
because of the limit problem that you
just discussed we have limits in
Colorado and we and we have demands that
have with that and so we've developed
products that don't utilize active THC
and they offer the full spectrum of the
entire medical benefits of the plant and
sequenced products and those products
can get placed by simply educating
teaching the others and the locals so I
do have two two partners actually here
if you guys want to stand up just real
quick those are actually my local
Partners so they they're actually
Jamaican they've been there 30 and 40
years in Agricultural Science and
education and so the first step is
implementing that technology and
implementing that farming implementing
and standardizing the genetics and
utilizing the the local communities to
create sustainable Community involvement
in the products that are made here
branded here and then globally
exported so there's ways to do that and
that's it starts once regulations in
place then
education and then you heal the
nation thank
you good evening um just to add to the
query the gentleman raised when I
mentioned that father src's mandate is
to develop neutraceuticals and
Cosmos all the things we're talking
about good evening one one second um my
name is Dr Courtney I've been involved
in dietary cannabis for maybe 10 years
it's a whole new field um the raw
material consumed runs in the area of 50
to 100 times the amount that you consume
when it's heated and turn into THC we
know the THC dose is 5 to 10 milligram
we know that antiox dose is 500 to 1,000
um really good guidelines are in the
United States government's patent on CBD
they have a phrase an effective oral
human dosage schedule a contemplated
range um and then an example range and
they end up with and in particular 20
milligram per kilogram body weight and
they identify the conditions for which
that dose is effective it I beg that
people that are making decisions about
the amount of uh cannabis that an
individual needs at least to base it on
that you know 1996 information there's
much more current information but it
gives you a very explicit um uh dose
that's required for diabetes uh
reperfusion heart injury cancer glaucoma
and it's it's so much different than the
amount that you would smoke if you if
you're going to smoke 20 joints a day
you're not going to very consume very
much you're smoking we're now talking
about eating a 100 worth and so please
allow people access to um the amount of
non- psychoactive cannabis that's needed
to uh prevent cancer and preserve their
health and and it is in sharp contrast
to the amount that you could smoke so as
we go forward um it's a difficult thing
to distinguish how do we prevent the
dietary person from doing other things
with her cannabis but that's not reason
enough I think to eliminate the
possibility of preventing disease and
maintaining health and restoring health
um because we're we're fearful of the
psychoactive low do usage schedules that
really inform all the laws in uh in the
US this is 5 six plant thing it really
is yeah you probably couldn't smoke that
much um but you certainly need a lot
more than that if you're going to eat it
and uh use it in a non psycho actic
fashion I go now
[Music]
yes yes I'm sorry yes I must say that
you both are the last
two uh persons who will ask questions we
want to wrap up in another 5 minutes
okay in that case I wouldn't ask a
question for straighten to say thank you
no no no no
no on behalf of my colleagues who are
not here my name is LEL poer I'm a
realtor and my company is New World
Realtors it is a new world seeing the
pastor sitting up there it remind me of
Jacob old Simeon when he saw Jesus
materialized as man and Earth he said
Lord let thy servant depart in peace for
my eyes of SE salvation it is it is also
a new world because here we are having
been grown up with a Christian and say
pastor advocating this herb which I was
told was was GR in and Samson
too to right the rest that can help me
out that therefore Pastor I thank you
for coming here because if you travel
from Mod point to n as a realtor you see
Jamaica is an empty
land and with this coming to Jamaica I'm
hearing about billions of dollars and
you're speaking not Jamaican dollars was
it US dollars right so can you imagine
all of us will be benefited I know I
will be because I have land all over
Jamaica
for together with my own colleague so I
thank than you Pastor I thank you Mr bur
you have been fighting and I'm and I'm
sorry court is not here for me to thank
him also and Tony we are going to need
you back into Jamaica because there are
lot of housewives in the hills and
around Jamaica live in these big houses
and they would have a little pot in
their house at the back of the garden I
hope you're are planning to do that
because I am sure I've seen someone in
St Hill sometime ago planted in their
back back in their house and they were
arrested so we will need you here and
and the the the medical doctor you
warned us in the beginning as people
must we must be careful how we use it
ourselves I wouldn't use it like some
people do but definitely my
benefit my benefit come from selling
land land land land right all over
Jamaica so I thank you all and this is a
new day for me and I look forward to the
great benefit and help promoting this
beautiful
girl Mr Po the more people want L there
the more business you do am Hallelujah
may God be
praised
final um I've been told that I can only
talk shortly so I'm going to try and
contextualize this the best way I can
think right on Sunday I buried a very
dear friend
right he he was in an accident in 1995
and he lost a piece of his liver his
kidney sorry right now because of this
chicken this chicken took him
out right my brother died from an Asma
attack my mother died from diabetes my
father died from cancer have to get this
thing in context the majority of the
people in Graves that day would be alive
now regard well you know time but still
this is how important this thing is and
we're still playing with it I asked this
question two years ago in KC when is the
Jamaican public going to get serious
about ganja two years
ago but I wasn't even allowed to speak
to the people I could only speak to
what's her name Susan Sims and she run
me out the place do you know this is a
school so where else should I speak
no this thing is serious and we have to
get this thing in context the world is a
war zone and we are here to clear it
away we are our brothers Keepers you
hear just imagine this place like Cuba
with
money this is what we're looking at Cuba
with money Cuba has a very good
system yeah it's about love it's about
sharing so it doesn't matter about the
amount of land you have it's about how
much you care about the people around
you if you have it and you can afford it
let it go what do you
need how much do we need on the planet
now with the death around us the
decimation of the mother this is some
serious stuff and we're playing with it
I could speak for hours right but but we
only have one minute all right so let
let me say that you asked the question
in which Forum shall I speak and this is
for this is the exact reason why the
board and management of the scientific
research Council gathered experts from
all over to come and sit and share the
ideas and so that all the ideas could
contend because if people understand
what is at stake how valuable it is and
how you can minimize the negative
effects then we can move forward can can
I add one thing well cuz there's been a
couple things said uh when you see when
you you a couple comments were made
about this ganja wealth thing talking
about health right so when I said that
the industry you look at the
neutraceutical industry and you look at
the plant-based medicine natural herb
industry it it can affect and help
millions and millions of people on the
planet billions of people and that
translates to billions or trillions
because of the healing properties so
that's what we were talking about when
you explor the full potential of medical
cannabis in its raw form in its
semi-active and its fully active form
there's different methodologies and
delivery methods for that that will that
will in that will explode into products
into different things and so that
opportunity and that ability to help 70
or 80% of the of the public on the
planet is what we're talking about and
so Jamaica has a very good situation and
a position to get that going started now
and I think everyone that I've heard
talk tonight and this is just from the
outside besides the political portion
and it moving fast or slow everyone in
the room wants this every single person
understands the medical value you have a
professer you have a pastor you have
every angle covering the fact that
everybody wants what everybody wants in
the room and so you have to approach
this in a systematic way and you have to
do it in a way whether you like all the
things and I don't know everything about
Paul I've just heard everybody talking
things I don't know all the things but
you have to take it in a systematic way
and you have to release things and not
be scared that was the first thing I
said it's how you perceive the
plan that's your potential one last
thing
um someone just spoke um about
regulation regulation and then education
I think it should be education and then
we can make the regulations because the
people can help to Define now how you
educate the people we have channels here
and there is so many documentaries about
ganja we just flood the people and
educate them just run ganja
documentaries are
we serious be serious wake the people up
you have the opportunity that the
dialogue has started yes and we must
continue the progress to make Gan the
product the the plant of choice
my yes just very live discussion I think
the presentations today were excellent
just three questions for thought no
response needed from the panelists
one how many products will Jamaica be
producing from G should it be legalized
um for medicinal purposes
um which ailments are we going to be
focusing on treating with these products
and how much danger Will Jamaica need to
produce to satisfy that
demand well I thank you for for those
three important questions that we will
think about and talk about some more at
at the in church I should we say at the
lounge pastor but at church at the loung
or wherever we meet to discuss how we
can move forward I want to thank you all
you've been a very good audience today
we at the SRC are so happy to know that
we got this kind of response and we
promise you that we continue we continue
the dialogue we'll continue to do the
research so that we have the dream
fulfilled so the dream continues we have
come to the end of this this session
this day of the conference and remind
you that tomorrow tomorrow we'll have
we'll look at investment opportunities
and new businesses from medicinal gandja
and natural products we'll have people
from The Bu of Standards we'll have
somebody from the kimar Bailey
Foundation we'll have people who can sit
down and tell us how we can really make
it happen how we can really make it
happen we thank you all for your
contribution and invite you to have a
good night and get home
safe
[Music]