[Music]
I guess I'd like to see the
frame something I like you know
yeah yes tomorrow I definitely can build
that peach
house out sounds good to me I think
tomorrow if it rains [ __ ] it won't
it's all outside it's not going to
rain we're not all
right all right guys we just got back to
Ashley's Place here what what a great
double tonight outstanding no mats threw
it down I mean you guys saw they were
they're very talented guys O'Neal was
busting it out Shep Evie
birdy uh yeah yardcore just making some
really nice dub and of course we held it
down in the Chalice station and mostly
uh got chalice up all night hitting the
Taurus of course as well as some of the
steam pipes but we figured we'd finish
it off we kind of figured that this was
a puff Wednesday he didn't even really
know yeah Ashley just asked me hey have
you filmed a puff Wednesday and I was
like I think we might be be filming it
right
now so puff Wednesday coming at you live
from Kingston Jamaica couple of last
rips for the night before we call it a
night
really nice want just a nice little one
there's one right on the Dabber right
now so you know really nice thing about
these pipes is there's literally no
turnaround of time between like my dab
and your
dab'll be gone in about 3
seconds
perfect damn fine
rip all right well I'm going to hit
myself one
more oh I know what I can show them I
dropped off some
but it's pretty dark but uh I'll show
you tomorrow in the light we got some uh
some Sour
Diesel some uh quen
OG some RI wreck is that what that is RI
wreck RI wreck all right never heard of
that OG Kush standard sour dream I'm
guessing a sour cross with blue dream
and then a granddaddy perss up on top
there so we'll be trying these out later
guys we'll get the microscope out and
photograph and we're also hoping on
making some bubble with those uh not
obviously these single little buds but
with some serious amounts actually what
we could do with each of these is we
could do the parchment the rosin
technique sure right we could Tony's
going to be bringing the um hair
straightener and the parchment paper so
maybe we'll give a get a couple of Dabs
out of each of these buds I don't even
know what the uh what the returns are
but I I suspect there must be a dab or
so or two in each bud so right on
there's
that liking this
hash can see cuz we have the overhead
fan
on yeah the denail element is almost
just
consistently orange hot so we don't
leave it on too long when we have it
under the fan you want one more little
one no you're good dude you're good
right
brother well I'll take one more for
Ash and really one more for all of you
guys we'll call it a day at the end of
this puff Wednesday what is it about
1:00 in the morning yeah yeah 1:00 in
the morning we got a long day tomorrow
we're going to be setting up our booth
at the new judical conference that's
happening uh near the zoo apparently Ash
has been there and it's pretty killer
venue right yeah it's like outside
really nice beautiful we'll see the
Prime Minister will be speaking por
Simpson yeah
and I guess some other people in the
industry from different um aspects will
be speaking so I'm going to be sitting
at the booth with crd and with sunspice
seasonings and almostly be promoting um
the processing uh abilities that ukan
crd will be able to offer smaller
companies like our friend Maurice's uh
with the infus of some of their spices
or some of their products with phyto
canabo which of course I specialize in
decontaminating so that's where that all
comes into play one more dunar
rusi a little
dbit and we will bid you good night and
uh well I'm sure we'll see you guys
tomorrow for all sorts of more fun stuff
sash is so sticky it doesn't want to
there we go want to come off my
finger
that was the
one right we'll see you guys next time
on Bubble man's world peace out from
[Music]
Kingston