[Music]
so morning morning after our nice long
night and is this yeah we went through a
jack file these are both empty yeah a
jack file and a l so we're going to put
some of this rosin that looks like it's
empty into here which looks like it's
empty but there's resin in there's
turpins in there tpin and I want to show
you how viscous it really is all right
okay so let me uh or we can put it into
another we can put it into one of these
things all right so's the
turps let's see what we got
Gorilla Glue diesel coug oh my goodness
let me see that let me show the that's
all of it let me show you
that there we go there we go put the
back on there boom Oh god dude yes no
that's it it's it's like perfect you
even take that away
better oh
god wow that's uh pretty
ridiculous so we'll put a little bit of
that here put it on here let's do it
with this all right here let me show you
that little tiny piece is all we need
hold
on got it for yeah let me see that
thing yeah there we go
boom these about to get
heavy okay so it looked empty right yep
it really
did so just right off the beginning it's
collecting whatever turpins are left on
it see how it got real wet oh
yeah so there's always going to be like
a little bit left in
there that's why I like to use these
jars and hang on to them and people like
oh that looks empty or you know whatever
but it's you can get a lot out of it you
can get another one of these really and
that's the lemon pie so that was the
Jack Frost you just did yeah yeah I
think I'm going to do a little Jack and
lemon and you knowon once you once you
get down to the end Frost pie once you
get down to the end of it it's kind of
like you know you want to get it's just
kind of like a seasoned pan right like
at some point it's like okay you've
tried that whole vial of that straight
tur or you've played around and mixed
with it now it's like it gets really
interesting when you just take very
small amounts of tpine profiles and mix
them together oh I B it's nice super
floral flavor got to get to those empty
jars somehow I convinced you to uh give
me that so take the da all
right so this is all quartz huh yeah
that's
crazy here we
go lemon Jack
T lemon Jack what's your
OG turp
sizzle actually the sizzle coming from
your
hash cuz I uh saw did it earlier yeah I
think you got a little moisture from the
freezer damn what's the OG you have for
that Lindsay wow the Lindsay
OG it literally goes straight out your
brain yeah some strains go out your ears
some try to go out your chest the Linds
he goes like literally from all the way
around
your from ear ear out the brain it's
definitely super heavy hey light almost
light
headed hell yeah as he goes can you
imagine just seeing him
go holy he be like dude dude are you
okay are you okay and then he's just on
the ground smiling are you kidding me
that that was
unbelievable hey guys welcome to the
Cannabis Cup Roots rest the fari
festival uh day two day two day two
we're here nice and early what is it
like 300 p.m. it's like 300 p.m. 300
p.m. so we're like 8 hours late but
that's cool uh tons of action going on
in the street cars all piled up on
either side people coming in pretty
steadily and uh we got the Bubble Bags
today Tony's got the Turpin we've got
our rigs did you not bring your rig or
it's in your backpack it's in my
backpack excellent so we have both our
Rigs and uh you did we did at least a
couple hundred people yesterday on the
turfs and the tur dabs 200 turp dabs So
today we're going to we're going to
double that up yeah see what we do
awesome we'll see you guys in there all
right all right what's film in
[Applause]
here oh today looks like a pretty busy
day you know what I mean like we got to
get over to the booth and start
absorbing all these people look at that
Jenny that's just gnarly
oh my God hey there's Cameron right
there that's where he's getting our
power I at oh my God that's
funny what's up
[Applause]
guys tweet's Booth is going to be uh
empty for the rest of the day
[Music]
nice how's it going got some good photos
of you yesterday om yeah looking right
at the camera where you going to go
today uh we're going to go to our booth
right over there oh you got your table
over there yeah they're sitting at it
right now with the yellow bag brought
10,000 what's that,
it has to smoke with
everybody you oh you got your eail oh
good yeah we got power too we're going
to go plug in right now and we're close
so we'll see you guys in a
bit
awesome you got I'm right we this guys
with the yellow bagar we're going to be
setting up
[Applause]
you
[Music]
[Applause]
that was Jack Frost Turing with
some is Barbara from Nashville
Tennesseee from 70s m
i t it up with the Jack
Frost Jack
FR it's just
straight try it again it's just keep it
keeps tasting good all the way through
the
Turin they they are the flavor and they
are the taste but what we're learning is
is that they modulate the effects of
canids meaning that when you extract
canabo in pure form like THC C CBN and
cpg you take them they're boring and
onedimensional and when you add just a
single turine to it it uplifts and
creates different highs produces
appetite and some it stimulates uh the
release of ocular pressure others it can
reduce Tremors Ms patients it can uh
induce sleep for insomnia so it does all
of these different things it does it by
imagine there like
doz plus it canile how much complexities
are happening in that and we learn that
just the Simplicity of taking pure can
avonoid and adding one tur changes it
multi-dimensionally what if we added 11
Tes and three other conoids specifically
ratio and when we learn how it affects
the brain the CB1 receptors and the CB2
in the peral organs we'll be able to
hone in on specific ails for specific
profiles and I'm sure one
day life hack so imagine this is a box
and these little turpine vials upside
down fit into the box and you can fit
like maybe 16 or 20 of these in here and
maybe on the other half of the Box you
have another 15 to 20 different canab
specific ratios imagine if they were
able to be pulled out in just specific
amounts to create profiles by dialing it
in and then vaporizing through your p
and that to me is like a potential
future where you could do the breeding
and you could do all the STS that will
exist as well love the idea of being
able to produce our own
profiles specific exactly exactly all
the all these other things present in
that in that way that
[Music]
yeah these are all bags
right hey you get a girl want to come
up go straight up baby go straight up no
there's no ly go straight up
what's up buy
them right go right inside girl go right
in
[Applause]
[Music]
there you take this you fill it the
little opening
fill it up with p f it over then we wrap
it in like parchment paper okay then we
take a woman's hair straight a flat iron
and we squeeze this for about 10 seconds
at 200° and the oil inside the plant or
the the hash will squeeze out a golden
shatter that is made with no solvent and
they can't make it ladies without your
hair
they will they will respect the hair
straightener I'm telling you this guy
buying a hair
straightener yeah they gave me a hard
time you're like I need this $400 hair
straightener listen I need the
hair sir calm down this is our last one
you definitely don't need like listen I
need
it this is what I need I'm going to buy
it it's amazing it's so surreal like
high school kids are in a happy place
let me tell because no no one was ever
able to turn Bud into dabs so bud is
like Bud you have to roll it in paper
and blue which definitely doesn't get
you high and definitely Alters the
effect of the high you're get it's not a
good way to get medicine and so the dab
for making that pure product that is so
pure that if you light it it melts into
a liquid that just becomes what you know
that is really the more the more P form
of the medicine
[Applause]
do it that easy like I I don't know I
just if I was 18 and I saw this I would
just be like
[Applause]
[Music]
you know what I do I keep two dils one
on top of the other one set 1100 set
trou right
there some CHS what's up man's world
hanging out with Cali P at the roots
rest the far Festival what you been
doing lately
Cali work
[Music]
music the healing of the nation
Corners respect you know man in a
Jamaica you know history you know love
it love it we're going to get to the
Turks here there's many excuse
[Applause]
me it's such a great
thing broth Hair St oh that's what you
said it just came out of the hash so
we'll try to get some on the
uh on the
Dabber there we go and then we will TF
it
up some Jack
Frost so let's uh let's Jack Frost
something extra different strain
this is basically the perfume of
cannabis it's the essential oils
extracted in a pure
form listen I gave
[Applause]
[Music]
a he's a Jamaican now
[Applause]
that taste on points or
what remember if you're best product
Bubble Bag best class Mothership
Mothership I don't know what
[Applause]
else
2015 Canabis cup
Jamaica got bubble man and Tony tpin
over here pulling the big
crowd let's check it out see what's
going on these turn the hair iron on
these are all pure Turpin the Essences
of cannabis the they they're not the
active ingredients but they're the
smells and the flavors that we love
about your herbs like texure there's no
alcohol there's
no this is an eyol purified turpy wow so
it's quite
something up against the back and walls
and all that I would love to see that
right have a challenge we have a
[Applause]
challeng this say I
oh no no I would never say such a thing
thank why why would to so listen we've
got a situation yeah it's not the best
you need
more I
got that's what we
[Applause]
need blow it on him they're not allowed
to take part
that's
the to try
[Applause]
it like here give some this I'm going to
press a little bit out of all right do
[Music]
that watch blue river
and river what's the
Fox Street Fox Street harb Harbor Side
he's Inver
[Applause]
this is such a small amount of hash this
is the world's smallest press hash I've
ever taken part I never even started
this ladies and gentlemen it's
the
I I just keep forgetting the other
third okay let's keep playing here
play
right I just ask you have step to back
let the
next making trying to get the out of
that
little sque this is like you know
sometimes it just happens really well
for me that like things come it just
came out naturally I didn't even have to
open I mean that's some clear get dabs
some clear there's some clear dabs we'll
take a dab of that over here take a dab
of that
I should take a dab of
that if we have one left over we'll give
it to
uh 7s
Mama this is the yeah
then I'm then I'm going to
[Laughter]
[Applause]
gorilla chilling with
you get one giant dab
off
upil like
take about
minutes [ __ ]
[Applause]
so that's what Turf rosin is taking four
or five or six star most
take away allation
get
out in the cooking other gra there's
levels of hash me this me does eight
bags so you do the water bag and then
you press through it I just press
through and I press the
Hat this is different these are pure
canis process this is what my uh other
hash looks like this is a tur Ro that's
a tur RZ and
butter that's
pure molec no B
people yeah there's no there's no chemal
no b no
[Applause]
alcohol so if you have a piece of
has this came from bu
flow yeah so this is a hybridization of
three types of
technology so this the boo we're best Bo
best product bubble bags for making the
water hash that we make a lot of these
dabs and these products that we're
showing you with these are the bags we
use that we smoke with
is
own we start you like the experience
here do you feel is the right we don't
charge anything just here I don't I'm
going to have them tomorrow I have a
local company in
King we're here to hit the tur beines
with you man the fresh essence of the
[Applause]
plant look at how many different flavors
this is very interesting different the
the iel hash and RW inside the turkeys
and then Tak
bre excuse me guys excuse me excuse me
excuse me bud okay yeah he's the first
one tell me about
this Matt's uh didn't make it I told him
today man he should have been here he
should have been here for sure that
would be
awesome first we're going to turn it up
we're going to turn this down for you so
we don't kill you cuz it's clean I
cleaned it it hasn't been hit on it
since it got clean but it was at 1,000°
and I'm going to take you down to like
580° low temp dab for
Jack this will be the the equivalent of
your music in a in a in a hit all right
sounds
great
quality you guys love the
CD no problem give one to Kimbo talk
about the vibrations you know what I'm
saying all right so let this go
[Applause]
down enough we have so much other about
it's all in the power we plug it in this
it's like a steam chalice this
dish
clean right here we
go things are
Burn yeah you have to be really careful
only touch
here what's the me tou the top okay
we're good you go you feel yeah right
there let make sure you can make it
Buble hold on there's no
holes see if get it going first all
right superf
[Music]
this is a special
hit flavor any
bab give some space give me some
space that's like head St that's like
that's people are just looking at us
[ __ ] Rockstar hat yeah that
is for
Real all right who's next I'll
try remember me
we Barcelona I was going to say I told
you CH
China yes man yes man how you doing I'm
doing really good
so
much oh yeah look at
that extracted by Smokey lit this is
getting extracted by Smokey right
now the
I'm
flavor that'll be on your lips for like
10 minutes 10 minutes you'll be walking
around well now we've got so we just
hooked up with these dudes again what
are you guys names
again London cannabis Pub East London
cannabis Pub how you forget anyway
they've got some nice Orange Hill uh you
know Charis finger rub it's actually
quite clean there's not material plant
material that you would normally see
doesn't actually smell a lot like hands
so that's always a good sign as well so
I think we're going to have to drop this
into the rosin
bag take out what he's got in here
already tiny little bit of resin still
in
here this is the one we already ran I
what did you run already was it the
Nashville 73 Micron '70s Mama hat no I
ran stephie's M okay cool there's that
clean that
up you know what I don't even have to
worry about so little there all we have
to do is press this out it's the only
complicated part it's digital it's
beeping it's got a light it's [ __ ]
way complicated this is your
girlfriend's hair iron and this is Home
Depot or Ace's heart favorite uh tool
it's just a laser temperature thing you
don't want to put it in your
eyeball show them what happens when
move my
eyeball all right so here we go I'm
folding up the hash in the screen I
would put way more hash in the screen
but it shows that you could use one this
small as long as you sort of fold it up
get it nicely folded up this is
32 s sour what's going on dude just
chill with he was uh gave you props wish
you were here man what are you doing be
here
all right so that should be small enough
for Tony to press out some dabs I
suspect cuz it's finger rub and the
heads have all been breached they've
been oxidized by the lights the oxygen
they they've gotten very dark so we'll
most likely see a very dark oil come out
of this but uh I'm excited to see the
local rub Which Jamaican I don't produce
o Jamaican hash always has been like
when it's the real deal not like cut
with bread fruit Beach Hustler type
dudes but real actual from the farm from
the scissors or the knife or even back
in the day I remember in the '90s you
could get some pretty good stuff off of
the sledgehammers they were using to
pound herb into like like tire wheel
wells they would squeeze these little
they'd hammer it down into little
pockets and smuggle it off the island so
good on you Jamaica for for keeping
people in all those years all right so
let's get this in the
[Music]
parchment right
the I'll hold the table so we can take
the
pressure good so we're using heat and
pressure to mkk the hash of the oil so
if you have a hash that is not a
dabbable product a hash that's not as
strong as you might not you might like
maybe you have a certain pain that
really involves using a more
concentrated form this is how you do it
and you get boom oil this is ital oil no
alcohol used no solvent used all we used
was heat and Tony will clean it up in a
second when it cools off might have to
uh I usually use like a little uh uh a
square piece of stone like marble and uh
I cool it in my fridge and freezer and
when I pull it out and you put this on
top of it the rosin cools right away and
it shatters and comes off quite nicely
so that's kind of cool almost a reddish
color
a little bit how's the
[Music]
tackiness sometimes it's very tacky and
very hard to get off if you've
overheated it this is just warm it will
often come off uh very slow this is just
warm we'll be
[Applause]
fine all right well I'm going to have a
little rip check out the
rares all right here we go
completely covered in the flavors of
Tony's Turin but still a really nice
smoke I didn't add any
Tes the whole dish is just full of
tpes well we'll have to pass some rips
of that around so everyone can get a
try was you or
Ash seems like the right thing to
[Applause]
do stays in the screen boils
off in the little screen that we press
the
SM on the back here he's picking it up
right now it's better to put on the
tip we need a cold plate we do Super O
we need a bunch of waters too we
get awesome I need a water than and you
guys need a dab have You' been getting
dabs have you've been ignoring all day
for D might have
not there a long
L for the ones that got to
geten them I thought they wereing off
for the
[Music]
day if you guys need a dab let me know
where did the dab go put it on something
I'm trying to get a bigger
one I'd like a
what's up we just made some uh oil from
Jamaican hash using a woman's hair
straightener and a we'll do it again a
laser and a laser here this
compli what hate did you have
them who knows I think was 320
110 last time you checked
325 EXC how do you get them to stay
off check it out can I see the iron for
a second abely he's got a sweet
spot with these is like the Diamond
Brand he got the
little
the got keep it like this yeah you can
do whatever you want all right so just I
like to go right across right there
right in the middle of the plate that's
where it's the hottest exactly that's
where you're going to the most
consistent yeah that's where I place the
ash so if you but if you go if you put
the laser like down through here look
one 160 180 170 that's where the heat
started and I think the heat will
actually interfere with the you know the
[Music]
microwave I think we can do it again
it be won be
thator that's like really hot yeah
that all right man we've been doing this
for
hours giving
hit let's do another
run doing God's work let's do another
run let's do another run let's do
another run you want to break another
piece of that yeah let me let me do it
at another we're going to do it better
this time we're going to squeeze you
know what you could probably get another
squeeze out of that oh he's
got yeah cool let's roll that up let me
see another
[Applause]
and then if you don't mind being the
monitor yeah be the T Monitor and when
this
to when this gets to 240 I mean I I
didn't taste it yet yeah I know but I
only it seemed really nice we had t on
here is a real nice high 190 okay uh
roll that up in here maybe this one has
to be like empty if it's sticky like
this there's lots of oil just right
there is it the same as his so these are
both the same put them together put them
in there which is also the same you want
to do some flow do some flowers we
probably press some flowers yeah FL
could be better
[Music]
withs so man we're going to get like
we're late here
yeah over
[Applause]
[Music]
here he was right here hitting this pipe
loing
it hit it real
hard Jack serious Jack frings with
bubble the lady from Tennessee at
Nashville gave me
Tennessee and uh we pressed that into
rosin and then we dipped that rosin into
the Jack Fross tures and that's what
Jack hit yeah that one's a Barb 73 Barb
it was all full when she gave it to me
but I literally all way I have I've had
one rip of it and it was
full if I get one rip and get to give 50
away that's a good
day uh matth the great Garder yeah did
you just didn't grow it was a woman 7s
Mama really cool lady she learned a
bunch of stuff from my internet Channel
and put it all in and basically came to
show me her final product and I was like
wow a great job growing beautiful her
processing it into beautiful hash and
then being a trooper and bringing it to
Jamaica give it away you know how happy
you would be if you brought your own
stash but then you just give it away so
I'm giving it
away what are we
saying more
dabs more dabs
I guess we'll hit some of this got 73
for my this is 73 yeah but not from out
here
from there's a lot of
[Music]
[Applause]
there you go don't turn it upside down
until you heat it up a bit don't heat it
up too much cuz all the Turin will
evaporate just one
quickit and hit that
they evaporate at room temperature even
in the pen and put it in his pocket and
he hit it an hour later would be the
same it's like
we want show up at the start of the meal
not at the end just get like a bread
roll a little gravy whatever like full
meal that's
a so you know he's having his first Turf
and how is that you like that flavor
respect respect first be like more like
CBN to see you guys glad came
back it's nice to be here in your
country having this
[Music]
experience I will I will I will I trust
I will you know my you know my son's
name is Tosh you yeah and I've hung out
with your mother before she passed away
on the property and I smoked your
brother
up grandmother yes and smoked your
brother up uh with a bubble hat that I
made there on the property in
[Music]
2002 2002 I came and brought these bags
and used water and ice and we made
bubble and it was uh it was amazing
wonderful
respect yes come back later for
sure well that was awesome Peter to's
firstborn son in the house trying the
Turpin and the bubble has so big respect
to him obviously Peter Tosh was the
militant man he was the uh the powerful
voice of anti-prohibition and Peter Tosh
got his head smacked open more times
than you can count and he was harassed
and he was uh you know press so it's one
of the things that if you listen to Bob
and the
Whalers make sure you pull Peter Tosh
out of there and get as many albums as
you can because the music has the most
incredibly powerful message and uh he
doesn't [ __ ] around he's he's the
militant
man awesome give me a d please I'm D
good
here to see you that I want each rip to
get two or three people a rip so whoever
goes first five six seconds that's a
long time pass on the next time 20
seconds of pure hitting this hit we get
three four people especially because
we're adding the Turpin so it's not like
uh you'll be feeling like you didn't get
enough play with
this now bubble man who made these TPS
these TPS were made by Tony and so Tony
does the Blue River the turine isolation
he also repres s my brand down in the US
through ukan and so and we'll be doing
collaborations as well so we'll be able
to get his tpin through various
locations you'll be able to get my
hashes then you'll also be able to get
what we're wanting to put together as
the quiver I talk about it all the time
the solventless quiver with the dry full
Mount the bubble has full Mount the
rosin full Mount and imagine a little uh
a little bit of Turpin in there too now
that is prob no one in America is
selling right now that's next level
that's some Next Level [ __ ] and who
better to bring it to you than Tony and
myself that's what I'm saying right
there J Bless yeah damn this is sticky
so sticky it wants to stay on my finger
that's California orange
og that's the
coup a dude I didn't know it was
Calo because I didn't know super Sonic's
pretty good here's the gorilla GL you
guys look like you know
gorilla you guys look
you're supposed to say on
point all right so we start you already
had a hit we really got to start with
some people that yeah people that
haven't had hits I want to we got to if
you've had a hit just step to the back
and let the next in because I really
want to make sure that that everyone's
getting fres rep so here we
go so this is going to be a good three
person
rep all right so there it is now pass it
the
BR
on
F got a normal
weed I haven't smoked
years 13 for me you smoked walk I
probably smoked uh smoked a lot of my
time but then one day I realized what a
waste it was for me to be between my
Purity my specialness and the plant
matter you know what I
mean you got got watch yeah sh no you
keep asking about sh and it's kind of a
dirty word so we don't do dirty
play it's true we stay away from the
chemical solvents we're hitting all
solventless stuff so we isolate gland
heads to 99% using mechanical dry
sifting techniques we use water and ice
processes to isolate glands to 99% we
take some of those varieties of hashes
and s them with heat to make Rin and
those are the products you know
with that's rosin the thing I just said
that we made with the hash we squeeze it
with heat and pressure and the oil
squeezes out of it and we're left with a
solventless oil yeah R Tech he sells the
little bags yeah I sell the bags that
make the uh the little screens that
we're pressing the hash and the herb in
can I check out one of the bags Mark
yeah here check it out are you selling
the bags I'm hoping that I'm going to be
they're on the website right now so you
can easily order them off your phone but
I'm been waiting for my [ __ ] for 10 days
and I still haven't got the call from my
guy in Kingston to see if he's on his
way driving here right now so I hope he
is he doesn't leave till tomorrow oh my
God it's going to be bad news tomorrow's
like day three and I paid 4 G's for a to
show products and stuff so what you can
do is if you're enjoying the TP rips
here
time here when you're voting Best Booth
Bubble Bags best products and the for
best exactly and you're voting that's
the Taurus
from
like best we be H everyone I'm going to
get going in here real soon so our
proposition here today isn't money but
it's to win your vote over by getting
you extremely lay the products that were
made from these bags this techn
okay so if you're willing to accept that
contract I'm willing to dab you out get
us up there get us up there get us up
there to D out from where from Costa
Rica Costa
Rica so if you came from Costa Rica
Revenge get a little
Revenge I have a friend Eugene all right
here we
go I have a friend Eugene in Costa Rica
that's lived there for over 30 years in
guanaste yeah he used to run Ang surf
campass he was with Julie for the
longest time you know his wife no but I
knew the guy he already came back to the
states he had a yeah he had to go back
to the States cuz he got some crazy
parasite and he had to go see a
homeopath in La he had like a
7ot parasite in his colon 7t long he was
eating raw fish every day for like 20
years didn't he that eventually he was
like DN something's wrong with me he was
getting real tired for a year he was
just sleeping all the time was taking
all the energy they take all the energy
bro Costa Rica me the camera got a
little footage
here of
kokar dabbers all the way what you
saying
CER what an amazing
it's
wonderful what
up we're hitting uh the
[Music]
Steamers what do you
want you got some
herbs we're hitting
concentrates we took the oil out of the
herb with
heat no no chemicals just heat we
squeezed the herb and the hash and made
oil ital oil ital oil no chemicals at
all so that is definitely where it's at
right there everyone's in the
house thanks for stopping by the fresh
hes Booth the Jamaican first annual
Roots resta
[Music]
farai it's so nice to see a Cannabis Cup
happening with a real culture backing it
you know in Holland for years we went
and it was coffee shop owners but it
wasn't like a spiritual culture like the
Rastafarian people and so this is yes
I I and I
beautiful I and
I get
for you oh all right go thanks man go
ahead go ahead get it right out go
ahead perfect perfect
ready well I live in New York
[Applause]
what's up
man you want to
[Music]
C put it on
right now
I'm representing oural Heth
[Applause]
loal thanks for watching Bubble man's
world we got a good crew here in the
fresh headi tent
yeah we go smoking those flips East
London cannabis club
[Music]
Strain Hunters we bumped into Franco
yeah we see Franco is uh know giving me
the T-shirt wicked wicked good
stuff how's it going
Tony it's going good we've uh we
probably given out a good uhbe 2 or 300
we have to we have to it has to be 2 or
300 I think it's higher to be honest
really because we have been here for
hours you're just not really
thinking where are you from I'm from
Brooklyn but I'm here in Jamaica now
from Berlin No Brooklyn Brooklyn another
Brooklyn in the house nice another
Brooklyn Jama wicked wicked
oh thank you respect
respect you know the
[Music]
drill you going just pure
turps yeah it's pure turps so it's light
it's the
essence it tastes so good my God it
tastes so good
that's what we're talking about right
there definitely hit at least two to 300
people up with Turf dabs today we went
through the Nashville bubbles went
through the BC rosin went through some
of the Cali and the Denver and much much
TP look at the darkness on this tarpine
vial from dipping you know what they
look like when they're pure to very very
clear liquid it's uh quite incredible
that uh this has got
dark oh yeah
superet see you guys in a bit we're
waiting for Bush man and luchano to hit
the stage and we're looking really
forward to both those performances so
I'm going to try not to miss them what a
day man that was
amazing we just did it up dude I think
we need to go around this way
[Applause]
no isn't there a VIP St oh it's over
there trippy okay Lead Me The Way Lead
Me the Way
[Music]
yeah dude we smoked out
today I got one in damn me too [ __ ] me
too I barely got one
in probably smoked three
[Music]
total that they made let's hook up no
the dudn't following us
Ravis
[Music]
yes have
Bubble we're going to smoke their bubble
tonight home he wants to go home awesome
yeah vital one
[Music]
vital he cry for the you
more than anything else he's calling
more than anything else he's
[Music]
calling he's calling he's calling Ang
go let's give it up for the
K hey how are you doing nice to meet
you debie nice to meet you this is my
friend birdeye hey yeah we know my girl
oh P
[Music]
[Applause]
this why hey
[Music]
balance balance
balance
like cuz any time she want she ask she
said she me
give so while the root thicker than M
man
real Bea she respect
soever together something to treasure
[Music]
forever she love
some
[Music]
V Baby Let Me Take
You More
We seash and I'll
[Music]
be and give you what you want some more
the realest you been with and I can tell
you those few lines in English spray me
love like a fire exting
that's why sing
[Music]
this she say she love
it hold on balance it there
you see when me sing to the princess
them you know we not going r&amp; B
something we just take it like a cush in
the bush you
know and me look in her
eyes and she look very trilled you
know and I just catch one side and say
baby let me tell you something some go
[Music]
[Applause]
I
[Music]
[Applause]
good night my
people good night [ __ ] are you feeling
good are you
feeling let me hear say can you hold