hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and we are here today at high integrity
glass art have this absolutely beautiful
piece to review today this is a
collaboration between uh Joe peder's
glass and SP Gat X on Instagram if you
check my Instagram BC bubbleman I've got
a photo of it if you check high
integrity glass Arts Instagram he's got
a photo of it and it gives the links to
both the blowers and uh mentions that
it's a prototype uh biosphere perk I can
show you now what the perk looks like in
slow motion you can see it's very
violent eruption from the base as it
curls around the back and comes through
this giant biosphere perk and almost
like shoots out of the piece rather than
in a solid stream like a recycler
usually does it's got this real sort of
cool Splash and it creates a a different
feel when you pull through
it woo tastes real nice high integrity
glass art just ripped it for the first
time and had a real nice rip and uh I'm
about to join him on that so I guess we
will torch it up boom boom
boom all right lovely remnants I'm also
going in for same strawberry
banana perfect yeah I heated it up a
little less than 20 seconds so we're
going to do a 40c cool down on that and
uh yeah there's really nice little sort
of a little beehive in the middle here
with this really cool disc perk that
comes out the bottom really a violent
eruption of the bees in there classic
Joe
P stoked to hit this I'm not going to
lie we about 8 seconds out oh yeah did I
mention I've been uh not puffing for the
last 8 days and this is about my fourth
or fifth Puff
orig
[Music]
IND wow
real nice preservation on those turs for
sure hitting out of the
Banger and uh that perk is unique I can
definitely say it is unique it sort of
starts out like a recycler but it's more
open and it has uh more chug to it not
as tight of a pull but really unique
nonetheless and I like how it uh how it
preserved those turps that nice low temp
dab of course
always good etiquette to clean your
friend's
Banger don't Chaz The
Banger as we
say all
right well that was just damn sweet I'm
not going to lie real real nice maybe go
and do a live Instagram video right now
and show them what they're missing out
there because this is uh this is
something new always props of the glass
blowers and uh high integrity glass art
peace out
everybody did I mention this
pendant did I mention this pendant I
don't think I did completely ridiculous
totally
sick my
God faceted on the edges
Jimmy Sign Sealed and
Delivered
I'll leave you with that peace out
everybody