[Music]
all right well I'm gonna turn this on
and we're gonna get into our positions
talk a little smack with Johnny be good
to see brother ridiculous it's been so
long since you've been here I can't even
believe it I think my head was bald I
don't even know it's possible you might
have been like a child
welcome to bubble man world everybody
bubble man's world or bubble man world
yeah bubble man's world that's the world
we're welcoming you to and I'm here with
my good friend Johnny [ __ ] be Johnny
[ __ ] bees in the house
well he's outside of the house he's my
start site in the house but you were in
it yet earlier I actually he walks very
slowly greeted by dog walk slowly
firstly smashed again no just a small
little sign for those of you that have
been keeping track of the Johnny B
dramas of car accidents let's see it
started with a dump truck no no it
didn't start with the dump truck I think
there's one before that oh I've been in
a lot myself to be honest but I feel
like they they are nothing compared so
Johnny B got smoked like less than a
month ago maybe two weeks ago I'll show
you the picture yeah it was it was L see
let's put it up right now so now they're
looking at the picture okay so much I
got t-boned you're that t-bone you can
see it in your car your cars I'll smash
the [ __ ] what he years ago let's
slide over to the next picture oh damn
see how it's hit on the front and I can
see that my car was t-boned on the side
and how the wheels are broken off like
that
I actually was crossing through an
intersection and he hit me
no brakes no brakes full want
acceleration as we spun through the
intersection I thought I hit a
people on bikes I jumped on when I
killed somebody because I've ever seen
them on the bikes going through the
intersection so just that whole slow-mo
action of the airbags going off and
glass flying right out of the movie geez
right out of a movie
and I came to a stop and I jumped out
tried turning off the car and oh you
know what what the officer said thank
God you were driving the Subaru was that
what he said yeah exactly what he said
so Subaru Outback full airbags went off
from the whole car as you can see in
this picture yeah yeah it's like come
easy and even have an airbag in the side
of the seat that went off like the whole
thing it's quite amazing actually but it
was a hard impact and you know the next
day I saw my doctor and then didn't even
do for about three days and it's a
weakening of not paying attention and
you know I just settled with ICBC a week
prior and I supposed to be a trial that
week but I wasn't gonna wasn't pay for
my house no try it
it'd be cool well they have to ask me
someone have to actually offer it first
you know I mean it's gonna be for sale
and I'm for it
hey Joanie become I sell you some hash
hey ICBC hooked me up with the check
oh yeah but some is what we're talking
about now we're talking about natural
medicine and full circle and it's uh you
know they gave me some
anti-inflammatories I went home and
started down with some CB Iceland you're
good to go
oh yeah that's what I'm talking about
I'm not low temps perfect low temp that
Oh
snippets
how is that wedding-cake
120 micron six star it's bubble hash so
the repeat now we're doing a lot of
people putting the dabs in the bottom
cold cold start cold starting I mean
it's I mean I I feel like I got to know
cold starting through the puff coke peak
the puffs go because that's really what
it does but I think Bobby nugs kind of
created the the hype on I've just seen a
few people like he did a couple of
articles and people wrote made videos of
them and it kind of went viral and so
yeah it's a great idea people that want
a cold start I think it's cool for me
with this unit I'm just so happy to be
able to blast yeah with the temp tech I
can blast my my nail without you know or
my banger without paying attention to
the amount of time that I'm hitting it
with and then just drop it usually I'll
be honest I usually do it for maybe less
than 10 seconds and when I put it down
it's usually around like 750 to 850
ready to go right away I like it to be
able to I have to admit I like heating
it passed the temperature and then
dropping it there's something in the
heat retention there that's different
from just heating it up to like 600
degrees in taking a DAB there's there's
a loss that I feel is better when I heat
it up past you know it's kind of funny
because we used like them from the
subtle mayor's to the details and all
these electric devices and I'm back on
my torch
I kind of like it better you keep
talking well the but I'm gonna fix my
torch what but the thing is it's what
I'm hitting with the torches I always
had the Dean yell on I come home and be
like didn't I go on and stuff like that
but I found that what I really want that
turkey hit that I can actually do a
lower temp table which is really
important for me I get up in the morning
and I want that turkey taste and you
know I used to turn down the Dean ale
and stuff like that but you know the
torch is just something that kind of
been working extremely well other than
yeah my butane but once again you know
there's all these different devices out
there that seem to work and the
old-school well it's not even old-school
I guess the old-school wouldn't be the
dropping down before I or even before
that in there so we're you're back and
ready to go by the way that was a nice
quick 10 second or second I was just
talking to white and I heard back to
that you know this I kind of liked it I
got I got like I got I got I don't have
a gmail in all my room so I have my
mothership outside of my garage I have
my Jessie only see my hippo sits at the
counter see I got all these little
things that I do and it's kind of funny
it's it's it's easier for me to medicate
that way than it is to actually like I
need to know I need this this is
important for me because I've been
burning the wrist
counting down with temperatures using
all kinds of things but the temp tech
for me is is something new game changer
I assess on the cold start and not was I
want to taint it with D 420k there a
couple weeks ago to me I was like okay
that's cool never done it before
and then seeing the temp tech is I'm
pretty sure that's gonna be like I'm
where to get this oh yeah
look it up for sure I've had tons of
people asking me since I did my unboxing
video it's just a great little tool and
for those of you that are already gonna
write oh for $15 you can get a laser
thermometer yes yes you can for $15 you
can get a laser thermometer and you can
hold it under your banger and it totally
works this is way more expensive but
it's a product it's a brand it's a it's
a unit it's got a solute out it's got
its little light it's if you can create
or control the emissivity levels which
is basically there's different
emissivity levels I've been learning for
different surfaces so quartz is
generally 0.3 0.9 32.9 4 I have it set
on 0.9 for right now I don't know it's
just like the laser is gonna hit the
surface and how it measures that surface
and what that surface is will change how
it measures so you tell the laser what
the surfaces and then accords and
adjusts accordingly so I didn't know I
still might not be explaining it there's
always some brilliant person watching
who if I have miss explain that to
Johnny be by all means write it in the
comments I think we should just keep
taking dabs I don't like that what would
what would you like to get some treats
from the heavenly days that's what I
just hit
just hit that same thing some heavenly
days give thanks to heavenly days and
concentrated acts who was the producer
of the wedding cake full mel 120 microns
you know I'm being kind like a big truck
there's a lot of big trucks I saw all
the new stuff did that stuff going on so
you know for a for being in the middle
of nowhere which really look at can you
see my neighbors like I'm here in the
middle of nowhere
I'm literally on the side of a mountain
and there are still countless monster
trucks
let's see what he's doing oh he's a big
one
he's a big one you know why he's a real
absolutely getting ready to lift all the
house that we have been making all month
long so we've got about 6,000 pounds
this is how we do the deliver he's going
to come in what's new we have to do
these days I mean we're getting to those
levels of hash making that the glossy
picking to the levels of how we are
setting years ago he said there's two
types of hash dealers those that require
forklifts and those that don't
[Music]
teen forklift entrance team forklift
teen crane new hash tags for it well
it's good to see you dude it's been a
while since I shared a bowl with you a
little - that was around 650 I like it
to be around 850 I like of course
well I don't want to dab at 850 now now
we're at 850 and it'll take a few
seconds it'll cool so when you down but
850 a 4-1 it rips into you really quick
and as you a 4-2 it just kept it like
hardcore that's why you see my baby
anywhere they were RC - I have one
that's non job it's not chance such as
that's my I have my Chaz extra chair get
Go Go Johnny be
yeah she's a slide and she's a slip'n
you go sir oh yeah it's always nice to
carb friend give a little twist on the
directional shoutout to JP and Toro this
is one of my favorite bangers and carb
caps in fact I think I could easily say
it is my fan favorite banger and carb
cap I haven't yet tried the chirp
slurper well mine I have tried it before
and I haven't tried the core reactor I'm
not a big like half gram gram Demi I
can't it's not not of a high interest to
me to do such things but I love the idea
of the core reactor that big chunk of
course but watching one worth actually
heat then it goes around the outer edge
and there's a sentiment saw the other
day
nice yeah endless innovation and it's in
one with the ball bearings spinning
that's all here in town
yeah there we go that clean a nice like
it clean now that was tasty
um I think it's what I just hit but if
not sure I think that's what I just hit
but I'll try again and I'll confirm
yummy showed up to the camera but really
close okay I'm getting up and then you
gotta put your hand behind it too so it
focuses on the hash yep yep yep I'm
skilled at this in the past and you can
kind of get hopefully a good look and
you get an idea there you go so it's
kind of like it's just lot going on
these days look at this amazing goodness
it's like really you dealing with like
really say concentrates for a pain and
really understanding how like just
natural medicine and making the house
it's funny how it came so far so quickly
but yet you know so much more needs to
be explained and how this works so well
the reasons why we do this that was
delicious
yeah it's so delicious the terms I
thought it might be a little bit
different that's why one because this
was a little special I think maybe
that's what that's what the big powers I
just thought it was the special special
and he gave me a small pile but knowing
ro he gave me the big pile of the
skittles so give thanks brother that's
much appreciated that was absolutely
delicious and tasty got me I ready yeah
looks good not irate not my RA
after the accident you didn't I mean it
was just the most amazing actually did
adopt it and you were done that's nice
yeah I do also appreciate doing like
three or four dabs in a row with a
friend for six you know just having a
good time
agreed not much else to share with you
guys other than we're both busy
obviously Johnny B's been doing tons
I've been doing tons just focused on all
things embark focused on Whistler
technologies and focused on travel
traveling a lot a lot a lot of traveling
so you see some pretty amazing sights
meters and amazing fields yeah I think
hopefully eventually I'll get to all the
videos so we had a crew come with us to
Spain and film a ton of stuff I put one
teaser up on the channel but hopefully
we'll get more and then I still have
Jamaica to post which I put one video up
so far but I probably have like a good
three or four other videos and then I
also have Colombia and I'm sure there's
at least you know two or three good
little clip itch videos from Colombia
going into the mountains in Kalka and
seeing all the coca plants and the
cannabis plants growing side by side it
was pretty neat for sure you would have
definitely been tripping out and loving
it licensed producers cannabis and
looking at this evaporation crisis yeah
it's a big problem it's uh it's funny
because you know they should honestly
you should be selling that data to
Health Canada I've been actually
compiling now spreadsheets had taking a
look at data and taking a look at who's
doing what and I want to know who's got
controlled packing rooms who's using the
oh there's different ceiling I'm seeing
so huge in abduction we learned this all
it'd be good to have like a like an
actual like they over regulate
everything except the important things
like regulating active water content and
the way you package and the SOPs package
under like make those regulations not
ridiculous and unreasoning here's a
great one but patient focused patient
focus so I'm gonna hit you guys in your
pocketbook and I'm gonna go after canopy
so they left 151 million dollars in the
first quarter I tested all of their
cannabis at 42% 44 and 46 so here's my
question how much did they lose any
operation in money-wise that alone
because you're now you're looking at
hundreds of thousands of pounds and when
you're losing 8 and 10% water put that
in your pocket yeah and really and and
and and if you look at that then you're
gonna start waking up because when you
can't control a packaging room to
package the product you put so much
money into growing yeah there's a
problem 50 million dollar facility you
think the packaging room would be
state-of-the-art I could pretty much
tell you right now if you package that
62% well Jim he may be that count ups
are coming where I flee about 52 53
inside the container so you have the oxy
package about 68% and that was the
little test that I've learned right and
these little things that I hope you guys
serve listening and you start learning
the same thing yeah it's a little bit
complex
it's just moisture content it's active
water content as you used to do which is
different than moisture this is concise
is the product and the space that
surrounds the product
not just the product not just the
product so it's really important to
understand that I'm learning I've been
learning for a lot of six months and and
really understanding you know I'm seeing
not see even what what my screen users
are probably coming up with the better
products because they're doing certain
well we should do a video from my
channel dude we should do an act of
water video test look at the bumblebee
just went in the house he lives in there
that's awesome I have a bumblebee that
lives in my bird house one single
bumblebee he's happy that's why I put my
finger in there I know what you're doing
up yeah I was seeing a fee was around I
put my finger and he'll like step on my
finger and I can pull him out of that
house that probably was the be that
ready Kirsch that's my medicine
he's like Johnny B but he's bumble bee
bumble [ __ ] bee
yeah but octave water is a really
important subject and now I want to go
deeper into it I want to have you over
and I want to do like a test of two or
three varieties and we'll just we'll
walk them through it will explain the
difference of active water versus
moisture going as deep as we can and I
know he's been sharing this on his own
channel which you guys can check out at
John Barr fellow but I want the content
for this channel as well and Johnny B
needs another reason to come out to
lions baby that's right I need to sit
down enough to explain it because my
content is invented pieces of my videos
because I'm always doing what I'm doing
some do a full one I haven't really got
into the whole I've done a water testing
but sitting down and explaining it as in
let's get some canvas let's talk about
all the different seals I know what
companies are doing hey let's do that
and you can talk about all the different
paths
we're packaging and how it's testing and
active water and seeing what's trying on
fantastic stuff that was packaged almost
a year ago by one company it is still
coming in to same a little busier let's
buy a bunch of cannabis I'll pay for it
and then we will do the active water
test and then we will I guess I wouldn't
want to waste it but it would be a good
show to do like you know Roz and where
half of it is used without the
percentage brought up and half of it is
used to be between this and I started
I've seen we meta fiying imprecise
that's like that but of small and you
know what that'd be great because you're
gonna completely see me see what strains
are where the see the the aw is that
like 36 percent this is low don't forget
breadcrumbs that's really low its food
it must be like almost like powder
pastas 50:29 in it went to dust dust 29s
ridiculous they also must realize like
that seal if it's going then are the
terpenes consuming whatever that
material was that was the other thing
what type of seal are they using is it a
chemical glue is it something that
shouldn't be consumed by terpenes and
then inhaled by a patient see this is
things that I don't think they've done
the research on here I got something to
show you Johnny BAC this is what's
awesome this is why we do what we do and
why we get so actively involved because
it's the passion of being able to see
and how things react inside containers
inside different things those little
great products that come to you and you
get to check out new little devices and
stuff like that and since I have the
agent I have my machine in my car
there's no machine for this no machine
for this
well this is as simple as like going
like this and pushing air out then you
can open it it creates a small vacuum
it's a nice glass job right away there
you can hear it right away you can have
that one because you were just saying we
get these cool little products so can
Locke sent this to me and I just thought
you know what like maybe we'll have can
lock sponsor us in our testing of
cannabinoids water content maybe they'll
buy the herb they've already supplied
the containers yeah exactly so companies
like vivo does companies like can lock
look I like this company because a very
simply you can create a vacuum and you
can suck look now my button doesn't go
down anymore
yeah just for all the air is out now
listen absolutely so for those are you
and you notice they make it a size for
an early smoker like this is not a hash
jar I mean it is my ice jar don't get me
wrong
second falafel I'm gonna use hash but
this is a perfect jar for like a flavor
you know you got your seven grams or
whatever it's a nice dr or something
down low so you know when their friends
come over see this would keep it real
fresh you know although I'd have to look
at you know is this a PTFE is this
terpene resistant because this is gonna
be different you know that's gonna take
a look at all those things with the lid
you know all that research with it will
go yeah so I think when it come down to
me what type of plastic it is is it a
metal ready yeah exactly it's got to be
it's got to be able to withstand
segregation from terpenes so I'll ask
them about that
so yes you can have that one I like it
built-in pump twist on this milk roof
washable jar travel ready maybe you
could put some here maybe you can put
some herb in it and leave it in there
for like 30 or 40 days and then we could
do the active water content test okay
how about we do this oh that goes around
here this goes in there which fits into
here there you go
it's only a half size so it should be
smudged up there you go perfect
packaging holy [ __ ] on everything it is
kind of ridiculous I'm not gonna say
it's not okay so buy a gram of say some
weed from friends weed MD and the
package is this big in a box a box with
the container in the Box in the box
inside of plastic not too different from
this actually comes with a bag here you
go but nonetheless look this is how
we've come to you yeah because they put
in another box we have to make ourselves
available to the audience to do this
maybe I want to do this I want to do
this active water test I want to show
them what it's all about kind of get the
model on line and so what we're gonna do
and I think this will you come here I'll
bring some nicely fresh I got some herb
I've got some peanut butter breath it's
nicely in a jar beautiful you saving it
I'll bring that here will touch the aw
we'll put it inside the jar will seal it
we'll put it away the aw see
I got in trouble for saying the content
I know I've gotten in trouble I know
that no because but you're educating
here's one of these head researcher he's
the main QA guy and scientists are like
that really did a lot of education and
husband Brian is the head quality
control and science guy behind the team
of Boveda both the nvidia has created
you know that communities for all these
different he educated me saying things
wrong how you just certain things that
really understanding of how much water
is inside of a container that goes we
did some explaining yeah we're
definitely gonna have a good show on
this to talk more about for sure
absolutely show bring the charts that
are printed out to have more of a
discussion on looking at the charts of
what levels to look at sauce and then
where Bowl ticket allen to start why a
lot of these people i would say would be
more concerned about how much active
waters in the cannabis because I think
Health Canada's scared everybody away
from being being able to sell fresh when
it says right on the container
yeah a big run on every mechanic that's
keeping us dry dry because they're so
worried about mold they've dried it out
beyond I still see a lot of
consistencies between the 44 46 percent
arts but I think that just has to do
with I can see I can tell you what
provinces and I can tell you where let's
package up right across the country by
its octopus and BC seems to be the
highest set of everybody to cross camera
highest percentage the rainforests right
even when it's dry it's little things
that I've seen that's cool yeah
interesting since Christmas Christmas
Day I wasn't expecting it but it was in
my know its moisture and it's neither
we're definitely going to come back and
revisit this
I would hope yeah we should do a good
good video well we write it down and
show everything and then in the meantime
I'm gonna load up dab of strawberry
banana for Johnny we're gonna call it a
day so I can actually go visit Johnny be
without being on camera that's kind of
like gotta save some of our friendship
for
but be so long since we all hung out
together and you know what every single
what are you guys doing we've been busy
so busy this great things
I know it's a witch it's a changing the
worlds as we're seeing it today when it
comes to cannabis extractions and get
that on the Banger anyway guys thanks
for tuning in
quick one from Johnny B and bum man
[Music]
you