[Music]
yeah yeah how's it been from med Tanner
you've been telling people a lot about
meditators meditator potater
everybody has before the tosh everybody
good on the coffee shop show us show us
show us what they're like airtight
watertight stores container completely
diverse flood of water storage container
100% airtight watertight strong enough
coffee right that's the best part of
both that look at this more than coffee
in that few beans like that right in
there already pre ground oh just a
beautiful frog and renewing fun abundant
water best thing about this met Tina
this air seal it's got the wearable
personal word for qualified medical
grade plastic restoring let's think
you're your mom's tough world to see
your grandma's coming with us still in
your closet that's what this made-up
table got teeth very unique design why
the world will parse the moving parts so
it never touches with that you don't get
anything metal shavings if you read a
little pieces of plastic with the other
grunts excellent sense RESP underwater
medicine
the Greenway meditator advancing forward
with cannabis medicine Annika and where
can people that aren't at the Cannabis
Cup check out meditator know he can go
down to the met Tanner Combat Team
Canada duck ca's just wiggle that tanner
and you will find us guaranteed twitter
myspace YouTube hits the ground were
there for every word I like John right
on buddy
he's probably talking to you