yeah all right oh man and Johnny be in
the house today where is our puff
Wednesdays oh yeah we're always getting
together on pop Wednesday and today I'm
going to treat John's got my house
smelling like a grow room from just
these four little well not little bit
like substantially beautiful tops that
you cut off you want to go through each
one and tell them what to you know just
like a quick like one minute explanation
of what this one is each one not really
a top but this one here enough set off
this is many cush and this is what when
my candles cups with 2011 2000-2012
treating yourself expo on my first place
at 2011 second place 2012 yeah listen
Eddie this is really the one that we did
our full melt of dry sip videos on stuff
Lebanese agonize happy really an
outstanding strength next in line is
senility this is this is sour kush
that's what the common and it's just so
nice so nice and we took some shots of
those trifles man there yeah quite
beautiful we'll throw some of these each
one that he's talking about while he's
talking about it I'll put some of these
trifles shots that I've gotten in each
one in the video so you can see up close
this is the last one that you took
when you were you were saying how
amazing the tribal oh yeah they're so
nice so so this this is this is a beam
craft in 09 2010 brought it to tea water
for the first exponent I was told is
pretty amazing so they said if you enter
you might win first place oxley Franco
said he would don't bring that here so i
brought my third in won first place is
done excellent and this is a really
strong OG cross with we really don't
know but culture maybe an m1 wait up you
know it's interesting strength Larry
Larkin string and last but not least oh
this one they're calling headband this
is a sour push but they're saying but it
is a master kush cross with an old G and
it is truly outstanding you can like wow
yeah we'll throw some nice pictures up
for you guys to some so it's all this is
what a city gonna have the house it's
all about the cushions then of course we
have a little dry slip crushes there's
also I've number for number three number
two and many Heys so there we go many
days along with two three four and five
number 10 mistakes long beautiful dry
cept you know eighty to ninety percent
pure heads maybe
zealous and clean that last ten twenty
percent down gets a pose for you guys
but all in all real just havin a good
time shooting nuts doing our puff
Wednesday's having a bowl I think we'll
have one right now perhaps of the many
case please yes I think that's my more
of your favorites I I didn't really
appreciate the hayeses I have to say
well that was this one else working on
is trying to pull the more the medicinal
class of the many cush and put it into
more of a hazy what everybody
daytime because of it
well did you see that just gentle tap on
the camera in it was like a cloud thank
God it all landed with us we're Garrity
golfing with 10,000 us oh that's only
about 97-92 oh if I can counter well
shoot them actually if I'm available
they do they look like it took up here
all right here we go hit the mothership
a little bit of fullmetal tricep from
John puff Wednesday's what I should be
puffing with you just gonna pass me that
p1 right over excellent with the dry
cept I don't even want to exhale I want
to keep it inside it's so good really
good anyway I'm going to get back to
doing a little photography hear John's
going to get back to doing some puffing
North apparently good medicine yeah
we'll turn the camera on again if we
feel that there's something worthy of
sharing otherwise if you want to check
us out live anytime come to the tinychat
com backslash bubbleman fresh headies
that's be you bebe le ma n fres HH e ad
IES be cool to have you come show up in
the video chat we got a bunch of cool
peeps in there right now blazing with us
and talk about this beautiful chillin oh
yeah absolutely one hundred percent
growing techniques and all the fun stuff
of comes with on Tuesday absolutely and
yeah we'll be hitting a sublimator in a
little bit later and running course
we're going to hit the fresh nugget in
this elevator and I want to mention that
Marc Emery is still not back in Canada
so let's do our best to get in touch
with the minister there in Ottawa and
regards to you on the phones getting
mark out
he was a resident back up to Canada the
US have said that they will let mark
serve the rest of his sentence in Canada
so let's try to make a lot happened
alright see you guys later peace hey
there hey how's it going bubbleman and
John here sitting out on the deck on the
beautiful afternoon here in the house
and we were photographing some earbuds
earlier that was kind of fun I will vex
big boy taking we smoked all the dry
sift flavors all five yeah those were
wonderful and you know we just saw the
Sun come out we kind of ended up out
here we've been laxing chilling out we
thought we'd have some bowls finish off
the actually hard working day yeah puff
Wednesday's you're coming to the near
end it's almost 4 20 you'll be here for
that as well but it's time to get a few
more bowls yeah meantime
really do like this or like this little
ones are the keys all right some nice
song what's what's up oh this is 1973
actually aka the real 73 my favorite
real 73
beautiful day for puffin bowls beautiful
day for enjoying cannabis as a medicine
just feeling blessed today or if you
could see this melt so glorious it's
wonderful i'm sorry you guys can't see
this but I'm actually maybe if I would
show up with some of them let some other
videos yeah i will make a video and
we'll add it to the video see every time
we say we wish you can see something i
want to be able to show it to you so
well i think they've seen a few of you
around nice videos yeah yeah there's
some definitely pissed dry sift up on
youtube there bubbleman world bubble
man's world channel just a quiet
beautiful day it's nice it's peaceful
sure don't have any clouds up in that
sky cold chilly tonight cold and chilly
tonight make for exceptional dry sifting
yeah
what I like some of the last of the many
Heys was the question would you guys
like to try to answer that that's one of
those strains yes exactly once a year I
know there's a whole health canada thing
all right i'll be able to grow again
your aunt will have it you're gonna be
able to grow it again um one that this
can't be a thing of the past oh you
can't get it away with one even myself I
have a license for 20 grams a day which
is about a gram of resin a day our sword
two grams of resin a day 20 grams
usually notes I like to lowball the
number but yeah seven to ten grams usual
evil queen ghost on the ground with nice
92 73
it's a mile to smoke mostly Graham up in
a day usually but sometimes you know if
I want to feed my end of cannabinoid
system and i want it i want to have that
extra gram or another extra gram my
license so i can do that each day the
becky to you have this whole place
but that's another topic and I have a
license and I'm thankful before having
it because I'm able to produce great
your medicine for myself as you're
trying I love it monka cabinet trionic
free clean medicine you want to know
what I call it grown by myself I've been
calling it this for years the
unadulterated cannabinoid hi worst fear
the profile extracted as is and simply
isolated to be enjoyed to its full
potential pretty much guarantee that
nice skin cream in the Sun it's
unbelievable it's looking so white
something a billion little hands of me
we should melt them this just in 425,000
heads have been burned in a fire and
inhaled I meant a nerd John well thanks
for hanging out with us today and
watching I know this last little bits
been a bit boring but hopefully you're
able to put it on nice full screen and
just enjoy that enjoy a couple bowls
with us and hold it back next week off
wednesdays hopefully i will have to show
lined up video pod TV so you can go back
and watch it for this palace but for now
we're just on my youtube channel easy
balloons will see the memory very soon
you
what's up man you got a little work for
22 left open up and said I'm glad to see
they can take away my job my friends you
see and
sunshine
Oh