[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here at high integrity glass art and
feeling very blessed indeed not only
because I'm standing in front of the
most EP epic denail electric nail table
that was ever built uh it's been an
absolute joy to be puffing on this table
but also there is some incredible
quality uh congales hash rosin just here
to my left which is uh what we're going
to be hitting today don't want to turn
it too sideways cuz there are little
shards and I don't want to drop those
but uh you can see the quality is on
point I'll throw up some macro
photographs just to give you an idea of
the quality of this resin and we are
hitting the one of one punty deppy ball
Fab with cold work and faceted work on
the base uh the mouthpiece and the joint
got a brand new quave Banger in there
and we're actually kind of showcasing
which is pretty cool when you're hitting
such an incredible one of one piece you
would think the Showcase was obviously
the piece but the Showcase is actually
this incredibly
beautiful uh Innovative design on a carb
C app from JS glass that's jsor glass if
you're checking them out on Instagram
not sure if you can see this I'll kind
of get a little closer for you maybe a
little update on that you see how the
the tip of it is a little bit offset
what that allows us to do is while we're
doing a lower temp dab to put this on
and spin it around the the um Banger and
what it does is it moves the rip and in
instead of letting it just sit where the
glass or the quartz is cooler it moves
it around consistency and you can really
get a pretty substantially uh better hit
using uh a carb cap like this so we're
going to rip it up here right now uh I'm
super blessed uh and honored to be able
to hit this piece because it's
definitely one for the books from
2013 so a solid three three plus years
old now and uh yeah we're going to torch
it up and hit
it L's world uh got the timer on it's at
about 15 seconds probably around 40
seconds 40 to 50 seconds depending on
how low temp of a dab you want to rip on
this uh and you can see I've done a
close-up video how the the resin well
I'll show you in about a second here
when I take my rip that it really sort
of moves around the bottom of the quartz
Banger it's a it's Innovative and that's
what I love to see in the community so
we're hitting 37 seconds 38 39 let's do
this
that
wow one of the things I found that was
really cool right off the bat is as I
was turning
it you could see sweet spots where if
you turned it too fast it would milk for
a second and then stop melking but if
you brought it back to that spot and
made the oil go over that hot spot of
the Banger it just gave this really
lovely really lovely Hit And The Taste
was on point we we've been puffing out
of the sapphire which was one of my uh
one of my favorite um dishes to hit off
of I love the way it preserves the tpin
and the flavor but I have to say this
carb cap with the quave Banger has given
a delicious hit so shout out to JS glass
for doing a great job on creating some
Innovative new uh options for um for
dabbing and obviously shout out to punty
and deppy and the mothership crew and of
course high integrity glass art always a
pleasure my friend thank you guys for
watching Bubble man's world and we will
talk to you next time peace
[Music]
out bu man set up the machine what kind
of strain you have there you why is so
clean and
clear come on
we da
in
da it's time da time time we
dabing
da da daing
[Music]