hey guys so I'm just at the end of the
cliffs past the lighthouse we've gone to
go to one of my favorite restaurant
places I haven't been here in 10 years
it's called just natural and it wasn't
there it was all closed up and I was
really bummed out so we just drove to
the end of the cliffs and right as I did
a u-turn my friends saw a sign for just
natural so we're gonna go check it out
here now
[Music]
welcome I haven't been here for 10 years
this one she used to serve me all the
time with my wife and my family and my
wife's back in Canada I can't believe
how excited I am to have found you guys
because the old place is closed I'm
promoting you on my youtube channel
right now yeah we're doing a YouTube
video for bubble man's world and we're
gonna tell about 10,000 people to come
to just natural my family is very good I
just had another little boy just like 15
you wouldn't know no I'm joking I got
three I got three three kids two boys
one girl I got it maybe one more boy
another girl one more girl okay all
right I'll get on that when I get home
literally I just what's that
six months here two more years
you're that sweetie I have to wait two
more years all right all right it's
really good to see you both
I'm so happy I've been missing the
banana marmalade of course you guys
don't know how lucky you are right now
let's grab a seat okay exactly
not face thanks
that me termination
the French toast it's amazing yes
foreign genessee they're always singular
that's why they're comma but you can and
a fresh fruit plate and a veggie or of a
fruit punch like a mixed fruit drink
[Music]
this is great I'll also mention that in
12 years both of you have not aged at
all so Wow just natural that's a little
bit gray in my beard
yeah that's what I'm saying I hope I
know
Wow yeah I don't try to hide anything
I'm a natural guy that's why we're at
just natural man I'm so happy to be here
you guys I can't even tell you what a
nice surprise it was for those to be my
friends that I haven't seen in 10 to 12
years Wow
my wife will enjoy watching this video
because they're also her friends just
natural look at this place you guys I
mean this is legit just bring you guys
in one more time through the front door
here place is pretty pretty relaxed
atmosphere super herb friendly we could
have brought the mothership and had a
mad session in here
[Music]
it's probably where we're sitting
or maybe even around the corner here
yeah let's do the corner absolutely this
is really nice
[Music]
are you kidding me
we have tables all the way back here to
like all giddy like a school kid telling
ya I love Jamaica
[Music]
[Applause]
Wow this is pretty cool just keeps going
more tables I think this is the end
right here Wow pretty cool
we got massage table set up over here I
go back a couple of massage tables set
up
[Music]
let's place is huge it's huge best part
of the day right here yeah I'm sharing
yep sharing is caring
I said order a passionfruit juice I have
to get one of course we're gonna help
judge and we're gonna be speaking to oh
that's nice yeah we're would I bring you
guys anywhere that wasn't delicious come
on just natural I can't believe how it
was found I'm doing a u-turn in the car
and Maurice is like there was a sign for
just natural I'm like what thank you
dude
just that following us long time you
know what
bubble bubble man fish you can call me
ya little Trinity and Tosh my wife yeah
I'll show you some pictures later all
right you bet I will
I'm gonna bring them right here I want
to see that wicked thank you so much
all right since I don't see ya
that's what it cost you
[Applause]
[Music]
wow that's cool eh this is my buddy's
castle over here well he sold it a
couple years ago yeah
one of the very beautiful places in the
grille the blue cape Casa de force
volcanoes castles just across the way
you sold a few years back for many years
and the whole pot to rock crew very cool
guys very old-school and legit history
here in that grille in Jamaica so uh I
guess we're probably gonna see if we
can't make it down the staircase and
just go get a few shots the caves over
here you go down there and the cave yeah
exactly exactly
so here's the cave that you can come out
of
and over there
these are the kind of things I want to
offer on the bubble man's tour the ocean
splashing up behind me pretty awesome
beautiful really beautiful really man I
want to jump in Tony no
I'll do it
so this is the entrance to the blue cave
castle it heads down these stairs and
when the seas aren't so rough you can
walk down you can actually swim in
through the cave and out into the sea
the Caribbean Sea so this is blue cave
castles found in Negril Jamaica come
check it out
not yet we're waiting for them
No
how epic is that Tony
not bad eh Brian
blue cave castle
but if the water comes in hot well then
we're getting wet I'm standing in the
zone right here where the water could
really come in literally soak me drink
like to the bone I don't know what's
gonna happen but I'm gonna hang out for
a while and wait I think we might have
to grab the mother ships and come back
here for a cave session that's what I'm
talking about
[Music]