hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm uh pretty relaxed here out on the
house sound chilling on the boat but I
wanted to uh give you guys a mention
that we're going to be doing hash church
again uh this Sunday I thought it would
be a good idea to let everyone know in
advance I'm hoping on getting Dr David
Allen to come in and chat with us I
spoke with him a little bit today about
some very interesting things that I'll
leave to him if he comes in on Sunday um
I've invited Horatio back I've invited
Johnny B in d420 K and I've actually
invited uh Tony verzura from uh United
cannabis and from River Rock Wellness
Center he hasn't said whether he's going
to be able to do it but he's definitely
going to make an attempt so that's cool
too and I figured while I had you guys
here on the
boat we would smoke a pure hash joint
because I know it's dark I'm back lit by
the sun I just figured I'd share a
beautiful hash joint with the bubble
man's world audience so let's do it
up
a little bit different than lighting
your everyday joint because you got a
big hollow space when you're sucking in
that heat off the Cherry it's
substantial you kind of want to put your
teeth in in in the way cuz the air that
you suck through the tube is extremely
hot that's why I had to light it three
or four times but uh that's a gram of
hash right there and it'll probably burn
for 15 to 20 minutes judging by my last
video where I smoked a pure hash joint
to the uh right down to the roach and
then finished that off in the Swiss perk
I think that was about 20 minutes
luckily I have a couple of friends with
me on the boat today one holding the
phone and one sitting just out of the
camera angle and they're they're going
to be enjoying it with me so remember
Church hash church on Sunday coming up
in four or five days we'd love to see
you in there it's Google Plus you can
check the YouTube account at the bottom
of the page it says live events coming
soon and it'll show you that event when
you click on it you open up the box
it'll show you a countdown if it has not
yet begun when that number gets down to
zero I'll push on air and we'll be
broadcasting live so come hang out with
us at hash church I hope to see you
there I'm going to uh finish this
beautiful hash joint with my friends
thanks for watching Bubble man's
world what