[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
and welcome to Toronto I'm at Pearson
International Airport I've just flown in
from Vancouver I got my apex pen as you
know I don't really [ __ ] around when I
come to Toronto Canada why I was pretty
good and didn't puff on the plane but
here at the airports a different story
put a while since I had a good tooth so
of course I'm gonna have to have one
here so I'm about to go outside meet
Elliott I'm here for the karma cup Sara
Sunday's throwing the Karma cup it is
today the final day of judging and the
festivities I've got Matt the great
gardener waiting for me at my hotel he's
flown in a special occasion I think he
had a family thing going on but he
happens to be here for the day so pretty
exciting all in all we're gonna head on
out grab my bags hook up with Elliott
have a session head down to the hotel
hook up with Matt have a session and
then I guess we're gonna hang out to
head down to the the karmak up and check
it out so stay tuned happy to have you
guys here with me in Toronto and
remember this is just the first part of
the trip guys tomorrow we go to Jamaica
for a week and then after that we head
down to Amsterdam for the cannabis cup
for 10 days
awesome alright guys I am picked up by
my good buddy Elliot yeah Elliot in the
house Elliot's been a friend of mine for
a good long time I don't even know how
long it's got to be going on well over
10 years now
and we kind of see each other here and
there he was living in LA for a while
doing the doing the hip hop thing huh
yes I yes I so now we're here we're in
Toronto Elliot's actually helping me out
enormous Lee we're trying to take bubble
man's world to the next level I don't
know exactly what we're trying to do
with it but Elliot Elliot works in that
sort of what's that beep ding ding so
we're doing things Elliot's working on
it you'll hear more from us you'll see
more of Elliot he'll probably be at
hashed Church tomorrow morning but not
nevertheless we're gonna head down to
the hotel here set up the D Nell and get
sweets cuncun thanks for the ride Elliot
or is there anything gotcha
what's up everybody Toronto Toronto
bound just bumped into the great
gardener got here a little while ago
with my boy Elliott picking me up at the
airport and now we're at the venue
underground cuts just down the street
here we're gonna head on in and we're
gonna check out Sarah Sunday's yeah and
of course Matt's got some entries in the
thanks red beard we might see him taking
home a cup for a computer we don't did
everyone welcome back to bubble man's
world and we are here at the underground
cafe I'm chilling at the karmic us
familiar faces over at this table
karma cup doing so far nice flavors I
hear there's like many edibles many
sativas indicas solvent list solvent the
whole nine yards excellent I haven't
seen a single entry yet but I'm sure
I'll be puffing on some in the near
future here [ __ ] hey guys good to see
you
what straight left review that Jason got
a few minutes for a few seconds just to
say what's going on at the karmic up
here with Jason Wilcox what's up
everybody is bubble man's world
yeah having a good time here with the
blue [ __ ]
the people here representing menos it's
up on big talk about what he's doing and
yeah hats off ideas thank you damn watch
out oh what's up with that es is he just
collecting trophies tonight or he's
pledging Jovi's you know what he thought
was donating and he's representing the
coalition stuff he's lying up there they
donate tonight but he has nabob yeah
that is a big supporter for sure respect
and for everybody here a round of
applause men love this and we're happy
to be here we came down show and support
I'm a judge it's hard to judge we how do
you judge 18 Mehta bulls in a week yeah
how can you judge oh yeah that's a
separate competition for sure oh yeah we
almost need like a four a four weeks
something like this and thought was the
awesome well I'm gonna let up the email
here soon and I'll call you over when I
do but thanks for taking time out and
chat with me bro thanks Jason
[Music]
this world all the cool guys are hanging
out nice dude you collecting trophies
tonight I just bought one so do with med
man and the great Gardner there's
clearly some people in the house that
know what they're doing I'm pretty
excited to start checking it out I'm
gonna light up the Jean I'll catch up
with you guys soon
[Music]
anyone know who this [ __ ] is [ __ ]
awesome dream candy press the marijuana
new school into our cultivation bike
Jenna okay
this book put your energy into the bag
there's gonna play on number and if
you're not here you don't [ __ ] get it
I'm kidding
- 9 1 0 4 1 so I get spending in zero
for one ends in 0 for 1 the closest guy
to the stage
so organize bubbleman back and as you
can see I am no longer at the party I am
now at my hotel and wow I feel like I
smoked about 800 joints in fact I did
not have one rip the karmic up
it was extremely smoky and both my
friend and I were unfortunately we had
to leave it was it was a little too
smoky for me on the herb side of things
but Matt stayed and Matt is going to
find out you know who won and whatnot
for us so I'm not sure I'll have a
footage of it but I'll definitely give
you a little update almost like a puff
Wednesday glad I got to show you guys a
little bit about a little bit about the
party sorry that I was kind of lame and
wasn't able to stay I am traveling
tomorrow to Jamaica and I didn't want to
get my throat any sort of in any worse
situation that it was now and so I'm
gonna wrap this up here in the hotel in
Toronto and I guess we'll see you guys
tomorrow for hash Church I'm gonna be
doing hashed Church tomorrow out of
vapor central on Yonge Street here in
Toronto so if you are around love to see
you come on down from 11 a.m. till 1:00
p.m. I'll be at vapor central and I'll
be doing hash Church so that'll be the
next part Bass
morning everybody morning morning yeah
holy smokes
I can't believe it bro you stayed the
whole night that was very impressive
yeah you can't tell with my voice or
anything
I mentioned it last night there might
from my little video guys that I had to
leave a little early I was a bit of a
lightweight for all the the cannabis
smoke smoke but oh and all fantastic
event yeah Sarah Simon took pulled off a
great show there's a lot more toast a
lot of familiar faces and good folks
there in our beautiful food ready
walking in the door and food everyone
was really friendly and nice so I really
like that I kind of wish that I could
have stayed I met people I saw people
there that I met at the chance show that
I haven't seen ever before or since it's
always tough food so it's like hey man
come sit down and you sort of sit down
for that moment in your life yesterday
for whatever reason the the three people
that I recognize from champs I
remembered them I didn't remember their
names but I was like did you buy like
dry sense well speaking of dry sift miss
your mat so tell us the story behind
this second place cup well the second
place cup was we called it barb 90 to
sift only because I had run out of barb
99 EFT because those are all gonna be in
a couple contests in a few weeks
yeah the Carmen Cup kind of snuck up on
yeah it snuck up on me I sort of
congrats the red beer for sort of
calling me out and saying don't you wish
you want don't you want one of these
cups that I sort of saw how awesome they
were and I was like wow man I kinda - I
got to do yeah I'm impressed with the
cuffs I'm honest with the painting
so looks good so it was a total
last-minute thing and we didn't have any
firsts left right
so we had we had you just clean that
five-minute run right and the seconds
was there we had the D mail there were
like oh let's test everything and the
seconds of that run was still super
melty while it was still super baldie so
we were like yeah well that's already
here let's enter the seconds let's see
on the second the seconds of the of the
process does and voila we sort of get
second place with that awesome well
second place is no slouch for the second
pass of Dreyse if it wasn't the first
but it was the seconds and go figure
Matt took home the second second-place
couple I'll be looking forward to
hitting that when we get back home I'll
come by and have a have a session with
the end of that pipe one day it was
fantastic and a great event again I
can't say enough about the Carbon Copy
I had a fantastic time and I look
forward to next year karma come to or
yeah I think you know what the only my
only complaint and this this is the same
complaint that you get every where we
have the same problem at our legends of
hash party every year the sheer velocity
and amount of smoke that just fills the
air and moves around and it just becomes
I mean at Legends it's a little
different because there's no paper no
glue and no plant matter in the air but
it doesn't matter once you get a certain
amount of smoke in the air you're no
longer getting oxygen and it just slowly
it the hardest of the hard core is I've
seen walk outside and just be like I'm
just gonna have a little bit
I saw the same thing last night I think
next year good next year at the karma
cup i I definitely will only say that it
same with legends little ventilation fan
go a long way
tiny little ventilate like a hyper fan
sure but I was thinking of how many
growers were in the room with Matt there
and Thaddeus med men and Sarah Sunday
and all these other people that I
recognize I'm thinking man there's like
50 growers in the room right now and we
don't have any ventilation in this room
but other than that killer event
definitely will come back next year
really great I mean Sarah Sunday
collected so many prizes to give away at
that event I honestly believe she had
almost a prize for each person that was
their books and lights and
and bubble mouths I mean literally that
was enough I ended up putting a little
package of papers lighters sticker and
then I put a jar of the barb
seventy-three micron here you go man yes
man what ideas goes out picks it up
we're all just like how ironic is sort
of bad bad winds winds the sample I
throw it I think there's like I don't
know how many people were in there 50
undred oh that's hilarious it was
hilarious good moment I liked it was
great it was Karma
so left over on the day today I'm gonna
try and go do a hash Church over at
vapor central I'm hoping that that's
gonna happen even if it's only for an
hour I really want to make it happen but
I do fly did you make it today yeah and
you know that nervous feeling of
whenever you're flying to another
country I'd like to be organized and
prepared it'll be a weird thing to go do
a hash Church for two hours and then do
a minutes was gonna run into the air go
to Jamaica we're going to make her first
then you'll be seeing you in Amsterdam
when you get back from Chile I gotta go
to Chile next week oh he's off to South
America I'm off to the Caribbean but
we're both gonna meet up in Amsterdam
for the legends of hash dinner and for
the cannabis cup so I guess that's
probably the next time you guys will see
both of us together Matt congratulations
to the seconds win second the firsts
will win stay tuned
[Music]
you