[Music]
Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World.
I have a special guest here today with
us. I have a local Vancouver activist,
lawyer, Kirk Tousaw. Where are you from
originally? Uh I'm from uh just outside
of Detroit, Michigan. Detroit, Michigan.
I remember when you showed up. It has to
be like 10 years now. Yeah. 2002 we came
to to Vancouver. 12 years ago. So Kirk's
been around a long time in the scene. Uh
you worked with uh Mr. Conroy for I did
for a while there. Mr. Conroy QC. Mr.
Conroy QC. There it is. Great mentor,
great lawyer. And today, one of the
reasons uh I invited Kirk over to talk
was um the Owen Smith um extract edibles
case that was recently um I don't know
if you'd call it convened or uh judgment
rendered by the court of appeal.
Judgment rendered by the court of
appeal. So, a lot is people are talking
about what it means and what it is and
how it affects Canadians uh patients,
designated growers, non-patients.
Uh, so I thought I'd invite Kirk over to
go over a little bit of a how the case
started. Um, the first decision in 2012
and then where we're at just recently.
Yeah. And thanks uh very much to you
Bowman for having me here. And um before
I give you that kind of recap, uh your
viewers may be interested to know that
you actually uh were the focal point of
two moments in uh in both the trial and
the court of appeal decision. And I'll
uh I'll tell those stories a little bit
later. Excellent. But I had Yeah. I had
the great privilege and uh really good
fortune uh to be retained by Owen Smith
uh who was at the time of his arrest a a
baker uh of edible products and a maker
of other cannabis based medicines for
the Vancouver Victoria can cannabis
buyers club of Canada. Victoria based
operated by Ted Smith, no relation to
Owen Smith. Uh and Owen was making
cookies in his apartment. Uh the smell
uh leaked into the hallway. Uh police
showed up uh and he was arrested
ultimately and charged with possession
of THC for the purpose of trafficking.
uh and uh we immediately decided that
since he was making these medicines uh
for sick people uh for people who use
them for medicinal purposes uh to better
their quality of life and because the
existing scheme in Canada at that time
did not allow for patients to use
anything other than dried marijuana um
in the MMA. We thought, well, we've got
to challenge the law uh because people
are being helped by this. This is uh
literally saving some people's lives,
improving the quality of life of other
people, and there's no reason that uh
Owen Smith should face 5 10 years in
prison maximum uh for engaging in this
behavior. So, we launched constitutional
challenge. Uh in 2012, uh we went and
did about a 20-day trial. a bunch of
members of the club, very very brave uh
people that I was really honored to
meet, uh came and testified about the
impact that medical cannabis and medical
cannabis derivative products uh either
topical products or edible products or
tinctures or concentrated uh forms of uh
cannabonoids like bubble hash for
example. uh how these products assisted
them in regaining quality of life or
treating their serious symptoms and
conditions. So, they told their stories
to the judge and I I had the privilege
of helping tell those stories. Uh and it
is a privilege. Uh Ted Smith testified
about the club and the history and the
background of the club which has been
serving and helping people in Victoria
and elsewhere for a very very long time.
It's got to be 15 plus years. Yeah. I
mean, right there from the beginning.
Absolutely. uh of really a medical
cannabis now revolution in Canada. Uh
and so we were successful. Uh the judge
uh understood that uh restricting
patients to dried marijuana only
violated their dignity, violated their
autonomy. Uh it infringed on their
section 7 charter rights, the liberty
and to security of the person in a
manner that wasn't consistent with the
principles of fundamental justice
because the rules and restrictions were
arbitrary. It made no sense to him and I
think to any thinking person why you can
grow and possess the dried product or as
a designated producer you could grow uh
the dried product and provide it to your
patient. But then the minute you put it
into a tea or made it into an oil or
turned it into a cookie and and wanted
to administer it in a different form
than either smoking or vaporizing it or
a or a hash or concentrate. Um you
became a criminal. And I think that you
could I arbitrary, isn't it? The analogy
of the tea, you know, like explaining to
the judge that look, you know, she's
using it legally as a dried herb. The
minute she puts it in her hot water,
steeps it and pulls it out. I mean, cuz
that sounds less like you're making an
extract, but the reality is you are
that's what you're doing. You're
extracting the cannabonoids into a a
weak oral solution and then you're
ingesting it orally. Uh, and of course
the medical cannabis forms you filled in
for the government had the option of
checking oral uh, which the judge found
to be puzzling and and their Health
Canada's document information for
healthcare practitioners document is
chalk full of information about how to
ingest it. uh bunch of studies
referenced in the footnotes about
edibles, topicals, all sorts of science
and and and it was sort of like, well,
you're telling doctors about all this
stuff and you can check off oral, but if
the patient actually does that, they're
committing a crime for doing that. And
so, we educated the judge about about
cannabis and cannabonoids. And here's
where Mark actually comes in uh because
he provided me with some very very good
macro photos of tricoms. uh and
close-ups of tricoms living from the
plant and from uh dried cannabis. And it
was instrumental really uh in educating
the judge about what the medicine is uh
and how it's not really in the plant uh
that is contained in these in these
things called tricoms. Uh and I really
when you when you get a visual like
that, right, it sinks it in. It's
educational for certain. That's exactly
it. And and part of what I do in the
courtroom is educate because most people
don't have any idea about this stuff. I
mean, certainly if they're uh if they're
not either consuming medical cannabis or
even if they are, but don't understand
really how it's all working other than
it works, you got to educate them. So,
so we were great. That was great. The uh
the the decision came down. We were very
pleased to win that. The judge struck uh
dried marijuana from the MMA. The judge
modified the definition of marijuana in
the MMA to include all schedule 2
substances. So, uh, that actually
included synthetic THC, for example, but
basically cannabis resin, anything you
can make with cannabis. Did he strike
the word dried and then he struck it up
and then just used the word marijuana?
Just use the word marijuana. That's
right. He also helped define as all of
these as all of these schedule two
substances. All right. Um, and
ultimately that that remedy gets
disagreed with in the court of appeal
when we get to that point. So the the
other side appeals of course uh and we
go and argue the appeal uh
and we we spent about half of the oral
argument time discussing a legal concept
called standing. And this this becomes
relevant because there was a dissenting
opinion in the court of appeal that that
dealt with the standing issue. And
standing is basically your right to make
certain arguments to the court. Um, you
have to have, for instance, in a search
warrant situation, you're supposed, you
have a reasonable expectation of privacy
in your home, for example, but your
buddy sitting on the porch in your home
does not have the same reasonable
expectation of privacy in your home that
you have. And so your your buddy doesn't
have standing to raise, for example, a
challenge that search warrant uh in your
home. So, if they get caught up in a
bust and they happen to have some drugs
on them or something like that and they
were otherwise arrested and validly
searched, if even if the search warrant
that got the cops in the front of your
house was completely invalid, that
person has no standing to raise that
because the charter doesn't confer to
them a right of privacy in your home
because it wasn't their home. So, so the
argument on standing that the court
grappled with was, well, Owen Smith is
not a medical patient. He was not a
participant in the MMA scheme. In other
words, he wasn't a designated producer
producing for a medical patient. He had
no license. So, how is he in a position
to challenge whether or not the MMA are
arbitrary and unconstitutional? And the
answer is given by the Supreme Court of
Canada quite a while ago. The the answer
is he's being charged under a criminal
statute. His liberty is at risk. and the
criminal statute, the control drugs and
substances act under which he will be
con convicted you're arguing is
unconstitutional because the medical
exemption is unconstitutional and I
didn't think and in fact the crown
agreed this is well settled case law but
we spent a bunch of time in the court of
appeal on that issue now ultimately we
won in the court of appeal that's what
happened in 2014 just a couple of weeks
ago right uh incredibly uh pleased to
get a great result we uh two of the
judges of the three agreed that the
charter order is breached, that your
right to life uh liberty and security of
the person is breached by the
restriction uh to dried marijuana only.
And they use some very good language uh
in the decision about what section 7
actually protects, you know, because
it's not just about medical cannabis.
What are these rights that we have under
the charter? And the the right that was
interpreted in the visa court of appeal
was they said look this choice of
medicine the choice of the mode of
ingestion of a physician approved
medicine like this is goes fundamentally
to what it means to have dignity uh and
independence and autonomy in our society
and I thought that was absolutely spoton
and and great language isn't it super
compelling puts a smile on my face
doesn't it and and you read that and
you're like you know what that's right
that's what that is what it means in a
free and democra ocratic society to have
liberty and security of your person. If
you can't make medical choices for
yourself, what do you have? And it's
almost not even a medical choice as much
as it's like, okay, you're legally
allowed to order pizza, but if you take
it out of the box, you have breached a
serious law and could potentially serve
time in prison. That's right. It's like,
no, wait a minute. Why would you even do
that to your people? That's like an
entrapment of sorts. No, it's it's it's
a tragedy and it's an ongoing tragedy
and it obviously should be fixed the
best way to fix it is obviously the
outright legalization of of marijuana
generally. But the second best way to
fix it is to implement a working medical
marijuana system in this country. And I
think we've got a long way to go before
we have that. So, but this is a step
forward. We win. We get a 2 to1 uh
decision. The descent uh wrote about
standing. He felt that Mr. Smith
shouldn't be able to challenge these
laws because he wasn't a participant in
the scheme in any way. didn't try to be.
Um, and you sort of say, well, he
couldn't have like I mean, he could not
have applied under the MMA to bake
cookies for the members of the Cannabis
Fires Club of Canada in Victoria, right?
He couldn't do that. So, what's the
point? What's the point of doing that is
sort of what I said in the court of
appeal, actually. uh and uh luckily two
of the judges agreed with us and also
luckily Supreme Court of Canada the
president was on our side and the crown
quite honorably and correctly uh
conceded that point at the start of the
oral argument. So really I think a great
decision, a great step forward. I'm very
excited to have been a part of it. We we
may be on the way to the Supreme Court
of Canada. Uh there was a disscent uh if
the crown wants to go up um I believe
they have an automatic right of appeal.
They don't even have to ask permission.
That's what that's what a descent is.
That's what that's what that means. And
so I got one in my case years ago. Ah,
for for for my side though, two two
judges were against me, but one thought,
you know what, you should there was a
few reasons why. He's got a point,
right? It's a case I actually used from
time to time in uh in various
proceedings. And I'll tell you, here's
the other way Mark uh uh assisted here
with uh the court of appeal decision is
uh you were in the courtroom for uh oral
argument in the court of appeal and I
actually stole one of your lines. Uh and
and I said I was saying to the judges,
it's explaining what a tricom is. Of
course, because you got to educate them,
too. Uh and and I said, "You got to
think about it this way. Uh the tricoms,
the resin
glands, that's that's the message.
That's the message. The plant, it's just
the messenger." Nice. And anybody that
watches Bubble Man's World Yeah. Yeah.
has heard Bubble Man say those words.
Yeah. Herb is the messenger. That's
right. And bubble is the message. That's
right. So, I can definitely accept that
one. But if it don't bubble, it ain't
worth the trouble. That was the skunk
man. That was the first one I used and
then I then I came up with that one. So,
I come out of a t-shirt or two with that
on there.
Yeah. It was fun to be able to to say
that and it's and it's true, too. So, it
was very very good. Yeah. Well, you
definitely have vast knowledge when it
comes to um you know canabonoids, how
they're produced, where they're
produced, a vast knowledge that a lot of
people don't really have generally even
in our scene in the scene that is the
cannabis community. And uh so it's nice
to see uh someone in your in your
position who can you know stand up and
get these laws not only you know fight
them but potentially change them. Yeah.
uh to have a good solid foundation. I
mean, I'm constantly disappointed when I
see a media story done on cannabis
because they just they don't seem to be
inspired to do great work. They don't
seem to be inspired to be like, don't
you have one guy who will just be really
good and learn about like it's not that
hard. You can learn about it. It it can
be very frustrating to sort of read uh
things that are so uh inaccurate. Yeah,
there's so much of it and that's easy to
do. But I appreciate the compliment.
It's it's nice of you because from
somebody with the knowledge base that
you have, it's it's a great you have the
knowledge. You definitely know what
you're talking about and good I mean God
thank us because uh if someone else was
standing up there trying to defend this
without that knowledge in my opinion
that simple knowledge of explaining
where the canabonoids are manufactured
inside the glandular tricom head and
that it's such a small small percentage
of the actual plant matter. There's a
huge understanding that would literally
change everything that we're even
fighting against right now. No, it's a
that's that's absolutely right. And I
mean, one of the joys of being a
litigator is that uh you get to learn a
lot about interesting subject matter and
I've been privileged to be able to do a
lot of litigation involving medical
marijuana and marijuana generally. And I
I love the plant and have for my entire
life. So, it's been an absolute
privilege to be able to blend those two
disciplines together. Yeah. And and try
and do good work for people. Very cool.
Yeah.
Well, I guess uh my one last question
would be where where do we sit with this
decision? Where what does this mean?
Does this mean that patients that have
MMA at this point with the injunction
going on are able to possess and make
their own extracts?
or is that I mean that's the question of
the day, isn't it? Uh it's a very
interesting scenario because uh when the
trial judge granted us the relief we
were seeking the the crown asked for a
year for the government to fix the
regulatory scheme. They they asked for
his ruling essentially to be suspended
for a year. It's called a suspension of
a declaration of invalidity. Uh and that
gives the government a chance to respond
legislatively. They've done this before.
They did it after Parker. They did it in
a bit after uh one of the heads
decisions. Uh and so they did after
Baron. Uh and so not uncommon. And so
what the judge did is he said, "Well, as
to patients, no, it's going to go into
effect right away. If you are an
authorized person, you can make your
edibles, you can make your topicals, you
can make your uh concentrates and other
derivative products. If if you're not a
patient, if you're designated producer,
then we're going to give the government
a year uh to to legislate." Well, at the
end of that year, government hadn't done
anything. They came back asking for more
time and and the judge, I think, quite
rightly said, "Well, I'm not just going
to give you more time to give you more
time. I gave you a year to do something,
not to do nothing." And he denied that
relief. And so, at that point,
designated producers in BC became able
to produce all schedule 2 substances for
their patient, uh, including, uh, bubble
hash, including dry sift, including
edibles, topicals, you name it,
anything. uh theoretically even pure
synthetic THC could have been produced
uh by designated producers. Now this
this court of appeal modified the remedy
said the judge sort of went a little bit
too far in granting the relief. Yes, it
was unconstitutional to limit patients
that dried marijuana only. Yes, it
violates their section 7 rights. But
when the judge actually rewrote the MMA
to redefine marijuana as all schedule
two substances, rather than just sort of
throwing the ball back into the
government's court and saying, "Here's
the problem. Fix it." Right? He went too
far. So, they modified that remedy. They
said, "To the extent of of changing the
remedy, we're actually going to grant
the crown uh relief on this appeal.
We're going to declare that those
provisions limiting to patients that
drive marijuana only are arbitrary,
violate section seven, and we're going
to suspend that declaration for a year
to give the government a chance to
respond legislatively. And so, what does
that mean for patients? I mean, the
government's really been given a year to
amend a regulatory scheme that no longer
exists in order to allow patients to
have access to these products. But what
happens in the meantime? uh our
designated producers now unable to
produce for their patients when they
were a week and a half ago even though
we won uh the section 7 issue. Are
patients no longer able to make their
own medicines uh in British Columbia or
anywhere in the country? I mean, I think
these are some unanswered questions by
the way uh the remedy section of the
decision was crafted. And I I got to be
honest with you, I got to think about it
myself before I sort of leap to
judgment. And I like to talk to some
smart people about that like Mr. Conroy
uh and and take some guidance on what it
really means. And there's no is there is
it not set up in a way that you can be
like okay we need to understand we have
a few questions in regards to your
ruling. There's no way to get more any
back and forth with them. No, there it's
I'm unaware of any it's a very it's
there's not it's not really a dialogue,
right? It's a presentation followed by a
decision. Are there firms that you can
hire that have brilliant people that
just specialize in looking at cases and
then telling you what they believe that
case? Well, you you could yeah, you
could go to a constitutional lawyer. You
could get a legal opinion uh on what the
impact is and you could have some you
could place some value and some stock in
that and let that guide your actions,
right?
Um and we of course can go to the
Supreme Court of Canada. My client Owen
has not made any decisions about we
whether we want to go uh to the Supreme
Court of Canada because perhaps we don't
agree with that remedy. Um myself as
somebody that's been an observer of how
the government's responded in the past
to declarations of constitutional
invalidity. I I don't have a tremendous
amount of confidence that this time
they're going to do it the right way. Uh
because that's not unfortunately the
track record. And of course, all of
this, you know, there's two other issues
that sort of arise. How how valid is
this decision out of British Columbia
that it's much more impactful than the
trial court decision. Uh whether or not
it's completely persu uh binding across
the country, I think is a legal question
that would have to be settled maybe even
on a province by province basis. Um and
then the other uh the other issue is
does it affect the MMPR? you know, uh,
are producers under the MMPR going to be
allowed to now provide these products to
their patients? So far, the answer is
no, but perhaps that's part of the
government's regulatory response. I
don't know the answer to that. I have a
strong feeling that part of their reason
to allow it is that they'll want to
allow it for LPS.
Could be. I'm not sure why they didn't
do that in the first place then. Yeah.
You know, I mean, that's difficult to
sort of understand the government's
thinking behind a lot of this stuff. I
mean, I just can't I I I don't really
see like small amounts of dried flour as
really as medicine. Well, for some for
some it is. I mean, to be fair, for some
people that is their preferred mode of
ingestion and absolutely their right to
choose it is part of their individual
dignity, autonomy, and independence. For
them, of course you would. And I know
you would. Absolutely. You just happen
to have a different mode of ingestion.
Well, you know what? And not even that,
but lately I get a lot of people since I
started this group on Facebook called
the endockinabonoid system. Um, I've had
almost daily a person who has been
diagnosed with a terminal illness
contact me and ask me how they can get
what they need and what is it that they
need. And I'm, you know, I'm like, well,
you need to saturate your
endockinabonoid system. You need to take
like a gram of like concentrated resin
gland heads. And there's different ways
of like it's even when I pull out my
creams that are, you know, the CBC cream
that's good for uh muscle pain and
stuff. Everyone sees it and they're
like, "Oh, I need to get some of that.
Where can I get some of that?" Yeah.
It's like, "Well, you know, it would be
nice if you could just get it at the
pharmacy or any of these other, you
know, I I at the supermarket. At the
supermarket, at the dispensary, at the,
you know, they're just not available
enough in the model that we're currently
in." Yeah, that's right. And truth be
told, I mean the the medicine is in the
cannonoids in the resin glands and that
is where it is. The rest of the stuff is
extraneous. Yeah, absolutely. Um it may
have other impact, flavor, taste. People
prefer to ingest it in a certain way,
but at the end of the day, we we know
where the medicine resides, right? Even
in one of Owen Smith's uh most recent
blogs there on Cannabis Digest, I
believe. Yes. Uh he wrote quite a bit
about Dave Pate who uh was the uh work
did work for Horafarm and one of our
experts in sport and he is an expert. Oh
yes really. And if you read Dave Pate's
words it's like all the medicinal value
is in the glandular head of the trial.
That's right. And and actually all of
the transcripts from the trial including
uh Dr. P's testimony are available uh
online. I think it's at
cannabisdigest.ca CA or if not you can
certainly find a link to it. Uh it's a
great site orology. Yeah, it's a good
good site. Absolutely. Well, I really
appreciate your time, Kirk. It's been an
absolute pleasure. It's uh been great to
come up here uh to your place and enjoy
your hospitality and have the
opportunity to talk to uh uh the people
that love Bubble Man as well. Excellent.
Great program. Thanks a lot, man. Thank
you. Awesome. We'll talk to you guys
soon.
[Music]