[Music]
hey hey good morning bubbleman here it's
about 5:00 in the morning here in
British Columbia I am just getting ready
to head over to the Vancouver
International Airport where I will be
flying into the Kootenays I'm gonna head
up to Castle gar and then drive from
Castle var to Kaslow maybe check out
when law and definitely check out Nelson
so I've got all my stuff packed up here
I've got my trippy sticks ready to go so
I can puff all the way to the airport
being a federally exempt Canadian I'm
legally allowed to transport medicine I
have a tiny little bit of maybe three of
these little bags supposed to be stink
proof they aren't they're definitely
gonna be smelling it and then I have my
actual airtight watertight Eric
meditator so this is filled with nuggets
as well and then of course I have a nice
amount of full melt bubble I've got
myself about 20 grams stuffed into a
nice little container here and I've got
my big 4x4 screens that we're gonna be
using while we're over there I'm gonna
be making a bunch of different bubble
and dry seft but I just wanted to start
us off we're gonna be heading to the
airport next so stay tuned
[Music]
[Applause]
is in my head is in my head you make the
change you rearrange me
[Music]
all right just parked my car and I am
waiting for the bus which I see is right
over there I got my stuff right here my
4x2 screens
my D mail the mothership all my bubble
and my herb I'm heading to castle oh
it's a cold wintry morning but well here
comes my bus so that's a good thing I
see it turning and I see it coming this
way it's a nice quick flight to Kaslow
only 1 hour in the air so I'll be quick
to clear customs or security and make my
way forward should be good I do have my
trippy stick as well as always it's
never a bad idea to have your trippy
stick with you medication on the go as
john b says here comes the bus
we'll catch up with you soon
[Music]
all right just heading up to the
departure for domestic flights be
getting our bags put in and getting that
over to boarding
[Music]
all right just got my boarding pass and
put my baggages away I'm gonna put this
card away now and we'll make our way to
security
[Music]
all right so
so pretty quick clearing of security I
didn't even really check my bags
I'm heading onto the plane now and
should be in castle in about an hour and
a half
all right so we're here at the airport
Trippi stick it away just waiting for
the bird waiting for the bird there we
go
gotta love BC
[Music]
all right we're just waiting for some of
the icing to occur here comes with the
icer now
[Music]
[Applause]
what's up Frank good to see ya
in my house
[Music]
so driving through the Cooney's my buddy
Frank
we just left we are at six months
oh yes the can filter complexes right up
here
the original can filter no fan too so
you can see what it is
[Music]
that was all
[Applause]
[Music]
got them all the small classroom install
Baxter
[Music]
box that's wrong well marvelous app
smart apps home
[Applause]
that's wrong we love them well we're
just on the cow slow ferry it takes
about five minutes to cross we're almost
there where does it take two minutes to
cross
[Music]
we are now getting very close
yeah buddy
No
[Music]
welcome to prop
[Applause]
[Music]
ah spray
ah spray mm
[Music]
you're really good to be here
sure my groceries down let's see if we
can go find Ron ha ha I see he's got
some bubble bags on the TV here that's
fun to see
putting my Pelican down I'll go see
what's up dude dude good to see you turn
like that's awesome
let's get your lights on yeah let her
wake up first all sleeping
okay well then we're gonna go inside
we're gonna have a session yeah awesome
Oh
right on thank you 50 years I picked
that up at the concert in Toronto for
you Wow yeah dude thank you
Oh got this for you too that's your High
Times Cannabis Cup Pass nice yeah and
then this is just a little silly it's a
ring people that up
it's a grinder Wow for you cannabis this
is a little brain girl you just take
your buds
yeah all right we're back in Ron's
kitchen I didn't even really introduce
wrong this is Ron and Ron was my mentor
and he taught me how to grow in cannabis
and more than that he kind of taught me
how to be like he he groomed me to
become the bubble man his reality
because really he's the most extreme off
the wall over-the-top person you could
ever possibly know there's movies to be
made about all that statement but in the
meantime you kind of inspired me to be
like a crazy wild like you know in the
way that we love the people to help her
place so I guess we're gonna do a dev
you came in blonde just did some
interviews on camera talked a little bit
about how he does is growing talked a
little bit about lights and air and
flushing the plans just a whole bunch of
stuff that will show
I'm gonna hit this because I'm jonesing
Torah alright thanks again Dean L Stevie
cries and ke ke times thanks Caitlin for
the sweet card cap
[Music]
yes yeah all right
let's enjoy cheerily
[Applause]
[Music]
nicely we can kind of do that last night
is very good
anyway we're going to maybe make some
food table pots about cash maybe gets
dry something a little later on but
tough we'll catch up with you guys in a
bit