[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am just uh doing a little session out
here on the hood of my truck beautiful
morning here in British Columbia we're
about to actually head over to the
sunshine coast to visit Cory and
Stratosphere they've got a bunch of
glass blowers over there and they've
been doing some wonderful things for the
last couple of weeks unfortunately they
ran out of oxygen the other day so we
won't be seeing them actually do their
trade but we will be lucky enough to see
the entire group of um pieces that were
made for the show down at Mr EDS in La a
gallery that I guess is organizing them
so I
think I think it's time for a little
blast
all right so we got a little little bit
of concentrated X for the morning
blast M nice nice
nice it's definitely like dry sift
butter not the easiest thing to collect
but
patience is a
virtue all right
so pretty stoked on heading over there
going to see Flav as well today going to
go see Flav and uh check out some of his
collection that we haven't seen in a
long time and just had an overall
wonderful session with him it's been
months since I've seen him he's got a
tarpine delivery coming so he's going to
be quite excited about his flavors that
are coming coming to him today so maybe
we'll do a little tarpine Gauntlet we'll
see what happens happens not exactly
sure how it's going to play out but uh
looking forward to the day nonetheless
it's just beautiful got the Drone so I'm
unfortunately I'm sure I'm not able to
drone uh on the ferry but
guaranteed we will be droning on the
Sunshine Coast today for sure we'll
figure out some nice footage for you
guys to
see all right here we go
took a tiny little bit of water in the
mouth there but um well it's always more
enjoyable when it's the fresh fresh cold
water that hasn't had a single hit
thrown gone through it so uh yeah give
thanks to the Hitman little baby cakes
there little piece I picked up in Spain
a couple years ago and it's really
served me well it's been pretty strong
it's dropped a numerous times it's never
broken and uh it's always gotten the job
done so shout out to them for making a
cool little pipe like that and I guess
really all there's left to do is drive
to the ferry so of course I'm going to
bring you guys along with me show you a
little bit of the road on the way there
and then maybe once we get to the ferry
we can uh chill out and have another
session see you there
[Music]
[Applause]
Che
[Music]
well as always I've gotten here to the
ferry a little bit early which is uh
definitely better than showing up a
little bit late I'm not going to lie
been sitting here for a while now and
figured why not have a little
grasshopper
session sweet little unit easy to use
and uh a lot less overpowering than uh
than the concentrates obviously which is
generally what I appreciate and am
looking for but sometimes it's just nice
to have a little hit of J herbs and of
course there's all of you out there that
have been telling me for years there's
just something different about the herbs
well of course there's something
different about the herbs it's the herbs
not the hash I'm loading up some
beautiful Astro Boy here super beautiful
Yul cured it's it really is a nice
pleasure to and I'm not talking about
like Beyond dried out like that other
herb that I had the Jamaican this Astro
Boy is cured really nice put put in a
nice uh enclosed space and just all
around nice so let's hit that we go from
red in under five seconds we go to Blue
see the little blue guys pretty
sweet thanks George once again from Vape
fiend had my own mother call about this
today and ask about what kind of
vaporizer is that it looks really
cool well looks like we're getting ready
to go on the
fery grasshopper session will have to
wait
[Music]
all right so we just jumped in the
elevator here uh on the ferry and we're
just going to kind of go for a little
loop around find a little spot to hit
this uh grasshopper cuz I didn't get too
earlier so I still got it with me let's
check it
out oh nice right to the Sund deck
beautiful avoided the entire Ferry
completely and we are now just on the
Sund deck so that's pretty
sweet over the front here and see what's
going
on still in the shade here there's the
captain up there
I I
cyan wow we having
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
oh can't see
[Music]
a
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
he
all right well as we're pulling up to
the ferry it looks like we have a little
bit of time to just have one quick
little rip on the Hitman so pull out a
little rosin from the West Coast
concentrate
boys as I'm always happy to be puffing
on there
rosin see we got some pretty nice stuff
here see
that yeah it's pretty
decent it's pretty
decent we'll just make a little dabby
Doodle
there get that away for
now so when it's time to go it's time to
go these fairies don't mess
around got my Hitman stacked up throw a
little water in
there it's always a little bit more
enjoyable with water I would have to
say put a little bit less than last time
in
and
heat the bow or the nail I guess you
could call it don't hit much titanium
but this one little I guess it's an 8
mil maybe a
10 um it's the one travel nail that I've
just never had a problem with I've never
lost
it never broke it obviously not sure if
you know if you can even break these
titanium Nails I've never done it myself
but who's to say someone out there
hasn't done
it
themselves all right so we'll put that
away nice if I could find my carb cap I
don't think I'm going
to well it happens like that sometimes
it is what it is no carb cap for this
rib
[Music]
[Applause]
well that was just about perfect aside
from the fact that I dropped my Dabber
got a few
carpet skirs on the Dabber
but that can always be cleaned off and
in the
meantime I'm going to wait until the
ferry gets to the end and uh we'll
continue our journey towards
Stratosphere and Cory glass to see what
those guys are up to
today all right guys so I made it here
I'm over at Corey's spot and flab 421
joined us as well so thanks for having
me dude yeah no worries it's time it's
been such a beautiful day we've just
kind of been chilling and puffing a few
bowls and relaxing in the beautiful uh
in the sunshine here watching the dogs
have fun but we figured we'd film a
little intro seeing as though I filmed
so much just to get here I thought I
should probably film a little bit while
I was here so uh what are we going to
take a look at today Cory uh today we're
going to have a look at some of the
glass that uh myself Nish Stratus John K
uh JT glass I've been making for show
coming up at Captain EDS it's uh Strange
Brew on April
15th uh they should be here shortly so
yeah we'll give you a tour of uh
upstairs and everything we've made
awesome yeah that sounds good what do
you say going to hump your buddy there
just a little dog humping going on in
the background don't worry about that
well no I'm super excited you showed me
a few of those uh
pieces earlier and I would do a really
uh I like the I like the style like the
the square s it reminded Meers yeah yeah
totally these
guys here they're like this is bubble
man's world I'm going to be what I'm
going to do what I want to do buy it the
whole time and then get that was awesome
anyway I guess the dogs are getting
kicked out now they got to go they got
to go they got to go we were puffing on
some congales uh was it rosin or bubble
some Cong bubble has pressed out to look
rosin es and very bubbly and gooey very
bubbly and gooey thaning treat we're
going to smoke out of Pam Mama the
recycler piece that Cory and uh Pat did
I think we looked at it last time I was
here it was completely ridiculous does
it have like a spinning herb Leaf yes it
does yeah yeah that's the one that one's
uh another rainbow spinner serious take
care of that one for sure yeah we let
kids don't have to clean it long pendant
big hanging like down
p p pendants away everything away
although you do still need what about my
keys around my neck is this safe that's
easy I'm driving no no no although if
you had it in your hand and you were
swinging it around like this as you were
dabbing that might be a little sick you
know you know what that's still too
nerve-wracking for me one of these just
catching it totally it's like well how
about it just be like the most
respectfully you can when you hit a
piece like that and there's a lot of
little hooks that you can grab on to and
send that thing for sure owe it to
yourself to be wary and take care and if
you're not comfortable don't don't it's
it's I would actually say it's the
probably the most the the most breakable
piece that I own the one that has the
most amount of fine detail fragility
when it comes to like the butterflies
and the flowers and this is even
compared to hands and the legs and the
fingers every single aspect of the whole
piece and the leaf that's thin scre it
deserves the most um care and respect in
that sense when handling it it's in good
hands yeah it is in good hands at least
absolutely well I'm looking forward to
checking out some glass I guess these
guys will be here in the near future and
we'll probably just have a little
session and hit some turps and some uh
some bong rips in the
meantime I think we should sounds like a
plan like Mass beautiful Sunshine Coast
multi-acre property hey that's where
we're all you cool people should [ __ ]
come up you know it's a great place to
live up here Jo us
actually don't it'll spoil how beautiful
it is stay away just 2% of you can come
yeah only the ones with the full melt
ooh full melt snobbery in full effect
here on the Sunshine Coast or Mothership
glass let's just take it to the next
level of snobbery Mothership glass
too hey there's the
ocean I could see the ocean through the
trees man we'll have to get some Drone
footage yeah
yeah oh yeah we can fly around your yard
here real
nice all right well this is Mossy and
beautiful if this was out east we'd
already be getting picked up by
mosquitoes oh yes but it's
not well when I was over e just last
week it was like 0
to4 and [ __ ] c as yeah yeah really no
this all summer long like you get the
odd mosquito but it's not yeah that's a
nice
shot still down from it's crazy and it's
just
like it hasn't been that long since it
really stopped raining no maybe like two
weeks ago this thing was like pretty
much full I know Butz that's how much
how much is so and in the summer it's
going to there's like hardly even a pond
here in the summer hold that what you
got there the red Congo the Congo
red I brought some treats as well I just
have to turn our backs to not be in with
the camera and then we're good and then
we are
good what that bring
here some concentrated X
this stuff's
nice stuff there's one of them down
there look it floats I even know what's
in there but it's
floating treat op we'll get it get a
stick
op Go Get It Go Get It come on op
go go get it come on op go get it oh Go
Get It Go Get It oh there we go that's
go get it come on go first one go get it
come on Go Get It Go Get It not the STI
go get that come on op I will get
everything opal go get
[Applause]
this Flav doesn't mess around when it
comes to Dro
hash he's going to bring it all the way
back
nice and slow nice and
slow unicorn tiar need to be saved here
folks unicorn tear indeed watch it'll be
one of the empty vials it still be worth
the effort even if it is
oh
yeah well I know who gets the first
dab don't open it yet I'm want to dry
that
off there we go now we'll open it in the
sun and we'll see how she
looks dry as dry can be and I guess it's
a dab for you want to smell
it very nice yeah
dude that is definitely a dab for Dave
mission accomplished already save the
hash now smoke the hash now we smoke the
[Applause]
hash what a perfect day
dabing in the beautiful
sunshine it's definitely
beautiful I
[Music]
agree
just just checking the
Temps for
turb
tasty who's
next you up that the Sun for a
second real nice rip of the concentrated
X
dryft yeah that's going to go down nice
here about eight 10 seconds
[Applause]
pretty good puffing spot you got here
Cory mhm I like the sound of the water
hitting the
water what a many
spot Once Upon a Time the property next
to this property was for sale
and uh yeah would have been Lord have
mercy now Mark's
turn I'm going to have a derb a derb at
the lake on the bridge in the sun in the
sun off the quartz off the quartz and
the mother
ship and the drop down and the drop down
so looks like nice in the
sun it's still pretty
hot it's
amazing I never even thought about we
could just time it off the camera
seconds could
some of that concentrated X bubble hash
come check it out up close you can get
real close to
it real nice quality on
that and then I've got a couple from
West Coast
concentrate in here as well and these
are just
Stellar check this
out this one with the purple kush or
sorry purple candy rosin and that one
which is a a 25
micron
is almost can't remember the actual name
I just remember it was from 25 micron
bubble hash that they
look
sh yeah
D pretty sweet I'll have to be puffing
some bowls of that too I
think let's see you
gentlemen sounds good to me all
right let's do
it I'm want to torch the bowl and I'll
gear up the D
ready for a dab of this too there CL
always God this is so
nice good thanks to the West Coast
concentrate crew
hitting dabs in the sun let's try to get
that down in the Sun and get a nice
camera shot of that sun
dabbing milk in long time
delicious that's the stuff all right
Flav we need to get you one of
those yeah that's pretty damn amazing
bubble it's bubble hash
rosin bubble that he squeez 25 micron
bubble which is
different just
shatter there you
Goa thank
you you are almost
welcome we're hitting
ring under the peruga
bridge on the
creek because that's just how beautiful
life is on the Sunshine Coast we haven't
even looked at much glass yet and it's
still been a pretty awesome trip so far
always happy to come out to the Sunshine
Coast see familiars
friends puff nice bowls enjoy fat
glass and enjoy the outdoors that's
really where I'm
at I really love the
outdoors it's always hard to work on
days like this yeah the minute you step
outside it's
It's Quickly
over that
[Applause]
yeah yeah I think next up is uh pull
that drone out of the box and let's uh
let's see what we're dealing with here
yeah I'm excited to see that thing in in
action Zoom
around good even nail coverage there
Flav oh yeah no [ __ ] definitely know
what you're doing definitely know what
you're
doing yes thank
you w it might be ready did you not heat
it up that much no I heat it up a
lot just even dispersement fly yeah it
just doesn't feel hot at
all perfect dab
damn
finish and then we ran out
so B
time so JT hippo and
yourself yeah collab and K and joh K
collab with
Niche beautiful little bottles the hippo
that one's hippo myself and Nish the
other two are uh Jared and Nish next one
is hippo and Nish and then the next one
is John K
and
N
did yes you
are is he even awake awake yeah Jared
maybe I don't know heal to that's who
you're talking about right he's going to
do the dance steps yeah yeah yeah yeah
look go
yeah for
sure he got backed into the corner on
that one you guys got more fuel again
more
I got a little like it's funny even when
he was at my shop so we just like
yelling back and forth no you're going
to do it no I'm not doing
here spent more SP
[Music]
what I can I can pretend to be this tall
too I'm tall he's
short how's it going everybody if I just
stand back here we're the same height I
just Jing all right so we are here with
Niche glass in the house and uh I guess
we're going to ask you a little bit
about kind of your style here these are
obviously collaborations that you've
done with other artists yes they are Y
and this is uh for the captain Ed
Captain Ed's uh gallery show in R
California R California all right that
sounds cool and that's happening this no
next month literally in a couple weeks
April April 15 actually April 15 so mark
that down in your calendar if you're
over in that area and yeah just kind of
wanted to talk about your style here
it's definitely a pretty cool little
vasik style of bubbler they chug real
nice and I can see that you guys have
done a variety of different uh uh
collaborations so maybe you want to
start down at the end with the purple
one uh yeah this purple one was made
with uh John K Glass and uh you know
where can they find them on Instagram uh
they can find John John K at junk j n k
glass um on Instagram and um yeah these
are really cool this uh uh is a purple
lollipop one with uh um a Wisteria
backed uh uh crop circle section which
is John's Forte which is also cool that
it's uh the matching marble yeah it's
also in the Millie as well and uh yeah
the style is kind of uh I guess based
off classical you know shapes uh that
are out there and I you know for me uh
the bottle is just seems correct for for
for smoking out of
it's yeah it's a meant to fit in your
hand meant to pick up the smoke so um
yeah the style is something that I'm
kind of stoked on and it's yeah simple
and I see these two here you've got
actual down stems fitted in yeah these
have removable diffys um that uh yeah uh
are 14 to 10 mm Transitions and uh you
know done with beautiful Line work from
uh Jared um and uh mashed into a bottle
with uh really nice uh 8 mm opal coins
uh that really pop and um yeah yeah
they're really nice line and JT's is uh
JT glass uh on Instagram and so you can
check out all of his Fun Line work
excellent uh this particular one was
made with uh Corey glass at Cory glass
on Instagram and with hippo glass uh
also on Instagram and uh kind of a
fusion of uh uh hippo's awesome fume
work and then Cory wrapped a really
beautiful Radell over top of it for the
midsection um and uh yeah just like like
use other fume uh sections as the
accents within it and again it's uh you
know has a nice uh 8 mm opal coin on
there and uh yeah to it for sure yeah
and this one here is a uh so uh is uh
done with uh hippos Fume Tech again um
uh just uh yeah a really cool little uh
chugger yep comfortable the hand for
sure could definitely uh y little cutesy
bottles very cool so these are all going
down to the show these will all be
available at the captain Ed Show and uh
there actually will be some others as
well that uh will make their way there
too so there should be a uh nice
collection of uh collaborative bottles
and so for people that won't be able to
make it down the show and and grab a
piece uh via you or via one of the shops
you sell at where do you direct those
people
uh I generally uh I mean I will take uh
personal orders but really in ideally
it's uh I I send people to the shops
that buy the pieces so what you name a
few uh some of the shops would be like
THC in Toronto um uh gez uh where else
am I um there's uh crazy bills Hamilton
there's uh Culture Rising in London
Ontario um so there's three options
right there yeah there's three solid
options there we I just did a show with
uh Jared in uh JT glass in um Calgary so
we at the next level so uh there uh they
may still have some of the pieces there
um and uh yeah so it's kind of spreading
out um hopefully soon to be a little
more available in the US yeah well it's
definitely a unique style you don't see
a ton of blowers doing this this
particular style so it's very cool thank
you thanks for joining me yeah thank you
very much Mark I know
PE all right so we are back with Corey
cotum Cory glass on Instagram as you
guys have known before we've been over
here before and walked through his shop
with Stratosphere and they showed us a
bunch of beautiful glass and I guess now
we're going to do it all over again yeah
dude you got some beautiful pieces here
these are also for the captain Ed's show
yeah c yeah we've been uh busy getting
busy so there's a bunch of collabs here
I've got some stuff from hippo John K uh
Nish is nishes in here no nishes was in
the other one right uh JT I still don't
have anything with uh Stratus here but
we've got a couple of the bigger pieces
that we've made that we're bringing
beautiful uh yeah oh you want to go
through them one by one yeah so this
first one here this is a collab with uh
Jared toner uh Nish I already gave the
IGS but JT glass you can find them it's
got the new uh Lucy color from Northstar
layered over top of uh what is that one
wisteria and jet black nice color it's
got some of uh JT's pin wheel uh Line
work re re uh reag rello one yeah one of
JT's rellos and then I took it to the
fasting machine and did some fasting on
it that's really I'll have to take a
picture of this and make sure you guys
see the fastening work and stuff cuz we
are a little bit away from the camera so
that's beautiful man thank you really
nice piece mhm and then next up here
we've got a piece with John K so we've
got his crop circles with some of my
readi lay it over
top very cool Illuminati always a winner
and then it's got the same thing with a
lot of uh nish's pieces had the opal
coin so it's got the opal coin in the
back same sort of thing nice the way is
open the down stem at the bottom it's
got another one of Imes down in the
bottom oh beautiful so the crazy rello
over mhm beautiful love the black light
work as well yeah me too I've been
loving working with these colors uh next
up we have another one with John K that
nice in the hand right yeah and same
with this one it's got a lot of uh you
of the Lucy over top of jet black uh
straight Lucy and then it's got It's
kind of hard to tell with the lights on
but it's got Lucy as the crop circles so
actually light up oh man beautiful yeah
try to get some photos of that yeah even
with the get some photos with the lights
turned around and you can get some
really good shots with the UV popping
beautiful and we got some uh timers sand
timers can't remember this one's either
30 seconds or 40 45 somewhere in between
easy enough to find out easy enough to
find out yeah and they're they're set so
yeah those look great yeah a couple
faceted ones over here also so this next
one here is a cubic cycler that I made
with uh hippo glass so all hippo glasses
fume sections with uh a bunch of hippos
marbles really stoked on this piece I
love like this one out in the sunlight
is so nice come on yeah that is a nice
piece it looks straight up
like like Plumbing yeah yeah it is you
know it's really
cool she pulls back that one nice pull
on it thank you and then uh the next one
we have is similar design so this one's
with uh John costic and this one's got
the Lucy over
uh lemon drop yeah you can't even notice
the Lucy it looks like straight lemon
drop and with the UV it just pops right
out same thing yeah same thing it's got
it as the crop circles so under when
it's a little darker it really pops out
it's harder to see with the bright
lights man that's nice though yeah we'll
definitely make sure we get some some
photos on all of these and then uh the
next one's uh just myself so slightly
different uh take on that design I
switched around a triangle and uh piping
goes a little different few more horns
on this one yeah beautiful I really like
this one thanks it's definitely got that
Personal Touch to it mhm the the ones
that I've made in the past are a lot
bigger than these ones they're they were
uh 3 and 1/2 in squares I knock these
ones down to uh 2 in squares so they're
compact a little more comfy in the hand
you got to make your own bangers for
this that they're also Square yeah those
will be coming you know not just like
the trough but something
square and it really go so nice with
this whole concept to have when you're
sitting there's something comforting
about just seeing glass in shapes that
aren't the standard vessels you know I
love standard vessels I love all the
different jars and all the different
sort of vase type things that you can do
but this is just kind of really a cool
concept where you've got like a little
cube of glass in your hand thanks I've
been trying to step out of doing the
norm and uh doing what everybody else is
doing it's nice to step out and do
something a little different nice marble
placement on those yeah thanks so this
this one here is another one with uh
hippo glass all this fume sections and
marbles this one has Illuminati with the
Lucy so the black is Lucy coated so it
uh glows purple Illuminati that bright
green with uh my ready sections over his
fumed
work really really nice really nice
thank you and then uh this last guy here
is uh just myself so it has some ready
sections over straight lines and uh
capped in between with uh just straight
white readies and then uh there's a
bunch of faceted uh Opals just rough
Opals on their tumbled Opals on the
back yeah six little circular ones and
yeah some little circular ones and uh
the base on that one also has a pretty
nice image with the uh
off access ready with the Lions
beautiful real nice uh mouthpiece on it
too actually open yeah and it's uh hand
ground so it's been laed so it's got
that nice
like too machine to be that's kind of
nice yeah like the flare opening that up
I just love pipes in general feel always
so blessed to be able to hang out with
these guys who do this amazing artwork
and of course focus on the plant that we
love by creating pipes to you know use
for cannabis and cannabis concentrates
it's just a wonderful thing that we've
come such a long way that it's not so
much fighting the law anymore and the
worry of having your pipe shop busted
and having your pipes taken away it's uh
it's definitely a shrinking word yeah
times are changing times are changing
for sure well thanks for having me man
thanks a lot Marie as always
Sage Johnny K get some glasses on this
it's bright as [ __ ]
hey so what's up guys I'm back with John
K you heard that name a few times and uh
most of his glass actually got packed up
but he's got a couple of nice pieces out
here that he's going to tell us about uh
so pick one and start telling us all
right well this is uh what they call it
drop drain recycler so it's uh it's got
the perk with the drain built inside of
it which is a little different than most
recyclers you see yeah I noticed that
right away I thought at first I thought
oh it's it's short I it didn't quite go
about halfway down but then I realized
you were filling the entire chamber with
water and it really chugs definitely for
sure so this is a collaboration with JT
glass or Jared
toner and uh
yeah yeah it's spin real nice it's
pretty beef Cakey too A lot of times
these recyclers feel really dainty to me
they feel almost like they're just going
to break and this thing feels like it's
like been super sized or something yeah
these are designed essentially for e-
nails or you know more heavy setup not
it's not a travel piece that's for sure
I travel in it oh there you
go yeah it's a beautiful piece so this
is going to be down at uh Captain Ed's
gallery show yep on the 15th of April
very cool oh yeah you got these lines up
here again too so yeah it has my
signature crop circle sections in it and
then Jared's uh tight line work here all
right nice yeah on the inside of the
perk there too really cool I didn't
notice that the first time very very
nice piece dude sure that one's going to
be getting snapped up in a hurry what
kind of marble you got there that's a
double pacello that Jared made beautiful
good job Jared all right you guys did
killer on that this is a pretty cool
little sweet kind of beef cakey little
little mini Jammer with the hippo glass
yeah you and hippo did that yeah for
sure so hippo did all the fume sections
and the fume marble and then it's got my
crop circle sections in it as well as
well as some UV reactive glass have the
flashlight right now very cool dude I'll
take some pictures of those for sure
well awesome I look forward to seeing uh
the rest of the work there I'm sure I'll
see photos of it hit up on Instagram we
gave your Instagram a bunch of times but
if you want to give it one more time
it's a John K Glass John K Glass so
check them out guys and uh thanks for
watching Bubble man's world cheers
thanks dude [ __ ] up going to be here in
a couple days actually around the eight
Cameron's coming to grab
that [ __ ] a bit of water up
that's
sweet damn
straight beautiful good score
Cameron I
approve I will definitely be having a
session in that pipe well he's giving me
the okay to have a session if you want
to try it yeah let's do it see I told
you I was having a session with that
pipe let's do
it it's [ __ ] sweet bro I really like
it that's
crazy it's hot it's summer weather
breaking it in what is it Dad Mark's got
a drone he's going to fly in a second
and we can check it
out
spinning got some tasty
bubble it's tasty treats it is
are
you is so nice got to do you Dad before
the spinner stops all right so we get in
there too of
course all right Stratus made it just at
the end here pulled out this beautiful
piece that my buddy Cameron is
apparently grabbing and said that we
have the right to have a little dab set
out of it so thank youer thanon
Stratus pretty cool little [ __ ]
piece my
goodness I like that
oh
yeah that just feels so nice when it
gets spinning perfect holding it in your
hand just like
yeah I don't mind saying the drop down
you made me Cory looks quite good with
it yeah yeah bright colors match
absolutely doesn't even look rosta s
with all that
[Music]
rainbow and so you're in the show as
well Stratus y all your pieces were put
away though I've got a couple upstairs
but think we saw a few just uh most of
their other pieces were they said were
put away as well but um I'm sure we'll
get some good photos through Instagram
through the you guys are all actually
going down for it right yeah that's the
way to do it represent meet all the
buyers there go good people oh yeah
always good to make a trip for your art
it's wonderful anyway I'm kind of
running out of time I got to still pick
up uh John and Niche is it John John and
Nish yeah John and nich yeah so I got to
go get on that so I don't miss the ferry
cuz I want to get on the 430 but uh
thanks for having me out guys thanks
foring peace with me and always uh nice
ride home yeah I think so as well I'm
really stoked on it looksy thanks for
watching Bubble man's
world hey yo baby
why the timber Ro feel good give me
[Music]
a one man home man
real keeps me
going the purpose after the we that to
the
m purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we time you
the
time it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I've been traveling to
Kingston about 20 miles hours spping on
J like the clock fresh vegetation with
trees and with flowers off stop
me give me a big Z don't give me give me
time no give me oneg and if
bigger pass pass
[Music]
pass I make pass
pass and
[Music]
that PA that
now purpose after the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed to the
mind
of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine on the road there
be some
setting
UPS man man we
me upon your scene inter in my bra St
that and behind your scene me and my
team another
25 smoke it up
[Music]
clean
now pass pass
[Music]
pause that pause that
now up the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
dying well I imagine on the road be some
cops
UPS we
me upon your scene inter in my bra that
and behind your scene me and my team
have another
25 smoke it clean
my now
[Music]