[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
it is nice and early on a Wednesday
afternoon and I'm actually heading over
to Sunshine Coast today can't really see
it over there but I assure you it is
over there just got to take a ferry to
get over there gonna jump on that ferry
in about about 45 minutes I'm only a few
minutes from the ferry terminal from my
house so nice and quick and today we're
gonna be going and seeing stratosphere
and Cory Cottenham glass so these two
guys have been absolutely killing it up
on the Sunshine Coast I only see them
every once in a while but every time I
do they have absolutely impeccable glass
that is you know beyond inspirational
one of the things I've heard that
they've been doing lately is they're
producing moving pieces of glass
spinners and whatnot built into the
pieces so hopefully we'll get to see
some of that today we're gonna spend a
little bit of time with them have some
breakfast have a session find out what
they're up to in the next couple of
months here and hopefully get this see
them on the torch a little bit for a
little bit of glassblowing so hopefully
that all works out and I'm gonna bring
you guys with me the whole time so we're
gonna jump in this truck right here and
head over to the ferry now so why don't
you guys join me
all right so we're heading down here
towards Horseshoe Bay which is called
the Horseshoe Bay ferry terminal from
Horseshoe Bay we're gonna head over to
the Sunshine Coast to the terminal
called Langdale I'm sure the trucks
beeping out there
Tasha credit
all right so we're heading down here to
the ferry so we can jump on that boat
and head over to see stratosphere and
Cory should be a good little day over on
the Sunshine Coast been a while since
I've been over on the Sunshine Coast
looks pretty dead I better stay in lane
eleventh one she told me to stay in
what I'm doing
right behind the old Impala all right
guys that much closer
all right guys so I'm here at the line
up to the ferry which isn't much of a
lineup at all we have about maybe thirty
five minutes to wait for it to come in
there's maybe 25 cars here I have once
again I have this bane of my existence I
have to share with you guys I have have
one of these converters a terminator
mobile power inverter and I try I got
this from my Dean ale and I bought this
and of course the Dean ale has too much
power it doesn't heat up using this so
that's okay because I talked to the guys
at Dean ale and they they were like
we're gonna send you a battery we're
gonna figure out what battery works best
and we're gonna send you a battery so
they sent me this battery they actually
sent this battery locked into a table
that my friend has so my friend who
bought the table food email who didn't
want to open the table he got me this
battery the same battery and I'll tell
ya it doesn't work with the D mail which
you guys have seen in my videos before
and I keep forgetting the unit that does
work which is the dab inator
the dab inator is a European model it's
220 volt it works on 110 it basically
works everywhere and it on everything
but I forgot it it's a little bit bigger
my D nails the smaller unit and it's
more travel friendly so I really got to
start figuring this out because I was
gonna have a nice D mail session with
you guys I got not a bad back up here I
got the sarin pen which is my little pen
that's got the ceramic internal pieces
here I got it let's see there we got
that on there we're gonna heat up we are
gonna heat up we've got heated up edge
nice sizzle on that pen and I got all
sorts of nice rosin that I'm bringing
over for to share with the boys we've
got some some darker stuff here that I
made from some sweet sweet pink cush the
sweet pink that's some other much
lighter stuff that I made from the
Lindsay og this is also Lindsay og
really nice color on this lane
it's got beautiful color and really nice
stability too you can totally pick it up
and play around with it a little bit so
why don't we put a tiny little bit of
this lindzei into oh my god it's so nice
yeah I usually just turn the little
heater on a tiny little bit when I'm
putting rosin in and it just it just
drops it off beautifully so we'll have a
couple of little rips here pretty
excited to go see these guys I haven't
spent a ton of time with either of them
but I have known them for some time now
between the two of them and they're just
extremely talented glass blowers it's
nice that we have some glass blowers of
this sort of caliber that lived right
here in British Columbia literally right
across the water from me so I have to
admit I am feeling pretty spoiled today
that I just get to wake up drive the
truck over to the Sunshine Coast over
the ferries maybe catch some dolphins
and whales you never know off the ferry
and you know go see a couple of great
guys see what they're up to and share it
all with you guys so I hope you guys are
excited for this saerom pen Gibbs I got
to admit it's got two heaters on the
inside if you want to know how to spell
it at CER AM PE n the Cera FN and it's
got two ceramic heater coils on the
inside two little loops so most of them
come with one this one comes with two
and I have to say it really makes a a
notable difference on how it how it
vapes
well I guess I'm gonna sit here and puff
more of this rosin and yeah once we get
onto the ferry I'll give you guys a
little bit of ferry view get out onto
the top upper deck and maybe check out
the water I think it's a pretty nice day
out I'm not sure exactly the temperature
18 degrees or something a little bit
overcast but you know what
this is the kind of weather that you see
the wildlife in the ocean so I'm not
bummed out about it at all
we'll see you on that ferry real soon
guys
all right so I'm back at the back of the
ferry the classic place that you had to
if you want to enjoy cannabis
be a pretty chill but
having a few rosin drips out of the
ceramic pan at the back of the ferry I
look forward to landing though and
having a serious d-mail session
[Music]
alright guys so the ferry is almost
ready here just about to head out pull
up to the Sunshine Coast which is right
there
and I just got a little bit of a drive
today I'm going to be driving up to a
place called Roberts Creek which is
about maybe 20 25 minutes up into the
Sunshine Coast
I can't even remember all the different
names these places but
this is where we're heading
make it on me there now so won't you
join me
all right Sunshine Coast bound here we
are alright so now we just head down the
one Main Street here that is the street
to be on Gibson's way is the one we're
looking for we're going to be turning
onto Gibson's way and this Street takes
you all the way through you know right
to the end to the ferry that will take
you to the powell river and lund and
that sort of stuff this is the Sunshine
Coast and you can drive down this road
for God it's got to be over an hour
before you get to Earl's Cove which is
the ferry at the end of this road and
you go through Gibson's you go through
Robert's Creek and you go through sea
Scheldt so we're gonna be taking
Gibson's way here just in a little bit
less than half a mile beautiful up here
on the Sunshine Coast though real
different vibe right away you land and
you just feel more of this sort of
Island vibe even though we're not on the
island we're on the mainland it's still
a ferry away they're not able to drive
their cars so it makes for a pretty cool
cool vibe on the coast no doubt about it
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
I'm here on the Sunshine Coast I finally
made it here and I'm here with
stratosphere glass and Cory Cory caught
him in the house thanks for having me up
guys
this is I got up and it was rainy and
gray kind of like drove to the Horseshoe
Bay ferry it's all just this real sort
of somber it happened halfway here
literally halfway here it was like oh
the clouds will help this morning it was
shining here already it was beautiful
day yeah that's nice for sure yeah yeah
we went to what was that the angry chef
yeah that is a pretty good spot if you
guys are ever in Gibson go check it out
they definitely had been hammered out
some really nice breakfasts for a pretty
darn good price for four people and yeah
we filled up we came up here we've
already hung out a little bit and puffed
some bowls and they showed me a little
bit of glass but I thought you know what
why don't we sit down have a little
discussion I don't really get to talk
about the glass scene that much on my
channel so it's nice to be able to
veteran dude I can only imagine because
to me it was just happening all around
me and I guess we don't realize when we
look back at things like that at how you
know these communities are so small that
eventually when that small community you
travel 25 years into the future and
they're you know these are well-known
artists now who
in museums and capturing prices for
their glass that you just kind of can't
even fathom from a from a layman's
standpoint but it's it's quite something
when you're in it you don't realize that
it's like these all these amazing
artists were involved in that project oh
my god some pretty inspirational pieces
in there for sure I got to give it up to
slinger cuz he was really you know I say
that we both curated that show but in a
sense when it comes to the art really
slinger curated that show in the sense
that he knew every one of those blowers
there used to drool over that East peace
doughnut penetrated yeah I do what it
looks like the bowl at the top but it's
not the bowl actually comes through the
penetration yeah because it's almost got
this weird like not a pendant it's a
part of the piece but it's like pushed
there soon yeah I loved it because I
used to put hash on my pipes that was
one of the pieces that I have to admit
that I was a little bit bummed that I
didn't get you know because that the
color on that thing as well was just
absolutely spectacular
I remember slinger being like hey you
know Jason wants to do a piece with this
guy Steve hops he's not not not many
people know who he is
can can he be in the glass show or oh
I've got this friend bearclaw he's never
been in a show before but he's really
he's he's on point and you know can we
bring him in it was just like to be the
responsible to be one of the people who
are like yeah let's bring this guy in
and then you know once again look back
10 to 15 years later and see you know
where some of these guys are it's it's
been pretty great I have to admit you
know as a hash guy I really have to give
it up to the oil in how it seemed to
induce this frenzy of collecting would
you guys not agree that somewhere along
the line when it
[Music]
it's like a futuristic thing it is
you're just going to have a rip it's not
it's not your standard thing anymore now
there's cables and plugs and wires and
carbs and you know all the different
things and then you guys take it a step
further with your with moving blacks so
I like that you guys have sort of you
know what what kind of brought you to
the fact that you wanted to see glass
moving on your pieces because I mean to
me as a blast user there's been lots of
other people have made some cool pieces
I mean that back-in-the-day pieces I've
seen it here and there being able to
play with your glass too you know that
extra little bit of function it's got
that more purpose to it I think it's
pretty cool I like to that things have
gotten so much more accurate if you will
you can get so much you know that
perfect detail in where you can have
that glass spinner spin so perfectly
it's on a boat they call a cavitation I
don't know what they would call it in
the spin when when the spin is not
proper when it's just there's some
little bit off a little bit of problem
in water through cavitation it's
unbelievable but it'll make a boat feel
yeah it's just taking the extra time the
tediousness to make sure everything is
lined up and straight the lathe really
helps out a lot with it too oh I can
imagine very cool I'm definitely loving
the spinners we're gonna show you some
of those guys as some of those pieces
here in a little bit but I'm just
feeling so good just sitting here right
now in the Sun after a few nice balling
reps Sunshine Coast is the place to be
it's just absolutely beautiful a
different pace yet there's a really
wonderful sort of community that still
exists within I mean I've always for 20
plus years I've come to the Sunshine
Coast see Shelton Roberts Creek and
Gibson and there's always been a really
solid group of people
a lot of artists and musicians and
pretty interesting people for sure yeah
absolutely it's definitely have a few
really good studios Terence Mckenna said
it's all about cognitive activity if you
can focus your brain on cognitive
activity and he of course put the arts
highly up in the cognitive activity
place place so uh yeah I guess we're
gonna sit here for a little bit longer
off-camera and enjoy some conversation
but we'll take you guys on a little tour
of the shop here in a in a few minutes
all right excellent
excellent so here we are in the shop
looking good boys got a couple of kilns
got some pieces on display here yeah
this first piece here is a collab with
glass monkey and myself damn looks so
beautiful in the Sun the I see the
shining yeah that looks so sick
beautiful this last monkey made the
dragon I made the female goddess oh yeah
all with tubes that we pulled out of the
crucible nice just rockin that Nicki
Minaj yes I like the little bit of chain
in there it's kind of a cool addition
blocking it out with my own yeah that's
proper it's
very nice move our way onto this
ridiculousness I saw this in Spain in in
Barcelona correct yeah this is on
display and spam over there for a visit
[Music]
spinning this one's all little faceted
cups oh yeah God that color just is
explosive in the Sun oh I can only
imagine
nice work indeed so when did you guys
finish this piece here that's classic
yeah just two days before we left
sometimes yeah that's real real real
nice now this piece I saw a photo of it
I don't even think it was finished yet
but at what tell it tell me about this
piece this is just pretty nuts on this
one seriously delicate glass spinners
yeah yeah that's gorgeous it's got the
scarabs all over the the piece little
beetles and little butterflies beautiful
little trichome like it's part of a
private collection right now it's just
still hanging out here this is probably
the most hours that Stratos and I have
ever put into one single piece
intensive it must have just started
getting more and more intense as you
started stacking and building exterior
and scarier yeah yeah it's I mean it's
kind of leaves you with nothing to say
what do you say that cannabis leaf
spinner is incredible because our having
fun with that I can tell I can only
imagine
beautiful work guys let's get back to
the middle here and see what we got
this piece really grabs me I love the
way it looks
love the colors fiery orange --red it's
clean damn its proper spinners nice
thick base on it too I like that very
good very good I agree I only put my
sublimator on pieces with the thickest
most supportive bases and as this custom
as well for the sublimator yeah it's got
an extra-long joint so the god those
colors just pop in the Sun the Machine
Elves for those of you that don't know
what the machine elves are self
reflecting machine elves that were
jumping in and out of his chest telling
him not to be amazed but just to do what
they were doing
I'm sick spinning the molecules and this
piece was was produced in Europe
well ago this is actually the first
anyone seen of this piece no it's pretty
spectacular so people will be able to
and where where where are the collectors
able to find stratosphere and Cory glass
where's the easiest place to locate
Instagram is the spot oh nice to be able
to definitely get in touch with the the
blower direct when you want if you guys
are collecting want to add something
like this to your collection holy Christ
you know I'll put those instagrams and
kicks across the screen in the Edit just
in case you missed them beautiful love
these little ones too so nice beautiful
workmanlike come on the colors are just
so go so well together
yeah I've been loving the readies um mix
match it's got a few different ready
yeah so what I'm talking about right
there
it's funny that I guess that's kind of
old-school now nice little size pipe
right there too you think that is about
four inches about that
this one one a little penetrator Oh
oh yeah oh yeah a little more of a
challenge to make but right those little
pieces go right through don't they
superb class always looks so great in
the Saudi accents on this one to you
mm-hm seems to be the most all the rage
right now yeah it's a nice little piece
right there beautiful
so here here's where the magic happens
this is where I spend most of my time
we're here on my bench got a bunch of
prep started over here for our trip
coming up to war in Germany
haha Frank and fall yes that's sweet
that you guys are going to see Martin in
Germany and then shortly after we are
going to Vienna to the culty the show Oh
at cultiva yep beautiful so we're where
we'll be I guess it will be pretty easy
to not miss if it's a glassblowing demo
it'll be easy to find it's uh we're
being sponsored by roar and Herbert
Arnold - they're flying us out there and
that's legit taking care of all
accommodations so pretty sweet show
we're pretty excited to go do some work
over there yeah hell yeah guys it's
[ __ ] awesome you were showing me this
little tool a second ago this thing is
[ __ ] awesome yeah these are the
Herbie Arnold rollers I think I probably
had them about a year now that these
things are cat's ass this is so nice for
messy benches like mine whenever I need
to use them I don't have to clear out
any space or have the deal with moving
my
there's so much easier yeah that's
definitely sweet what's up puppy you
want us to play with your stick hey hey
buddy it survived to survive the coyote
and let you know it's a coyote survive
another survivor yeah very good well
it's [ __ ] great to come and hang out
at you guys shop and see see the
beautifulness definitely have some great
pieces I look forward to seeing what you
guys pull out in Europe I think both of
your jaws are gonna fall over when you
see that his his kiln suite well I think
man I'll tell you I feel blessed that I
got to go for that little tour
especially with you know like dizzle and
hops who are both just drooling as we
went from one room to the other because
it seems like it's one building after
another building and they all just seem
to be attached and it's just like it's
huge yeah it's definitely just like a
kid in the candy store I'm gonna buy all
these tools oh yeah bring cash bring
cash although they'd probably take glass
too that's awesome
see I wanted to ask you guys a little
bit about this crucible system that you
guys got going on here so what what
exactly is going on here to the to the
knowledge this is our clear pot that
we've been pulling some canes through
making readies so we've been putting
these color plugs and dunking them in
here and then pull them out so a really
really really long skinny cane down the
driveway chip them all up and
Ready's interesting yeah just heat that
right up in the crucible that's just
solid glass in there right now big chunk
aside we've also been getting into
mixing clear with color in the crucibles
too it's just been pretty awesome we've
been getting good results oh yeah they
just play around a little I like that
that seems like a good thing to have
under your belt the ability to sort of
control and manipulate and produce your
own color that's a great way to make
prep in bulk yeah thank your own colors
awesome cold what was it 18 pounds or 19
pounds of tubes that we pulled in what
two hours saves a lot of time nice boys
nice all right so yeah thank you guys
for coming and watching thank these guys
for walking us through the the glass
shop telling us what they're gonna be
doing I guess you guys are pretty stoked
to get out of here I'm gonna get headed
over to Europe yeah that's good times
not too bad at all so yeah if you guys
are in Vienna first week of October at
the cultiva go check these guys out
there doing the glassblowing for Herbert
Arnold and war that's do you guys have
any idea
nice nice good idea yeah wait till
you're on the ground there well that way
all three of us are in the same room and
we can brainstorm a lot better than over
the phone absolute listens yeah I think
that's the way to do it for sure
hook them up with something oh yeah well
as always I'm going to finish this show
with a dad and say thank you guys for
having me thanks for watching
[Music]