[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with my good buddy Cory cottam
in the House always a pleasure dude yeah
so Cory is on his way from the coast
into the City and in the next day or two
he's going to be making himself uh
making his way out east for a glass show
that you're going to be a part of yeah
I'm going out to London I'm going to go
uh to Culture Rising and I'm going to
have a whole bunch of my glass that I'm
going to have displayed we've got a few
pieces ahead of us in front of us here
beautiful dude when I say a part of it's
his show it's a solo show it's a Cory
cottam solo show uh it is at uh Culture
Rising Culture Rising so that is in
London Ontario there's posters all over
our social medias you can check out
check out my Instagram there's posters
that I've already posted it's got all
the info on there exactly so these are
just unbelievable as always was really
impressed with the hummingbird
feeder I mean I love the the the
recyclers that your style of I mean I
don't even know what these particular
ones are called orb
cyclers K cyclers all right cool yeah
very very beautiful I mean the the The
Wiggies the the the art in this one and
the colors loved you pulled this one out
first and it just absolutely blew my
mind and when you pulled this one out I
think it was about second and I just
thought holy smokes like the same colors
and lines but in an actual pipe I will
admit I was not 100% sure that this was
even a pipe when you first pulled it out
cuz I was looking inside I was like oh
they're all sealed up like maybe this is
like a hummingbird feeder I don't then I
saw the down stem and obviously guys I'm
going to take some photos of this so you
guys will be able to look at things in
beautiful uh detail but uh these are
only four pieces that are also come to
the show you'll see them in full detail
and that's what that's what we're saying
you know these are only four pieces
there are more than four pieces in the
show you've got a a whole slew I saw
yeah I've already sent them a whole
arsenal of work so they're taking
pictures or getting t-shirts made
stickers I saw the t-shirts what were
they the goddesses on the can yeah
there's the two posters that they made
so there's those two style shirts and
then he's also doing some graphics for
some of the other pieces so they'll be
few shirts available at the Show
excellent so this is sort of you know
the culmination of wouldn't you say I
mean obviously your entire career but
the the the the recyclers and how you've
really been trying to you know innovate
that recycler and create something
that's really you know more Corey than
anything else how long has that been now
has that been a year has it been two
years uh that I've been making the
recyclers yeah that you've been on this
sort of innovative cuz I've seen they
started out as cubes Tri uh yeah close
to year a little last I'd say eight
months now oh so you've done all of
those design cubes and it's just trying
to find the best ones that the ones that
function the best and they slowly
progress into these ones I find you can
hit these ones the hardest you don't get
any splashback few of the other ones you
you have to start them a little slower
you still function 100% but you got to
just kind of Kickstart it mhm no for me
that's a major point kickart then you
can haul as hard as you want but these
ones you can hit right off the bat hard
I remember the Kickstart one that you
had the one where like pull it just kind
of gentle get it in there and then start
yeah I was like oh that's kind of
different I find with the Eternal drain
it's too close to the perk and it wants
to if you hit too hard it'll want to
suck the water up the center right
before it starts to go around well
that's one of the things I love about
both you and Stratus is you know
obviously all glass blowers are on the
hustle they got to blow glass they got
to be on their torch they're not working
other jobs they're blowing glass so I
understand that Hustle but I also have a
deep respect for and I always take it
back to Jason Lee who was always very
obsessed how they how they felt when he
put water in them and and pulled through
them that Rumble and it had to be proper
the hand fill it's the visuals it's
everything absolutely I love these ones
cuz they're just the're the most
comfiest grip in your hand yeah like
your little guy said right it's like a
handle Dad yeah you can almost use these
like a cup and drink out of them yeah
they're absolutely spectacular like I
said you know one of the things that I
appreciate about both you and Stratus is
that you Contin you don't find something
to do
and then just do it over and over and
over and over and over and over and over
again there's Innovation and change that
occurs in each aspect of it and I you
know as a as a fan of glass and smoking
and seeing new things I really really
really have an appreciation for for that
I mean I watched Stratus with a simple
little spinning marble turn into this
explosive idea that's like all right
serious that he doing yeah you know it's
it's it's very cool to see and the fact
that you guys are both just right across
the water from I'm surprised even
earlier saying oh I'm surprised high
integrity glass art doesn't stop by more
often cuz he's he's so close I'm
surprised I don't stop by more often
because always open come by anytime you
guys get up there like twice a year
that's insane yeah unless it's
summertime I'm pretty busy and I'm in a
shop all the time so it's a good good
time to come and visit yeah well this is
exciting man so how long does the show
go for is it a is it uh it's on Saturday
night it's from uh 7 to 10: y yeah
you're going to be there for the whole
I'll be there so yeah by say hi let's do
some dabs excellent well Ontario always
represents really well for me when I go
out that way so I'm sure you're not
going to see uh much difference in that
it's uh there's a lot of people out
there there's a lot of people in the I
went to London for uh College I went to
fcha for a couple years so it would be
interesting to see if anybody that I
knew actually shows up it'll be uh
looking forward to it for sure yeah I'm
pretty sure my buddy Pete is from London
he's got a shop called Shakedown Street
yeah I know Pete yeah he's I've know
I've known Pete for 20 20 plus years so
uh yeah he used to be good close friends
with uh with friends of mine over here
the breeder Steve organic traveler is he
not exactly yeah before that the NYPD
yeah NYPD yeah I was like what that's a
weird
uh name so tell me a little bit about
the uh inspiration for this I mean it's
obviously substantially different from
the other three pieces on the table uh
yeah this was uh my inspiration for
uh the DFO piece that I was going to
make I had a hard time just kind of what
am I going to make that's going to be
the nicest that I can actually make in
the the short one day 12 hours that we
had MH and uh the hummingbird was one
that I could come up up with it was a
good theme that was relatively easy
enough to make in that time frame well
relatively easy is it wasn't as worked
as this one right definitely not it
didn't have any of the rello or anything
and the were just flared open cut so
there was some shortcuts that I took for
the original piece that I was going to
make and uh yeah I just I haven't seen
anybody make the hummingbird feater so
it's dude it is kind of like an on
Tapped uh re or Avenue to go down so
fully Bravo I'm telling you it's uh this
is what it's all about you know a lot of
these these glass blowers and I know
that they it pains them because there's
it's techniques you need to be learned
these techniques glass blowing was
always passed on from from Master to
student student it's not like a student
just decided he was going to be a glass
Bower these things were passed on and so
now we have this community that is very
scared of being jacked of being bitten
of being you know taken for their
techniques and their unique things that
they're creating and I see you in
particular always you know like you do
these e the excellent Line work the
things that you have learned from the
glass blowers that you have learned from
you represent them beautifully and I can
see how you know in the glass blowing
world that's a point of contention with
some artists they're like they have no
problem um charging for a class and
teaching these techniques but then they
also kind of have no problem being a
little bit pissed off when some of the
people are using techniqu just went out
and taught well and it's it's a tough
thing to see sometimes the student
surpass the master or the student do so
well that it's kind of like throws the
the teacher off a little bit but uh and
I give you guys props you definitely
like this hummingbird feeder go with it
it is a good style it's it's amazing
dude and I mean the the little birds
turning them into dabbers and stuff like
it's just too much it's just the quality
of it is really on point as you guys
will be able to see from the photography
as well I'll take the pieces outside and
I'll go with the 4k camera and give you
a nice kind of close up because uh my
goodness Cory it makes I'm not going to
lie it made me want to go to Ontario and
be there at the show yeah do it it
really did last minute Tri nothing wrong
with the last minute trip yep December
3rd December 3rd December 3rd that's
Saturday that's Saturday okay man I miss
having my Galler and doing things like
this this would have been a great thing
to have all these years maybe another
time you know Vancouver could really use
something like this yeah you could for
sure Boro and Beyond has been talking
about doing a group show with us all so
that's possibility down the road yeah
well I mean you guys have the talent
you've got the the glass it's uh it's
kind of silly not to Glass events are so
fun too if you guys have ever been to I
haven't been to a ton of them I I threw
a couple of great ones with marble
Slinger the degenerate art and the
regenerate art epic historical shows but
there was the Melting Pot show in San
Francisco prior to that uh there's been
shows at uh goosefire there's been shows
at a variety of galleries around North
America and of course the damp cran
Gallery in Amsterdam I've been to some
wonderful shows there as well it's it's
just a nice thing for our community to
have access to to get us out of this I'm
always looking to get Canabis more
normalized cannabis use more normalized
and to me super high-end functional art
plays a very important role in bringing
a group of people who would maybe
otherwise not be as into this culture as
we are with with something like this
like I I can guarantee you that this
could be sold to a collector without
them having any knowledge that it's a
pipe whatsoever and still being super
stoked on it and literally hanging it
for you know for for enjoyment it's it's
beautiful man yeah thank you man makes
me want to smoke actually yeah let uh
and we're not going we're not going to
dirty up your beautiful
pieces and these are all going to be
available at the show yeah hopefully we
get to try a few of these at the
show yeah that's always nice always nice
when the collector comes in and purchas
and then offers uh I always did that I'm
not going to lie and it was always hard
with someone like Marcel who was always
like uh I'd be like you take the first
hit and he'd be like no you take it
like
okay but Slinger took it a few times
he's like yeah I'll do that yeah I'll
take that hit yeah it's like damn
straight you will
bro damn straight you will well I'm
excited for you man I think you're going
to have a great show I think looking
forward to it it's going to be good to
be back in Ontario it's been a long yeah
it's the old stomping ground right yeah
it is very
cool let's get that going
carbed
up yeah I'm uh very very stoked to see
this glass I wish that it was a sunnier
day and I could get the most epic photos
of it it's pretty cloudy but we've got
some pretty good white bright light out
there if I photograph it from the right
angle uh I should be able my main factor
in photographing glass like this is
doing it justice doing the artist
Justice and doing the actual doing the
actual peace Justice cuz uh man I'll
tell you
sometimes when the pictures aren't very
saw a vice article recently where I
think it was about a glass
blow yeah it was about some guy I blow
$100,000 glass pipes or something and I
didn't even recognize his name I was
kind of like what but the pictures
literally looked like they were taken in
1980 by someone who was drunk at a party
like they were all out of focus if he
was blurry super out of focus like kind
of like Jack's got to be on point can't
be a fingerprint on there anyway it's
got to be clean no forget about
fingerprints this was like [ __ ] up
like every comment in the comment
section was like what did you hire like
the worst photographer on the plant Blah
Blah Blah Blah Blah by the way that
rosin you just hadit is 6 months old
yeah that was tasty yeah that's that
green crack God rosin nice and dipped
into dipped into some Swiss yeah all of
the um High CBD cultivar have these
fruity Cherry esque flavors which you
hear people say CBD has a cherry flavor
it's actually High CBD cultivars have a
cherry flavored tpine profile would be a
more accurate wave of saying
it oh yeah that's what I'm talking about
well I don't know if I will see you in
Ontario but I do look forward to this I
hope that you will do a little bit of a
live stream while you're there I will
yeah little Facebook live stream
definitely try to do so if you can do a
5 to 10 minute live stream that would be
amazing um I'll share it on my social
media and we'll make sure uh a big
audience gets on there to watch it cuz
it' be kind of a cool way for those of
you that aren't able to make it to be
able to to get a little taste yeah to be
able to have someone walk through
quickly I'm sure we'll be able to figure
that out between the two of us for sure
for sure most definitely
have you ever noticed rips don't stop
ripping when you them I know they keep
going you probably go like six seven
times before they actually
stop what is
that that's insane I I
know even some other some other oils and
stuff that I've smoked do that do the
same just hit and hit hit and hit some
live residents I find it like that too
they just hit and hit and
hit awesome all right well we're going
to call it a day here got uh some things
to get done in the city and I've also
got some things to get done but you guys
know the show is in London Ontario
Saturday December the 3rd come check it
out Uprising uh it's a Culture Rising
Culture Rising let's make sure we get
the name of the place right Culture
Rising you know Ontario is representing
the glass scene really strong maybe
substantially better than we are here
out in the west coast not in regards to
blowers but just in the community that
seems to want to have these shows and to
support the um to support the actual
artist so I wish you luck my friend
awesome thanks awesome dude peace out
guys thanks for watching Bubble man's
world bubble in action I
reaction
satisfaction sck
73 welcome to
[Music]
the cha herbalist The canab
Specialist herbalist
horizonal and a
heris it was Tuesday night in
a
u Manu
[Music]
D say comes the officer asking for
search find a weapon
only
[Music]
heriz the can
specialist
speci
herbalist herbalist can special the off
pull me over and you search Dr the