[Applause]
[Music]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my open wi the sun was up in my face the
wisdom of the W keep my head straight
with I canot
[Music]
try to Perfection smoke synic I love
the found we get the
full ring I love
the I when the rest consum the
meditation to CB1 and
CB2 can receptors in the brain and
happiness
for
horiz man herbalist The canab
Specialist
[Music]
herbaliz over you
search
a pull it up and give it a sniff
turn I say yes and I also got
hash full m edes all that dry make you
cool and relax and if you get some you
must come
back man her canot be
[Music]
special
origin
indigenous we
[Music]
justop
indigenous cre them from the
in be care and turn you TR in
[Music]
Ander
sexing
orous
indigenous can just
[Music]
some phone out Yes
[Applause]
[Music]
Man
full full full full
[Music]
full
yes you want to hit some full melt yes
[Music]
[Applause]
m
[Music]
full full full
full
[Music]
with
full yes
[Music]
m
he
now yes
[Music]
m
you know I know
I
you
know you
[Music]
know