hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to a little
sesh a little sesh in that grill finally
got to the place that I'm staying I
guess we could wait a few seconds to see
if more people are coming into the room
I'm not sure who's in the room because
they don't actually see any talking yet
but yeah we'll just
patiently await for a few folks what is
it 252 here in Jamaica ah there we go a
couple more I still don't see any typing
hopefully that starts to come in soon I
usually like to see the typing and that
lets me know what's going on let's see
do we have any words to be said no
typing still YouTube's 73 people now
come on there's got to be top checks so
much has seen as possible live chat all
messages are visible let's I still don't
see anyone's typing see no orientation
is locked
alright well I'll just pretend that
you're all there oh look at that it's
delayed but it just popped up 81 people
in the room I am here at Llantrisant if
you want to check it out online it's
Beach Cliff calm beautiful little
facility a little place here owned by
the good doctor Craig and his wife
Sherry I've got a little tennis court
I've got about four acres here in the
grill right on the water they got a
private beach over here they got a
private beach behind the tennis court
over here some beautiful epic trees what
I thought we would do was we could have
a little session you guys want to get
your pipes u-joints whatever it is
you're puffing on and we could have a
little session together yeah you know
this banger is actually a banger that
goes with the product for mr. hot box
that sits on the beam it sits like on
top of it and then the beam heats it up
there's a little piece of metal that
goes under here so I've never actually
used this banger with a torch so I may
get a hot dab
I may get a too cool of a dab bear with
me hey Anthony you're just gonna have to
get more ripped sorry to say what's
going on Joe Dalton and what's up bubs
wagwan Babu man you in a cottage in the
grill I'm in this really [ __ ] sweet
place in the grill it's it's decent
private beach over that way
let's pour it right over here you know
oceanfront in front of me it's really
quite beautiful it's it's good stuff
what was that your purple fab egg huh my
Chino that was a friend of Mines most of
the pipes I post that aren't just clear
our generally friends of mine unless I
specifically say that it's mine this is
the Jamaican dude with the wind blower
he was just wind lowing for about an
hour and a half straight I finally had
to ask him when are you gonna stop wind
blowing leaf blowing and so he told me a
little bit ago within five minutes he
quit but I think he's now already
forgotten and he's coming back around
the side of the building to to do some
more blowing so we'll just deal with it
it's jamaica style I'm gonna hit the
torch and I'm video now I'm on the video
you're on the video they're all saying
what's up to the gardener 25 years 26
years 26 years in gardening this man
knows how to garden right there I'm only
gonna do this for a little bit so if we
can just keep the sound down just for a
little Oh perfect all right well we're
gonna need some dabs no problem I'm just
doing dabs right now on camera all right
we'll talk soon yeah man it's your most
expensive piece bee man me and brick
we're wondering if you don't mind I
don't really know you know I've got
pieces that are old that could be worth
25 or 30 thousand dollars
he definitely grows ganja he offered me
some ganja earlier and he definitely is
oh nice nice toaster girl here well I
better hit this so I'm gonna have to do
a little bit um I got this today from
from uncle stoner I'm not sure if you
guys are familiar with uncle stoner but
he lent me this torch today I went to
saw him he was just leaving back for us
just bang on clean give it 20 seconds or
so
we're gonna trot in there that's smoke
it out I like to keep it nice and clean
sometimes when I'm puffing in Jamaica
it's a little bit hard with lack of BC
glass cleaner I do have a whole thing of
q-tips but what I'm feeding hits out to
a lot of people I find that it
definitely becomes difficult to keep it
as clean as I would like to just with
myself all right we'll get that off now
we'll go forty to fifty to two so yeah
about fifty seven forty and I will hit
this at and I guess I better get a dab
little cookies and cream you know I love
the tech temp USA check them out if you
haven't already I think that's the way
to go personally their little unit is a
laser thermometer it sits right
underneath your banger you roll your
banger over it or you roll it under your
banger and I'm telling you it is the
most accurate rip I've gotten from a
torch there's no comparing even
absolutely no comparing it's hard to say
you know I can't tell if this bangers
gonna hold heat or release heat so I'm
even gonna get probably because I'll
wait longer than I then then I would you
know I'm not gonna go too quick I'll
probably get a low temp tab before I get
a real hot one so let's check it out
here I think we're good to go
damn you're perfect no Chaz still a
liquid in the bottom I use vape pen see
how they're convenient I'd rather hit
this every day of every minute but if I
got whoo you know I'll hit a vape pen
that was perfect absolutely perfect I'm
excited because I'm about to walk you
guys around this property now I figured
that's what I do for a live video I'm
gonna try and film some videos with the
4k camera and the GoPro and you know
give you guys a little bit of a show
that way but I thought you know what
sometimes I never get around to editing
and sometimes it just takes so long and
I know how much people appreciate seeing
things in the moment when they're
happening proof is that we have 175
people in the room right now and so why
don't we walk over here see Q who's me
there we go Oh yep oh there we go sorry
about that guys yeah a little too far
away so we'll have to stay a little
closer I'm not sure how long how far the
internet how much does the how much does
the internet suck here I just wanted to
take you guys for a little cruise but
you know what let's be honest it ain't
happening there are some beautiful trees
over there but this is all the better
reason for us to just have a couple of
puffs and have a conversation and I can
film this place with my 4k GoPro and
camera you know maybe go do some some
fully checking out the property and then
you'll be able to check it out on on
YouTube that way because right now this
is not the best way to share I guess I'm
yeah I found the sweet spot exactly so
I'm gonna stay in the sweet spot so we
don't go paused again all right we lost
almost half of our viewers when it went
down like that a lot of people just have
no understanding of how tenacious and
committed I am to to pumping it that's
right
organics for life so I'm sure a lot of
you guys have seen the conversation
that's out and about about Philo's
Biosciences and a lot of things that
genomics
this one's you know omics are saying we
all released something from the de m
Peter family today I'm not sure to check
that out on histogram a lot of
statements were made but I don't think
it was really strong and we need to
promote you know conscious no-till
organic regenerative farming because
these are the expressions that we want
our hashes and our extraction processes
so yeah I think the statement was there
there is some confusion in regards to
what actually happened some people are
thinking that Center that Mowgli and his
team basically know took samples from
everyone and then tissue cultured those
samples and are growing those genetics
that that did not happen that's that's
not something that's happening so people
are able to pissed off about that even
though it didn't happen but the thing
that did happen is they did request
genetic sampling DNA sampling from all
these 4,000 Plus you know samples that
everyone gave and then they announced
just a little while ago the different
being as though they're claiming that
the breeding have anything to do with
the genetics they collected but the
community feels as though that's not the
truth and a lot of people feel a little
a little bummed out about that I'm not
sure if we're still online here are we
still online I think it's turning I
don't really think that we're online
we'll check it out I'll be patient I'll
wait otherwise I'll make another cheers
140 people
you're live ok cool cuz right now it's
doing this in the middle of my screen so
it seems like it's not live but I'll
just keep going with it
so that's kind of one of the
conversations I want to do a hash Church
where we can get a bunch of the people
who really have an idea what they're
talking about when it comes to this and
and have an open conversation about it
on hash Church because I think hash
church is really a great platform for us
to get to get together and that there's
no there's no team hash Church is not a
team it's a it's a combination of all
the people from the community and we're
not for or against it's just a matter of
having the conversation I think that one
of the problems with the society today
is that when we have when we make
mistakes when we do things that are
looked down upon society people want to
hold those people in that energy forever
they don't even want to have
conversations about it there's certain
things nowadays you can't even have a
conversation about that's why so many
comedians are not touring colleges
because that's really where this whole
thing started they started in
universities and colleges they compel
speech they pass laws and then they get
to define what is hate and what is you
know okay to talk about and what is not
okay to talk about I'm a firm believer
that everything should be talked about
if possible not a really big deal I
think that even if you disagree with
someone greatly that you should still be
able to sit across a table from them
without slinging insults and talking
down to them and getting into into war
basically that which is what people do
it's I've fallen into it myself I'm not
saying I'm void of it but yeah don't
move it it's so good I'm not moving it
bro
yeah Church must survive I agree you
know it's not something I can do every
Sunday especially when I'm in countries
like Jamaica but it's still pretty cool
yeah I saw the Adam Dunn show had it the
past two weeks and I did enjoy it you're
right actually that's that's true I just
think that the hash Church like I think
I watched the Adam Dunn and it seemed
very one-sided it didn't seem like too
many people were representing Philo's I
think mildly called in one time and lots
of other people called in and it was
cool and I like that idea
cuz that's something hashed Church can't
do so shout out to Adam Dunn for being
able to put that together and I was on I
was in the chat room I almost I almost
called in as well but just inviting kind
of the key component people that are
involved in passing this information
whether positive or negative yeah like
I'd like to talk to I'd like to have
Kevin Jodrey I'd like to have Kevin
mckernon MOG Lee Holmes
you know maybe chimera maybe Dave Watson
maybe Rob Clark you know like I think
that would be a pretty incredible panel
and then maybe a few other people that I
don't quite know about yet and I learned
also have a deep knowledge of this and
have a deep understanding has Church
really feels I can't
I missed you sorry feels it more of a
think tank with the educated people in
the right area with no [ __ ] yeah
it's kind of like a think tank but at
the same time you guys are all a part of
it you know like I read the chatroom
throughout all of hashed shirts I have
for everyone and I engage and I bring up
your conversations if you ever notice
I'll say something that I read in the
chat room and I then I'll say you know
James MIT McDonough said how's Indra
these days do because that can just
Brian like you know promote cuz you guys
come up with that you're a part of the
discussion and I think it's what is one
of the hardest things about me doing
Hatcher's because I'm moderating I'm
interacting with all the people that are
in the room and I'm directing and kind
of you know carrying through with the
conversation while simultaneously
engaging with the people in the chat
room all the wild people hitting me up
on Facebook people hit me up on my own
personal I message people hit me up on
Instagram like endlessly trying to
engage and I always say like listen come
into the YouTube chat room if you say
something good I'll repeat it and it can
it can help direct the conversation is
what a yearly family trip for me kid
Karl
157 we gotta get back up to 200 yeah I
learned about growing with soil good
call Kelvin Kevin yeah you should check
out well that's powerful to check out
but Dutch blooms is a good one to start
with Jesus Yeshua must be saved Mohammed
don't die from you and all others I
don't know about that I mean I'll leave
you be for now but if you keep spamming
the room with that I'll bounce you
pretty fast I mean I'm all about people
I think it's better to engage with the
conversation like if you want to save
Jesus and Muhammad and everyone like
just engage in the conversation at hand
and and somehow it'll be directed to
what you want to talk about but don't
just like go off top I can throw a big
spam in there greetings from Tacoma do
you recommend a base for soil growers I
remember around this time last year
you're in Jamaica took a tolerance break
I've been in Jamaica a lot over the
years hello Jim Bernardo from
Massachusetts Sam H laughing his
[ __ ] ass off no negative BS
hello Marcus from Italy uh good Seif
bina hello from Italy very good
beautiful beautiful country hi from
Ontario my own country also beautiful so
celebrate Liberty all right TEKT Liberty
didn't mean to send reading my indoor
gardening guide but thanks brother hello
from Asheville North Carolina that's
cool spot peat moss homemade compost
what are the actual general pros and
cons of indoor versus outdoor both are
done to perfection well right off the
bat you're never gonna grow cannabinoids
as cheaply in a field as you can in an
indoor grow so if you look at most
people don't think of the excessive
waste that it takes to grow cannabis for
water and electricity and all the
products and all that just packaging and
shipping it's just like it's a we gotta
do better than what we're doing and I
think I think that's what the Dragonfly
earth Madison Crew is you know being
conscious listening to the soil trying
to do the right things just it's really
simple you know you go back to the root
unintended and just take care of them
create these living soils these living
biomes that used to just be you know
nature until we destroyed and killed it
go back to protecting the
simple things allow these plants to
express themselves and maybe lower the
footprint on the environmental costs to
growing cannabis too much packaging in
the interest in industry absolutely I
mean in California how much how much
like those guys go through water like
crazy I'm sure for cannabis I mean they
probably some of the largest growers in
the world can only imagine how much
water they consume for growing cannabis
and Sun is absolutely where it's at and
packaging is a good idea
oh thanks London Ontario Trent Taylor go
check out Jay London Tom the bubble man
sent you dabbing and smoking on some
wash wish Mountain and some wookie all
right Curtis that sounds good right on
I've been I like to top it ok cool I'm
doing 50/50 ocean for us cocoa with
roots were gonna try minutes will hurt
us now very few problems there you go DM
I have been there California oil
extractor representing excellent welcome
I was wondering about mark the weed guys
he's still around you know mark the weed
guy disappeared I have no idea what
happened to mark the weed guy I he was
around constantly and all the time and
Benny kind of had like I had a
falling-out with him a little one I'm
not bad like if I saw him I wouldn't be
upset but he had a big falling out with
his his friends Remo and some other
people and then I don't know he I
believe he's married to a woman in China
so he's probably in China but he had a
strong social media following I'm
surprised you know he also was a cancer
survivor he's a pretty intense guy I met
him years ago when he was I think he'd
just finished slike putting his canter
into remission with cannabis oh there
will be rare 710 but nothing I can talk
about just yet but you know this second
I can I'll be dropping it like beats
their have basically printing filament
I'm not too sure about that especial
health risk in a distant in those in
those cartridges mostly around the coil
so the coil ends up being an alloy
instead of like a grade of titanium like
a grade 2 which would be like a pure
titanium
you've end up with an alloy and then the
alloy has these metals in it and those
those leech heavy metals as it gets hot
and cold hot and cold and absorbs oil
and releases eventually the oils pull
out these toxic heavy metals you can
look there's been an article or a paper
done at the John Hopkins University and
they did it I think on like the top 57
or 67 vaporizers and they found heavy
metal contaminants in most of the oil I
don't think the great gardener ever had
a YouTube channel to be honest but he
does work a big legal company now I
think he's a consultant for canopy
I thought suffered with depression in my
life I've been pretty lucky I've gotten
a little bit of anxiety when my father
was killed in a motorcycle accident with
his wife quite suddenly that caused me
anxiety for some years and I kind of
understood what like anxiety was
definitely just tapping into that for a
very short period of time I could
understand the absolute and utter hell