[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
sitting here with d420 K we just bumped
into each other a little while ago here
in the
city it's been a good trip man
excellent trip man excellent food
excellent smoke excellent ride all of it
we just W wolfed down uh Sushi cones AI
tuna tacos and some stringy french fried
things that were just [ __ ] awesome
french fries like so good you know I
like french fries a lot yeah and those
french
fries I'll travel for those french fries
I actually did actually they're at the
top of the list for sure y so yeah it
was good stuff we got our little Hitman
little mini little baby
cakes we got a couple of different
torches and some dry sip that both of us
made so we figured it might not be a
full episode but in the least we'll film
a little session with uh with you guys
out on YouTube so go grab your pipes and
your hash and uh your dabbers and uh get
her ready get ready to go cuz we're
making this happen you got to about 25
seconds to get her ready i' say that's
generous smoke on time with us that's
right that is generous all right so just
cuz it's you know it's polite
this one almost looks like it needs
gas let's just do that real quick I know
I filled that one the other
day I bought a w of butan it's in the
bike
too I picked up a little Roar from your
from your shop oh yeah the little mini
hitter yeah
yeah nice try it out come down to the
collection oh yeah I love those little
guys traveled in Jamaica with that very
pipe on a multitude of
occasions anytime you're
[Music]
ready
dabs oh that dab barely fits we'll have
to force
it so we went to the Coalition for the
repeal of uh the mm AR program yesterday
that was really nice about to see Remo
and Jason Willcox and an G and John Bell
and a whole good good crew crew was
there so that was
nice Johnny B Johnny B was
there got your DB ready Mister ah I
could have it ready pretty darn
quick it's the trick now get ready it's
tiny little you can't see
[Music]
it had an awesome time with Vancouver as
always hit up cannabis uh culture
headquarters and smoke nice off to top
there was great yeah today yesterday
probably probably do it tonight too
later on because I can and uh you know I
hit a vapor lounge um Eden that was
pretty neat we uh my buddy chance and I
went in there and Yeah we actually we
actually did some dabs oh yeah I dab the
dab bar we dabed at the dab bar what was
neat was you just literally pull
yourself right up to the bar there and
you see order like you're ordering a
drink and boom they're doing the dabs
they're running the torch the running
the Dabber the running the whole show so
you have the nice most optimal talk you
can have and I was impressed with the
whole situation i' actually go back
there again and uh I liked it I liked it
a lot very cool man yeah it's nice to
have a city that you know we've got our
our compassion clubs which are very
serious sort of almost medical
establishments we have our vapor lounges
which are really just like anyone can
kind of go you pay your five bucks or
whatever then you have your combination
Club Dash Vapor Lounge like what
Darren's talking about where you would
require to show a license you can't just
medical license they won't just dab
anyone out you got to have your license
so it's very cool that these things
exist and then then you have anomalies
it's so nice it's available you have
anomalies like um mega ill you know
these guys that are like Mark the weed
guy who's literally selling medicated
pizza and Med medicated treats I believe
there's a company in Vancouver called
Fusion that's also now doing it or
infused sorry I'll uh I'll write it in
the comment section cuz I don't want to
get the name wrong but uh
it's nice to see it starting to blow up
here in Vancouver you know it is for how
advanced Vancouver was in the '90s it
seemed like it really took a slow pace
in this last decade of not really in the
'90s it was really it was really hard to
get into that like that's when I was
coming down and met you you know and and
we're you know we're always smoking and
stuff but we never we're never uh you
know openly like this did we do this at
all it was just you know it was was it
wasn't wasn't able to be done although
getting [ __ ] we didn't mind getting [ __ ]
either yeah but not stupidly right
yeah so it's nice that we can do this
we're not offending anyone we're not
throwing anyone's day off and in no
shape or form to Darren and I feel like
we have to look around all rubber necked
worrying about you know any type of
police or security or any type of
actually take a look at the video yeah
watch this when you when you look back
at this video look to see if we were
like if we did that even once I I don't
remember doing it if I I did it one time
at the start of the video when the
Harley drove by and I just went like
this to to see the was yeah it's like
when you're on a bike and you hear a
bike you're looking at the bikes I look
at bikes even when I'm not on a bike yes
sir [ __ ] right it's part of loving it
you know dirt bikes [ __ ] crotch
rockets you know Road uh anything on two
wheels I'm telling you anything on two
wheels and even some of those [ __ ]
spider three-wheelers are pretty trippy
the two two wheels in the front I take
that thing for a ride I might not buy
one but you know I'm wondering if those
wheels go like this those yeah they
articulate like a car they literally
well I know they turn like this but do
they when you will they
lean I'm not sure you know what I mean I
don't know I'd like to check I bet if
you went around a corner fast enough
it's hard to say though because it
really is going to offset if I really
want to know I could just YouTube it
good I yeah it's true I'm sure someone's
gone like 130 mph like around sure does
the [ __ ] spider articulate or maybe
some of you out there know and you can
yeah let us know man video maybe you got
a video you be doing some crazy [ __ ] on
it too or something Fu well I'm looking
forward to driving through Stanley Park
right now maybe you guys want to come
through Stanley Park it's a beautiful
Park that we have here in uh Vancouver
I'll strap the GoPro on the front of the
bike uh sorry actually on the front of
me I don't have a bike uh strap for it
so you have to look through my visor
like like last time but uh yeah we could
rip around the park get to the highway
and split wav if you want to Oh no
you're heading back this way I'm going
to head back this way buddy cuz I got I
got my way it's quick this way yeah yeah
yeah all right so I'm going to go
through the park Darren's going to go
back his way we'll link up tomorrow for
sure yes we you know we might have a
late night session but who knows you
never know what's going to happen bub
it's true enough true enough man so well
I'm going to say goodbye to you then my
brother we'll see you uh either later or
tomorrow and I'm going to take these
guys for a little ride through Stanley
Park we on peace
guys all right s I'm gonna get you
taking off on the
GoPro all right good to see you bro
peace
bro be back
[Applause]
[Music]
a
oh w
[Music]
a
pap
[Music]
oh
a
[Music]
w
[Applause]
[Music]
he
[Applause]
[Music]
this is a li in Fr be production
he
[Music]
d
n
[Music]
a
he
[Music]