[Music]
all right holy [ __ ] John and I have
slept like 2 hours and we are now in Our
Town Car Town Car and we're going to
head over to the airport to catch this
flight to Jamaica so yeah yeah I think
that's the plan all right we made it to
the airport we're doing our thing before
we get on the
plane got some o what I
got had to bury the Trippy Stick buried
the stick eh buried the stick see you
got your bubble bags there John is that
uh got the XL bags are we taking some 20
gallon bags to Jamaica this is my
carryon this is his carryon it's our
carryon actually we have a lot of carry
on so I don't know I guess we're going
to go hook up with our uh friends that
we're flying into Kingston with so
couple more rips and we're out of here
hey Johnny we're popping all the
way catch you in
Kingston what I was going to say is
that's that's why it's good that you
will be willink to get the United canis
the way out you will still be able to
work with other
groups for our company
I
love each and every day
everyone got
their each and every day
love the G more and more each and every
day
my my on the mountain I
the cing snake living in the redwood
tree theil
wean what's up guys bubble man John B CL
and Ashley in the house and I don't know
your name buty Kelly helped us she was
our protocol agent she helped us clear
through customs made the experience very
nice and now we're going to head outside
and uh start the trip to
Jamaica right boys that's right
around
he just jumps right on that truck from
the
[Music]
car Spanish Town
green bucket yeah yeah yeah with
the didn't even see the green bucket
until I was looking at the
truck man here in Spanish Town Jamaica
pre yeah and we're grabbing some ice pre
and I are getting some ice is this party
ice time pres right now right now right
now right now we're not we're going to
be partying with this ice real soon so
uh I'm going to grab a bunch of bags
with prey and we'll see you guys when we
get where we're going some ice you are
with the bubble man right now we're
about to start some history right now
dude we are about to start some history
we've been driving around for the last 3
hours maybe I'd say two to three okay
and just to find these these are not
easy to find in Jamaica everyone's got
one but good luck finding one to buy we
managed to find too because of course
we're with prey and when prey uh when
you ask prey to find him you a bucket
he's going to find us a bucket so
basically we're on our way now to the
place where I think we're going to be
meeting our friends and then heading
over to the field or perhaps they'll
already have the herb there either way
we're going to be making bubble real
soon we just landed in Jamaica about 5
or 6 hours ago so let's see how fast we
can get to mixing up the medicine
[Applause]
[Music]
n
[Applause]
[Music]