[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
been a while since I posted a video
actually but today I had to post one
because this is the last day before
Canada legalizes cannabis recreationally
now a lot of you may know that I have
had a MMA hour license a federal
exemption from the government since 2011
2012 sorry I'm out of breath I just
literally ran up from my truck need to
catch my breath
and also pretty excited about this I
know a lot of people are still you know
calling it prohibition 2.0 they're
they're bashing on it they're saying
that all the laws are worse they're
absolutely not happy with the way things
are playing out at all I on the other
hand see this as a great step forward
more access for people obviously we
still have to fight for dispensaries and
we still have to fight for different
products like edibles and concentrates
but this is pretty big news in Canada
legalization up to 4 plants everyone in
the country can grow we're allowed to
carry 30 grams we're allowed to smoke
outside the airport we're a lot of smoke
at campgrounds and any public place
where you can smoke cigarettes we're
allowed to smoke it's a pretty big deal
from someone like myself who for 30
years has been fighting the prohibition
machine and you know watching a lot of
my friends get arrested and having their
lives ruined myself included having
having been arrested and having gone
through the court systems and it's just
a huge huge relief to seeing it come to
fruition
tonight at 12:01 a.m. it's October 16th
right now and I'm actually gonna be
heading over to Victoria to party at the
pachu pachu party they've got like a
couple of special guests I think one is
Tommy Chong and the other is the actor
- rapper Ludacris you'll see what that's
all about
mostly I'm excited for to go see my team
embark it's the first time the entire
team is going to be together that's my
extract lab that I've been working on in
Delta and we've rented a beautiful home
if you can imagine a team of 12 to 15
people 200 plus dollars a night at a
hotel we ended up renting this really
beautiful epic house on a 43 acre
property it's got a helipad and it's got
Dido know seven or eight bedrooms and
it's just really like spectacular you
guys are gonna be able to see that
footage because I'm gonna film all day
and I'm actually gonna be heading down
to Harbor air right away here in the
next 15 minutes or so and it may be
jumping on a float plane from downtown
Vancouver and we're gonna be flying into
downtown Victoria in which case I'll
jump in a cabin and head over to the
house after that but super excited
figured I might as well take a quick dab
with you
shoutout to solvent this winter sent me
a little bit of treats here this is the
dance hall almost identical to Juanita
levy mosa but the guys from maple butter
were sending me there for a while very
orange e very delicious and why don't we
have a quick little DAP together shall
we kind of a pre post-prohibition dab so
we've got one more day here I don't know
what it is 12 13 14 more hours before
we're out of that sort of Prohibition
mentality that's plagued Canada for at
least the last hundred years
pretty exciting times
so I do a 20 second heat up on my quartz
and a 50 second cooldown for those of
you wondering
boom all right I might even go a whole
minute for this particular cooldown so
yeah it's exciting I'm looking forward
to seeing the team I'm looking forward
to seeing a bunch of people I was
supposed to go to the canopy growth
party dnase coming into town for a quick
bit for that my good friend Hilary Black
was the one who invited me and I'm sure
Kurt to Saad and Matt Baron and all the
other canopy team will be there I'm sure
they're gonna have a great time and I'm
sure that we'll see footage of it and
find out what went on there but in the
meantime I'm gonna cover the party in
Victoria and just sort of this little
bit of a trip you know I want to just
sort of have like a fun little adventure
where I take you guys with me and we
have dabs and we meet people and we have
good conversations and of course show me
this in spectacular property that we're
staying at in Victoria and then hit a
little love hit a little of this dance
hall and see how that goes make sure I
got my carb cap ready got my q-tips got
a couple here perfect perfect and more
perfect I'm excited can you tell it's
been a while since I've actually shared
time with you guys on camera so I'm very
excited how it's all gonna play out
well to taste the spectacular on that
alright so give that a quick little
q-tipping just both have dirty ends on
one side but clean ends on the other
side and even though it looks pretty
clean I'll still give it a little little
droplet of the DC glass cleaner
everyone's gonna ask me what kind of
glass cleaner was that again Dark
Crystal glass cleaner don't forget it
[ __ ] works really well I don't know
where the lid for this one is I'll just
leave it off anyway let's get on this
adventure shall we we're gonna head down
to Harbor air we're gonna jump on a
float plane and I want to bring you guys
with me the whole way
so let's do this
[Applause]
[Music]
Sony's strike like seen as the margin
break my game is open why this one was
up in my face
all right so here we are at Harbor air
in the Pacific Ocean and yeah let me see
if I can get it better oh there we go
I'm a little bit more lit up now pretty
stoked to get on one of these planes and
go celebrate legalization with my peers
my group be jumping on one of those
planes right there so let's go check-in
[Music]
if our lights lighting chinese i got her
but nothing
if I write like Chinese but not verbally
[Music]
enjoy :
we must come back
I'm Charlie
indigenous here gun
[Music]
my
original indigenous fear gun
[Music]
I'm not big enough
I
[Music]
ah stop
all right we have landed here in
Victoria head over the cab
beautiful day in Victoria
[Music]
you work in all right let's do it
how's it going excellent all right get
that one perfect thank you sir
[Music]
let's see if we can't get in here maybe
there's a I guess so
oh it's going on something
it mentioned that it was ridiculous
right this [ __ ] place is definitely
Wow stay there for a couple of minutes
all right here we are let's check this
place out Oh
let me get such a small place like how
we're gonna deal with this r19 my gun
[Music]
not her values if I write like Charlie's
or not her value cannot be shy
but the apart right side Chinese
[Music]
I like honestly I forgot search cuff I
know where pond
I got her like Chinese but not her but
Lucy cut nothing special
nice place
[Music]
movement over Adam septic you watch em
drop it
noise angry bitter sleep
also that high-rise peacemaker :
[Music]
all right so I have been here at the
house for a little while I was kind of
hoping on taking you guys through the
tour right from the second I got here
place is absolutely incredible really
really incredible it's quite something
quite a quite a unique situation to be
in to be able to spend it with this
great group of people my team at embark
I just thought I'd come over here and
grab a little seat on the table there's
the epic house that we're staying at I
might have to wait till tomorrow to give
you guys the walkthrough but it is
definitely a spectacular house let's see
what we got Wow this house is
spectacular all right they're gonna be
cranking music in there so I'll stop
talking and we're gonna put some music
on of our own while we enter Victoria is
one and only the view with the
conquering lion right at the entrance
yes yes there we go
looks like I got locked out I got locked
out
thanks funny all right here we go little
tour why the team baraq read up to be
that you do mine do we gave up too
easily type you
he's not here to trick the mind
he's already here to do its purpose of
that van Johnny's not here to change the
mind he's only here to do its purpose of
that without the traveling to keep some
boat 20 miles and all while asleep in
I'm a job wood for tiny craft to watch
fresh vegetation we trees and we throw
eyes office apart if you can jolly it
move up the walk
give me a bigot ramble on Oct don't you
- give me time the one who Twiggy no no
- give me one big E and if you see from
my bass bass bass bass banka banka I
make a pom pom pom pom pom you see me -
I made out - snappy obsolete and inside
I great process when the same tycoon
boss side will remove the country
manager before me like a cafe bliss that
tragedy through lunch break on a people
and ba ba
booby booby booby type you today which
is not here to trick the mind it is only
here to do its purpose of - ganja is not
here to change the mind it is only here
to do this purpose of diet when I
imagined only rudia peaceful cops
sitting up the blood and semen a lyric
in our TV trucks well do menara believe
in the lives and tell me your grams and
pass upon you see you see reality I mean
every smoky workday from pass - pass -
pass
and then we pop on car roof on car roof
on car and they could pay from bass
vampire vampire
and then you pop punk ass punk ass if
you go to pump ass put some bass you
found bass and then we pop on cast your
punk ass punk
[Music]
for the line set up a machine what kind
of train you up here tryna sell clean
and clear come on dive in dive dive dive
dive diamond a Bugatti
it's about two times whatever New Times
time to dive in dive dive dive dive dive
dive dive agape
it's about two times two times
fresh from the instructors uncheck
percent pure adventure
let us work nice of a front wheel and
pretty like on their words of use this
good fun just be nine-fold
good for the young on the whole with
that mean damn time time time time time
at Abu Dhabi
it's a double duel time never do time
time with our baby
[Music]
coming in the morning stopping in the
evening time in that supper time that me
when you're weary Ivan Lendl only having
cars we're feeling fine
something perhaps we want to stop in
I've got to show you my job in machine
got my brother in problem I'm bringing
in with I think that dive dive dive dive
down I got with nothing number two times
W times time we dive in dive dive dive
she's a couple do times never do that
it's good for the endocannabinoid system
Ola feel great
[Music]
banana man
dive dive dive dive dive dive
this is a double two times never do
change time
[Music]
hey obi-wan drop it
why the team baraq read up for you
really stop to be that you to mine do we
gave up too easily type you to die which
is not here to trick the mind it is
already here to do its purpose of that
bad Johnny's not here to achieve your
mind
[Music]
how's it going
how's it going it's going good
we're almost at legalization stage man
is six minutes before legalization
[ __ ] six minutes before
legalization now we do keep pushing for
no limitations on yeah
no limitations on animals for a
everything's concentrates every every
limitations
watch again alright cuz I want to be the
first but what does the word person and
be smoking some [ __ ] me don't smoke a
so what is this what is this [ __ ]
clock do is you [ __ ] look here when
this says 1200 you [ __ ] are we are we
are [ __ ] use your eyes fifty [ __ ]
five forty seven seconds oh [ __ ] you
okay so now we're going to 50 seconds
mine watch my I'm watching this six
seven eight
[Music]
[Applause]
we are living in different realities and
you can do the slo-mo movie and then you
can watch and see which one no but it's
still zero zero when that says 57 but
still it could be a fine
11:58 he's got a minute and 27 seconds
all right so now this whole minute I
will let this cool down and then this is
gonna be my post-prohibition
my first post-prohibition right into the
new year fifty-five seconds there you go
I've been put in the back of police cars
I've been thrown in cages yeah I've had
my nerve all the store taking my herb
all those oh my god soon to be done
it'll men start your engines oh wow we
got 40 seconds left 3003 a lot to get
rid of tiny another 20 seconds this is
going straight into here we go
yeah we're almost legal all across the
board in Canada code 9 8 7 6 - here we
go
[Music]
the
keeping to 200 kilos a day crystalline
CB crystalline
[Music]
what's going on everybody
post-prohibition day one here in
Victoria at this incredible house it's
just been pretty awesome so far had some
great meetings with the embark team also
blew off a bunch of steam and you know
Huff turbine should have had a good time
and now we're now we're barbecuing up
some food so it's just non-stop here at
the embark Commission prohibition post
prohibition
day one it's pretty [ __ ] a pretty
pretty [ __ ] amazing excellent view
here let's see there's an infinity pool
here behind me
it goes out pretty sweet I'll just had a
couple of dabs on the mothership and
decided I'm not gonna put this hot tub
to waste I'm gonna get in and enjoy it
so you're gonna say what's up and I'll
continue to film throughout the rest of
the day here on day one and celebrate a
little bit of a party so to show you
guys as much as I can alright alright so
today we have rented a party bus we're
taking the party bus into Victoria so
here we go party bus
it's the party of us book was I'm gonna
read in song and I also gotta take care
of a lot of things I'm gonna thank for
Cheech
[Applause]
I've been teaching Vancouver because he
was up hiding from the war in Vietnam so
Canada means a lot to me it doesn't give
me my attitude that got me where I am
today because if it wasn't for we
[Music]
[Applause]
the Vietnam War
candidate took him in he became almost a
landed immigrant in Canada but then when
we got together and I found out that we
could be funny there was only one place
we had to go was down the states to make
it
and so Cheech was the first Mexican to
sneak into the States from Canada and
he'd be here today but he's hiding from
Donald Trump because Chuck wants to
deport his ass
while we were down there being Canadian
really helped me with my career because
no matter what we did down there it was
nothing compared to working up in this
[ __ ] I had the worst jobs you
could possibly have because I dropped
out of school soon as I smoked my first
joint I said [ __ ] this I haven't done
those school I became a roofer I became
a truck driver I've dug ditches for the
telephone company I had all the [ __ ]
jobs that you could possibly imagine and
so when I went down and find out that we
can make a buck being funny and smoking
weed and getting paid
that's what we did again
[Applause]
the Canadian it was a Canadian attitude
that got me right where I am today
because of the beat I couldn't do the
interviews all day today because of the
weed and they wanted to know you know
what my favorite screen is
I'm still looking for and then they
always say the read today's a lot later
than it was back then and I say no you
know back then and today is the same
thing only bad we is no way because you
don't have to smoke
it's all in your mind it affects the
brain and when I was in jail I never
smoked a joint I never touched it but
I've got high every night just thinking
about it because it does affects the
brain the Johnson for a week and you
don't have it just get quiet and
remember what it was like when you were
high and you go get that contact I it'll
come back to you it does to me all the
time anyway okay on the way here I try
to think of something special because of
the legalization so I started reading
this song I just got the last part of
the song done because it's the Canadian
anthem you know and I'd like to sing it
to you now
[Applause]
let's see if I can remember I just wrote
it so I sent free you said the state for
all the world to see
[Music]
[Applause]
we
this is post-prohibition
street dabs with what was your name
again with what was your name again with
Alice from Brazil and flash and [ __ ]
Johnny [ __ ] be 20 [ __ ] B oh my god
we were this is great this is great just
sitting on the side of the street
nobody's worried because
say hi to what some post-prohibition day
legalized it
keep fight the new slogan I'm perhaps
civil disobedience still practice love
the idea of the psilocybin mushroom
stores dueling gabs Johnny B is gonna
Chazz my bowl
[Music]
you're probably pretty good are you
hitting Redmont dabs we're here on
whatever Street with a couple of hot
dabbers here here here come on Johnny B
you got this
[Music]
all right