[Music]
we're good to go
boys
okay uh well first of all I want to
thank everyone for coming today I am
Marcus Bubble Man richon I'm here with
my partner Tony vura from United
cannabis and Blue River extracts and uh
I guess we're going to talk to you guys
a little bit today about uh the
glandular Tricom a little bit of the
science of the glandular Tricom I'm
hoping as I didn't bring a
presentation that you guys know what a
glandular Tricom looks like if you don't
pull out your phone go on to my
Instagram account BC bubbleman I have a
ton of them on there I take extremely
closeup macro photographs of these
glandular tricomes and in essence they
are the essential oil secreting glands
of cannabis that secrete all of the
phyto canabo as well as the turpine and
turpenoid profile that we of course know
and love all the smells and the tastes
and so I guess I'll give you a little
bit of a history how Tony and I came
together we share um a similar Vision in
quality and in standards I've been doing
the bubble bags for the last 17 years
teaching people how to extract their
resin glands using water and ice to a
99% glandular Tricom head ratio uh this
is the ratio you want to acquire your
medicine as it is it is the medicine of
the plant people ask me all the time why
don't you smoke the actual plant and I
say well the actual plant is is like a
carrier and it carries fiber it carries
cellulose it it carries essential oil uh
uh secreting glands it uh it produces
seed oil uh that is extremely rich in
essential amino acids and it produces
all these things generally from the one
from the whole if we want to make paper
we take the cellulose if we want to make
fiber we take uh clothing we take the
fiber uh if we want to use Medicine of
course we take the glandular Tricom head
and so it was really in my passion for
following the glandular Tricom head
teaching people how to isolate it that I
met Tony who's doing very similar things
uh to me but in a very different way
Tony was responsible for founding River
Rock in Colorado with his partner he's
no longer a part of that but he was a
big part of it and he created some
really incredible things during that
time the act now program which is the
activated canabo Therapy Program that he
does with his Proline teaching people to
micro do canabo suspended in tpin in
extremely small milligram Doses and
really teaching people how to saturate
the endoc canabo system rather than
guessing with an actual visual um map or
landscape that is created by empirical
data people feeding the data about their
sickness about the strains information
going back and forth into this program
created this digital landscape for
specific
cannaboid uh potencies and and levels
activated and non-activated to create
what what he's created which is The
Prana so it's really it was very much an
attraction for Tony and I to come
together um one of the things Tony
started doing in the last year which
really was a path he's been on for
several years but really sort of EXP
loaded uh in the hash Church Forum I
don't know if any of you watch hash
Church would like to see your hands if
you're a hash Church fan hash church is
a live YouTube show that we stream
weekly we get a thousand live viewers
watching uh maybe 15 to 20,000 in the
first week and it's really a forum of
radical openness where we share our
ideas and we discuss uh things about
cannabis in a way that is very open and
allows people to learn and be a part of
it it's an open source sort of a program
and that's that's really how Tony and I
got brought together Tony also
represents my brand uh the bubble man
brand uh down in California at
Harborside and maybe you want to give us
a little uh little Lowdown on how that's
going down there yeah I was uh just
wanted to say thank you for having me
the last time I was here I think it was
two years ago much different type of
conference this was a this other one was
more of a business conference so I'm
really glad to see the uh industry
progress as far as it has gotten um I
understand that everyone's is still
going through the three tiers LP
dispensaries and individuals uh all
having different types of uh
constitutional rights if you will here
and you're finding your way so I know
it's also a hard struggle when you're
doing that I've started with this plant
since
1996 and have been treated like a
criminal since um my background is I
started when I was in a couple car
accidents in '96 they uh prescribed the
wonderful Oxycodone to me
and uh I dropped about 150 lbs I
couldn't eat I couldn't sleep constantly
constipated and uh I started to smoke
cannabis I started to use it in Edibles
and uh was able to get myself off of
opiates and since '96 I have no longer
used anything not even a Tylenol uh for
my condition I was also in y thank you
appreciate that for those out there
using cannabis in substitute of opiates
it's 100% possible um there's quite a
bit of an illusion that goes on I don't
I don't um not subscribe to using
cocktails or pharmaceutical grade
cocktails when you're going through a
surgery back surgery you know a knee
surgery brain surgery heart surgery
probably don't want to smoke a joint
before you go to one of those surgeries
so there is uh there is a place in the
world for pharmaceutical types of
cocktails or drugs that they can use in
those small short window terms but in
the long term term uh use it's it's uh
something that's going to break down our
body and ultimately cause a lot of side
effects and a lot of other conditions
and organ failures you know all kinds of
things that will happen to us so in the
long run we have to search out for
something that's alternative something
that's homeopathic something that we
could turn to First exhaust all of those
things so diets Foods things that we put
into our body anything that you feel in
the essential oilbased world I feel that
we as as Society should exhaust those
first try the natural path and then
explore the other ones if you're dealing
with cancer you're dealing with um
life-threatening diseases and things
like that and ailments obviously I'm not
going to be the one that says uh to use
cannabis as an alternative uh for cancer
but we've have about 3,000 patients on
our current program we use uh a blended
version of um uh ratios that are
suspended in fatty acids and lipids and
with the tpin with the plant fats with
these cannabinoids in raw form in active
form we're able to do them and control
dosages from a milligram to to 50
milligrams in three different Delivery
Systems and we have plenty and plenty of
patients that are in remission I just
put up a story before I came here of a
leukemia uh cancer patient that didn't
have any chance whatsoever the doctor
said look we're experimenting at this
point you're going to die the kids uh uh
brought in our products in 3 weeks they
released the patient he's still in
remission today from November this
happens quite a bit with cannabis and
it's these bioessays and these
observational datas that we can't ignore
and so for four years I developed an EHR
electronic health record software a
platform that's free to patients um it's
supported through nurses and doctors and
scientists one of those scientists
actually was from Calgary uh discovered
stem cells in 1980
um and has is one of our lead scientists
and what we wanted to do was provide
products that were 100% plant-based that
utilized all of the turpine profiles
these cannabinoid profiles and delivered
it in a very uh pharmaceutical base but
taking as you say the farm out of
pharmaceutical and putting the farm back
in yeah taking the harm a pharmaceutical
is spelled phm if we take the harm out
of pharmaceutical and we spell the word
f a RM we can put the farm back in
Pharmaceuticals yeah so that's really
key and so you know both of our nations
are going through those Growing Pains
we've got 28 experiments going on as I
call them uh Colorado California Oregon
Seattle and the media and the news and
the PO politics they they are very
crafty in the way that they can finesse
the different messages that are out
there and the message is still the same
we're still dealing with prohib I and
we're still being treated like criminals
instead of patients and not only that I
I just want to interrupt for a second
Tony that it it hijacks the actual
medicinal component of the plant when
you you don't understand it the people
that are putting these these laws into
into play they don't understand where
the actual medicinal components of the
plant actually are so they're looking at
it much the way a Prohibition based
grower would have looked at it back in
the day which is how much can I get and
how fast can I get it and these aren't
really conducive thought patterns to a
medical program or even really a
preventative or in my opinion even a
good wreck program it's just not the
vibe for us to be coming from yeah and
when we talk about standards I my
background is engineering so I like to
break things down in
systems and I also like to relate them
to the end end use so as a patient I've
also been growing since '96 I stopped
growing six years ago because all of my
friends grow and they grow very well I
subscribe to sungrown uh live soil te
Brew everything that you can possibly
make organic because it kind of defeats
the purpose of using this product in a
chemical format I'm not against
hydrocarbons or CO2 or things like that
but this is where Marcus and I our bond
has really really came together was I
was first a patient I discovered
cannabis worked for me and then many
years later the United States said hey I
think we have an opportunity for people
to do this legally in a medical platform
so I became obsessed with how do I make
enough medicine to help other people
like me and I came uh across photographs
of these tricomes and so if you're
obsessed with your medicine you want to
see the details if you're an engineer
and so I started seeing these pictures
of these triome heads and I was like oh
my god there it is it's like a grae but
it's blown up you couldn't see them cuz
they were so small and I'm like who is
this guy and there's like these
unbelievable photograph s that I could
never do you can't do it with your phone
you can't do it with your camera and I'm
a I'm into photography so I'm like you
know exploring this and then I one day I
got a 2,000 micros 2000 Zoom microscope
and we cut a Tricom head in half and we
looked at it and that triome head
actually had a brain and it looked like
a whole bunch of like uh vessels inside
it like the human brain let's talk about
that a little bit yeah let's we got uh a
lot of you guys came to hear a little
bit of Science of the glandular Tri and
cannabis so we know that all of the
cannabinoids are biosynthesized inside
the glandular triome head as long as the
T as well as the Turpin and the
terpenoids there are six varieties of
tricomes I won't go through them all
right now but the three most popular
ones are the bulbus which are little
round balls that lay on the leaves
they're high in a different level of
cannabinoids than just THC and they
happen to be the the glandular head that
is responsible for oil yields being so
much higher uh than say water extraction
or dry sifting mechanical separation and
the reason is is because these heads are
so small they're attached to the leaf
they don't break the same way they don't
uh isolate the same way when using
mechanical separations or when using
water extraction which obviously freezes
the wax membrane and breaks the head the
density of the triome is still affected
by gravity due to its its density and
its oil makeup so it sinks while
everything else floats so inside this
glandular triome head we have we have uh
organal basically vac walls and plastids
they're two little Chambers inside the
head and they create phenols and tpes
and those phenols and tpin one in the
plastids one in the vacols they're all
different types of organal they push up
into the upper membrane and that's what
you would have seen when you cut that
Tricom in half that that fibrous mat is
where the phenols and the Turpin are
pushed up into the upper cuticle of the
glandular triome head and it's through
UVB light that the cannabinoids are
actually cooked into existence first
with CBG and then it goes from CBG on
through a variety of cannaboids CBN is
not produced by the cannabis plant it's
a biodegradable canabo when it when it
goes down and it starts falling apart
and degrading it turns into CBN but
cbn's not actually a a a canabo that you
will see in a living plant by testing so
just thought I'd lay a little bit of the
science on them maybe we could talk a
little bit about those Tes in there well
let's let's talk about the uh how those
are evolved so prohibition base based
growing methods I've done it we've all
done it we grow using metal highlights
or High Press sodium um we we you know
I've started and did three parts Hydro
System I did a drip system deep water
culture system I've done Aero aeroponics
how about aquaponics aquaponics get
right after Arrow I hope after AO and
then ultimately at the end of the day it
comes back to soil I know it's it's you
know everyone like tries to find ways to
get away from the Sun and away from soil
but I always tell everyone that's like
so you're raw you're vegan you eat
everything organic farm to table so how
many of those things were actually grown
indoors all your vegetables all the
things that you're eating that you're
putting into your body are you throwing
them in your closet are you growing your
micronutrients under just a shop light I
mean because then wouldn't that limit
the ability for that fruit or those
herbs or those vegetables to really
mature into what it's supposed to to do
which is really code it's code for what
we put into our body so when we put
these things into our body we either
have an interference pattern meaning
fats inflammations sugars glucose uh you
know whites breads rice all of these
different things that we put into our
body we're all different we all process
them differently and so if we don't Dr
Grow those herbs or those vegetables or
those nutrients to True Value and we try
to put them into our body we're cheating
ourselves yeah so if we all ate an
orange together and we peeled open the
orange and we didn't smell anything and
it didn't taste like an orange chances
are it doesn't have lyine and chances
are there's no vitamin C in it so what
are we doing we're eating a 3D printed
orange and you know why we're
carbohydrates and sugars what the hell
is that the reason we're doing it
is because we were duped by prohibition
we thought okay prohibition is bad but
we're going to do it anyway and what we
did was was we we fell into this
mentality where we would see how much we
could get and how fast we could get it
and we limited the cannabinoids and the
tpin that were being produced in these
plants and I guarantee you when we get
back to land race cultivars and we start
breeding the land race strains back into
our our our uh platform here we're going
to see canabo that we haven't seen in
decades and we're going to see tpin that
we haven't seen there's 140 plus Turpin
in the cannabis plant that can be
produced plus about another 40 that have
never been identified so that's close to
200 most Labs test for 12 to 24 tpin and
that's because only about 12 of them
repeat over and over and over again and
I can guarantee you that has so much to
do with the way we've grown cannabis
indoor under this prohibition mentality
yeah so if you look at that and I have
nothing against indoor growing
operations whatsoever there's plenty of
them that are good but we have to look
at what's being grown leaf or resin so
that's great if you grow three lbs a
plant but what was your resin content
that means hey right away if someone
tells me they grew three lounds of plant
I know they're growing for plant because
anyone that was growing for resin would
tell me they got 2 and 1/2 ounces of
resin not 3 lbs of plant correct are you
growing for resin the medicinal Compound
on your plant or are you growing for you
know to pay your mortgage and to pay
your car payments which is you know
unfortunately it's the situation we find
ourselves in right now with you know I'm
an act I come from an activist
standpoint I I fought for hemp to be
legalized and grown legally in my in my
province in Manitoba we got our first
hemp license in 1995 and have never
stopped growing it there I've been
deeply involved in this industry and uh
I just I think it's unfortunate to see
the way the legal mechanisms and the
illegal mechanisms are unable to
somehow meld together and work together
it's all this it's Health Canada in the
middle convincing dispensaries to hate
LPS and LPS to hate dispensaries and we
really really really need to stop doing
that because the only way to conquer a
people is to divide them and we do not
need to be divided LPS and dispensaries
are doing the same great job they're
giving access to patients and that's
something we need so I just wanted to
kind of say that a little outside of the
science version that's okay it all comes
together right absolutely so when you
look at I've grown we've grown uh in my
experience I would say 500 lb a month
for the
last I don't know I did that for like 6
years 300 lights indoors 20,000 square
foot in green houses and now as it's
evolving I'm getting more away from that
and just focusing on processing resin
into products because that's really
where my passion is but really when I
look at it and I pull the pull back and
I say okay what's really the best form
for this plant for growing the medicine
and the Turpin it's sungrown Greenhouse
all organic with supplemental lighting
that is the future of cannabis whether
you like it or not and the reason why is
because ultimately when you find
something that works and we produce a
medicine for people we have to get it
insured we have to do it on such a
massive level and we have to standardize
it and we need to do it organically and
so those things come together and that's
really what the what the key is and so
the best price per pound for your resin
is going to be in in a controlled
Greenhouse environment however that may
look and the reason why I subscribe to
that is because I'm looking at turine
profiles so our booth was set up today
with uh we had over I think 20 I've done
over 51 different tarpine profiles today
we had like 12 of them available I think
we're down to four but what this was is
capturing those essential oils and the
turpins from those tricomb heads and
doing them from flowers without any
solvents it's kind of like if you took
like a grape and you had to figure out
how to pop the grape and take the inside
out without any THC and you just wanted
to take the essence and without leaving
a footprint which is very very difficult
it's where the intellectual property
comes into play it's and it's you should
really sort of point out the difference
between the indoor grown Turpin versus
those sungrown Greenhouse tpin yeah so
what I've what I've just in my
experience is running a uh let's say you
run tpine extractions on flowers grown
Su grown tpine FL extractions grown
indoors big wide range so everything
I've grown in Sun grown
ACDC uh a cavello sour diesel um you
start pulling these profiles from the
outdoor strains we see 10 12 13 of the
tpin that are in the in the grid pattern
of the DNA if you will you can come the
booth and check these out if you want to
see got them all printed for you 6 so
you'll see like 10 12 13 11 you'll see
wide spectrums full spectrums of tping
you'll see eucalyptol you'll see loning
you'll see lenol you'll see pining
you'll see different types of pining and
each type of cultivar each type of
strain leaves a DNA in these tpin and so
we can we now have been testing the flow
the flower rosin the flower next to the
hash so you look at full Mount then we
press out the full Mount so we're able
to look at the full Mount and those
tpine profiles the rosin and those tpine
profiles and the tpin of the original
flowers next to the flowers so you can
compare kind of track all the way down
and when you do that you discover that
when you're growing indoor and you're
you you have to look at what your lights
are and you have to look at what you're
feeding so if you're growing in gavitas
or papies or you're growing under
hlc uh or
hplc high pressure sodium um if you're
growing under these different spectrums
these different spectrums are going to
allow that plant to express differently
exactly a perfect example of this is if
you understand lavender the herb where
is the best lavender grown people that
don't even know about lavender will
often see it on the package French
lavender there's a region in France
where lavender grows this incredible
turine profile it happens to do with how
high they are away from up from the
ocean you know it's all altitude and and
the the soil and it's all these
variables and it's a very important
thing to note and and before Tony gets
back to the tping I just want to explain
you guys in case some of you really are
more of a coming from a newb standpoint
like a newbie in all of this is that
phyto canabo um you know help regulate
our endoc canabo system which helps
regulate our biological functions we
have CB1 and CB2 receptors in our brain
and peripheral organs and depending on
the deficiency that our endoc canabo
system may use we can use a variety of
these uh canabo in different ratios
which is you know one more time to
reiterate and I I don't own shares in
this company uh I'm the the part the
part that I'm involved with United
cannabis is we are Partners in Jamaica
together but other than that everything
he does in America is his own thing and
uh it's not guessing they are not
guessing about ratios and seeing Oh try
this try this they are creating a
digital landscape with the act now
program and that is unbelievable it's
not a guess it's more like much more
accurate based because it's based on
actual evidence from people that suffer
from the same sickness and I just kind
of wanted to let people know a little
bit about that and realize why are we
extracting these tpin because about 12
years ago one of my mentors skunkman Sam
he uh acquired some pure cannabinoids
CBG CBD CBN and pure thca uh from a
laboratory in Amsterdam and we went over
to his place and he was like Hey you
know you got to try this out you can hit
this pure thca in a pipe and I hid it
and it was very one-dimensional very
heavy set heavy in my eyes not really
what I would call an enjoyable social
experience uh but then he said hey I
also have these pure tpes uh they're not
derived from Cannabis but they are pure
analytical tpin and there's delemon and
there's uh terpinolene and there's uh
pinene he had a four or five different
ones and he said why don't you now try
that thca but take one drop of this
turpine and this revelatory experience
occurred that we realized that the
modulating effects from Cannabis come
more from the tpine profiles than the
actual ratios of phyto can aboid so
while everyone's trying to sell you CBD
and and and different ratios of CBD and
THC we were more focused on what directs
those compounds because I understand
those compounds are the gas they make
you go but the Turpin are your steering
wheel and they direct that and when you
can induce an appetite or a different
medicinal component out of a plant that
otherwise didn't give you that by
modulating it with tpin that is some
next level go ahead yeah see if I
could tie that together to what he was
talking about cuz a lot of people
probably don't know what act now is so
we'll get to that but first how we're
breaking down these turpins was first
looking at them in Full Spectrum in
their cultivars comparing them and how
they're being made and I just saw a lot
of uh differences between Sun grown uh
Sun assisted versus say indoor
onedimensional type of light instead of
seeing 10 and 12 turpine profiles you
might say three or four or you might see
five only and it would be concentrated
on that and so uh this is a really
unexplored territory but what we've what
what's what it's led us to is saying
okay from what we know which has also
changed in the last three years most
people look at Cannabis sativa cannabis
indicia and hemp and so the vernacular
of that isn't really true so it's
afghanan in indic
drug type varieties and Cannabis sativa
is a hemp variety and this has been
something that's been changed as of the
last few years Robert Clark and
different individuals have uh expressed
their input on this and this is
important because drug cultivars meaning
things that produce resinous uh tricomes
is what we're talking about that carries
the tpin and hemp varieties lack the
sophistication of these turpine profiles
and so it's a part of their survival so
they're producing they're producing male
and female they're cross-pollinating and
their intentions are not driven in the
same secretions in the oils and they
definitely don't have the full profiles
of those tpin and so that also lack of
sophistication in my opinion in what
I've seen so far and the data is lacking
in in indoor indoor does a great job
raising THC levels um and you see spikes
of different types of cannabinoid CBG
thcv um and and spikes of CBD when
you're outside even CBG uh a and so all
of these types of cannabinoids are being
produced on these types of varieties and
the turpins that are involved in them
have to do with the genetics and so the
Breeders that are out there and good
breeders that know what they're doing
they're going to be breeding for turpine
profiles and they're going to be
breeding for resinous profiles exctly so
the what's happened is our world has
gone from smoking to concentrates or
extracts that then go into medicine and
those people that are making the
extracts are going to tell you uh what's
what what happened and so when somebody
says hey I grew this Sour Diesel outside
and you run it and you get an 8% yield
on flowers you go oh what happened and
they go what do you mean what happened
I'm like yeah I'm sorry did you have a
drought at uh week five to week seven
did something happen with uh your
phospherous cut out towards the end
right or you overfed or you had this and
I start breaking down what happened to
their crop from the footprint of the
tpine profile or from the footprint of
the resin that we extracted in in bubble
hash so it doesn't lie and so those
yields tell me what what's going on and
you collect that data and
ultimately you need to know how to
translate the data and so for for what
you call newbies and P and and patients
that are trying to find their way
hunting down strains and now hunting
down turpine profiles complicates the
process even more when you're looking
for results and so my engineer brain
decided to say okay let's create
categories five simple categories which
is P1 2 3 four and five and in those
categories we categorize them really
simply put P1 is going to be all of your
what everyone knows as Cannabis sativa
but that would be your Jacks and your
geran poisons your sour D's things with
high loning things with high tpine t
terpinolene uh beta beta caropine the
names are going to be the categories
only in the future patients need to know
and it was Chimera who mentioned this on
hash Church um that the constituents of
the plant what make up the plant or the
resin is going to be what the name is if
you're a patient you want to know what
Turpin you're getting you want to know
the ratio of cannabinoids I don't care
if you call it Jack Flash I want to know
what tpin and what cannaboids are in the
end product and that's definitely going
to be the future of cannabis names will
always be there but the true name in my
opinion is going to be the constituents
that make up what you're using medically
and why are cannabis cannabis Drive tpin
important well if we know there's 140
something of these can uh turpins and we
know there's an extra 30 out there that
are unknown and lavender is
one-dimensional so that flower produces
it produces one type of turpine really
well and cannabis being one of those
first plants on Earth that things
evolved from different species like Hops
and things like that they have vast
complex uh tpine profiles so this is
undiscovered chosen by us our noses that
chose those Tarin over thousands of
years it was this old factory that
smelled the ones we liked it wasn't the
plant looking a certain way that made us
like it I guarantee you if you go back a
thousand years it was our noses it was
the turpine profiles and some of those
tpine profiles are act as incent
repellants um some of those tpen act as
nutrients some of those uh tpine
profiles uh have different solvent they
can act as solvents but what's important
is to know where they where they belong
as far as classification so if beta
carene we know turns on CB2 receptor
that's really important because that's
really the gas for that particular
receptor and so if we know we're putting
10 Mig of CBD or 10 Mig of THC and we're
modulating with you know a particular
profile that has high beta uh caropine
then we know we're going to press that
then what is it carrying with us so does
it have mercine does does it have pining
and then how much cannaboids does it
have then we go a step further and we
say okay that's great so you're saying I
can eat tpin and I can eat this bud and
that's going to and that's going to
solve my problems absolutely not
necessarily but it's going to turn on
especially if you have that beta carry
offine you're going to turn on that CB2
receptor and when we talk about these
receptors some of the receptors are on
our brain in our central nervous system
and some of them in our peripheral
organs so if you've got a liver cancer
and you're turning on your CB1 receptors
that not not might be the ideal way for
you to go about saturating your endoc
canabo system because the CB2 receptors
are the ones you're going to need to
engage to get those cannabinoids to
communicate with those cells to produce
apoptosis to kill the mitochondria of
those cancerous cells uh Christina
Sanchez from the University of Madrid if
you want to write that name down she's
done some absolutely incredible work in
regards to apoptosis and and THC yeah so
absolutely there's individuals on this
planet that have inspired myself and
like Marcus you've got Sanchez you've
got Dr marzo uh that's International
canono research out of Italy um Mula all
of these people have been identifying
these receptors now what we know is
we've got like four of them on the board
but there's thousands of them and with
cannabis we've got this large spectrum
of turpins that are that are being
pinged and so we want to know what they
do and how they act we know what they do
in uh Foods vitamin A is a tpine we know
what that does to our body and and so
we're discovering these things in
cannabis and what's important is in the
beginning is put them into grids and so
the uh what Marcus is talking about this
evolved into what I call Advanced canabo
therapies so if you wanted to look it up
it's actnow
program.com and it's a free service for
patients in the US and since they didn't
do any insurance I just said it I
hate to Hate to use that kind of
language but at some point you get over
it and when it's a it it's a
it it's a it because at some point
you have to say how do we help people
and how do we follow up with them so I
created a program that's hippoc
compliant EHR software that has nurses
running it that tracks patients results
and you get free Consulting and we learn
how and and we teach you how to use
these different categories P1 through P5
with different type of ratios with
different types of full spectrum flour
and resin uh derived uh products they're
infused not extracted active and
non-active in raw form and in active
form form and some people would be like
why would you give me the raw form of
thca and cbda together well most doctors
and scientists they think that it has to
be activated so our Edibles RSO all of
these types of oils that we're putting
into our body in its activated form is
what they're thinking is actually
pinging the CB2 receptor so what happens
when you eat an edible a 10 milligram
edible it's a long chain uh and the way
and the way that works it get broken
down in your small intestin large and
goes through the liver and so if we're
eating it or if we're eating raw THC oil
or we're eating Edibles we have about a
95% loss in bioavailability so there's
5% bioavailability so if I'm eating a 10
migr edible it feels like .5 mgram and
so on our website that we put on there
we have not only the services and the
programs on there we have links to
scholar scholarly articles and
Publications cuz many patients are
always looking for proof Pro and
evidence in pancreatic cancer breast
cancer um id1 Gene peroration of THC so
I put all of the reports that I could
find out there the Entourage effect um
how Tarpin work with those things you
know the only thing I wanted to add is
Tony's saying a lot of stuff that some
of you may understand and some may not
when he says activated we're merely
talking about removing a carboxilic acid
ring from the thca molecule or the cbda
molecule all canabo come in acid form so
they they are THC a CBD a cbga a it's a
carboxilic acid ring that can be removed
with a certain amount of heat uh applied
so that's what he means by he uh
activated uh thca is obviously
non-activated but there's still
medicinal benefits and THC minus the
carboxilic acid ring is activated and
you're going to feel the effects when
you eat it when you put it on your skin
smoke a joint as soon as you light the
lighter you're activating it that's it
the fire activates it most of the most
of like most most people didn't
understand that uh Courtney was uh
christe no no no the uh the guy that
does the juicing oh uh William Courtney
William Courtney Dr William Courtney he
was a inspiration for me a while ago you
look at someone juicing leaves right and
juicing THC buds to get the thca so
William Courtney just to tell you a
quick little bit before Tony gets into
it is he had a 3 and 1 12month old baby
patient who was suffering with a brain
tumor the size of a small potato in her
head it was splitting the left and right
hemispheres of her brain and the the
chemotherapy was for sure going to kill
her and so they started juicing cannabis
and giving her cannabis and I guess it
wasis it was a couple of months two or
three months and they Shrunk the tumor
so far out of existence that they
decided that an MRI would be unnecessary
radiation for her so she's in remission
and has no tumor now it is amazing and I
want to say you know the reason we don't
hear doctors saying this is because
every doctor will tell you I cannot say
that they will lose their license if
they say that but the fact of the matter
is we as a people cannot ignore this
information and Tony and I won't lose
if we tell you that it can shrink
tumors that's right so we will so how so
then I said okay well everyone's a
little different and the patient story
that we did this guy was a uh in a VA
Hospital military completely against
cannabis his kids snuck in non-active 50
migr 3 to1 this is a leukemia patient
Yep this recent one and and activated
one to one and you know snuck that into
the Hospital 3 weeks later I I was
explaining went into remission I didn't
really want to film The Story So I
waited from November until last week to
film it just to make sure because you
know when somebody walks in extremely
ecstatic and happy and and like it's
shocking for us as well and so we want
to make sure that we have the that right
the right information um this this has
happened many many times hundreds of
times but you can't ignore this and so
what happens is you have to figure out
how how do you create how do you create
a use for that and so suspending it into
uh infusing it and suspending into fatty
acids and lipids allows for
bioavailability increased to 300 and
400% utilizing can cannabis tpin whether
you're using them in in in your rosin or
your hash or extracts and you're smoking
them or digesting them or using them in
sublinguals increases bioavailability
just like it does and oranges and every
kind of fruit vegetable and things that
we put into our body and so I feel like
the wave the next wave in the future of
of real medicine especially here is you
know figuring out how to uh you know
educate the the public first on that so
you've got breeders and you have farmers
and you know the wave of just breeding
CBD genetics it's kind of like ready for
the next chapter we need to breed CBD
genetics drug cultivars that Express
specific profiles of tpin so that we can
maximize the bioavailability in the
medicine that we're making so if the
government decides to restrict you to 30
Mig per capsule then you say man if I
was just eating a 30 milligram edible
chocolate bar I've lost 95% of that
medicine but if I'm eating a 30
milligram capsule uh like what we're
creating then you're getting an increase
in that bioavailability so we only use
10 20 mgram capsules and 50 MGR capsules
is our Max I personally don't eat the 50
MGR active capsules um because it feels
like 350 MGR and I don't do well with
Edibles so that's why I was very keen on
micro doing and after talking to our
scientists and different doctors when
you look at sublinguals and you say okay
I can give you 400 dosages in the power
of your fingertips at 1 milligram
dosages you look at canabo uh Pharma
kinetics that's done uh overseas in
Europe you realize that when somebody
eats it or somebody smokes it or they
use a sublingual you can see the
bioavailabilities but you could also see
how well it absorbs so Crossing into the
glandular underneath your tongue doctors
can subscribe to that they understand
that they're like okay I'm giving 1
milligram dosing I'm ad administering it
as a sublingual and I can work this way
up a new can a new cannabis patient
instead of jumping into a 500 mgram
magical brownie that's going to take him
onto a trip for two days and probably
they'll never use cannabis again we
start with one milligram with one unit
so if somebody says I have pain and you
that's all you have you just have pain
you have neurop neuropathy or pain you
don't have trouble sleeping no you don't
have IBS no you don't have tumors no you
just have pain well that tells us
category one thca if you're brand new to
cannabis and you're sensitive we go raw
and so by susp suspending this into
plant fat we're able to get the raw
cannaboids into the body just like with
the juicing that you were talking about
and building up a proper saturation if
someone needs a massive dose it's best
to build up to that to give someone a
gram of resin in one shot that's
especially if you're eating it there's
something that happens in the liver when
we consume cannabis it goes into our
stomach and then it metabolizes in our
liver and THC in particular metabolizes
is into a metabolite called 11 hydroxy
metabolite and it is extremely powerful
for anyone that thinks they've graduated
from Edibles because they've smoked a
joint they quickly learned that they did
not graduate from Edibles once they ate
that Brownie and they were like wow this
is a real serious thing so that's
another thing that could be very
uncomfortable for patients and it's why
it's one of the things I'm really stoked
about the The Prana and the act now is
that it's this this micro doing 1 mgram
drops under the tongue you know how much
that is most Edibles are 35 or 50 or 100
m milligram some are 250 some are 500
I've seen 1,000 mgram medibles those
will knock you out those are not really
what I would give to Grandma yeah and
they're just uh it's taxing on the body
you know so these are these are things
that we're coming and AD and you're
advancing and
so the the possibilities are really
unlimited in the sense of how you can
combine things so there's other studies
out are combining black tea with fatty
acids lipids cannabinoids tpin that
increases bioavailability so just think
about like how superfoods or if you look
at alkaline chart of foods and you say
Okay kale Himalayan uh salt um cayenne
pepper all of these things that are
considered superfoods are very high on
the alkaline and things that are
generally bad for us are very low and
acidic and so when you're dealing with
cancer and things like that we want to
lots of theories say cancer can't
survive in a high alkaline diet and all
of all of the uh all of the patients
that we we work with as well as myself
as I try to recommend that is say okay
let's strengthen our body and our and
our mind and our health to be as as good
as it can and you look at foods and it
works the same way and so when we when
we look at the future of that it's
saying okay we've got this wide spectrum
of tpin we've got this organic resin
we've got these uh categories and
putting them into suspended fats and
delivery methods and then the next
chapter to that is how do we incorporate
into the mainstream into other medicinal
Foods cuz that's really what
cannabinoids are they're medicinal Foods
yeah they're they're actually essential
they are essential if you understand
that essential amino acids are the
building blocks of endoc canabo the can
the cannabinoids that we produce
endogenously in our body that is why
they're called essential amino acids
because we need endoc canabo to survive
it regulates our endoc canab cannabinoid
system and in turn that system regulates
both our immune system and our central
nervous system it puts them into
homeostasis and so it's it's it's a very
important thing for people to learn I we
don't have much more time to talk I
really wanted to end it on um letting
you guys know to not be afraid to share
this information with anyone that you
know whether it's for a preventative
aspect a recreational someone that's
stressed out and needs to relax someone
that needs it for medicinal purposes
Don't Be Afraid like doctors are to to
share this information because it it's
the right thing to do and uh there's
nothing more important to a terminal
patient Than Hope and if you can give
hope to a terminal patient you've done a
great job thanks everyone for listening
I really appreciate it you make some
questions yeah we could hit maybe a few
questions but I want to make sure we
leave the time it's 350 you want a 10
minutes two questions we'll take so if
you want to brain trauma brain trauma
okay so that's a good one real quick so
difference between
CBD yeah so we created one called P5 so
that's all uh that's activated CBD with
ACDC tpin and so that tpine profile
modulating CBD and so that's when people
think of CBD think of anti-inflammatory
think of uh improving cognitive function
it's really good for brain trauma if you
wanted to pair that in a non-active you
would do like a 3:1 CBD to thca that'll
be the best for repairing cognitive
function and postbrain
Trauma so sleep problems that's our P4
so in large dosages we use CBD and CBN
so that combination of CBD and CBN is
really good for inducing sleep why
because when THC is degreg into CBN that
breaks down into a byproduct like Marcus
was talking about that's the ocular
feeling if some of you that are as old
as I am have ever smoked what was called
regs orag maybe the worst you ever had
in Canada was BC bud but in the United
States we had Mexican swag and that
stuff made my eyes go like this and it
and it put me into couch lock that's the
AL that is THC converting into CBN in a
longterm process on the plant after it's
dead and when you smoke it it's very
like sedative so what you could do for
yourself like if you weren't able to buy
these products is you could take a
coconut oil you could crock poot it you
could take a a high a heavy indicia
something that people are like oh this
is really like heavy you could make a a
nice extract with it and eat a
tablespoon or less right before bed and
you'd sleep like an absolute baby you
don't actually have to smoke it and
mostly for preventative and and the the
consumption of cannaboids orally to me
is one of the most important ways we can
take them in now if you have ocular
pressure nothing's going to beat smoking
one puff of a joint to reduce ocular
pressure instantly and that can avoid
blindness so I would never say to the
people that say we're never going to be
we're going to move away from uh the
medical aspect with smoke it's never
going to happen there's always going to
be people with Ms Parkinson's uh
glaucoma that can re relieve ocular
pressure and relieve uh Tremors
instantly after one or two Puffs so and
and a real quick tip so those that smoke
bongs you if you collected your reclaim
or you were able to get keth or you were
able to get your cooking hash if you
just threw it in an oven
250 and you did it for for a long
period of time like 9 days long periods
of time you never hear me say this on
hash church or anywhere but you can take
your ke and you can convert convert it
to CBN and so uh I've done full
conversions of ke into CBN with like 250
to 270 if you did it quickly like and
you were trying to cook it on a pan on
the stove it would go from being light
light brown then it would go to CH like
a chocolate coffee ground kind of color
and it would get really dark you could
do that with a coconut oil now you have
CBN and then if you went and got
CBD right if you could get access to CBD
then you can combine the two and that
would be really good for using that for
sleep you guys can check us out at booth
number 627 Bubble Man brand in Blue
River and please check us out on hash
Church live every Sunday at 9:00 a.m. to
1:00 p.m. West Coast time thank you
everyone all right let's