[Music]
hey welcome everybody to bubble man's
world I am here today just for a short
little video got the m1 all turned on
and up and I'm gonna press a little Ross
and have him pressed a little rosin for
a bit figured I would share a little
video of doing that and 19 to 20 grams
of some I guess I would call it between
a three and a four star there's a melt
to it it's Lindsay oh gee it's very
potent and it should squished rather
well the growers well-known and he
generally produces a lovely variety of
resin heads now he does mix a lot of his
hash so this hash isn't one micron it's
probably gonna be 45 all the way up to
120 and generally if you look close
enough you can usually see that there's
there's some variety in there but too
sure if you guys can see that but I have
a feeling like that we should maybe
press it up what do you guys say shall
we weigh it out on the scale here real
quick and get it pressed I grabbed a
business card got the business card
alright I find this just the easiest way
when loading the resin into your screen
it's a simple thing like that gives you
the ability to to pouch up to kind of
dig right in and drop it right down I
suspect we're gonna get a good I don't
know maybe 10 grams of this pressed in
one shot so we'll see what happens the
largest amount I've ever pressed a
bubble for those interested was a 40
gram chunk that I did some time ago d
for 20 K might have been there it's hard
for me to remember exactly but it was a
big Prats I actually did it in the
original D nail press as well and got a
decent return
you know with these presses I hear
people constantly saying Oh get this one
get this one get that one you know get
one that you feel is you know for me
it's a whole it's a whole thing I love
the customer service that I get from the
Sasquatch people that's a big part of
where I'm gonna use mice mice my where
I'm gonna put my money I like the fact
that the unit is really well made and
works really well
now I constantly hear from people who
tell me oh you know you should get this
one you should get this one and I asked
them well what does it do that's better
is it getting a bigger extraction is it
preserving the flavors and the terpenes
is it doing it faster because those
three things let's be honest would be
the only three things that could
potentially well that is one smidge
under ten grams so we're gonna do a ten
grammar get that little bit in there oh
yeah ten point Oh ten point Ellen we're
gonna show you all right so we got ten
point Oh on the screen very well
generally what we'll do now is we'll
figure out getting the hash into all of
the corners you don't want to let those
corners in any way shape or form get to
have hollow little holes you want them
to be full full full so and then a
little bit of a pre-press is never a bad
idea at all all right okie dokie well I
got my little packet here Maebh tiny
little bit of air in the in the corner
there that's I could probably do a
little better with but there we go
pretty excited about this little squish
I'm not gonna lie we've got everything
pretty much set up on the unit here
all right I'm gonna have this put up
here yes down here this could be serious
get a serious squish going on here I'm
using the hand pump which is the SPX
power team right here you can see how
effective it is as a lowering or down
and then I guess what I'd like to do as
well as maybe just push that in a tiny
bit all right so I got the temperature
turned up a little bit
220 sometimes they do a 180 a 190 or 200
this is fairly warm for hash but we're
gonna get a full full extraction from it
so without further ado why don't we so
you know that the first little sort of
pre-press trying to see that I actually
gonna put you guys into a better
position here so you can really see
what's going on
all right we're bubbling up a storm here
people all right beautiful the hash
feels completely empty I can't even tell
you what this bag feels it feels like
there's just nothing left in it
all right so I've got a nice return here
clearly we've got a beautiful squish
looks great always happy to squish hash
you can see the way it just squishes out
that was the warmest I've squished in a
while it'll be interesting to see what
kind of flavor profile we get off this
and I guess what we need to do now is
grab a dabber and start collecting
sitting back so there we go that's what
we got right there a little bit of rosin
so let's put it on the parchment let's
find out what we got here
any takers for grams we got four grams
out of the first press not bad at all I
doubt there's much left but for the sake
of testing why don't we just take this
little guy and flip them in upside you
know give one of these a little bit
sticky little bit of schtick we'll just
give it another another little press
[Music]
right away which is always a good sign
yes starting to squeeze out a little bit
more I suspect we're gonna get that gram
plus that's gonna bump us over the 50%
range we'll see what happens
always good to do a second run for this
very reason alone you never know what
you're gonna get out of it
and I keep them separate obviously my
first and my second press always get
kept secret separately oh it's coming
out the sides of the press as well so
it's a good press right a quick short
press for that what I think and what
have we got here I guess it wasn't MP I
guess it wasn't empty holy [ __ ] that's a
real nice press right there so without
further ado let's collect it all right
so we got another little rock of rosin
from that so we shall throw that on the
scale let's see what kind of return
we're getting I'm feeling pretty good
that we're well about 50% I'll tell you
that much all right you see the lovely
color too when you get it thin enough
darker when it fit when it gets into one
chunk but it's dark ash as well so all
right so we got one point six for the
first one three point nine five point
five we got fifty five percent returns
oh she wrote I guess I could put this in
a little let me get this disc top for
you I think it's worth it
that's crazy
look at that there's your color right
there oh snap
time to put that bat away in the freezer
and get it sorted all right so we
managed to get that Lynsey og disk
pressed out it's got that amber hashey
kind of color it's it's you know it's
obviously been heated up a little bit
more but man I'll tell you the Terps are
on point no burnt popcorn smell it's
incredible how warm you can actually
press some of this stuff and I you know
generally when I do a first press and
I've got a lot of something I'll press
it pretty hot like a 210 220 and that
will let me know exactly what my yield
is what's actually there to get and from
there I can go back down and decide okay
right now we're gonna do a press
actually and we're gonna press at 205
and you know I'll keep going down to 195
to 180 once I have all the different
varieties of hash truly only then will I
be able to decide which one I prefer for
that particular cultivar because believe
it or not there are some cultivars that
are so terpene rich that the excess heat
it just changes it up a little bit it
activates a little bit of the THC it
keeps some of it not active and once
again it just produces another wonderful
thing for our quiver so when you're out
there trying to lock yourself into a one
or another mentality remember that it's
a quiver and you can do as many
different options as you like so don't
forget that that's our second chunk of
rosin but got another little batch here
to press this one is a seven gram or so
chunk and it's pretty pretty solid I've
been pressing it in my fingers here to
get it going but I think we're gonna
just have to wait for this timer so once
the timer's done we'll go we'll go for
it you know I figured while we were
waiting I could hit a little bit of this
second give me an idea what this is all
about this Lim's EOG focus there we go
there we go it's focusing on the wrong
thing it's all good let's check out this
you can see as we get it into strings
it's a much nicer color almost that
really golden you know trippy I don't
know if you guys have seen this with
rosin but it does this really kind of
cool well that was kind of fun I got my
dab on the lens man I got that dab on
the lens
all right well listen the temperature is
almost down I figure it's about that
time for us to take any little rip in
the ball let's check it out it is
Lindsay Wow I will tell you it's like a
champ we will put this in here and get
you guys a little bit of a better view
was that better yeah Pachi yeah pretty
close to the edge hopefully we don't get
any push out we will see let's get into
it it's wanting to push it out I can
tell I think we're gonna maintain now as
long as we don't blow out we'll be
laughing of course the worry of a
blowout is putting the pouch too close
and then what happens is it gets pinched
between the edges of the press so always
a good idea to be careful and wary of
that as you're applying more pressure
nice and gently great color on this
seven grand press so it's gonna be a
little bit less than last time obviously
my fat head out of the way and maybe
we'll get a nice a nice view of this
press it's coming out all around that's
for sure at the minute and thirty second
point just let it let it come out this
is a substantially cooler 15 degrees
cooler than the last press and you can
see a little bit of it in the color for
sure that's swirly beautiful mess clear
domes missus Bob went out
[Music]
although so you can see they're a nice
fat press rosin hair there but yeah nice
fat press let's pick it up and see what
we got
very nice once again picked up quite
lovely
that's rosin where
really nice it's pretty sweet roses 3
grams so once again just under 50% on
the first press what happens when we
take it and we press it again it should
squeeze nice for us oh look at that
she's flowing just a matter of looking
away for a little bit
laying around with a nice gold cube of
rosin oh yeah damn here push that up
against the screen - you know what I got
them - down with this one - this one
just looks absolutely delicious let's
just do a little dab of that one show it
just a little one all right
all right feels a little bit dryer ever
getting another little bit off of our
second press not quite as much as we
thought up that second press in the
first batch but you know definitely
worth collecting nonetheless pretty
stoked got jeez must have gotten like
five and a half eight about nine grams
and we pressed out about maybe 17 grams
so definitely stoked on that I think my
friends gonna be pretty happy and thanks
for watching everybody
[Music]
you