[Music]
all right Tony and bubble man here we
are
over the grill for the last few days it
was pretty awesome dude yeah it was so
uh yeah we're we've hooked up with the
nomads we're just doing a little car
rearranging ev's over
there um birdy's in the Mercedes here
just moving we're going to follow them
to Kingston as the show was good last
night huh do they think they play killer
actually play killer there was a couple
moments where uh there was like some
celebrity action going on old schoolers
there really was yeah totally after the
nomads Bongo Herman came out he invited
up uh um Lee Scratch Perry which was
awesome really good photo shoot they did
with the nomads and and Lee and then
Andrew Tosh came up afterwards man like
man he was he was killing it too like he
really grew up and kind of became very
Peter esque I was impressed with the
music and whatnot so we're uh we're
going to have a little adventure with
the nomads and we'll bring you guys
along actually for the uh oh yeah
tonight is uh prot's uh CD release album
I'm not sure the name of the album hey
do you know the name of prot's album
that's releasing tonight Ancient Future
ancient oh it is Ancient Future Ancient
Future Ancient Future so the Ancient
Future now what is
that acient has to do with the past
future has to do with the future the
future so right in between there
that's some beautiful words they find to
put together you cuz he creating AG ient
future you know that future that brings
you
back but in the
know makes you feel so ahead you know
what I mean Wicked oh all right Asian F
yeah
yeah all right so heading out of neg
Grill here following the nomads we're
just in the last strip which is uh
mostly just monstrous hotels like
sandals and uh these types of resorts
here's sandal right here big monster
entrances mostly all inclusives down
here going very
quiet oh I was just sorry about that
mention we're still driving
back all right we're here in Runaway Bay
just about 40 minutes past uh Montego
Bay on our way to Kingston I think we've
already been through St an can't barely
remember if not we'll be turning in soon
I haven't done this drive too many times
myself I usually fly in either to
Kingston when I'm going to Kingston or
fly into Mo Bay if I'm going in NE gril
or the other side of the island but uh
oh well this is more of a reality as we
come here more and more for crd and
Yukan getting more things done in the in
the business aspect we need to have cars
we need to do driving and it's not like
we're really here for tourist trip so
although that'll be in the future too
it's exciting times here in Jamaica
telling you it was amazing at the
stepping High Festival to have all those
ganja plants fully budded
on the stage I don't even see that in
Amsterdam at the Canabis
cup
so all right still driving still heading
to Kingston still excited about the
Protege CD release party today that's
Ancient Future it's a dichotomous name
how Protege makes the future ancient
while we're going to learn tonight and
uh we're just actually going on a detour
to the highway you can see a part of it
up there uh we're driving through a
small little town very tight Road got
some big trucks in the way and we have
not lost the nomads Evie and birdy are
still in front of us doing their thing
we got dabbed up in the grill before we
left but we haven't dabbed since so uh
it'll be good to get back to back to
Kingston and get the uh denail going
we're low on dabs but what we suspect
we're going to do for the next couple of
days rather than uh not have dabs is is
uh get a nice steam chalice and uh
probably we should have two or three of
those over at our buddy's house anyway
and uh have a nice chalice session I got
to admit I got a really nice um head
Buzz head rocker bell ringer if you will
from hitting those Vapor chalises last
night obviously you're not getting the
concentrated hit it's a much lighter
tasty sort of fluid hit but what you got
to do is you got
to right so you're getting it going
you're getting it going you're getting
it going and uh eventually once it
finally gets going you get these hits
but you get this Li headed almost like
you're going to fall down like you've
been hyperventilating so that's part of
the The Vapor chalice
experience and this is the country right
here
this is just some beautiful [ __ ] right
here you know oh yeah so nice look at
the tree
monster yeah I got
that yeah that's what I love about that
wide angle lens
man gives you that little extra bit that
you don't have to really pan over to
get much wider frame
[Laughter]
plaining
it a nice Highway finally on this is the
Spanish Town Toll Highway so we got to
pay for this highway couple hundred JS
up at the toll as we get closer into
Spanish town but this will whip Us in
now in probably under a half an hour
until we reach traffic which maybe will
be 15 20 minutes depending on the time
that we're rolling look how beautiful
the countryside is that's absolutely
beautiful they're putting a highway
right through the center of these
mountains
pretty
incredible that semi is still like
flying behind us going like 100 130
right
now going 140 right now 140 is in your
blind
spot holy [ __ ] can't even see him
through there dude that's
insane 140 km that's what we're driving
look that gu show the the
speedometer 140 and that truck is behind
us man he was speeding up to pass he's
got his lights on now coming after you I
see flashing his lights yeah that's the
was it police officer TOS Drive semis
here in
Jamaica let's see if I can get
him he's got some kind of he's got his
sirens on let's see if I can get
him yep you're having fun here in
Jamaica people lots of he's got his
lights
on yeah
perfect some quality footage you get in
there I'll be editing that transition in
for
sure Bubble Man decided to pass our our
escort it's pretty funny they they come
here comes bird eye
[ __ ] passing you and
[Applause]
[ __ ] flat Bridge man
f a bunch of people just like dude you
just hit that little kid so hard dude
he'll be
fine someone's just got to lift him off
the
back just
epic up the mountain going to the
[Music]
you know what the best part is we're
driving on these streets right
screeching our Wheels not really driving
like maniacs by any means but you never
see the like ladies with little kids
give you dirty looks no you
know it's quite
something driving here is quite
something ding here is quite
something a long
I thought it was going to open
up oh Jesus that was awesome some of
that footage will just be
great holy [ __ ] this footage I usually
just grab very and short piece of yeah
just to show behind the scenes and [ __ ]
following our
buddies we are deeply in uh sun shining
out the cloud
bro some Paradise [ __ ] right
did you ever grab your air air iron last
night yep straightener of course right
when I go to do that I got no Tre might
be cool
looking yep look at
[Music]
it
[ __ ] I I love that you're laughing about
it like it's just oh that was so funny
you almost broke my left arm how many
times we almost run off the [ __ ] road
imagine the mountain just comes into the
car and breaks your arm I'm sorry man we
we've gone off the road three times just
three times it's not uh it's not a lot
driving through Jamaica is slightly
traumatic it's not quite as traumatic as
snowmobiling in the mountains but it's
up there for sure
4 hours of intense race car driving yeah
how long been how long have we been
doing this for um 4 and 1/2 hours today
in the new we leave at
2 we left at early 2 we left early it
was close to 2 2:00 so now it's
4:50 yeah it's a little later than that
I think no it's 550 sorry yeah so that's
4 hours 4 hours we're almost back 4
hours we should be in Kingston here real
soon but what'll happen is we'll be
driving for another half hour and then
we'll get into traffic when we finally
get into Kingston and that'll be another
half hour and we'll actually be back at
7:00 which is fine cuz it's just in time
for the 8:00 door open door opening atas
prot and the indignation ban which which
really won't start till 9: I'm hoping on
getting an interview with Protege I'm
going to see if I can't uh pull him
aside for a few minutes and do a little
interview ask him about what's been
going on since the 8-year Affair since
his release party at the Ed theal Edam
Manley School of Music here in Kingston
that I was uh present for and now this
is Ancient Future so it'll be it'll be
nice to see the growth of the band over
the last 3 years during the reggae
Revival your back AR Kingston in the
background all right so we're pulling
into Kingston here you guys can see
Uptown just above Kingston coming down
Blue Mountains in the background
Caribbean
Sea yeah this is good we're at the magic
hour here as photographers know the
magic hour is right as the
sunsets sunsets in Jamaica at 609 and it
is
609 you did hit the side of the car on
the mountain just now I think it was the
uh
tree it's been a crazy ride but hey you
know what this one's paved they did a
great job actually yeah relatively not
too many potholes those are the real
kind of stop you dead when you hit a
pothole and pop your tire
yeah the flow is a lot better on this uh
route yeah now we're not talking about
the flow OG we're just talking about the
flow of traffic yeah we're almost back
can't wait for this
show stoked
[Music]
[Applause]
Exile come on stoked for
[Music]
this you
out in this
Jungle everything
I enter my
soul about to protect my
own protect my own I will protect my
own protect my own
[Music]
so really know here for the music so
quick track to his criminal this is the
first rhm winter senent to me that
started the whole project I heard it and
knew that all right this you have some
serious production skills so we can do
some work together the this song I wrote
right off the butat right away I was
thinking about Walter Rodney you know
visions of Peter Tash murder in um
September 11 1987 talking about dty
Bookman in there and his revolution in
Haiti talking about the fact that the
band Walter Rodney from Jamaica just
channeling all these energies you know
going up you know against the real
criminals what are um in a in in the
world right now not just the people who
[Music]