[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
pretty stoked to be bubble man today I
just got in the mail which I'm guessing
from the size and weight this package
and then I'm expecting a package from
Lush an LED 2XL Dominator haven't opened
it up yet but am totally
eager cut the
tape oh
yeah right off so it's not attached love
the packaging on this seriously
sturdy so I've never grown with an LED
light this will be my first time I have
a brand new tent 8 4 that John and I
just put together the other day it's got
a single HPS light in it right now sorry
metal highlight I'm vegging and I'm
about to flip that to an HPS drop this
Lush in see what I can start uh getting
accomplished I know very little about
the Lush lighting so I'll be learning uh
as I go along and sharing what I learn
with you guys and uh yeah just pretty
much
stoked 2 * XL Dominator is 200,000
lumens which is a comp compared to a
1,000 wat HPS is
145,000 uh you got 3 point EV for
voltage power for 2,000 extremely
intense 650 watt agricultural LED grow
light for all stages of plant growth
double lens providing up to 7 70,000
lumens and 1,000 Yoles at canopy level 2
in away I've heard a bunch of different
things I'm going to be careful with my
canopy level I don't want to
burn um looks like it's got a ton of
Lifetime hours it shows exactly how to
set it up up uh for hanging it's pretty
cool I got to say I'm looking forward to
following the proper instructions um
I'll probably hang this tonight I'm not
sure if I'll video the actual hanging of
it we'll see what happens um this is
just the light spectrum that it has um
giving you in regards to the LED
lighting and then it also came with a
chief green bud so it looks like some
music smoke as much as you like the drug
bust swag puff puff pass a friend with
weed in 420 somewhere so I'll listen to
those 420 friendly songs I want to thank
you guys from Lush for you know putting
your belief in me that I would be
willing uh to be uh not willing but that
I would be able to you know do you guys
Justice uh review your product honestly
and huge shout out to Kingston herb uh
Facebook pal bubble Ambassador for
putting all this really together with
the Lush folks and really for showing me
the first herbs that I saw grown with an
LED light that even made me want to
consider doing it so without further
Ado man I really like the uh the
packaging on this is
incredible absolutely incredible here
going to take
this off to the side so we can turn this
around for you and show you how
beautiful this is check this bad boy out
now that my friends is a light bulb 1
two 3 4 5 6 * 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
13 14
15 damn
50 as I got to about 36 I realized
they're all numbered each row so 50 rows
of six to eight six lights that's 300
lights that are in this little bad boy
they look super top quality they're tiny
little diodes
um sort of melted right into the metal
there plus and minus I'm really looking
forward to trying this bad boy out I'm
going to take it over to the tent change
the camera setup and uh let's get to
that right
now okay so I now in the tent little bit
tight in here I've got the two times XL
Dominator this thing weighs serious
weight it'll be by far the heaviest
thing I've ever hung in a tent like this
we're going to make sure that it's
secure got these great little units
right here that they come with which are
quite
convenient nice strong cable and they
set it up kind of no brainer style for
you I guess it's two on each
side let's see what we got here oh let's
get this somewhat upside down here all
right so this is a simple as you got
your
Carabiner and we're going to hook up two
on each
side really nice built units you know
they really feel like something you
really got something with this
unit which is uh saying something these
days all right so we drop those in there
there's two on either side and there's
three sets of them so they give you
three of these little
bags this is great you know especially
with a light like this
you don't want to leave it to chance
that people are going to Jerry rig their
own sort of
method oh it's my little ballast that I
still got going on I usually try to shut
down all the fans while I'm filming I
could hear the fan going and I was
wondering hm what is that now I
know
okay and I can't tell you how excited I
am to get this thing up and hanging and
lit
up seems like everyone's on the LED
train these days now I'm not looking to
replace all my crops with LED but in the
least I like the idea of having an LED
tent or even better I like the idea of
having a full spectrum tent LED metal
highlight high pressure sodium how cool
would that be I am not going to listen
to anyone's experiences but my own and
I'm going to play around and I'm going
to experiment and that's going to
involve different forms of lights no
problem now you've got the hours of
operation use this track to track the
light span of your fixture so it has a
start date that you're supposed to write
down and then you can use your hours
used
that's interesting I'm going to try and
keep a nice little journal with this guy
so let's see what we got here it's going
to be Superman styles to hang this guy
now all right and I think this one will
hang on the other
one okay and those are still hanging
good okay there we
go
exciting and this has got the power I
might need a tiny little extension cord
depending on how long this is going to
be oh no looks like we'll be okay so
it's a three pin
plug definitely haven't seen one like
this before has a little slot so it can
only go in the one way if you're
plugging in one of these for the first
time make sure you pay attention to that
that little
slot would be a good thing to pay
attention
to I kind of like to have this out of
the way there but we'll see what
happens
[Music]
there we go I think that's a little bit
more even and I can just
uh possibly tie that up to keep that
secure we just worried about the one bar
here it's a little bit lower it looks
like it's pretty secure but you know to
have the double bar connection I'm going
to get a little bit of tape and we're
going to tie that all right even
better let's get this guy turned on
let's zap strap it or Zippy strap as
Johnny B likes to say do a little Zippy
strapping there we go oh would you look
at that isn't that just a lovely looking
thing all right I'm going to get out of
here move my box little rundown on
that so here is the LED
light looking oh so colorful and Shining
down onto these
plants and then over
here we've got the
metal H for now it's going to be turned
into a high press sodium a little bit
later here let's get these a little
closer I'd love them to be in both
ranges LED and High Press
sodium so this is it guys this is the
beginning of my experiment with my
second tent uh we're at June 18th today
June 18th and everything's in I might do
a little bit of vegging for another few
days and flip them right before I leave
for Jamaica which is on the 24th so yeah
we're going to give these guys another
week I'm going to veg them up nice and
good and we'll see how it goes remember
this is my sweet skunk congales and East
Coast Sour Diesel so these are sativa
hybrid this tent here and uh HPS versus
LED thanks again to the people at Lush
for taking care of me thanks to Crystal
Mountain for taking care of me with the
Nano Lux and the secret jarden tents and
thanks for my Green Planet taking care
of me with the medy one that's my food
that's the one I use so keep watching
Bubble man's world this is the beginning
of great things you're going to see a
lot of nice sativas go through this tent
and if you have a favorite sativa that
you think I should be rocking through my
tent let me know what it is and I might
search it out thanks for watching Bubble
man's
world
[Music]
oh