[Music]
[Applause]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my open while the sun was up in my face
the wisdom of the wi keep my head
straight with that sweet
[Music]
try to Perfection smoke syn I love
the we get the
fulling I love
the I when the rest consume the
meditation to CB1 and
CB2 can n receptors in the brain and
body happiness for me and you you got
the T
[Music]
the get me the
fin try to Perfection spoke synic I love
the
stre we get
theing I love the
stre Mr m e d i c a l Medical canab
[Music]
m e d i c a
n can can make it better I can without
the let's up many many and then we to
all thean
farm
Comey try to
Perfection City I love
the we get the
fulling I
[Music]
love
s s
[Music]
s