hey guys bubble man here and I am at
Remo the urban grower absolutely
spectacular indoor grow where the guy
pulls 2 and three lbs off of a single
plant indoors I'm here doing macro
photography going to share a little bit
of the goodness with you guys today um
yeah this is just a little tease video
to let you guys know I'm sorry about
puff Wednesday I totally flailed
yesterday um it was my father's birthday
he's been uh passed away now for 9 and
1/2 years uh in a motorcycle accident
and so I was just bummed out after I
found that out and that it was his
birthday so I kind of just ended up
spending the day chilling out with my
family and my my kids and stuff but uh
I'm back at it today we'll have puff
Wednesday for you next week and for for
now I'm going to get on macro
photographing and doing a couple videos
with Remo so stay tuned on both his
channel and mine for more great cannabis
content see you guys
soon