[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
I'm here with Dee 420k sitting in
beautiful lions baby sea and we're about
to get it done today aren't we yeah
we're gonna we were playing around a
little bit yesterday we kind of filmed a
little bit of a video but my neck was
completely tweaked out slept on at the
wrong way and we ended up having to kind
of I had to just put the video on hold
and say another time so this is our
second attempt at it yeah we made some
nice rosin yesterday I know we did there
was it's nice hey you know we did it's
pretty sticky right you gotta hit it in
the freezer a bit but so I kind of
thought after doing what we did
yesterday I thought of the idea of
wouldn't it be cool to show people
pressing hash pressing rosin out of hash
but in more than a gram or two of an
amount so we don't have the industrial
presses we're not even actually doing
the teabag folding yet we're still doing
the original Jeff Church wrapping a
little bit of hash you know maybe like
less than a half gram into a ball and
then squeezing that out
onto parchment paper and we were going
to see how long it takes us to do an
ounce of rosin yeah see what we get out
of it yeah so I've got a couple of
ounces of some pretty darn nice oh wow
so that's powdered bubble right there I
found because finally when you brought
it over yeah oh my goodness just from
sitting in the Sun night Wow work with
at least a it should be easy to work
with so basically what we're gonna do is
take you through this you can see here
on the scale I've got just under 2
ounces fifty five point six fifty five
point eight grams
it's very nice bubble that presses
between the fingers quite beautifully
and bubbles and melts and nicely in a
bowl or on the nail but today we're
going to uh we're gonna press it up so
do you want to just kind of get started
make sure you don't contaminate yeah
okay yeah we got our pads here for once
yep we've got our tools we're short on
table doubles so we're gonna use these
for Davin here they torch a clean and
then carry on because we don't want to
contaminate the rows with anything and
in this color I need darkness or
anything cuz it just take away the
beautiful of it it's true
well footwell cheers bro I need to grab
my dad sorry you're go ring they're
hopeless right there I think the whole
thing if you want we got the whole thing
there okay thanks buddy
Cheers ting don't try that at home
so I'm hitting off the titanium D nail I
believe it's a highly educated with a
sapphire insert I've got the crystal
quartz 14-inch insert 20 on the ball B
beautiful
well it seems it seems to be I'm only
gonna turn mine on a little bit
differently I'm using a very small unit
so I also want to show you today that
you don't need industrial units that you
don't need the biggest tools to still be
able to press a decent amount of rosin
and that's kind of what we wanted to
show you here
now obviously Darren's about the bigger
tool so he'd probably be able to press a
little bit of a bigger piece and get
more out of it I'm using quite a small
tool but I bet you we still get this
done within a half an hour no I don't
think so
all right well I guess we're just I
can't believe this Wow ve a beautiful
see I'm just doing small amounts half to
four 2/3 of a gram you can tell when
you're squeezing it when you're not
getting anything out of it anymore
[Music]
all right making rosin
come on takes a little bit of a maybe
like less than a minute to heat up
I usually still do a bit of a press I
find that just gears it up for a a good
proper pressing we've got some nice SAP
you sure here that one this little ball
of baby I'm sure that's not gonna you
always wanted to produce a little more
don't you go what are you going to chuck
because it usually does it sure can
yeah that one just squeezed out a little
bit more fire mostly it's gonna be me
and Darren shooting the [ __ ] they're
gonna rip every once in a while and get
as much of this work done as possible
it's slow yeah it's fairly consistent
work so as long as you're
[Music]
it's sure nice when you've got great
quality resin to work with I think it's
another reason to probably what you can
hold back on the temperature a little
bit because the
[Music]
good fun making rasen with your buddies
out on your deck was that cool down for
that
that looks mushy to you notice any
difference yes the color my last sheet
you had was literally like dark orange
compared to that looks like water she
wasn't steady I'll just look this is the
sketchiest I go out where I actually was
holding it I've seen that and that's red
so I don't think it's what makes sense
that that heat is going to affect the
resin and the degradation of the
cannabinoids we know that THC degrades
into CBN from CBN in there oh yeah when
it comes off in a huge crazy sheet sheet
about death holy sheet so I know there's
a couple of products soon to hit the
market there's the rasa nadir which is a
pneumatic press I believe and then he
now also has a product coming out as
well so I'll be able to do reviews of
both those products and I thought before
they got here
I thought what better way to show
without rushing just the speed of what a
couple of guys can do sitting down and
pressing out some nice resin just with a
couple of you know a really small hair
strainer and a large hair straightener
globs
as producing globs ladies and gentlemen
blobs
it's amazing how after I turn this thing
off it stays hot for like I'd say five
or ten minutes I think just enough time
for me to take a big Ripple's nothing
that we made though it's the freshy yeah
that's all right I'm hitting this on the
sapphire disk love this thing
that was lovely so yeah like I was
saying the D mail unit and the rasa
nadir unit I probably should have within
the next couple of weeks and we'll come
back and we'll show you just how fast
you can press out an ounce of rosin with
an industrial pneumatic press compared
to you know these small little units but
I really wanted to show you guys I mean
you can see right here right said I've
already trust a decent tiny amount oh
wait I don't real quick must be a few
grams here anyway it's like 0.6 of a
grandma probably not hard to believe
that looks like a lot of rosin you know
what these all these things are
different way that probably maybe a gram
we're getting there 28 times more to go
you got another little bit there and as
soon as this lets me i'll get it going
yields are just yet
they seem fairly decent just keep adding
them to this to this sheet
so easy to clean off the pail it easy to
clean on forever
they're small
somewhat easy before I do that I guess
I'm gonna do another Barbara there's all
this rosin stuff right
and you must have a Wacka hash in there
see this hash still has residue I can
tell the way it's acting so what's going
right back here right back in she goes
[Music]
got close to four or five grams here
like when it's just nice and lined up
and not trying to move too much in the
room the paper mm-hmm but this thing is
so hot I'm gonna have to take a little
bit of a break I'll probably do a lot of
this video in fast-forward you know what
I mean like put on a song and just show
all us in like wait fast-forwarding
again
it's good though you know because I hear
a lot of people say oh I don't like Roz
and it all tastes like vape lead I think
that it's that person where it's the
worrisome factor of like I want to make
sure I get it all and there's that worry
that sometimes pushes through and
actually can commune razzin where it dry
sifting works that way you want to try
and get it all well good luck bro you
know I want to do is get the best of it
all you want to get it all well that's
different
like very different patients
[Music]
single squeeze that was a very efficient
squeeze you just never know when you're
gonna get one like that yeah I got most
everything out of that in one one little
rip I squeeze on that one just heavenly
man does this pick up wild almost like
taffy
it's just that perfect now it's going
back to more like normal but first few
pieces picked up select
might look a little dark on the sheet
but it'll press out nice and golden
don't you worry all right so you've had
a nice little small improvement on our
technique here I had had my wife bring
up these little clips or clips for
keeping bags closed we have longer ones
that we were using these little ones are
perfect for keeping the pressing screen
twisted nice you know when you've
pressed most of it out here's when it
just comes out I love being able to look
into the paper and watch the house use
out we also find the smaller you use
like there's no envelope we talked about
before with the smaller that I'm using
working with it the better I can and
with these clips your resin doesn't seem
to climb up yeah or at least as it does
you can control it better that's one
thing I was just literally noticing
online but I can control that off nice
little collections like decent amounts
for these little well just less than
half gram balls that I'm putting in what
know trying to keep an eye on our mounts
here first 15 grams we we collected
about 13 grams so somewhere along the
lines we lost two or two or three grams
I'm not sure if it was because he was
heating it too hot earlier and steaming
it and we had quite a bit of grease on
quite a few in the paper that was able
to get cleaned up but valid I bet that
we've got close to 10 grams now 7 8 9
we're probably closing in on 10 grams
which is about a third of the way there
we've been at it for about you close to
an hour now wouldn't turning the camera
off yeah so we'll see if we can't double
our our productivity and see if we can't
hammer off the next you know just under
20 grams
just a little job I suppose little suits
to go along with it does especially when
you're trying to talk on camera and
stuff dick just monster dabs coffees
[Music]
yes this is very good well I went and
left my thing on here so it's gonna take
me a few minutes to let it cool off it's
very rewarding work when you're making
it it's really not that hard labor wise
you could do this job while sitting and
watching movies with your buddies we can
just as easily been sitting in front of
the big screen TV and you know watching
YouTube videos while we hammer this out
it's not really like I would call it a
hard work patience is what it takes the
bubble hush and Lovejoy sift and dry
sifting more so but this is pretty
famous baking ly you know tedious and
small going but rewarding it's very
rewarding
really yeah when you think about it like
when you think about the Cameo 10grams
that we've made and probably a little
bit over an hour that's not too bad
especially considering we're using the
most you know the smallest of tools we
haven't used anything that's
commercialized or industrialized by any
means not t-shirt press and we're just
using I mean I'm really using literally
the smallest tool that you could
possibly use and I just pressed out four
or four and a half grams of rosin just
in the span of this video and I've got
more left in me we're gonna well we're
gonna continue down this road until
we've got ourselves a nice twenty-eight
gram a nice ounce slab of rosin for you
guys to look at so
just gotta fill these things up parent
fill these slicks up with rosin and
we'll be done okay
because who sits down and rips off an
ounce of roll of rosin with hair
straighteners it's absurd we do yes we
do and I'm sure there's other people out
there doing it as well to those people
who are flying right now yeah it would
be amazing if we could put all of this
in one single pouch and just go and just
have like you know 20 grams just reeked
out the sides into like little
containers and then literally just be
like boom okay that's how we're doing it
nowadays and that will be how we're
doing it I guarantee you within weeks if
not
that temperature drop we did lose a
little bit of temperature from the Sun
going behind not that I'm complaining
[Music]
bonk yes okay how's the cat runs fine
the dog jumps up to chase it they're all
just playing their parts takes a little
longer than we thought we'd been at it
for a well over an hour now so a couple
of hours we ended up getting about a
half ounce
yeah we're just under a mouse bones
right now so we figured we'd have a
couple of bowls with you guys
squeeze out maybe a few more of these
each just to get that last little bit we
just experienced this is with his
smaller one the resin has somewhere to
go to
to the wider one there's not as far of a
distance to go to unless you use it a
great big chunk like mania
ground-to-ground when we were talking
last night my buddy was saying he's he
does 7 grams squeeze on it
7 grams 7 grams really so that's
interesting
listen I'm not sure no I just know what
kind of tool is eases hair straighteners
right the same way it's just it's going
for the big yields just cure yeah no
mess not messing around
yep that was the whole purpose of it I
got to doing this squeeze that last time
that you know there's something that's a
nice little unit right let's turn light
on again let's just throw it to the
first everything it says it's 365 365
392 419 and 455 that's way too hot well
let's go down to 365 the lowest one oh
is that the lowest one yeah wow that's
pretty one that's pretty one that you
won't have my problem is that yeah I
think so right
yeah but then again you could fix that
problem by simply turning it on and then
just turning it off as it gets a little
bit too long I'm sure you'd find the
super sweet spot on that thing and be
like if you had you know I'm gonna go
buy a new one that's digital that I can
control the temperature completely there
we go
well if you get one of these small ones
you'll be forced to do the turn it off
yeah that's so well that's what I want
to do the digital because I'm I'm a
turn-on kind of guy and just leave it on
yep you know I can still like feel how
hot that is I turned it off like yeah
that's hot man but it's hot
yes
and you go grab the rest of the rosin
there's a little bit for you guys at
home to see so far what we've got nice
little puck o rosin quite lovely little
color on it not sure how well you guys
can see that but caramely and very
strong
lovely you doing one more Caesar I bet
you between what you squeeze there would
I hear
[Music]
Oh
at least we're getting to the 14 mark or
you know halfway what we kind of hoped
we would get to but yeah actually
surprising whereas we figured we figured
we'd be done in 40 minutes to an hour it
would exquisite amounts but do it we can
do it today I got something we go eat
that's good idea - I think we'll
probably do a part two it's hard to beat
right here man reduce when I think of
all the places we could do it at I think
I can picture us back here doing it
maybe finish them off on the water with
a big sash that sense of a plan right
there sure let me just squeeze another
couple of points out on the Roger I'm
just doing another point
well let's see if this isn't enough
right here I have a sneaking suspicion
that's going to be an eagle dirtbiking
from here you just go behind your host
via the trail yeah just go hide it
behind my house still a little up the
street the street goes up and around
behind my house here
no suppose you go further no there's
water and some trails and stuff go up
there plus we have all sorts of trails
along liance Bay in other parts of the
area
yeah we have three different hikes that
go up to the Lions one goes up to Mount
Brunswick this stuff was so nice and and
soft and we're cool and I was just hard
and crumbly that Sun sure does a job
while I was on for sure you monster
dr. all right buddy
we did it for stream work kids 14 so in
the least in this part I will show the
slab I'll get some photos of this and
add them to the end of the video thank
you for 20k for awesome [ __ ] press in
session and let's finish it off with
another bubble dude alright let's finish
it off with another Bowl let's do it
let's do it
awesome awesome
we did it
[Music]