[Music]
hey good morning guys it is the next day
here in Majorca we just woke up in a
beautiful apartment that was supplied to
us by Dani and grace our most amazing
hosts who took such good care of us how
good did they take care of us last night
right so we've got this little apartment
here it's pretty sweet here's the little
Town Hall across the street there a
little the police station right across
the street and it was the little town
right here we're gonna probably take a
walk down to the beach which is
apparently only a couple blocks from our
little apartment here right now so yeah
we're gonna make a little bit of hash
today and do a little bit of rosin as
well we got to go help Dani and grab the
rosin press apparently it weighs damn
near a ton and he can't do it by himself
so we're happy to go and help him do
that and in the meantime I think we're
gonna take a little walk down to the
beach and have a little session on the
beach so why don't you guys join us
[Music]
woods we're gonna go do this your way
good morning good morning good morning
some peanut oh yeah there you go there
you go all right well here we go
[Music]
can George I'm looking at the hand this
is wonderful
[Music]
where you guys going
I think the beach is this way I always
just go away from the copshop
oh yeah there's a coffee shop on the
corner there you guys want to go to the
custom Manolo yeah all right here these
guys got coffee too he told me this was
the coffee shop well do you want to get
your coffee right okay perfect perfect
I will wow this is a nice little village
man you really feel the vibe
[Music]
smelly
buenos dias cafe and croissant really
the black cat I'll sleep yeah another
one comes right by this guy's just
sitting here for no apparent reason in
his car those are not busy streets here
you can just stop anywhere for like 30
minutes
doing a little work down here it sounds
like Mediterranean
here we go to the left out on the
boardwalk maybe
this is pretty sweet
yeah he's doing a little little drilling
definitely not the sound I was expecting
but that's okay that's okay
it even sounds like a really efficient
Chuck now where it does now this is
definitely where we're having a session
isn't it on the boat
maybe out on the out on the dock there
at the end of the dock
there it is boys the Mediterranean Sea
what a [ __ ] beautiful little town
Majorca
there's got to be room for us at the end
of this thing
this is just beautiful what's up birds
a little bit of poopies a little bit of
bird poopies
push on through
sup dude
that's okay
so does the poopies
this is just beautiful logo he's like
look at this [ __ ] look at this [ __ ]
yep
all right well what do you guys think is
this our spot - sash I like it and right
on my Orca so far so good
we're gonna get the pipe out start
hitting some dabs did you read you gonna
do redo yeah it didn't
okay no problem good because honestly
the camera wasn't working properly there
it was giving me an error so I'm happy
to redo this god the sun's coming out
for this session man this is so nice
it smells like
well maybe go 46 to outside
[Music]
there you go okay Jimmy forty seconds
will give it even heating because of the
wind player yeah it's so hit it I read
it now
hohoho do it do it now he's got a big
enough tab there it's fine it's like
we're running on 25 I'm still gonna
notice it on the dabber
first my orc and dab out on the water
and yes I do you think we should rent a
boat yeah that's way too much dude go
fishing it's really hey where's your
bike
Mike's not here
beautiful
we
all right so this is our first session
of the day busting out the where is my
bike rosin dry set frozen rice it dry
citizen and we're thinking of maybe
renting motorcycles or a boat today
maybe pressing some rosin maybe making
some bubble hash we'll see what happens
in the meantime
what's cool a coolness in the air so
good
it was hot
yeah you can see each has the bowl Chazz
are gonna have to squirt the cleaner in
there now which works perfect now little
DC glass cleaner it's gonna overflow and
heroin I suppose
[Music]
she's coming off she is coming off this
is the beauty of the DC glass cleaner
more and if it ever doesn't completely
clean off it's not too hard to get it a
little bit more and that looks pretty
darn good right there
now it's recording a hot bike in the
morning hot bike in the morning it's hot
do I want this is my background
these [ __ ] mountains right here so
far so good
you got the carb cap for me ready I
guess I better hit it huh I think you
should
[Applause]
no time
yeah a little bit of heat
oh yeah it was rockin
low temp perfection
thanks jack
yeah beautiful be beautiful
cheers brother
well here comes the Sun again
oh yeah that's perfect
all right so we're all dabbed up on the
bike and I guess we're gonna go get
these guys some coffees and go check out
the rest of this little village lead the
way boys
all right sitting in the little town
square here right across right near our
apartment having some costs aunts and
some juice and some little one euro
coffees amazing yeah are they delicious
delicious
that's awesome I caught that up real
close when you poured the sugar it's
alright well the ones last night alright
so off to get some motorcycles
or look at motorcycles look and ride
alright so apparently there's a
motorcycle place just around the corner
this is our friends club right in front
of us here this building here is the
club what is called edifact tea solvent
it was the main street down there grace
was telling us last night John and I are
walking right down the street for no
particular reason well you know what why
not look like what we are perfect we'll
get you a lebara
there we are
Poochyena Malkina Elpis ito
I kind of thought we were almost there
already but maybe I think we took the
wrong Street I don't think so yeah mall
hum OH
a lot of this long walking stuff I'm
gonna speed up oh snap toy store oh part
virtual party stores shoes a little
space from this way I think it's this
way I need it to the left or to the
right
straight straight it is
jiae's even just these garage doors
they're just so different from what
we're used to
[Applause]
[Music]
three scooters
ya see a couple of those
oh wow he's got a whole stack of
motorcycles all right this is the BMW
home no the Honda and the BMW oh man
there's 200 Hey look at the seat on the
Honda that's comfy
I even pull the helmet inside of you all
right I saw that it came with two
helmets that's great
all right cool how about regular
driver's license you can get this is
just a 250 mm with this one that hey hey
nice ride
ours are numbers I have a five and a six
motorcycle and car your just class five
plus five which is the equivalent of
what movie to or something around it's
like a regular license that you can buy
[Music]
right from the start 10:13 notes are
friends Western was right
instead
the old blood medicine
[Music]
food