[Music]
hey what's up bubble man here about to
hit a beautiful head out of this most
beautiful creation mothership Marcel the
ready air trapping got the D nail with
the 14 4 to 18 adapter going into the
courts poking beagle I always feel like
I'm pronouncing that guy's name wrong
where this is from Dean out poking
beagle nail and also there's this little
quartz carb cap and we're gonna hit some
Congolese 90 micron Congolese so let's
get that rolling ooh that one's too big
that one's too big alright so here we go
oh that was super tasty Wow high
integrity glass check him out on
Facebook
high integrity glass art actually if you
check them out on Instagram as well and
higher end for the mothership connection
it seems as though the mothership has
landed here in bubble man's world I'm
gonna get back to this