[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm just here at the Vancouver
International Airport and I'm picking up
a good friend of mine who I have
actually never seen in on the west coast
in Canada and uh I've seen him in
Toronto at the champ show and I've seen
him all over Europe from Germany to
Amsterdam to Switzerland to London to
Spain he's been at all the shows he's
been uh around a little bit longer than
my company his company is called rure
from frankenthal Germany and of course
I'm talking about Martin bizel so he's
coming in right away on Lanza air I'm
picking them up I figured I'd have a
little bit of a session before we get
things going here playing and
helicopters all over the place but uh
it's to be expected at the airport isn't
it so yeah I've just got my car parked
up around here waiting for him to arrive
and
uh yeah I think we're pretty good yeah
I'm good I guess we're going to go grab
the rig have a quick dab here on the
bench and then we'll head up and grab
Martin sound good all right guys so I'm
here at the uh airport sort of I guess
they've got these little beautiful
Hangouts sort of all around the airport
and uh being a federally licensed
cannabis user I'm suspecting that it's
more than legal for me to come here
there's no kids there's no people run uh
to interrupt and just have a quick uh
quick dab I got some of the d420 K dry
sift there for you guys oh yeah thank
you d420 k bro of bros that guy is bro
of
Bros all right got the little uh DC
glass Banger on the Taurus didn't have
any water didn't really want to H uh go
around looking for water so just going
to uh take a quick little rip right here
on the
uh on the
bench all right going to go for a
dunk dunkaroo
airport
rips nothing like airport rips to get
yourself in the right State of Mind to
head into the actual
building got whistles
happening got to love the Mother Ship
even with no water in it this thing hits
like a
champ
so we guess next
up head in here and see if we
can't go find
Martin all
right all right guys I managed to find
Martin in the airport welcome to Canada
man hey welcome welcome to Vancouver
you've been to Canada before yeah great
great yeah this first time in Vancouver
first time in Vancouver so Martin as you
guys know or if you don't know is uh the
um uh the owner and operator of rure uh
German glass uh blowing company uh in
frankenthal Germany and uh yeah we've
had some good Adventures over the last
jeez close to 20 years yeah this year we
have uh it's my 20th anniversary this
year yeah they will be coming up some
celebration and as well my first Booth
of the cup was 95 yes the cannabies the
first cannabies that's was my first
public have you been there course that's
probably where we met because I had a
booth with the Cannabis business in what
was it
90 I wonder if it was 97
or was it a little earlier than that the
can business in Dortmund I was there but
this was 1995 was the first one I'm sure
1995 okay okay that's why I have 20 this
is 2015 oh yes yes my first Cannabis Cup
in Amsterdam also was in
1995 and it was like accidental that was
not planned so I mean I I make this for
years with no name and I find out the
child needs to have a name so that you
know what you're talking about right so
otherwise this is just a clear piece of
glass you true was like um in any other
area of the market it was very uncommon
a jeans is no name a car with no name
sure nobody will accept that you know a
watch with no name so it took a few
years to give give it a name uh uh yeah
it took me like one two years to find it
I I I I I had my I didn't have the name
but I had my vision what it should be it
should be like Timeless sing and show
some yeah some kind of design some
Timeless design you know I love that
it's a pal Dr and so we had so many
suggestions and go through kind of I
wanted to have like the double meaning
sing in it mhm because
uh especially in our industry you know
it's often this double meaning if you
make it intelligent then absolutely it's
they here like forever and I know the
double meaning I know the story of the
RO it's like a yeah it's a very cool but
even the name you told me years ago
about how you found that name yeah he
was like heory so I was marus founded
from the grop in D he was how Mark
German he bring him to Germany and then
and and
uh started selling his book in in German
was the first language which was transl
and it was the word that you
saw uh is it the word
microorganism no this this is the the
word microorganism was on a title from a
book which which said the biology of
microorganism this was the book about
was on the title H yeah so if you say
that word
microorganism right you say it enough
times you'll you'll hear the word RAR in
there micro organism it's the it's at
the end of micro and at the start of
organism you get r o and o r and uh yeah
the rest is history rure well we're
going to actually be showing some rure
pipes in a little bit a few historical
pieces from the past but uh yeah we just
thought we'd kind of let you guys know
that we made it back to the hotel we're
in downtown Vancouver we stopped off at
Eden we're going to be in
420 on Monday in a couple of days we'll
be doing 420 but before that tomorrow
we're going to be at the Great Northern
extraction the first annual so this is a
little thing that they're putting on I
guess I don't know if it's with Eden in
conjunction but we went to Eden today
this was the first dispensary Martin
ever seen in Vancouver and they gave us
a bunch of really nice things actually
we got uh what did we get we got uh well
these are packs so there's obviously
like entries for solvent and solventless
entries but then we also this one's not
Mine mine's over here one
more that one's for
enrio and then they also gave us all
sorts of uh little candies little
droplets goner
droplets um a couple of cookies some
nice chocolate chip uh peanut butter
cookies and then also some really nice
chocolates really nice pieces of uh
homemade chocolates so Edibles
and
extracts never a bad thing right yeah no
they good and then of course I'm pretty
impressed is a
um the legalization or the
open how this is dealt with you can uh
and this is pretty amazing compared to
Germany or other parts of Europe or the
world so you pretty good here and keep
on fighting for it so if you think it's
pretty good it comes over the ocean when
it's you know when it's you hear it
every day in Canada in North America
it's uh now it's pretty much in the
media but the politicans don't react yet
so well it's going to happen in Germany
no doubt about it you know it's just a
matter of Germany's a a tough a tough
nut to crack like you said there's a lot
of history there and you know you can't
really for instance when we came out
well even when I picked Martin up at the
airport we walked out across the street
and I could tell he probably wanted to
have a one of his American Spirits he'd
been on a 12 plus 10 hour flight with
waiting and whatnot maybe more and so we
I just said oh let's just walk right
over here and literally within like 30
seconds of walking out the air Port
we're in this natury beautiful Zone and
I actually had a little of Horatio's
delimine extract so I was able to put a
little tiny dab on the uh American
Spirit Forum so nice way to land in
Vancouver yeah it's definitely very good
to see that and so uh uh I already
thought uh we should probably think
positive so when we know it will going
to be happen one day Absolut we should
have something to present and to start
is or to you know to organize like the
first cup or the first something like
absolutely right away they when they do
something you know trust me it happens
fast nowadays you know it might be like
all like closed off and no one's doing
it but the minute it blows that's why I
say we should B start thinking about
what to do so maybe internationally he
also do something you know you will 100%
be inspired by
420 in two days cuz there's going to be
there's literally like I don't even know
how many thousand thousands of people
but it's just really quite an impressive
Vancouver's 420 is always good we're
going to be down there of course I've
got a booth down there with Johnny B
Martin's going to be down with the
sublimator booth we'll it's already as
it seems so I looked a little bit up in
the internet about the history and the
the last days from this 420 in vanov so
it's like Organic Grown there's people
who support that to finance that to
fight for it you know think can't do it
just you I thought about doing something
like this in Europe but you cannot bring
It Like a Rolling Stones concert to
every place you know it's like it's
different there not the people who fight
it so they think oh no I can't say that
in public because of the legal situation
which is uh which is unfortunate which
is unfortunate and and what happened to
that dab did you roll it all into the
cigarette no no no there's still a
little dab left there this was uh was
that the I SED it on yeah that's I
sticked it on top of this I just have a
tiny little dab of that one I'm pretty
sure I know what it is
goad yeah it's Barb first one we pulled
out how funny is
that the first one we pulled out stupid
European
never hey no
no Pioneers man
Pioneers so yeah we've got flab 421 one
coming down here he's going to be
bringing a few RAR pieces from uh back
in the day a few collabs with some
well-known artists and yeah we're just
super stoked to to have Martin in in the
city I mean literally I've been bumping
into this guy at cannabis cups for so
many years 20 this year man 20 plus
years and although we've had canab was
the first show in Europe after that they
came in in swand and then yeah yeah and
I was at all those to Holland trade
finally to Spain yeah and finally to
Spain lafier was the first Spanish one I
did back in 2002 or
three I DC already 15 years anniversary
or also something or 10
years oh
yeah nice and delicious that was
great all right well we'll be back in a
bit we're going to uh continue to puff
some bowls and uh when we come back
we'll have flab 421 with
us all right so we're back we made it
back and Flav 421 in the house how's it
going everyone yes I guess uh you're
going to take us through a little uh
Memory Lane here with yeah um with
Martin in town I thought it would be
rather enjoyable to go back down memory
lane from some of the old uh he roarers
that I have on some of the older ones um
I mean Roar has been synonymous with the
top of the glass game since well since
they came out in
'95 and um even when before all the
American Glass was as notorized as it is
now everybody wanted Roars everybody
still wants Roars and it is a pleasure
to share this with you guys awesome dude
I'm excited yeah I mean it's cool to be
here and and see these days like fans
and year old
pieces the other side of the world
people love then it's cool to see this
one's an old jar rice oh yeah this was
Johnny
rice I see yeah yeah yeah so tell us
about that whose was
it h Johnny rice it's uh he's U from the
US and he was like cing with stay there
for a week or 10 days and so we combined
his design with our technique let's say
what year was this
po9 or something probably
something I think I got it in 20 in late
2011 something like that maybe 9 8 N I
don't think I've ever seen this piece
before no I it's it's actually the piece
I have beside my bed really yeah so I
mean you know we can make like probably
10 15 pieces doing that not more so
that's it I have I have two I also have
special pool and then we we
did Mark my son
um played with his uh yeah designs
creations and that's a big piece put it
together like this the marble the ball
the Dos there yeah it's all nicely all
matching all nicely
matching I have it beside my bed there
there there there there were three
identical ones to this with the same
color patterns and sections and I got um
high high integrity glass art got two
out of the
three and I still have them they never
they never they kept they got kept in
the collection so Tre kind and stay for
a long time oh forever and ever and ever
and then this
one is I don't know what year this is
from I have no idea it's um Red Man's
originally it's um been around but also
with a beautiful little marble here and
the the clear
glass imprint on on the on the tube I I
just love that yeah that's heavy
yeah nice down stem too on that one
yeah beautiful work down
stem there is for sure
also 7
eight Maybe maybe 9 years old yeah still
going strong still going very
strong it's damn nice that Pole's nice
if you see the pipes today you see is
already like hisory years
ago yep totally is looking down the stem
of the Roar well there's a lot of
collectors that have you know I mean a
lot of people hold on to the Roars they
don't you don't see a lot of them going
up for resale you don't see a lot of
people trying move them so there's got
to be a reason for that yeah I heard
many times so over the years they kind
of
get you get close I we see a par so oh
yeah every day very very very much and I
mean
uh certain like I cool to see yeah we we
I mean that's the most uh what you say
get reward or what for your work when
people love what you do and so well
they're just not buying it to use it cuz
there are people that buy them to use
them then there are people that are
buying them literally to collect them
totally yeah I mean you know the the our
philosophy or it's like two two feet
standings know it's the quality and the
the the design and the quality also
about how does the filtering system and
the volume and these all work together
yeah it's always it's all working
machines and when and you respect your
if you learned a little bit you you need
88 or 4 in4 for example so you see what
is good for you and then it's working
perfect every day MH and yeah true
enough I sure like so that's what is our
goal also so like you have your you know
your everyday piece works really good
good to clean the daily driver we even
do repair service one day oh really you
really would break something like that
he sent his already three four times
nice so people laugh oh you we seen this
pipe so many times and it's cool you
know so also when they unpack it when it
what she destroyed it again well I still
have my we went over the ocean five
seven times back and for the first time
I brought it back why is that why is
that one by the way it's I have it shap
beautiful sh we pull it out and we'll
use it I the one he's talking about is
actually the one of five it was the
first time I believe RAR had ever done a
collaboration with an American Artist
and that was Mike fro yes and so yeah
that piece oh I love that piece it's
it's real nice and tight and smaller
than my my other ones that I used to be
more into the bigger the chunky yeah 188
and stuff and I gone into the 144 and
this one's a really nice th thin tall
tube really beautiful I mean Mike fro
was the first ever he was the first
ameran come yes yes and in that time it
kind of started to grow bigger and then
they started to do really beautiful
pieces totally fro a I met him at the
exhibition in in Santa I think so I had
an amazing experience with that finally
he came over and we we did five pieces
and went to the Cannabis Cup and win it
beautiful and you bought one of the
first I think it was the first mhm which
that and that's the one you still have
at your house it's really nice really
nice pie awesome and you know what's
funny when in my holidays and Mike Mike
contacted me Mike fro and said hey how
are you nice everything good should we
do something together oh very cool you
should yeah what year was that 03 no no
no no the year that it originally I
think it I seen five oh5 yes 445 I'm
thinking earlier but the pipe signed
that's why I think it's 03 but maybe 04
it's signed yes yeah even dated I think
underneath one of5 and and those are the
ones the signature should be on
everybody after the years you don't know
it it is nice to have that I love it
you've always done that even for the
first piece that you ever gave me yeah
and in in Barcelona the GU you Tony who
wi this yeah talk to you know him well
yeah and
uh
uh he was on our bus and we started
talking about mik FR so he said he's
he's spoty he won he Liv just around the
corner oh wow so and finally we hooped
up I just had a a conversation that'd be
neat to see him come out again and do
another collaboration yeah years later
yeah yeah totally I mean and if it was'
05 do it full decade later yeah yeah
know even and you could do more than
five but it would be yeah it would just
be neat to go back and be like oh let's
look at pictures of the original pieces
and go from there yeah totally that
would be awesome it would be pretty cool
there's an idea for you
Mike as you're watching this it's all up
to you well I have two others that I
brought and they are American
collaborations as well and they're very
special to me and also Mark helped make
this all happen too so this is the
double jacketed um hops
inline hops yeah from9 that's
unbelievable dude and that's one my
that's a piece of History right there
that is my wife's actually I got to make
sure I specify on that she once uh once
she uh saw
that I I remember sitting there watching
you guys all sign it I'll never forget
sitting there watching you guys all sign
that
C9 09
yes 09
I guess that was seven years ago why did
it seem like so many more no I was
thinking of Mike fro Mike fro was like
03 or 04 yeah Mike fro was before him
yeah way before can I see
that I broke this piece in as you're
looking at that let me take this one out
too so that you guys can look at them
together
HPS the Dizzle and and Sasha the big the
big Swiss
one of my pride and joys is that how
very cool and there you
are dude that's so you're blowing me
away right now these These are
unbelievable right now to be holding
with you this many years later it is
pretty
Co dude little ISO is still in the
bottom sorry we got to clean that one
out this is great yeah I'll never forget
it the Cannabis Cup the same year
when yeah both
and I believe there were two or three
hops right hops did two or three of them
and and Dizzle did two or three and then
one was a Dizzle hops War collab which
inline to the
Swiss which Whoever has that out there
if you're watching this video hit me up
dude look at how biging for for a that's
unbelievable that is nice huge holy
smoke yeah I know I have a picture of
like on my face and it's like your eyes
line up like right in the
two I have a picture of Nate Dizzle
blowing this sick in Germany with his
big
white
whatever Shades and he's like holding it
up on a tube and it's covering his head
he he big guy yeah you just have to hold
it the perfect size away and it's like
he's inside of this perfectly in the
photo it's very cool Nate this was uh
yeah this was historical for me too just
because I I was talking talking to
Martin about it earlier before we we
started
filming that it was just really like I
wanted to just help make it happened it
wasn't there was no monetary reason for
me it wasn't a business venture for me I
wasn't involved in any of the selling of
the pieces or anything I just I bought
them off direct off road yeah I just
wanted to um get them there and it was
quite an adventure to get them there
Y and I damn near died that trip I got
some Wicked food poisoning really oh in
Germany or in Holland in in frankenthal
in frankenthal when you beat it was yeah
I remember I was gone for a whole day
when they were blowing all these pieces
and I never got like a whole day I
missed of being there because I had food
poisoning [ __ ] brutal I for you da
there Flav sure yeah and Cory C so we
can call him back too awesome yeah very
cool for you to bring those pieces and I
brought I brought slides and and uh I
even brought a Club Banger Banger so we
can hit them if you guys want seven
years they look nice all lined up
together well I still have another I
still have another four or five that I
left at home because I just don't have
enough bags to Fig yeah I hear you
so that would have been cool you know
trust me I got nine Roar bags on it was
cool well I mean we did roll to
Amsterdam that one time with like six or
seven oh yeah I've had we've had more
yeah it's a small one but here that's
okay thank you kindly and this is a
better uh I should put this also on the
photo on Instagram here what's that oh
you should absolutely huh oh yeah man
Absolutely I'll get a few shots of you
for
sure um next up is another session I
think uh we'll catch you guys in a
bit so what do you think of that
Martin nearly H op gripping I think what
is it 88 88 I don't know yeah 88 with
counting the the
so as someone that's known for precision
you can feel the Precision in that in
that
piece in the in the um the Opals and the
way they're encased in the glass it's
almost uh
Martin oh that's the bowl in the ofcc he
encased is it 10 or 10
OP yeah you see they love the quality
there's a lot of very detail did you see
the swing though amazing work in it
great just the swing for
now see
H how that quartz bucket opens and
closes and then that other piece carbs
it the same way I was using my uh vial
of hash to carb
the this pipe comes with a slightly
more fancy
version it's like the most the world's
most expensive ofc
yeah and I've seen themel for like what
ISC uh optimized flavor zone so like
yeah you know the the Zone it allows you
to take a colder colder dab which gets
you more flavor yeah so you put this on
here then no the other way though or is
it that way uh oh yeah yeah it is that
way that way yeah like cuz the you would
he you would when you torch up the the
tie or the or the um oh yeah quartz it's
so you can have the actual element at a
lower temperature so that the more of
the flavor comes through cuz when it's
at a hotter thing it it instead of
vaporizing it combusts so basically caps
it and it's still allowing air to to go
through so you're still going to yeah
it's got that little hole right in the
center yeah they're very
cool Opals like you wouldn't believe
very cool yeah
yeah s also pretty functional this works
also very good this one too cuz it's the
one that uh Scott basically is the only
one who can do and it's his his design
yeah this is like all of the designs
Martin all of the you know the Taurus
and the kle yeah those are the three cuz
this is this is the
Taurus right this one's just the Taurus
and then there's the Fab egg and then
there's the Klein that's pieces all
three of them in one
piece yeah that's pretty incredible he's
going
to tap oh you know what probably won't
matter I'll probably just
uh put some music yeah okay sorry about
that 10 seconds with bubble
[Applause]
has
some other flowers and you guys the same
as like the overall amount of bubble has
you you'll be
getting so you're not losing you're
precise you're not
losing really it's a
about but with
like I know people that are starting to
Ros in their really high quality and
[Music]
personally