hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
just wanted to do a little update I had
uh John B show up a few days ago and he
brought me a couple of clones that he
never marked or anything uh they've been
sitting in my Dome um just in water but
they haven't actually been well you can
see right there one's just been pulled
right out they're definitely ready to
clone so that's what we're going to do
today and yeah medy Hayes three of
John's medy Hayes Cuts these are his
number seven pheno
and I've got the pucks right here
they've already soaked I've got Remo's
rooting
gel and we're just going to do a quick
little cotton root those birds are
making some sounds out there I guess
they're excited about the
uh about the my little or sorry the medy
medy haze so just give that a little cut
and a
dip we'll get you right in
[Music]
there all right
one nice to have the medic Kush this is
uh definitely one of John's prized
possessions between his uh medy or medy
Haze I should say between his medy Haze
and his medy
Kush he's quite
happy and they're uh they're definitely
beautiful strains so I'm happy to have
the medy haze in my jard my secret
jardan and finally number three so all
I'm really doing is I'm cutting at an
angle about a
45° dipping it in Remo's cloning
gel and then inserting gently into the
puck and there you have it three nice
clones so I'm also going to cut the tips
of the
leaves just because they tend to
uh they tend to get in the
way
in the cloning
area
excellent well I'll keep you guys
apprised of what's going on with the
medy haze in my garden and uh yeah
thanks for watching guys three new Cuts
going into bem man's
Garden