[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world I am in my kitchen and it is the
same day I showed you the dry sift uh
repress pressing and reheating up to
avoid that Whiting out on your wet wash
or your dry sift if it's dry sift it's a
guarantee that it's moisture pulled out
of the air if it's wet wash it's a
little trickier it could be moisture
that you left trapped in there or it
could also be properly dried bubble that
sucked moisture out of the air through
the humidity so what I'm doing now is I
was going to make myself a pizza I got
myself the Pea pizza crust and I put a
little tomato sauce on there and then I
realized well this is an excellent
opportunity to medicate my pizza and
it's an excellent opportunity to share
with my audience because personally I I
don't know how to make the best
medicated pizza but I know if I make a
medicated Pizza you guys are going to
see it you're going to think of other
things that could be a better way of
doing it we could start a dialogue and
see who can come up with the most
awesome medicated pizza so I'm doing the
old standby that John and I have done in
the past I've got my dry sift right here
I got a couple grams of it actually I
won't be putting that much on but I'm
going to sprinkle it quite nicely I've
got my crushed garlic and a little bit
of Pineapple and then the key is the
mozzarella cheese so rather than put
this thing in the oven for 8 minutes or
5 minutes which I could easily cook at
420° I know John's favorite temperature
because I haven't decarbox the dry sift
uh I'm going to put it in for a a longer
period of time on a lower heat so I'll
probably take about 12 to 15 minutes to
cook this um pizza and I've noticed from
the few times that I've done it that the
dryy sift becomes a lot more active and
for whatever reason the cheese is an
incredible carrier uh it's a real good
fat it really gets it into your system
you feel it almost immediately so I
guess what we're going to do is we're
going to take a little bit of this dry
sift and we are going to gently drop it
down onto our pizza crust so I've
probably put so far maybe a/4 of a gram
um I'm not looking to get destroyed so
I'll probably just put about a half gram
on this pizza and
uh well it's still going to be quite
active that's for sure so a little bit
of this a little bit of that I also take
a little bit of the crushed garlic and
do the same thing drop it down on that
pizza and
just there we
go that
[Music]
down my pizza is going to be pretty
simple today sometimes I make them fancy
sometimes I make them simp simple uh
this one's going to be pretty
simple pineapple and cheese and dry sift
so the dry sift was oh jeez I think it
was
Barb I'm pretty sure we'll get this all
on there our mozzarella cheese which is
going to activate that sift for
us sitting in that
sauce we'll get this into the oven for a
nice slow cook I will uh show it to you
guys when it comes out of the oven so
stay
[Music]
tuned all right so our pizza is cooked
took about 15 minutes or
so nice and
crispy
delishes all right
so let's take that
outside
medicated pizza with a little bit of
pink
lemonade all right so I think that was a
great idea I've got my medicated pizza
I've already consumed some infused
coconut oil today about three or four
times nothing to give me full effects as
I'm inhaling through my vaporizer for
those things but uh never a bad idea to
medicate a pizza in the middle of the
day if you can I'm surrounded by my
strains in beautiful British Columbia
and uh I'm ready to try out the dry sift
medicated
Pizza thanks for watching and I hope to
hear about your medicated piece of
recipes on Bubble Man's
World Peace
[Music]