[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with d420 K in the house and
we're about to come check out this new
dispensary I heard about called Med poot
now yeah you were telling me about that
where did how did you meet these guys
you know I was at a dinner the other
night and I bumped into a few of the
people that are involved uh know one of
the young guys that uh moved here from
Ireland Named Sam who's a big fan of
both the channels and I thought it would
be a good place for us to maybe uh go
get ourselves a membership at why not
why not always good to try out new new
strains new new products like the
cooking Edibles the I I I heard there
was an award or something like that for
the top strains of out of all the
compassion clubs that's right so lift
has this new this is a new company
called Lyft and they're doing the the
Cannabis uh Awards uh in Canada and
basically uh this particular place got
number one for best dispensary and
that's one of the major reasons that I'm
dropping in right now with d yeah we
take my license get a membership and
have some strong good medicine to
[ __ ] medicate and also see you know
what you think of it see what you know
is it the best dispensary in in Canada
well we're going to go and check it out
we're going to see what we uh what we
can find and and uh why don't you guys
come with us now all right here we go so
the best drains out of all the
compassion clubs number one oh man I'm
really excited just to see just to try
cuz I don't smoke much butt ever no I
guess not you're but I will I will try
it out because uh cuz I can right okay
so here we are here 4170 Frasier Street
cameraman can show us the wall here
we've got Med poot now medical uses of
cannabis and they've got a whole list of
things that if you're suffering from you
can uh you can potentially get
alleviation and maybe even uh complete
remission of these particular things so
let's go check it out all these things I
can't believe it that's incredible isn't
it hey how's it going good how are you
today very good good excited to be here
we heard you guys uh were number one on
the uh lift awards for indeed yeah very
impressive that's really impressive well
thank I've got my my license here my
perfect and uh get some
paper yeah right on and I've seen your
driver's license if
you excellent
perfect it's always in the the fourth
pocket it's always in the fourth fifth
fifth
pocket did I go all the way there and
not get it no there it is oh you got it
perfect you got it okay so I'll
photocopy this and put this into the
system okay and I'll check you in here
in the meantime while I'm doing all of
that you guys can go in the back and
consult here bud Excell Sam thank you a
second great thank
you
right hello gentlemen how you doing
bud
good this is the guy you were talking
about here you want to grab there how
you all doing today doing very very good
excellent so welcome to me now this our
pending area uh we have the full menu
just behind you there with all those
trains on okay W yeah w we go that's it
so we Tred to keep around 20 to 25
trains at a time 20 to 25 yeah keep a
good quality on them and stay around
that area excellent you've got a good
variety of Edibles and baked goods and
caps yeah definely got lots of Edibles
if want for people to take some lots of
uh some low sugar ones if people may
have dietry uh confinements and then we
have other concentrates on the right
excellent right shatters Butters and
others which I'm guessing are the sifts
and the water hashes exactly how's uh
what's that uh Rockstar Green Crack
Skywalker OG yeah
um we got some uh organic ones that just
have found there from Co Organics up in
there really nice and blueberry Let's uh
let's have Sni for some of them yeah
definely to check them start off with
this is one of the sativas this is a
strawberry cough so
it's right off the yeah really
nice all organic hand and then
jure really takes a lot of care with his
work and goes extra couple of weeks you
guys uh I guess have some good things
implemented for sort of standardization
to make sure that there's no Milos or
bugs
yeah we try to keep a high standard for
our medical patients you know de with
their health they have to have a good
product that's clean that's safe use
daily that plastic there y well that
looks very nice yeah let's have a look
we got four phos of the fighting
building here that's number four three
two and one and then we got number one
and two are more the migrs we got a 640
Inda and a 640 sativa and gorgeous stuff
on the fenal Chun 4 we have a more
blueberry one that's a look this is the
tree that's the tree
there check those those out so these are
Buddha yeah so it's a cross between BL
and Burmese oo this is wow well cured
this smells very nice well it's got that
Burmese in there yeah that's a very
almost exotic smell spicy exotic SP def
something about a diesel a diesel Cross
or something like that what do you got
for that I really like that stuff it's
always exciting to come with d 420k and
check he's like a kid in a candy store
at these places I haven't even showed
him the candy
yet that's nor straight 70% C Sour
Diesel really nice blood structure very
consistent and I great one for the
daytime very uplifting very nice show
that that's that one
this is a really nice one sorry sorry
that one belongs in the this guy show
the camera show them the camera work
this guy this is a really nice one it's
a God's green crack so 70% Indica so
other end of the spectrum but really
nice strength to it definitely a strong
body effect right off the bat you got
that pine cone structure real lovely
haven't smelled it yet but let's see if
I can pick up the dog yeah get the
to oh it definitely has that stress to
yeah it's God God is so
unique anytime you get God in there it's
just different yeah I I appreciate the
God bud and the God Bud crosses how
about your rockar oh rockar got an
organic rockar minute it's super super
nice it's definitely a strong body
effect but definitely good with it re
activity as well it kind of keeps you
active and thinking about things ick a
couple of Sy if you had some nice ones
[Music]
I guess one of the great things that
working at a place like this would be
that you know what better way to learn
the ability of the strain than to
bioassay it than to than to try it
yourself I personally would feel more
comfortable purchasing something off of
a bud tender that had actually used the
strain than one that was telling me you
know how it the effect what the effects
should be yeah you know I want to know
what the effects were exactly how you f
the fact
and lean towards maybe a bit more in
what you felt about I also appreciate
the fact that you're a hash maker oh yes
and you know I think every Bud tender
should be at least have to go through
hash education yeah hash eation hash
acation and and learn about the resin
yeah before trying to you know explain
it definitely especially water
extraction oh yeah it's very clean way
for people to get their medicine
absolutely some people may have elments
that such as long lung issues they can
get the same effect but not some smoke
absolutely 100% pretty right smell
this I didn't smell it on the first one
but that one I popped and was like oh
that's this is a different fennel but I
like that that's the more blue that's
the super
blueberry the super blueberry pheno
right there for the camera it is isn't
it you know I'll take focusing
nice beautiful that's Jake on the camera
for you guys at home You' seen from PG
our good budy took me out for a rip
there on the snowmobiles that
day oh
God yeah defin getting three grams each
one of these it's
to have to yeah now is there a strain in
here that uh everybody
wants it's the most popular the most
dominant strin best what's your best
strain here best strain in here these
guys would definitely be the top ters at
the minute and older than that some very
popular ones I would say we got black
diamond at the minute which is really
nice look to it this is this guy looks
looks looks good already yeah it's got
like a very kind of a like a blue to it
almost yeah a blue hue yes and indeed it
does purple purple Hue for the camera
there yeah that's quite a nice one it's
a very heavy indic very body orientated
so great for sleeves great forain paint
anything like oh that has a nice smell
that's some exotic uh yeah that's pretty
nice it's earthy yeah an earthy earthy
herb that's the kind of herb that you
could literally grow G of that too you
can grow herb like that hydroponically
and tell people you grew it organically
just because of the way it smells the
Turpin are so earthy very nice very nice
the best part about this is the D's
getting a bunch of these
strains you're going to have to try them
all out yeah come absolutely I look
forward to the days where there's more
um melts and dry sifts on the menu
that's uh well you know I don't smoke
much but you know that cuz that's the
after you're on the dry sift and the
hash and you've got that product you're
available to it it's well you look at
this you look at this as you know a jar
of hash I look at this as one of my nug
jars full of hash that's right with a
blue shoe to it yeah to the hash you
know what I mean like that's what I
would what I see both of us would die to
just grab this whole thing and then
crush it over
screens oh yeah like I would go do that
right now yeah right now we can set it
up in the backroom we almost did it the
last place we were at yeah but um what I
do like to do though the most is is you
know is introduce this to other people
that that that are patients and stuff to
say look like this is what's available
down there yeah yeah you know and uh you
know you can come down you can you can
get signed up bring your license down
because some people are getting the
stuff mailed to them that is absolute
garbage from some of these places like
like the whole plant is being put into a
wood Shredder and then and then it's
sold in in pill bottles that's sent in
the mail from these government grown
places and it's just complete garbage
quite different from being offered that
you you won't see that yeah yeah you
know people need to know that right and
uh you know I hope this kind of lets
people know that there is better things
out there than than the government
standard yeah definitely [ __ ] their
standards you tell them well you guys
have really beautiful looking pod I'm
inclined to to ask to see a few more
just for the audience because I so far I
haven't seen anything that I haven't
been impressed with so it's you know
great structure on the both of these are
beautiful Theos check this one this is a
watermelon it's a great kind of day
timer and it's a 50/50 so that gives you
a relaxed feel that is watermelon that's
the Astro Boy as too heavy to keep from
doing this it's pretty ni wow of TS in
there oh yeah well that's what uh yeah
that's the the hash that I make that's
the one e that's the as you can tell
like look at it look at the colors
structure of oh just the taste that that
taste you can smell that close that he's
got
flavor so there's some Astro Boy that's
been well cured uh you don't see this at
my house ever because I take it fresh
frozen right off the plant and turn it
into hash it looks real real nice
velvety even yeah it's going to Unique
Look to it that it's it's well cuz it's
so coated in resin yeah as it it grows
that way as well the tur are just
beautiful well that was a nice surprise
a big jar of the watermelon P always a
great one to have so that's another guy
see what we got
here we got this is an MK Ultra this is
a really nice one very heavy resin on
the outside
and it's got a very strong effect to it
it's definitely like a very
heavy yeah quite sticky on the side as
well get my hand on there so I can focus
going to oh you're going to have to
update it nice you know what let me give
this a squeeze and put it under the
cameraman's nose cuz what a cruel cruel
world this is he's watching us all smell
this smell this but that is really like
and the cameraman really loves smelling
it as well a really nice deep Cush yeah
and also once again these eight little
little little just solid nugs of real
nice nice excellent good been one of
them like I like the bar you guys are
setting so far excellent that they here
this is great to keep as high as you can
well I think it's good because if you do
then the people who are out there
producing these grades of medicine if
their grades aren't cutting it they're
forced to up their standards up their
standards which is a great thing for
them to do because they want to up their
standards they want to do better they
want to produce a nicer product and then
it just works out for everyone they're
happier you're happier and most
importantly the end user the patient the
the person who's buying this cannabis
isn't it important that they're the most
happy exactly the patients that going to
be using that as this is cannabis that
if you were to purchase and go home you
certainly would not be disappointed
later on you know sometimes you can get
sold herb where you're like oh did I get
hit
that is nothing but a disappointment a
one it's a one joint wonder One joint
the rest of the bag is no good well
we'll make sure that we show Darren
smoking some of this herb maybe I'll
take some Vapor hits through uh one of
the vaporizers that we have access to
and we'll give you guys a little bit of
a background on um the quality of the
resin I'm obviously only giving you my
opinion on the smell uh the feel and the
look of the bud but that's generally a
pretty solid uh giveaway if you can nail
all three of those
definitely right on man well thanks for
showing us all these flavors I guess I
guess D is going to want to start some
up some up here and uh we C you going
yeah you have to give us feedback and
yeah definitely you bet I'll write the
feedback down on every strain that I
smoke yeah definitely and uh give a
group report on it yeah absolutely yeah
so I'll probably you know what I wanted
three of each one but I'll take just two
G of each one of these these two then
there's the Rock star got the rock star
over here and that MK and the MK and the
water excellent two G of each two G of
that to oh definitely two gs of each two
two
two I'm all about the two two toes two
bong reps and are you getting nice
containers like this or what I hope so
oh yeah definitely we got to get you
some every time I open it I'm
like [ __ ] you know what you know what
I'll say about this place as well I'm
going to say a second thing maybe some
of you at home have noticed but for Bud
that they're showing to people this
looks like Bud that has never ever been
touched it literally looks like look at
that dude that's that looks I listen
I've seen a lot of bud that's never been
touched and that looks like Bud that's
never been touched that's a rarity I
think it's another great standard to up
because it's like guess what this is
someone's medicine don't you be touching
it don't even though you know we've
squeezed a few buds I know we did and I
feel terrible maybe we should buy those
particular buds this I will not give a
squeeze I like touching the touching it
giving it a squeeze and if you know what
the dense buds I had no problem doing
that with the MK it didn't change it it
didn't alter it at all but this it's so
this looks like it's never been touched
man look at the resin content on that KX
right there let's get that up close
yeah
tails that fox t awesome really good
that's a healthy happy plant it it
certainly is so here's a question that
the viewers at home might want to ask
how can people who are watching this
that are like oh my gosh do you need to
be a Canadian or do you need to be from
BC or do you what do you have to be at
we try to we well we definitely do have
everyone have a medical license um so we
definitely Canadian Canadian what if an
American comes up with a medical license
as long as they have Canadian
license like a a Canadian prescribes
license by a doctor doctor practitioner
or a specialist then we can definitely
go years to that which isn't impossible
to get so now you're hearing this uh you
us uh people down in the America that
you are also able to come up here as
long as you were to get the doctor to
prescribe it while you're here which
shouldn't be that difficult cuz he could
prescribe you any other number of drugs
you would then be uh able to have access
to come here and access uh
now as long as we're prescribed in
Canada we can definitely um do you do
mail order in Canada we do indeed yeah
for federal MMA which is still kind
of and then um full prescription by a
medical doctor so also prescription for
medical doctor MMA are licenses like the
license that Darren and I have the pink
one from Ottawa uh how would they go
about doing that do they just Google
medot now yeah we've actually have a new
launch of our website and so if you go
to med.com excellent and go on there we
have a full side of instructions that
you can go through for registration and
we also have our phone number there and
our contact details and uh feel free to
give us a call any emails concerns
comments we're always happy to help okay
spend a bit of time going going with you
people excellent I'm going to put all of
that information your website and your
phone number and the address in the
comments of this video so you guys don't
have to go looking for it it'll be right
in the comments and you'll be able to
click on that so that's great um are
there limits is it basically 150 g
you're able to order yeah definitely so
we try to stick to our limits and ADH
here to the guidelines as best you have
to legally thing illegal thing and that
where gives the room to yeah it defin a
gr area the mid but we just try and do
the best we can to all the rules I'm
thinking right off the bat of my friend
uh dell bage who we met online who we
sent the the pink Apex to his wife for
her birthday um Dell this is another
opportunity for you maybe you don't have
to drive to Toronto I I'm telling you
right now I'm here I'm looking at this
stuff and I think that you would be
happy um if you purchased Medicine of
this quality and acquired it and they're
telling me that they're going to send it
right to you so right to your door
there's something for Dell and maybe
many other thousands of Canadians I'll
I'm sure I'm going to be making an order
just because I can M it hasn't been
touched that bud that hasn't been
touched you got to buy that bud
dude it's right there it's right in the
top Bud the KX that we were showing on
camera there so that's the one o that's
the one bud buddy we'll photograph that
very carefully that is very nice what at
like 2 point something 2.2
excellent and what brand name is that
that is that Colorado fighting Buddha
pheno Number One it'll be easy for us to
remember because it's number one just
like this dispensary in the newy awards
yes indeed thank you very much to lift
for yeah right on that's cool I don't
know how to get a LIF award but I'm
going to I'm done in for one now that I
saw you guys have one I need I need a
lift award yeah definitely best resin
producer I think could be yeah you know
unfortunately I don't produce resin for
the market until it's federally allowed
once whe allow concentrates federally
then I myself would step up to the bat
and I would start producing resins um
with my company FH filtration processing
so and we'll be looking for you know
guys like yourself who are specializing
in learning how to really hammer it out
and you'll be able to when we when we do
that uh know that you're doing it under
patented license for the water
extraction process so we're under
license we're we're doing it and we're
paying for the process that that goes
along with it yeah exactly yeah so it's
exciting it is very exciting yeah yeah
man hope soon than later my God very
cool well man thanks for everything oh
pleasure really appreciate you guys
taking us through beautiful product and
uh I don't know what to say other than
uh keep watching Bubble man's world and
getting high getting high brother thanks
you got man anytime
[Music]