[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here down at the cchq on the second
floor of the vapor lounge and I'm with
Opus 420 hey hey how's it going dude
what's going excellent brother to see
you man very good to see always good to
see you uh ois and I were sitting and
talking for the last little bit and we
realized that we could have been filming
a little episode while we were sitting
and talking so we've got the uh the
motherships ready to go we were talking
about the difference between silicon
carbide right and quartz so I thought
maybe a fun little experiment for you
would be to have a rip of the same hash
on either surface and tell us what you
think I could do that so I've got a
bunch of uh d420 K hash o he gifted me
recently oh that's a call from Horatio
we have to uh take
a take a rain check on that
one little Variety in
there oh wow that's a uh just a mix
of different fragrances yes well we're
going to go with uh the all powerful uh
New York City Diesel which is a Soma
special looks almost like Wax this is
dry Sip and smell that
oh my God and it does awesome and it
does it looks just like Wax yeah and if
is that uh God uh quick froze uh this is
dry sifted uh not fresh frozen uh not
bubble hash but made with mechanical
screams just just sifted gently and then
cleaned using a couple uh different
techniques that we talk about on Bubble
man's world uh Darren would have used uh
carding static carding and uh
potentially the two gravity trick which
are all things that I cover on my
channel little tricks of the trade for
making hash but uh I want to start you
off
with the quartz all right um quartz now
takes a little bit more energy and a
little bit more heat to get it up to
temperature each time if you're using a
torch uh they've uh the guys at Dil have
done some pretty good
thermodynamics uh testing on both the
different uh sources not just the
different ones but quite a few uh from
Titan ium to ceramic so this will be uh
the New York City Diesel dryft on the
quartz oh wait
fail it's not on we haven't turned it on
yet but watch how fast we can fix this
fail plug that back in get that back on
get this back on the
Dabber we've got the units on and the
unit is climbing so hey sometimes you
can see when you have a little bit of a
fail with your denail like we just did
getting all stoned prior um you can fix
it pretty quick so I'm going to turn on
the dabinator as well just to make sure
both units are
on there's steps to things and we skip
one oh yeah sometimes it's fun to skip
steps until you put the hash in the
quartz and you're like nothing's going
on I think it's working man and it's
just sitting there hey awesome that's
not very melty well we're already at 429
de you you see the Dil doesn't take very
long to heat up it's going to get us up
to 700 it's usually within 2 minutes
it's one of the things I really like
about the the denail the quality I don't
know if it has anything to do with the
quality of the um components that he's
using but you can see that it's climbing
uh somewhat
faster yeah this one really is getting
up there fast yeah 620 630
mhm so I'd say once we get up to 700 I
would just let that heat for just a
minute or two and then we'll give you
the dab so you don't get that super slow
slow dab
on and that'll be the quartz hitting it
through the mothership Fab EG which is
also always a pleasure I love the
evenness of the mothership due to these
four little points in the glass it
brings the water up completely evenly
throughout the whole pipe it almost
feels like the pipe wants to take off
this is the most amazing piece I've ever
hit of um I have had the opportunity to
hit this a few times and absolutely
incredible it's was like oh my god I've
never hit any piece like that and I've
hit some pretty expensive pieces
actually your old store that you had on
Commercial Drive your gallery oh yes at
the the legends of bash yeah holy hey
that's going back now the legends of
hash was originally started in Amsterdam
however for the first three years that
we did it I coincided my Vancouver
gallery to do one as well so you got to
come to uh was a couple of those that's
awesome dude yeah those are few two of
them I think those are historic all
right so New York City Diesel on the
quartz slow ripping with Opus 420 at the
cchq it's nice to have the whole floor
to ourselves right now usually there's
quite a few people in the room and uh
I'm getting texts from Horatio saying
that he's at the door so I'm going to
let Opus tell you guys about a little
bit about that hit and I'm going to go
grab Horatio real
quick wow
that is uh first of all I got to say
that's quite different than hitting off
the uh titanium nail which is usually
what I do uh hit up um I use a highly
educated nail and uh heat it up with a
butane torch I can tell you this is
considerably
different uh extremely smooth and clean
um now I'm not sure if that's just due
to the uh the fact that the quality of
uh what we're smoking here this this dry
SI this wonderful Diesel doesn't that
taste unbelievable the pipe will
literally taste like that now for the
next 10 rips no matter what we put
through it oh are you kidding oh no I'm
not that's it it's obiously but the uh
again I was smoking This Mother Ship
this thing is I'm going to take a little
incredible thing to hit now to catch up
with you sure do that this is another
mother ship another Mothership a
straight Fab instead of blowing it out
into an egg it's just a straight and uh
this one has the silicone carbide nail
with the drop down
so this thing's almost as fun to watch
as it is to actually hit out
of just the evenness of the bubble
action is just perfect it really is it's
a pipe that deserves to be clean always
oh yes all I think any good piece of
glass deserves to be clean always
there's nothing kind of worse than and
I'm terrible for letting my pipes get
grunged up uh I have people comment all
the time they're like man that guy
smokes so much out of his out of his
pipes and they always seem to be clean
what do you clean them with uh you know
what one of my favorite cleaners to this
day is grunge off now grung off is a
product that's been um kind of is that
an automotive FR it really is in a sense
you can find it at Home Depot and it's
um not called grunge off but it's some
sort of an uh um orange no it's not
Orange it's from the soya bean it's an
enzyme or something something and it
makes this real a soap that feels like
that you can't get off your hands it
makes this weird kind of so if you soak
engine grease any sort of Grease it just
peels this stuff away and overnight you
could soak a bong and grunge off pour
the grunge off out rinse the pipe with
hot water and it's clean even from Salt
residue and little hard water marks that
it leaves on the glass sometimes and the
interesting thing is you can reuse it
over and over and over again even once
it's black and nasty and there's chunks
falling out of it much like the pur
power and those other I mean purple
Power is an ISO with sort of like a a
rock salt mixture in it and then they've
added color this is a little bit
different in the sense that it's an oil
it's not a solvent and that it really is
like reusable Beyond well I was just
pointing it
reusable product that's all I was merely
pointing yeah so I mean I use grof I
also use alcohol is isopropanol 99% I I
dislike using it as much as grunge off
cuz I can reuse it over and over again
the alcohol as I re use it it just I
find if I use dirty alcohol it just sort
of coats the pipe and in grunch I don't
like you reusing so I although I have
reused it to uh will soak a a nasty
piece in a small bowl or something that
you know has been let go I'll soak that
in used stuff yeah but then I'll give it
another clean later in a fresh toally
that's what I basically so yeah soak it
in the old crap is fine a drop down yeah
something that's hard to get clean and
uh so this one has this is a really cool
little carb cap and i' suggest that you
use it yourself and it just it's going
to go on top of the the Silicon there's
a little hole in the top that you can
carb actually right there right there
yeah and then uh you'll see when you're
hitting the pipe with it on there that
you can seal it the more you can seal it
the better rip you'll get and I mean
constrict it completely almost so you're
just like and you'll really get the rip
so uh okay let's do this is the silicon
carbide same hash not giving it Monster
rips just a nice little taste test and
remember slow and steady is going to win
this
race yeah move that around and you'll
kind of eventually it goes click and
it's like whoa it's quite an interesting
feeling how well this ID dab carb cap uh
fits onto the silicon carbide bowt
literally in at one point just
constricts so perfectly that you can't
even hear the pipe
barely bubbling right
now Opus
420 this is not his first rodeo I used
to go visit Opus on the island and he
had just this beautiful grow he was
always really well known for his uh
burmes uh [ __ ] incredible or just
Burmese bures Burmese it was so good
such awesome uh strain had some
specialness to it for sure you know well
it was a beautiful fenal uh me and uh
myself and two of my buddies that I grew
with on the island uh the three of us
kept that string going for uh I think it
was like 11 years that one cutting
that's awesome yeah and uh and she
produced and
really uh was pleased a lot of people
were pretty happy with that one
so that was uh yeah that was actually
Michelle rainy's second most favorite
scen yes next to her uh next to her bull
rider next to the bull rider which you
know you got to give some props to um
Jeff uh to Jeff but also to Raz now a
lot of people don't know about Raz but
Raz was actually with Michelle before
Jeff and Raz um and Jeff were really
good friends of course you know when a
woman gets in between you can have a
little bit of a problem there which is
understandable but um he uh Raz made a
point on getting Jeff the bull rider
from San Diego so he was very crucial in
getting that because he knew the guys in
San Diego really well and he was able to
get that cut Jeff took that cut and then
crossed it with the Afghani and came up
with the bull rider the Afghan bull
rider which he gave you know a lot of
people talked about Jeff saying he
wasn't sharing that strain I asked Jeff
one time for that strain and he gave it
to me within 12 hours so Props to Jeff
Tech for kicking down a strain that
seemingly people were saying was hard to
get it it always lets you know when
someone really wants you to have a
strain or they don't when you you ask
them for it and you have it 12 hours
later no one has ever given me a cut
that fast in my life so Props to Jeff
Tech as well and of course rip Michelle
we think about you daily uh gone but
never forgotten I uh I wish we were
upstairs because there's a big beautiful
picture of you we'll uh we'll show it
over this video while we're talking
about there you go yeah we think about
you so how did you feel about that this
uh definitely hits well first of all the
unit hits quite differently than the egg
it does and uh that card cap is that's
something that uh is to be
experienced right you had an amazing hit
too I I was watching it like the bong's
not making any sound right now I slowed
that went down like I was like okay I
I'm a champion B hitter I smoke a pipe
all the time I'm a regular pipe smoker
so I'm used to smoking a pipe right so I
understand the whole point of
controlling the your to and not like all
the time so you don't you know people
are always like taking a to off the pipe
and like choking on it like go no no you
can't smoke it like a joint you got to
take it easy pull right you're just
going to hurt yourself slow they're like
like they're trying that the wonder why
they're coughing and you're packing nugs
in there too so to go slow with I mean I
haven't done I remember when I've grind
an her been putting in ground hers right
when I first met marbl Slinger he was
like all East Coast guy putting the the
big buds in the bowl and he just
couldn't wrap his head around that I
couldn't wrap my head around that right
I was just like I was already getting
into at that point really being a
full-blown hashish guy so well actually
when I got into the uh Bubble Bags doing
water hash um it's going back and yeah
and I was actually making uh the bubble
with the burmes and also with uh some
Island sweet skunk that I was growing
out and I had to actually make a rule
that I wouldn't smoke the 73 Micron
bubble before 5:00 right right otherwise
because I had this this double bubbler
Destroyer hype and I would be like
across town and be like I got to go cuz
I have to go home and smoke hash I'm
Jones I need to go home and have another
hit of bubble hey on that note I hope
you guys watching right now are going to
hit a hit a bubble we're going to do one
more round and then uh who knows maybe I
might be on op's uh show on Monday
Monday where and they can check that out
on PO TV po TV and hear it on this
second floor you have your own YouTube
channel as well I have a YouTube channel
you can go actually I have two YouTube
channels and unfortunately you're both
the same well let give them one but it's
a mickman m i k m a n mcmah that's the
YouTube mcmah and that's my YouTube
channel it was uh previously Opus 420
but they made me change it really yeah
it was all that issues with the Google
and you know real names and oh wow
various problems like that and since I
already had 900 followers on the one
channel I had set up another and then
it's all kind of was confusing but it's
the one where you'll see a picture of me
and uh it's a closeup straight on head
shot yep and where I'm actually split in
half and one side of me is me and the
other half and I'm looking like uh doing
my impression of um Heisenberg from
Breaking Bad ah Heisenberg we've all
done our impression of Heisenberg well
my good friend Goodwood actually uh
cropped that picture in half oh really
yeah with a picture of uh the actor
there cranon um yeah Brian Brian cranon
and surprisingly enough I look just like
him in the picture like the picture
actually does it was like oh my God like
so it's kind of
funny so but that's how you know you're
on the right YouTube channel look at
that wow literally that just broke in my
hands that was the glass yeah that's
okay it's still going to
work all right all right here we go
mildly disappointed but still ready for
a
dab I about like it better as a
stubby yeah it didn't take off a
functional piece really so that was the
Goji ogi and that was
completely a different taste profile
from uh what we just finished hitting
the New York City Diesel there if you
feel like having a rip on either of
these nails by all means let me know
yeah we will dab you
up p on this one right here to the front
I actually kind of I actually think you
know to be honest with you I like this
one a little bit better yeah yeah with
the carb with the carb all
right nice and gentle gentle does it
not like the He-man the He-man snapping
of
the well luckily it broke pretty blunt
too dancing
around
Beauty look at that
by far the quietest bong I've ever
ripped in my life it is pretty funny
once you get this thing on at the right
uh at the right it just like it's like
my cat purring totally awesome that's
that's absolutely delicious and smooth I
they tell you that's as smooth as
15-year-old whiskey yeah shout out to D4
20K for the great dry sift and uh your
grow team there chilling it representing
here in Vancouver
we're going to continue on guys but
we'll see you guys soon on Bubble man's
world
peace welcome back guys we are now with
Horatio and Matt the great gardeners in
the house for a short time welcome both
of you guys how's it going everybody
it's going very good I just took a rip
of your uh warlock full Mount what was
that 73 Micron or that one was the 90
the 90 Micron it was definitely proper
that's great is fantastic the Barb looks
even more ridiculous the Barb is always
ridiculous this one's the 73 and then I
didn't even realize Horatio Al also had
Ridiculousness out on the
table that's a pretty good color right
there that's um that's the death Bubba
without the Seven Star ah and then this
is some MK Ultra ah Seven Star this is
what you said was ridiculous right yeah
okay cuz that cuz that was one of the
ones we smelt that I can't remember if
that one's grandma or that one's carrot
right but it was one of the has this one
greased up
at one point I haven't see the the fun
thing about these is I don't know yeah
that has tur but um I seal it then I
freeze it for a week and then pretty
much I open it when I get here so I
never really know the consistency week
to week so looking at this one this has
got more of a cakey less ooey gooey to
it this stuff was like sand I took it
out of the freezer this morning it was I
just poured it into these jars and
now it looks like just pure brown sugar
though they not coming out yeah that's
that's some rocked up
sugar it's pretty crystally that one's
the Warlock again yeah I think I'm most
eager to taste this Barb it looks so
nice in the
[Music]
sun I feel like I just pulled like a
single head into each eye as I smell
that I can't wait I can't wait to share
all these in Span Abus dude you're going
to be like walking around you be Barb
I put the post on last night I was like
hey if you see me in spanis ask me for a
where will you be every single post is
like I will ask I will ask I'm asking
for sure I will ask well you better ask
him when you see him in Span I hope to
be there as well I've got a trip to
Jamaica right before but I'm not one to
back away from a a Barcelona trip love
the city love the venue so I'm
definitely going to try to be there best
show love
Barcelona we'll probably go over to the
HQ headquarters play some Russian pool
with the
boys def over to the resin Club probably
go
to is it strain The Strain Hunters Club
yeah stra hun stra Hunters Club
beautiful those are like the three clubs
that you'll see me at in fact they're
fantastic might even do a private night
um at HQ with David and EDU and I'm sure
all the the our good friends will be
there I'm not sure what day that's going
to happen yet but we've uh hinted at it
so yeah hopefully that'll it'll be
something that occurs and we can all get
together and dab ourselves
silly what do you think of the 2D Now
set up oh man that the wood the wood car
reminds me of old school the old kit my
parents bought me when you right pulled
out the wood burning kit yeah know it's
pretty sweet when we used to get things
like that as kids would burn wood
burning kit and the lawn darts and we
had all the safe toys as children Barb
was spectacular by the way oh nice yeah
that tasted great right off the courtz
water hash too wow
were what's
that you want to hit something before I
go hit something before I go why are you
leaving right now got to go I got to get
going yeah I I got to catch the the
flight maybe you should uh hit hit
something on your way out a little Barb
or the Seven
Star let try that this one here that
one's uh five star this that's just you
could say regular what do you mean by
five star I guess it was just my regular
best 10
Stars I didn't know either bizar
Brothers down in California have a
rating system that they rate their full
m hash and they kind of created it for
their own a hash making but then they
have a little spot where people would
come and you could buy hash and enjoy it
at their little spot there it was based
on a star rating and basically like the
superb like full full full melt drip
right through the screen that's a six he
just came up with the Seven Star
recently their systemar the seven star
is manmade like was that was that a
title like bestowed on you of sort of
seven star status it is one of those
things that when you've defined it you
have to be able to isolate TPS in order
to create SAR he put back TPS that would
otherwise be lost in the drying process
so he's collecting those turps out of
fresh plants and then reconstituting
them back into the dry sift at a
particular ratio Seven Star Seven Star
it's attempt at the wet dry it's what
fresh frozen on the carbide nail on the
carbide nail excited to use the carbide
nail as excited as I am to hit Seven
Star there you go what better way to hit
the Seven Star than off the carbide
that's just
nice bummed that she broke but she broke
so perfect I can still dab with her no I
know other than the fact that there's
broken remnants of her on the table
therea clean my nose is
tickling it's the actual strain cuz I
did that I made it in the LA I'm like oh
my God I got nose pickle this is bad and
it's the actual uh tpine profile of that
MK Ultra so I really want to go back
into the the alcohol and the water turps
and pretty much figure out where in The
Taste did that profile go cuz I remember
you had noticed orange in the alcohol
but not in the water and I was like I
wonder where that Citrus lies in the
final product if it's pretty much saying
I'm only in this jar so cuz he's got the
hydrol like the alcohol tpin and the
water tpin as well my are you doing a
steam distillation just with the that
would turn all the plant material into
spinach if you if you no plant material
like just the with the wash
from the bubble bags that goes through
like essentially the hydro the hydrol I
don't think people are trying to collect
it from water well with the when you try
to collect the hydrol the first problem
is it's filthy so what do you put in the
plant what's you together put the plant
into a solution you extracting that well
hold on hold on hold on I'm questions
look I'm getting the eyes over here like
going too deep I'm liking it go deep
well it's um what it is is reveal the
secret well what it is is you're like
you're asking over here and you're
asking over here and I'm like wait a
minute are we talking about the bubble
hash water we talking basically you
could you 331 tell now he's got a flight
to catch the best we can do is we can
clean the bubble hash water to this so
that's mku water yeah
what oh I got some on there it's all
right it's all right he drinks it it's
all right that one's the alcohol it's
the hyp so try that or snip that and
snip the
alcohol this is a special occasion see
this one smells this one sort of smells
like like uh that's got a cushy smell
though this one smells like you're doing
like bubble hat or something then you're
like your water's running through the
screens yeah this one smells like that
fresh like oh it's the resin yeah so if
you taste this where does the taste
compared to the smell come off tast it
go for it m al water
Tes how's
that and then compare it to the mku
alcohol alcohol which I I'm flying not
driving turpins modulators
I don't drink alcohol come on no I don't
that's why I give it to people to taste
I'm like I don't know how much alcohol
in this is but I can't drink
0.5 booze basically alcohol-free booze I
can't touch right so I basically if I
take about half of this and mix it in a
whole bottle of soda then I can drink it
and it tastes
insane uh the up strrretch on this is
insane the water turps are great they're
still like tasting strong on my lips and
T I don't know but that one that one
sort of right in the face so this
is all a sudden it just sort of like
that sort of like hit me in the back of
the throat and sort of washed me forward
this is the one I'm hoping I possibly
could get back out of the bubble hash
water but the honest truth is I'm not
working with bubble hash water so I
would have to have the opportunity's
what are you putting here full plan
solution
into that is uh question the 20 m dollar
question I guess the best way of putting
it is I am using water to get them um
it's so you're just putting a whole
plant in the water freezing it putting
the whole plant in the water no that's
um that that if I even kind of hinted
that that was the I'd be leading you in
the wrong direction um if anything I'm
taking advantage of the water that's in
the plant and where it is in the plant
I'm not
at so I'm using the pressing it coal
pressing it well no I'm only going to
give so much what I can give is me so
much I absolutely using the water that
is within the tag me on my Instagram at
Great Gardener if you think he's using
the cold press technique let's start the
discussion look at these guys they're
both like uh well no could be I love the
discussion goes where's that discuss
press this by their this by their
mannerisms you be like oh man look at
ratio he's getting queasy he want
look we need a hit we need to take a dab
I'm always all right I got to goony all
right dude awesome scene Everybody Take
It Easy brother safe flight all Stu
works for you the we will uh see you
when we see you all right take it easy
totally Spain the most Spain it's coming
I can feel it awesome all right uh
Horatio and I are going to uh continue
this you can dab out on that stuff what
we're going to continue it elsewhere
remember to share with those guys the
corner wait did we hear this straight
folks dab out what we know see you guys
later take it easy all right guys
welcome back we are now at we're at
ignite yep yep so this is Ryan and
Brandon's Place yep basement Lounge this
is my first time here in the basement
Lounge at ignite but come check them out
what is the cross streets that they're
located out there what are we Abbot and
Pender right here Abbot and Pender ab
and Cordova abbit and Cordova that's
what it is abbit and Cordova so come
check out ignite they've got some pretty
uh good good glass up there and a whole
bunch of other little little sort of
glass jars and trinkets and silicone
thingies so uh yeah come check it out
we're downstairs they got this little
Lounge I'm not sure what the rule is to
get down here if you have to have a
Compassion Club card or a uh mm license
or whatnot is that not sure but it's got
some pretty banging beats on the weekend
so I think when it's not a vapor lounge
um DJ's spinning on the one and two
something pretty Fierce okay yeah yeah
pretty pretty chill group of people
hanging out so definitely come Che check
it out and uh we're going to continue
our conversation which we were uh in the
middle of kind of continuing with Matt
Matt was uh really pressing on Horatio
to see how he does things of course
Horatio hasn't finished how he does
things he's in the middle of discovering
how he does things so it's a little bit
hard to uh each week is different you
see this consistent nothing like last
week's Seven Star so I mean is that I'm
starting with this week's Seven Star how
about that check out right into it this
is the MK yep and so Seven Star this is
dry that uh Horatio has readded um tpin
that he's extracted from the plant using
uh a technique know well I mean the M
the main thing to really emphasize is
from the same material that derived the
dry SI cuz obviously when you imagine
some people have an infinite amount of
uh plant material they can uh produce
effects that um aren't necessarily you
could say um industrial standard or a
process so um my real goal is been
I these TPS that we're looking at right
here came from those heads that uh we're
smoking on and they just returned to
their Source after it's properly been
dried which is naturally what needs to
be done in order to sit excellent very
cool let me give a little Whi this is
the mku yeah
oil you got to be so careful when
opening a v like this it's very
Priceless in a sense on I can't recreate
it's yeah it's just it's very very few
drops you certainly don't want to uh
it's the perfume it's the the the pure
essence of the of the plant minus the
phyto can abono mhm tarpine
delicious so do you want to taste that
off the sil car or did you want to taste
it off the silicone carbide here a real
easy method to do that oh
yeah is the nail comes up
go so
put that
there slider there that out of your
way I love uh how I can change these
nails in mid use especially with
obviously if this one had the drop down
it would be even
easier so you're going to give a rip on
that did this uh
did this white out or I'm just kind of
pressing it I never really know well I
mean the the I wondered what the
final preserved end would be if you do
reintroduce what is naturally a part of
The Preserve you have to remove this to
preserve it so if I reintroduce it what
is the end result are we is this
basically now a fresh seasonal only know
we know that tping can act as a solvent
so if it was a a fraction of pure
turkins it would be one thing we be able
to which ones were which but because
it's a profile of tpin you'd have to get
it tested and find out what in here
could potentially act to break down the
yeah cuz this definitely even in the
fact it wasn't as you could say um live
resin like as last week it definitely
seems to make a different style of cake
and that may just be the amount of resin
heads left in it sure the wax sure
melted out beautifully and took on the
the proper look when I hit when it hit
the nail that's
she stuck for a while now she's boiling
was interesting
here this what really makes the size of
this nail much uh thought I was going to
tip you over there pull you right
down so starting with the seven star is
always a great way to start uh uh an
episode with
Horatio even though we're kind kind of
in the middle of an episode right now as
we've already talked to Matt the great
Gardener and we've talked to Opus
420 and uh yeah now we're just going to
continue on with a great little session
you got your hydrosols your water
soluble your water Turin yeah so now
your pure trines yeah just I'm always
because these don't go back so this
alcohol portion is always fractured out
that's kind of I always wanted to know
if do you smell any of that portion in
the actual um the heads cuz this has
always been the most
unique now if you want which one did you
just grab the MK Ultra without the turps
yeah I had both or the Bubba king sorry
oh bubble King yeah which the last time
I had this the first time I had seven
star it was Bubba King it was death
Bubba oh sorry death Bubba right yeah so
now here's a
pure got a nice uh texture to it that's
sure little gooey and
gummy
thing well I mean because I'm in the you
could say the experimenting Arts of
preserving I'm getting to see uh what
the consequences are on the different
the different heads the different melts
um you know kind of I haven't done much
macro lately just because I've been so
busy but um I really wish I could uh
start macroing the stages of here it is
now I just touched it here it is after a
week cuz typically when I make it I seal
it and then I freeze it and you're
usually out of the country until now so
I kind of Let It Go for a weak cure in
the freezer to see what what that
natural process will do well I'm going
to be leaving the country again really
soon here head back to Jamaica go check
out um the high the it called the I keep
forgetting the name each time but it's a
Rass Bobby's putting on a cup in neg
Grill so I'm going to go down there and
judge that and speak on a panel and then
we're going to do the neutr cutical
conference in
Kingston should all be good stuff I'm
looking forward to it and the soccer
match which I've mentioned a few times
and I'll probably mention a few more
times posted the soccer match poster on
my Facebook page if you want to check it
out it's worth checking out it's like
the Kingston artists versus the St
Catherine artists playing a big football
match G to be serious and then the other
one is the Jamaican con conary Force
versus the Spanish
youth the youths of Spanish Town the
youths of Spanish Town versus the
Jamaican it's going to be good soccer
yeah it's going to be good man it's
going to be pretty uh a lot of Pride
getting thrown about
right there this is next week's strain
it hasn't been sifted uh
the MK you kind of uh it's the first
time I've ever crashed my screens pretty
much is what I'd like to call it you you
finally make I thought I had environment
under control I thought I had strains I
thought I knew variables but this mku is
pretty much probably the closest thing
if I've never sifted the Barb but I
would imagine it must be a day like this
on the races
where yeah today today was my fail Tech
uh 15° C average room temperature no
dice no dice and um once I saw it and I
saw I'm like whoa that's I can see my
hand shape in the screen I'm like okay
this is this is going to be some of my
best sift whatever I get back but um
needed to work in a much colder
environment
obviously whatever whatever soft was
soft whatever these I've always been
able to work the mku pretty much
recently what I think is I looked at it
here's the thing you will see many many
many different differences in the resin
over years and even decades well when I
first started these res I was like this
is awesome and I'm like whoa whoa whoa
wait buddy as soon as you think you're
awesome that's when you're going to get
your ass handed to cuz someone will say
well then SI the bag of this and you're
so for instance in my case if someone
comes up to me and they oh I just
learned to this I did I'm like I got
some mku for you
uh let's see what you got going cuz
that's what I mean these Bubba King
these are soft and I'm an environmental
controls guy this
mku it is re that's kind of why I'm
wondering now I'm like is this the
equivalent of the Barb where is the Barb
have you ever had a bad days race with
the Barb when it comes to
sifting and you got to admit that is
insane expect to get this through screen
that's well I know that's not even the
dry set it is
go damn love the Barb I got a Barb
blooming in my tent right now as well as
a gg1 The Afghani from uh great Gardener
both of those are maybe a week away from
me cutting them down and running them
through the bags they're not huge plants
they're not going to have an enormous
amount of resin on them but I'll get
some grams of each one
EXC dar excited yeah so I guess looking
at um like I said M KU is by far the
most difficult I've ever touched and I
looked at what I thought yeah that's
pretty difficult but I can handle it my
environment can handle it my skills can
handle it my patience can handle it so
the other guy's going to [ __ ] up but
today was my day it's one of those
things where I'm like okay I didn't [ __ ]
up I did I did get out but I didn't like
how
I I couldn't work as fast as I wanted to
work I couldn't I wasn't in control I
was in heed of the strain that's kind of
where so where would if I was to smell a
bag and anticipate a day's work could
would you say follow the turps in my
nose to how the profile or would it be
by um more the genetics no I would say
that if you're going to be making sift
on the regular or even not on the
regular but here and there that you're
just going to want to understand the
importance of controlling the variable
that is the temperature of your room and
that warmth is the enemy even when it
might not seem that warm to you resin
reacts very differently to the
atmospheric changes like humidity and
temperatures if you can just make it
like lower the humidity and lower the
temperature resin suddenly becomes like
a dream to
work it's that's kind you see the stress
in my voice cuz I'm like I do those
things I'm in control I know how to I
control the resin and that's kind of why
I
like like I said I made but I realize
I'm like oh my gosh if some poor bastard
and it's your and you think you're going
to clean up something and this is what
you come
across you are not there's you have to
build my room to suck to suck like me at
it right this is um I kind of wish we
started to kind of develop a list it's
usually when you hear oh it sared on me
I'm like it's your environment dude but
I'm like okay this bypassed my
environment and that environment has
worked for everything well once people
have a a larger knowledge of what's
going on such as like the proton hm
these different forms of testing for
different things you know then then
it'll be a little bit more solid in the
sense like okay we know that
this these canids were in there yeah cuz
right now if you literally
if someone just said this is a sift off
um sift for your life and smell the bag
you want to work with um that's kind of
why I'm like okay wait a minute this has
been a rough day what can I smell in
this that I can smell in the Barb I know
the Barb is hard work is it a fruity
tone is it a there's almost sometimes A
Min when it's a good cush it's a
minerally kind of
um I can't I can't T it just it's like a
a mineral good kind of smell and um I
don't know if it's that cush so
been trying to find similarities where
I'm like I know that fruity taste I
smell it in the bar whether it's Lola
whatever it may be you find it in the
testing before we get a test I want to
know this is going to happen cuz I was
lucky enough I can push a button I can
get through but I'd love to know that's
going to happen by smell because I feel
like there were guys that could do that
on experience they kind of they could
smell the bag they could just have that
sense of what kind of days work it was
cuz
when I was um luckily I can experience
the fresh plant so I knew people were
having trouble trimming it I could see
it in the scissors and I'm like okay
it's showing up in the scissors showing
up in the SI it's showing up in the LA
CH it's in this strain I can count on
that but that's not a science to say
that shows up guaranteed someone else
could grow that strain you don't see it
well that's what that's what I mean cuz
if I don't see it and it's a real clone
that means it's really in the news and
that's cuz that's what I'm getting a
sense of I'm like I've had a few of
those where I'm like okay organic versus
inorganic certain things turned out the
same the flesh was the same but the
nutrients were way different and I'm
like wow the one that was on Commercial
nudes it every description online that's
what it read like I'm like wow you
really taste like um the Kool-Aid
packaging says um everyone's description
of it but then when I tried the organic
one I was like wow this is a lie this is
like the LIE version juice that late
with Bas off cuz I really like that
warlock um you probably had years of
experience with it but it was my first
time today and
uh yeah it's not like the coues I mean
like I'm not
a I'm not a cush man but
uh I'm not either usually like let me
get the exha or somebody else's exhale
but um was that the Barb or was that the
you reach for was the Warlock it's yeah
it's
uh's your
car super tasty obviously from the great
Gardener always always good flavors from
Matt always nice flavors from Horatio
working on different things with tur
addition we're just going to continue to
pop along here we might catch up with
you guys in a little bit at another
venue for
now thanks for
watching feel good give
[Music]
me one man HR man
real the purpose after the weed to the
mind
purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we let I
view the
time it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
ding well I've been traveling to
Kingston 20 M hours sing on like the CL
fresh vation with trees and with flowers
[Music]
off I
make B pass
[Music]
pass PA that
now purp of the weed that keeps me going
the purpose after weed that's to the
Mind purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine on the road there
be some cops setting up them plat
alls
man we
me inter in my bra that and behind your
scene me and my team have another
25 smoke it
[Music]
clean man
and Pass and Pass and Pass