[Music]
hey what's up welcome to Bubble man's
world puff Wednesday with medtainer John
dude uh we're just uh where are we going
to go Mega ill Mega ill uh we're not
going to get mega ill we're going to go
to Mega ill Mark Clo's uh pizza place uh
Med friendly we're able to bring the
denail and a couple other all of our
hash your herb and we're allowed to
blaze down in mega we're just over at uh
Mark emer's bcmp you can kind of see the
herb museum is right behind us here
David Malmo lavine's herb Museum you
guys should check them out if you
haven't they got a Facebook page and I
believe they have an Instagram account
as well but uh yeah why don't we head
down John let's do this let's do
this yeah pretty stoked last week we
tried to do puff Wednesdays and go to
Mega ill and I ended up having to go
back home uh bring my wife her car back
and
so today we're going to make
it all
right check out Mark emer's cannabis
culture headquarters down on Hastings
when you get a chance too see you guys
at Mega illm
[Music]
[Applause]
classic Vancouver
traffic oh well Mega ill will be well
worth the wait
call call completed
that don't
there
giveing out here hey what's up we're
back and it's [ __ ]
cold holy Christ anyway we're right out
in front of Mega ill you guys want to
check it out there's the
sign a nice sign with you're 646
Kingsway Street in between Carolina and
Fraser why don't we head in all right
cannabis friendly environment please
what's that right there look at that
cannabis friendly environment plus 18
please beautiful that's that's a nice W
all right take a
in
warmth what's up guys enjoying some
pizza and puffs yeah yeah Mega ill and
in no way was this set up for this shot
what's up
Jesse not on all
right so to be here at Mega ill how to
uh jacket
off check out the menu and set up the
denail so we'll be back in a bit right
on now now you have to get
sound oh you got that oh perfect we
don't need to hear right
now you the news
tonight all right
want to help set this up John get you
that
anyway the plug uh right over here is
the plug
so yeah did we get everything out of
there we need
Perfect all right setting up the day
all right
so and there we go for
[Music]
that all
right bu man here back with John we've
uh got our jackets off and the dnails
all plugged in John's checking up the
menu I'm going to do a quick dab of
something wonderful I'm thinking uh
maybe some House of the great Gardener
oh what did we get we got sweet skunk
99% pure heads dry sift so that's some
real nice product right there the D
Nails plugged in and ready to go what
are you thinking over there John uh you
know what pizza wise I'm thinking maybe
this uh the Rambo caramelized onions
aroke gr Peppers mushrooms shaved
Parmesan
pretty much guarantee that's a buin and
Mel man that sweet
skunk gets you every
time just such an
incredible flavor and taste on that
strain more people should have the sweet
skunk in their Garden
what a great smell for us to uh to be
lighting up here at the uh Mega
ill you can check thank you here you go
sir you can grab it I trust you pass the
heads he's a professional
[Music]
people well I might go plain Jan I've
always been pretty simple with my
pizzas blow that out your nose I dare
you
it's incredible the spice I'm like I'm
tearing up now from blowing that rip out
my nose I can't
BL so much lovely hash you got some nice
herb there that was uh you grow that for
100 101 days 101 days all right well
that's just special yeah but this is uh
we made that fresh frozen on the on the
on the side of the glacier there well
this is the chamus bubble this is the
cheek miss bubble Pony I kept this going
for another 35 days when this was at Day
70 remember or day 76 so I let this keep
going so this is this 35 days longer
than what that was a day 84 very cool
like this crazy we've got a sublimator
set up here so maybe we'll uh hit a
little bit of that herb later be nice it
hit some flavors and you know what on
that let's order up some pizza and uh
maybe they'll let us go into the back
and show you their skills of making
making the pizza and popping it in the
oven probably throw some hash in there
oh maybe we'll throw some hash in we'll
be back in a
bit I figured it'd
be he going to get maybe Pan the uh
ingredients oh yeah I'm really soed
on it's it's a good thing
one of the first pictures Mark posted I
was like yeah I was like holy [ __ ] he's
got someone that knows what they're
doing I know this man this guy I I like
I've worked with some top chefs right
it's always a key just man just to see
somebody that's even younger than me
just be amazing like that with food it's
like and you can't open a restaurant
without that just like if you wanted to
open up a place that had B bouncing for
trampolines you better have an acrobat
you better some someone with passion and
the love really blow people's minds yeah
and so yeah this uh the minute I saw
that pizza I was like woohoo definitely
want to try it that's homemade sauce huh
oh yeah so you guys made the sauce yeah
everything everything we make here is uh
from scratch that's real right away you
look at that you see that Big Tomato
chunk that's the real deal some people
will be like oh get rid of that chunk
that's what lets you know it's real
yeah got to make it tasty holy Christ oh
right off the bat when do you see that
yeah people are getting away from
actually the real Pizza you know or the
just the concept of cooking all it
together you know what I mean M
everything's got to be squished and out
of a container nowadays you know yeah
it's not
right no it's nice to have the passion
of just the very thing you're doing
right now is almost an art form and a
meditative process yeah you know you're
putting your energy into the Pizza it
puts my me into zen that's for sure
that's funny he said that well it's cuz
it is you can tell it's a
meditative process like from the
kneading to the it's really kind of like
art like you just created your canvas
and then you painted it and then you
added texture better it's pretty cool
kind of like art way better than art
it's medal art what do we got there uh I
don't know what that is caramel
caramalized onions I was going to say
[Music]
holy killer delicious yeah stoked stoked
to be here at the mega ill P definitely
digging it what a cool concept you know
like we've really come a long way in
our view on cannabis use I've always
dreamed of a day where alcohol and
tobacco weren't the main focuses of a
Food Industries right like come on like
I know that's a that's another thing for
me
I just hope it doesn't go uh like too
too commercial you know what I mean like
well I think McDonald's I think there an
aspect of it will but as long as they
allow us to have our our other levels
then I won't have a problem with their
commercialism commercialism will always
feed the masses yeah and the masses need
to be fed too right so but for those
that choose and this would be better to
feed a bunch of massive people than well
that's it they just did a preview uhal
girl or criminal and show you oh my God
okay I got to go
watch the oven and that's a thanks yeah
no problem I love olives yeah you lovees
I'll look
you on which one the Rambo or which one
you get which one did I get I can't
remember
yeah uh we have a fraboni what is it
freab okay it's not like that all right
he makes those Med containers what's
that makes the med containers yeah the
med can or Med Cade or whatever
yeah tribute to my
ex plain
Jan which she's nothing like
[Music]
man like that
so John tell us what we just saw in the
news the little clip the little clip
well it says um legal grower or criminal
and I actually did a little interview
with TTV news actually not little huge
interviews with TTV news yesterday for
about 3 hours and my story is coming on
in about 10 minutes and the way they
just progressed that was legal for a
criminal is I'm about ready to show what
a legal grower does when how he produ
medicine it's kind of cool but I'm too
nice well we'll check it out it's going
to come on here soon St you guys some P
oh that looks
killer one did you get I got
the awesome
[Music]
happy and I got the
J this looks just Jane doesn't look
Plain Jane that look you know what I
love about the Plain Jane and even yours
is the Hat between them
wonderful thank you so much
Eno smokes it to relieve pain right now
John Bell has a license to do it legally
but as of April 1st production will be
shifted from small Growers to large
commercial operations leaving people
like Bellow pet Granger has
more former construction worker John
gfell has a license from Health Canada
for his personal grow up for years he's
on a disability penchion after a fall on
a construction site 9 years ago the left
side of his body is weired with broken
bones they healed but nerve damage
remains he's in constant pain and
allergic to pharmaceutical painkillers
marijuana allows him to function one p
is of all Beads it's like this pain is
like Bam Bam Bam with cannabis and then
something this
like still there it's just not as hard
he's created his own particular strains
perfected for his particular pain coming
revers new federal regulations will
limit Le the production to a handful of
industrialized Growers they'll only be
producing a limited number of strains no
Edibles oils or creams at a price that's
four or five times higher for me it's
all about finding exactly what it takes
for you to function and
and I've I spent years researching St
and now the government wants to take it
all away that must make you rib
man I
[Music]
scared scared
no I'm like what am I going to
do heard lawyer John Conroy is trying to
help her fellow and the other 177,000
licensed personal pot growers in DC by
suing the federal government it's more
than just affordability affordability is
a huge barrier according to the study
but also the control over your own
medicine what goes into it and so on CL
says the new rules ignore a citizen's
constitutional right to reasonable
access to the medicine they
need and thousand could soon become
criminals unless the courts agree Health
Canada has gone too far Peter Greer CTV
News
generous that was great John really that
was totally a great story did great I
love
youren you know what that was I was a
little scared how they're going to cover
that I think they covered it as well as
they possibly could with the cut to
Conroy and
everything that was great and then of
course tricking us with the design R
story
right oh that pizza was so
good d420 K to the
table don't
the some 99% gland head
dry and this is the OG cush and luckily
the denail is always ready
which were your olypic
[Music]
dreams I mean really what is better than
eating great pizza in a good environment
and then taking a rip of your favorite
whatever it is you're puffing
on I am sold on Mega ill the food's
great I'm stoked on the people and I can
smoke my hash here with no
judgment no
judgment wooo
[Music]
beautiful so John just hit the My Little
Pony I believe it was the chus River
bubble hash that we made a few episodes
back Russ's
the
world givey the camera a
rip I'll give him the dryft you can
ninja him the my little Tony oh
ninja and I'll take the camera is the
organic
[Music]
ninja that dry sip just went it was like
it it melted into nothing
yeah buddy and the bubble just came back
suddenly how was that so Anthony is
often doing camera work for the weed guy
Mark and uh yeah
kush.com ill as he often is and just
helping us out with some camera
work thanks bro don't problem any time
all
right to the
camera all right cameraman's always down
for a rep
[Music]
beautiful making you go big what's that
I made you go big well don't oh look at
this now he's like now ch
[Music]
oh thank you for making me go go
big that was the kind of dessert I
[Music]
love all right oh I think
going this one I think
wow yeah that was I don't think we're
done yet the OG no we're going to
continue to pop holes for sure
absolutely
many
[Music]
flavors that one's the Barb dry sift
that I I cleaned up um Barb is
shishkaberry crossed with an
Afghan and it is absolutely splendidly
oh yeah
[Music]
I this right here would be like a hurt
someone
hit yeah that's why you're making it for
yourself you guys up for a rip on the
Dil yeah sure sure all
right of course it's always
nicer when you're sharing oh yeah
sharing is caring sharing is caring all
right that
okay got over the side you
howy all
right so yeah this is the Barb Afghani
Shish Berry
cross bubble up
[Music]
nicely might be able to get you a little
light in
there barbs bubbling away
nice delicious
delicious all right burn off a little
bit no
problem all right here we go for a fresh
[Music]
one is that a hash yeah that's dry
sift so no water no chemicals no nothing
just screen sifted resin
sweet yeah the denail is kind of like
learning to hit a whole new way it's not
really a quick blast right it's more
like a I lost my breath quicker than
anything yeah but it's so slow too
sometimes like the residual smoke it's
still there for you and usually I have a
carb cap uh that I'll put over the
quartz little quartz carb
cap sweet thanks dude oh hell yeah
dude you ready for another flavor John
thank you yeah right on
guys were you ready for more pizza I was
thinking
uh dessert dessert desserts on the house
tonight boys oh wow yeah all right well
let's get the
dessert sounds good that sounds awesome
what are you H for yourself um I don't
know that one's so Barb so where I bring
Barb
Barb sweet
Scar and then oh this one this is the
[Music]
one it's all stuck together
that's just
uh kind of peel some off there
first bounce oo you're going to want to
hit that J that's that really strong
cush after after what let you take your
own and this is some dry stuff that you
bounced that's the first bounce of of
uh My Little Pony oh
great well never a Bad Thing fun
[Music]
flavors Baked full content stoked on
John's news
story I guess we're going to continue to
puff and we'll be back with Dess
so this is the twice baked cheesecake
with h blueberry
compost and this one is a organic apple
crumble with uh vanilla ice cream and
maple bacon and they've both been
sprinkled with hemp Parts with hemp
parts and a little drizzel of uh vegan
coconut chocolate syrup seriously D come
on we're doing it here it's awesome all
right and we can puff yeah that's the
bigest thing he's like here I'm going
right up I'm going to go vegetarian
first and then uh here we'll clean a few
Bacons off and you can that's just the
bacon that's that's the only bacon that
and then I'll just have that'll be my
ice cream guess I don't eat bacon but I
will still eat this this looks
unbelievable patience must get the
blueberry
[Music]
that's pretty
ridiculous wow baller desserts baller
Pizza bong rips inh house felt so good
walking in here with my
rig knowing that I could set it up on
the table and just enjoy
myself that's so good
this is so so
killer it's like the perfect temperature
this thing is like ice cream
cold like just not quite Frozen but just
as cold as you could be without being
frozen gives the most perfect texture to
it it's got the crumble crust there too
oh man
yeah I have to grab some of that yours
bro I'm just like wow that was so f
it's
delicious I'm G to have some right
now once again the perfect
temperature it's warm not hot it's like
warm
chewy I'm going to uh they're doing it
right here I'm going to give Mega ill
two thumbs up on
atmosphere quality of the food and
desserts and just all around VI smok and
hash at the
table I like this new world we're living
in it's
comfortable so to was a little bit of um
out the
[Music]
b yeah talk a little bit double dessert
double dessert this is awesome
[Music]
oh you're right oh I thought I did hit
this it's got good prop
[Music]
properties what a unique
taste particularly with both of these
desserts on my palette as well I'm
curious with that
that's dessert hash for
dessert
right it could be argued that there are
are that are hashes to smoke during a
meal as opposed to the desserts I find a
cush a deep heavy hash to be more of a
meal and sometimes this one in
particular it's just so tasty and got
such a good head to it it's almost like
it's a dessert we said that quite a
while ago
[Music]
too you rub your yeah if you guys are in
and around Vancouver I definitely
suggest that you come check out Mega ill
down 682 Kingsway is that what we at 646
646 I said it earlier so 646 Kingsway
come check it out bring your own stash
they're not selling you anything
here find desserts find pizza yeah if
you forget your papers they're going to
be open in a head shop next door so come
check it out man H man certified
side note side note uh just notice now
there's no water in the Mother Ship
we've been puffing out of it for the
last hour and a half and I literally
just notice now when I went over to the
sink to dump the water and none came out
that there was none in in in the pipe
the whole time probably you guys have
noticed when we were puffing that you
were probably wondering why are those
guys why didn't they put water in the
pipe anyway that's a testament to the
power of Mothership anyway peace out for
Mega ill say goodbye everyone
[Music]