[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and Merry Christmas it is December the
25th and I'm just sitting here taking a
break from my family activities and I
thought I would come and share with my
audience a small Gauntlet of sorts I've
got the denail with the mothership
quartz pooking bee uh collab going over
here and then over here I've got the new
uh quartz Banger that I got from uh Dark
Crystal glass and I've really been
liking it actually it's quite a nice
little unit got it in my Swiss perk
which is always nice to hit the Swiss
perk and uh yeah I've got uh a dab of
some Barb 99 I've got a dab of some of
d420 K's uh full melt dry sift and I've
got a dab of some sweet skunk dry sift
full melt as well and then after that
I'm going to take a CBD infusion of
CBD with
turmeric which has been CO2 extracted so
a friend of mine gave me this and he
wanted me to check that out so I figured
I'd give it all a check out here on
Bubble man's world so let's start with
well let's start with the quartz Banger
that's what we'll do we'll start with
the quartz Banger now I've had a few
people get a little upset with me I
admit I'm not torch Savvy when it comes
to heating these bowls up and I really
was hitting it too soon after heating it
up so uh for those of you that were just
having a hard time witnessing such a
thing and I believe that it was a hard
thing to witness I'm going to let the
quartz cool down this time and I'm going
to take that nice tasty rip um
surprisingly enough the few hits that I
I took when it was really really hot
weren't as bad as you might think they
weren't that hot burnt sort of oil taste
that even sometimes bubble has will do
when you put it on a nail that's too hot
so there we go with that I guess we'll
hit the Barb first and
foremost and we'll give it a little bit
of a a little bit of a a cool down guys
probably see I've got my melt shirts on
representing the triome heavy extract
crew jibs and Ken shout out to you guys
my main boys out in Colorado killing the
game literally killing the game so thank
you guys for doing what you do and here
we
go all right so that is the Barb 99%
Barb really nice we're going to follow
that up with a sweet skunk
Chaser all right and last but certainly
not least we're going to hit a little
d420
K full melt OG cush dryp now he gave me
this almost a year ago was probably
about a year ago that I was at his place
in PG I think it was just before
Christmas and he gave me this little jar
of hash you can tell it's almost pretty
much empty in there
but there's a few little nerds of
goodness left so I figure what better
place to hit it than on the Christmas
rips with bubble man I hope you guys are
all having a great Christmas um to me
that means spending time with uh family
friends and loved ones more so than
acquiring uh gifts I acquired just a few
gifts this year and that really wasn't
my highlight at all my highlight is and
always will be the people so we got this
thing nice and orange you can actually
see the ash from the last hit the sort
of little bit of U me uh just the I
guess residuals from the Barb the Barb
was actually I called it 99% could I
should call it 998 it's it's this it's
uh it's his 24hour run that I managed to
clean up into 99% heads but the quality
of a 24-hour dry sifted tumble is
obviously going to be much lower than
say his 5 and 10 minute tumble even his
1 hour tumble that he does is very high
quality so here we go let's hit the last
one
and there it is guys the Christmas
Trinity with bubble man have a great
holidays and a Happy New Year and we'll
see you on hash Church in a couple of
days peace