hey everybody bubble man here just got a
box in the mail I get boxes all the time
in the mail this one's got me really
excited I noticed it was from one of my
all-time favorite companies which is
Method sevs method
7 these guys have had me stocked with
HPS and metal highight and led uh
shades for for I don't even know if it's
been five or six or seven years or more
um James is just an awesome aome guy the
owner of the company um great folks uh
from day one they've just been
absolutely incredible super supportive
and they have great products I mean the
bottom line is they make great products
they make their glasses in Italy uh the
the lenses are absolutely spectacular I
often take my uh method sevens off and
give them to people with you know the
fancy expensive Shades and I'll say Hey
try try these lenses out and it's
constantly the same thing wow holy [ __ ]
that's unbelievable anyway they've sent
me their newest pair uh and I figured
you know what in the least they deserve
me to do a little unboxing video for
them and so that's what we're going to
do here today we're going
to open up a
box little bit of peanuts in
there ah yes let us dump the
peanuts there we
go there we go got a very small
case to dump these into but I'm making
it
work easily manipulatable all right here
we go so ooh yes these are the FX2 Clear
Vision for maximum yields don't grow
blind always love that logo Comfort
Clarity safety and resin repel oh really
well I need some resin repellent so
these are the evolution FX2 Emerald
tortoise so that's what that is right
there the emerald tortoise let's check
them
out always with a couple of nice little
oh that's nice look at that little
bookmark never seen one of those before
from growing exposed that's my good
homie Justin from Green Planet who does
the growing exposed videos they're great
if you haven't checked them you can
check them out on YouTube uh and then
he's got uh discover the new FX2 lens so
if you guys want to
discover can do a little screenshot on
that you can scan that little card and
remember don't grow blind some of those
HPS lights have been absolutely
detrimental to healthy eyesight so we'll
avoid that oh that's cool growing
exposed very very cool I like the little
planet on there o I'm looking forward to
these I you know I've got so many black
pairs that anytime I get a pair where
there's a little bit of style or color
to it uh I get pretty excited about
about that so oh my goodness gracious
golly Molly g's look at these guys look
at those the emeralds oh dude are you
kidding me right now these are
beautiful oh
jeez yeah no big fan of those growing
exposed right on the uh on the inside
there really nice lightweight I love how
they always have the double hinge so you
can you know you got a bit of a fat head
you're not going to bend and eventually
break that hinge these are really really
nice got a little bit of grip on the
inside right here so when I guess it's
on your head it's not easily falling off
but I have to get these under the Borg
and check them out beautiful lens looks
great when the when the light is shining
through the uh the
goggles absolutely the goggles I mean
the lenses the the the glass
classes anyway um yeah I think that uh
huge shout out to Method 7 just want to
thank you guys for always taking care of
me I'm going to be absolutely wearing
these uh every day these are going to be
the new favorites and uh you guys can
check them out at method
7.com and uh thank you so much for the
support and I offer it right back at you
may the full mail bless your bowl sooner
than later peace everybody