[Music]
Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World
and welcome to the Mothership review.
Um, I was probably going to do in the
in, you know, in the in the future, uh,
potentially a review on each piece, but
I thought I got all three. People are
asking me the differences between this
one and that one. And if I were to do
this one, the Taurus, I might end up
comparing it to the egg in some way and
then comparing it to the straight fab.
So, I figured I would just do a quick
little review here for you guys. Um, I
only have two dn nails, a sub a
dabinator and a dnail. Uh my third one
is not plugged in right now, but what I
figured is we would try the titanium,
the silicone carbide, and the quartz and
give them sort of a test. And what I
could do is uh hit the Taurus first, hit
the straight fab second, and hit this
one last and simply, um unplug this
particular whip and plug in this whip.
So, I'm using this unit for two nails.
Uh so, we'll probably be a little bit
bound by the time that it takes to heat
that up, which isn't so bad. Uh if you
know the D nail, particularly the 2.0,
which is the unit that we're working
here with today, as well as the
Dabinator from Germany. Um this is a
customized titanium nail that D nail was
working on a while ago. I'm not sure
they still have it. It breaks off in the
middle. Sort of has a round dish for uh
collecting claim. Uh I've got the I dab
drop down. Got the Corey um cotum uh
drop down, the raastic colors. Thank
you, Flav, for that kick down. And this
is on the silicon carbide hybrid nail.
We're not going to be using the Sapphire
today, but I figured we would try all
the pipes with sort of a different
uh a different bowl in each one. And how
I'm going to test them is this. I'm
going to hit each one with uh the
sapphire uh with the quartz. And then
I'm going to heat each one with the
titanium and then I'm going to hit each
one with the silicon. And we'll see what
the differences are. Turn this phone off
because that'll be uh some endless
interruptions. So, we've got all sorts
of D420K sift in the house today for
doing dabs. So, I figured we'd start
with a little bit of that. And I guess
we will start
with let's start
with let's start with titanium. I think
that's a good start. You kind of figure
that titanium to quartz to silicon are
sort of the ways of preservation. I find
the silicone carbide preserves tarpen
just a little bit more than the quartz.
So, let's start off over here with the
big guy. We got a big tall straight fab.
It's got to be close to a foot tall, if
not more. There was my dab rag. I should
have used something a little
more
sturdy to keep that from blowing away.
It is a little bit of a windy day, which
is kind of good that I'm not testing out
lighters. I'm testing out motherships
with demons. So, all right, here we go.
Oh, we're just going to go for a dunk on
this
one. Boom.
Yeah, it's tasty. Got a little bit of a
grab. I don't hit off titanium as
much. And I haven't been hitting out of
the straight fab as much. A lot of room
for
air. A big pull.
Quite different from the Fab Egg and the
Taurus. Quite quite different. I would
say out of the three, this one hits the
most
open, the least
restricted. And of course, the titanium
to me made the hit just a tiny little
bit hot. Probably could have turned the
nail down, gone to 600 and something.
So, give that a little clean out, which
is uh real easy to do and and makes it
for uh nicer next
hits. Scratch it out. And always close
your eyes when you're blowing uh any
type of the residual out. This stuff
gets very hot. And uh from those of you
that know that watch the videos, I got a
little piece of it in my eye on my last
trip to Jamaica and it stung like the
dickens. All right, so that was the
titanium through the straight fab. Jeez,
I kind of want to be able to do this
full review, but nine big dabs. Well, I
guess I'm in for the long haul here,
guys. We're going to take this guy out.
Uh, it's not hot, but we'll lean that
down nice and
carefully. Here we
go. Let's try the same
nail, the same heat source, uh, through
a different pipe. I'm going to take a
little bit of a smaller rip because that
one was uh seemingly endless. All right,
so now we're going to hit the straight
fab or sorry, the Fabra egg. We just hit
the straight fab and uh right off the
bat, it's a much lighter piece in your
hand. Feels a little bit more well
balanced just because it's smaller and
round. This one's very tall. The base
alone on this one is monstrous. It's the
biggest mothership base I've ever seen.
Quite big. Uh, this one just fits a
little nicer in the hand. Uh, compared
to the Taurus, I would still consider
this a big pipe, but compared to the
straight fab, it's kind of in the medium
in the medium area. So, let's drop
another dab onto
there. Oh, yeah.
Well, I can say right off the bat that
there was more of an intense flavor in
this in the fab egg compared to the
straight
fab. I'm hitting OG
Kush made from bud turned into dry sift.
So, it's literally an unadulterated
canabonoid uh profile. Let's make sure
that GU is going. Yeah. And
so, you know, it it is an unadulterated
canabonoid profile. And because of that,
I can really taste the subtle
differences from this piece to this
piece. Even hit off the same nail. The
filtration on this one, the way it uh
filtered the smoke compared to this one
is obviously different. They're
different structures, different makeups,
and I really tasted a flavor enhancement
on the Fab Egg from the straight fab. I
also found the hit uh was almost more
evenly uh distributed in the in the
Fabrajet egg than the straight fab.
However, the straight fab really
reminded me of that old school kind of
meets new school. It's like a tube, but
it's not. It's got that Swiss Perk sort
of action in there and it's just uh
yeah, it's really cool. The the
obviously the laser perforated flower of
light life disc perk is also adding to
that. Um Nate Dizzle who does the Swiss
perks, he does a sort of a frit fritted
holes on the bottom. I'm not sure if
he's still doing that, but when I first
met him he was doing that and it was uh
I'm certain that Nate Dizzle and his
Swiss perk design was uh inspirational
in these designs. So, right on. Shout
out to Nate Dizzle. I'll never stop
using my Swiss perk. So, little hit of
the lemonade and then we're going to
move on to the
Taurus. Move on to the
Taurus. All right.
So, this little guy
is he's on
All right. So, yeah,
just same heat source once again through
the different pipe. Now, the Taurus, if
you haven't ever hit one, a lot of
people say it's the most flavorful. I
haven't hit them all personally. Well,
maybe that's not true. Maybe I have.
I've definitely hit a Klein. I've
definitely hit a ball rig. Well, maybe I
have hit them all. I haven't owned them
all and I haven't got to know them all.
So, I couldn't really say for the Klein
or the Ball Rig, but I can speak for the
three that I own, even though I've only
had the Taurus for the last four or five
days. So, let's get this down and find a
little rip with that
D420K. Such a nice hash. I'm really
tempted to hit a different flavor, but
this review is really going through I
want to discuss the flavor enhancements,
the flavor differences from the three
perks. I mean, of course, I can give you
my personal opinions on how they feel in
the hands and how I like them to for,
you know, sight to how they look and how
they photograph, how they hit. But, uh,
also wanted to majorly talk about how
they affect flavor hitting the same.
That's why we're going uh, you know,
rather than have each one with a
different source, you can really change
the flavor from titanium to quartz to
silicon carbide. So, what better way to
try it than all titanium, all quartz,
than all silicon carbide. So, here we go
for our last hit with the Taurus. I'll
let you know the difference from the
straight fab and the fab egg in about 1
minute.
that carb cap literally locks into
place. It's really nice.
You want to start stop your coughing
while you're removing the the drop down
from one piece and about to drop it into
another joint. Probably a good idea to
halt on
the because you don't want to be
chipping
glass. So there we go. That was the
Taurus. And I'll tell you the Taurus.
Okay, I'll I'll say it. It sounds like
it feels like um a fab egg that's been
silenced. That's literally if you put a
silencer on a gun, that is the
difference. It's it's restricted, but
restricted in the strangest of ways
because this is Scott's version, Scott
Deppy's version of the
recycler. It just recycles so perfectly
and beautifully that it creates a
restriction that just to me seems like a
silencer. The Taurus is the mothership
silencer. uh you could literally give
someone a monster rip with this piece
and they may not know they're getting
it. Whereas when you feel the chubble
and the chuggle of this piece and you
watch the smoke come up through the tube
and into the stem, you're pretty much
sure that you're going to be getting a a
really monstrous rip. Whereas with this
little guy, these little mini Tauruses,
you know, 8 to 9 in um tall with the
seed of life disc perk in the bottom and
the recycler in the top. It's just
really a cool little
pipe. So, yeah. I guess uh next up we
will
try the deep dish. Let's go for the deep
dish. Careful. Now, let's get that back
over there. We'll go deep
dish. Start with this guy.
All right, let me get this guy put away
here for a
second. We got mad
pipes going on
here. All right, that's what we want to
[Music]
do. Oh, yeah. It's ground and it only
goes in a certain amount of the way. I
was a little confused thinking that
uh it was sticking out a little
bit. Okay, so let's change up the flavor
profile this time around. I want to go
for a little bit
of the great gardener's newest creation,
the CBD Renee. This is a Canatonic cross
with the uh with Renee, and it of course
created his CBD Renee. He won the
Cannabis Cup this year for highest CBD
content of any entry. So, here's to you,
great gardener.
that has such a great flavor that the
minute you finish hitting
it, you really want to hit it again. It
really is that
tasty. It's uh it's wild. And it's not
Renee tasty because you would assume
when you say, "Oh, the Renee CBD, it's
so tasty." You would assume right away
if you knew Renee, that it was going to
be tasty because of the Renee. And it
very well may be because of the Renee,
but the profile is substantially
different from the actual Renee. So,
that was the straight fab. Let's get
this back over
here for the egg.
Booya. Got to be so so careful with
these mother ships. Really want to be
thinking as you're moving them around,
especially I'm taking one rip after the
other and moving them all back and
forth. You're probably all watching
like, "Oh, bubble man, don't give me a
heart attack." I'll try not to I'll try
not to give me a heart attack. A little
bit of more more lemonade ought to uh
ought to relax both of us.
Okay. So, Fabra
Egg, CBD
Renee, Fabra Egg, Deep Dish Banger
Quartz. So, okay, let's talk a little
bit about the difference between the
quartz. Right off the bat,
um, I felt like the quartz hit was
substantially cooler in the sense that
it didn't sharpen my throat and it felt
more preserved in the tarpine
content. Now, obviously, I didn't hit
the same strain. I hit a very different
strain, but I know them both very well.
They're in my stash. I smoke them daily.
I smoke them off of a multitude of of uh
of heat sources. So, I can say with with
assurityity that the titanium, and these
are all at the same temperature. I'm
trying to basically do all these things
at the same temperature. So it's within
uh you know even if it's 10 or 20° the
real difference is is how the substance
holds heat and releases heat how the
tarpine profile is preserved or
destroyed when it comes in contact. So
CBD Renee
Yep. Very nice. Very
nice.
So, that one tasted very very on on
point. The the flavor profile in this
one is a much stronger flavor profile.
Not as subtle as the
OG. So, I would have to say this, the
egg and the straight Fab had a similar
taste. The only real difference was in
the
um in the restriction that the Fab Egg
offers and also the equal I don't even
know how to describe it. Just the way
the water comes up through the piece
equally on all four sides. If you've
ever seen a Fab Egg, it's two pieces of
an egg that are attached by four points
and then there's these rectangular slits
that go around the center of the egg and
that really splits the egg from the top
to the to the bottom. Really nice unit.
I have to say obviously there's a ton of
hype on the eggs and uh you know it is
what it is. I I really like mine. It's
uh it's a really nice piece of glass and
I feel that it's right on point all of
these pieces with being welld deserved
of hitting the hashes the quality of the
hashes that I'm often hitting here. So a
mad shout out to Matt the Great
Gardener, D420K, John Burfello, Horatio
Delbert. These are all good friends that
have uh learned these processes uh
adapted them uh enhanced them and are
now making beautiful products. So, right
on guys. I guess uh one more hit of the
CBD Renee. This time we're going to do
it out of the
Taurus. Looking forward to this one
because this Taurus generally, you know,
it's it's pretty much accurate that most
of the things I've hit out of it have
had an increased taste, have had that
more preserved tarpin profile. So, let's
give it a shot.
hands down that was the most flavorful
of the three. Hands down.
The rip was I tasted it deeper in my
throat and even though I just took that
sip of lemonade and it's a very strong
lemonade, I can still uh taste the
powerful flavors of that CBD Renee right
on my lips and even down my
throat. That out of all three of those
rips is the rip that I want to go back
for. Taurus Quartz Club deep dish
Banger. Two thumbs up from the bubble
man.
So, I guess what we'll do now is we'll
do a quick switch on our
nails. We'll plug in our silicone
carbide and we'll get him into the egg.
Actually, we'll get him over into I'll
I'll keep my order. I like the order.
And we'll start
with the straight fab. So, the silicone
carbide nail uh is a new uh nail that D
nail has come out with recently. I don't
even know if it's available yet. You can
check out
d-nail.com. Use the bubbleman 10 code
for your discount if it's available.
It's a hybrid with a titanium base. And
they're now making a small shelf that
screws into the top to the bottom of the
nail. And then you can put a sapphire
dish right on top of it. So, that's a
nice combo I haven't yet hit. and we'll
talk about that in another review. But
today, we're going to hit the silicon
carbide uh hybrid with the titanium base
through the drop down through all three
of the mother ships, the straight fab,
the fabra egg, and the Taurus. And we've
already hit the titanium and we we've
already hit the quartz. I've hit I'm six
rips in right now. Three OG full melt
dry sifts and three full melt dry sift
uh Renee CBDs from the Great Gardener.
Other dry sifts from D420K. So, we're
going to finish it off with a little
Horatio Delbur sevenst star. So, I've
got a little sevenstar, and it's from uh
My Little Pony, if you can imagine. A
little My Little Pony sevenst star. So,
that's what we're going to do our our
carbide nail with. Got a nice big chunk
that I'm going to break into three here.
And uh yeah, what better way to honor my
good buddies than uh you know, smoke
some of their beautiful hash that they
were so kind to leave with me. I'm never
uh never shy away from a hash gift.
Telling you, that's the gift. The gift
of gifts. The best thing to give some
your friends. Little hash. My goodness,
it's just wonderful. All right, so we
got some sevenstar broken into some
rips. We got our nail at about 600°
Fahrenheit right now. We got the sun
going down right behind us
here. Just another epic day in British
Columbia. I'm leaving tomorrow. I'm
going to jump on a plane, fly to
Toronto, and then I'm going to get off
that plane, jump on another plane, and
I'm going to be in Jamaica. And Jamaica
is really exciting. This next week,
we're going to show you the neutrautical
conference uh announcement that's
happening to announce that industry in
Jamaica in Kingston on the 5th. Uh then
we're going to be heading to Negril for
the 7th and the 8th uh for the Stepping
High Festival, which is a 13th annual
now uh cannabis cup type celebration.
our buddy uh Ras Bobby, Bobby Dread from
Ya Media is putting that on. So, we're
really excited to go down there and do
some judging, speak on the panel, meet
some amazing uh ganja farmers, and just
have an amazing time all around. Uh
after that, we literally have to zip
back to Kingston on the at the on the
8th, halfway through the day, and
there's going to be a soccer game,
celebrity soccer game with the Kingston
artists versus the St. Catherine
artists. I've heard Beanie Man and
Chronics and some other well-known
artists are going to be dawning the
jerseys and playing playing the game and
uh so we've sponsored that through uh
Ukan CRD canabonoid research and
development and we want to be present
for that as well. So of course I'll have
the camera there and I'll bring you guys
all along. Uh I think we're up to
temperature. Let's get this job done.
Start with a little sevenstar Horatio
Delbert.
Unbelievable tarpine content right off
the
bat. A heavy tarpin content. Almost
overwhelming. Still learning the recipes
of how much to put in. And I I bet you
will end up putting in much less in the
future. But wow, is that
turppy. like really nicely turpy, always
uh I mean almost uh more turppy than the
My Little Pony has ever been and I guess
that was his whole purpose, you know,
recapturing those tarpen that have been
lost in the drying process, potentially
lost in the water extraction process of
water-soluble tarpen being lost. So the
silicone carbide nail with the sevenstar
top-notch even through the straight fab
which is for me I say that because it's
very big and it's a very open space and
I'm thinking more and more as I go
through the mother ships and I learn
about what piece I I I'm going to love.
I'm digging these smaller and more
restricted pieces. So still a great
piece but probably about as big as I'll
ever go. All right. So, next up, let's
go. Fab
Egg. Put this over
here. Top of Zid nail. Put this over
here. Oh, this is almost a test in
itself to just
uh be moving around this
piece. A little slow dab there. Still
smoking a little bit.
All right. So, another sevenstar dab.
This time
through this time through the Faber egg.
Well, I'll tell you one thing that that
t melt does right off the bat is or t
sift, sorry, or sevenst star. It just
goes forever. The tarpen seem to enhance
it the same way a joint a hash in a
joint makes it burn longer. You just
keep getting rips.
I'm not putting any more in. Then I put
in the other stuff and it just keeps
going and going and going and that's
just a nice
treat. Tasted pretty pretty damn good
through the Fabra egg. Um, once again,
main
differences a deeper chubble in this.
This is more of a I don't even know how
to explain it. It's it's it's a louder,
but this one's deeper and almost a
little more silenced from this version.
I guess I'll use that term. And compared
to the Taurus, which is an even more
silenced version of the Fab Egg, which
we're going to get to right
now. All right, this guy's all turned
off. Might as well just get him out of
the
way,
right? Safety
first. All right.
Last
one. The last one. Some of you probably
saying, "Damn, Bubble Man just took down
like nine rips of full melt dry sift."
Actually, eight. I'm about to do my
ninth right now. So, without further
ado, this pan a little
cleaning. Also, the dish seems to be
more stained with the wetness of a
tarpin, even though the hash itself is
completely dry. Like completely dry.
Here we go with the Taurus. And the
final end hit of my review. See how we
go.
Yeah, that's tasty. Once again, deep
deep in the throat. That's the Taurus.
The Taurus has this restriction on it.
You're kind of pulling harder, but by
the time you exhale, you're hit, you
realize there's some sort of
preservation going on
there.
Awesome. So, there it is.
the Taurus, the Fabraier
Egg, and the Straight Fab. All three
with titanium nail, deep dish bucket
quartz from Puking Beagle, and the good
folks at D nail. And of course, the
silicon carbide titanium hybrid nail in
the Cory Cottonum dropdown and the
Taurus from Mothership. I want to thank
everyone that was involved in making
these products from the Dabinator to the
Dail, Deep Dish Banger, Pooking Beagle,
Great Gardener, D420K, Horatio Delbert,
Johnny B, uh, Mothership obviously, uh,
DNA, just because they're sitting on my
table right here, Unity and the
Community Brothers, and, uh, Oil Slick
for producing these, uh, cool little
products that I'm able to put these
pipes on and not worry about the base of
them.
chipping on me. So, if you guys have any
questions, throw them up in the comments
section. If you haven't already, please
subscribe and of course, give us a
thumbs up if you thought this video was
enjoyable. I hope you tried to take a
rip each time I did. And, uh, if you
couldn't keep up, don't feel bad. Uh, if
you could keep up, right on, man. You
guys are popping tough out there. So,
thanks for watching Bubble Man's World,
and we'll see you next time. Peace.
[Music]