[Music]
hey why Tim feel good give
me man home man
[Music]
real the purp after the weed to the mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I've been traveling to kingst
about 20 M hours sleeping on J like the
clock fresh vation with trees and with
flowers
[Music]
stop I make pass
pass pause that
now after the we that keeps me go
the purpose after the weed that to the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind he