[Music]
her stly s oh yes oh
[Laughter]
[Music]
[Applause]
again head people always ask me say why
you so humble I don't smoke Co that's
why I
[Music]
[Laughter]
don't s media oh
[Music]
yeah must bur like must be cleaned ra
vital for Spiritual hene a king Salomon
certify the tree and he is the wisest
man to we
SOA prach never true speech so meanwhile
the song called leaders deceive man
obligated to clarify and teach you
[Music]
now
marijana purple just get from
friend the
[Music]
highest
play by G man and say you with resources
and in turn showing your yearly
[Laughter]
[Music]
budget
Earth's
oh yes my
medicine some call it
Cy some call it
weed some call it marijuana marij some
call it
herbs some I call it
[Music]
push
herbs
[Music]
[Laughter]
strictly St kind of real cloud like I
say is I bring
[Music]
this Ro alongside one
SP oh
yes again
[Applause]
[Music]
highest me say why you so humble I don't
smoke Coe that's why I don't
[Laughter]
[Music]
Grumble stly s me yeah
[Laughter]
[Music]
must be burned like must be clean V
spiritual a kingon certify the tree and
he is the wisest man to we so propaganda
the preach