hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
haven't made a video in a couple of days
here aside from our really great hash
church that we did today so I thought I
would give you a quick little show of an
incredible piece that flab 421 dropped
off the other day for a couple of days
here for me to get photographs of it is
the Dosa Mothership now so many
beautiful things about this uh Dosa
we've got this perfect opal in the
marble on the front it's got this
incredible kind of Mossy green color
with the crushed opal and the rainbow
cane um really an incredible
chubbler it's got a real deep deep pull
to it for the amount of water that's in
there and I've got the denail set in
with the direct injection quartz Bowl
we're going to hit a little bowl
of the sweet skunk so let's get a let's
get a big bowl actually cuz we're doing
dabs for a video here so here we go
Mothership
damn let me count the ways on how that
was an incredible awesome hit
one the size of the hit was great but
the pipe takes the dab no matter what
you put through this thing I swear it
just it pulls with such ferocity that it
really is and for such a small down stem
on the thing I'm not sure exactly how he
nailed it but this is a winner two
thumbs up on the dose of Mothership and
I want to thank Flav again for bringing
it by and I want to thank you guys for
watching Bubble man's world stay tuned
for the next show
peace