[Music]
hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world I'm here from with
zan from the mr. hotbox the vaporization
from the future company and I first
heard about mr. hotbox and zan from a
good friend online friend Adam also
known as handmade and I saw that he got
one of your units and right away I was
like dude that looks like a killer
little electric nail I also been I also
love the fact that you guys had the
battery pack that came with it yeah yeah
why don't you tell us a little bit about
how you guys came to be in regards to
starting mister help us yeah mr. hotbox
we've been around for about four years
now and we originally started out of
Bellingham Washington we saw that there
was a need for an email that basically
could last you forever you could take
wherever you wanted and that's we filled
that market which is I guess kind of
goes hand in hand with why you offer a
lifetime warranty on it exactly yeah we
were hash smokers and we note that we're
sitting there with a torch every single
day and we were like we need something
that's just gonna be consistent that's
gonna give us yeah we're not dealing
with something that looks kind of
sketchy or anything like that either so
that was the first mr. hotbox was born
and then two years later this is our
newest version of it so this is mr.
hotbox classic we went like how Apple
had wood
the iPod Classic back in the day after
they discontinued the first iPod so this
is like the new sleeker design that we
we came out with that had our totally
our own circuit board it's designed by
our own team but one of the guys on our
team is a SpaceX engineer and and it
looks like it was engineered by a SpaceX
engineer I'm not gonna lie
it truly does so they got the bubble man
custom on there they also got my logo on
the back there then they got their name
right on the front
mr. hotbox just a nice little unit I
gotta say like it feels like I could
drop this thing and that I would not be
worried they broke it exactly be okay
yeah we've there's there videos on the
phone somewhere of us shooting the first
one with like pellet guns and all
dropping in and throwing it and then you
talking about taking some dabs out this
is truly like an indestructible email so
let's set it up yeah yeah the box also
has got some other things in there as
well and it's yeah stuffed it receptacle
so this is our power supply that allows
you to it's a big boy but it allows you
to plug it into anywhere in the world
you can go or switch lunge and make up
Africa anywhere and depending if it's
110 volts AC or 220 it's all ready to go
and so and for those of you that have
seen my video at the krasnopolskiy in
Amsterdam the High Times Cannabis Cup
where I plug in my gmail and I'm getting
things ready and I'm getting it all
organized and I come over to sort of
feed on the nail if it's heated up and I
look in the units flashing and I I'm
like oh [ __ ] [ __ ] I'm sure a few of you
remember that video it was it was
because the D nail at the time I don't
know if they
fixed it since they only really set it
out to be working off I guess 120 110
170 in Old North America
not quite the 240 volt which is in
Europe and it fried my whip luckily I
had an extra whip but that's one of the
reasons I ended up using the dab inator
which is another electric nail company
owned by a friend of mine Max and so you
know for this one one of the main
reasons I love the fact that it's
beefcake I love the fact that it looks
indestructible that it's warrantied for
life but one of the things I was really
really excited about is that they make
this little battery now we don't have
one here because they're so popular
they've sold out of them but they're in
the middle of manufacturing some more
and if you want to pass another other
dental battery it's smaller than the one
I've been using which this is just not a
very good battery at all it works for
maybe twenty to twenty minutes they're
claiming their battery is two to
two-and-a-half hours and they've done it
with your experience it's not just like
a theory and some two to two and a half
hours of a small little battery smaller
than this in the same metal finish
correct yep same metal finish love that
dude yeah and it has a long enough cable
so like you could even wrap it around
and just stick it underneath so you can
just how this whip feels great thanks
it's really loose and it's not it
doesn't feel like it's like too strong
yeah that was some of the other many
complaints that we heard from about
emails in general with that there was
the whip was a pain in the butt what's a
chrome it was either out of Kevlar and
it made it so it
would let you both this is a riffle um
and so do you go upside down or right
side up I do it upside down look at this
yeah personally just to keep the oh yeah
that's tight and nice in there too yeah
that's not like a loose fit I've got a
puking beagle in this one just because
we thought it would be a nice idea to
transfer the the whip but the way this
fits I don't think we're gonna have to
transfer the whip at all I think we'll
be able to transfer the entire yeah hole
and just put this one away you know
because that's usually it doesn't pull
out so nice like that that's actually a
really nice concept yeah having it not
be so loose and having it I mean it
feels snug in there yeah we wanted
something that was snug but because if
you have an air gap we were finding that
it was it doesn't really give you an
accurate temperature reading and so like
people people we've seen other nails
have an air gap people are us to have
their nail set to like 800 degrees or
something and then they're still getting
like a low Tim tabs on their nail and a
mic something that you noticed well in
the sense that if the thing isn't tight
around the quartz you definitely not
going to get that accurate temperature
well look at this guy
so yeah you press the power button five
times to turn it on it's a safety unit
let's say baby pen yeah exactly it's
like it to prevent someone turning it on
or off special battery yeah exactly
and so right now it's set to two hundred
and eighty-three degrees Celsius that's
kind of the temperature that said about
five 80s yeah yeah five five 80s yeah
600 but sometimes you'll smoke get it
down to like 550 or something like that
or a little bit lower but if you want to
just change that
the the temperature you just click the
up or down arrow right here so depending
on what temperature you want you can
just click the arrow to your heart's
content and then the check mark here lot
is the menu function so that allows you
to change the safety timer so it
automatically sets to 30 minutes also
like you click the check mark again to
select that menu function but so you can
thirty minutes 120 240 or four month in
eighty minutes and pending on your
session italics let's go for for a yeah
I usually just like for any because it's
it prevents it from shutting out off
when you don't want it to and then you
type the many of you just select exit
menu and then if you want to change it
between Celsius and Fahrenheit you can
go into the unit's section okay and go
so I did and we have a story behind mr.
haibach says a robot from the future and
from the year 2050 seven he beat all the
other vaporizers in the great vaporizer
war not a gimmicky name but so we say
the global standard for the year 2050
seven is Celsius and the other option is
Fahrenheit so you can change it to
Fahrenheit if you'd like to and it works
just the same either way perfect
beautiful nice and easy and clean and
and tight and so when you're ready to
power up the coil you just click the
coil power button and it starts heating
nice and so does it let you know what
it's got up to temperature or is it so
you're just you're looking at that I
don't what's right here so yeah it's
starting to climb and if I don't have
feeling that it would show us that yeah
that you're climbing that's great and
then the H also lets you know that the
coils on so like if it's off they go
away plucked yeah exactly
beautiful well played well played on
what else you got some other accessories
here like your arms and such yeah so
this is a little carb cap that mimics
our actual mr. hot box design that fits
our quartz nails and our titanium nails
this is the head to our titanium nail so
it you can fit both that fits nice and
tight oh yeah it should fit even if you
didn't yeah I like that it seals well
beautiful yeah I push this all the way
down very cool and then so then we also
have it so that's like you can vaporize
flour out of it this is which we have a
bunch of jars of Thank You dragonfly
earth medicine for the lovely flavors
that we're gonna hit here today yeah
it's this is something that is unique to
us we designed this I guess has never
seen one yeah it's like a little
cartridge so like your Kuo goes around
this top piece will show you here
shortly but and then you've grind up
your herb throw it in this little
compartment and slide it in my little
seven and just starts baking away like a
volcano and what a what would you grind
it up with you can grind it up with a
mister
I asked tomorrow I was like oh I'm gonna
go get a grinder he's like oh no no no I
got one of those too so yeah this is one
we made for bubbleman that has his logo
on it then but we made a grinder that
has unique teeth design that allows it
to actually cut your flour instead of
just ripping smashing it and kind of
like tearing it apart like that's what
innovation is all about let's be honest
how many grinders are there out there
there's still room in my opinion to
create a grinder that actually grinds up
the herb in a proper way rather than
what he's saying which is ripping and
smashing it and it's uh it's not quite
as quite a good little sound on this one
I like it very cool super lightweight
too for what it's made out of like
beefcake again but super lightweight mr.
hotbox very cool very very cool and yeah
this is just the head there titanium you
know the base of our herb attachment and
titanium nail are the same so if you
didn't want to smoke herb or vaporize
okay you can just as you can do
additional yeah the deep dish and it we
tried to design our quartz and touching
nails to be very similar so I like the
fact that it's very beefy you know I've
got of course Corey cotton who produced
created a beautiful little drop down for
my pipes it was a gift from flat 41 I've
broken it since and waiting on him to
come pick it up which is actually
supposed to happen today or tomorrow
he's gonna pick up the remnants and said
for sure he can fix it for me so
generally you know this this feels
really light as well is this okay yeah
really nice and how hot does it get when
you've got you can hold it you can hold
it yeah this is the key right here
you'll notice the quartz I have no
problem putting right into the stem of
my motherships because courts generally
even with a hot whip on it I can usually
grab them at the bottom and lift it out
and
and interchange it although with mr.
hotbox because it fits so nice and tight
on the top of the quartz bowl I'm not
worried that it's gonna fall out and I'm
definitely not worried that this part is
gonna get super hot and affect the
distal of my pipe these however I will
say that I'm less comfortable with the
smaller ones that I've seen putting them
right into the pipe just because they
can get really hot they can start
expanding and the glass can can
eventually produce cracks in them also
having someone put this into your Vista
Bowl that maybe isn't paying attention
you can chip it and you know these
motherships aren't cheap so you want to
take good care of them but today we are
gonna try the herb attachment without a
drop down and I would love to be able to
try that later on for sure cool looking
unit man I really think this is you're
onto something right there thank you
what a cool way to be able to load and
unload the herb dish yeah it was
something that it was a long time coming
and finally enough people were like
hello love mr. hotbox but I'd only use
it if I could vaporize flour all right
like that's just weight and it got
contacted that same person within a week
it was like we made the thing that we
thought about for you yeah this one
looks just beautiful man I'm super
excited to get a rip in so that's what
we're gonna do we're gonna have a rip
I've got a bunch of different maple
butters I've got these ones which is
from heavenly days and then I've even
got a little Frenchie cannoli water hash
that we should definitely probably rip
up just because it's the last that I
have and it's a full full flavor so yeah
I don't know if you want to have
yourself the first rip off the unit sure
you don't want to go first it's yours
[Music]
you drove up you're so generous and kind
to come all the way up with your time
but I won't say no to rip of course my
tolerance is still mildly low but that's
what building tolerance is all about
having some rip so I think I'm gonna hit
the Juanita mmm
one thing about this one Nita as you hit
it through your pipe and then everything
tastes like Juanita it's got such a
strong terpene profile really nice nice
resin from it's called Juanita lana
biddy bolsa lava rosin one gram and that
is from my good friends at maple butter
I feel like I should probably use your
dad you know
exactly so we'll make sure that that's
nice and tight
I did just do some photographs I think
it's good on the bottom now it's perfect
yep excited to have a little rep and
when I say little I really do mean
little not hitting us the monster dabs
but what we'll build it up we'll get
back not that I ever really hit monster
dabs I have to admit I'm not a huge
monster dad guy seems to be more of uh
of the youth takin taking grand grand
two grand abs and stuff
yeah so yeah it's just nice to see that
I love the whip and the blue light on
the front of the unit that's real nice
kind of combination thing very cool that
you've got these at first when I saw
these unique inserts for how you plug in
the whip and the plug I was kind of like
oh [ __ ] I won't be able to use any of my
current whips but you know what this is
such a nice whip that comes with it I'll
just have to uh get myself an extra yeah
we can we can get you any other whips
that you need and yeah these sorry to
cut you I'm just saying that the
connectors make it so this is
technically ip65 so like you could
technically break your bone on top of it
and it's not going to short out here -
mr. hotbox or the house so that these
are splash proof massage water resistant
buttons as well as connectors huge bonus
yeah so that's why we have different
connectors is that screws it and seals
it in versus the other you know one of
the things you'll find out there is when
companies offer you a lifetime warranty
on their product it means one of two
things either a they're completely
[ __ ] insane or B which I'm guessing
is the case in this case as well as the
case for me with bubble bags we build
the products so well and so good that we
eliminate the majority of the things
that people would require warranty from
in the first place and if you can
eliminate all those sort of stupid
little mistakes mishaps then what you're
really doing is you're warranting the
product for things that actually would
require a warranty yeah and when you've
done it properly it's not hard to offer
a lifetime warranty because the product
is built properly I mean the fact that
it's got buttons that are waterproof and
the seals on both the power and the whip
being splash proof that's a big deal you
know again how many times have you seen
a pipe or a glass of water go over right
over it's been fine
all right well shout out to mr. pop box
and shout out to mothership and shout
out to maple butter because those three
companies at
point-in-time are making this rip for me
the bubble man possible give thanks
love the little hold of the car that's
great
been able to really sort of get around I
think if you're gonna hit that one mmm
you should hit it out of this pipe yes
and then we should hit the other flavors
out of this one because I'm telling you
yeah you're not gonna taste anything
else I'm good today it smells amazing
tastes amazing and that's three rips
already on a tiny little black Wow all
right we'll go for a little cleaning up
thanks to glob mops as well for making
this a EZ clean yeah jeez nice the way
we're both obsessed zan and I with
obviously keeping our our bowls clean
although if you saw my puking Beatle
before I pulled it out if there's
anything but cleaning fluid dirty it was
a little dirty it was a little dirty so
yeah there we go I think you could
possibly do your own q-tips for this
yeah that's it I think that would be a
really smart idea ones that are just
mean not that these don't fit good they
actually fit nice and snug and I'm not
finding that it's a danger to flip them
around and clean that yeah perfectly but
something that you could possibly do mr.
hotbox q-tips yep that's you read our
minds a little bit of a mess on the
outside of a car
that's to be expected Wow Thank You
maple butter rosin that is just a nice
light hi completely the opposite from
the heavenly days rock star 73 micron
bubble hash pressed into rosin which is
this ridiculous white rosin this stuff
is like super intense full body full
full mind really oh yeah look at that
and pretty exciting
new electric nail one that I can travel
with with a battery most excited is is
my current situation
I am currently most excited I've had a
bunch of great products sent to me
recently that I'm going to be doing more
unveiling and unboxing videos as well as
the the full package from vape exhale
and but today it's all about mr. hotbox
I obviously love any type of unit that
allows me to use my current glass mm-hmm
you know what I mean I love the ability
to hit out of my motherships
yeah I think that they're great pipes I
know that there's a huge hype on them
but truly the way they hit the perks the
uniqueness of thought and the concept
that Scott has put into these as well as
the rest of the blowers that work with
him and our part owners it's hard to say
that they haven't done a great [ __ ]
job yeah you know they're fantastic
pieces to hit and unlike any other I
mean I remember years ago when the
mothership was less known of and people
walking around dispensaries just like
hitting them and I was like what piece
is some of these they're this hits like
literally the best that I've hit and I
agree with you and I think that's why
sometimes people they get it mixed up
and maybe you know maybe there's a there
is a bunch of hype I mean the pipes
definitely got very expensive and it was
the thing to have but sometimes there's
really the hype is there for a reason
yeah you know what I mean that it
actually
has a foundation in reality yeah which
these pipes are great [ __ ] pipes yeah
you know the first time I had a fat bag
I just wanted one yeah that was mighty I
was like oh my god not because I thought
it was like a Ferrari and cool and
people would think that I was cool if I
owned it was that I wanted it yeah it
the intake like the breath that you get
it just like clean and no restriction
really no restriction at all just
beautiful
so you've also got a really cool little
vaporizer unit here that I have you know
I think Dean L sent me something years
ago and it just it was weird I don't
know it was like a glass thing or
something yeah with it like a heater on
top of it or something like that
something like that yeah and don't get
me wrong because then one of the first
vaporizers that I really hit that
absolutely destroyed me was this Dutch
guy and it was also the heater on top
yeah I'm just trying to remember the
name sublime inator no no way before the
sublimator
waited before the sublimator that's on
Rico and that also was a very unique hit
yeah a little bit more you know that you
have to pay attention because it's got
this big sort of hanging on him and it
was a little bit more dangerous in that
sense but no this was years prior his
name was Everett the gentleman who had
the vaporizer and it was soma always had
one at this house and it was the first
time I saw this vaporizer was in 1995 at
the Cannabis Cup and it was it was like
it had this big heater that sat on the
top of like a jar it was unlucky
mother's and let me tell you that
vaporizer it's very big it's very good
Scott Hughes felt like a big glass bong
and the piece that goes into it it's not
like something that's very portable yeah
even though it kind of started as a
portable idea he had the jar around the
waist and whatnot but this this is a
great concept and an idea to offer to
people with electric nails yeah you know
what I mean because there's definitely I
don't consider it an operative a per
eyes but when I have my yeah yeah just
plug in all day long exhibit if I can
just pop it off yeah and put it onto
another unit yeah you can just throw it
on
just a little unleashing but that it's
not even hot if I touched it here it
would burn my fingers very badly but on
the bottom of the joints almost no heat
whatsoever so then this is just the oil
goes around the top like this so it's
heating the intake air like like a
volcano basically just has like a heat
gun inside the base of it and most other
vaporizers just have like a heat gun and
that's what's producing that hot air or
like a coil and then you sucking through
it is producing there yeah heat in the
air so this is this is our version of it
so you hit it more like a vape and
versus like clearing a bowl or something
like just a little bit lighter of a hit
because yeah exactly
and so yeah you just put it on your
regular bone and just grind up some
power and then you just throw your flour
into the little compartment insert your
compartment in here so one of the
reasons the sublimator is so effective
and in fact just noticing this it would
probably be a best idea if you're using
this to have the pen inside the unit
before you fill it get it warm
you know maybe not blazing hot you don't
want to burn yourself but you would
definitely want to get this little dish
yep warm and is that something you guys
yeah because that we found that same
thing we've tested a whole bunch of
different times like just loading up a
cool cartridge and just start hitting it
and it takes about like 20 seconds or 15
seconds before you actually get some
milk unless unless it's in there so like
you either heat it beforehand and then
loads of power and then or you load your
fire in and then just let it sit for a
couple seconds like five to ten seconds
you can
and start pulling through and that that
just gives enough time for the actual
pans absolutely no design it's
definitely like it's to me it's very
much like a personal vaporizer yeah I
mean sure you could share with a buddy
or two but the way an electric nail can
be shared with hundreds of people is
kind of unparalleled in the industry
yeah for how fast it is to load and
clean and load and clean and it's always
hot it's just going yeah it's probably
not gonna be like that with the
vaporizer of the herb you know you could
probably bust up a bunch of herb and I
guess in a sense you can have a few of
these already but you know really that's
almost a design for a mass unit for a
dispensary yeah you have a small like
little design that just fits these
things hold nature a lot yeah and so you
pull them out you stuff them with the
herb you put them in the thing that
would be a good way in a in a blink to
speed that process up not that we need
to I mean you could hit concentrates off
this thing and how many concentrates in
a row do you really really mean before
your blasted I got pretty blasted just
off the last three rips and the wanita I
was extremely tasty I was hasty that was
great well why don't we pick an herb
from from the Dragonfly earth medicine
crew we've got so many different ones
it's kinda ridiculous for Turkey no
that's a nice smell remember we both
said the motherships yeah I was just
thinking about the mothership was it's
just different
let's do it
ya know it's dance its density on fire
like that - really yeah like British
foam being
that's wild like that that's uh you
wouldn't I'm looking at this father you
wouldn't think there was like all right
they're really knowledgeable in their
soil and the the soil food web and you
know the way they feed and the intention
that is behind the growing I really like
but they were totally responsible for
the last episode of hash Church the soil
Edition where they got some just
wonderful people in to talk about you
know the science of soil the
spirituality of soil like there is
everything
yeah they had Swami on there and him and
Nicky we're just giving one perspective
while you have this guy column dropping
hardcore knowledge on compost there's a
great episode that's boom I felt like I
learned a lot and I like that about
hashed Church that's what everyone loves
about a hash Church I'm usually in the
conversation and part of the people that
are kind of in the noble on that
particular conversation yeah but in with
soil it was it was very much I felt like
a noob that there was a lot to be
learned so give thanks to the dragon
flavor of Medicine Shelton them out and
this is all there so you kidding me
Starkiller across with public oh yeah
mothership going in the mothership yeah
effects that's like earthy yeah it's so
is there a little trick to not burning
yourself when you pull this out I guess
you just want to push a little yeah it's
just I mean yeah my technique is get a
little pinch and then just kind of push
it down which is you know it's gonna
heat it up to a red-hot temperature you
know in luckily there's not I mean the
edge of this little dish is there's so
little surface contact that is if you
want to have it a little cooler you can
always just put it in obvious
we realize that the terpenes are
volatile so you know you want to hit
them both at the same time you want to
get that heat at the right temperature
the minute the heat is exposed to the
Terps because the Terps start
evaporating pretty much immediately and
you want to be able to capture those
I won't say no I wonder if we should try
it out of this this pipe yeah just so I
can actually taste yes but taste the
sunshine all right there we go it's
exciting no carb on this necessary oh
just this yeah I didn't need to turn up
the temperature a little bit sorry
spaced out what to what temp what are we
going to so we're so good so we're gonna
crank it up to 300 degrees Celsius cuz
so because you're beating the air that's
coming through it it it you heat it up a
little bit hotter than you normally than
your normal vape tips that you'd like to
set on a volcano or another vaporizer
that first taste was insane really yeah
I'm telling you insane it's almost worth
leaving it and oh yeah right away what I
was gonna say is leave it at 280 hit
your first rip then turn it up because
when he turned it up this thing went up
in temperature fast like it's already at
the temperature that he said it to
that was great dude
like all the way down to the end here
you take that one over grab this one
passing ships yeah do the night even
repel it's very much brown it's like
I've definitely was it was a very very
very nice green look at the depth yeah I
gotta show them that hopefully I can at
the angle that the cameras at so you can
kind of see the difference in the the
grabbing as it gravan it's always hard
to tell but there's major differences in
the color there so that's a
substantially vaporized dish well it
came out beautifully so yeah beautiful
and it's actually warm this time so I
suspect a bit although the flavor on
that first rip I barely exhaled anything
there was a tiny little plume right at
the start and then it was just pure
flavor it's almost like you don't want
to be exhaling it yeah that's really
nice I have to say that's that's a great
herb vaporizer thank you yeah I'm a
little bit of a snob when it comes to
greater vaporizers I'm not I'm not a big
fan of all the different kind of like
plastic hard composit yeah yeah same I'm
the same way I'm not a fan of that yeah
I income when I was in college I had a
buddy who had a volcano we probably
smoked it of us every day at some point
throughout the day so familiar that
first step um with the volcano so I was
like that's yeah I want something that's
gonna at least hit well yeah absolutely
and you know what nothing against
volcano they set the bar very early
late 90s early 2000s with that unit it's
a total Hospital friendly unit it
removes all concept of prohibition and
you know getting people to think in a
different mindset but at the same time
there's no comparing the rip that you
get off of a good sort of vaporizer
that's designed to actually make as the
Arab regardless of what the pipe that
you're smoking out of you is for me the
pipe is a part of it to filtering that
that vapor through the pipe depending on
the perk and the amount of water that's
present and just the feel of the glass
is a part of the experience to me yeah
to me too
and that's that's love of the volcano
it's a great unit but yeah that was the
one lacking thing for me to I was like I
got my piece that I like smoking through
gives me a really clean hit I'd love to
be able to add that mm-hmm have that
functionality well sure you know opened
up the ability for me to have a little
vapor up every once in a while you know
I've got the flavors this is great huh
thank you
glad they popped up today yeah thank you
for having me
make a little video on bubble man's
world I know I haven't made a ton of
videos lately I've definitely been a
little under the weather
in that sense just having hurt my leg
but I'm feeling a lot better
that just goes in even awkwardly with my
arm like this it just goes in nice boom
yeah and the crazy thing about that herb
attachment is until we started making
them they they have the tolerances
within like within a thousandth of an
inch and that's been more precise than a
lot of a lot of things that are made
these days and so like yeah we're like
that that basically has the tolerances
of an airplane or like anything air
aerospace-grade or
like that and unlike many other things
on the market so hey listen nice to be
able to pull it out and look at the
color mm-hmm and know that there's still
a little something-something left yeah
and when it all falls out clean you
pretty much know that it's it's baked so
where can they find mr. hot box you can
find mr. hot box on instagram at mr.
underscore hot box and you can also find
this at mr. hot box calm and if you're
interested in getting mr. hot box or any
of our accessories feel free to shoot us
an email or DM on Instagram mm-hmm
perfect to you awesome well you know I'm
on instagram at BC bubble man and I
guess zan and I are just gonna continue
to have a little session here with the
with the fresh brand-new mr. hot box and
as always may the full melt bless your
bowl sooner than later thanks for coming
up thank you for having me it's great
time awesome
peace out everybody have a great one
guys you want to hit some foam out yes
[Applause]
[Music]