[Music]
what's up
everybody Matt the great Garder New
Year's Eve day with Matt the great
Gardener and myself uh we've got another
crew we've got Flav is dropping off his
son
and uh Aaron and his wife are dropping
off their daughter and then uh I guess
we're going to head up there over there
yeah yeah so we're going to be heading
up Whistler we really haven't uh this is
the first time you guys are seeing Matt
I meant to do a little intro video with
him last night showed up last night yeah
I guess you were at your grandma's
hundred 100th birthday back in Ontario
man that's incredible man I saw she's
the cutest and the most you know
endearing Grandma anyone could ever have
that's amazing 100 years like the
stories the stories that she tells of
1914 not that she remembers 1914 but
that's when she was born when she was
when she was a young person right and oh
my God incredible she seen it all she's
seen everything so seen it all it's
incredible hopefully we're going to see
some cool things today up on the
mountain and we're going to share that
with you I didn't really bring my great
video camera I got my phone here and I
got my 5D so we'll do a little puffing
up there we'll go uh maybe hit some
jumps with some friends and just looking
to have an around fun day here up in
Whistler it's going to be a great day
today Adventures New Year's Eve in
Whistler see you guys in a bit great
[Music]
day
yeah buddy yeah
[Music]
buddies that was the first time I used
the RFD reader how many people weird
little thing what did you think of that
I think I felt it in my leg go off I
think it was touching
[Music]
me the electro magnetic frequency puls
through my ve what up what up what
up
[Music]
what's that buddy gondolo time for the
gondola do you want to be in our
movie all the skis and Boards inside am
I tripping out did she really say that
did she really just say
that Holy Smokes come on jump in here
guys come here come here as moved as
moved can be
all right Whistler peak in the
background top of the roundhouse with
flab Matt The greatek Gardener and Aaron
from DNA made it dude Cali boy up in the
mountains no strange of the mountains
here we go to theous here isn't it
beautiful it's like way warmer than that
the bottom an inversion so today it'll
be
great
all right New Year's Day on Whistler
with Matt the great Gardener and
Sarah Aaron from DNA somewhere we got
flab 421 in the house somewhere and
we're just shredding down a little Hill
here going to RI it up there
buddy
all right nice little speedrun down
Whistler
Mountain so
good so
good
killer that's what I'm saying this is
like just insanely
Epic aome
good fun good
fun all right we're going to continue
the shred we'll get the GoPro out and
show you some of that footage too
soon
nice line at the emerald
chair thank you which is
awesome wow is this ever
different oh [ __ ] we're a three but
we're going to get a
four might makeing a little
bit this is the new
RFD
boom little click mine just turn
green it's not
ideal so if that child goes missing well
exactly they usually keep them pretty
pretty close and whatnot but still it's
you want to keep those on the on the
child so like what'll happen is it'll be
monitored by the computer and it'll
start beeping when it's not moving from
the group and then they'll they'll radio
to him and say one of your kids so
amazing what a great idea yeah I it made
me happy to know that my kids were
wearing it's it's funny how they always
get us with these sort of scary you know
they they always said that oh they're
going to get us all microchipped so they
know where we all are and it's like yeah
but wow like as a
parent it's a terrible thing but it's at
the same time it's like yeah just have
just lose your kid at the grocery store
for 2 minutes and see see how that feels
yeah 2
minutes all right guys we just got to
the top of the roundhouse here we're
going to head up these stairs go check
out seos and go check out a little bit
of food so why don't you come join
[Music]
us
there
[Music]
right it's true just down there I I kind
of pointed it out to him y so I'll tell
him to go there right
now is that a siser jacket on your phone
no oh all right so Aaron's just informed
me that his wife has the keys so he's
good to go I'm with you he can do some
falling down this mountain here and uh
the keys won't get lost well nope and uh
I won't get home DNA Army bubble
ambassadors representing Whistler black
home see you up
there hey it's the duck party dance Zone
dude get your crack
[Applause]
on
party bar come down party
bar and there we
go hanging out with Aaron and Patty and
zanka going up to Whistler
peak come
on sne
me let's do it we came out of 6K Mark
Jesus which was hell and if you would if
we would have came out closer to five
it's one big giant Cliff band that's
that this it's 500 plus feet that Cliff
Pand multi 100t death Cliff ban and
guess what I also ended up there that's
where I ended up first and I had to hike
out along the cliff band were you alone
yeah holy [ __ ] see at least I was with
[ __ ] tart and and no cell phones I had
one beer and a and a and a half D
there's no reception yet were you taking
me no this was 20 [ __ ] years ago or
24 years ago and we didn't have cell
phones of course not if you did you were
like those big giant [ __ ] at
you didn't even yeah and it was like a,
1,500 bucks to buy and 100 bucks a
minute here comes the
bar hey
hey Whistler bailed bow to Shale
smoke most difficult
conditions those signs should say most
fun conditions most [ __ ] awesome man
mandatory drop to get in yeah drop off
the Cornus Tosh took me in there oh yeah
when he was 8 years old really yeah and
he's like Dad you got to check this out
my ski teacher showed me
and I took him in there he took me in
there and I was like are you [ __ ]
kidding me bro this is
not so uh safety what are we doing then
mellow I'm following not like following
yeah
yeah yeah I don't know these guys got me
to go down that thing right there we got
you on the top of the mountain most
difficult conditions
expert expert breeders [ __ ]
DNA
Army all right Pate well I'd say let's
do the scoop but I don't really uh you
just take us where you want bro I know
you're like
so when you got beat sungasses
well yeah it's just a bit of a Traverse
to come out that's all right whatever
you like dude where EAS he we'll have a
look at it anyway let's go have a look
at it what are you talking scoop or
cake
I like has it has it been real windy
here apparently it looks like it looks
kind of wind blowing eh
yep that's what Devon was saying it was
reallyu it he didn't say it about this
area and per well I'm sure over there
looks better but here like we're only
going to go to here then go around right
so [ __ ] it
y
ha
whoa whoa
whoa almost went a little too far
left I'm
good windy up here
please my Patty and zida will be
gone all right guys that was our first
day on Whistler Mountain what did you
think of that Aaron man you guys really
got it going on up here dude it is good
fun up here this is some world class
[ __ ] when you come to Whistler one of
the things you'll notice really fast is
that it's a world class class resort and
if you think you can ski you probably
can't you probably can't so we figured
we'd have a little Trippy Stick session
it's the end of the day we're going to
go hook up with Matt the great Gardener
and FL 421 but we figured we havn't been
puffing too much for you guys so we
figured we get the Trippy Stick out here
we got some of Matt's uh CBD Renee yeah
which has been real tasty I need that
from my legs right now boy
anti-inflammatory well you hit that it's
nice and freshh really nice dry sift
that we're puffing on and you can see
the mountains in the background here
just like we say epic epic world class
mountain range and uh it's nice to have
this guy up here man I've hung out with
this guy in a bunch of different
countries but never Whistler never
Whistler you now I'm here I had to come
back dud I've been on the water with you
yeah you have the girl's been wake
skating behind your your boat yeah she
killed it on the Wake skate so that's
what happens when you marry a Canadian
girl Canada will represent in your life
yep for sure couple more rips on that
thing
and we'll head on down we're going to
head down in the Gula we got some little
kids with us so we're going to take them
down in the Gula
Gula and I guess uh what's next we're
going to have a big Feast jacuzzi yeah
hot tub at the place 2014 it's a video
you're on it oh dude bubble man's world
bubble Man's World
YouTube all right that guy doesn't even
know it but now he's on a major cannabis
website he doesn't even know now you got
it that's
okay all right that's how friendly
Whistler is everyone is smiling everyone
is happy but he didn't want to hit he
didn't want to hit cuz he's working for
the snowboard school you can't offer
anyone that's working on the mountain a
hit because that would put their job at
risk only for a couple more years when
Whistler Goes Pro ganja and we're
actually using recreational Cannabis
here in Whistler all right let's go Aon
just up at The Roundhouse here seos up
at the Whistler Canada versus US Canada
just scored a couple of B uh more goals
and got everyone really excited this is
sort of what we do on the mountain when
the riding is done get together with
friends have a few puffs with the Trippy
Stick and enjoy Whistler
Mountain