[Music]
all right
so welcome to Bubble man's world guys I
am here with Flav and Aaron from DNA
genetics and we have made it to Whistler
beautiful drive Beau beautiful beautiful
drive the this the time of of day with
the orange sort of magic hour light and
then the pink mountains right as we came
into Whistler oh you guys obviously
noticed that yes um we've gotten here to
our house that we've rented wonderful so
You' got a whole bunch of nice Congo on
the I see Congo 73 second run I see
Congo 73 first r0 I got some tongo 90
right now T90 you going for a dunk or
you want a dab uh I'm going go for for
Dunk Dunk it
up dunk is that ready beautiful I like
the drop down you have on that as well
youw walk very
nice very
nice hold that there you go
Ewok Ewok glass excellent here let me
move back so I I'm I don't feel like I'm
blocking and you kind of move forward
there we'll be good we're good we'll be
good beautiful rip
tasty nice better than the seven than
the nice one except for my dunk I
actually did kind of dunk it
down after you brother after me I'm
going to hit okay look at that little
guy we got here let's check out the
function on this actually we'll do a a
close-up later love that little piece
yeah you got to show the function on
that piece for sure we will do a closeup
yeah these were the his and hers
matchings all yeah Fab ripping I don't
think so
her Dobie balconies it's being
respected yeah we're not smoking does no
but we will be I hopefully we will be
soon hopefully we will be soon cuz I
brought some um mexa that I grew some
Congo that's I grew that's been curing
forever some Skywalker I'd love to try
that I actually have seeds of the
Skywalker that I've never even popped
I've had them for like three
[Music]
years well that's
real nice real nice acceptable yeah real
acceptable I went like 90 I got my uh 90
right
here what I just
hit and it was delicious of course flab
brought
a plethora of Epic glass pipes we did
yes chop your head off and you stand oh
boom back in the screenshot we brought
the Marcel deppy Fab EG we brought the
his and hers matching Marcel mini
rippers the mini
rippers we got uh two dosas and a puny
tube with some disc flips really nice
Alison Wonderland disc flips actually
really nice on oh I saw that that tuo a
little worm
smok super nice and um I don't even
remember what the hell else we brought I
saw fdk in there oh yeah fdk of course
don't leave home without it though saw a
Toro yeah there's a Toro from the uh
City 5th year anniversary edition one is
the fdk the green the green the one we
were rolling with in Holland oh yeah
that's like great king yeah the best for
such an expensive piece to be your daily
driver and roll out with you to you go
this oh that's
lovely
ooh what's that what's that we been
holding out yeah no I just told told you
when I put it in a K in a in a small jar
that it was going to smell even more
like cherries and fruit it's that CBD
Rene
CB
beautiful very nice yeah I've been you
know what yesterday I was really
enjoying
this really enjoying this it was it you
know what it got me at first into this
kind of no high Zone that was very high
like you I was not high kind of no it
was just like and all sudden I was like
w no I'm like really high but different
nothing cerebral at all very different
totally I'm into it like mm not like the
Congo that all just like yeah I know
Hammer your brain yeah totally I don't
want to smoke no more son you want to go
to bed no we want to smoke more we want
to smoke
more so we got a whole six more seven
more days of Adventure here in Whistler
um today's kind of been a bus just
driving up here the kids are all excited
outside they're having a blast and uh
tomorrow we've got Matt and Sarah from
the house of the great Gardener arriving
and then our crew will be complete we
may have visits from higher end from
high integrity glass uh we may have uh
Alex from uh from the uh hemp not hemp
exchange the Manitoba hemp hemp
uh oh yeah yeah Manitoba Harvest fresh
hemp Foods yeah Manitoba Harvest he said
he was going to pop up that's cool I
invited Johnny Bell up for a day we we
should see John at one point in time up
here for a and who knows who else
there's definitely a already a crew of
people up here in Whistler that will
bump into we're basically trying to you
know do more than is humanly possible we
have a we have we have a calendar
actually we made out which is a pretty
awesome a schedule for our days here
like because we're we we're Limited in
time and we all want to do so much I
mean like and every day it's like okay
we're going to do the Olympic Bob
sledding for instance we all say yes we
have to do that 125 m kilm an hour down
the Olympic bob sled course in the
Olympic bob sled units like with VAP
pens with VAP pens or whatever I want to
have the Fab EG with a battery and a
dude sitting in the back with the with
the Fab egg he first of all the guy in
the back a man in his glass the guy in
the back is the break man bro yeah so
the man I doubt either one of us are
we're not doing the fourman Bob slid
here no three men three of us and if
there's is there a six
man maybe like Matt and I can go and you
and Aaron can go or something like that
what is this a Jew thing an anti Jew
thing anti oh [ __ ] didn't go it was
going there I was like
ah it's okay bro me out I'm all good
with that
kind we'll send the Jews down first them
down first see if it sa cut cut
rewind you know you know like do the Bob
site thing I think that's really cool
and if we could hit the vapor little pin
well on that in the least you should be
able to like you said if you pick your
seat in the right spot which I think is
going to be not at the back and not at
the front but maybe right in the middle
or the middle
back you yeah the second good you're
going to be right up on your boy that
you got on that thing with the first
dude is going to be the driver the last
dud you're not even going to realize the
G force of going around the turns you
think we're going to lose
I don't think you're going to be getting
your pen out I don't holding your pen up
to your [ __ ] mouth I think you're
going to be like this like [ __ ]
crashing like
C just like you'll just be like dude
[ __ ] bro I did not think it was going to
be that
intense think it's going to be like a
smooth
like it's not it's all turns like once
we hit 80k it was over dude it's 90 and
180° turns that's crazy that's what it
does they don't just go like this they
go they do this you're going to be like
this I'm just going to be ducking down
yeah we're going to be in the look as
those fools because they're going to be
the ones that are pushing off they're
not it be
violent we're going to be already like
right when you get in and we're like B
you know I'm like right up on you you
should we're like now we should be
hitting our pan right there why like one
two and they start running they got to
jump in they all hit the Fab in the in
the bob sled just like
this heat it up right before they start
to put
that'll give you the 30 seconds drop the
D perfect well I got this i got this new
pen that I could turn it up really
yeah I can just do like a vapor hit yeah
turn it up I got one too does yours turn
up yeah which and yours is the triy
stick Trippy Stick and your Trippy Stick
too oh he has the herbal unit mine's no
mine's not I got trippy steti I got the
concentrate whatever the same [ __ ] no no
not the same [ __ ] I've really found Apex
and Trippy Stick to stand Apex gives the
best ahead of the game what I found was
that I love Trippy Stick and I took it
everywhere and I used it everywhere and
then I got the Apex and I was like the
Apex was like I don't even really
compare it to the Trippy Stick it's like
a different level it's closer to this
this is what I'm going need to put in my
Trippy Stick this is the ultimate boom
boom boom if you can just hit a small
rig if you can get something that's the
ultimate next an apex pen cuz the rips
it gives are insane then for like when
I'm up on a glacier or a mountain or on
a boat or wherever my trippy sticks are
so sweet The herbal one I've just gotten
used to it's nice to be able to hit did
you bring both your pens did I what did
you bring all your penss course cool I
think I brought like three or four pens
so that we all had pens and well I
brought one too so we're all good cool
good I did not I broke my last pen sat
on it two days ago you can just hand it
over to the dude here you go bro here
you go dude I have a Leo o over my car
bro really yeah like I've had so many
different pants I've had the atmos P
this
one the CBD you know the taste on that
it's just really for Taste oh dude cuz
it's certainly not going to like here's
a really nice idea for a session you hit
the Congo it's just
destructive it's very potent it'll throw
people off their game in fact uh great
high but like Aaron said it's pretty
much most people are done they don't
need to smoke like 10 more rips of the
Congo sure you could just don't need to
this one is more like this incredible
flavor and taste that is like the
dessert MH yeah and it's not like the
there's no real Hammer no you know what
I'm saying you're high but there's not a
hammer definitely not which is strange
cuz it must be the canonic influence
because the Renee also much like the
Congo Had A Hammer massive Hammer had a
ceiling this High yeah meaning that it
just would take you up and and I'm
talking about best tastes concent has
one of the best tastes man the Hat
listen it's the only thing I ever smoked
exclusively for 2 years didn't get bored
of yeah my buddy was growing a
ridiculous amount wow that is a long
time you guys real tomorrow we're going
to have other hash on the table I know
and one more individual to smoke with
yeah yes and listen if if uh if we get
higher end up here we'll have other
other hash on the table no and we'll get
higher end up here we will we will like
yeah he he was he didn't come that first
session we had and I made sure to tell
him that I want to make sure you're not
hiding behind me no no I'm I'm out and
I'm not out of the thing so I kind of
have it it's a weird way we should have
had a seat set up right been goodt but
we're not going to uh hang out for much
longer we just wanted to give you guys a
little intro to Whistler you saw the
Epic House it's fully kick ass um if any
of you want uh the information on how
you yourself could rent this particular
house um the woman Pam is super cool and
uh definitely she doesn't rent it often
but when she does rent it uh it's
something to take advantage of for sure
so you'll see more of the place you'll
see more of Whistler and you'll
definitely see more of us uh smoking
[Music]
hash
yeah
[Music]
world but it flew away
from since you run away in a
sleep dream power Paradise power power
Paradise power
power every time she closed her
eyes
[Applause]
[Music]
par Paradise
Paradise every time she closed her
[Music]
eyes
power every time she closed
her
[Music]
here
oh
nice nice oh
[Music]
when she was just a
girl she expected the
world but if flew away from the
re since she ran away in the
S
par Paradise
par Paradise par
[Music]
par
oh
[Music]
oh the
[Applause]
like down down
down like this [ __ ] don't like
this
don't
[Music]
like the light there like that this is
the end of our are we all fitting in we
are fitting in oh all right in the shot
but welcome to Bubble man's world we are
in the garage of the Epic [ __ ] house
that we're staying in and uh it's New
Year's Eve New Year's
Eve what time is it I'd say it's
like not check cuz I would never know
where if I didn't check 7:30 7:30 so
we've got uh got some time four and a
half hours there are people in Canada
getting close on the East Coast what's
the East Coast total time hours all the
way all the way to the east Co three and
a half I thought it was just three no
three Ontario what right to the east
coast they got another one it's got to
be another few hours okay I'm not going
to argue it I got the Dosa and I'm about
to dab it
up and light flab on fire oh I'll be
safe well the rest of us are part tasty
wees of some T some Tangi growing on the
west coast I can some growing on the
West Coast what's that that that one I
think that's that's this is Tangi that's
next
Eon kind of scared me when I over have
that right there
ohes so you need a heal that you can
take this torch we should quickly duck
and get some more hash and then also
have all right we get good go ahead all
right this won't be my last dab of the
year but might be the last one I take in
this garage
for us lonely smokers we are stuck out
it in the garage as you can see it's
it's nice and warm in here there's a
nice heater right there but uh can't
have it on can't have the heater on
makes loud sounds affects the quality of
the audio next thing you know we get
[ __ ] commenters wow this video was
really hard to watch Bubble man it was
just way too hard to watch
you want to dab of this no you're cold
he's from California can you
tell how about you Matt would you like a
dose of rip yeah sure what you got your
bowls what you got to do why you heat it
up for if you want it till it's a little
yeah exactly there you
are no I think oh maybe what he's like
yes it will yeah I thought it was
broke was a little dab from that what do
you got there uh I don't know a little
dab holy
crap I pulled it off of maybe it's
warlock yeah
look torching up in the garage it's kind
of warm getting
close you think so no no no that's super
good you're good you're like super super
duper good no you're good he's like you
think so think so some nice it's
it dab it
up da anybody want this
dooby-doo that bong hits like a
champon
chonan
yeah well good day today up on the
mountain the whole n yard there's the
heater yes this video is over
break
time oh yeah 24 we're shpping it up
coming
[Music]
in all right so uh we've got Matt the
great Gardener is about to crack a
firewor out will it blow up right on the
deck or will it leave no I'm going to
aim it right through that hole
there that's where look like a good
ready okay yeah
[Music]
wow that was perfect sweet that's just
the beginning till we get to the Thunder
smack down
[Laughter]
the safety safety oh my
God how cool was that that was
awesome called the par pastel
Paradise
uhoh
yeah look at
that oh am I still going it's still
going hear the
echo there we go
oh wow oh yeah ow
oh
my that's
amazing oh yeah that's really
cool oh
my that that's really cool wow New
Year's action in
whis 2014
minutes into the
2015 w
yeah all right well these are serious
fireworks bro holy
Christ yeah
[Applause]
yeah oh my
God holy Mo W that was awesome that was
no oh
run uh-oh I don't like what he
did C holy
[ __ ] are you kidding
me oh my
God mat That's crazy dude he bought the
he bought the he got the good [ __ ] he
got holy [ __ ] you didn't skip on The
Works who man oh my God and then the
Domino's guy goes by after after this
huge yes that is planet Smackdown yeah
that's at 12:00 I agree what time is it
we have half an hour tops to wait that
was pretty good that was ridiculous that
was like dang I thought the last one was
awesome the last onew it was shocking
how fast it came out how did the bus
come in the middle like that's wacky I
also appreciated the Domino's Pizza Guy
going after the moner explosion and they
just J they're like what the hell what
was that what do we do just eat this
pizza Kirk and I did a did a a Halloween
show in his neighborhood and we pretty
much alls we had was those big square
ones videotape this thing cuz it's so
ridiculous s in and give her hug so
she's not
cold there we go New Year's for someone
right now this is the end of my year
with my two favorite
Girls
BC 5 4 3 2 1 happy New
[Applause]
[Music]
Year World
mother it on
it it got it wo
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah yeah look at
that look at their
fireworks
[Applause]
whoa
yeah it's never going to stop
[Applause]
the
smackdown that's a
Smackdown listen out loud
Patty this thing goes for eight
minutes okay I'm Lou
than
yeah W that's it happy New Year guys
[Music]
year