[Music]
welcome to bubble man's world I am here
at the green conference just outside of
the seven sales convention center in
Vancouver and I bumped into these crazy
guys we got Jason Wilcox John poor
fellow flab and the urban grower so
we're just we're just here at the green
rush conference checking out some green
actually purple purple purple it's
purple green that's purple it's for the
purple conference over here yeah the
purple rush what's up we ubc chemo Oh
Rockstar beautiful role famous always a
pleasure
you're not in the sunlight that's just
amazing God is that beautiful or
I wouldn't roll that up right here right
now all right let's supercharge it for
you - what do you got Johnny that's the
sativa that's my little pony no no
nobody got this came from Planet we
don't know what it is it's a soaring
City all right John's not gonna tell us
jason says it's a soaring sativa yeah
yeah this is so it's handed to me I
don't have my own because I'm in this
suit oh yeah doing talks and I'm very
good you're doing very well
very professional thank you very much
yeah so John spoke earlier today at
about 8 o'clock 8:20 in the morning and
he went over a speech I videotaped a
little bit of it I'll share it with you
guys and I'm speaking at 11:00 and then
after that it'll just be kind of
cruising around checking out the rest of
the speakers and meeting some people
it's a lot of people from the financial
district not a lot of people from the
cannabis industry but there are a few of
us and there are some familiar faces so
we're gonna puff we'll see you in a bit
medication look at these three guys
right here there's there's some guys
that have been making some making some
action with our injunction yeah fighting
the good fight keeping our licenses in
order you know we shouldn't I give all
three of you huge props though it can -
tional right we can't lose it and you
know what whatever sounds why are you
spending so much money that's something
that's all right this should just be a
given they should they should be
coverage to be funding us this fight
what do you think - I support that oh
and once again the great gardener just
comes out of nowhere who's super good
we're talking about the injunction we're
super charging joints
Sydal thought we were smoking some hash
wish you guys could all be here it's a
great time here in Vancouver at the
green rush conference peace
I'm not sure thank you thank you and
ma'am
what is
just wait
you have no idea sir
probably have you registered
they do
there's no
[Music]
it's basically to the next generation is
cannabis it's the next goal people and
that's why we're all here today we don't
have to find it from the ground we have
more wood from the earth we don't see
the difference
rounded neck but basically to know
history isn't worth so much but what is
its real value it's something just a
look at right pajamas it has more value
than any of the minimum or plant on this
earth it's a people it's a fiber it's a
food hey it's a medicine and that
medicine we're just scratching the
surface really we have no idea how
things are gonna happen to the patient
the future is cannabis the teacher is
now and it is until the atomic
initiative must work upon us here today
we're all here to learn this industry
about its potentials and everybody's
talking about the green the green which
I'll be here all day is come and see the
man and I really enjoy these industrial
and we have to offer
and why I'm here today is to understand
the modern this new industry the billion
dollar industry but like Harrison is
actually a trip you know industry and
it's only just begins we have a lovely
lady kind of cherry nice joy Davies and
she's been meeting them here and the
perpetual and faculties and
education to myself
[Music]
control Drugs and Substances Act for
about the last ten years
watch the industry grow from time your
Vancouver when I virtually do everybody
involved in the dispensary industry to
the current scenario where as a
tremendous number of players entering
the LP market as well as it seems like
more and more great market medical
cannabis dispensaries opening at least
in Vancouver every week it's not often
you get the opportunity to speak to such
a varied group of people and I
appreciate that opportunity I just have
seen here from virtually on the aspect
of about the cannabis for patients all
the way right up to investors and
companies seeking to enter this sector
I'm gonna assume for the purpose of my
remarks today that because this is a
business oriented conference most of the
people here are already familiar with
the general contours of EMM
purposes regulations if you are looking
to get into the sector you're not
familiar with the essential basics of
the system I do offer full-day seminars
where I come to your place of business I
walk you in your management's go through
the MMPR impart to you as much knowledge
as I can over the course of that days
the least you have a baseline
understanding of what the regulatory
scheme looks like what the rules are so
that you can get and understand whether
this is an opportunity that you wish to
pursue and one of the hurdles and
challenges in pursuing those
opportunities I'm also not going to
discuss the ongoing litigation
underneath mmm AR or the repeal that
MMAR the former regulatory scheme
Johnny Conroy has seized in the back of
the room I know he's gonna have some
things to say about that later that
could possibly do it as well as he will
so I'm gonna leave that on inside yeah
question is about the ongoing litigation
I'm happy answers I'm gonna think
there's gonna be an interesting panel
they just afternoon as well what I am
going to focus on with my remarks this
afternoon are three areas of the MMPR
that I believe already cry out for a new
regulatory approach or amended
regulatory approach the lens that I'd
like to view these issues through is
that a patient access this program is
Terry mentioned is the home
no the MMAR program in the MMPR program
really amazed are designed to ensure and
we've heard about important decisions
requiring the patient strictly
chronically ill Canadians that require
or wish to use for a lot of medical
purposes having reasonable access to net
and that's a right that's grounded in
Section seven of the Charter of Rights
and Freedoms and one that's not going to
be going away I think it's important to
while we cover all the different aspects
of the industry not lose sight of the
fact that this exists is because sick
and suffering citizens of this country
and residents of this country need
access to this medicine it's good for
them and it's it can both help their
symptoms as well as we're now learning
how potentially curative effects whole
host of conditions so patient focus in
my view absolutely critical not just for
understanding the regulatory approach
that should be applied but also for the
success of your business as in any
business see if you're not serving your
customer base and in this case those are
the patients that require access to
medical cannabis or wishing to use
medical cannabis or Kevin the space
products then you're not going to be
successful and so my focus here is to
focus to talk about really I think three
areas in which the regulatory scheme can
be amended either through lobbying or
litigation and those changes will both
run patient access as wetlands benefit
people in the industry that after all
want to have a successful company that
ends
again making money and paying your
employees payin bills and those kinds of
things so I have three general areas I'd
like to talk about the first is and I
think joy Davies probably talked a bit
about this this morning although I
unfortunately missed her presentation
lobbying the provinces for covering the
costs of canvas canvas based medicines
the sad reality as we heard in the
earlier speech before the break is that
most patients that are currently using
canvas around the purposes at least many
are the same on fixed incomes are
seniors they're living in situations in
which they're simply unable under either
the old system or the current system to
afford sufficient quantities of cannabis
medicine it is the provinces and not
Health Canada that determines which
medicines to cover in terms of
reimbursement cost of the medicines and
so I think that there needs to be a
focus put by patients and by licensed
producers in this industry you're not
going to the provinces and making the
case that canvas the canvas based
medicine should be covered under
provincial plans like we have with MSP
here British Columbia I'll admit today
and I am not my usual self typically I
am pretty stone-cold
stoic but we're coming up on four years
the Saturday money husband marked in US
federal prison for helping begin twenty
years ago the industry and the movement
that we're all sitting here today
talking about as if it's legal and it
works it on illegal are totally legal
for medical but um I gotta admit I am
getting tired of waiting for my husband
to come I am a business owner I employ
twenty eight people I have four
businesses cannabis culture calm was one
of the first print two magazines and
websites in the world about marijuana
and right now it remains one of the top
marijuana news websites in the world pop
TV is a video website it began when
there was no video on the internet at
all in 2000 when my husband Mark and we
started it at the same time as CBC
television launching their revolutionary
new video streaming on the Internet
my husband started a lot of things
starting 20 years ago with bringing High
Times magazines and books and bongs and
types into Canada to sell and begin this
industry when even a magazine about pot
was prohibited and had a heavy fine so
mark and twenty years ago this industry
and he created cannabis culture magazine
he created pot TV he started every scene
which was the biggest
in the world selling millions of seeds
and giving all the proceeds back to
finance and activism through the
magazine to plot TV through ballot
initiatives which made medical marijuana
legal in a number of US states through
financing groups like Marijuana Policy
Project which is now a multi-million
dollar major lobbying group in the
United States changing laws in numerous
states
Merck helped finance all sorts of groups
and rallies and programs and even the
United States Derk Enforcement
Administration tracked the millions of
dollars he made and said yes he gave it
away to political activists political
groups and no drug dealers no drug
connections at all but they still call
them the most wanted drug trafficking
kingpin in Canada and hadn't faced in 30
years to life in prison for sending C's
through the mail from Canada paying
taxes and never leaving this country
while doing so in running for office
creating the PC marijuana party the
marijuana party of Canada and of course
supporting different political parties
across this country when they choose to
support people's rights
my husband was x-rays in 2010
and I was made to take over our business
which is not related to marijuana itself
in any way I've not even stepped foot
inside and operating dispensary I don't
have a medical license I don't have any
connection whatsoever to medical
marijuana except to say people have a
right to use it either to treat what
ails them or to prevent illness from
setting in and that isn't right we all
have and I've always right okay well
thank you all for joining us today
good afternoon my name is Mark
Richardson I'm a local businessman owner
of fresh Eddie's and bubble bags and a
distributor for hemp hoodlum clothing
here in Canada I've been involved with
cannabis fairly intimately for the last
25 years actually not 15 that's okay and
it's I'm not a scientist I'm not a
doctor all of this has been through
bioassay
a lot of my experiences have been
learned through my experience with
cannabis it's it's nice to see everyone
showing an interest in cannabis here in
in Canada I'm gonna be covering an
overview of cannabis by talking a little
bit about industrial cannabis which is
hemp recreational cannabis use and
medical cannabis use and I prefer to use
the word cannabis over marijuana mainly
because the the foundation of marijuana
it's a Spanish word it's rooted in
racism it comes from the 30s so we all
be referring to cannabis today all of
them whether it's to be smoked
recreational to be used medicinally or
to be used industrially I'll be
referring to it as cannabis I started I
started my own company fresh heddes
which is a company I've run for the past
15 years and we specialize in glandular
trichomes isolation
little try to get to a picture to give
you a little bit of an idea there's a
glandular trichomes right there I took
this photo myself you have two types of
trichomes here a capitate stalked
glandular trichomes is the tall one and
then the smaller one is
capitate sessile there are three types
of trichomes there's a third one called
bulbous which looks exactly like these
ones but it doesn't have it doesn't have
a stalk it's just the head here's a
picture of a cannabis plant that you can
see is just covered in these medicinal
aspects and Kirk touched on it a little
bit as well as I'm sure dr. Hornby did
all of the medicinal value that we seek
the cannabinoids THC the terpenes the
terpenoids the modulators they all are
produced inside the glandular head of
the trichome so the actual medicine that
we're talking about here today is inside
those tiny little little glands the
resin produces the cannabinoids that we
have found to feed our endocannabinoid
system and I wanted to tell you guys
just a little bit about the
endocannabinoid system I'm personally
not a doctor but I've been learning a
lot from the doctors that I know and and
studying and so the system the
endocannabinoid system or the ECS is a
system that each and every one of you
here today has a system that helps
regulate the biological functions in
your body now in the 90s we discovered
receptors in our brains called cb1 and
later discovered a second receptor
called cb2 which are found primarily in
the immune system
the GI tract liver spleen bones heart
and kidney and peripheral nervous system
these discoveries of the cannabinoid
receptors endocannabinoids and the
related enzymes that make up what is now
called the endocannabinoid system and it
seems to be essential in most of our
physiological systems and it is
essential to life as it relates messages
that affects how we eat sleep relax
forget and protect these receptors
protect proteins include
endocannabinoids synthetic cannabinoids
and of course phyto cannabinoids which
are the ones found in cannabis and this
leads me into my final discussion I'm
getting beeped here I'm sixteen seconds
over I hear a lot of people say well I
support medical cannabis but not
recreational well let's took a look at
that through the eyes of the
endocannabinoid system now obviously
smoking a lot of anything isn't going to
be ideal but vaporization and oral
ingestion will feed your endocannabinoid
system and offer preventative me
avoiding health problems later in life I
spoke recently with dr. David Allen who
specializes in the endocannabinoid
system and he mentioned that if people
could rid themselves of the ECS
deficiencies this could help avoid such
things as old age diabetes stroke and
heart disease and his real focus is on
the ability for the body to continue to
produce insulin through endocannabinoid
regulation deficiencies in this older
age could cause old-age diabetes which
can in turn cause diabetic complications
and we know that cannabis has never
caused any harm never killed a person
and in fact this made amazing medicine
is one of the only plants one of the
only things people consume on this earth
just for the euphoric side-effects and
they have been for centuries now it may
sound ridiculous but for me this is how
I started on my road to learning and
that I stand in front of you sharing
through my relationship with cannabis as
a young person who was experimenting
with experimental cannabis I was able to
learn and teach myself about this
miraculous plant as I developed a
relationship with it today I'm a federal
exempt cannabis user and grower and can
say that growing is an aspect of the
plant is part of the healing that it
offers me the gardening aspect of being
able to produce my own medicine within
my own space and breed my own strain is
one I do not take for granted I stand
before you as supported supporter of
licensed producers personal production
licenses dispensaries and all forms of
cannabis trade and sale everyone should
be allowed to grow this wonderful
medicine thanks for your time man pretty
good job another very bright
of American farmers and producers and
consumers in the United States to be
able to access industrial hemp food
products and body care products fashion
and composit products so a little bit
about a corporate office myself as I
said president of the Association Larry
started with him trainer
also here at the booth witness if you'd
like to visit with him as our Vice
President Steve Levine is our CFO a
treasurer and our edge president and
then our executive director Eric - Steve
shock so here's just a list of our quick
reward as mark was talking about the
street and this district gives you an
idea everything from a fashion to so to
Hampton Court occasion - fiber
processing and food processing is
combines our board so here's some of us
one of the things that we do is a lot is
working directly with the vote amp and I
will be sharing more about the work of
both campus I'm here in just a moment
but here we are with some of our members
as we were up on Washington DC for our
Lobby day this was a full organized
Lobby day when we were in the and the
offices of our congressional leaders and
I will be displayed a little bit more
about why we are on Capitol Hill and why
our Lobby days are so important to us so
a little bit about vote him as the the
hip industry association and how they're
registered is quite different than how
podium is registered and they're
registered is an advocacy group which
can actually go then on to Capitol Hill
and do the appropriate lobbying that we
need to do in the United States don't
most of people my age I say you know
about 420
no idea I got to appear now a number of
the years of Hempfest in Seattle where
this huge number of people come together
in August and have stages and people
talking in bands and someone one time I
got to be on a stage just before 4:20
and this huge puff of smoke went up and
the police who were here and there
although like this
[Music]
and that's been that way for some time
in SIA so the I've been involved in this
issue going back to the mid seventies
and while I grew up in Africa my father
was a consultant on the growing of
tobacco and the African people that some
of the commonly used cannabis and I'm
talking the long term to cover
oh my father would pull out the plantain
throw it on the ground that was the
extent of the enforcement of the
cannabis laws vacuum I'm talking the 50s
and very early sixties and the sky
didn't fall
as far as I am and anyway I came back to
Canada and was Calabar in 1972 I was a
just so before that so I wasn't that
involved in everything in the 60s it was
the early 70s that Veronica came to the
goal and I'm comparing those days
because of what I see here today it's
the end of the conference and me and all
my buddies here just pop in the place
down
[Music]
yeah we bit some joints and they were
told you're only allowed to vaporize so
covering it really fun conference check
it out on green rush finance and office
the video available meet hey guys
welcome to bubble man's world and
welcome to puff Wednesday's hey guys
Johnny be in the house and we just have
woken up the day after the green rush
financial conference that let John tell
you a little bit about he's been the
specialist in it
green rust financial conference wow it
was quite a really amazing event
yesterday guys you know what a lot of a
lot of different crowd but the
conference is about bringing a lot of
people in to more or less educate one
another on the benefits of cannabis
around the health issues the prohibition
ends of it the hemp industry end of it's
right into the financial end of it
finishing off with the 420 investors and
then we got into there's such a wide
review of cannabis and it was all over
it was definitely covered by CTV News
global national all the new all the
newspapers it was a great event it was a
lot of fun I liked that it was the first
event I've been to potentially ever
where when I spoke I didn't feel as
though I was preaching to any choir I
could tell I was literally educating
people in the audience that just had
almost no knowledge whatsoever about
what I was talking about a lot of the
people there because it was a financial
conference are from the financial
district and that's they came in from
this area and you know they're basically
they're they're about making money they
know that you can make money
cannabis and the laws of changing so
they came to check it out and it was
guys like John and Kirk to sod and John
Conroy and Jodie Emery those were kind
of the core speakers that spoke in
regards to more of the roots and then
you had financial people speaking and
people that do IPOs and public companies
and stock market guys and those guys
were the suits so he had the roots and
the citizens and I'll give that quote to
Kirk because yesterday he came up with
that at lunch during the conference then
today I'm wearing what the roots are
right here wearing my hemp underneath
and make some with some suits right now
as well you can be the suit on the roots
always supporting the coalition so I'm
always supporting my right to grow and
stuff like that but right now i am i
stepping on stage and we're gonna be
able to educate on an international
platform we're getting great coverage on
exactly well it wasn't it was i'm sure
you can find my talks here in there
there were some videos of course taken
and they're going to slowly emerge you
know how this conference is taking place
and our next direction we're having
medellin june 26 inch wanto it's also
going to be an amazing event it's
already almost already sold-out as i see
there's a lot of hype around it there
already
advertising forward the media's about it
they're just gonna be like it's going to
be a really good event in Toronto and
that's that's what that's what we're
gonna bring with a plane here right now
is we're gonna start emerging these
industries together and show them
exactly the proper well you know what
like you say there's big money guys and
that's their only interest but there's a
lot of good guys out there that exactly
what they're looking at is not just
benefiting financially
from the education and getting the
proper information to the patients and
understanding this cannabis plant really
get involved with exactly what we're
both above them pretty sure there's
gonna be a big change yeah it's coming
for sure you can feel it and you can it
was the definitely the strangest roomful
of people I have ever in camp there were
so it was just neat to see these
different worlds sort of leaking into
one another and mixing in because there
really were like literally people that
you would just tip typical people that
you would you know the typical
stereotype of people that you would see
like a cannabis cup you saw the same
typical stereotype in all the suits that
we're walking around that just looked
literally like the certain ones looked
like you know private investors certain
one looked like lawyers certain they all
just were the suits and then you have
the roots and it was just a definitely
interesting mix to see them all both
coming together you know once again
brought together by cannabis which is
great what was the headline of the story
yeah I'm not sure it was some sort of
negative connotation and there wasn't
trying to be negatives but what it was
is not it wasn't much people side
smoking pot there's a lot of people
inside will be worried and we're all on
the trapeze sticks I think things have
changed now they have where we're not
everything there isn't a bunch of guys
outside we were but we were - and we had
our pipe
this was flops ridiculous crazy little
me no good no see it was running around
I kept going down to my car but every
one hour and doing bong rips apologizes
venue so I was feeding my is out front
with Remo and with Jason woke up okay so
then you must have been hitting goals
with us in the morning yeah yes I
thought you were in the video we just
play this so exactly so you were there I
wasn't he was there I was there almost
get she was yesterday was a long day
over there at 7:30 8 o'clock John spoke
at 8:20 yeah it was the yeah you kind of
wanted to be there throughout the whole
day and meet all the different you know
you've had your talk about Levin's and
then there was Jody and oh it's great
all the differential walking around you
can bump into the owner of the solar
tech ballasts and value some great guys
coming up with some really cool new
things that they were talking about with
us and so I'm looking forward to to
getting some of their products and what
yeah what else who else did we see we
saw Hillary Black was there from the BC
compassion Club yeah we saw oh the guys
met the guys from th seed bank great
guys David Hutchinson hi Oh what was the
other gentleman's name he was a really
nice guy too we gotta give him a show
about xanax our cards they're all right
here but there was a lot of good people
of this conference and I think that for
my highlight of the conference was the
amount of media coverage and and and
just the fact that people were just so
interested in and really taking a good
look at what's going on hopefully you
know the next one that comes to
Vancouver will be even you know busier
and more full and more people will come
to just offer what they have but also to
learn you know because it's when we all
share and learn that you can kind of
step this in to the next level of like
how do we build the proper
infrastructure to actually
put this all of these ideas you all know
that an idea is about 1% inspiration and
99% perspiration so you've got ideas
coming out the yin-yang but how do you
execute them we were talking about that
once we finished the event we all fell
back to campus culture yes we did yes
that was the kind of really nice session
again this big people we didn't get to
film any of that because we were
literally pop just so top out it was a
great group of people my old business
partner Martin rob truck was there
fermentable harvest and our other
partner from the beginning giangio was
there who we hadn't seen in forever yeah
Kirk and John Conroy myself John there's
a great group of people that kind of Oh
Matt I know over Horatio
yeah no they're just give your mother
money and extract like you just pulled
in there was really cool to sit down and
just how about like it was nice to
actually have that out for the
conference oh yeah it was necessary and
in fact it was kind of one of the keys
that one day when these conferences
because at the end of the conference
although you saw us puffing down in
there we were really the only ones and
we left after that and I'm sure it was
just alcohol after that it was wouldn't
it be an amazing that one day those
conferences have the vapor bar and the
smoking area and then they also have
medals and they also have you know if
you want to have your alcohol as well
I'll just be so neat I think we're gonna
have to try to pull that one off I think
it would be really cool I mean we have
licenses there are legal everything you
can't easily do a small little loan you
know but we have done the Ocean Center
we're gonna deal with these guys if you
diffused I told them we would do a
review of their products and they they
just like well tell us what you like and
we'll make it out so keep an eye out for
that infuse the new Vancouver company
highly infused cannabis products so you
can check them out actually at WWE used
that's fuz IDI saying that like an
American 4/20 calm so WWWE nfu Zedd
like a Canadian DD 4/20 calm check them
out so how about I looked up a bowl
Johnny yeah yeah you worked hard John
worked so hard if he imagines he did his
men Tanner table he was doing news
interviews he was running around like a
chicken with his head cut off
you know what at one point in time some
pieces of [__] stole his men Tanner's
from his booth let's play come on what's
that all about
he would do such a thing you know there
you go buddy no we're sharing it I'm
gonna help it give him away
yeah thanks yeah mark was on stage I
wanted to go see him talk I got pulled
off to the CTV in a news with Peter
Gehringer and Jodie Emery was on the
other end that last night on News at
6:00 and while I walked away from my
booth these boxes that were sealed seven
of them and you guys know who you are
over there
you opened up the boxes and stole
basically all my meditators there was a
display but they weren't open there was
boxes and I guess it is what it is and
that was one part of the negative part
for me about the conference was
and we didn't give a lot of weightless
growing pains it was nice and everybody
liked it and I made the promise paper
today we'll then the Med Tanner guys so
you don't want that get the big gun in
the back so thank you very much because
it was just horrible good products I
think on the right hands probably that
was how good did your head taste if mine
tasted as well as good as it did oh that
was amazing that's the barb oh my god
and the barb I find when you do a
ridiculously huge head of the bargain
there's almost a reason to do it just
for the taste first part of it I mean
Joan and I are well past like trying to
take the biggest red totally did it in
our 20s and it's fun and it's awesome
you guys should keep doing it for sure
just keep hitting those huge ribs and
you know that's your the biggest rip you
can box in the two layers but it does
get to a point where you acquire your
stash and you have your medicine all the
time in full melts around it you can
just have it whenever you want
just cool that's it I mean that hit was
a destroyer
for most yeah yeah just like take one of
those and then like try to like do your
taxes or no you know what you turn let's
try editing this video no no we get on
Facebook and we laugh at people doesn't
know exactly the video that I'm editing
right now is the video we're filming
right now so trippy is that that's
pretty cool yeah it's just a ending of
this video we'd like to stay slightly
ahead of our time just like Panasonic
that's their motto is that just just
just slightly ahead of our time
Panasonic if you're too far ahead of
your time it's your panel summer coming
well not really I have one katasonych
yeah but I'm like a little bit more than
slightly ahead of my time I've always
been just a little bit too much ahead of
my time and then it kind of misses some
jobs like having the vapor bar in 2002
in Vancouver like ten years before so
what's gonna be probably like what
should we think right now tell everybody
because we got to make this popular now
and not ten years well let me think
what's the next thing that I'm feeling
is really well you know what
mark low-key nailed it with mega L pizza
I think he's doing a great job with that
medicated pizza and medicated truths
about a catered food across the country
I've got another friend who's basically
doing one and it's not really my thing
to say on camera but he's got another
idea that's very similar but different
doesn't involve pizza at all and it's a
great great idea great concept and so
hopefully we'll be able to talk about
that soon once he's organized himself
into getting kind of closer to effect
well you'd hate to give a great idea way
up on camera and just have someone
that's what was yesterday was always
there was a lot of great ideas at this
conference that people want to invest
into to make these great ideas bigger I
had three people approached me at the
conference and you know say that they
thought that they could help mean you
know make a lot of money in this
business and whatnot but I just sort of
was like polite and took their cards but
didn't I'm not really it it feels
strange it feels strange when someone
approaches you that way probably because
I've never been really approached that
way I've been approached for my skills
like photography or consulting to make
hash or something but never
like just someone that wanted to use the
name that I've built for myself you know
what I mean like I've never had anyone
approaching you that way so it felt a
little bit weird
for me my perspective even though I
could see from from a certain
perspective it could be very exciting
like oh my god this could be my big
break but I just sort of let it you know
let it sit and just kind of move forward
I mean John is smart the way he got
involved with next-gen next-gen is all
about education and conferences I think
they're going to be doing an analytical
company which will all be all about
testing and doing all these other things
so for John it's communication and he's
not he hasn't sold his name to anyone
he's not like backing an LP or you know
anything he's he's just John BIRT fellow
that it's not one that you think you
guys who without John I wouldn't have
been at the conference
Jodi wouldn't have been at the
conference Curtis all wooden bed the
conference he brought and and quite a
few people came up to me and said oh you
know it's really neat that this this
part this middle part of this conference
brought me to the conference like I
don't know any of these financial people
and it just
if these names brought me and I you know
was about three but you picked it you
had a group of people out of the
business or out of our scene into that
business you have you have a lot of
friends in it you can I into 20
different people
know so much I'm gonna pioneer then and
I look up to a lot with your skills out
there and I'd like to see what we have
to offer to this industry in which
someone all of us do we all have a
different aspect but I think these are
the people that people are listening to
in the financial guys here our names -
none of the guys talking about
hey we watch your [__] my videos hey
I could make you a lot of money and that
was funny we know software is that I
just came up from the US I think I've
seen that all areas so it was it was
kind of cool that people are paying
attention to exactly what we're doing
we're educating one another and now the
people that really need the education I
mean another and we're edging and we're
bringing more people in that are
educating they want to get the education
and it's being able to great to be able
to actually just be involved and bring
everybody together it's not a cool like
we're all inspiration it was cool this
there's no doubt about it
it was cool and you know you know we
came this inspiration you know what this
just talked about gives you going a few
people said that Michelle Rainey a group
of people together we can obviously do
this this way and you know my Michelle
is great she was one of the big
inspirations of Y for for me why my
moment was involved with this conference
was was something that I remember it was
about me bringing that medical aspect
she would have been all over this five
hundred percent that's what I mean it
got these moms think about that yeah or
stuff like that bro she gave me that
inspiration that was just I actually say
thank you to Michelle for being a big
part of the inspiration of where I am
right now - Michelle Rainey for those of
you that don't know she was a bank
teller that Marc Emery often went to the
bank and dealt with and they had
interactions and they spoke and he
learned over the I don't know if it was
months or a year over a year but he
learned that she had promised
and I don't know if he had turned her
onto cannabis or probably he did but
maybe she was using it before but anyway
he eventually pulled her out of that job
and said come work for me and Michelle
really held together cannabis culture
and all these things not so much
cannabis culture but the the BC MP the
the bookstore at most she always was a
pleasure to deal with with fresh heavies
orders she promoted bubble bags huge she
was a good friend for for a long many
years and it was very sad when Disney's
over over cut yellow overtook her she
was invoked the trees old magazine they
treating yourself as stuffing sure Ron
and Mishelle was really about having
educational packages out there and stuff
like that without some of my educational
packages and that's where my link with
Michelle came in as we were both doing
the same thing and it was but anyways
you know what he's in love with her of
course absolutely recipes on a shelf
you're a great person
yeah how about I give you a bomb rip on
that note I'm a reasonable one not even
sure what it is a bunch of different
Barb's got left out on the plate can't
remember what's what it all tastes so
good after a nice not hard work and
stuff like that was kind of nice to just
come back and relax and talk about a
great day yesterday and yeah reminisce
today just talked about what we see
looking for the future and where we're
positions live for all of us people
involved in this industry and have been
so passionate about our whole lives yeah
if you guys want you know come check
them out in Toronto I'm not 100% sure
that I'm gonna be there but John will be
there and the next-gen team will be
there
another conference he's already given
the dates once but it's June June 26 26
in Toronto and I guess that's that also
the convention Sunday it will be hundred
percent sure so I'd better make sure you
can check out Green Rush financial
conferences calm they'll give you all
the information that you need there and
yeah man thanks again for coming up for
puff Wednesday - Thursday Thursday
[Music]