[Music]
hey how's it going everybody Welcome to
Bubble man's world I here again with Mr
Chris Bennett and uh today is uh today
the specialty is skateboarding
skateboarding day yeah it's like have a
few Puffs but we're not really going to
be going on about a lot of different
things we're really going to sit here
have a few dabs with you and then we're
going to head out Chris got uh a really
nice new electric skateboard I'm pretty
stoked on it actually yeah the evolved
GT uh all terrain I got the all Terin
set up today it's got a street set up
too and then we've got I brought my
other two evolves the evolve with the
bust and deck Street and the Evolve
bamboo with the allterrain so we'll
we're at Seymour Trailways demonstration
for us my favorite place rid an 8 Mile
PVE Road through the forest and
mountains best air on the Lower
Mainland yep I agree and we're going to
hit some absolutely phenomenal quality
rosin yeah before we go out and do it
and then when we come back from the
street we'll do some allterrain yeah
another session in the car and then do
some allterrain I'm definitely down with
bringing the camera and uh you know
filming uh whatever we end up doing this
rosin is just so nice found myself a
wooden Dabber for today if you can
imagine I'm hitting with a wooden Dabber
but uh I think we're going to be able to
pull it off give thanks to douge for the
baby
cake just don't hit it too hard or
you'll be sucking water okay that's the
gig well I'm definitely stoked that you
are getting into this skateboarding
thing while getting into it you're deep
in both feet like you are deep into it
and it kind of holds me with a foot in
this world cuz I I don't have any other
friends inviting me to go skateboarding
well it's hard hard in my age group to
find people to go skateboarding so I
appreciate you coming along dude I'm
always down always looking for somebody
to go hit this spot with it's kind of a
long long way to go by yourself you know
yeah for sure for those of you that
don't know we are in North Vancouver
like Chris just mentioned at the M Mount
Seymour Parkway and these are pretty
special Trails it's like this beautiful
paved little road that just goes right
through the middle of the forest how
long is it I think it's like eight miles
I've never made it right to the end wow
uh um and it's it's a good ride and
there's lots of turns and curves and the
Pavements really nice and smooth that's
awesome Hills and gullies and all that
type of stuff man then there's some
really good off-road trails as well just
getting the Dabber here or the uh carb
cap
she may be a small little piece but I'll
tell
you she hits like an absolute
Champion I am going to give you a more
reasonable hit this time I think I gave
you a little bit too big of one last
time yeah I'm not lightweight when it
comes to the dab well it's not even
about lightweight it's about being
comfortable with the hit that you're
comfortable with having and I myself who
smoke pretty large dabs if a friend
loads me a dab I'll often get like
higher than I would get if I loaded the
same
dab so let's load you one up Chris is
just like me when we get into this
situation the talking the puffing it's
all good and fun but let's get to the
riding that's right
man it's so great people really enjoy
these skateboard videos too so uh you
know there's not uh I mean last one
obviously there was an En an enormous
amount of uh good cannabis knowledge
dropped but today I don't think we're
going to be dropping quite as much we're
going to be dropping
carves we're going to be dropping
uh turn down a bit since it got run over
by a car it only lights at a certain
amount the gas has to be on a certain
amount before it lights I uh I lost at
dirt bike riding on the way up to brome
Ridge and uh I went by two trucks and
they both said they never saw it and
then when I finally found it I could see
why they never saw it because cuz they
clearly had both driven over it but uh
it's still working pretty good you can
see a little bit of Marks here nice not
too shabby Chris is like all right
should I hold this thing good for you
yeah I think it's a good idea
okay give that little guy oops parchment
paper don't worry it's the empty one let
it cool down a little bit the beautiful
thing about this tiny nail is that it
cools down so fast you certainly don't
need a 45 second cool down or you will
be getting the ultimate in uh
in uh low temp hits all right you ready
yep the challenge is to not touch the
wood to the actual nail this is uh
hillbilly dabbing
101 there we go seems just about right
that seems about
right
beautiful be beautiful well I think uh a
dab each is more than enough we both
eager to go going to take the camera
with us on this ride so uh enjoy the
ride guys
cheers I like the orange and the orange
it's
nice Chris is rocking the brand new
evolve so there it is hey there it is
very Sak looking it's a beautiful piece
of Machinery I'm not going to lie man
work for design you know like a just
industrial design thing because it's
such a Sleek looking
machine and fast too you know lives up
so how do you turn it on at the bottom
yeah this one here you turn it on the
bottom I just turn mine on yours is on
the side yeah I think we're good okay
cool
[Music]
Bubble Man set up the machine what kind
of strain you have there this why so
clean and
clear come
on we dab
ining it's time
time
[Music]
time it's a time do Time Fresh from the
extractor 100% pure
G this clean and pretty
like of used this good for just been
unfold good for young on the whole yeah
Soul we're
dabing
da we're
dabing it's a Dao time da do time time
we're
dabing da
[Music]
da time timeing in the morning dabing in
the evening dabing at supper time dabing
when you're weary dabbing when you're
lonely dabbing car we're feeling
fine some people ask me what is
dabbing I've got to show you my dabbing
machine that my bir bubble man bring in
we
dabing
[Music]
dab time
do time
do it's good for the endite
system oh lovely oh
[Music]
great yeah we
this is a Dao time a Dao time time we're
dabing dab dab dab dab dab
dab this is a DA time
[Music]
timey n
well it's hard to say much bad about
these electric skateboards they're
really incredible they still get a
little bit of a workout you feel it in
your back leg you can feel it in the
ability or the the the way you have to
pay so much attention you really can't
just stop paying attention on these
things they're fast they're Furious and
uh you will bail hard if you don't pay
attention they are super super [ __ ]
convenient and easy to use to learn um
this one works complet look at Chris
about to go over the the gravel that's
awesome so this one that I'm on right
now for instance is very different from
the boosted board yet I'm feeling that
I've uh pretty much acquired The Sweet
Spot of it learning how to carve on it
learning how to go nice and fast St kind
of real cloud like I say I BR about this
music
[Music]
man Royal alongside one
SP oh
yes
again on highest
High looking at me eyes so red because
we head people always ask me say why you
so humble I don't smoke Coe that's why I
don't
Grumble s me
[Music]
her her must be burned like must be
cleaned vital for Spiritual hene a king
Salamon certify the tree and he is the
wisest man to we so I propanda preach
heard never s true speech so meanwhile
the sound leaders deceive man obligated
to clarify and teach you now
[Music]
marij friend carry my same of the
highest just from the
high me
up
the yes but give me the
[Music]
[Applause]
when you sing on your you tum down you
me
inter would really know
comeet
people I don't want to get tossed man I
like the Humble Pie action just be real
easy I'm going to be I was real easy
with this one it was completely
different from the Boost that I don't is
a completely different you know the
boosted has better Electronics than than
this one better handset uh um but just
this is this one is all about the car
and then you get good range you know
what I mean like we would have the range
is killer I think I I think I three or
four times boosted with this I think
well it basically seems like about 40
minutes of ride time yeah that you could
do on it which is yeah yeah well I could
go say from Sunset Beach all the way
around Stanley Park and back to Sunset
Beach and still have juice left on that
board wow and uh um this one I went from
my place down to house Street and then
back
all around the seaw wall um towards
science world and over the bar bridge
and then back to my place on 10th so it
was like 12 miles didn't even touch it
was crazy just like half a charge that's
insane should we get a little water in
the bubbler
sure should we get a little water in the
bub this
little should be squeeze it out
yes
no there it
is just needs a little
help all right that ought to
do nice to have the backpack with the
water right there
mhm well here we go again for some
dabbles tble dab that will
do all right
this this little trick good thing s like
a hose you point it in your face CH
what's wrong with
this dude I'm already afraid of of these
torches man burnt me
up you should have to have like some
sort of a ticket for uh um being a dab
yeah Tor juice and dabbing yeah I got my
dab ticket I got my dab ticket oh really
how many dabs did you like what what T
it's a 25 dab ticket yeah I can
basically sit and operate a torch after
24 dabs and I'm still solid it's like
damn bro it's impressive I like it I
like my electric nail
myself this the oh you're oh rolled off
what's that your stick rolled off oh
jeez I was wondering what was going on
there look I caught it without even
touching the dab it was sitting on my
pants like that spear point when you did
that at first I was like I'm not going
to even pay attention I just put a bunch
of hot things down I hope nothing's
burning
here you go oh me SM yeah you're good to
go champion
champion so unbelievable ride by the way
didn't even really mention that when we
started filming again but that was
smooth and beautiful really nice looking
forward to trying the GT I'm not going
to lie I had one in the checkout a
couple of days ago on my computer I was
like I wonder if this is the one that
Chris was talking about I wasn't 100%
sure I held off but uh yeah I haven't
even had the street set up on it yet I
imagine the street set up can be pretty
sweet on this oh my god dude it looks
really nice I watched the
video of just like cruising through the
city does this one also have the
lights no doesn't have any lights on it
no lights I've got a light at home I can
put on good for nighttime riding I guess
you probably don't do much of it not a
lot must be kind of a night it can be
fun was uh last year I was doing uh um
night shifts on Davy Street and then I'd
ride the seaw wall back at night you
know yeah and it was always a blast to
like what about during the fireworks oh
yeah you know for sure that might be a
good time
to bring the board into the city the
city is gridlocked like 50,000 people
yeah come to these fireworks from all
these different areas around Vancouver
and uh
yeah if you if you get caught in it it's
a nightmarish hell but uh imagine being
on an electric skateboard and just
whipping by all the cars and all the
people and that could be nice
yeah yeah it's so nice here right the
air is just so fresh dude like look at
where we are it almost seems like it's
just a shitty little park but then you
look up and you're like oh right I'm
like this is like epic Back Country yeah
it just happens to have a little Trail
and an access point in yeah no for sure
yeah Vancouver is right on the edge of
the forest and then this road and trail
goes into the forest that's the
Vancouver's on the edge of so it's a
Nifty little kick of
nature get the City Vibe out of
you well I live in this very similar
kind of experience but uh I would always
want to come here uh more so if I lived
in the city as well cuz the city's a
good vibe but it's like you said it's to
kick it out of you every once in a while
and get out into the mountains and
pretty amazing that you can do it with a
an electric
skateboard that was a delicious
dab I got a low temp on see how it's
still kind of there yeah it's still kind
of there this pipe is is amazingly
resilient and the nail cools down if
that was any other nail I would be so
burnt right now but it it's uh barely
hot
now uh picked it up in Barcelona Spain
from uh plantur I believe little travel
pipe great little travel pipe and I've
carried it all over the place and kind
of you know it's it's definitely not
what I would call cheap glass because
I've tipped it over and I've dropped it
and I've had it have a quite a few
different experiences over the years and
uh it's still unchipped and in perfect
condition knock on wood there it lasts
this trip knock on graphite there we
go well what are you saying you got
motor on I mean I'm not going to
complain and say no let's do being like
wo oh yeah all right well give
thanks say you with resources and in
turn showing off your yearly
budget
herb you
know Roy
[Music]
the
earth oh yes my
medicine some call it
Cy some call it
weed some call it marijuana marijuana
some call it
herbs some call it
Pence
but
make
[Music]
with
strictly all right so now I'm on the
brand new evolve and I can tell you it
is absolutely Psych otic the GT mode is
faster than fast much faster than the
the busted from evolve and uh the
smoothness of the large air uh tires is
something that has to be felt to really
be
[Music]
understood it's my arm it's my arm go
back to the car I think it's over Chris
is like no we're pulling out the four
and now we're taking the off Offroad
Boards out so uh you want to lead the
way on this one Chris sure
awesome this right here is some
[ __ ] electric skateboarding on gravel
roads first first time in my life that's
for
sure this is definitely one of the
cooler things I've done in a while
Electric for going to do some
off-roading
but it's pretty solid
[Music]
a
clearly an amazing experience
longboarding
through the rainforest to British
Columbia just ripping up
ahead a little bit smooth ride
compared to what we were on anyway
[Music]
right don't need
to this one here really you're
awesome all right well let's say goodbye
to these guys thanks for watching Bubble
man's world we are done see you Chris
cheers
[Music]