[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world
everybody we are on a beautiful Sunday
afternoon fresh after hash Church really
after quite a hash church today it was
an epic hash Church you will have to
check it out hash Church 86 and I'm here
with Samurai Sam from uh I guess uptech
Omicron uptech is the manufacturing
company Utopia plena Technologies
because we're a bunch of nerds and W9
tech.com would be our website sweet
brought a couple Vapes by today Mark's
been checking out the Omron which is our
Flagship wax pen it's got an 18 mil
battery inside and has four power
settings the Omron is our goal to
introduce a really easy to use vaporizer
so you click click it on with five
Taps and you can change power settings
adjust it three times Twist Off The Top
to access our coil which has a grade 2
titanium wire wrapped around a black
porous ceramic Wick we also have other
heating options available ceramic Donuts
we discussed today on the church yep so
there's all kinds of different things
you can do with the Omron it also comes
with the glass globe yeah I've got the
glass globe on mine right there rocking
the glass globe so you can see your
Vapor production super easy uh learning
tool really nice to learn how to use the
unit pretty important for this unit I'll
have you guys know because it's not just
a vaporizer that you're going to buy and
just use out of the box they're sort of
trying to create a little bit of a
better product something longer lasting
something a little bit more sustainable
and non uh you know constantly replacing
and so one of the important things about
this unit which Sam just really told me
about today was the actual cooling of
the unit once you've hit it a bunch and
you've heated it all up uh you really
want to cool the unit it down and he was
showing me by
just taking dry hits on it we'll put it
to use here I'll here with a glass glue
W just a couple of dry hits pulls the
the cooler air through the chamber and
it actually cools that little element
and most importantly it cools the oil
because those three little holes that
were sucking through if you heat that
oil up too much and you let it sit the
oil will actually drain down into those
holes and and kind of clog it up a
little bit so definitely an important
factor to pay attention to it's happened
at this one I'll have to unclog at a
moment um one of the nice things I like
about this pen and we spoke about it on
hash Church where Samurai came on and
discussed the different qualities of
components that are being used in these
different pens and pointing out how we
were all very obsessed about uh the
grade of titanium if it was an electric
nail uh some of us weren't even hitting
titanium we were preferring uh different
forms of ceramic Sil silicon carbide uh
quartz getting into Sapphire and he just
pointed out like you guys will hit all
these incredible different surfaces um
but what about all these pens you're
just hitting any Chinese rebranded pen
uh that's nothing against China when I
say a Chinese rebranded pen it just
happens to be where the pens are from I
can't talk smack about our people and to
be UPF front we have our most of our
devices are manufactured in China as
well they're manufactured in our faculty
using materials that we've carefully
selected and we want to make sure we're
putting only really safe materials
inside the heated air path of these
devices well when I had my I did it
wrong I put too much turp sauce in there
it all drained down it completely coated
the unit it wasn't giving me full rips
anymore Sam walked me through
troubleshooting when I pulled the
element out and I took it it actually
came apart because I had so much oil in
it and I the way I was twisting it I
twisted the piece out of it a little
overloading I was amazed at how it was
so simple it wasn't a bunch of like it
wasn't like a bunch of stuff that I
didn't know what it was it was just it
was super simple there was the ceramic
dish there were the two little wires and
there were the elements and that was it
we actually call this the kiss cartridge
for keep it simple stupid because
Simplicity leads to a beautiful design
that doesn't have extraneous materials a
lot of which are unsafe um your
cartridge came apart cuz we're not using
any glues or nickel mesh to attach any
of the stuff inside here it's just
titanium wire but it also went back
together just as easy exactly you know
and the only reason it came out don't
get me wrong it didn't fall out I was
pushing paper towel and wiping all the
oil that I had that I had done off of it
and I didn't realize some had pushed
onto the inside and was spinning the
inside compartment which finally
released and came out but uh otherwise
I've had an amazing time with this pan
I've taken it to Jamaica I've taken it
to Barcelona uh it's traveled well it
hasn't caused me any problems at
airports or at security uh so that's
been good and uh yeah it's it gives a
really tasty rip there's no doubt about
it so where are these available you were
going to mention there our website W9
tech.com you can buy them directly there
they're in smoke shops uh across the
country and at a bunch of different
online retailers too the Omron comes in
three different battery sizes this is
the smallest light duty 900 milliamp
model I think we're both rocking the HD
2100 milliamp right there and then you
have one in between the two and there is
a midsize which I didn't have out at
this moment but there's a 1400 and in
between medium duty size too so what
does that mean to the average person
what kind of timeline are they going to
get with this versus this on using
definitely it's kind of a hard question
to answer because it totally depends on
how much you vape so for somebody that's
only taken a couple hits a day this can
last a day or two between battery
charges if you're a heavy vapor and
you're using this thing 10 or 15
sessions a day you might want to step up
to the biggest battery size but maybe
just take this one to the concert that
night cuz it's small in the pocket abely
you know I'll be honest with you I I dab
a lot so I have an enail at home and I'm
not using this as my only device and
when I originally got my vape I thought
the biggest one's going to be the best
and after a week of not needing to
charge it I asked for the small one and
this is the one that I use the most now
cuz it's really pocketable yeah makes
sense well we should maybe load a couple
of these up for sure take take a few
tasty dabs we were making some rosin
earlier had a nice uh actually had a
really unique blowout I didn't have much
to press for rosin so I just used some
five and six star west coast concentrate
bubble hash and uh it it came out
beautiful the rosin actually this is
some of the rosin right here uh it just
happened to release bubble hash into the
rosin and I'll show you actually you can
see it dripping out of the thing right
there in the top left you can see how
the bubble hash is getting thicker and
darker however the rosin still separated
really nicely and we were able to get uh
a really nice pure product out of that
so why don't we uh load up a few why
don't we hit some of this pure yeah
absolutely I'm not sure if it's going to
shatter like it was when I was
collecting it or what's the deal but
that was really
pretty here we go
thank you sir put a little in mine as
well yeah I really love these little
units for you know obviously out and
about in the world you know where the
dab uh and and I do still carry with me
my Mothership and uh my Dil and
sometimes a battery and so I'm always
ready for a serious session if you've
got room for a pelican why not if you
only have a pocket this might fit your
needs well I'll tell you one thing for
traveling this is unparalleled when I'm
traveling it is so nice to be able to
have this unit especially across Canada
cuz I can actually leave it dirty and
have it filled um not a problem when I
can't you know it's nice to be able to
have different elements travel with
clean ones leave dirty ones behind and
just use them when you get back to that
country so yeah I've got my setting on
Blue I'm pretty serious blue is the
highest setting and uh giv some pretty
pretty damn nice
ribs The Taste on that's real nice so
when you you're using harder rips when
you're drawing harder the higher power
settings work better and if you're going
to use lower power settings you've got
to really milk it and breathe very
gently to get those T ribs which is
quite counterintuitive to a vaporizer or
a cannabis user who's used to smoking or
taking bong rips or dabs it's hard to
wrap your head around the fact that you
need to really pull gently and that's
much like the Jamaican steam pipe one of
the original the original um vaporizer
you know you don't want to pull too too
hard but uh definitely just hard enough
to to get that sweet
spot and when you get it right it's so
so
good
agreed very decent very decent so that
is the Omron pen the one that I've
definitely been using for the last few
months and getting used
to we're also going to cover the
Hercules oil cartridge today which is
you know from my perspective of just
learning about this it's seemingly like
the cartridge it is the bubble bags of
oil cartridges uh not needing to be
replaced warrantied uh even fixed if
need be definitely there's a a big
discrepancy between you know an easy to
ous vaporizer like this and a serious
tool and the Hercules is kind of a
special case product it's for somebody
that really consumes a lot of oil and
they want a a professional grade tool to
put it to use something that doesn't
break down and require Replacements so
while we think thon's a super high
quality device the coils inside will
burn out eventually and need to be
replaced and the Hercules was a groundup
approach to make a device that didn't
require replacement parts didn't have
pieces that burned out so which is
incredible I will show you guys what's
inside the herk yeah he's going to show
you and I'm also going to photograph
what's inside the herk and show you with
inlaid pictures as we always do here on
Bubble man's world to show you just how
you know it it's it's quite there's
quite a few pieces yet it's quite a
simple unit in the sense that uh each
one of them comes apart quite nicely and
you can get a nice overview of all the
pieces certainly it's a purpose built
machine it's kind of complex and we
don't intend this to be the uh we don't
intend it to be the device of an
everyday vaporist it's for that 10% of
people that really want a serious tool
that don't mind cleaning occasionally
and the trade-off there is that if you
you know maintain this device properly
it can last you for years you can put
hundreds of grams through it and not
need to buy replacement parts and uh get
really really really flavorful
performance out of it so yeah tell us a
little bit about the inside of the unit
here it's all stainless steel is it so
we have stainless steel housings and
these are called the heater core we have
the upper heater core and the lower
heater core and the upper heater core is
where you load your oil into there's
also a ceramic Rod placed inside the
center of it you can remove the ceramic
rod and this heating unit actually comes
with a warranty disassemble this all the
way so you can see inside mhm oh yeah a
couple extra pieces there it's quite
incredible when you see the whole thing
taken apart and you look at each
component what each thing does andone
there's little ceramic Rod exactly none
of these were off the shelf components
they're all designed for this purpose
chamber goes inside and then you place
this Wick inside which fits around the
rod and this almost looks identical to
the pad that volcano did years ago for
their um the Volcano Vaporizer now I
don't believe they did it out of
titanium didn't they right they were
doing stainless steel that's what I
thought that's what I thought as well so
this is V2 yeah and we did a St the
steel mesh a couple years ago and then
we made the grade 2 titanium mesh it's a
little bit better flavor with an interm
metal mhm very nice so the rest of the
Hercules is there to uh basically Supply
power to the bottom of the ceramic Rod
so that it can heat up and uh trans it's
really nicely well made though you know
definitely thank you yeah what uh do we
have one loaded up that we can uh rip we
can put this one to use um our newest
version of the Hercules comes in a 510
threading so it's compatible with a lot
lot of different box mods out there and
it can run 20 to 35 watts is our
suggested operating range and I'm going
to pop an optional accessory on this is
a bubbler that we have called the
Nibbler XL the Nibbler XL check this out
so that we can see the vapor production
get a little moisture conditioning very
cool this has been my uh GL that thing
tastes like
turps oh it's still there oh yeah oh
this will be fun it's tury so this is a
product that I've been using for a
number of years before became an
employee I put a couple hundred grams
through my her and became an evangelist
and then decided to uh spread the word
hell yeah so the Nibbler XL put this guy
to work as I mentioned a lot of our
products are made in China this is one
of the things we make in America by
American scientific glass
blowers uh take some rips on it
sweet so Sam was telling me while we had
the camera off briefly that he has put
over 250 g of oil through this
particular cartridge right here which is
his Hercules this is the one that we
have all apart and the one that we're
going to be photographing uh so when I
photograph it and you look at it and you
think that it's a brand new thing you
can understand that this is just a
cleaned product that Sam has used
hundreds if not t over a thousand tons
definitely for a couple years I've been
using the same one and I think the only
pieces I've replaced in this unit are
the little PTFE insulators here these
are used to to keep positive and
negative separate and we sell rebuild
packs for 10 10 piece pieces for 10
bucks something like that don't quote me
on that it's close but there's not too
many parts that need to be replaced
these bottom insulators are a semic
consumable item especially if you are
using the Nibbler you can wear those out
and need a replacement they're $10 so
the majority of the components in here
are really made to last and we even put
a one-year warranty on the heating Rod
inside wow those are tasty tasty
delicious rips you can definitely tell
this is a serious unit this is not a
unit that you're going to buy and not
take seriously you have to clean the
unit you have to maintain the unit and
you have to cool the unit down unless
you want your oils to be dripping down
into that lower compartment it's a good
point you've got to learn how to use it
properly this is not as easy to operate
as the Omron it has a specific usage
technique you need to do draws to
preserve the flavor and keep air flowing
through it so that oils don't cook up
top and lose potency and lose their T
right so you'll take right now he's
drawing on it without pushing the button
and what he's doing is he's cooling the
oil inside the chamber so it doesn't
degrade to the point of all full tarine
loss and so you're hitting this really
generic sort of reclaim ta tasting uh
rips exactly we have air flow engineered
through the Hercules to cool down the
rod cool down the metal coils and
resolidify your oil so that you can load
a half gram at a time inside a coil and
it tastes good in the first hit and the
10th hit and the 20th hit and as long as
you maintain that buffer load inside the
coil and keep it saturated the flavor
stays good it doesn't degrade like after
three and four hits on a coil VAP we put
t drops of turps in there
too so we uh we're going strong here for
certain really nice unit that's a
serious unit that is not like I'm ex
toay with my wife and I just want to
take a little dab that is might not want
to go for this one yeah that's like a
whole different level that's a that's a
medical unit really I mean people that
are in chronic pain that require dabbing
to reduce their pain they could
definitely get their pain reduced i'
I've definitely talked to our customers
some of whom have have been in hospital
and they've brought Hercules inside to
medicate when you know they're basically
not able to eat they need the device for
pain management yeah we're definitely
trying to make really top quality
components not beating around the bush
with uh anything that could be unhealthy
or deliver a less than flavorful result
wow it's quite an incredible unit and I
guess it can fit on a variety of bases
sure any 510 threaded mod so standard
issue box mods these these days and it's
got fairly low power requirements so 20
to 35 Watts nothing fancy needed mhm we
are working on our own vaporizer that
will have a few fancier functions than
the EEG boxes that are out there or to
come on that down the road walk us
through the components one by one and
what I'll do is I'll show the closeups
of them as you're talking about it so
just talk about each one of these little
kind ofs that you've got going on here
maybe the best thing to do would be to
start with the instruction manual make
sure I don't miss any beats there you go
so the her does have a lot of components
and it also comes with instructions that
show how all these things are put
together great instructions thank
you and uh so we start at the bottom
this is uh in the inter computer cord
this allows power to transmit to the
ceramic Rod the ceramic Rod is going to
sit inside the upper chamber which is
where the oil coil is installed into and
this is what Wicks and feeds oil into
that ceramic
Rod so this slides
inside there's an adjustable airflow
washer that will go on the bottom so
that you can control the Restriction it
kind of acts like a carb
cap then you've got to set that manually
once it gets a little sticky with the
oil you were mentioning it's an optional
piece exactly and you would basically
wait for a little bit of oil to get
through and you can stick it to uncover
or cover the holes if you choose I like
to use my Hercules without it it's my
personal choice
lots of options there I think with the
bubbler it's nice without it maybe
without the bubbler you might want to
have it have it turned on a little more
who knows possibly there's a million
different preferences out there and so
we want to make sure the Hercules is a
flexible device so that different people
with different preferences can do
whatever they want to with it just like
the Omron has four power settings so it
works for people that want to take a
really light rip or a thicker one
Hercules has a lot of flexibility too
this is the bottom insulator so you
thread the assembled heater core onto
this and then we have PTS Fe heat shield
that threads on the outside of
it there's a top cap that goes inside
and this seals the top is that screw on
or just pop on it's just a press fit and
it does get sticky with oil so it won't
fall out of there once you've used it
and then the mouth piece threads on top
or optional bubbler attachment exactly
or the Nibbler XL mouthpiece replacement
piece excellent really cool the way you
can take that whole unit apart 100% see
every component of it it's uh I'm just
really stoked on because these fate pens
to me were always just like a mystery I
always wanted to be like but what's what
what is it what is it hopefully we can
do some work to demystify all that yeah
well I think the way you guys have
shared and uh are showing uh your
product is definitely a good way of
leading yourselves down that road of of
demystification and it's wonderful we've
managed to I've personally hit full melt
dry full melt bubble and rosin in these
units uh the Hercules is a serious unit
in this sense that it will rage through
F melts definitely it's the one device
we make that's intended for contaminant
Laden hashes so Omicron works great with
oils and with rosins uh but anything
with contaminant will build up on the
wire and you have to clean it off yeah
you get a crust over the wire and
obviously you don't want to be you know
brushing it too too difficult right you
could damage the coil by trying to flake
that crud off you can damage the coil at
the same time from my perspective at the
price that you guys sell these coils at
which is is it $12.95 they $12.99 for
one right we you know you have discounts
20% off for two or more to me that's
ridiculous to me those are borderline
replaceable in the sense that you just
I'm very happy that I have a few extras
I don't replace them all the time I
clean mine as I can but when one goes
it's so nice to just roll in a nice and
they're totally cleanable so if you have
a couple of them you can soak some of
them in isopropyl alcohol use your one
and then when the other ones get clean
cycle them out yeah no totally very cool
but the Hercules is awesome because uh
of its design you can soak all the parts
in isopropyl alcohol you can boil them
and the grade 2 titanium coil will get a
little buildup from contaminant
especially if you're putting Bubble or
dry sift in there uh however you just
hang that off the end of a grade 2
titanium Dabber hit it with some heat
you're going to take all the carbon off
and then the rod can be selfclean you
just apply power when you've uh rebuilt
your her so the whole thing is
completely user serviceable and it
shouldn't require any replacement even
if you're putting really dirty material
inside that's pretty [ __ ] awesome
dude very cool very cool I've put
straight um unscreened or sorry I should
say unsifted ke just out of the bottom
of a grinder with tons of contamin in it
so like 1% melt yeah and just cleaned it
up afterwards it still works great still
give you a tasty rip as tasty as ke can
be not as tasty as those not as tasty as
the dryft d42 uh TP dipped dry sift that
we that we hit down not at all well
that's great man I'm really stoked on uh
seeing how this moves forward in the
future I love the idea of these pens
just getting more and more conscious and
and more user friendly and at the same
time sustainable you know not tossed and
thrown away little components it's one
thing but the entire pen like people are
just like people buy too many pens and
they break and they throw them away and
we just we can't stand yeah that's it's
terrible all those batteries end up in
landfills if your Omron ever has a
problem you call us up or get in touch
there's limited lifetime warranties in
all our gear so we're here to take care
of you not make something that you have
to throw out works well that's one of
the things we offer at fresh headies as
well on the bubble bags and it's why I
use the analogy you know the lifetime
warranty that it's it's important to
stand behind your product you guys are
selling it at a great price too like I'm
surprised some of the pens that were on
the market in the beginning were more
expensive than what you guys are selling
like your full-size battery kit for so
that's that's pretty
mind-blowing definitely stoked want to
give a shout out to uh Gary the uh the
creator of these products and uh the
owner of the company he's uh really
doing good work out there and I'm stoked
to have hooked up with Sam to be able to
bring this video to Bubble man's world
and share this uh this information as we
can left to do really we're going to add
some pictures to the video which you'll
have already seen uh but we have yet to
do I guess we're probably going to end
the video on that note and go and enjoy
some more bubble and some dry sift and
some rosin and just uh thanks for coming
out dude apprting me this Sunday
pleasure absolutely really appreciate it
so we'll see you guys soon on Bubble
man's world and and uh yeah May the full
Mount bless your bowl sooner than
later bu in action I
reaction
satisfaction sck
M welcome to
[Music]
the herbalist can
specialist herbaliz
[Music]
was
night
in
50u Manu
[Music]
D say here comes the officer asking for
a search find a weapon
herbalist horiz man herbalist The canab
[Music]
Specialist
speci pull me over you a search
the pull it up and give it a sniff
turn I say yes and I also
got full m Ed all that Dy make you cool
and relax and if you get some you must
come
backal man herbalist can
special her
[Music]