[Music]
a
he
[Music]
all right so doing a little pre-soak
here yeah getting things nice and cold
he's rocking the trim and the and the
ice and it's a good
idea it's always good you ever pre-wash
your
trim there's a little trick you can do
with the trim after after I make it
sometime I wash the hash okay okay yeah
this is a different little trick I'll
show you it's uh basically
about just taking what just doing
basically what you're doing pre- soaking
it and then when you take it out of
there a lot of the contaminant will stay
in the water okay that's that's a good
idea buddy yeah you just filter the you
can filter it out and still save the
hash that is potentially lost as well
your can too buddy what's that
Fu [ __ ]
sh so basically where we're walking used
to be under the
ocean looks like that it really does
man Ching nice let me pop pop this place
over do your thing do your thing no
Rush's the general General's
coming he's
coming here comes
trouble so he's got quite a few planted
in each one
easy [ __ ] taking chunks of my skin
huh
tell us about the neem so what I do I
chop the neem tree and throw the leaves
all over here you know yeah so nice it's
a natural pesticide NE oil of course
that's excellent so you've just got neem
leaves all around the area and it's
protecting the plants from
PES but it's great man but this pest
it's
also it lives in the leaf I've seen them
do this yeah so they they eat like corll
or whatever they take out the leave here
yeah come down buddy and come
over irrigation yeah very
smart we from the river you know you
using uh gravity or a pump oh we using a
pump okay cool
cool just started flowering in the last
week yeah great it's starting to look
really nice already
though going to be
big this is nice you notice how narrow
the Leaf is on this so are what what are
the the cultivars here do you just have
a lot of seed that's a mix of seed that
you plant and then you put them out or
do you have an idea that there's some
varieties cuz some have I started out
with um the blueberry it's very broad
get some Diesel and I mix them together
so I don't know what I got but I got
something nice for sure you do
yeah
yeah quite a narrow leaf on this one
yeah man all over here we got even the
vegetables growing right with the ganja
this is the Cal kalalo yeah little
kalalo growing with the ganja all over I
bet you everything loves growing with
the ganja yeah man and everything is a
pest of the ganja Birds ants everything
loves it everything loves it not just
the people no sir they're all like yeah
goats every animals everything loves it
so you can really tell that you've done
a lot of work in this little plot
fencing it off I mean even just to move
this many tires filled with Earth and to
place them in this uh environment is
it's a lot of work man it's commendable
you know the Ganja Farmer is a hard
working man but it's not work when
you're having fun exactly when you love
it yeah it just becomes your passion
work when the [ __ ] Federal is taken
from you oh that's stress
[Laughter]
oh yeah we can't have
that well good job man I'm impressed I
really like what you got going on
here so I feed them basically water
every day and I use like the goat the
goat manure I put it inside the tires
with mixed with the dirt do you do you
water in the morning or or do you water
as Sunset well in this stage it's it's
better to water in the evening yeah
that's what I'm saying those ones over
there is best to water in the morning
because they they could gather the
energy to grow in the day and these ones
are flouring so they water them in the
night so they use the water to make big
buds you know mhm all right so the
vegging ones water at in the morning
keep them from burning give them water
to produce their their vegetative state
and then
water these guys at night they're I I'd
say about one to two weeks some of them
seem a little more than a week in yeah
what what is it this seems a couple
weeks in well they're all the same ages
but um some of them are faster than some
because there's the mixed train with the
blueberry and um the the diesel right
yeah so they
move whatever some come looking like the
blueberry and some come looking like the
Diesel and some come looking like
something different I don't know you
know M
see well you know some might call you a
Ganja Farmer but I call you a tricomb
farmer cuz you're also a hash man and
you get those tricomes off the hash yeah
you're growing for tricomes Dam man yeah
man the ganja
man great job yeah really nice uh nice
little Gard
Garden nice bigger tractor tires here
yeah
tract got the tractor some more
vegetables growing in with these
ones
everywhere call can't get came up here
and I get my
dinner our break are something that's
beautiful when you get to go to your
ganja fields to pull some food
out that is definitely a good thing yeah
and if I didn't have to fence here for
the goats I'll be having like corns and
beans and and lots more
stuff no I I'm a worker and I'm also a
hustler yeah dude so you know you got to
hustle I'm not just a
hustle you know it's so much more comen
commendable when you have the ethics of
a worker yeah to back up the Hustler
mentality what's going on an ansest are
we on an ants nest right now I was on oh
[ __ ] this little one right here yeah
that's that's the H to get in but right
here is all the nest all the nest damn
well let's stay off of that you
definitely reacted to that you got to
move you got to move the
N damn ants what are you thinking there
John pretty awesome man a bad e yeah
pretty Dar I've been hearding about
bubble man for the longest time you know
said I wanted to meet him because you
were like my Jesus
oh this guy let me put food on my table
every
day yeah man as long as you have hash
you always have some
cash yeah man no lie it makes you
different than the rest of the folks
here having the the bags and
everything not really because everybody
has to find something to do and you know
it's like you know when you find
something you're good at and something
people respect you for you just keep
doing it
true yeah man and I hold it all to the
hash to the bubble man see he's the
general yeah man bless up
General want some water I would love
some water soon come come man yeah man I
come with
you some nice freshly freshly watered
plants saying it's a little jungle trick
they think it's the rain they start
shooting up more shoots
and that would definitely be something I
wouldn't have known I would have thought
that the water would have burned the
plant where does it go you pour it right
in the top there don't worry about
it
perfect oh a little bit more little bit
more poured out too much oh I'm going
just going to pour in you catch yeah
perfect perfect all right
man all right right back to the session
I got the denail set up sorry the
dabinator set up over here with this the
denail Whip and silicone carbide nail
we're about to do a little ganja session
a little hash
session here in the ganja field all
right hey guys bubble man here we are in
the beautiful beautiful Negril Orange
Hill up in the mountain side uh over at
the hash man's place we saw his hash the
other day he had the handful of course
on Instagram it got over 2,000 likes so
we're stoked for that very good picture
yeah and today we wanted to see a little
bit of where that hash you know is being
grown and he was able to bring us up the
mountain to one of these little these
little Fields some plants over there in
veg some plants in bloom maybe about a
couple of weeks into bloom at the most
and still looking very nice wonderful
smell on the resin and we thought we
would have a little dabinator session so
we got the mothership Fab
EG the denail dropped down Cory cotton
them dropped down with denail sick Bowl
in the dabinator we got our little
battery and I'm going to hit a little
bubble man brand orange creamsicle it's
the last that I have left and I thought
what better place to come and hit the
last of some of this beautiful
hash oh yeah it's just like butter we're
also going to do a TP dip into the Jack
Frost
because why wouldn't
we we TP dip see the hash getting wet
from from the TPS M so when you pull
them out the hash it's got a little bit
of a shine to it on the tip there that's
the TP
dip all right this may be my first ever
Mothership dab in a ganja field in
Jamaica so I want to thank you for that
y welcome man blessed love y all right
here we
go
[ __ ] yeah that changed the vibe a little
bit [ __ ] you want some biger
LS absolutely wonderful we're going to
continue on smoke as many bowls in this
field as we can I do have to run off and
hide in the shade every once in a while
we're also doing live Periscope and
John's filming as well for his Chann
Channel which is Ming media Ming media
check those guys out on Google they've
got Vimeo and YouTube channels really
great stuff uh really nice documentary
and editing Styles and he's helping us
out a little bit today holding the
camera so wanted to thank him out and
maybe offer him a dab oo
lovely hey
B why the timber Rock feel real good
give me a puff
[Music]
one manr man real purpose of the we that
keeps me
going the purpose of the we that to the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after the we l I
view the
time with is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of been traveling to kingst mil hours
sing on like fresh vation with trees and
with
flowers give me a
big
me
[Music]
pass I make pass pass pass and
then I that I couldn't that up thew that
now before BL
that
and that
now purpose after the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
mind after we gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed L I
view the
time weed is not here to trick the mind
all right so we're just in here chilling
out in the little ganja field five six
more weeks you
think to go yeah what do you
think maybe tree really you go that
early you only flower for 5 six
weeks well in
Jamaica due to the the on the weather
the plants doesn't go that tall so we
got like basically 6 to 8 weeks before
Harvest okay okay that makes sense 6 to8
weeks these 55 gallon drums are they
your rain
catches or you just pump water from your
pump water
cool fill them up yeah man pump it from
the river and how many you know how many
55 gallon drums can can you use on this
field when it's like you know really
eating water the whole field is it like
a one a day or one every two
days
M maybe two every day two every day wow
that's a hot
sun 250 so 100 gallons of water a day
for what could be anywhere from 200 to
300 plants uh blooming in various
different stages but actually blooming
in the same
there some ones over there oh yeah
little babies oh yeah I
see little
[Music]
babies there he
is with
yep and do you plan on turning a lot of
this into
hash yeah well
mostly the trimmings and some of the
small plants goes into hash that's great
that you're using the trimmings cuz I I
did see your hash and it it sure looked
a lot better than most of the hash I see
commercially available on the streets of
well you know this part of the country
in orang Hill the resin on the weed is
is higher than every other place I've
been to so we can use the the the
trimmings and make beautiful hash too
that's great yeah and you you take
pounds of weed too sometimes and just
make hash yeah man sometime even five or
10 lbs beautiful make a pound of hash
excellent yeah that's the way to do it
respect it I'm
on sometime guys want like a pound or
kia hash and I got to make it for
them wow th000 grams on demand yeah man
hash man is your man yeah man have to
make it for them
great get it dried and ready to smoke
well I definitely want to thank you for
inviting us up here to hang out and
chill with you for a bit I know we're
going to make some hash later on today
yeah and so we should film a little bit
of that as well I'm going to turn you on
to some new tips and I want to get you
some uh some more bags for your kid Yeah
man so uh we're going to do that later
you guys can check it out it'll just be
a simple transition for you but for us
there'll be a whole couple of
experiences in between the two so thanks
for watching one love my life it's my
life it's my life
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
life we're coming from behind
[Music]
behind Spirit you un worry years are on
a
mission showing the world
of spiritual
Warriors