I am over here in one of flab 421 secret
Chambers he's pulled out patcha Mama
blown by Cory cotnam and Stratosphere
glass you can check them both out on
Instagram @ Cory glass and @
Stratosphere glass this piece is
unbelievable not sure if you can see the
leaf but it's got a beautiful spinning
cannabis leaf and it also has a nice
little spinner down on the bottom here
at about the halfway point in the
pipe so we got these two spinners
and I think we're going to go in for a
lovely dab this is a piece that you do
not pick up but you hit
it while it sits
[Music]
man as tasty as it is beautiful thanks
for watching Bubble man's
world I
make and then
[Music]
all right so you've got Swiss Tsunami
Tsunami with some of the RZ in there
purple candy no green crack God and then
the purple candy bubble and then purple
yeah this is all West Coast turn it
around so we can see
inside oh oh greasy all right and then I
dipped it in the tsunami in the sour
tsunami and now you're about to rip that
[ __ ] Cory cotum ripping the P pcha Mama
yeah pcha
Mama
beautiful spin it that's what I'm saying
right
there can someone please spin that thing
choice