[Music]
[Applause]
yeah oh yeah oh yeah I forgot
something on your seats of course you
you've all got the little gifts of
extracts but you've also got this
fabulous bookmark and you're looking at
it you're saying great I'm going to read
something with it right turn it over on
the
back if it is signed by
Paul you have been given a free copy of
my celium running and he will sign it
for you up
here
[Music]
this is going to be um this is going to
be an immersion talk I hope that
subsequent this talk your lives will
forever be changed for the better um
this is a a culmination of over 40 years
of research and I'm just so honored to
be the messenger of this knowledge it's
really hard and and know it's not right
I can't claim ownership of this
knowledge but I feel like I'm a conduit
and um the end of this talk there's an
epiphany that is taken me 30 years to
achieve epip usually happen faster but
not with me um and so but I want you to
sort of clear your receptor sites open
up your minds take a deep breath hold on
to your proverbial hat um and um I do
speak rather quickly um but the um
Avalanche of knowledge that is about to
wash over you is U something that is
that really speaks to guyan intelligence
the intelligence of Nature and I'm just
so honored at this time critical period
in the evolution of Life on this planet
that I'm alive to be one of the
messengers and there'll be more
Messengers obviously you know in the
future so um okay so I want to tell you
about my hat because Jeff has one oh I
wanted to first I want to dedicate this
uh talk to Steve Shephard Steve will you
please stand up
so uh Dr Steve Shephard is the chair of
enology at Washington State
University um and our relationship has
been magical it's been catalyic uh it's
a dance of minds and spirits that I
think U synergizes to something that'll
U lead to an evolutionary jump and what
we can do to help this planet so this
hat is made from a mushroom called amadu
amadu is a birch poly por it's a hard
wood con and amadu um is a mushroom that
really is uh responsible for why humans
survived especially thousands of years
ago there's no doubt that we came from
Africa 40,000 years ago we migrated
North into Europe we discovered
something new called winter oops and
this mushroom allowed for the
portability of fire this called a Tinder
CLK uh and our ancestors realized if you
Hollow this mushroom out put EMP of fire
inside it can carry fire for days now
ceremonially today in First Peoples the
firekeeper of the of the clan um has a
very important symbolic role but not too
long ago they literally held the life of
the clan in their hands because as you
approach the winter if you couldn't
Kindle a fire uh then of course you know
the freezing temperatures would be very
very detrimental so moreover um this
mushroom when you put it into lie water
ashes and water and pull it after a few
days it delaminates into melum and so
this mushroom is made of melum um and
our this is this tradition has been
going on for thousands of years this hat
is actually made by some ladies in
Transylvania um and there's about seven
or eight hat makers a few years ago now
there's only three or four um and this
is an example of the threat of knowledge
that goes through time and because of
disease War relig religious persecution
you know accidents the the threads of
knowledge have been clipped and um and
this is why it's so important with first
people here the on on the west Western
North America in particular the oral
Traditions when there's disease and they
lose their Elders they lose that contact
you know to the ancient past so this
mushroom also revolutionized Warfare in
Napoleonic times um this this mushroom
became the the the punk that made Flint
spark spark guns work it created the
spark that the gunpowder so there's a
massive amount of trade in Napoleonic
times of the of the Amad mushroom um
this mushroom also is the first mushroom
ever found to have an antiviral property
highly active against the mosaic virus
uh which afflicts many many plants um
and um this mushroom um has other
properties um that are key to the
ecosystem that I'll be showing you in in
the very near future here so I have a
few other f friends and I'll be talking
about amadu a lot I'll be talking about
the red RI mushroom that I have
here you'll be hearing about the red
belted polypore which is called um
phomopsis picula these are all up on the
slide here by the way so as I hold these
up you can see them um and then there is
another Birch poor called cha innot
oblas so these are four of the species
I'll be talking about but I have one
other friend I brought with me
and this is a garon a garon goes
exclusively in the old growth forest
it's known as f topsis a fish nus it is
uh now thought to be extinct largely in
Europe a few sky islands in Austria and
Slovenia uh and the high ales but
otherwise largely extinct in Europe
because they cut down the old growth
forest it still grows in Northern
California Oregon Washington State and
here in British Columbia diares
described this Mushroom in 5 ad 2,000
years ago as elerium at longum vum the
elixir of long life um and this mushroom
I suggest to you is similar in a
significance in terms of it medical and
benefit for human survival as we enter
into the next Century so I want to um
well here we
go so the title of my talk is mus of
melum in the worldwide food web and
micro diversity is essential for
biocurity we live in this wonderful
Planet but we've now entered into Sixx
the sixth greatest Extinction event
known in the history of life this planet
but this Extinction event is not caused
by an asteroid it's not CA by methane
hydrate hydrate bursts out of the ocean
um is not caused by Cosmic race is
caused by an organism by us not only we
the cause of this Extinction event but
we're very likely to be is vicin but I
think there is a path for human survival
in in um in the dance with nature and
that is if we follow the path of melum I
think we will be well rewarded as well
Justified well unfortunately there's a
lot of bad news before we get to the
good news and this is an article that
came out in science just recently and
basically 58% of the of the the species
richness uh in the land masses have gone
now down below the caring capacity for a
sustainability and so we have fracturing
ecosystems we're artificially supporting
our food web through importation of
foods we have factory farming uh in the
pursuit of efficiency we lose
biodiversity but there is a a context
here when we bring fungi into the into
the conversation in terms of ecological
stability there's lots of benefits that
are being reaped but let's first go back
in time this is a pict gra in a in a
cave in Northern Algeria that Ayan andar
Plateau um and this was from 7,000 years
ago it's very interesting to me because
there is um a there's a term that argon
Watson described it's called mobia the
irrational fear of fungi um and it's
really quite clear what the artist's
intention was here the artist was really
excited about
mushrooms even though this is in scient
several scientific journals not none of
the scientists would dare speculate what
the intent of the artist was or what
these little Figures were well I think
this speaks to something that also
afflicts the Sciences in that you know
we in our experiential viewscape uh we
have long-term contact with animals and
plants we have a familiarity Factor but
mushrooms they come up and they
disappear in a few days typically the
flesher mushrooms and so mushrooms that
are so ephemeral and you only encounter
their very infrequently and there
suddenly gone but with something that
can feed you that can kill you that can
heal you that can send you on a
psychedelic spiritual journey and yet
disappears you know our experiential
context is very very limited so it's
natural for humans to fear that which is
so powerful but which is not well
understood so now we we've come to a new
threshold of knowledge and um and this
knowledge I think is just really
revolutionary in its implications well
going forward in time this is 450 BCE
and this is a a a a Codi where demer is
giving prapan a mushroom uh and upon
consuming the mushroom then she goes
into the underworld this is speaks to
the origination myth and Greek culture
of the seasons and so the winter would
ensue and then the spring she would come
back up and you know the crops will grow
and warmer environments and this is the
cyol the seasons all related to deer
giving prapan this mushroom mov and she
went to the underworld there a great
book called The Road to elus the Elan
Mysteries that speaks about the
religious use of psychoactive mushrooms
by the Greek cultures Plato um Sophocles
Aristotle all partook of these magical
mushroom Brews and a great teston in
Greek culture thousands of years ago but
hypocrates around 460 BCE first
mentioned amadu uh for carzing wounds it
was recognized back then as being highly
flamable and it was very very good has
an anti-inflammatory as well as carzing
wounds because of this flammability and
as I mentioned diares in about 65 ad the
very first Materia Meda um introduced a
gacon um and recorded it it was used
long before that of course um as highly
active against respiratory illnesses
especially consumption so um these this
gives you sort of the threat of
knowledge going back over the eons that
the use of these mushrooms were actually
and knowledge of were quite pervasive
but I always like give credit to my
teachers and so this is uh Dr Daniel
stunts from the University of Washington
Dr Alexander Smith from the University
of Michigan Katherine skates from Post
Falls Idaho and Michael Bu from The
Evergreen State College he was my direct
Professor these three individuals have
passed on and Michael bu and I are still
in contact I just saw him last week and
um I came into the field of mology
rather Young when I about 16 or 17 years
of age my interest in mushrooms um and
when I was about 18 19 19 years of age I
was sort of adopted by these these huge
giants in the field of micology um and
they took me under their wi all the more
surprising because Alexander Smith in
particular and Daniel stunts were yeah
politically conservative individuals so
when I came on the scene um in about
1975 it was um all the more surprising
that they took a liking to me because
this is what I look
like your suspicions are I'll
[Music]
confirm so um but they saw that I had
sincere interest and and Bui and of
course had magic mushrooms and the
reason I had such an interest in magic
mushrooms in particular is because of my
dear brother John who unfortunately
passed away a few years ago um John went
down to Mexico and Colombia came back
with these fantastic stories of eating
soul and mushrooms I really excited I'm
the youngest son the youngest child in
my family of five John was the oldest
brother but John was was a serious
scientist we grew up in a small town in
Ohio we had a complete laboratory in the
basement I'm talking three rows of
chemicals on on on on shelves three
three shelf rows of chemicals and my
father was a lieutenant and that y car
there in trepid and so after wood War II
he got the Intrepid aircraft carrier
radio the main radio so we had that in
the basement and my brother would let me
play in the laboratory on the radio and
and I was listening to all these cated
messages behind the Iron Curtain strung
these long wave antennas and it was just
totally exciting I was this boy
scientist I thought oh when I grow up
I'm going to be a scientist you know
have own laboratory because my brother
wouldn't let me play in the laboratory
so John went on the Yale my brother bill
went on the Cornell uh my sister went on
the Ohio State and then I had the
laboratory to myself you know which I
remember immediately looking up every
experiment and said danger do not bring
their flame boom um I had a few of those
um but that was sort of really imprinted
me and now I'm living my life's stream
you know I'm fortunate and gratified
that I have a a wonderful company I have
75 employees I I Own 100% I have no debt
um it's been a long road I'm here today
because of the generosity and kindness
of many people including many people in
this room many of you so I have really
you know been been um sort of imprinted
uh by this love of Science and um and
from my family and I want to give a deep
respect to my brother John who really
first inspired me but this is where I
love like to say we go to church on
Sundays I like to go in the old growth
forest I grew up in a Charismatic
Christian environment um after my family
sort fell apart my mom became very
religious and my mother says when are
you going to go to church and I go mom I
go to the Old Forest all the time so to
me that's like I going to church but
let's look at the the ecosystem of the
of the forest and to get better
understanding this is a cross-section of
the mixed deciduous Conor for Forest
there are sacrific fungi that break down
dead wood there are the endic fungi that
are inside Tri of trees and leaves in
fact there literally can several hundred
species been identified tically that are
growing beneficially to help the host
defensive immunity of plants against
infections and then the microa fun lots
of you uh know about this and I want to
give a shout out to Dr Suzanne Samar she
is a hero of mine she's a micro rology
you know and micrology here in British
Columbia and then there's a parasitic
fungi that can kill weakened trees and
uh and then often times grow cytic like
Jeff mentioned the honey mushroom is a
parasite and they can grow
cytic well as wasn't until just recently
that scientist discovered that all
plants are part fungus now I remember
doing thick thin sectioning in the
botney and looking under the microscope
and I see threads of fungi and my
professor would say oh they're
infections it's causing a disease well
now we know that they aren't many of
these threads of fungi are part of the
community of fungi that gives the host
uh organism the plant better immune
protection and um and the consorting of
the spongy really make a huge difference
in terms of their survival now excellent
book I highly recommend is micral
symbiosis this is the little pine tree
this is the root here but all this is
the rizosphere this is the microsphere
around the rizosphere and it literally
extends the root zones hundreds if not
thousands of times the plants are
secreting sugars and then and they're
benefiting the fungi and the fungi are
then uh contributing Minal that then
helps the plants to grow but increases
the moisture absorption capability and
the mineral untake uptake enormously
well yeah so science is so slow to catch
up to me what I think is the obvious but
this is a great experiment it was only
done in
2013 and this experiment kind of
revolutionized our understanding of the
communication networks that Suzanne
samart and other ones other scientists
are now talking about and what these
scientists did is they had five bean
plants and separate pots and they uh the
beans were growing up fine and they
exposed the first bean plant with aphids
well immediately um anti-aid alids
uptick uh uh were coed and expressed by
the plant that was being attacked by
apids as a protection uh these were
toxic Al alids the apids well the other
four plants did not of course they
didn't have direct contact when they
repeated the experiment and they put all
five plants in the same common U vessel
of soil where the microsphere of the
melum then inter connected when they
exposed the first plant with aphids what
happened all four other plants remote
from contact up regulated the anti-aid
alkaloids this then proved for the first
time the scientists that the melum
actually is a communication pathway that
is communicating in order to protect the
community of organisms within the
biosphere to be able to protect the
biodiversity and so this was an
astonishing breakthrough on our
understanding that these myal networks
are actually communication NW n works as
well now mycelium can take many
different forms this is just some of the
forms that I I enjoy and this next is a
10day sequence and so often times my
time La sequence don't work and this is
the melum rep dis this is a lot of part
of my life I have about 700 strains in
in culture of melium about over 500
species in our laboratory complex um but
we most mostly primarily focus on
sacrifice because I'm naturally
impatient and I'm very interested in
saic fungi sapic fungi break down Li
cellulose the primary plant constituents
and um and so we take wood primarily we
had melium lots of things happen but
ultimately we generate soil so these
sacratic fungi are the grand molecular
disassembles of nature the soil
magicians they break down complex plant
and animal tissue and they render It
ultimately into soil and that way of
decomposition then feeds many other
communities and and in in in um in the
ecosystem now I'm involved in the
permaculture movement and I was at a
zeri conference and the Zer permaculture
people were wondering how is it possible
mushrooms grow in in the desert we you
know we have these mul sheep piles and
then suddenly all these mushrooms are to
form and I realized that that they did
not know if you take a 100 like 100
kilos of uh of sawdust for instance up
to 20 kilos of water will be released
out of 100 kilos of dried sawas mushroom
melium generat water so it inhales
oxygen it's then breaking down Li
cellulous it combines hydrogen oxygen to
H2O and so it generates its own water
hydrating the habitats in advance of
contact this makes sense because around
compost piles many of you've seen little
puddles of water that's what's happening
so very interesting article because of
monoculture and I spent a lot of time in
the woods uh for 3 years I was in the
wood products industry actually four
years I was U I ran I was on the green
chain pulling Saw Mill I caught up in a
shingle Mill I went into as a logger I
set chokers became a rig and Slinger
three guys in my crew got killed and
they wanted me to appoint me when I was
21 years of age as the head of the crew
I said I'm going back to college um but
those three guys who died I mean I they
I depended upon them for my life and
they depended upon me so I really got a
feeling of deep Brotherhood and respect
for the School of Hard kns so a shout
out to all those people who've gone
through this scho of hard KN who have a
great respect but unfortunately because
of mono culture of slash and burn
planting trees slash and burn
unfortunately we're harming the
biodiversity of the ecosystem um and now
we are seeing um that we are getting
premature decline as soil lenses become
thinner the carbon exported out of the
ecosystem but it's very inter this that
in healthy soils 70% of the soils are
composed of microbial mass and 30% of
that soil mass is fungal so 20 1%
approximately of healthy soil is fungal
cells living or dead that's how much
fungi there is literally in under the
under your feet upon every step that you
make on soil now I spent many years as a
scanning electron microscopist this is
some of my electron micrographs here's
the mushroom myum under under electron
microscope and then under the response
to four environmental stimuli well
introduction of rain we've had lots of
that turn to be a great mushroom season
when you have introduction of rain and
water that's one you also have
evaporation so you have cooling so drop
in temperature that's what happens in
the fall that's number two the third is
the melium then as it comes up to the
wet surface it exhales carbon dioxide
inhales oxygen so exposure to oxygen is
number three and the fourth one is quite
surprising to many people is light 99%
of all mushrooms require light before
the mycelium will produce a mushroom
fruit body and so light is critical for
mushroom formation so those are the four
primary stimuli now the fact that we
exhale carbon oide in fungi 2 speaks to
our common evolutionary relationship 650
million years ago there there we had a
common ancestor in fact a new super
Kingdom has been created called a pisant
that joined Animalia and fungi together
at that split when we split from fungi
the fungi went underground externally
digesting its nutrients outside it cell
walls we chose the path of in
circulating our nutrients in a cellular
sa and then producing enzymes and
digesting foods Within so that's kind of
the split between animals and fungi
fungi e digest our nutrients externally
we digest our nutrients internally so in
respons is for environmental stimuli
then a mushroom then severly emerges and
a matter of four or 5 days it goes from
this state here to this state now
mushrooms actually do not have a good
very good immune system most all of them
because they're the fruit bodies like a
peach on a tree it ripens it attracts
herbivores you know and us and insects
and animals just spread the pits and
spread the seeds mushrooms are no
different they're very very protein and
sugar rich but they're delicious and
they attract a lot of animals that can
help spread the spores so but I'm
fascinated with the decomposition cycles
of mushrooms and so the mushrooms then
as they begin to decompose for instance
there's a rush lless species in the Old
grth Forest a few days later I come back
and all sorts of spores are germinating
there's other fungi and lots of bacteria
a whole you know microbiome is evolving
and then a few days later it goes
underground e goes Subterranean in a
single inch of soil there can be more
than a mile of these Thin Red like
threads of melium my foot covers
approximately 300 miles of melium and so
the melum actually is resident in the
ecosystem for a very long time the melum
is the immune system of the mushroom and
my friend Patrick hicki made these
movies and when he made these
microscopic movies it really
revolutionized our understanding about
the how these fungal networks work these
are are bundles of nuclei that are
streaming through the mycelial networks
and notice that they surge in clusters
well as it turns out melum grows and a
SWAT of mycelium the breath of my arms
here can literally have billions of end
branches are constantly forking at the
very very tips they become polynuclear
many nuclei for cell later on they just
have two nuclei for cell as the mcel
that's old but the melum you know all
nuclei don't go in One Direction some of
them are going backwards against
cytoplasmic flow and so think of the at
the branches the tips there's hundreds
of nuclei sometimes per cell and it just
takes two nuclei to reassort and if
there's a new insect a new toxin a new
piece of plants a new piece of wood and
if they code for the enzyme that can
break down that new potential food
resource and then they can incorporate
it what happens the melium surges but
then that genetic information becomes
encoded within the melium so not only
are these externalized digestive
membranes not only these externalized
lungs exhaling carbon dioxide inhaling
inhaling oxygen but these are are
learning networks you know these are
these are Micron neurological networks
that are constantly adapting to sudden
chains to C catastroph and they're able
to navigate and then learn and encode
within them within their genetic memory
the ability to to have that information
to help them to survive in the future so
we're up here in the BC Zone um and
here's the Columbia River and I live
near Olympia Washington and we're going
to fly down here to the John Day
Wilderness I literally hired an airplane
and flew down there to see the biggest
organism in the world is a myal map 2200
acres in size 1665 football fields and
it's one cell wall thick now think of
that you have five or six skin layers
that protect you from infection the
melium has one cell wall on the other
side of which are hundreds of millions
of microbes per gram many of which are
trying to consume it how is that
possible possible how is it possible the
largest organism in the world only has
one Thin cell layer that protects it
from from infection it's because it's a
constant bi communication with his
ecosystem it's able to navigate is able
to learn to adjust in this case the
largest organism in the world is a
hunting mushroom now I hired an airplane
and I flew down there once as a small
Bush pilot with a cloth you cloth
airplane uh covered airplane I went down
there and we couldn't find it and we had
the L latitude longitude from the
scientific article on this and we went
back to Boe field and we looked at our
our you know maps and I was there so the
next day we flew back down there again I
flew up and flew down there I still
couldn't see it so we had a climb an
elevation a climbing elevation so we
spiral up spiral up and I finally I saw
it and we're at 14,500 ft we just came
from sea level and I told the pilot I
think I'm going to faint and he goes me
too I oh no so let me get this
Photograph boom I took this Photograph
the best phot photogra I think of the
largest org in the world and when you
and it would kill the trees and so the
fort service would cut them down because
of lightning strikes C Firs but this is
basically the honey mushroom this is
what the trees look like I suspect for
my hiking in the sub alpar regions of of
the Cascades in the Olympics I wonder if
these mushrooms are actually Meadow
makers they actually climax the forest
they kill it the trees then die off and
Meadows come back and this is the way of
the ecosystem do time out with ulates
and deer and Elam and gra and way of the
ecosystem reestablishing but I've always
been confused why would there be Meadows
when there's all these forests and and I
think the honey mushroom is actually a
meadow maker so looking at the melium it
uh is wonderfully articulated and it
forms these micro cavities the micro
cavities swell with water and so a bated
habitat is a spongy habitat it holds
water it keeps water in the ecosystem
well that benefits all sorts of other
members in the ecological community and
moreover it's it's integration and it
sophistication of n working allows it
such that there's a break in a strand
then there's alternative Pathways
removing information nuclei Copic flow
to the rest of the network and so this
is one of the few organisms that you can
actually disturb and it benefits from
that disturbance um so the melium is
producing extracellular metabolites it's
absorbing nutrients anywhere along the
entire surface area and as it in these
metabolites it's they have anti
bacterial properties antimicrobial
properties and I believed and stated
that I believe they're deterministic in
pre-selecting the micro uh micro
microbial environment that is essential
for the plants to grow in the soil they
give rise to the canopy that grees the
debr field that then feeds the melum
resonant within um so I think these are
deterministic in the in the microbiomes
they're selecting that then helps the
plant communities Thrive and ultimately
guarantees the the progeny from these
FAL networks well Co with the growth of
these Fong as I mentioned there are
bacteria these are rods of bacteria here
um and and these rods the bacterial
communities are controlled by the
extracellular metabolites so um I put
together this this chart just in the
past few days you're about to see and
this is the melium that's grown on
sterile substrates in our laboratory now
this is eoli the dreaded 0157 staus orus
this is Mera MRSA the methy strains stus
orus I sered uh they chose about 12
species and this is a this is 10 to the
eth power a little higher than that uh
10 to eth power is more than 100 million
colonies and a and a milliliter of water
one gram is 1 Mill of water so the
startings the FDA laboratory and then we
challenge it with 1 milliliter of these
extracellular droplets uh from the
melium with 1 M of the bacterial
enriched water and in 24 to 7 2 hours it
went from 100 million colonies down to
uh to 10 to the thir power and then 10
to the second power so it went from 100
million colonies to to 10 thou to
100,000 one reduction to 1,00 to 100 a
remarkable uh drop in pathogenic
bacteria so this was the first time this
has ever been done um and I was able to
show that growing on cized substrates
that the melum from the wild would carry
forward these antimicrobial defenses
because we share in common many of the
same pathogens that harm us also harm
funi so candida uh um saus eoli are
pathogens to fungi as well as pathogens
to us so we can make take advantage of
the antimicrobial host defense immunity
of these fungi in order to protect us so
there's I have about 38 YouTube videos I
really encourage you to look at this one
I don't have time to show it but we
developed this submerged fermentation
method where we just take wood chips we
put it in water for two weeks we do this
with straw we can use this with salt
water and um it goes Anor robic if we
don't stir it it gets a bacterial slime
on it and and and the microbial
population changes from aerobic bacteria
to anerobic bacteria and then we just
let it sit for a long time for two weeks
and then we drain it uh and when we
drain it oxygen becomes a sterilizer
against the hobes and then you can
inoculate with mycelium and mycelium
runs like crazy it gobbles up the anoro
which not es fixating and because of the
high oxygen environment so we've been
doing this there's a great YouTube
videos I have up there to show you how
to do this and then U so I was said okay
I have a common batch of wood chips let
me inoculate from the same batch and I
put in the garden Giant in one and I put
herex lacus which is a crusted polypore
that's very important in bi remediation
and so I put them in the same wood chips
that and then we did what's called next
gen sequencing and a wonderful thing
about being in charge of my own company
and having a control of the bank account
is I can spend
money and so I spent thousands of
dollars so on this chart and this this
this we found a thousandfold difference
in the relative abundance across 500
species of bacteria that were selected
out by the garden giant mushroom versus
the crusted polycor first time this has
ever been shown is that the microbiome
in the soil in this case in the wood
chips was controlled by the antibiotic
profiles of species that we were prob
this was huge so um so this is an
example of healthy happy melium uh this
strand of melum here I weighed it and uh
1 cm compared to what this weight was
the difference was 30,000 to1 so 1 cm
length of myum held 30,000 times its
mass phenomenal so myum grows through a
habitat it's also tenacious and holds it
together well the melium runs is why my
book called myum running this is a happy
melium this is where it's multinucleate
on the very tips of the running edges
melium are are Edge Runners they love to
run along the edges um and so this is
this is what we want to see as
cultivators is rapidly the diverging
myal networks that are constantly on the
move and they're producing all sorts of
enzymes lactases in particular that are
able to break down cellulous and lium
well in the old growth forest was a
treasure Trove a genomic treasure that's
so important that we Preserve especially
in the Northwest here um we go into the
Old grth Forest and this is a place that
is very spiritually important to me I've
had many many exper experiences and I
was involved in cutting the old go
Forest so it's karmic payback for me to
give back to the ecosystem you know and
considering that I was involved in in
its decimation so being a manly man I am
very focused on decomposition so when I
see these logs and these trees laying
down in the ecosystem I like to watch
them over over the years and a log like
this will totally decompose in about 10
years it'll just be dff in the soil well
one of the most primary medicinal
mushrooms in the world is a woodland
mushroom called turkey tail tr's versol
Coral's versol is the old name retired
you know decades ago but this is the
most well studied medal mus in the world
um we applied for an NIH Grant and I was
a co-investigator co-pi is called
principal investigator help right the
Grant and NIH the national AG of Health
the United States awarded us $2.2
million for rest cancer clinical study
um so turkey tail was really indicated
in Asia as being very very helpful for
the immune system so we applied for this
grant we got the money everyone are very
excited they go Paul you're the my
callers where do we get our mushrooms
they go oh please get them from us
mushrooms hyper accumulate toxins the
mushrooms from China are notoriously you
know toxic with all sorts of pollutants
and heavy metals and pesticides I said
the chain of custody is really
critically important if you're going to
reproduce these experiments they said
well you can't be a principal
investigator and supplier so choose one
so I became a supplier we were put into
a jury of five other suppliers
thankfully we're chosen to be number one
as a soul Source supplier on the first
clinical study uh breast cancer clinical
study using medical Western the United
States so we fast forward and the
results of the study show statistically
significant highly significant increase
in CDA cytotoxic te- cells one of your
Frontline defenses and natural killer
cells um on a dose dependent basis so
prior pre radiation you your native
killer self Community is relatively
stable and high post radiation it
declines most of you know that your
immune system is impaired by radiation
therapy and two weeks later on a dose
dependent basis the immune system is
enhanced depending on how much of the
turkey tail melum now we've compared
fruit bodies and mycelium the melum is
far more active than the fruit bodies um
and so we're real excited about this it
was published um it got a lot of other
oncologists I work with a lot of
oncologists and medical researchers uh
on this and then um you know the breast
cancer clinical study was progressing
and then we had an internal tragedy uh
in our family and I think it's just best
for this short little Ted Med video to
address this
issue another mushroom empowers the
immune system and this is turkey tail
this hit home to me very personally in
June of
2009 when my 84 year-old mother called
me up and said Paul I have something
very serious to talk to you about but
you're always so busy it's a terrible
thing to hear from Mom I said Mom what's
wrong and she's a very happy genuine
person she goes I'm worried and my
mother's deeply religious has not seen a
doctor since
1968 she said my right breast is five
times the size of my left I have six
swollen lymph blands the size of walnuts
and her voice started shaking and I'm
not ashamed to admit that I started
crying why didn't you tell me sooner we
spent a large part of June at the
Swedish Breast Cancer Clinic in Seattle
the oncologist examined her and upon the
second examination she had a 5.5 CM
diameter tumor it metastasized it went
to her sternum I went to her liver she
had stage four breast cancer the doctor
gave her Less Than 3 months to live and
stated it was the second worst case of
breast cancer she is seen as a doctor in
20 years in practice we had to circle
family meing many of you gone through
this my mom announced that she bought a
pine casket the cheapest one that she
could find because she was going to
heaven but then the doctor said you know
you're too old to have radiation therapy
you can't have your breast removed but
there's an interesting study on turkey
tail mushrooms at B Medical School you
might want to try taking those and
that's my go well my son's supplying
those so she was put on taxol and her
septon wonderful drugs and she started
taking turkey tail capsules a day 4 in
the morning and 4 in the evening and
that was in June of
2009 and today my mother has no
detectible tumors and I'd like to BR
my
[Applause]
[Music]
so here's my wonderful mother and then
when she passed the 5year disease free
survival rate which doctors don't like
to use the word cure but there's no
evidence of disease we common people
will say cure but this is the message my
mother left on my
voicemail I everything's go everything's
wonderful all the fly colors so thank
you for your prayers I love you and I'll
check in with you later byebye so my
mother now is 91 years of age she's
cancer free she's sharp as attack and
she just beat recently my two brothers
in
Scrabble CU my twin brother I said
really mom beat you in Scrabble she got
lucky you
know so then my mother was written up so
is the best case come a international
Journal they interviewed me they
interview interviewed Julie Smith her
oncologist at Swedish Breast Cancer
Clinic um and throughout these
interviews it was very interesting
because several things came up uh Julie
Smith recommended turkey tail mushrooms
in Seattle but my mother lives in win
Washington at the time and she started
her s program in Ellensburg Washington
over the mountains and she goes well she
I tell me new oncologist I'm taking
turkey tail musroom I go no please don't
the oncologist had an invent of caution
that they not experienced Julie Smith
oncologist Swedish Breast Cancer cancer
was up the learning curve the other
doctors will say no stop taking
everything so upon interviewing Julie
Smith and my mother we believe this was
a life and death decision that she did
not tell her oncologist that she was
telling taking turkey tail mushrooms she
Ed intercepted program 50 women did 48
women have died in that program after 5
years my mother and one other lady are
the only two known survivals survivors
this led in also then to a subsequent
study that found that psk is and turkey
tail mushrooms and that the turkey tail
mushroom constituents at help her septin
work better so it's a great example of
of conventional therapy uh working with
natural medicine in order to potentiate
a a a good recovery recovery now this is
something I really want folks to focus
on this is an extraction chart basically
using different solvents you're going to
see this three times so the the hot
water is a great is a polar solvent it
pulls out proteins glyc proteins
saccharides but most of you know that
lipids you know are not soluble and oils
are not soluble in water and so they use
the least water loving uh non-polar
solids hexane P ether Etc and so when
you do hot water extraction you
partition away all these other compounds
some of them come through but the
majority of them are left behind because
they're not water soluble well I
involved in these group of Physicians
you know who literature driven and so am
I but I said I can't figure out what psk
is it's a molecular complex but there's
no molecular signature you know what's
the hlc that we can use for psk there
well there is none and so I hammered
these medical researchers and finally
kind of I think I got through the noise
and I was extraordinarily happy with
this recent article that came out by
some of the co-authors in the west
cancer political study and they found
that that psk and they Val not a pure
compound as a molecular complex of great
uncertainty but when they use lipases
that dissolve the lipids away from the
giant scaffolding of the beta glucan
complex it denatured the immune benefit
of psk by
83% so it turns out the beta glucans
they're wonderful they're this huge
moleular complex tons of literature but
until this time no one had used this
these enzymes that would take away the
lipids and this this huge black complex
is a you know big glucans are going to
have a million in terms of a million dot
in terms of its molecular weight but a
giant scaffolding embedded into which
are all these other active constituents
so this showed that if you didn't have
the lipids in the beta glucans then you
lost immune benefit well then we go
forward and um there's an extraordinary
uh uh uh double blind conceivable
control uh uh study here that show that
tury tail enhances the microbiome
helping Lac of basilis and bacterium
beneficial bacteria in the GI TR tract
suppressing inflammatory stus Custer and
oconus um and it modifies the vle
microbiota well then the mushrooms then
I realize oh my gosh just like in the
ecosystem of the environment they they
set the stage of the beneficial bacteria
can to help their their members and
their ecosystem well these fungi as you
consume them internally also affect the
bacterial Flora in your gut and to your
benefit this is why when I meet people
who say I can't stomach mushrooms
they're actually giving you a very
important scientific observation their
microbiome is mismatched to the
mushrooms and so this is why I think
some people can't tolerate digestive
mushrooms have incompatibility and the
in the bacterial microf in their gut
versus the mushroom
species so the species that I mentioned
before a gacon f Thompson fishys is the
longest living Mushroom in the world and
I received a National Geographic award
um for uh in for my work in U in
studying the old growth forest and they
wanted to do a story on me so they sent
a photojournalist from New York and
before he came out says Paul we want to
do a search for the Aaron it's perfectly
from that Gio you know the go course but
we don't want you to take us to a place
you already know an aaran exists we want
to have that Eureka experience of
Discovery and says now How likely would
would you find can we find it I totally
lied you know it's so rare find this
mushroom this one out of 100 trips in
the Old Forest My Dear Professor Dr
Michael bu 45 years hunting the Old
Forest found this first garon last year
and he goes into the old course all the
time he finally found one that's how
rare it is so I said oh 50/50 with my
answerers for the
phal I didn't want National Geographic
to cancel the story on me you know so
but I had good reason about 10 of my
friends with high power binoculars we we
rented a motor sailor here of Cortez
with a zodiac and the idea is we go up
the Inland passage of desolation sound
lots of Old Forest and we look for snags
and often times they look like a giant
beehive and often the bald eagles are on
these snags gacon grows in the same tree
so you know we have 10 people with high
power binoculars and we're going up
desolation sound and there's a tree SN
nothing there there's a tree nothing
there there's a tree nothing there you
do that for 3 hours 4 hours you got
retina burn right and it's like they put
a journalist talking upside like and you
promis me like no I said 50/50 is like
fishing be patient you're from New York
you
know so so the photo turn so our Skipper
said you know listen it's lunchtime we
were out for hours let's go over to a
first people site and the first people
site is is not really clear what the
pictographs mean I've met a number of
First Peoples and we did wage white
people did wage biot terrorism against
indigenous people you know purposely or
or by accident but nevertheless
tuberculosis flu viruses and pox viruses
and my friend guja is the president of
the height of people he said you know
Paul you think that us Indians know
everything about ethnobot ethnology well
we knew a lot more before we had these
pandemics but when you have six
pandemics come within within 60 years
wiping out 75 to 95% of the indigenous
people it's a oral tradition we get
disconnected from our ancestral
knowledge so any we motor over there and
this is a great place at a 30 foot
overhand
and we both over there have lunch and
we're going over there and then one of
my teammates goes there's one found one
could not believe it it was right out
our first people's uh site and this
one's especially unusual because it was
scrolling underneath another Branch it
fell it Teeter tottered and then the
myum regrew from the mushroom back into
the branch and connected with the myum
in the tree and then it grew two legs
you know extraordinarily uh interesting
well when you look at the origination
myth women or the height of people this
is an arite plate from Charles edans
Shaw in 1894 this speaks to the
origination of of women the height of
and there's Raven pading on a canoe in
the sea of Eternity and Raven seeks help
from the bear the killer whale the bald
eagle none of the other animals you know
in the ecosystem can help Raven steer
her canoe to find her Galia except for
fungus man and this creature here and
then and it turns out that grave Gard
Ians that the that were carved from
aacon were placed on the first people's
Shaman's Graves to help the protect them
to go into the Afterlife so they were
the Chicago Field Museum and they were
repatriated thankfully back third First
Peoples and they analyzed these they
were not made of wood they were made of
a gan they were carved now as it turns
out there's two potential candidates for
the Orman that helped Raven there's a
gacan there's also the artist conon and
the artist conon may have been this
fungus also not a gon even though we
know the gra Guardians were carved of a
gan and the reason arst may have been
the one is that you can draw a map you
can actually draw on this thing so from
a practical point of view if you want to
show someone help it up the fiords and
the channels and pass the islands you
could actually draw on this wood conon a
map so kind of makes sense also but so
we're there at the site and there is a
fungus man like pictograph with salmon
eggs and this is Dr Scott franbow he's
the director of the tulous research
institute he was very interested in
ethnology I wrote an article in a gon he
saw it he contacted me say I'm funded by
The Gates Foundation we're very
concerned about xdr TV multi resistance
strange tuberculosis and he said I'd
like to you know go with you Paul on the
for so we invited him and he went with
us to the site and so we take these
tubes here we just need a small piece of
tissue okay so I worked with Scott FR B
and the UIC to bosis research division
for five years we did
solvent extractions we use the most
polar water the least least polar and
this is called bioga fractionation so
you ref fractionate a natural substance
and you go down a decision tree polar
nonpolar you test those post fractions
that increased activity was found in one
fraction against tuberculosis and less
than the other well of course there
would be so you follow the path that has
the most activity and you keep on
fractionating fractionating
fractionating each fraction takes weeks
months it's a very laborious prod
process this is how the pharmaceutical
industry discovers active constituents
new drugs uh from from from nature so
after 5 years lo and behold Scott and
our team we discovered two chlorinated
cumin of aaran Highly active against
tuberculosis wow I said okay I mean we
we actually found active new drugs that
resident in this in this mushroom that
were celebrated by the Greeks the
celebrated by Haida and First Coast
peoples um so that was that was really
exciting okay we'll go back now five to
the time we were there and we were there
and and we're exploring there for
several hours and I'm such an idiot and
I'm there and I I see this rock wow I
see this rock and W that rock that's
interesting kind of kind of looks like a
g yeah there's a rock there's a gon
there's a
rock so How likely is it we find a gon I
don't know one in 100 How likely is it
we find pictographs are really
reminiscent fungus man helping hide
Raven to see eternity I I don't know one
one in 10,000 one one in 100,000 How
likely is it we find out a rock that
looks really suspiciously like it's been
carved in the shape of gon I don't know
maybe maybe one in a million How likely
is it we find it on my
birthday and this is when the
photojournalist start shaking your
nervous and going does this happen to
Paul
often and my friends looked at him dead
pan and said
yes this I think speaks to a higher
truth and the core of my belief if you
walk with faith in nature with respect
of indigenous peoples respect of your
ancestors and the obligations of your
descendants can you walk with
truthfulness not motivated by money but
inspired by science and Discovery and
sharing that I believe nature will
reward you and that's really what I
believe
in
thank you and so Aaron is really hard to
find but we have now 70 Springs of aaran
by far the largest library of aaran in
the world sometimes we have to go up
trees a 700 year old tree on qu Island
and this is what the gon the branch is
hard as a rock so it doesn't Rock the
branch that supports it and so this
one's about 70 years of age and then it
goes through a metamorphosis and I
brought both of these specimens here and
it goes to the white form the ghost form
as it's known and so this mushroom
changes into this white form as it lays
in the Old Forest subjected to rain so
we um this is dead and this is alive so
we dat our cultures from this now we
thought that was the biggest one in in
the world but until we saw this one and
this is from Northern California a t
typical Nor Cal kind of guy and this
one's about 20 lb it's over 100 years of
age so this was the forest was going to
be burned going to be cut down and
slashed and burned and so the people
called us up saying hey it's going to be
log go for it dude you know but please
send us a specimen send us a giant chunk
so we got this one in the culture the
forest was cut down and burned so we
saved this phenotype we saved this
strain of a gacon uh and we have it in
culture today so we typically go on the
old forest with the GPS we take a
stainless steel tube we leave the Aaron
we only need that amount of tissue we
get it in the culture and then we grow
them and we compare strains these
strains are different strains this is a
ridge of incompatibility if they're the
same strain they grow together
seamlessly and so this a way of our
testing different phenotypes in the same
Forest to see how many different
varieties we have well I've been
fascinated you know with the my
antimicrobal properties of mushrooms and
then I published an article in
herbalgram in June of 2001 and
summarized in one page all the
information in scientific literature on
the antiviral compounds and properties
for mushrooms now it's a whopping one
page long but less than one page with
two big photographs and so I found about
six or seven references that's all there
was in scientific literature so that was
in June of 2001 I published this made
the cover of herbal gram and then 911
occurs several months later 3 months
later so 911 occurs and then you know
the biggest concern very quickly became
weaponized viruses in particular
smallpox so a physician with the
Department of Defense US bios Shield
biod defense program got a hold of me I
said Paul I saw this article you were
very concerned about biot terrorism we
we know you have a large library of old
gr fungi uh will you submit some of your
samples uh for the BIOS Shield biod
defense program which was organized by
ni niad and US AMD US Army Research
Institute infe diseases so it was a huge
honor they got of me so we started
sending in mushrooms we sent in hot
water extracts of RA and Artis con and
aaran and then we did go out the melum
we said water extracts of that and then
we did ethanol extracts of melum so this
this went on WE s our first 80 samples
out and I waited a few months um and
then um then uh I was up in Canada one
of my managers called me up say Paul
there's a helicopter over the laboratory
I know no big deal helicopter laboratory
and he goes well I goes no Paul it's
really close I go how close he goes
Listen whoa I go what's the the numbers
on the tail of the helicopter he goes
there are no numbers there a Blackhawk
helicopter going on no so so now that
same week what happened is that Federal
Express delivered us all these research
results from the BIOS Shield program and
I'm flipping through them no activity no
activity I get the sample 78 highly
active against box viruses then I got
another sample highly active against box
viruses another one so I had three hits
against box viruses I didn't tell the
government what they were I had coded
them in a not quote and I looked up the
codes and they were all a gan so I got
really excited and I so called up I was
appointed a a a um a one one person in
the bio Shield program was my manager my
contact Dr Huggins he's a physician so I
called up Dr hug and said This research
results extraordinar exciting this is
great
he goes what research results I go
Federal Express just delivered me all
these research results you know testing
all of our extracts he goes you're not
supposed to get those I go no problem
I'll photocopy them and send them to you
you know it were so disorganized you
know and then then the helicopter shows
up I oh my gosh so I told my employees
okay shut down the business give three
give the employees uh copies of the
cultures that had activity against Fox
viruses don't ever tell me who has them
shut down the business right now leave
while the hill copter is over the over
the business
and so we did 11 Vehicles separated from
the facility later on I got security
clearance we choked about it I told I
told the defense department why didn't
you guys TOA together they oh my God if
you only
knew so everything was fine but they
said you know you did just the right
thing you decentralize yourself as a
Target so we advaned forward and um you
can all look this up an interview with
the BIOS Shield program the deputy
director of the FDA and myself on
National Public Radio Google stamus and
small Fox NPR and we have a Ved press
release from the US from the US
Department of Defense it says that top
10 samples of more than 200,000
specimens was over 2 million and we're
the only natural product that have high
activity against pox viruses the other
ones were Pharmaceuticals so okay now we
go forward and we do biotic
fractionation again this time we do the
University of Mississippi School of
Pharmacy same things as before you know
polar solvant you know water non-polar
you know
um and we fractionate it out and after
about 7 years lo and behold we find two
active molecules highly active against
Fox viruses more put sopir the
preeminent positive anti-drug control
with less side effects and so sulur EIC
acid turns out to be highly active
against pox viruses well most you know
pox small pox you know cow poox is out
there camel pox Etc um but uh small pox
supposedly doesn't have any natural
reserves uh we know in Russia and the
United States and um two or three other
countries they do have small foxing
culture um but those of you who are not
immunized so I think it's about 1968
they stopped immunizing those of us uh
you know who were in school at the time
have smallpox vaccination scar on our
arms typically but otherwise you're rest
of you're immunologically naive which
means you're highly susceptible to small
pox and the first people in particular
were super sensitive and 90% of the
those First Nation people infected died
us a European and African background 30%
will die 30% will become blind 30% were
highly scarred and recover and 10% would
be immune so anyhow so we were great
with nonactive molecules but then very
quickly the virus of concern began flu
viruses now there's been several uh
pandemics you all know about Spanish Flu
in
1918 um and then different V flu
pandemics in h5n1 because a very big
virus of concern and then a poultry
virus this P two years ago 87 and9 hit
Minnesota and Iowa Mill millions and
millions of birds were then euthanized
um and um we an organic chicken owner
who I helped their family out with a
medical crisis um contacted me said Paul
we're killing all these chickens and can
you help you know we know about your
research you know um can you help these
chickens so um we sent back 50 kilos of
a gon melum grown on Rice they fed it to
20,000 chickens and those chickens
became an O Asis of immunity they did
not get the the the bird flu and so they
did not to euthanized all the other u
uhtry in the surrounding counties were
euthanized and this was a stark stark
contrast well the reason being is that
this is a a from the BIOS Shield by
defense program
prologist it's called the C activity
index anything as two is active anything
as 10 is highly active well this is a
summary of our antiflu research results
with the BIOS Shield B defense program
and ribavirin is the preeminent of drug
control anti control so you can see
anything over 10 is active prob well
this is you know 32 17 45 so here is our
agaron melium our RI melium our cha
melium then did a blend so but we gave
the then we knew that the ethanol
extracts of mycelium grown on Rice by
the way uh were highly active against
pox viruses so we sent those extracts in
now the extracts are in 35% ethanol it's
the very basically s to the extract you
have that you received on your seats so
we these are inv vitro human cell assays
you can't put 35% EOL extract in a on a
human cell it kill it so they deluded it
10 to1 to 3.5 10 one again to35 so 100
to1 delution of our extracts and this is
the results phenominally more potent as
a natural extract diluted 100 to1
compared to a pure antiviral molecule we
beat the pants of a riron and then a
combination of all three of these end up
having extraordinar high activity
against H5 And1 so of course I got very
excited about this this is back in 200
five and I filed a patent and I you know
I My Discovery and spent all this money
so I found a patent and then the patent
disappears off the U the patent never
gets published the applications are
published within a year or two and the
US pto. homepage uh US patent and
trademark office homepage the patent
didn't get published so I get all my
patent turn going where's my fraking
patent and so he contacted the patent
office and the Department of Defense
took the patent out of the patent office
the because of national security for the
same reason you can't write a patent
about making a nuclear weapon you give a
terrorist a blueprint for making a
nuclear bomb so we had to do
intergovernmental agency Trace after
four or five years we pull the patent
back from the US defense department it
goes into the patent office and then we
got the strangest rejection of all time
it's like somebody talking to the patent
examiner the patent rejection no sense
at all we went to the board of appeals
unanimity of opinion 10 examiners then
approved the patent it was then
published in
2014 um a gan active against flu viruses
and act against STA and eoli as well as
herpes and pox viruses now I have a
medicinal mushroom that's active against
viruses the bacteria is really
significant the more the most people who
die from um U flu viruses die from
bacterial pneumonia their immune system
is challenged by the flu virus and then
they have their immune system depressed
and and the bacteria start going their
lungs they die from respiratory
bacterial pneumonia so to have something
that's dually active as medically
significant well so we did this and then
the vector Institute in Russia they came
out with an article you know in 2012 I
discovered this in 2015 but it's very
nice because the vector in like for dri
is the top secret you know biot
terrorism and and they have small pox
there they also found that L beh to gon
it's AC active against pox viruses so
that was kind of good because they
validated what I discovered I have a a
talk in Washington DC and a whole bunch
of people from Port Detroit they knew my
research and the BIOS Shield program so
I invited him to my talk I showed him
this I said we beat the Russians by
seven years and a small cheer went up in
the
audience and then another group of
scientists then also found the same
thing so was good we had multiple
validation okay so the story now starts
to take some strange twists and turns
this article just came out recently it
turns out that tlu is dependent upon the
supply chain of the star Anis star Anis
produces shmic acid shikimic acid you
know tlu is antiviral against Blue
viruses it turns out that blue light
stimulates the melium of oyster
mushrooms to produce shmic acid
247 so imagine Supply chains of of star
anas coming from Afghanistan are rather
strange in so with the T flu shortage
because they couldn't get up star anos
to make ham flu now we know that oyster
mushroom melium under blue light
stimulation produc the antiviral
precursors that that so that okay that's
interesting so we go forward and this is
we go lots of RA we go fruit bodies we
go melum um we have very large
Laboratories is a beautiful amp form and
so I've been espousing because I'm a I'm
a myologist with a strong emphasis on
ecosystems and understanding I've been
saying for a long time the mushrooms are
the end of the life cycle you know the
challenges of the melium are much
greater than that of the mushroom fruit
body they have to navigate through a
microbial and hostile environment one
cell all thick lots of microbes in their
as side and so sure enough complete
genome sequencing of RI mushroom shows
that the melium codes for many more
compounds than the mushrooms still uh
and so because they coding these more
compounds there extracellular
metabolites that we have been focusing
on so uh we then were able you know we'
kind of been ahead of a curve here and
then science then validates a lot of our
premises so this is
cha cha was on Birch trees and beach
trees sometimes on
chestnuts um but unfortunately chaga is
being cut off you know by the thousands
and a wild west harvesting of chaga and
scaring the trees and I'm nice to us a
group of physicians in the United
Kingdom got some of our choga extract
with IBD patients and found that the
melum grown on Rice uh protected DNA
damage more than 55% highly significant
against D DNA oxidative stress damage uh
using the cha extract which I think is a
very good argument that we should grow
the melium in the laboratory is
sustainable this is not sustainable now
for your family and your friends I don't
have an issue with this but when people
go out collecting hundreds of pounds of
chaga which was widely available a few
years ago now you can barely get 10
kilos if you you're lucky because the
cha the cha nearest the roads and trails
have been chopped off and it takes a
long time okay all of this now has been
a story line that comes up to an
equation that's going to lead to a
paradigm shifting solution so I call
this microf Factor number one F of a
okay so antivirals and antioxidants from
polyer mushrooms so I'm going to create
a Mico factorial equation that's going
to lead to a paradigm solution that is
going to hopefully save hundreds of
millions of lives in biodiversity of
this planet so these are I didn't know
what to call them they're experiences
they're
factors so I swung these together okay
so that's micro Factor one we'll call it
a okay f f of a for you math people out
there okay so the next experience I'm
growing the garden giant mushroom in my
garden and this is
1984 and I go out to my garden
and there's my garden giant mushroom and
I look really closely and I go this is
so bizarre there's all these bees on my
wood chips they move the wind chips outs
side I looked at them very carefully and
they're sipping on the melium there
little droplets they uncover the
mycelium that's hidden by the wood chips
and it's like you know it's a huge
amount of weight there and for 40 days
from dawn to dusk there's a continuous
Convoy a bees from my beehives that
going to my garden giant patch my patch
was about 8 10 in thick and it shrunk to
about 2 in and strangely the garden
giant mushrooms called the burgundy
mushroom they're burgundy red like
Burgundy wine and these mushrooms are
all white so like this is so strange so
I published this I mentioned it and
herris Smith magazine 1988 was published
I put it in one of my books growing gmet
medical mushrooms in 1994 everybody
basically ignored me um and I called
this Michael Factor number two okay F of
B okay this don't make sense to you in a
while these are this series of strange
experiences in my life ever since I was
a child you know to the present day so
I'm hiking in the oldw forest it's what
I like love to do bear Scrat
trees and the forest service L Timber
industry put a bonty on Bears to kill
them I live in Skookum Inlet there's
massive Salon runs coming right in front
of my place and there's no bears at all
because the hunters killed the Bears on
on a bounty because bears are scratching
the trees and when they scratch the
trees they introduce fungus the polypore
mushroom in particular the red belted
polypore that I held up at the beginning
so when the beer crat trees then resins
ooze out and uh and bees use the resins
to make propolis to seal the cracks in
their hives and for anti microbial
protection so I'm hiking the South Fork
of the h River in the Olympic mountains
I like the orienteer I go off trail and
I see this bear strike this is the best
bear strike scratch photograph I've ever
seen and I take this Photograph and you
know bear went up this tree went bam you
know and I'm wow I'm there with my wife
dy I said you know the the forest and
Timber industry killed the Bears because
of these bear scratches they said the
red belted poly pork you know is a
parasitic fungus because of the scratch
and it hurts their bottom line so let's
kill all the Bears humans are so good at
choosing opposite of their best interest
so it turns out that work here in
British Columbia found that bears bring
salmon carcasses up on out of the stream
the be the the salmon are bringing sea
phosphorus and other minerals and by
Scavenging animals of of wolves coyotes
bald eagles Etc Ravens that they spread
the phosphorus through the forest it
helps the forest grow um so um but so we
go back two years later took a long time
to find this hours and hours hours and
pouring rain and we find the exact tree
two years later and lo behold my God the
the red Delta polyp when is growing
there a different tree but there's a
scar also but this is what red belt PO
for looks like it was growing out of the
tree well the red Bel of Po also creates
the pesticides this is very active in
micro remediation breaking down toxins
uh so I found that to be really
interesting because I was working with
it already and I connected the dots H
interesting be scat trees the red four
comes out of its tree scratches that is
Michael Factor number three F of C okay
so my friend Lou schwarzberg who's a
National Geographic and Walt Disney
slowmo fast Mo photographer he knew my
work with enop pathogenic fungi I have
seven patents now on using fungi to
control termites you know mosquitoes
carpenter ants Etc he said Paul do you
know about colony collapse with bees is
horrible and a ver of Might I've been
interviewing these beekeepers and
they're under assault by this might and
I went wow I have I know how to use
these Spong to control insects and
arthropod so maybe I can do something
well so I started researching about bees
and then President Obama came out with
this memorandum and bees are on multiple
stressors it's a Confluence it's a
perfect storm all these stressors are
coefficients in a in a in a formula the
end of which is causing the bees to die
well there there be nutrition last lack
of foraging lands there's parasites the
mites in particular the vector viruses
and the uh cooccurrence of pesticide
exposure and insecticides Etc so um and
the use of now neonicotinoids neon as
they're known um and it's harming the
Drone sperm vitality and limiting their
lifespan so again it's a perfect storm
so I this sort of started coming at me
and um then and whole foods thank you
Whole Foods for this Photograph but
here's your Dairy selection with bees
and if we had no Bees this is what your
Dairy selection would look like so 70%
of your food is
indirectly uh indirectly dependent upon
bollin
pollination so um then the New York
Times came out with an article and this
has been all over the news for the past
several years that the line of
pollination Services by bees and bats
and other uh and other insects is a
threat to Global Food uh
biocurity so I'm laying in bed and I
love the space The Ether space between
sleeping and dreaming and wakefulness
and I find that to be a really creative
M to engage now and spend some extra
time I'm writing this book on medicinal
mushrooms and work with a bios Shield
biod defense program you know I have all
these patents on on working with you
know controlling insects and it's not
true it's all over the it's gotten
viable about 10 times many of you seen
it Paul stus can take down Monsanto you
know not quite true you know um um but I
do have a very destructive technology
that we're launching in January that
will be a big threat to Monsanto um but
so I I have this Epiphany um and I went
oh my God I think I know to help the
bees I may be able to save the bees so I
is Epiphany and I put these spots
together I'm at ched I called the
University of California Davis and tried
to explain what doing the people got
blurried eyed or ear I don't know what
you're talking about I called Steve
Shepard I said Steve just give me a few
minutes to explain this and after
explaining for a few minutes Steve said
stop don't go anywhere else Washington
State University I'm the chair of
enology we're interested in doing this
so I'm going to show you 5 minute movie
that's aired on hundreds of PBS stations
that kind of summarizes the initial
research that Steve and I were doing uh
with his with our
[Music]
teammates wow very nice these girls are
fantastic I LIF that lid up and those
girls are slid across there and they're
making honey and they're making babies
ericon owns more colonies than any
beekeeper in Washington state h no
there's nothing greater than to open a
beehive and see them doing well they're
doing well today look at that tickled
but just months ago he opened his hives
and discovered nearly half his bees were
dead I spent 20 years as a pilot in the
Air Force and my share of combat
situations and I never was as low as I
was when all those bees were dead that's
the lowest time of my life it turns out
this maybe The New Normal the US
Department of Agriculture says that
nearly half of colonies across the
country died in the 2014
season big losses have been happening
for years and scientists haven't
pinpointed what's causing them they say
more than 60 factors may play a role in
collapsing colonies factors like
pesticides malnutrition and loss of
habitat if we don't find some answer I
am really concerned about whether these
little girls will survive but one
unlikely solution may be growing close
by in the forest of Western
Washington
another enter Paul stamis he's a Pioneer
in the study of
mushrooms this a beautiful specimen the
white margin here means is growing
brilant well that's what I call Happy
mushrooms makes me a happy person
too I'm involved in the study of fi ever
since a very young age
my initial interest was magic mushrooms
and then I got into edible mushrooms and
medicinal mushrooms and my mother was
much
happier scoured the forest for rare
types of fungi I use mology the use of
fungi to help clean up the
environment improve the immune system of
animals and I began to think we've gone
to the Moon we Bond the Mars and we
don't know the way of the
be
all right bet I can do something to help
the
be stam's recently discovered a mushroom
that might be able to take on one of the
honeybee's worst enemies and that's
called the verite with the the name
veroa Destructor verites began wreaking
havoc on USB hives in 1996 we lost about
half the colonies east of the
Mississippi over that winter Steve
Shepard is an entomologist at Washington
State University he spent decades trying
to understand how verites
honeybees he says they invade hives and
attach themselves to infant bees I
always think of it as having something
about the size of a pancake feeding on
you they live off Be Blood and transmit
a slew of viruses to their
host some sickly bees lose the ability
to fly and gather food for the hive many
end up dying prematurely they'll Kill
The Colony within a couple of years
unless in Keepers
[Music]
intervene that's why Shephard decided to
try a new approach something doesn't
look quite right with that
yes he teamed up with Paul stamus stamus
told him about a type of fungus that's
highly attractive and highly lethal to
termites Shephard wondered what this
termite killing mushroom extract would
do to the viral kn so we should U do
something he recently started testing
the product on bees in his
lap so we take bees from colies with
high might levels we set up numerous
cages some with fungus they're finding
that the product is killing mites
without harming bees it's certainly uh
encouraging so
far and that's not all that mushrooms
can do for bees bees have immune systems
just like we do and these mushrooms
they're like miniature pharmaceutical
factories their initial results show
that certain forest mushrooms can reduce
viruses in bees and help them live
longer I think I've discovered now that
the fungi that ring the logs are
absolutely critical for the
immunological health of the bees this is
a really interesting potential
breakthrough and understanding how
nature works and how we coevolve with
funi Shephard and stamitz plan to expand
both experiments by partnering with
commercial beekeepers Eric Olson was the
first to sign up I don't have too much
hair left I have pulled my hair out we
just can't seem to get a control on the
paroa m
we've got our fingers crossed the future
of Western honeybee colonies and the
billions of dollars of crops they
pollinate may depend on
it so most beekeepers will tell you that
the ver verite Vera Destructor is really
the the biggest issue with u with bee
colonies and Steve Shephard me told me
that once there's 7% uh of the bees have
barites the colonies are doomed
so 7% of the population are infected The
Rite that spells the death of the colony
so this is metum anle it's an enop
pathogenic fungus it's a mold sometimes
it can produce a Corps mushroom and so
this is the area this is the what I
presented today at the B conference
because this is very new information um
and the next few slides come from
Wasington state uh uh University C
Shepherds team and Brandon Hopkins uh
and a new post Nick nagler uh we uh they
treated uh 10 hives uh with the metum
fungus uh and 10 hives with a control
and you know I was thinking about
delivery system and the simplest
delivery system by far was just a petri
dish and so we put a petri dish on the
top of the frames and the bees
immediately started Scavenging there's
Sugar In Here Also malt sugar AG so I'm
sure that's appetizer to them and then
in a matter of a day they actually remov
all this entire fungus and The Malt Ager
and then the pach dis is basically empty
well this are the newest research
results just came in in the past two
days um and the uh High significance on
day five and day seven where we were
able to uh eliminate a lot more Mall
normalized MF the control is uh in Gray
here the sporulating the melium is in
red um now bear in mind this fungus that
we have it was not they grow they kill
mice and also ticks and Carpenter Rants
and termites uh but there's a a species
there's a different varieties and more
that are tuned for different uh targets
insect targets so what we're doing with
WSU is uh after only 3 days some of the
mites fell uh from infection with this
fungus and now we put the mites onto a
pachra dish we grow out the mycelium as
a second as a first generation and then
we'll grow out the we do that again and
then we'll get more MFS and then we'll
then navigate to find a a new strain uh
that uses epigenesis and natural
selection to find a more virulent strain
uh of metum against mice okay so that's
myofactor number four okay F ofd metum
infect okay so I'm writing this new book
I have literally my manuscript up on the
table and then this journal comes and I
was really happy when I made the front
page of the journal and it was about
colony collapse and what these
scientists found out that the colonies
that for those of you don't understand
the colony collapse there's lots of
different factors but basically the bees
just abandoned the nest and in two days
they're gone you know thousands of bees
that were there 2 days earlier now
they're gone it's not like they're dead
all around the nest they could be some
but most of them are just gone it's like
where'd they go um and so what happens
is that the workers uh that used to
forage for the average of nine days and
now foraging for 4 days so the nurse
bees taking care of The Brood then
become worker bees to go out get more
pollen because there's not enough worker
bees coming back so their foraging range
has been limited both temporarily as
well as geographically so when they
looked at the honey and abandoned
beehives they found the honey lacked
peic acid well peic acid I know peic
acid when melium breaks down wood it
produces pic acid and so I was
astonished to learn that peic acid
controls a cyome p p450 pathway is the
detoxification pathway that all animals
use we primarily have it in our liver
many of liers detoxify uh Xeno compounds
uh and the bees only have 47 genes but
these genes are controlled by pic acid
turning on the cytic p450 pathway most
insects have 80 of these genes humans
have 60 but bees only have 47 so the
absence of pimaric acid prevents the
bees from detoxifying pesticides
insecticides all sorts of other toxins
so I went aha well the melum is
producing pic acid as it breaks down
wood so I surmise unlik gosh well the
bees want pic a they need to go to a red
LA and you take away you Forest you do
monoculture you use fungicides to kill
all the fungi in the environment you're
dismantling the pathway of
detoxification that bees need because
pic acid is no longer there what turns
out that g phosphates you know uh this
is something mon Sando doesn't want you
to know but it's very well established
that gly phosphates interfere also with
the p450 pathway even in humans so this
is not just been found that glyos Fates
are in all of our Foods
in the United States the EPA was not
testing for this until just recently
it's widespread throughout our entire
food chain now so this is also
interfering We Believe with with the
detoxification pathway now so it started
Mak making sense to me now remember my
garden giant mushrooms were supposed to
be red but they're white and then I had
this Epiphany oh my gosh see as it turns
out it stimulate mushrooms to form we
need light but but muss are most highly
uh stimulated uh and light in the blue
light in the 320 nanometer range that
stimulates the melium to produce
mushrooms now the melium is growing
don't eat the wood chips has no light
and when you the wood chips that are
taken off and myum exposed to light it
stops La cases which are breaking down
the wood but now is triggering the
mushrooms of form so why digest now
let's produce a mushroom so myum stops
lactases pic acid are stopped and then
tyrosinase is coded for that leads to a
pigment so the bees I think where and
the bees can see down to 320 ners we can
see down to about 400 nmet so we can't
see this but I think the bees are
buzzing along the habitat and they're
looking down to see if there's any blue
reflective melum and it's a whisper that
melium coming up then they can go down
there dislodge the wood chips get the PE
cheric acid that they need for
detoxification but once light hits that
melum mushroom to a form but it turns
out that it interferes with the teras
pathways that causes melanization so I
think my mushrooms were white because
the bees were interfering with proat by
exposing the wood chips prematurely to
light I don't know that's my ey
mother
so thank you very much that the first
audience has gotten this
okay this is
microfactories okay F fungal pic a acid
activates the detoxification pathway
okay so we started working and um we did
develop mro honey so this is all from
melium rown on Rice it's super sweet
it's delicious and so we started
developing micro honey uh it's great and
coffee by the way uh super delicious
we're going to eventually come out with
something like this you know for
consumers and then we start presenting
uh different forms of melium all grown
on rice to Steve shefer at WSU for
longevity stress experiments in
captivity worker bees live about 30 days
they kind of die after that period of
time so the bees are being fed extracts
and this is the
artist you know of the heida for
instance this is a 10% solution and um
the bees that are exposed and they're
drinking this sugar water now uh
beekeepers are feed their bees uh
commercial beekeepers in particular
sugar water is 50% sugar 50% water or
corn Sy uh and so we the idea is you
could put this this Michel honey or the
extracts into the sugar water and that
way the bees then can be consuming okay
so after doing this working now with
Steve Shepard and his team at WSU a
summary of the best mushrooms that
showed benefit to the bees are uniquely
associated with first trees and they are
the red Delta polycor it also goes on
bir trees birch trees chaga now remember
chaga was active against flu viruses uh
that you saw in the bio Shield program
amadu which my hat is made from remember
amadu is the first antiviral ever found
from a mushroom against the mosaic virus
came from amadu and the red RI mushroom
well here's a summary of some of the
best results that we got the longevity
effects of omdu my hat is made from this
is the number of bees that are surviving
high significant and there's nearly a
doubling of the number of bees that are
this time critical period where they're
foraging so there's many more bees out
there that are surviving compared to the
controls Steve made the statement in 39
years of experience setting bees is uh
he's unaware of any materials that can
extend with life of work be more than
this and then we go and we look at the
mushroom that bears introduced the red
belted polyur here and here's the
control and at a. 1% solution
is also nearly a doubling on the light
number of bees that are alive during
these later stages of their life now
this is at .1% that's one drop per
thousand drops one milliliter per liter
a very small amount of this extract from
the red Delta polypore and then looking
at the viruses and from cha the control
viruses go up one week to the next week
and looking at the as we increase the
concent ation then the viruses and
plumet and then looking at the uh the
effect of viruses by the red R she on
the B viruses they go up with the
controls blue to blue and then on a step
as we increase the concentration of the
viruses
PL so the summary from these initial
results so with the rice control the V
viruses go up with these extracts
remember this one is the BIOS Shield
program active against Blue viruses this
was active against Blue viruses the red
Bel for is a sister species is called
PSIs picula a gacon is called kopsis
fical that's interesting so we found a
cluster of four polypour mushrooms
rotting wood that's highly uh
significant and extending the lifespan
of bees and also reducing their viruses
then now I got really fascinated with
this I started became a literature Hound
uh looking at B viruses and the in the
past 80 years from Asian BS the deformed
Wing virus has spread all over the the
world originally from Asia and now it it
is thought that all bees in the world
have the deformed wi virus it is spread
this is just this is four articles in
2016 where the deform wind virus is
described as a primary one article the
primary cause of colony collapse being
vectored by the mites the mites are like
dirty syringes they're shooting a slew
of viruses not only the form wi virus
but other ones as well and then uh TL
came out Andre TL came with this article
saying the deform wind virus is a
leading Contender as a cause agent of
colony uh Coline uh the Klein and
another article here in 2016 by m MC MCM
as say that there's a global pandemic of
DMV is spreading throughout the world so
the latest research results so that was
very encouraging and I really just
wanted just profusely thank the
Washington State University and Dr Steve
Shepard for having faith and carrying
this Mission forward because our latest
results hold on to your hat this the
latest results with the aladu mushroom
the mushroom that my hat is made them
and the red RI that reducing Amad
reduces the deform Wing virus a th000 to
one in the matter of about two weeks two
to three weeks the uh the red R sheet
decreases the lake Sinai virus 500
to one well we have species specificity
here folks we have different poly
mushrooms more active against uniquely
different species of viruses so and then
the Jay Evans a renowned biologist with
the USDA uh sent this statement recently
I've never seen such strong antii B
viruses I've seen with st's extracts
this is huge and then for the queen
breeders out there uh they have viruses
and it turns out that cha reduces the
the black queen cell virus by more than
100 to1 as does the red ra well this is
huge so I got really excited I spent all
this money on this and so I did file uh
US Patent I filed international patents
they did massive searches through every
language you know English German Chinese
Japanese there was no prior art no one
had ever made mention of this in
anywhere in scientific or popular
literature I apparently the first one
the patent has now been approved is
publishing October 25th the
international patents will soon follow
and this is the most important
communication that I can give you as all
hands on De we are facing 6X is a direct
threat to food
biocurity now in order to be charitable
you have to be profitable to be
sustainable with that condition I am
announcing that I am going to open
source for the comp all these be
[Applause]
pounds but we have to be profitable
enough to be able to to show people this
delivery system have to do it we make
thousands and thousands of gallons of
these extracts uh this is totally
deliverable
Deployable um you know one of these
barrels can probably treat you know
10,000 20,000 hives uh it's a tremendous
uh uh uh it's it's it's so ecologically
rational it's so partible it's so
deliverable uh it benefits from
biodiversity of the forest ecosystem
we're intimately tied and the irony of
this is that um we all grew up with
Winnie the
Pooh we all knew that bears when the
wild logs because honey honey would be
there for the beehives so I propose to
you the stesan mushroom be
hypothesis B scratches introduce
mushroom molum of course woodpeckers do
and you humans do be attct the rot LS
Hab for immunological benefit the myum
reduces viruses provides peic acid
reduces Xeno xenobiotic toxin exposure
the mum breaks down toxins bolsters the
general immunity of these and I think
they strengthens the wingspan because
the deformed Wing virus and you saw that
very terrible bee didn't have very good
wings that would be kicked out of the
hive it would die but what about the
bees whose tensal strength has been
diminished by low titer low infection
population rates of the deform wind
virus and so that may be why the bees
cannot forage as far their wings
basically are not strong because they're
infused by the virus and it increases
longevity now we don't know if this is
true so this is a great project for a
graduate student so folks
micro Factor number
six okay now this story starts to get
really really really
strange okay I'm there you know I'm such
an idiot my new book you know and this
communication uh you know about pic acid
I get really interested uh in being able
to help the bees but I'm thinking to
myself I got 70 strains of aaran I sent
into the BIOS Shield program seven three
of them were active against flu and pox
viruses the other four were not this is
probably why the pharmaceutical industry
missed this what if I70 I'll get a super
hit Superstar there got to be one that's
going to be really potent compared to
the others so I get a NIH barology the
BIOS Shield program had been shut down
you know several years ago so I write
NIH
orology and uh and and 17 minutes later
the director of orology NIH Chris sang
tsg just retired he basically said hi
Paul we love working with you was great
work with you you had such a high hit
rate there a percentage of the bio
Shield program you had 30% hit rate
where they dropped you so we had a
really high percentage of success and he
said but you know we won't bio Prospect
for you we won't do biotic fractionation
you have to S us in a pure structure a
pure molecule I'm not a
chemist I'm like good news bad news NIH
would love to work with this but with a
pure molecule and before they'll accept
it they have to have virologist look at
it and number one has anyone ever tested
this before they don't want to repeat
somebody else's test they want a new
molecule a new activity and secondly
secondly the psychologically doesn't
make sense so I'm going you know I have
this great opportunity NIH will give me
they give me literally millions of
dollars worth of research and now this
wonderful opportunity doing research but
they want me to send a pure molecule
there's more than 200,000 molecules uh
being by the melium and in these
mushrooms which molecule will I send
them why not why don't I send them peic
acid so I went into the literature I
looked at the delignification pathways
found two excellent articles that show
that pic acid as it breaks down the
melum breaks down wood pic acid produces
vanilla acid that's why wood smells like
really wonderful rotted wood has that
vanilla likee smell the vanilla AC acid
is related to americ this being produced
so I chose 20 molecules that's all there
was and so I ordered the molecules from
Sigma chemical and then I so I sent in
10 molecules to NIH biology and they got
all got accepted they said yep no one's
ever looked at these this makes sense
we'll test these and I said another
second second set of 10 molecules so I I
I will show you some of this results so
this is extraordinary now this is again
HP the human papala virus for which
there is no good antiviral remember the
SE activity index number anything over
10 is is highly active well this is
really lowly highly active it's only at
12 um so it's it's there's some
antiviral activity but there's no
antiviral drug that is on the market
today that can control HPV and these are
they W sheet from NIH phology this is
their red lettering this sample this
sample this sample this sample this
sample I hit home run here folks five of
these molecules turn out to be highly
active against HPV and the SI numbers
are just fantastic they 125
1253 and then the strange and then
tested against these viruses verol
zoster causes shingles Epstein bar anco
virus causes cancer uh human papala
virus causes cervical cancer neuro virus
that many of you know about the ships
and polio turns out of the 20 molecules
that I sent eight of them them highly
active and better than the positive
anti-drug controls and the National
Institute of
healthology used as a standard control
the strangest one of all is vanilla
vanilla acid vanilla is more potent than
a cycler against the shingles virus
you've all seen the TV commercials are
everywhere now about people getting
rashes and how harmful chiggles is
they're pushing a cycl it's a 10 billion
now off patent drug and vanilla no one
tested vanilla as an antiviral until I
tested it and all comes from my
Association of peic acid and deification
of wood so a few chemists here in the
audience I know this so this is for you
chemist there are the structures and um
this is basically uh showing the
comparison of the drug controls versus
our activity and this is the list of the
new anti molecules new to science and um
then the summary we have the drug
controls cycl Riv viin interfer Alpha TV
Alp this is the viruses the drug
controls our samples are more potent
than all of these new standard antiviral
drugs that is mof Factor number seven
antiviral molecules related to pic acid
are active against viruses pathogenic to
humans so I present to you for the first
time
ever a microa factorial equation a
formula for a paradigm shift that's not
paulse stus that's paradigm
shift a revolutionary solution for
disease prevention so the the in order
to achieve paradigm shift is f of a plus
b plus C plus d plus e plus f plus G and
this is what all these correlate through
I just walk you through the entire story
of the of the microfactory equation that
can lead to a paradigm sh but but the we
there's something more it turns out
remember amadu extracts limit the mosaic
virus that harms
plants if that's the case then we can
create folar sprays of amidu melium and
we can spray on the crops to prevent
plant viruses and also give bees access
to the antiviral properties of omin
melium there's no examples of viruses
that infect plants that cross over to
humans
but this is an example of the common
solution that can control two different
types of viruses in two different
kingdoms where is this going to go well
I don't really
know micr Factor you know I what's F of
I this is a gateway folks this is a
gateway to a whole new Arena of
knowledge this is ready for the Paradigm
Shift these microfactory equations can
be dialed in they can be targeted
specifically have ecosystems disease
vectors population of the animals and
plants I think this is huge
now we are all hopefully now be
mushroom the scientists across
disciplines need to work together mic
diversity is our
biodiversity and our
biocurity so I present to you humans
trees Bears mushrooms the birds and the
bees all terrestrial organisms evolve to
be interconnected with the myal web of
life within Earth's natural
internet and we follow the path of melum
we respect nature we respect indigenous
peoples we we honor The Descendants and
a shout out to the first people the
concept of Seven Generations is
something that we all need to adopt it's
seem to be part of our constitution
frankly you know uh the constitution of
the of the UN the United States Canada I
think we also need to reframe the
discussion we need to celebrate
decomposition up
Rock bumper sticker the best thing that
you can do is put wood in your backyard
and just let them
WR so I want to just
end with A New Concept
here and my friend Sasha here is the
graphic artist and we co evolved this it
is now time to launch into the
microe we list forever together within
the myal micromolecular Matrix I am
Bound by confidentiality but I highly
suggest that you watch Star Trek that
comes out in January of
2017 and I think that we have the
ability of terraforming other planets we
can be able to to be able to create
micro genomes that can be launched for
the into other planets in order to
transform and create
biospheres and I'm going to wax
philosophical this is the most expansive
view view of the universe it conforms to
the same archetype that is shared by
melium by the computer internet by
neurons and I personally believe matter
begins life life become single cells
single cells become strings strings
Branch become membranes and these
archetypes are resident throughout the
cosmos inevitably we will find myal like
network based organisms on other planets
and I want to leave you now with a short
two-minute movie that Louis schwarzberg
and I are collaborating on so this is
the very end of my
talk
mus myum represents rebirth Rejuvenation
regeneration fungi generates oil that
gives
[Music]
life
the task that we face today is to
understand the language of
[Music]
nature my mission is to discover the
language of nature of the fumble
networks that communicate with the
ecosystem and I believe nature is
intelligent the fact that we lack the
language skills to communicate with
nature does not impune the concept that
nature is intelligent it speaks to our
inadequacy for
communication if we don't get our act
together and come in commonality and
understanding of the organisms that
sustain us today not only will we
destroy those organisms but we will
destroy
[Music]
ourselves we need to have a paradigm
shift in our Consciousness what will it
take to achieve them if I die trying and
by inadequate to the task to make the
course change in the evolution of life
in the planet okay I tried the fact is I
tried how many people are not trying if
you knew that Every Breath You Took
could save hundreds of lives into the
future have you walk down this Path of
Knowledge wouldn't you run down that PA
of knowledge as fast as you
could I believe nature is a force of
good good is not only a concept it is is
a spirit and so hopefully the spirit of
goodness Will
Survive thank you Jeff Lee thank you
Steve sheer thank you
[Music]
all