[Music]
who's here buddy somebody
here holy smoker in the house
what's going on man good to see you dude
I know I feel like I've been hanging out
with you on Bubble man's world dude
you're hanging out with me right now on
Bubble man's
world with you all the time buddy saying
hi hey buddy all right time for one of
these do I smell like dogs you know what
you need Mark the bubble M World song
yeah you got to get a theme song is you
just sniff sniff sniff when you smell it
burning so how many times do we leave
this on the front well first of all you
burnt the butter you put the butter on
and it just burnt that was last night
that that was last night today two times
so so last night you did it so we can't
cooked here is this it's why we don't
eat he needs you bad we don't eat he
needs you
bad anyway anyways just go to show where
where uh sometimes just butter in there
but anyways mess I burned it first and
then just just so we can have some hash
browns I just wanted hash browns and
then I left to go get you and to go get
the bubble bubble machine out of the
shop and everything else get all ready
to go and I had the element on on six
ready ready to put the plate on put the
half on I was going to help him and then
I walk away and I burned the
butter so now round three you really
want the
half it sounds like something I might
want okay so half are finally making the
pan there dude woohoo hey we're
photographing dry sift
resin have you got on the uh so we're
doing some macro photographs this is our
dirty our one time
cleaned and our Pure headies just small
amounts but uh the lesson is good I
think the whole process was good look at
that difference in
color yeah so we can really and I want
to learn from this lower buds not
supply growing the bigger plants and
having the buds lower in the plat so
these all one little bit of contaminant
in there but for the most part pretty
darn heavy
oh Ron was just saying how glad he was
that the camera wasn't on why is that
Ron because here I'm so stoned that that
we I was sitting here and I remember the
last little episode there we're talking
about how be burnt the B and and and
then I got it going I left the AL do
went picked up Paul that way down the
road and gone for a long time anyways I
come back and here I'm talking to you
have a hoot and then I come back I'm
talking to you guys and I'm I'm thinking
I'm stirring heating it up cooking so
Mark can keep on doing what he's doing
and the El start and almost not
on a to without the El on this is how we
do here in the cies all right we're
going to try some of this aren't we yeah
you you wanted uh Paul to give it a
little tast that's any good the colors
are really beautiful the smell how the
smell the smells too things can look
good and they're they're total tops and
the beautiful thing is is when you have
bit large you can only get good tops
from bigger plants we all know that it's
t you got a hell of a breed but uh but
for Purple Kush and see the they purpled
out nicely when the girls trim these of
course when they're Bud fress these are
bone dry but when the girls trim these
that would they would sit there and I'd
say look no put a little extra into that
and trim them between and make let's try
to make it look like a cactus in the end
so people can have this buds for you and
uh and so we put a little extra care
into trying to make them all so they're
all this little nugget stuck otherwise I
found a purple kush it ends up like this
here because it's such a tight growing
plant that's so so dense that you can't
leave that as a bud so then they all end
up being smaller like then you end up
getting a lot of this stuff the which
are still nuggets we should all grow
nuggets if we can agreed you know they
when someone hits the floor it should
have a clunk yeah oops still want to
throw them on the floor just tossing his
nugs
around but that's Paul but Paul's going
to roll one up and then then give us a
they're both the same everything's it's
all the same bass
thisen well this is what yeah yeah this
is already let's take a nicer one though
take out nice one let's take it so
that's uh that's
probably yeah let's just because
everybody always wonderers about weight
because everybody always wonders about
weight things when they see they all
that's not a pound of P I'm going to put
that nugget on the scale we see how that
do where is uh oh here it
is try try using that this is is your uh
airtight container that's the airtight
watertight medtainer you can break your
cannabis up with it oh no way how do you
do that now pull the second one out take
the lid off now pull the top one out I
think yeah you got it oh look at that
sneaky what was that thing I saw you
were showing some kind of grinder on a
on a like a credit card oh yeah that's
uh where are they I'm here I don't I
don't get to the big city anymore so I
don't know what it's all have one you
know Mark now how does that work as a
grinder open it like a like a it's a
little greater but feel it it's quite uh
oh I see this is your credit card I mean
now your business card
yeah very cool it definitely does job
nice graphic excuse me yeah so you just
rub the butt on there whoa yeah sh oh
exactly six G butt six G butt yeah six G
that's almost qu
o very cool thanks much so they're dance
too they're dry and that's dry hey Mark
could you not hit that with a a badon
racket it would just disinte dry it
would just disintegrate that's the only
way it can be to be safe right to be
putting you know met medtainer should
next think about getting getting us
people really high quality uh con bigger
containers so that we can have uh so we
can be confident that there's that uh
that what we put our I have to use a new
B bin every time between storages of of
material right just because I just don't
want because I just don't know what's
going on right I like the idea of just
having a screen right on the bottom of
that oh wouldn't that be neat and you
could just I should make without
cheating it without cheating and rubbing
it off people roll it off so I heard
that I oh no it's terrible as a grower
how about a liner maybe we want like
like just just my association with Mark
bub m i i just just know I realize I
grow grow all that material only for the
glands triome farmer and so so uh so
it's so important to keep the glands on
there you know oh yeah we can have our
turpine our colors everything else have
you seen the uh I'd be proud this was
waterm I was showing over over just
purple Crush I'm just I'm sorry I don't
want to call Purple Crush down but darn
it's just but darn darn have you tried
any of the
[Music]
pure all right the joint is roll you
guys going to like that yeah and Paul's
going to hly smoke her down and we're
going to see Paul how he is now smoke at
all well we're smoke her down I don't
want you to tell me he's old papa for
many many years PA POA the Holy Smoke
yeah I I said no to a to Once In
1978 really I still regret it and that's
a true
story yeah
[Music]
you're not actually burning weed anymore
are you not for a long time but I will
smoke a bowl with you yeah you want to
try this uh no I'll try the hash here I
always feel bad
but remember when you first got your
volcano and we started holy smoke and
you said so what are you still burning
your weed you might as well throw in a
mud what your car
I want the video to end up
[Applause]
burning be
the
the doing whistle though with like
frozen pizzas we burned like three or
four pizzas cuz we kept sitting down
having for 3 weeks your believe that's
what I mean I I flush for three we oh I
bet so badly need to be clean it's got
to be gray and burn nice and that joint
should not go out if we put in the as no
it's burning nicely and it goes smooth
like velvet too on the throat I got to
say does it taste nice
too something to look good but it's also
got to be good absolutely very true
spoken like a true
grower my sens of taste isn't what it
should be though but is there some
well that's rocking my world
yeah I wish I was growing a true old
Stu stinky old thing you know they
wantet your friends walk up you and go
did you you're a girl would give me a
hug in the old days and she go Ron man
you stink bad you're did you drive over
a skunk yeah yeah I go holy I want that
back that's what I wanted that's what
your whole house used to smell like
skunk man Sam or whoever you are or
whoever's got skunk number one they're
true fat Leaf big old nugget we uh man
those I heard I heard bikers had it
breed out like there was a lot of biker
weed that they didn't anybody had
control breing it out I we just lost it
because we were all afraid of getting
busted because we didn't have can
filters back then it's true lot of
people wouldn't buy it if it was too
stinky back in the 60s or L late 60s
early 70s probably 75 something we used
to have one big skunk plant in the
closet one 1000 wat light good air good
air in and out as much as we could that
plant stunk one one plant one 1,000
Watts that was the old days and if you
got made it by you made it by you're
lucky but you wouldn't believe how many
times the neighbors would always say hey
I don't care what you're doing and then
of course filters came in and big rooms
came in and all but then we lost it
because nobody really want everybody was
against that smell was going to kill us
that that smell will kill you yeah
getting now we want her back cuz now now
we can honestly be proud of that smell
walk down the street and smell that
smell we can go hey that guy's growing
some dank all right so we're at we're at
a half of the of that well well rolled
joint by the way Paul and tastes good it
looked good so now it tastes good I
think it's good but you know what I I'm
the grower and I feel hard it's hard
when when Mark's here with me because
when you're smoking dry sift when you're
smoking bubble of the highest qualities
in the world yeah and then you have your
high the best I could grow it pot world
you know like the stuff to try to have
it just it's just so hard for pot
smoking pot to measure up to go in the
same uh it shouldn't be a contest this
is about this is but it's hard anyways
so I feel inferior when I have but pot
that we can make bubble out of when I
got when it's compared to dry sifted
bubble it's really tough so I'm humbled
by bubble and and and uh and dry sift I
really am so you have my humility Mark
I've tried to grow the best bud and I
hope it passes our standards anyways for
what plot oh yeah totally I would
compare it to something like say
moonshine like you can make moonshine
out of your wine you can take your nice
good wine make it into Grappa and it's
the Grappa is way stronger it'll kick
your ass but there's something to the
wine you know it's got its subtle
overtones and its tastes and that that's
what the bud has you know yeah you can
you can extract it make it way stronger
with so holy smoke what do you give it
is it is it does it deserve to be holy
smoke oh yeah this is AA a quadruple a
maybe even the way it's trimmed and
stuff triple
A oh it's so hard to get that seriously
you feel inferior when you're taking a
what's it call a dab dab of a of a fancy
fany bubbling product and uh and that's
the first thing you wake up to it's but
you know the crazy thing is it's sad we
were saying on the way in the ride when
I picked you up but the problem is that
it's not available to everybody in the
world yeah you know I I still like good
old low Tech although I got to say like
I love smoking I love this is the first
joint I've smoked in a long time but I
VAP 99% of the time and it gets me
higher it's a way more efficient use of
weed I miss smoking every once in a
while I'll smoke a joint just to smoke
so with the taste of this Reaper because
I because remember that I also got
scared that this is a this is the first
batch of Reaper I've everever taken down
where I didn't have plates and plates of
finger hash I love my finger hash and so
when that happens boy I get scared
because like you know Mark does tell
teach me something that maybe sometimes
the plots that went through uh through
crisises or or through a little more
stress while their envirment wasn't
perfect perfect you know they sometimes
make also a good bubble house is that
not correct Mark oh yeah so it's uh but
uh but anyways
uh but I want to go back to Growing some
a product that's that's really admired
by myself but for the world to grower I
I don't want anything that just that
just you know just average yeah so I
want to find that plant if I if I if we
get to keep growing for a while yeah I
want to find that plant or go grow that
plant the god that no I'm growing never
lost the race because I he never had to
have competition yeah every every race
ran and he was too old for anybody to
buy all right here we go we're dabbing
it
out a little dab will'll do you is this
dabing the right way when you dab it
with we're going to do a big one melt as
opposed to some kind of oils that are
made in
very I think it's a good idea nice
little carb on
that you can clear
it beautiful nice Bo wow what's the how
does the taste on that uh hash like I
keep saying my sense of taste isn't so
good because I no story about a sinus
infection years ago and never quite
recovered but I can taste it with my
brain oh that's we like to hear yeah it
rocks man on the brain Goes Down Smooth
too that that hits nice like yeah
perfect T all right we're back what
happened
Ron I I swear to God we didn't plan this
this and it's not for to make bubble
bubble world like uh like Wayne's World
uh like uh this uh I swear we did not
plan that we we love talking we got Paul
here talking old stories we're going
crazy we burned it what do you think of
that Paul
no funny now that you that you mention
it it's really
smok buy the smoke it wasn't our ho
smoking holy [ __ ] all right okay we
burned the hash browns but that's okay
somebody should have smelled it we
burned the hash as well we should go out
forast we'll see you soon
perfect you can stop
that I just all right there Ron would
you like to increase your dbit toe I
will have one just so I can get rock and
roll ready for work Ron's going to
increase his
dbud oh of course it
[Music]
is great little carb
cap yeah
how's that feeling good
good I guess weak 60y old lungs you got
your uh knee pads on for working in the
grow got to get [ __ ]
man cannabis
Warrior the Big Money Maker so I
guarantee take a du
take a
dub
boom yeah little dab will do it to
you
indeed do kids know what that means
where that came from little dab will do
you I hope so
all right
so so here we go
that's all I can do
[Music]
Perfect Two those
roll see uh yeah EMP Genesis that time
I'm tripping on marijuana then she
puked
yum all right we just had a great day
hanging out with Paul D from the holy
smokes and he's off now he's taking off
so yeah good to see you all right it's
not the end no we'll see you again maybe
tonight awesome see you guys
later as I fall over on the bud as I
trip over on I just about broke my neck
on this way to go hey this is dangerous
leaving this Ling around man what's
going on all right peace guys
bye guys bye