[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh today I'm doing something well I'm
partially doing something that I've been
talking about for a long time bringing
you all with me I'm finally getting up
to the pton ice caps to go visit some of
the Epic [ __ ] I Ice Caves up there uh
beautiful beautiful Ice Caves really
Majestic and and and deeply
deeply spiritual places very quiet and
unique places a place that you won't
spend a lot of your life uh in and so
the short time that you do get to spend
there it's always very much appreciated
particularly by me um I just did my wake
and bake video my 13th episode and took
about oh I'd say three or four rips of
this particular rosin some Congo from
120 Micron bubble very strong stuff very
good very very tasty so going to have
one more RIP just with you guys but I
thought I'd do a short little interlude
sort of intro to this video for the day
I'm not going to do the regular you know
take the camera and set it up in my
vehicle so you can kind of drive up the
road with me probably we'll just start
in the parking lot pulling the sleds off
a lot of it's going to be first person
at least getting to the the spots will
be first person on my GoPro and then
I'll have my camera as well just to film
a little bit of the Ice Caves that's
mostly what I'm looking to do just film
some some nice action um oh there we go
getting little little messages about my
stripe account kind of felt like I just
wanted to make sure that wasn't a fraud
uh email but it's not so it's all very
good news happy 420 uh day after 420 to
everyone I hope that your times were
great and that you had good times we of
course had 420 in
Vancouver uh which is going to be its
own video so you can watch that on my
channel as well and uh it was pretty
good Prett pretty good lots of people
I'd say maybe 35,000 people uh as we
were standing out on the stage myself
D40 d420 K and Johnny B and of course
Jody Emery was there and marijuana man
and David malol LaVine and all of them
really Dana Larson the crew of Crews
that have been putting on this event for
many a years and let me tell you they
pulled it off without a hitch it was
perfect it was great uh I even saw ra
rayquan from the from the wuang clan at
one point in time walking around and
puffing big blunts so that kind of put a
smile on my face toos let's have a rip
and then we're going to head on up to
pton and we're going to get this sled
video out of the way cuz today we're
going to the Ice Caves
[Music]
and
rock free and live fre and rock free
your mind and dance
Dess
Dess distress
distress and save your life oh yes
distress distress
and save your life oh
yes like a oh yeah and like a r oh and
treat you like a mat they will die you
like a a and they will miss R my people
before your realize oh yeah they T to
dirty Li they will show you like a dice
ice distress
stress
beess
Dess and save your life for yes distress
distress
distress distress
distress and save your life
yes to keep you down they you and you
all
around to sound a sound so you got to
listen to yourself and know which one
you must choose and which one you
must get
confused oh no
no
and
and mind and dance de
stress deep stress
he
stress and save your life for yes he
stress
distress and all right so we are here
bu's Ryan is in the background there the
rest of the crew went up to the glacier
ahead of us we were waiting for one more
friend Ricarda and we're going to head
out so the next little bit of footage
you guys are going to see is going to be
from my GoPro chess mount
uh I'll bring us up to the mountain nice
short little view I'm not going to
record the whole thing cuz I want to
record some of the riding while we're
there and of course some of the uh
spectacular ice cave so thanks for
joining us bubble man's world we are
going to shred today peace out
yes step steing out the right place walk
walking out the
Right Moving on the right
[Music]
this skip
skipping on the right Bas run running on
the right lane dance dance upon the
right base dance uh-huh
Dess
Dess distress
yes and save your life for rest
distress
Dess
Dess Dess Dess
and save your life for rest
beess
Dess
distress and save your life for yes
distress distress
distress
distress and save your life for yes d
[Music]
stress Don't You wor All About a Thing
take he
Rel me and never give in don't do
wor about the thing they keep he's
believe man and never give
in life is not hard as it
seems take it one day at a time and
fulfill your
dreams remember no one is an island no
one stands
alone in your doings always remember
you're a
[Music]
theme all when things get hard and
lean hold on to your faith and fulfill
your
beam and don't right all right ice cave
bound see what this is all
about you guys have been waiting waiting
for this on Bubble man's world for I
want to say a couple years I've been
promising to get you guys down to the
ice cave and
finally finally we are doing it let's
see if we're actually yeah we are we are
we're
recording recording
Ricardo recording Ryan hi boom look at
this is this insane it's pretty Nar is
this the one we used to go in with Ben
the entrance is different what happened
so well
it melt you have got to be kidding me I
can't I can't film walking down there
you can film me falling on my ass down
here okay that's what I'll do do we just
slide I I think so but I don't I'm going
to try
sketchy I'm going to try and make some
big footsteps for you guys okay and uh I
got [ __ ] to carry we got to make this
happen I do need to just have a puff
down here and then that's
it take a few pictures
a this going to be the hardest cave to
get in all it is the hardest cave but
you know what we can do this can't we
Ryan or is it too stupid it's not it's
not the sketchiest one but it's it looks
like it's the
hardest I I think I'm good for this you
know I don't know I just don't want to
go ripping down into the cave of
course no you got to know that you can
get up so it will flatten out you know
no I know I know the thing
getting out getting out
yeah what about over there I see people
have gone over that way that looks like
a PE spot to me oh cuz it's a hole it
looks yeah it could be a PE
spot well maybe we're not going in the
ice cave look at that maybe we're to the
next ice cave if I can get my sled
started cuz it stopped working when we
got here so it looks like there's some
easy way right
I guess we kind of need gloves for this
hey I didn't bring
gloves yeah next time I
guess what's that
oh
yeah
my 5D wasn't getting
so
[Laughter]
wet yeah it's kind of easy to come down
sideways it's not as bad as it looks
Ricardo oh my God is that of her
beautiful
image the shot of Ricarda is like the
sky is so blue behind her it doesn't
look
real
[Music]
really woohooo
100% wow Ry guy it's been a while since
we've been here man a long time my
friend all right we made it guys I'm
here in the original ice cave the first
ice cave that I was ever brought to on
the pton ice caps and it is absolutely
[ __ ] cool goes down in there Ryan's
down there part is over here and that
was our entrance to climb down into the
cave we got this pretty beautiful ice
behind us it'd be nice to come in and
run a batch of bubble has in here I'm
not going to lie got the nice ice got
the Klein up here didn't bring water
down from my um from my sled and it was
quite a walk to get down here with all
my equipment so we're just going to hit
it as is and uh oh I guess you know what
I'll do the timer with in my
head time it in my head
time' be great it's good to know you
know
m a little bit cold out so I'll heat it
up a little bit more than
[Applause]
usual then you got the timer y all right
click
it give it a
go damn it's not not starting sorry well
that's okay we'll do it with the uh
wrist Tech sometimes iPhone timers do
that you go to hit it and it just goes 0
00 0 it doesn't really engage that
wasn't bad 5 seconds
late all right so we'll take the first
hit using the flashlight to carb
the it's the only thing I have that's
not like plastic you know matches the
jacket exactly give thanks for that I
think we're just going to hit this here
sooner than later so let's do it
[Applause]
perfect con go for the win man was that
delicious
delicious mildly chazzed up the banger
but not too bad
not too
bad all right get a another rip for
these guys cuz I'm sure they want to try
this Congo Bongo you go next I'll take a
couple more photos get in there
sure get your
photos yeah I've been watching ricard's
Facebook page he's just been having the
most beautiful photos in regards to
these ice caves and some of these uh
snowmobile days at brome Ridge as uh she
always is at bro Ridge always that's the
best Mountain to ride right y so close
to my house yeah so
blessed all right here we
go definitely have become an ice CER the
resin is so cold I have to warm it up
yeah to try and get it onto this uh
Dabber I've had this uh problem in the
winter as well even sitting in the
jacuzzi oh yeah all right we got the dab
you got the timer uh yeah uh wait the
timer has to be activated again not
right away but once we stop
the
ready Chaz out the Banger a bit this is
my Chaz Banger I don't mind getting it
all dirty and then burning it off but if
you do that to your quartz all the time
it fogs it out and it's and then it's
done well it's definitely not ideal I've
done it you've done it you're on the
boat you know yeah you got a rosin
press that's
awesome in the ice cave taking dabs here
I'll move over a little
bit you got room for you over here
[Applause]
Ryan can I put this here
yep I'd say about 40 seconds Mary yeah
hello oh that
was
Exposure One More yeah nice is that the
44 17 to 40 yeah I got that lens it's
wide angle right yeah you are on the 18
to so
25 something mine's 24 to to 105 oh
that's what it is oh no that's that
yours is the other a little bit
cooler with the flashlight carb cap
cuz we do what we got to do here in the
back country the sled doesn't work we
pull out rope Ryan doesn't know what's
going on he fixes it it's fine it's fine
yeah we've already had quite the
adventure oh my gosh so delicious yeah
so Marky for me just a little one little
itty you guys
are no problem dude you smoke a lot more
than me actually put that right here
thank you very much you're most welcome
that was incredible so good right enough
for some flavor yeah just a little
little a little a little touch
everyone's got their
own
levels yeah and we're we're we're in the
back country right now dude like this is
a serious I to fix your sled again I
kind of need to have my head screwed on
I would I would like you to have your
head screwed on if you have to
fix if you have to fix my
sled you know you're going to have to
fix my sled well then you better give me
an itty ditty one it's tiny
perfect it's a tiny one started to do
smoke thingss the dad smoke yeah it's so
fun I forgot I haven't done it since I
smoked joints right so fun yeah that's
fun what' you guys do for 420 yesterday
have a day up on the mountain worked
worked I worked till 6:30 I worked uh I
worked my dabs well I bet you did I
figured you guys were all doing
something fun but I was working so I
could take today off and come out riding
with you guys well I'm very glad you did
right to get the extra work done glad
you did so that'll be a few seconds
oh I came
C still very hot so I guess we're going
to go head up out of here after this
last dab and I'll walk you guys down
into the ice cave show you a little bit
and then we'll head uh we'll head up and
move on to our next
location which is never bad
thing boom that go a perfect little one
what I'm talking
about wasn't that little delicious you
really do forget the size of
it it's a big big
cave once you start walking down into
it get an idea
the
depth adventuring hey with sledding it's
so crazy CU you're always going further
you're always pushing
yourself well my
camera just told me that my card is not
formatted
for never ever SE format it
form at
it don't go past here oh God no this is
it this is where you slide to your desk
I've gone to the end there um we walked
down the side and had ropes like tied
onto this stuff and the very end there
it just drops straight
down how cool is
this so happy to be at the ice cave so
happy to be at the ice cave you can see
the colors in these in these walls it's
uh the temperature is like literally the
perfect temperature for dry sifting and
making water hash it's literally the
perfect
temperature good stuff when we wanted to
come out here and do bowl of bags in
here I still do I've been talking about
this is the first time I've made it to
the cave since talking about that Ryan
since talking about that three four
years ago yes no joke right so crazy
crazy and fulfill your dream
remember no one is an island no one
stands
alone in your doings always remember
you're a
theme all when things get hard and
lean hold on to your faith and fulfill
your
beam and
don't worry h all the
They
EAS never
[Music]
give
about take it easy believe me never
give test of time test of
patience just like in the days of f
[Music]
remember the man called job he tried it
the rocky
road he know where he was going so he
know where he was coming
from believe in yourself my
friend as you
pursue just what you go
through and don't you worry hry
the thing than you he's believe man and
never give don't tell
wor
[Music]
about J believe me
never my people keep the positive that
to
do hey kids F your back time to go to
school
if stop the got the
rolling you you what on the street side
Lo Rising the Winds Don't
you about the thing
take
he me and never give don't you wor hry
[Music]
take he
said
man don't
[Applause]
you w
w w w
w w w w w
my strike lightning as the morning break
my open while the sun was up in my face
the wisdom of the wi keep my head
straight
with try to Perfection smoke synic I
love
the we get the full m
ding I love
the I tell you when the rest consume the
meditation Vine to CB1 and
CB2 can have n receptors in the brain
and
happiness herbalistic can
specialist
herbaliz herbalistic can
herbalist in my
can
[Music]
specialist her
can up and give it a s
turn yes and I also got
hash full m edes all that dry make you
cool and relax and if you get some you
must come
back
[Music]
herous
indigen original
[Music]
indigenous from the
beginning care and you
TR Pier
bring me sex and bring
in I
know
orig
[Music]
indigenous you want to get some phone
out Yes Man
[Music]
[Applause]
full
[Music]
with
full yes
[Music]
be a great day to do some
skiing that hole Zone over there called
Project X there's a bunch of names the
mountains Mount semm but that
whole area Middle all those
bumps he's just stopped hey yeah he
stopped uh Dave no there's a skier up on
top there oh he's going to hit that
jump uh well there's a bunch of like
spiny goodp line type lines there he's
just pulling he's just tugging his oh
[ __ ] man look at that yeah I wish I was
still a skar
boom sick
[Music]
sick these are the things that happen
when you're up on the top of Rutherford
Creek six ski line is busting I don't
know what was that like a 30 or 40
footer I don't know man looked pretty
big from where he landed I don't think
he actually aired I think
heow just SK through that like I'll have
to watch it on the camera narrow shot
am I leaving enough room for people to
get by uh yeah they can get by
oh
[ __ ] all right we have arrived at the
ice cave everything is iy as it should
be we're going to head in to the ice
cave better put my backpack on properly
cuz this could literally pull me right
in and let me show you where we're at
guys e
Jesus that's
ridiculous I see
really we can walk right through this is
an absolutely stunning ice cave
this is one of the nicest caves I've
ever been in
going up hill
wow that is [ __ ]
crazy holy [ __ ] this is unbelievable
real keep going yeah just how beautiful
this wall looks right
here it's [ __ ]
crazy you don't want to stay under that
part too long no I didn't want to stay
under there for much time at all stay on
the side
even that's walking on the creek
too when you're in the middle
wow so I'm right inside a cave now this
is absolutely
spectacular I think this is where I
would love to make some water hash some
bubble hash you can really see these
spots too people have climbed way into
them and you can go and keep going down
into the entrance I'm not going to but
pretty cool that's a cool little tunnel
that goes for a
while oh
wow beautiful in and
out so bubble man in the ice cave like I
told you I would be God is this [ __ ]
killer so ridiculous I want to take
pictures I want to make video I want to
do all these different things but uh I'm
going to have to uh take my time and do
one at a time
you can see quite a ways into both of
them yeah it's kind of neat I think I
came in that way oh really rolled in on
the belly well there was no snow there
oh jeez happens fast doesn't
it spectacular huh
someone's got the light on
there looks great with the light shining
in well
I can't even explain to you guys how
ridiculous this thing is see if I can
turn my oh you don't even need the light
on here see the
ice how trippy it
is super super trippy [ __ ]
okay so I just climbed through this tiny
little port hole and got to I guess what
I would call a pretty epic
location very limited with my height let
me get to a spot here so I can show you
where I'm
at ice cave that way
exit outside that
way and then uh looks
like a
substantial distance around this corner
can be
taken but I won't be doing that so you
see sometimes these networks go
forever obviously it makes sense to be
very careful when you're in these zones
particularly this time of year the Melt
is occurring you can hear it happening
you don't want to put yourself in a
situation that's more dangerous than it
needs to be so be careful out there but
uh yeah absolutely stunning
stunning head in here for a little
bit just show you guys what's going
on well man's world getting you out
there to the ice cave first time this is
what cannabis is all about to me using
it as a medicine and allowing myself to
be inspired and to be touched by by
nature in these zones you know glass ice
wall in front of me that's like I can
see 2 3 ft right into it uh right above
me as well it's just beautiful so I'm
glad to bringing you guys here in 4k I'm
going to go see if my friends want to
come over here for the sesh or if they
want to have the sesh over there but we
are going to have a sesh real quick
here okie dokie oh we got to find oops
we got to find that uh Flash like too I
don't know where the heck put it in
Pocket yeah yeah easy well cuz it's my
car oh right and then I did this isn't
that awesome pull the thing right
out session all right we're in the ice
cave everybody this is the ice cave
session the one you've all been waiting
for
I did kind of lose my carb cap
flashlight it's not even mine but I'm
sure it's in my bag
somewhere am I ready what ready for for
your appearance yeah here let me move
out of the way and you can make your
appearance all right ready y
[Laughter]
[Music]
W that's
hilarious all right so this is our Shelf
that we can stand on without cutting our
heads
off and maybe someone could hold
this I'll give timer again yes excellent
Ricardo's on the timer I've got shards
of this smell this
condo you always have fragrance stuff
that's for sure yeah it's good to be
fragrant I mean not like a fish W that
hasn't showered in like 3 months but
sometimes it's going to be
fragrant clean this off a little bit
have a little bit
of stuff that we don't want on there so
we are like literally what would you
guys say from just the parking
lot we are at least 60 I'd say 60 maybe
even 75 km from the parking lot in a
straight line we've traveled further
than that though right yeah how cool was
that
incredible where we are standing here
the ice is at least 15,000 years old
15,000 or more
wow pretty cool you take a little Chun
back to my whiskey no you know why
because actually there could be bacteria
I know I know I know water yeah of what
bacteria oh yeah prehistoric times could
be frozen in this ice and you never
know damn Ricardo with the
schooling we got all the bubble bag
colors red and blue and green and yellow
maybe a little
black you got that
timer how you doing we're going to turn
it on now perfect I was a little worried
about the the torch it was
not well it wasn't turning off no oh
yeah lots of things seem to be doing
that today yeah I wish I had that
flashlight part uh carbing this would be
super key but uh well I know it is what
it is your little container there you
know the quartz if it's too hot on top
it will be a no buo the plastic would
melt to it I'll just take a big Airy hit
in the ice cave nothing wrong with that
what do we at
dir still pretty hot
make me want to find that
flashlight cuz it's not like it would I
remember putting it like tight with my
video camera and my camera now had
43 Stone
thing a stone
yeah ice how cool is it
worked just chilling y in the
cave wow that didn't work too
bad doesn't get much Chiller than
that booah there's so many more to pick
up I can throw my carb cap down after my
rip all right so want to hold that sure
I will hold this I will find
this we will do our cleanliness thing
because cleanliness is Godliness
the best we can
anyway this is my travel Chaz Banner so
it's okay to get some
CH all right actually hold that I think
there's a real order to this and I think
putting the hash on before you need this
key yep I think so otherwi you know may
scramble and the B may fall over or your
torch or anything's possible just not
ready for
it yeah and then you missed your da and
you wasted all that for nothing what a
waste and I hate butane as it is yeah
exactly it's pretty much like my least
favorite thing exactly in this
experience oo it's not a bad sound when
you're and your dab makes the sound of
broken glass
wasn't sure when it was going to happen
wasn't sure when we were going to get
out here I mean I knew you guys would
get out I wasn't sure when I was going
to go get out here I was going to make
you guys get out here matter what both
be working too much you can believe it
you might want to pick up a nice flat
piece of ice for your carb
cap nice FL
that's not dirty this one little bit
bigger maybe that one
work oh yeah that ni
I think that'll be a full 50 seconds on
that one okay heated it up good and got
all the black
out
there ah what a beautiful place to take
bong
ribs seriously
unparalleled
right excellent
a cage in all hles around
us beautiful thing where we at there the
31 we can go bit
here it's
funny that is indeed funny
my Ry I enjoy it a
lot so delicious the whole experience
has been epic some of those open areas
where we were sledding I was just like
so mindblowing it's kind of like the
only thing I really hear
is yeah yeah like just constantly oh
it's like that part in the movie where
everything's amazing sun shining through
it's almost like there's supposed to be
an orchestra travel beside you just play
epic music yeah no for real yeah it's so
amazing the views as you coming down
it's just
like yeah they can bring you to tears
yeah like if you really thought about
it fast up here
yeah little one for Ry guy itty bitty
one it's a little bit bigger than you'll
be
fine remember I got to get us back yep
you I listen put it this way if you're
not if you don't get back I'm not
getting back probably so we're pretty
good to go yeah hey you still got me I
have a to Rob don't worry that's right I
just never leave him here if he didn't
get back I wouldn't get
back same well it's pretty nice here I
think about moving in the hammock over
there
and here you tripped out to see a bear
in here though a bear would seem so
close yeah I don't think bear is living
the stuff Chang s they're sleeping way
lower but they go on the ice oh I know
they do and you know what those guys
have apparently a dead duck in their SE
really I don't know
what whose T is that
uh that's Rory's plan it kind of kind of
felt like it might have been his that's
cool I don't know I don't know I've
heard the name a couple times and I
heard I've met Rory a couple of times I
heard that there's a couple people
living in a teepe somewhere around here
and uh now I've seen the teepe Rory was
married to
Sarah yeah that's kind of when I met him
well I did a a I did a thing with Blake
Jorgenson uh a class yeah
and um he was Rory was one of the riders
that Blake had hired to be like just
he's an allaround he can do mountain
biking he can do this he can do that and
so uh that cool down a little
bit that's how I met him and then uh
when Sarah passed away I went to her
thing as well up on Whistler and the
super pipe there yeah and saw him again
go
blow it out blow it
out that was a proper carbing right
there that was a proper carving the
reason I said blow it out blow it out
blow it out cu Ryan doesn't need to hold
that in for any amount of
time okay that's it we did it we had an
amazing session thank you both to Ryan
and Ricardo for bringing me here and
getting me here and getting all of you
here thank you cuz you guys wouldn't be
here with us and I suspect there's going
to be some thousands of you that get to
see this so enjoy Beauty yeah we're
going to shred for the rest of the day
we might pull the pipe out again but
we'll
see
really just getting back to the middle
is going to be
[Laughter]
yeah I think
so I never guessed that's great be like
actually this is the way we have to
go this is super
trippy super trippy
whenever I see rocks I'm happy cuz they
give a perfect amount of
grip
wow that
spectacular spectacular
definitely put your shades on moment
glit
this guy got here the way he's supposed
to get here hey
is
all
right we going are we backing up out of
here or going uh he's just backing up so
he
can you should I be starting this up uh
yeah
this is incredible
it's nice
all right so we just stopped in this
little Zone and I thought I'd give you
guys a little peek at where we
are pretty
epic all
right got it going on here yes we are
recording can hear people blasting
around there's a nice cave over there
lots of lump little
avalanches and just beautiful beautiful
epicness this is of course the pton back
country just a little bit north of
Whistler for those of you wondering
definitely not something you want to
just drive out here and go into without
any uh guides or people that can uh you
know protect and and help save your life
but it is definitely a beautiful place
if you can put it all together and get
it all right so you have a crew of
people willing to take you out here so
figured I'd
share cool
St kind of real cloud like I say I bring
[Music]
this Roy alongside one
SP s oh yes
againest looking at me eyes
so on Sal head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke coing
that's why I don't grumble
s meia
[Music]
yeah must be burn like must be cleaned
rather vital for Spiritual jeene a king
Salomon certify the tree and he is the
wisest man to we so propa preach her
never Sound True speech so meanwhile the
song called leaders deceive man
obligated to clarify and teach you now
what say
you is that
Mason it's
Mark I'm also rather
excited those dudes that's a good crew
right there the little bit of time that
I got to spend with those guys
bro all right we just got to our
third and final ice cave unless we
discover a couple more on the way
home at least two on the way back that's
hilarious how's that
looking oh yeah
looks like a pretty steep entrance
that's what he
meant whoa
they all look so similar but
different whoa is this it mhm can't get
in any more than this no you can really
yeah yeah we're going to on the side
there
[ __ ] thought we were standing on the
cornes oh yeah
it's
[Applause]
doable hug swarm of
birds
no I'm too low to see it mhm
going to be able to get back
up H yeah
really
wow if I will make
it devices
out all right
ice cave number three no joke how about
that didn't even bring the bong down for
this
one we can have it in the sun yep
exactly see what Ricardo says we can
have it in the
sun yep she
knows all right all
right that looks so cool yeah
can really go down in this thing
all right are we live are we live I
think we're live third Cave Final sesh
for the day pton ice caps just epic so
so great up
here oh damn want to do all this but
it's not safe
trying to deaz my banging here it's not
really working
don't use all the gas Mark don't use all
the gas oh yeah we're recording good
good I lost my uh lens CP in there I
think oh we're not in the ice cave
anymore so we don't have any real ice
chunks to carb with I'll have to make
one ah this one will work fine I
suspect
perfect cuz that's how you got to do it
sometimes all right let let's do
this how enjoyable is that to have just
a lovely bong R up in this area it's so
nice everyone else is stoked on beer
yeah I'm not no at all want to hold down
sure all right little bit of bubble
hash that
I know Ryan wants a
double
no yeah the stuck that you do out here
it's amazing it's lifechanging stuff
it's living life you climb and you play
and you get on your belly and you you
get inspired and you say things like wow
that's unbelievable that's important to
me in life yeah the same way I see it's
important for my son to feel that way
yeah it restores your the good energy
like you
said all right so we'll hold that for a
little bit maybe 20 or 30 seconds maybe
40 so
nice
mhm we got quite a quite a rip back
though don't we it's like an hour and
now we're just ripping through the to
the parking lot to the oh that's not bad
and most of that is in the uh most of
that's on the glacier still really the
trail is like half an hour okay so half
an hour is so like I think we could
probably still pretty hot proba back in
like an hour 15 hour 20 minutes yeah
yeah if we just went kind of straight
back well we won't do that but should we
take that
uh little Sizzle from our carb cap
melting into the quartz Banger that's
how we do it up here on the pton ice
caps incredible it's how it has to be
done oh
yeah thank you very much oh yeah always
a pleasure always a
pleasure should we take the ice ball on
the way
back back
over I told I'd follow out on the main
okay all right we will see you guys when
we see
you see
you
MEP get a
friend my of the
[Music]
[Applause]
the I
[Music]
earth when you spping on your you tumble
down
come Street my people still P by and say
you resources and in turn showing off
your yearly budget
[Music]
her
know Roy
[Music]
I oh yes my
medicine some call it
Cy some call it
weed some call it marijuana Marana some
call it
herbs call it
[Music]
push I make
me so me
[Music]
with strictly
yeah
[Music]
right High alone
[Applause]
my w wo wo
W wo w w
[Music]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my head open wide the sun was up in my
face the wisdom of the wise keep my head
straight
[Music]
with to Perfection
smoke I love
the from the we get the full m dry the
rising I
when the rest consume the
meditation to CB1 and
CB2 can n receptors in the brain and
body happiness for me and you you
[Music]
got me the
Perfection
smity I love the
street the St we get the
full I love
to m e d i c a l medical Canabis the
patient m a d i c a n
canab can can make it better I can
without the let's many many and then be
to all the organic farmers I'm a to
respect and when com
I
smity I love the
stre we get the full D on theing I love
the street
[Music]
[Applause]
to the real authentic people
[Music]
or
indigen Iration where you watering give
me full weeks
flowering full St with the
raining bu with the full
bubbling well I was joking that we would
maybe find another ice cave before we
ended up back home lo and behold we have
found another ice cave ice cave well
what do you know what do you know it's
almost like we knew these were here
almost like you did know they were here
oh
yeah at least this one has a n decent
entrance my
God some of the caves
today oh my
gosh there's a Frozen little song bird
what
yeah a Frozen little song
bird it really does he could be alive to
be
honest yeah we just noticed a
hummingbird the other day I thought it
was a hummingbird we had to start
feeding them there's not a lot out right
now no wow look at these clouds baby
could well or just a tiny little song
bird look at how cool this looks
beautiful poor little
guy oh snap are you kidding
me these places just keep getting better
and
better the deeper in you
go the bigger it
gets
wow wow wow
wowowow spectacular I mean it's just uh
what words can be said other than thank
you mother
nature for producing such a beautiful
array of Ice Caves for our
enjoyment all right guys we're we're
going to call it to day on these Ice
Caves we're going to head out back onto
the glacier and try to get ourselves
back to pton and then I'm going to head
home so not sure how much more I'll
share with you you might get a little
bit more when we land and uh get to the
trucks but uh otherwise what a great
great day having you guys all out here
with me in the ice cave
Adventure couple of percent left on the
camera so perfect
timing to bid you all a gar
still respect the Muslim the Christian
where you go through this strle
orig
indigenous we
[Music]
just
indigen
themy cre take them from the beginning
and be careful and turn you traveling
[Music]
Ander
sex
orous
indigenous just
[Music]
orous
indigenous orig
orig
[Applause]
[Music]
bubble bugs in action ice schol
reaction
satisfaction sck 73 night
M
[Music]
welcome specializ
uu
[Music]
D herbalist the can
specialist herbalist
[Music]
herbalist pull it up to nose and give it
a sff him turn around and
I say yes and I also got
hash full m Edibles all that dry make
you cool and relax and if you get some
you must come
back
her
[Music]
Canalis can Beal
reaction know
know I
[Music]
I