[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh just wanted to do another quick
little video much like the last one that
I did a little bit of an introduction a
little bit of some puffing and then I
wanted to get into the mountains the
last one we put up was the dirt bike
video up in brome Ridge and everyone
really seemed to love it uh I'm glad
about that and I figured I'd follow it
up with a video that I posted a similar
one a a version of this small video uh
in my snowboarding video up at uh pton
ice caps so I also sitting here talking
a little bit and going through a couple
of videos there is one video on my
channel that's similar to this video for
those of you that think hey I think I've
seen this before but trust me you have
not it's a very short video just a few
minutes and it's uh myself uh a ghost
ride my sled down uh a mountain on the
pton ice caps just north of Whistler and
I snowboard down real simple real fun
got the camera on the end of a pole and
it really shows you the beautifulness
that we are surrounded by up on those
glaciers every minute of every day uh
this is the same place the ice cave is
and uh I'll throw a couple of pictures
up on the ice cave at the end of the
video so you guys can get an idea about
where we're going to try and make this
batch of bubble hash this year up on the
mountain I'm also going to try and get
up on Broome this weekend with uh my
buddy Phil and we're going to try and
whip off a nice batch of some Bubba cush
for you guys that is
absolutely beautiful quality so why
don't we start it off with a dab so was
ask to start with a dab got a little of
this OG Kush
rosin I puffed my Lindsay rosin down
pretty fast and now I just need to go
down to my truck get the Press that's
still in there from when I visited Corey
and Stratosphere on the coast and did
that video get it back up here so I can
start squeezing the goodness all right
so we're about 660 de on the
denail and we're ready to hit that Fab
bag here we go you got your rig grab
your rig yep get your
Dabber grab your
dabs all right we
ready all right
enjoy the show guys here's what we do we
will set
[Music]
up this is tunnel
vision from planet to planet solar
system to solar system from Galaxy to
Galaxy
we switch you
to come in
please
[Music]
uncensored that skywat
clear another Public Service message
from way out
we care about your
world stay tuned