[Music]
this not [ __ ]
around we're getting Bubblicious look at
the one that I have in front of me I
swear I didn't plan that yes I did
Los Angeles [ __ ] Los
Angeles imported to Canada true true
vacation Style with these dudes welcome
to Bubble man's world guys and uh what a
fun exciting episode today is with uh
these two characters flab 421 in from
all the way down the street with epic
glass just to come where you from
sampton dude all the way from sampton in
the hood sampon dude
South
LBC we're sitting in the lb right
now west west y'all and uh yeah this is
exciting these guys uh Aaron's come up
Aaron of course from DNA has come up uh
to to enjoy this trip as well we've got
our families we're all taking up to
Whistler for a for a pretty awesome
family trip and in the meantime I guess
what we're going to do is we're going to
test out Flav's Congo bubble hash out of
all of these just ridiculous pieces
you've you've got the straight Fab over
there yeah so this bowl doesn't turn I
just no it's it's fixed that kind of
sucks does it I'll trade you yeah yeah
boom so now he has I like
to put at an angle because you it's
easier to torch the bowl yeah no at at
an angle excellent and that's a super
fat I wonder if he might need the bigger
torch
now most certainly so this is the little
cran I on the other hand don't need a
torch at all I have my little candle
light right here my little T light and
my be line so romantic around here oh
dude this is pretty spectacular I'm uh I
say we hit this Congo oh I think that's
a fabulous idea D I need a tool that's
the 120 hit the 73 hit the 73 hit the 73
you guys get the 73 I'll hit the 120 I
actually haven't even tried the 120 I
just put it in a p you want us to hit
the 120 out of these fad pieces over
here exactly it's just not good enough
press a little piece together for you
for your yeah can I get the can I get
the little tool right there I was going
to give you the fancy Dancy dab ey oh be
ninja about it is that an actual dab rry
because I think actual dab R have like
this WAP and stuff exactly and did Nick
T do those dab r no it was some other
guy okay cuz yeah I'm not sure I thought
oh this is the happy happy Daddy this is
the happy daddy one yeah Patrick gave me
this in Amsterdam which is a very nice
uh little kick down
this This Ti Da for you my friend thank
you of the Congo you're smoking what
we're smoking whether you like it or not
I like it or not and yes this is the
Congo we'll lift this up a little
bit you like that
no I'm glad that's in the middle when
I'm over here he's like watch out for
the teeth oo so what when do we make a
lot of noise and start torching us I
think you guys can torch anytime
I'm going to go up high and not to get
torched in the elbow yeah you almost had
it into the miror I will uh I can't
believe my finger didn't get burned dude
was right here by the way that's pretty
that's insane I mean I still have the
scar it's going to be a lifelong Scar
from the email I think you should show
him a picture of Mark's finger dude your
[ __ ] is hot holy SM no you want yeah
that thing gets you want it you want to
make sure it's hot enough you
do especially for
hash you ready all
[Music]
right
damn that was
acceptable holy
smokes that was a killer
rip so now what switch like it's like
the old te game something like that yeah
pass the pipe to the left hand side I'll
tell you no you can keep that pipe right
there the rip I got out of this one that
way the rip that this one gives
you I saw I saw that cloud bro I
watched was a nice blue color I'll tell
you I'll give you that one okay oo I'll
take it gladly happily look at all that
other stuff that's I got a to right here
we could talk about that Congo for a
second too sure
um didn't see the Melt Factor on it no
not a ton of melt well I couldn't even
see it but it sure got a nice feel to it
yeah it's got a nice taste nice taste
yeah it was older older dried mostly
flowers that's been that I've been
huffing on for about like sure gave me a
nice rock yeah like a rocker of a hit
yeah but that pipe is absolutely
astounding oh yes you just don't realize
it's such a it's such a huge can yes
with an
absolute ridiculous amount of water I
don't know if you guys can see how much
like like compared to a hand oh I know
the water's all the way up and the can
is very unique how far does the down
stem go though the down stem is massive
let's pull it it's a very big
downstep no I can see you don't need oh
you can do
it no no no don't pull
it don't pull it
up no because I can see it from this
angle yeah so that's I mean it just goes
below that first line yeah so you need
actually quite a lot of water in here
just side Ang careful this really does
does like move on this yeah it does like
unbelievable when I tipped it up the
tiniest bit and it did this little
wooo and was like
whoa watch out for the B well this is
always one of my favorites to hit this
little Mothership that is by far one of
my favorite pipes ever made like period
by any artist even if I beautiful little
piece it really is like just even after
seeing all the beautiful uh you know ftk
with with the marbles and all the
different Opals and this is just super
classy it is yeah Marcel you Marcel and
buck representing here it's it's it's
straight to the point it is you don't
have to put all this other bells and
whistles on it to make a beautiful pie
you don't totally the simp the round
Opals on it yeah are pretty tight you
know but even without those it would be
yeah it' be nice you know just the
workmanship solid stem on the inside
that's solid white it's the workmanship
what put into it you know mhm what the
people can't see is all the little air
bubbles and every little yeah the air
trapping is absolutely astounding in
every little cross-section Marcel
actually told me um he talked about the
r aellos and the air trapping and like
the history of it from Italy and they're
they're Venetian techniques and some of
the older families some of the more
ancient families that knew it if once
you came into the tutelage of the family
you literally were not allowed to leave
literally like you they would kill you
before you were allowed to leave because
of the the knowledge the sacred
knowledge being passed down to to the
individuals that were that were under
their tutelage so I mean like yeah like
these are ancient techniques like some
of the more modern techniques you know
like some of the stuff that buck does
make stronger you know I I don't I don't
know I don't think so I think it was
just to do with the actual difficulty of
it with the kind of tools and heat
sources that they had like they don't
have like crazy torches back in the
downgrading no I'm just look this Dow
it's still like a really nice piece of
quartz I got to say no it is I love Club
bangers but would you use a Club Banger
when you got one of those no I just
wanted to look at it of course not this
is you know beautiful with the cut too
yeah you see how the the oil is like oh
is it that one or the other one there's
see how the oil is right on the
underside of of the thing so you know
how I I borrowed your um purple Power or
whatever and Holland and you were like
make sure flab like these ones are I
know you do the the orange cleaner or
whatever to clean my pip the grunge off
yeah yeah the grung yeah yeah and U
purple Power I guess was the older stuff
but ument cuz Mark's always like dude
like you know like you do this a lot but
you know like you don't always clean
your pipes the best like make sure you
clean these ones really good you know so
I cleaned them really good like I I
cleaned them spotless but there was a
tiny little smudge of oil sitting on the
honey bucket and the [ __ ] s didn't
see it and they had me in there for like
2 and a half three hours looking at my
pipes like testing they were swabbing
them down yeah cuz never swab the bll
down oh they didn't they I told them
they were used so I was like I torched
all the the canabo I torched any resin
off of them so they actually took all
the buckets they took all the swings
they took all the pipes in Amsterdam no
in Vancouver o and they in yeah coming
back into Canada from Amsterdam time
like the ftk like they took it yeah and
they were just like and you were just
sitting there like deleting text
messages on your
phone they had my phone already actually
that's the most [ __ ] up
thing me to your phone I'm like no yeah
you got search warrant no then you can't
come to can I'll be like cool no problem
see you later you a getting my [ __ ]
totally dude you ain't even to get my
passport right now dude you already know
who the [ __ ] I am cuz you had nine hour
three hours from when I bought my ticket
all right we're going to try this one
now the 120 mhm
wonderful I me the 73 was darn to I did
I did see that show though which show
border customs oh Christ here in can the
one with Flav though where where he's
got 250k wor of glass and the guys like
they're all talking about it it's like
I've never seen anything like this like
I don't we're not even really sure how
to proceed with this and then they're
interviewing him he's like this is
$250,000 wor a glass I'm legal literally
out those door so this is ridiculous
that they're even talking to me about
this I'm a federal Exempted like it
would just be that's actually sort of
how it went down yeah it would just be S
well because it is listen I could
literally walk out into the airport go
right out front in the smoking section
where everyone's smoking their
cigarettes and burn the [ __ ] out of this
so why is there an issue you guys can
see clearly that I'm not I'm not trying
to hide it look and I said that I was
like I'm leg this one would have just ch
this one would have any of these this
one would have got him through they
would have broke that [ __ ] dude I
wouldn't even let them touch it no no no
this one won't be traveling across
International borders anytime soon
unless I driving if I'm driving after
getting [ __ ] searched like that
brother I wouldn't be traveling with my
[ __ ] either dude you know I've done you
have one and that's it that's what I the
the thing that I worry the most about is
if they they could say cuz like in
Canada technically another one it is
illegal like paraphernalia is illegal I
don't know if the viewers out there
Canadian viewers know that but it
technically is illegal paraphernalia at
the border well even in even to sell
paraphernalia to possess it know it's
true yeah well I'll tell you it's which
is kind of [ __ ] up cuz all these
beautiful [ __ ] we're smoking we're
smoking tobacco exactly yes tobacco use
yeah this is all tobacco resin all for
tobacco so uh and these pipes are
tobacco water pipes oh my
God so uh well we all know your I'm
going to fire up my tobacco
do you want the small one for that
little guy yeah you guys should this
one's so huge can I have the beine
please oh yes s right thank you forward
oh very
nice very good very good nice to Puff a
beautiful hash B exceptional glass C
good peeps good peep this is just the
beginning of a good long weekl long
adventure that we're going to be on so
you guys are going to see a lot of
footage from us in some fairly different
situations we'll see what what comes of
it all well I personally am very looking
forward to the bob sled on the Olympic
course I told Mark I'm I got a brand new
pen that's specifically designed for the
bob sled bro when I'm in the tuck I'm
going to be heing the pen bro mik says
that Pen's going to be gone in two
seconds I'm like there's no way bro I'm
going to hit that [ __ ] bro he's like I
want to hit it on the Bob slot I'm like
it goes 125 km an hour he's like what's
that like 20 M an hour or something no
like 75 yeah or 80 or 80 yeah
totally still fast it's very fast to be
on just a sled not in a vehicle no and
they luckily they they have a driver
right like I mean and they have a
trained
breaker we don't oh so we don't have to
we just sit in it I don't even
I don't even know if we get to go are
they going to tell you that you're going
to have break [ __ ] that bro dude like
you're on vacation bro you're on
vacation dude you don't want to be like
I'm going to be responsible for these
three other fools in the front it's only
the course where the dude died in the
Olympics I know that's what I'm that's
what makes it more interesting about
going but I don't want to be responsible
for you to you
know it's a fan Bob said right so we got
like
one two it's quite a course I've never
been down it but uh I'll bring the GoPro
hopefully we'll bring you guys with us
so you can see that and uh so cool from
that to the cat to the snowmobiling to
the the ice cave to the ice cave to the
back country snow you need a snowmobile
to get to the ice cave oh yeah okay
absolutely so all need to get a
snowmobile too snowmobile is essential
to get to the ice cave I'm thinking
about riding on the back of a snowmobile
nice well there's no home mobiling it's
just
m't it's just uh side by side is what we
do side by side yeah side by side what
side it means one guy's holding half of
the steering wheel in the middle and
he's standing on one side of the sled
and the other guy's over here holding
the other middle and the other cool
there's so one of your homies has the
cliff side you know that's not you know
what I'm saying give me the throttle
side dude so I can be
like I'm excited actually to do snow
I'm really excited from all the pictures
you've always showed in the videos and
everything like that it's one of the
things I'm obssed about it'll be some of
the most epic footage if we can get out
on the sleds even to just get simply out
to sprout or brandy wine which is just
the back country of Whistler just across
the seas sky highway on the other side
is so ridiculously beautiful my friend
Ryan's been posting photos for the last
couple of days and you can't even
believe how beautiful the photos are and
they're just taken with a cell phone h
so it and we'll bring this with us it'd
be very nice if we could get back there
no problem things like this travel well
in a little yeah totally we're just not
yeah not this guy I'm ready for my last
rip I think I'm going to go back to the
original Congo the 73 I'm going to bring
this around for you dude it's so easy
all okay it's like a gun just think of
it like this like and don't put it on
that mat cuz holy did it slide on that
mat it won't slide when you lift it up
on just table I think it's cuz there's
still like it's almost like there's like
condensation from the amount of water
that's sitting in the bottom of all I
know is I want to rewatch the video cuz
I want to see I don't even want to risk
this thing bro this thing's like dud
I'll take that one okay boom I'm all
about this one and this one can go over
to you and I'll take this one so just
literally like these are over here you
can just leave it up all right so it's
like a gun but don't touch anything yeah
don't pull the
trigger all right and you can have you
can have your your your your legal right
to bear arms arms
of joyousness not destruction yeah
actually that came up you know it's a
subject that we brought up tonight what
was that guns the gun the gun thing you
know the toy gun thing right toy gun
thing you know what what's okay in
Canada is not
necessarily okay in the United States
you might get shot for a toy gun yes you
know so that's so true I just encourage
uh playing with toy guns yes for sure
yeah period you know what my son never
even plays with him I don't know how
that thing got taken out of his toy
chest and out here for your daughter
dude your daughter was all over it like
she knows I've been trying to kill whoa
what no I'm just you know just it's just
like driving for the first time you got
to take a second you're good man you got
this you're professional you got this
professional as it comes
this
Okay it definitely is a learning curve
to hit all of flabs glass it all has
different little nuances and trips and
it's I don't know Singularity is it's
never bad to ask questions I love
Singularity we should just bring
Singularity up for the piece to be in
the Whistler middle of the table the
whole time it take you know come could
you imagine no that easier to bring them
who else is in Whistler right that one's
ridiculous who else is in Whistler right
now I got a big crew of friends that are
in Whistler that I'll be able to
introduce you guys all to I got a these
three brothers that I'm good friends
with Ryan and Ethan and Devon and
they're up there all the time living the
life of the snowboard
bum so is this all one glass artist or
is this a collab that one's buck and
Marcel essentially Marcel blue the
can and all the sections so Marcel made
made the sections and then Buck made the
like skeletal structure of the fish that
sort of um right yeah that's really his
his one of his major just the little
nonfunctional add-ons yeah dude all I
know is that piece is
ridiculous it's the piece that rocked me
the most oh
dude that last out was [ __ ] huge I
can tell you're cusing up a storm there
oh yeah bro I got mild hits out of this
one and this one but this one gave me an
absolute you got a really good hit off
that one this one has a really good hit
too yeah I just feel uncomfortable with
it because it's this one the torch it's
such artwork and functionable Y that
being said you know that you know it's
it's not mine and
money yes scary I like expensive pieces
is like that
size and it's the it's all the the like
the sharp Parts like the teeth and the
spines and the that those are the parts
that are it's just a matter of being
careful totally you know if you want to
hit fat glass and you want to be able to
appreciate it then just respect that
each piece deserves to be hid in a
particular way and the way you might
grab this piece is not the way will not
be the way you grab that piece that's
pretty fat though that opal right down
there dude so sick right and that takes
a while before you see that one same
with the eyes like ratachello Madness
yeah and there's another opal right if
you turn it around in the front yeah see
that right in the front it's so sick PR
czy right there too does this [ __ ] glow
under PL no it's it's not glow but well
it's sure damn near it's pretty though
pretty damn near impressive to me I'll
tell you the color the color other than
the r aello is Dee's
Darkness the classic Dee's Darkness you
hear a lot about that on the internet in
the glass forums people are chatting
about that color yeah well I think uh
we've done a good session of ripping
each one of these pieces each one time
very much so this is the first of many
we'll see you guys tomorrow for hash
Church which is uh Sunday 8:00 a.m. West
Coast time wake and bake and yeah we'll
be wake and baking with everyone and uh
after that I guess we've got one more
day here before we're going to head off
to Whistler so the Whistler Adventure
will start soon so
thanks for watching Bubble man's world
thanks Aaron from DNA and Flav 421 with
the Epic glass collection for for making
these videos possible that a good hat
yeah always thank the good hat good for
the Good Hat Congo
Bongo sharing is
caring
[Music]
peace