[Music]
hey welcome to work up here with John G
and we are at the vapor lounge on the
top floor right above the CC HQ found a
next door above and
so Peters banjo absolutely
impeccable piece of glass was puffing it
recently as you saw it's Animoto seven
John that has hit the larger piece
before but today we're going to hit mini
because the way that here I'll hold that
up so they could see porchetta
the dome right here upside down in my
head but it will be right side up when I
put it on I assure you
[Music]
always a pleasure to get such a
beautiful piece of art and of course
we're hitting the beautiful
ultra dry savanna
all right here we go
[Music]
watch out
an amazing
[Music]
now wait all that no here
the tiniest tiniest tiniest little
amount of water in there
yes all right let's eat yeah
definitely that
it's already a shelter
forget the
[Music]
the bowl is quite deeply yeah home so
you really want to dump it
[Music]
so real arts going to put the dog way
out I'll do the whole thing for you
basically take the rim
[Music]
that the plate
around us
[Music]
- nice little piece just hit so
beautifully
[Music]
thanks again last course you wanted to
let us Hansel to be nice
face
[Music]
hey what's up welcome back Bubba man's
world here with John be at the vapour
lounge upstairs and [ __ ] handle
availa G one of the pioneers against
that pioneer I'm told by split
underscore dabs on Instagram this is his
piece as a collector
all right that's very cool try to show
you guys following me of that little
piece really a small amount of water it
comes with a really nice dome
can't really see good in it so we put in
a gel form I saw it for me
we're gonna hit a little sweet scum
the great gardener he's trying to
remember all these things the shout out
simultaneously doing a little torch and
something you don't see me do very often
once again you see that it was like you
know
and the perk on this one particular it's
just so he'll tell you
there really is something to be said to
that smallest amount of water almost
like nothing is there at all but I think
one of the things
that he pushes up the bottom a slight
bit definitely give more access to the
water
[Music]
check them out it spliff underscore
NAB's on Instagram
[Music]