[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
today we have a bit of an exciting day
we're going to go see the great guys
over at high integrity glass art uh my
buddy higher end and I'm going to be
bringing Flav 421 who has been a part of
that as well from the beginning and uh
I'm actually going to purchase myself a
nice new Fab egg Mothership pipe um I'm
not really big into the Super heady you
know 2030 $40,000 ones but uh right now
Mothership Fab eggs are going for around
2 to 3,000 us and uh that's something
that I can kind of put my my investment
in uh my Straight Fab has done me
nothing but but Wonder uh I've traveled
all over the world with it I've smoked
uh with hundreds if not thousands of
people and I really love the hit of the
pipe the quality of the glass um
everything about it just feels good so
I've been waiting to get a Fab EG for a
while one's finally come up on the
market and uh I'm going to scoop it up
so why don't you guys follow me we'll go
pick up Flav and we'll head on down to
high integrity glass art hey hey hey so
I ended up picking up Mr flab 421 what's
going everyone and what are we doing
dude we are going to get a Fab egg for
bubble man dude how stoked are you oh
I'm very stoked stoked than me oh I
think I am I was waiting outside for
like you know he told me he was on his
way it takes him about 25 minutes to get
to my house I was already outside I was
so excited for this to happen it's true
it's true we just went into the tunnel
so you'll see a little bit of adjustment
there this is one of the only tunnels uh
big tunnels in Vancouver it's a pretty
substantial one that'll cut off your
phone call or cut off your your music
but uh yeah we're going to make our way
to highend Integrity glass and uh see
what they're saying that's right we'll
see later catch up with you guys in a
minute all right guys well we've made it
here to uh the wonderful high integrity
glass art thanks for having us here Ro
and Flav they've got the most epic
beautiful motherships out on the table
right now as well as this really
beautiful little
slime recycler and uh this is actually
you can get in touch with high integrity
glass art in regards to this little
piece it is for sale these two are
definitely not am I right about that
that is right correct and this one it
would actually be best guys if you
contacted me directly yeah just get in
touch with touch with flap hit me up on
on on kick or my Instagram page and this
is marbly coated uh Eric Anders Eric
Anders that's a real nice little piece
yeah for sure and it's not it comes with
more than this too I saw it had a little
Dabber and yeah it's it's a full set
comes with p
D has nice and clean as clean can be yep
got to like it well as you guys know I
am here to pick myself up a Fab egg
nothing nothing uh compared to the
quality of the two that they have right
here not that this is a Fab egg but this
Marcel is a Fab egg yes and one of my
favorites for sure this one is I said
the name of this and got attacked by
like 800 people on my YouTube channel
what did I call it I think I called it
the exosphere I believe it's a b EXO a
ball EXO okay well you heard it here
it's a ball Expo EXO he he believes so
please don't attack us if you are
slightly more obsessed about this than
us I don't know there are people very
obsessed what I'm saying like we we had
some what the first F kids right okay so
Scott called him an ftk I was at the
shop when he pulled him out I was one of
the first probably because it was the
order that they were all put in yeah and
now apparently they're called f
kts and some kid was going at me for a
little while about it saying like well
you know you should know the name man
like if you have one you should know man
you know what I got a little glimpse of
it when we were in Whistler and we had
everyone at the table and it was Aaron
and yourself and that that cool Mike
from pton and Christian well Christian
is into this like he had an indep like
he was just like you could tell that he
spends a good amount of time researching
it and focusing on it and it's it's
serious uh it's a serious way of
collecting people really has the love
for sure he's got I'd say he's got the
obsession and I don't say that as a
negative Christian keep up your
obsession it's uh it's it's contagious
and here I am buying a
Mothership egg so should we pull it out
or what sure pull up the
egg pretty exciting pretty exciting so
yeah you guys uh these as you know are
fairly difficult to find I've been
looking for one for probably 3 months
and I know these guys I know these guys
and I've been looking for one of these
for 3 months I wasn't looking very far I
was just looking for them to get me one
and and here it is here's one so I guess
we better open it up it's kind of
exciting isn't it oh it's very exciting
it's always nice when when more
Mothership joins and stay the family as
opposed to uh you know heading off to
other parts of BC or Alberta right yeah
no I feel that even though you know
probably end up hitting those ones too
eventually yeah well knowing you someone
will come by and actually bring it for
you to hit so it's possible I like the
idea that this particular piece will be
a very very very well-traveled
Mothership it'll be internationally
traveled it'll be internationally
traveled it'll probably be going to
Jamaica at the end of the month and if
it does it will be celebrating Bob
Marley's uh 70th birthday party down at
uh 56 Hope Road that's of course the
house that he purchased off of uh Chris
Blackwell when he kind of started making
it he really wanted to own that house
and that's actually the house that he he
ended his life in he he didn't pass in
that exact house but he lived there
right up until the time uh he passed
away amazing yeah so that's 56 hope Roo
and uh I was really excited to see
recently that my buddies the
nomads uh got um basically they are one
of three Bob Marley ambassadors for the
70th anniversary so you've got chronics
obviously chronics is one of the top
names in reggae music right now uh
kabaka pyramid also really really
powerful Lyricist and Conscious Reggae
artist and then finally the nomads which
uh I was really really stoked for man is
this beautiful just give that a little
gentle you don't have a bowl in there do
you I don't need one yeah comes with one
[Music]
oh look at that nice thin Little Neck
yeah
the the th the thinner mouth stems are
nice man is that nice yeah really really
sweet well I'm pretty excited to slam a
denail into this now Dave and I we are
uh federally exempt obviously so we are
able to give it a little shot and uh man
what an unbelievable
beautiful little piece of glass I'm
still excited about clear ones oh yeah
no but I mean I really am I'm not even
joking I'm there's only so many of these
but the level of precision and
Perfection like we were talking about
function everything like every single
one is perfect and if it's not it
doesn't leave the shot yeah it is
perfect like the the the level of
precision the level of quality it's
Second To None anyone it's awesome dude
yeah I mean they're the Rolls-Royce of
of of of of glass this is a very like
perfect egg I have to say Dam near might
be one of the most perfect ones I've
ever
seen wow I mean I appreciate you guys
for having these and I love the fact
that collectors are out there and
they're giving the you know they're
putting the amount of money in that that
in a sense well whether you want to
think it's deserved or not obviously uh
Mothership and some other artists out
there have taken this art form to the
next level where in our society how we
usually acknowledge that is in the
rising of prices and I mean you guys
have very much so these got to be two of
the most beautiful motherships on the
planet I know they've got a fair amount
of them but really this is I'm just
happy that I can come visit you guys and
and have a rip on these every once in a
while well since we enjoy sharing them
so much with quality people it's always
a pleasure to have you I think I'd be
more nervous traveling International
borders too oh I would say so like
[Music]
this just roll into Barcelona
well you should have seen the look on
the on the custom guard's faces when I
came back with the with the aridium ftk
and they were like okay so cuz I said
like they were like do you use this I
was like yeah it's fully used but it's
cleaned and they were like it's cleaned
cuz you know what happens if it's not
clean right I was like oh yeah you guys
will arrest me you'll confiscate that
I'll never see it again blah blah blah
blah blah blah blah and they were like
yeah that's right and they were like so
still though it's used I was like yeah
it's cleaned it's used it's cleaned it's
all good but then after they took it
away and swabbed it and did all their
things they started talking to me about
it and like the value of these things
and like how they're made and all that
kind of stuff and they actually found
out quite fascinating wow yeah I had a
good hourong conversation with the
Border guards about the glass world I'm
glad that it came to that you were able
to get through get all your pipes back
into Canada and just have uh no real
experiences cuz that would have been
that must have been really hard for you
cuz he didn't have one piece or two or
three or four I'm pretty sure he had
like nine or something nine or 10
super super heady pieces that you take
over the Border not as heavy as the
sublimator roar though yeah apparently
that well you know what sorry
sorry it's true the real reason that the
sublimator rure will take first place
over uh pieces of this um Quality is the
simple fact that it's the only piece in
the entire competition that everyone's
hitting
the whole cup and this year the cup was
canell so it was it was even more so the
only place that people could go was to
the greenhouse and try it so it was and
and as the dampering gallery is a
little step back because it doesn't have
the exposure that a coffee shop would
cuz if you're going to the gallery
you're going to see art you know you're
going to buy something you're going to
go and look at the pipes you're going to
go and look at the t-shirts true they
don't have this the hang no yeah exactly
the like the Conant walk through you
know but other than that I mean we
actually did have quite a lot of
visitors this time around I think it was
great I think the dam cring was in a
position that they could have become
even more oh that they could you know
they will yeah building it I think the
Cup this year not to get off topic um
but it was almost like an old '90s cup
because of the way it was broken up and
because there was no main venue it was
like oh you could go to all these little
shops it would have been cool if all of
the people who had booths were able to
go and get and set up in a coffee shop
so if you had like Som and myself and a
couple others in Amnesia or you had do
you know what I'm saying and then you
just have a list you have your you have
your little because nowadays we know
that the herb itself isn't enough to
bring the people to each shop but if you
had like hit man at this place and you
had Som at this place and you had you
know what I mean like all of these over
here exactly you know emotech held it
down at the noon and that was pretty
cool those guys were really pretty much
the whole time at the we did one little
video there and it was good um yeah I
pretty much want to get this thing
watered up and do a little water test
show you guys a close-up video of that
and uh maybe we'll have a little session
we'll see what happens I think we might
have
to thanks
dude okie dokie well session time inde
dud clear egg dude I'm telling you break
it in break the
Cherry feel this thing Rumble oh it does
like when you put your your fingers just
on the bottom of the
Bas There's an actual emotion to it yeah
but the glass almost wants to move when
you chubble it up so pretty excited here
I got to say um I brought some hash but
jeez you got you have so much hash here
we might as well hit a little bit of it
oh what do we got here nice little patty
just got handed to me so I'm going to
have to uh hit that we got the denail
turned up to 738
got the puking be quartz bowl with the
16 mm I don't hit the 16 very often it's
very small but this dab will be perfect
for that so here we go breaking in the
Fab egg high integrity glass
art if you guys uh if you're in uh BC or
you're in Alberta or Western Manitoba I
mean um there's a high demand and
limited availability but always contact
us if you are interested in getting a
hold of some other show I can attest
these guys can hold it
down oh
yeah wow I really like that that's
incredible look at one little little bit
of reclaim already on my on the top on
the top of my
hand well that tasted really good and I
know people are going to ask me so what
I'll do is I'll I'll write it in the
comments when I find out out what it was
it it was a little Congo
esque Cho
esque uh sweet sweet
cono sweet skun and Congo there you go
wonderful the uh the combination of
those two I think can only be a win-win
of course I was lucky enough to check
out uh Remo's sweet skunk the other day
in fact I
brought in that little pouch right there
um Remo's buds if you guys want to roll
yourself up joint or if you just want to
look through them and smell them those
were grown with Remo's nutrients cool
and uh a lot of people ask me if Remo's
nutrients are organic I would say
absolutely not um however I have to say
all the stuff that I've ever um used
from Remo whether it's been vaporized or
made dry sift or made wet washed it's
been on point so you know I of course
I'm a bit of a purist I do prefer um
organic outdoor sungrown tropical IAL
Jamaican resin but that's not saying
that that's all I ever
hit I know that uh years ago there was a
sweet skunk outdoor crop done and it was
unfortunately not flashed and so it was
beautiful sweet skunk bud but when you
rolled it up and tried to burn it uh it
would burn with a very black ash so I
took the same um material almost a pound
of it and turned it into some really
lovely hash and the hash smoked with a
white ash
perfectly was only the flower material
right that was that was holding I guess
what I'm saying is that through my own
bioassay my own hyper awareness I'm very
sensitive like if someone lit a
cigarette I would feel ill speaking of
someone who smokes cigarettes I can I'm
trying to quit trying to quit but me and
Mark Travel often and when I smoke 20
minutes later all come into the room
it's been 20 minutes 20 minutes for sure
no one else can smell a thing and you've
been outside the whole time the whole
time totally and wearing a jacket with a
sweater and I'll take my jacket off I'll
sit down nextor he can still smell so I
will definitely attest to that I'm
telling you my old factory is has been
off the chain for a long long time yeah
it's pretty H hyper intensive I'm going
to get a little
congoo goodness that thing rips
wonderfully it really does I mean I'm uh
it really does I'm pretty excited about
this it's
uh lovely
just [ __ ] holding it
down and you know what it's good that
there's a company like high integrity
glass art who's bringing it to BC
because so many people want this trust
me on this guys there are enough people
down in the US that want this that if
Mothership and Scott deppy uh weren't
you know decided they didn't want to
send them up to Canada they could easily
get rid of them down in the US so I
think it's very generous that a I'm
stoked that these guys have created a
relationship with Mothership and done
good enough business and had a good
enough relationship that they continue
to send um these beautiful pieces up
here thank you it's very fair it is but
I mean also
like like we there's a love for the art
a love for the artist a true
appreciation for the art itself which is
why you know like prices
aren't hyper exaggerated or overextended
to the point you know where where where
some like online internet sales and
stuff like that some sometimes it can be
like that but you know so there's like a
love and appreciation both ways between
the artists and us so well I'm
completely baked the battery's about to
die I've got a brand new Fab Egg and I
just want to say thanks guys D and uh
you'll be seeing a lot more of this and
check out high integrity glass art
Facebook YouTube Instagram in
Instagram
[Music]
[Applause]
peace
[Music]
he
[Applause]
[Music]
n
for