[Music]
hey how's it going bubble man here uh
I've been filming my uh YouTube videos
with my good camera lately but it's
taken a long time to upload them so I'm
going to give you guys some mini
episodes of what's going on right now we
are in a little makeshift hash making
room right now we've got uh a nice
little pile of Bud right here and a
bunch more right here I'm guessing we
must have I don't know 4 lb or something
3 or 4 lb uh mostly popcorn Buds and
what we're doing is we're basically
gently we've got them out on the um 200
Lines no the 100 lines per inch yes 110
lines per inch which is a 140 Micron
screen it's a silk screen that's
extremely tightly uh glued to the frame
and what we do is we just gently bring
the buds back and forth ever so gently
not squeezing them not being too violent
with your work and uh what this is going
to do is it's going to give us a single
screen extraction which by lifting the
screen up you can see there's a light
sift there and even in the corner I've
got a pile of gold over there already
it's nice slow work we're not trying to
beat the [ __ ] out of this material uh
like the Moroccans do with sticks to the
point where it's giving us you know 95%
contaminant we're really trying to
gently extract just the heads and from
there we're going to do the secondary
process and we're going to do it outside
because that process is this is good to
do outside as well it makes the the
heads more brittle but the secondary
process of caring the material over the
screen and pushing that contaminant
through the tighter hole while leaving
the gland heads on top of of the mesh
it's um yeah it's a little bit of a
easier process much easier when done in
cold uh the capitate stocks and the cyth
hairs just seem to break much more uh
readily when it's very cold so stay
tuned for all of that and uh yeah we'll
be making more hash here
soon
f