all right well there we are live on
Facebook Johnny B and Bubble Man puff
Wednesdays uh I'm going to have a real
quick rip here a quick
[Music]
R it just came up here in my phone that
we're
live we're live we should check it
out
live welcome Joe mountain man
this is what we're
hitting that is indeed what we're
hitting things are good how's everyone
doing welcome to Tom aderman and
Stephen and everyone else that's rolling
through wow that was dark though hey
like look at that it went
red just cleaning the Banger welcome
Darren Cochran Curtis
fuks hope everyone's having a good day
Johnny B and I we just filmed a
wonderful puff Wednesday did we not
Johnny B here I feel like I'm Too Tall
let me get down on the level just
filming live is there any way to suck
the smell it smells yeah just filming
live right now on uh Facebook but I can
absolutely do that I will absolutely do
that for you in 2 minutes all right just
the wife requesting I take care of
business here real quick so we'll make
this a short Facebook live let's clean
this Banger this cleaning solution I
can't say enough of Welcome Keith bu
right into the Banger it
goes a quick couple of little little
wraps and there she blows so how's
everyone doing out there Greg The
Hoot coming in from the UK well-known
cannabis activists out there and patient
in his own
right I hope everyone's doing good I
just got a really nice dab and I think
that it's time for me to give Johnny B a
really nice
dab yeah we just filmed a really nice um
puff Wednesday do you have some of that
rosin present that I can show them I
know you just show it but here's some of
the batter that we
made uh dry sift
rosin it's just like cake batter
absolutely stupendous death Bubba made
from some uh dry sift that came from uh
from a buddy's trim bin correct that's
correct Johnny got it directly off of
them today and it was scraped it was uh
trimmed up last night and then I got it
today and then uh next thing you know
hey and what TP would you like my friend
my friend um star dogs Sunset sherbet
Jack Frost Clementine and
Tangi Tangi I just light something light
not not so hard on Clementine Clementine
Tommy West just joined Tyler Marino just
about to give Johnny B A TP dip on some
of this dry sift rosin I took the dry
sift I separated it out into about three
or four different piles and then we took
a couple of those piles uh and we
pressed pressed them out actually I'll
give you the dab because it is on the
um Titanium Dabber
ah thought the torch wasn't working for
a second there I'm also trying to set up
equipment to fix my phone because this
happens yes we're doing multiple things
here we're troubleshooting guys bear
with us they say what's up Johnny B I
the one Clementine that's the one ma
team he hit the Clementine it's a little
a little lighter than this the Tangi
still beautiful citrusy taste just not
quite as much of a intensity look at
that looks pretty Co look at the colors
all that side oh yeah his phone is
pooched pooched pooched journy B needs
to fix his [ __ ] let me tell you just
getting this Banger nice and clean and
last little bits of remnants I like to
just torch them out of
existence yes indeed so we'll give that
a go check this out Johnny on the
computer here
boom got my 55 second timer like you
like that I knew you would like that so
this is your dab in fact my dab but he's
giving me the dab because he's got the
titanium going into the new Corner yeah
I don't want the titanium getting moved
around I'll just hold it against the
wall and then gently pull it out what
temp did you press your rosin okay well
we pressed uh the first batch was at
about 220 then we pressed the flowers at
about
180 so we had like a 40 degree
difference between the the flower rosin
and the dry sift rosin both are
incredibly tasteful I do have the OG
straight Fab that's not gone anywhere
moving this real quick here we go
there's the OG straight fab right there
going to put that up for sale in the
very near future up on my Instagram let
someone else own a part of History I'm
not as attached to to these clear pieces
although this little sub eight Klein is
on point let me tell you really [ __ ]
liking it absolutely t I have very much
so been enjoying it all right Johnny B
you're good to go want to get this I'm
in the mid of yeah I'm got to come down
here put it to your mouth and do
whatever you got to do because your rip
is perfect look at that just explosion
in there Jesus Louise Johnny B with the
winning hit you couldn't see it because
the bong's too low he's leaning down but
I'm telling you it fogged up very lovely
that was a big
rip
good boom boom boom Shaboom
excellent amazing uh well I would love
to get you a rig James Smith let me know
what uh what you want and we might be
able to make that
happen so many lovely rigs out there
it's nice too I love the the way the
motherships uh sell people can collect
them and move on from them and then you
know another person can come along and
collect them and enjoy them so it's one
of the unique things motherships really
done it's I mean really motherships put
that game back in glass in the sense it
really really I've mentioned it on my
last Facebook live how I want to really
get into this space this Bubble Man
space opening up a proper space in
Vancouver you know with a nice high-end
restaurant and a vapor lounge and a shop
where you can buy all the bubble tools
and the dry sifting tools have a demo
area where you can actually make hash in
a walk-in freezer have a studio where we
can film have um a high-end Glass
Gallery where we can do Mothership shows
and Japan shows and Philly shows and
Cali shows just I think it would be Co
yeah something I'm [ __ ] stoked to get
back into uh you know because I was back
I was into that in uh early 2000 mid
2000s before I closed my gallery that
was a big part of what we were doing I
still have a lot of those relationships
too so God this [ __ ] gets the Banger
clean right there guys it gets the
Banger
clean I love it make sure that Banger is
clean clean clean
clean you know both sides too because
yeah stuff gets on the inside stuff gets
on the
outside so what's going on yeah are you
slumping John yeah I'm slumping I'm
trying to deal with the phone here and
Stu like that no someone said homie in
the back is
slumped you should have seen John yeah
lemon drop Mega pot Ryan with the blue
dial and the ofc I took some really nice
photos of it with my macro lens today so
I'm going to post those today today in
the mothership
room yeah Ross that's what I'm talking
about a real high-end restaurant but
with a really beautiful gallery and all
these other aspects where you could go
or you could be in the gallery or the
restaurant and you can see on the TVs
maybe me and John are in there he's
busting out some sift I'm busting out
some bubble has maybe we're making some
rosin I want to have all my friends be
able to come by and use that studio film
bring people in and create a really cool
Vibe where we also have super high-end
glass shows so John are you medicated I
am very medicated
here look at us you're Shar you're on a
Facebook live with us ignore those
idiots I'm just trying to get an
appointment 6 I'm not until December
27th like like really oh my gosh well
that's you know that's reasonable if you
don't do it now then it's going to even
be a later weight can I just go in and
just walk in let's get some of that cake
batter dude can I walk in somewhere
actually no this is the cake batter I
somewhere you might be able to yeah look
at this look at this flower Ros and cake
batter that Johnny B and I pressed out
earlier with a single press we just
pressed it you can't you can't even
bloody see it it's so
light I think I need a little dab of it
though what do you say Johnny
B oh my
God it is ridiculous it was fun to make
this with you it
was there we go here tast it little dab
a
doodle Heat this up may you have a rosin
when was the last time you puffed on
flour oh my God I don't
know I mean I guess in Toronto I I I lit
that spliff that was the the Cuban hash
cigar thing but it was mostly like 90%
concentrates dryft Rosen bubble hash
tpin the whole n yards but there was
like a leaf or something wrapped all
around it so I guess in a sense that was
kind of like the closest I've come to
hitting flowers in a long
time token daily days hey Darren's in
the room bong rip Mother Lover we are
getting down dude we are getting down
bro about to hit this [ __ ] like it owes
us money and isn't
paying yeah Daren always adds that one
because you know what it's accurate to
add that one dry sift rosin no so here
we go we're going to hit the timer real
quick again boom and we got the 502
timer on mother lovers yes yes I'm about
to hit some beautiful beautiful flower
rosin that we made dryft RA in and the
dryft RW in D check this out [ __ ] is
thick this has got to be like five four
4.5 G or something five yeah five G very
nice very nice Johnny be a little dabado
do look at those eyes Johnny B's eyes
are just closed he's not even opening
them anymore they're so [ __ ] peeled
yeah pretty much John is on the moon
yeah pretty much yeah pretty much 21
seconds
left yeah you know what TP burping
that's not true do you think flower
rosin is the most turpy out of all the
out of all the rosins John um come on we
tested the flower rosin versus the dryy
sift rosin that I DRFT rosin was the
kill dude come on 80 80% heads dry sift
rosin is more
intense tasting like the flour than the
flower rosin is I'm telling you most
people have just never cleaned dry sift
up to that level and then run it but I'm
telling you it is by far the most
[ __ ] on point it was so worth the
clean and press that's for sure we
didn't even try smoking it we just
pressed it up right
that was it it was just like a d deal
done of course you know it's just
amazing nice hits clean refreshing
tasty wow so good telling you really
that's just [ __ ] delicious and you
guys can see I'll give you a little look
into the into the uh thing here nice low
temp dab you we're puddling over here
there's not there's nothing else going
on but straight [ __ ] puddling over
here I'll have you know and so that's
what you want that's how you want to see
your Banger you definitely like earlier
in the puff Wednesday actually I'll tell
you guys it's funny I torched the bowl
real clean and then I gave it to John
and we did the timer but the timer
wasn't enough and of course John took
this rip and it was the first time this
Banger and I've been religiously
cleaning this Banger it was the first
time this Banner Banger literally got a
burnt like caked not black but Brown for
sure I've been doing nothing but uh low
temp
um you know TP hits that are just like
super still prevalent in the bowl drippy
like that John hit it burnt the [ __ ]
bottom of it and I was like the puff
Wednesday will be funny cuz you'll see
me biting my lip trying not to get upset
but being like okay I got the new
cleaning solution that dark crystal
glass cleaner I got it right here I'm
going to [ __ ] just patiently clean
and John what happened on the third one
that I put into the bowl you remember it
just lifted off like this dude the whole
it it was pretty amazing how it was to
witness how it all happened and stuff
like that like I said I'm trying to do
this little Live Chat thing that you I
mean waiting for did the update on the
phone and all this trying to get this
all figured out for the last like hour
so I'm just like now he's like well I'm
like you know what I'm nice and relax
from the h yeah the pipe is hitting hey
Wood Thrush Needler just joined us
welcome wood rush and Rand Corp is with
us as well what is the solution it's a
natural um mostly uh non-chlorinated
water Kanga oil processed coconut
extract processed kelp extract and
process extract of sugar cane those
three extracts how they're extracting it
and what they're doing with that those
three combinations I think is also an
important part when the quartz is really
hot and you put it on the Q-tip and you
drop that in there it's the water that
steams and it's very much like the way
the steam from bud and hash is steaming
out the resin from azin press this
process seems to very much so Steam and
create this you know agitation that
carries the the the dirt resin or
whatever away from the glass and if you
check out DC glass on his Instagram he's
got a couple of videos where he Heats
this stuff up like he gets it real hot
and then puts glass into it cuz it
doesn't work cold and basically he gets
this really really incredible product
you see the oil dripping and moving away
from the glass I was sold the second I
saw it hit my courtz Banger Anyway full
Madness going on outside of my house I
think my dog's barking there's kids
showing up but uh it's Christmas it's
the holiday season friends you got
everything like that you know what it's
great seeing everybody no James Patrick
trust me baking soda works nothing like
this [ __ ] I can honestly say it works
like nothing I have ever seen and how
easy it is I don't know if you're
hitting quartz bangers but if you are
it's just so easy it's super inexpensive
I'm definitely giving it a two thumbs up
I put it in little vials and carry it
around with me so I'm not going to be
carrying this giant bottle with me each
time but there it is again for those of
you that want to see it I am not a owner
of the company this is just [ __ ] that
works exactly Rand well contact Mitch
it's made in Canada um his name is Dark
Crystal glass so if you Google Dark
Crystal glass you'll be able to link up
with him and uh Dark Crystal glass
exceptional resin lifting power sa for
acrylic glass and quartz I'm sold hey
doesn't matter where you are dude it's
the internet they sell this [ __ ] all
over the place what do I use to press my
rosin ask question well let's show them
real quick here what we got set up for
pressing
rosin all right so first of all you're
going to want to get a decent um air
compressor so we got the DeWalt 15
gallon goes up to 200 PSI you don't need
that I stick it at about 80 and of
course right here on the top of my desk
with John's C coffee is um my rosin
press uh from Sasquatch
sasquash so got the magnets up here for
when when we have the parchment inside
the plates the plates are customade
Bubble man's world plates so shout out
to soil grown Phil for uh for busting
that out for me I'm looking forward to
the V2 very very
fun pneumatic is better by far T burping
it's your opinion you know your opinion
but I can tell you that uh I'm very very
very much enjoying my sasquash and uh I
would say the opposite that I have used
pneumatics I've used manuals I've used
all sorts of different ones and I just
love the sasquash I love the custom
plates I love sasqua uh the soil grown F
Phil s and how he's promoted and really
started this and I think it's important
to
support support the people that have
popularized and made you know made that
push and done some form of innovation or
been a part of the timing that you know
[ __ ] I mean shout out to that guy for
sure the least I can do is love his
product when it works great we pressed
out damn near six grams of beautiful dry
sift rosin today that uh was super super
super on point yeah soil grown is
awesome dude [ __ ] awesome dude yeah
Todd I've just uh ordered six of them
myself going to be wholesaling them in
Canada so anyone that uh uh whatever's
turp branding here I got an idea boom
there we go just get rid of that guy
real quick cuz he's kind of bringing my
vibe down uh breett Maverick hair
straightener Vice Tech yeah well Johnny
Be hair straightener Vice Tech he's also
on the hair straightener Vice Tech it
works but you know what I mean
definitely this house clch works a lot
better um I like how to be able to
control the temperatures and I can see
the different ways of the product is
being dude we straight made cake batter
today I know straight cake batter and
and I'm you know like with me I've done
the squishing with this at home when
that came up very clear more like like a
different type of texture and stuff like
that so
absolutely definitely and turbines and
everything you get to see that it's kind
of interesting pretty cool Darren beat
it I know were you feeling that guy it's
like T burper just coming in and try
trying to cause some problems eh there's
always someone wanting to come in and
start [ __ ] up are we really that worth
coming in and starting [ __ ] with oh I
like a press you better come in and say
it's not a good press and you better
tell me what one is the better one and
how I'm wrong oh my goodness it tastes
super loud I'm telling you guys super
[ __ ] loud I got my little pieces here
from Johnny B look how crazy the flower
rosin turned out it's like I'm going to
take some pictures of that with my macro
lens and you guys are going to see
straight [ __ ] Beauty should I do it
right now it's amazing look at my macro
lens is right here and we're doing a
Facebook live why don't we take some
macro photos why wouldn't we Johnny Be
honestly macro photos I think I'm going
to do it you know what Happ is this mine
uh that is
yours it is absolutely yours Johnny B is
this mine the infamous is this mine all
right I'm just curious it's absolutely
yours
dude look at that
that's pretty like epic cake batter can
you guys see that
or cake
batter anyway you guys will see it
better later oh you don't even know I
haven't even opened it up yet here now
that is one hell of a camera well steo
la we're just uh We've pulled out this
ridiculous macro lens that Nassau sent
over and uh we're taking some close-ups
of this rosin that we pressed through
the sasquash rosin press um yeah that's
what we're doing we're taking some macro
pictures of the caked out buttery
battery goodness over here and uh we're
of course going to share it with you
people as we can maybe through the
Facebook maybe through YouTube maybe
through this live chat I'll see what
happens it's not easy let me tell you
just trying to get this guy
to oh my God just as it just as I was
about to get
it well right off the bat you know what
I can see through it I can see that
there's a little hair on
it that's just settling of the dust in
the room that's where it's coming from
you got to keep all your stuff covered
up so that way you don't get anything
particulars are definitely going to just
run right towards your resin so always
make sure you have it covered up and you
know what just sitting up for like
five minutes yep that's all it takes
it's okay we got rid of it real
quick we don't need
it so this is definitely like a
challenge of challenges I'm change the
lighting can I do that and put it
towards the resin need to turn in and
down there you go that's better I just
don't want to
touch I think I'd rather shoot from this
angle not easy what we're doing here I
can see the work trying to give a little
bit of you know little
all right so here we go right over top
of
it it's not
easy
me tell you what I'm going to photograph
this you talk to those guys that way
we're both not focused on the same thing
so you know what is actually pretty cool
to sit here and watch how he's just how
how how the camera work works and how
actually can see it through the eye cuz
I get to see it personally all the time
which is kind of cool right
you know definitely it was pretty cool
to go to the Garden take a look at the
way these guys wow um to take that's
pretty damn cool but
anyways let's see if we can show it to
them you guys see that
[ __ ] oh my God yeah I should strap into
that thing Sor to cut you off Johnny you
keep going Chris Ortiz is saying hello
that was just so sweet looking it it is
pretty amazing it looks pretty damn nice
kind of impressed with how crazy that
looks no it's it's definitely in the way
it's it's like yours mine was just left
in between the parchments so it's kind
of like it's it's going to flake up and
stuff like that yeah yeah yeah well it's
buttered out good already yeah Rosen
failed Rosen
failed Ros and fail I don't know what
that means but I know these are Ros and
fail got on there dude very cool [ __ ]
resin for photographing it's definitely
fire we got some good fire here it was a
pretty good press you'll definitely see
it tomorrow right yeah
100% so creamy and so buttery I'm going
to have to stand up and take a few
pictures here while Johnny B talks to
you right Johnny B I guess I'm talking
to you guys you know what well what
basically what this was it was a resin
that came from a trim bin um and that
was freshly trimmed just yesterday or
like it was yesterday it was gathered up
and put into a little plastic bag and uh
then I uh proceeded to come over here
today because I left the little bag of
buff death Bubba here last week and uh
we were going to squish that out so this
is actually from the bag itself the weed
that I left behind and the rest that
were particularly taking a look at it
was roughly n g
of was that n gs of Bud 9.2 G of Bud and
we 1.9 or 2 G of 1.8 G of overall so
roughly about a 20% return yeah it's
pretty awesome which is pretty good you
know what I mean so overall you know
what it looks pretty good really happy
with it it's nice for Christmas so it be
kind of a nice little keep away stuff
like that and yeah you know what just
kind of works out pretty good hell yeah
it does well you know what I'm getting
absolutely wonderful beautiful creamy
pictures I'm going to put some up on
Instagram I'm going to put some up on
the Facebook and uh in the meantime
Johnny Be and I are going to finish our
uh visit here going to edit up the puff
Wednesday thank you guys for hanging out
and watching and we will see you all
very soon so peace out yes you got it
Louise