[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh it's been a while since I put up a
video I know I've been pumping out the
hash churches every Sunday but I have
been very busy lately and trying to get
some new products uh on the up to on the
market uh as well as working out with
some different Consulting gigs and of
course constantly trying to promote uh
the JAMA project that we started last
year uh along with our partners uh and
United cannabis so all of these things
are sort of coming to a head and there's
you know they beginning here and they're
beginning there and I finally wanted to
get this video out uh I got this new
product in about a week ago um these are
of course the Rosen bags um I've got
three sizes here we've got the 4 in x 5
in which you can see right here and it's
just a nice little screen pouch that you
can put your product in I've got my
medium size uh which I have at about uh
3 in by 4 in uh this Micron screen is 32
Micron so I've moved away uh from the 25
and I've gotten the 32 Micron uh which
I'm able to offer at a better price uh
and of course I don't think people are
really interested in paying you know
seven eight $9 a piece for these I
currently have these up on the site you
10 in a pack with the pouch and the
label and uh it's 40 bucks so they're
four bucks a piece and of course they're
very very very reusable um and then the
smallest ones which I think are going to
be very very popular this is really the
hair straightener size right here these
two although I'm sure you could get that
into a a one of the wider hair
straighteners just um I find that these
two are really going to be for the Press
uh this one for the 5x5 that we have
right here and this one I would suggest
to use on the larger press all the
although I might try to fold it up in a
way where we can get off one Press today
this is also a 90 Micron bag uh the
larger style a lot of the people that
will be using this larger style are
going to be packing it full of hash uh
those that are going to be using it for
Bud uh good friend Rufio from the
advanced rosin Tech group was mentioning
that he prefers a 90 over a 120 maybe it
was a 120 over a 90 I can't really
remember now but uh we'll make sure we
confirm with him later we've got custom
sizes available of course if anyone want
wants uh more than uh 200 singles I can
do any Dimensions that you want in most
microns that you would request uh
depending on what you want to do just
hit me up at bubbleman bubble bag.com
and make the subject Rosen bags all in
capital and I'll be able to give you a
quote there so I guess today what I
really wanted to do was squeeze off a
couple of batches I've got my new paper
here that I'm going to be using instead
of parchment now I don't know the name
of this yet as I'm still basically
researching it along with Tony who sent
it to me uh it's his release so I'm just
using the material uh you can ask as
much as you want inside the comments but
I won't be able to tell you what it is
cuz I still don't know what it is I
thought it was a Teflon sheet it is not
a Teflon sheet uh hit up Tony vura T
verzura on Instagram if you really want
to know he might tell you but uh I think
we're first going to be making it as uh
sure as a safe product as possible
before we let people know the Nam so I'm
going to be doing a squeeze initially I
think we will do uh one of these with
some nice hash in it as well as a
packing it full of herb I think the
majority of people let's be honest are
using these smaller batches uh to
squeeze herb a lot of people are
squeezing bud and I know that you don't
necessarily need a screen if you're
going to be squeezing your rosin out of
your bud but it's definitely comes in
handy if you want to have the clean
clean clean and you don't want to spend
uh a very long time picking out
particulate from your rosin uh that got
in there from the bud so of course a
small little screen like that is easy
now it's got a very small hole to fit in
so what I would suggest doing for people
is you get a business card like this one
here my bubble bag business card fold it
in half sort of stick it in like this
and then you'll be able to uh easily
fill that little bag say if you wanted
to pack it full of some ground up herb
that you had it would uh it would pretty
much pack pretty nice like this
this there we go I love efficiency it's
just my favorite thing so I'm not sure
if I'll pack all of this in here I'm
sure I could if I wanted to I'm not a
big bud uh squeezer I haven't squished a
lot of buds I really have mostly uh been
doing hash we'll slide that out right
like that and then you can see you have
a nice little pouch uh full of
Bud so basically why don't we turn on
our press
all right so a good thing to make sure
when you turn your uh Dil press on is
that you have it lowered to the proper
um
size yeah that should do good for mebe
one little half unscrew you always want
to make sure it's good when you're on
camera especially so a lot of people
were using my uh pressing screens these
are the original pressing screens from
the bubble bag kit and uh that's what
people have been using
uh to press out their rosin right now
but I found that it was more efficient
for us to produce a product for them
make it a less expensive and uh easier
to use with the sewing it is a pain in
the ass when you only have them folded
uh the folds uh can potentially open
quite easily so turned on the denail
Press it's already at 30° C uh it heats
up quite fast this one of course is
going to go to about
120 125 and that will be a good 240 to
250 fahit I usually don't really go much
uh hotter than that um we should also
pull out some of going to want to press
some
bubble we got some
OG we got some pink so we've got uh some
bubble that we're going to be pressing
as well I'm going to use some more of
this Lindsay OG she got a real nice
color on her in there you can see real
light tan color uh a Sol four star
bubble you know by no means a five or a
six but a solid four real nice enjoyable
flavor and taste and uh while it presses
out unlike uh anything I've really seen
let me see if I can really just show you
a little a little of the cured out
lindsy OG rosin that I made oh this must
be a couple of at least a couple of
weeks old now so
that's that's the quality that we're
dealing with right there you can see
that's pretty pretty much the goods
right there squeezed out of one of these
little pressing screens and uh so I want
to show you both today basically I want
to show you um the process being done
with hash and I want to show you the
process being done with uh some bud now
this Bud here I would wager that it is
not a lot it's very light and
powdery we can throw the one of these
screens on the scale real quick and
that's a04 so we'll tear that and then
we'll throw that on and this is 2.5
g 2.5 g of
cannabis and it's nice to be able
to if you've already got your thing
heated up it's not a bad idea to just
just close the
top you can you can see that right there
how it just folds over real nice and I
still have a little bit of room for the
bud to actually expand so we're not
going to be popping anything out
and uh we'll just get it on either side
of our sheath
here and we'll do a little squeeze and
we'll see what we can get here off of
uh off of a little uh Bud the bud by the
way for those of you that were for sure
going to ask is my 20-year-old Bud
20-year-old seed from Jamaica see if you
can see that without the reflection in
the camera and uh this is from Johnny B
John Bell was such a kind dude he gave
this to me for one of my birthday days
this was the first Bud he grew he was
one of the first people I gave the Clone
to of the 20-year-old Lamb's bread
Jamaican and uh I have a bag of it it's
you know 100 G or so but it's mostly
been powdered and and broken down so I
thought why not we'll use that uh and
we'll show them what we can get out of
uh out of that so let me just make sure
yeah this is
closed give it that gentle little First
Press going
in
and here we
go it's got a 9C timer on it I love this
little denil press with the
timer I can just just starting to hear
it now after about 6 to 7
seconds I like to use my ear because I
can really hear what's going on with the
Press I can hear it squeezing out resin
and uh let's give that an opening real
quick all right so
oh yeah nice little squish of buds by
anyone's
standards decent little squish I'm
guessing there'll be at least a half a
gram there uh out of uh our 2 and 1/2 gr
that we put in so it looks like we
should have about a 20% but of course
I'll gather that all up and uh show you
that on the scale here in a little bit
what I want to do is I want to get to
pressing some hat all right guys so just
did a quick weigh in uh to show you what
I got the tear on this is uh 0.1 sorry I
guess I can't really turn it at an angle
like that and so the total was 04 I'm
not sure if you guys can see that or not
kind of hard without showing you the
actual kind of hard without taking the
actual camera not 3 it doesn't weigh
three all right here we go tear
so that's at a04 or
3.4 probably squeeze out another tiny
little bit on there if we really wanted
to uh as the screen bag still has a
little bit of stickiness to it as you
can see there still a little bit of
stickiness left there if I want it to
clean out but uh a solid uh 18% return
on bud like I said I could easily take
that and give it one one more good
squeeze I'm really used to squeezing
hash so uh enough of this squeezing Bud
let's get to squeezing some of the fun
stuff shall we bubble today now some of
these are quite large this one for
instance would
fit easily 15 to 20 Gams of hash so
that's a substantial squeeze let's start
with our little guy and uh I'm going to
use if I can find
it the business card there it is nice
little business card right there
and a real simple method for filling
this guy up is to get your card into
there like that and then you can just
drop your hash in there and it fills it
up real nice and simple I've got my
scale right here as well so we can put
one of these on it and tear it at the
point4 I believe that they
weigh all
right there we
go okay so that's at point four let's
get some bubble has into this show and
squeeze out some
rosin it's a real nice uh return on this
particular stuff I should get at least a
50% uh possibly 60 if I really kind
of go for
it all right let's see what this little
guy
weighs all right so that's almost 6
G I guess we could put a little bit more
in there just to make sure that it
reaches that 6 G marker I always like
working with an even number if I
can and uh you can see that it's uh
filled up pretty nice there I'm of
course going
to press it down a little bit all right
so that is 6.1 G now you can hear the
denail working away in the background
clickey click clickity click so yeah I
just kind
of you know make this as
self press it into a little sort of
Puck oh that feels
nice all right uh one of the things
people have been talking about is
flipping the bags inside out this is
something that you can do simply enough
uh with the edge on the outside here you
get a fair bit of um wicking this is
what people have been saying anyway I
haven't noticed it myself and I've
pressed both ways but hey it's a trick
that if you find your screen is uh too
full of resin uh you can flip it inside
out now if you're like me and that just
sort of becomes a pain in the ass I can
also show you a little trick that if you
do have resin soaked into your screen at
the end what I've done is I've taken
this and I've just wrapped it up in a
bowl with nothing in it and pressed it
for a few seconds inside one of my
sheets here the experimental sheet that
Tony sent me and I find that all of it
comes out to the point where you can
feel the screen is dry it has no
stickiness to it so those are a couple
of tips that you can do you can do the
flip inside out if you if you feel it's
necessary and uh even if you're still
finding that there's some resin on your
final screen after You' flipped it the
right side uh or sorry inside out uh you
can do my little trick which uh I'll
probably show you here at the end but if
not just remember simple rolling it up
into a little piece flattening it down
between your parchment or whatever
you're using oil slick pad experimental
sheet whatever it is squeeze it down on
there and you'll see that that resin
will escape quite quickly so we've got
our little guy here our little six
Grammer I'm just going to fold that guy
over real nice slap it into our
experimental
sheet I like to give this a little a
little prepress as we call it that just
gets it sitting nicely in place and
uh let's see what we can do with this
little guy here make sure the plates are
lined
up and away we
go oh she's
coming yep I can see her leaking out
here not sure if you guys can catch that
but that is rosin just
dripping dripping
out okay
get that opened up
shoom all right
so as you can see we did a nice little
squeeze there with that little that
little
screen nice return on that beautiful
golden color and a real nice allaround
smoke now we can kind of pull this guy
out from the middle I thought those were
actual uh I thought that was a actual
fiber and it was just oil coming off of
the thing so you can see this still has
a little bit of stick and a little bit
of moisture to it and in fact you can
see on the edges what people are talking
about with those edges picking up that
rosin well I'm not done yet and I'm
going to show you how you can refold
this up into a a smaller little piece
we'll get that into
a a quarter the size that it was we're
just going to give that one more squeeze
while we can a self press is always help
helpful to keep it from popping back up
out of place
and a secondary press so much easier
than a hair straightener it's not even
funny uh nice and convenient to have
these sewn up and uh also to have 10 of
them in each pouch is uh is a real bonus
so let's see what we got coming out here
oh yeah I can hear it I'm usually quite
efficient in my first press I have to
admit I've managed to get quite good at
this
all right Shunk so let me just get this
little guy out of here now this guy is
much drier now although I can see a tiny
little bit of that rosin that I'll just
get off there you go and what a
beautiful color on that once again you
can see that's just
yellow all
right so that's basically the small
screen in effect what you can do with
this screen is it's very easy to clean
if you do find uh personally I don't
need to use alcohol at all I find that
the safest way to clean it is to take
the hash out of it once you've squeezed
every last golden drop out and merely
clean the screen by pressing the screen
fold it into as small of a little chunk
as you can with nothing in it except the
soaking oil that's been trapped and
squeeze that out and you'll see that uh
you will literally get every last drop
out and you'll have a nice nice clean
dry screen with no stick ready to go
again I would suggest you can use these
dozens of times if not hundreds I
haven't personally used any single
screen a 100 times or more yet so I'm
not going to claim that but I will let
you know I've got these ones going now
and there's certainly no stopping me um
I'm going to clean up this rosin off of
here I'll let you guys know what kind of
returns we got it looks at least like a
50 uh% return and I will come come back
uh in a few minutes for a dab all right
guys so I added that all up I kept my
two runs separately uh I can show you
real quick uh I ended up with 3 G of the
initial press which is right here and
here's my second press right here and
you know I've often had people tell me
oh you know the first press and the
second press should never be mixed etc
etc I agree in certain cases but in a
case like this you would really have a
hard time noticing um the color that
came out the the second time was just as
light as the first I've already dabbed a
little bit of each one uh what I total
what I got total by the way was 3 G of
one.5 of another uh when you divide that
or uh you you take that and you figure
out your six G starting we had about a
58.3% return 60% pretty darn good no
complaints there and uh I've still got
this so I can take this hash you can do
another type of extract on it I
personally prefer to do the coconut oil
extract which of course you can check
out on the coconut uh oil hash
extraction uh video that I did also for
those of you that don't know how I got
this hash I have a whole slew of videos
uh under the playlist water extraction
as well as under the playlist dry sift
both of those will show you two
solventless ways of producing an
incredible product that if you happen to
have any that isn't so great it's a
little bit lower than your best quality
this rosin process is an absolute dream
for such things so I figured we'd do one
more press like maybe a nice big press
out of this particular bag though it's
going to be quite a bit bigger than the
last one we had I'd say you could
fit one and 1 half to two times the
amount that you would press so let's say
we do 12 G this time and see if we can
still get 80 to 90% of our initial yield
in a one squeeze while uh you know
getting that last little bit out of the
second squeeze so I'm going to grab more
bubs first I'm going to tear this to see
exactly what we're dealing with 1
G all right
so always happy to uh have such a nice
product to be able to share uh this
process with you guys obviously when
you're using something that's so so
which I've had happen I've had many
people ask me to show me the process
with their product and it just ends up
being a real bummer please people
understand that the better the product
you start with the better product that
you will end up with this is uh this is
very important all right that's 10 G not
too bad two more G in she goes let's see
if that's accurate 11.6 just4 G left to
get that up to 12 like I said I really
like having the accurate numbers it's
definitely something to be said 12
exactly and you can see this OG Lindsay
is getting a little bit lower but uh
still plenty of Ros and to squeeze out
of that bad bad girl right there all
right so
we've got our 12 G bag this thing is
going to squeeze like you wouldn't
believe want to make it too fat but fat
enough that it's going to really press
that resin uh out of those uh little
shells those little wax cuticle
membranes that can that basically hold
all of this wonderful profile canono
tpin terpenoids cesa terpenoids the
whole nine yards it all has its place
and and uh let's get this show on the
road I think I'm going to do a double
this time
around give it one like this and one
like
that a double meaning I'm not going to
fold the sheets that way I can just do
my initial squeeze right like this and
uh still have good success so let's see
if we can't get that in
there all right here we go for 12 G
press
probably going to see it coming out the
side here so I'll hold it up for
you lot of hash it's taking a bit of a
time before it's actually accessing and
boiling the majority of those oils out
and you can see them coming out
now here they
come you see that
drip there we go rosin drip down for us
that's a
girl that's a
girl beautiful all right let's get that
lifted
up this is going to be a huge return
absolutely wonderful you get these rosin
bags out of the way it's always nice to
have a nice clean place to work I can
actually see the rosin dripping back
down as I lifted that
up all right all right so there's one
size of our side of our
sheet probably a solid four four plus
Gams just sitting there uh we're going
to still obviously press this out again
for a second which you know
what why don't we do that right
away fold that up you got to be so
careful as to not you know make any
unnecessary mistakes so let me see if I
can get this back on
nicely okay try to keep these two
somewhat apart from one another not
necessarily guess it's not the end of
the world if they touch get that back in
there give that one more nice little
squeeze I love working with this
material it's real nice to work
with
all
right can hear it squeezing out
beautiful you always want to pay
attention cuz once you start seeing that
rosin come out you really want to be on
the ball otherwise it can really make a
bloody
[Music]
mess all
right oh
yeah
booya so there's another squeeze right
there on the top and you can see it over
here as well let me get that little guy
out of the way you can see it right
there so I am going to go take some
macro photographs of this cuz I see some
real interesting stuff happening here
and I will be back here in a bit I have
found that it's not really the most
enjoyable thing to watch people cleaning
these uh off and uh so I just don't have
to do that on camera but I will be back
very soon to show show you some
beautiful uh piles I'll let you know
what we got in our first squeeze here
and what we got in our second and
whether or not we're going to have to do
a third squeeze so we'll catch you back
in a little bit hey guys so I'm back I
have squeezed out the last two batches
I've only squeezed twice so far I got
about a 57 to 58% return as well I got
almost 6 G right off the first squeeze
and then I got about 1.4 g off my second
squeeze for a total of
seven uh about 7.2
7.3 still kicking around that 50 to 60%
range which uh basically when you find a
material that you know how much return
you're getting it's going to be very
important for you to pay attention to
those numbers because it'll let you know
your efficiency so I'm sure I could
probably squeeze these two maybe one
more time I could potentially get them
both folded up and squeeze out another
batch now if you do such a thing keep
that separate because guaranteed by the
time you do a third press the amount of
heat and the amount of Taffy like sap
that's going to come out of there it's
just not going to be worth putting in
with your you know really beautiful
stable rosin that uh I mean this stuff's
going to be absolute fire I can tell you
right now I think I might have shown you
already but I will show you again just
in case I forgot here is that same
material uh after oh a couple of couple
of months maybe maybe a month I can't
even remember now but there's that
quality that we've got that's what we're
looking for right there really nice
transparent beautiful looking
bubble
and nice and easy with the bubble uh
with the rosin bags uh keep calling them
Bubble Bags mainly because our first
time they've come with a little label
that says Bubble Bags that's going to
change you will see that say Rosen bag
sooner than later and I guess really all
there is left to do is to squeeze out
one of the big guys this is going to
require a bigger press um I'm not really
comfortable squeezing it out on this uh
particular smaller press so we're going
to have to do that on a bigger one I
think what I'll do is I'll do a whole
show just for these guys right here and
in that show I'll show you both herb and
hash but for today I think we're pretty
successful we've made a solid 10 G of
azin uh in a very short period of time
as you saw it was actually quite easy
for me to even collect much easier than
it has been in the past off of this
particular type of sheet and like I said
we're not going to be throwing this away
you can still use it to squeeze out a
little bit more rosin or if you want
your coconut oil to have a nice potency
to it leave that th that third squeeze
uh in there and just run that material
through the coconut oil it really
depends on where your efficiency lies if
you can squeeze the rosin out of there
and get every last drop well then
obviously that's a great idea because
you can take that rosin and put it into
your coconut oil now if you're not as
efficient as you think you might be uh
then the coconut oil will do a really
good job on getting in there and
squeezing out every last little bit of
uh phyto canabo that are left in there
particularly if you do the crock pot and
the water and really kind of boil it
down slowly the water of course
preserving the canabo and the Turpin I
think really we should finish this off
so you can see I have my denail here
pluged PL in to uh the dabinator
actually at
105° and what I'm doing is I'm using it
to clean my halo Bowl each and every hit
that I take and you can see if I just do
a quick little unplug cuz I'm going to
be plugging it into the other whip
anyway you can see the quality of
cleanliness that uh comes to be on the
Halo when you uh when you get it right
so that's how you want your Halo looking
each and every time you take a hit and I
suggest that if you have one and you
have a couple of dnails this is a great
little system uh one turned up to 1,000
one turned up to whatever your
temperature of uh dabbing at I've got
mine I think it's 630 right now I was
hitting at 550 for a while and I felt
that it was pooling a little bit I was
getting very nice tasty rips but I felt
like I needed to bump it up a little bit
more so why don't we take a couple of
dabs here of our freshly made Rosen I
think I'm going to hit this six gram
batch right here this stuff is
absolutely just phenomenal
uh we're only down to 810 de so maybe
we'll talk a little bit about you know
really what this whole rosin thing means
because for the longest time I've been
teaching people how to make bubble hash
but many people were convinced that they
it was just too far away they need uh
from their reality they needed to get
Bud that they didn't have access to in
large amounts they needed to get the
bags they needed to they didn't really
understand the whole process of water
and ice and I've I've been showing this
for people to people for a long time and
basically what has happened now with
rosin is it's so accessible you don't
need any bags you don't need you know a
little bit of a screen some parchment
and a hair straightener and you're in
the game and some people are even doing
it without any uh uh screen at all so
this is a very easy game to get into
however I think that you'll notice that
as you do get into it you'll realize
that Rosen isn't really necessarily the
be all end all as much as it's a really
amazing
decontaminator for resins and but bud
you know for for accessing dabs from bud
in an instant it just can't be beat it
is an unbelievable process uh to for
taking hash that was otherwise a non-
melty grade non dabbable a 45 a 25 a 160
a one sometimes 120 sometimes people's
90 and 73 are low quality this gives
them another chance to recreate a
product that is actually going to be
increased in quality which is something
that you know we can unveil the quality
uh with bubble bags and dry sifting but
this rosin technique is a whole
different ball game of like creating a
quality unveiling to a Next Level
removing that fibrous mat and that uh
cuticle that wax membrane that holds
those phyto canabo in place removing
that is definitely decontaminating it
further although however I will say that
science will probably figure out in the
near future there's something going on
in that fibrous mat that is where of
course cannabinoids and Turpin are
produced and I think that it's that that
is missing from rosin that you get in
your full melt dry sift and your full
melt bubble has hits that to me gives
the advantage to both full melt dry sift
and full melt bubble has those are my
two favorite rosin is a nice third for
the quiver and a great way to clean
things up and I'm definitely uh I'm
stoked on it there's no doubt about it
I've been stoked on my denail press I've
heard all sorts of different things
people have been saying about them but
uh mine's just been nothing but a
pleasure to work with and uh I think
it's time hit the Halo Sapphire rosin
let's do
it beautiful that was a little bit
warmer I felt
that I haven't said at 7:35 but it seems
like it's at about 6 or 635 I should say
it seemed like it went up quite a bit
when I started sucking there I guess I
was really cool in the nail
down possibly because I'm hitting with a
a a cold carb cap now I've talked about
this as
well we take so much attention of
getting our product to be as tasty as
possible try this as an experiment leave
your carb cap on the nail just for long
enough that the bottom part gets warm
but the top part is still you know easy
to hold without burning yourself and
take a dab like that you will notice
that the temperature of your nail is
unaltered and does not go down compared
to if you use a cold carb cap
particularly a titanium one it holds
cold uh more uh so than the ceramic you
even cool it down more and I've noticed
it mostly in the sapphire I've never
noticed it in another nail before but
the sapphire is so sensitive and so
detail attentive uh it's a preserver of
tpin you really have to be careful with
it and what I've noticed is a little bit
of a warmer carb cap gives me that more
full flavor that taste was definitely
nice but it was just a little bit
lacking due to the cold carb cap uh
we'll finish it off with one more rip
I'm going to take a rip of the second
batch uh from the same press just to see
if I can notice any differences in
tastes the texture on this particular
second does seem a little bit more sappy
uh than solid and I think you can even
kind of notice that from uh from looking
at the big one is a lot more stable and
the small one is it's a little bit a
little bit more sappy so we'll have a
little rip and we'll see how that goes
let's do a little Q-tip Tech real quick
I'm sure you guys are familiar with the
Q-tip Tech a nice little couple of rims
around there and cleans out the majority
of that carbon uh leftover and uh allows
me to take another rip without having to
heat the nail up to 1,000° uh which I'm
going to do right after this
rip
so I will say this about
that I definitely notice a difference in
The Taste now for me I prefer the stable
version uh it was more preserved in the
turine flavor the second batch just
feels like it was exposed to literally
twice the heat that the initial batch
was uh exposed to and I really noticed
it in the sense that this material is
very dry but when I get a really TP Rich
rosin it will Sizzle almost like the wet
Frozen Frozen Frozen whatever John was
calling that um it almost sizzled like
that but differently it didn't pop and
crackle but it would literally foam and
like you can maybe hear it when I took
my first hit it was just almost
explosive but really just violently
bubbling and I believe that that's
definitely the Tarpin present in there
doing that without a shadow of a doubt
let me put that back on full screen for
you cuz that's just
nice nice to have that in the background
there we go nice little dab of Ros in
there anyway I think if you guys have
any questions you can hit us up you can
check out the rosin screens the rosin
bags at fresh.com as well as bubble
bag.com it's got its own uh rosin uh tag
under the categories there that you'll
find under products and uh if you have
particular sizes that you're interested
in getting uh produced and you're not
interested in the 5x4 or the 3x4 or the
1 and 3/4 by3 and you want a specific uh
designed screen we have no problem doing
that for you we can uh pump those out
pretty fast uh just get us an order
minimum quotes uh minimum is 200 100
singles so just let us know and we'll be
happy to help otherwise yeah keep
watching Bubble man's world I'm going to
try and put out a lot more videos here I
know I've been kind of on the down low
for putting videos out uh I've been
filming for other people lately uh
documentaries and other little things
and interviews such that it's taking up
my time to the point where I don't have
the same amount of time to offer to you
guys but I have been feeling it if you
guys have been feeling it and uh I'm
going to try and get some more videos
out there we got some Buble hash uh
videos coming in the near future with uh
my good friend Phil and his uh Team of
guys over there at West Coast
concentrate and uh who knows maybe some
really nice dry sift uh videos in the
future as well now that we have the cool
temperatures anyway thanks for watching
Bubble man's world and uh we'll see you
soon my life it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your life
but if we come together for one
life we coming from behind
[Music]
behind spiritual
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors tring from
behind ding forward at this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the tables
yes I and I come to turn the
tables turn the Paradigm around yes
deprogram and
reprogram