[Music]
Nation welcome to B man's world we're
here with Marcel Brun a well-known glass
blower from the community if any of you
have been collecting glass for any
amount of time you've definitely heard
the name Marcel Bron and we're also here
with Matt the The House of the great
Gardener so uh today Marcel is here
telling us about a new project that he's
working on and it's a little more
complicated than just blowing a sick
piece of glass so I'm going to kind of
let him Matt just came in literally
minutes ago to drop me off the tripod
the camera is sitting on right now cuz I
spaced it last time I was over there
left it on the island puffing bowls um
so he Marcel was just about to expl
explain to Matt what this project is all
about which involves this box right here
and I'll pass it over to you Marcel you
can sort of tell them about it awesome
yeah the project is called project 33
and it's a it's a project designed to
build community um and it centers around
uh creating awareness about currency and
the different ways that it's used to
battle the building of community and
keep people imprisoned um so last last
year I made the uh the idea is to create
a community- based currency uh so
imagine like somewhere between a
festival and a workshop where
people you know spaceship comes to town
builds a dome around itself throws the
party gates open people come in and
essentially the cost of admission is
being exposed to the images and
information that we have to share about
currency and permaculture and
survivalism and just general um human
values that are important and uh part of
the activity is the local Glass artists
and local musicians will be showcased on
our stages and during the midst of that
there will be creation of currency so
part of the activity is a as a
participant is you'll be one of the
people like polishing or slicing or St
in or on the team pulling the Millies
for the currency which are like these
coins I have here right so you familiar
with Millies I'm not familiar with
mellies it's like a cane of glass that's
been sliced and Polished that has an
image on it yeah so like a long cane and
it's got the image he can show you one
cane it has the image on the end of the
co at the when it's sliced right like
slicing it just like a a Lo so you build
it you build it but the idea is that the
community will be enlisted in order to
um create this these uh these coins and
the way that it works is there'll be
even like glass presses so we have a
line of people handing down hot glass
and pressing the currency and what
happens is the currency will be able to
be pre-ordered by people who are in the
know to like have the working assets and
resources for the project to launch and
to get to each location and then as the
currency is produced it's distributed to
to cover all those costs and the things
that are needed for it to go to its next
location and then all the excess is
given to the people who have attended so
everyone leaves with a currency exchange
and they're exchanging their time for
the currency and the the idea isn't that
we're going to back the currency per se
we'll have plenty of activities where we
will back the currency like at the thing
you might be able to do a metal coin
press and go get a thing of fries but
the idea is more that people take the
currency out and use it to sell the idea
to the outer world so each person that
has it tries to get what they can with
it outside and then the idea grows that
you know we're prisoners of our
dollars so very wild concept very cool
and these are the coins heck yeah that
you have brought with you today so
they're all exactly the same yeah
they're all from the same cane but I
guess he's got they're not exactly the
same they have different sizes to them
oh I didn't even see the other
but we've been looking at the big ones
oh yeah I didn't realize they were
Stacks
High I've been hitting some great
Gardener resin all day so very cool
that's
cool sweet and so how can uh how can
people uh get involved with this how can
they you know right away if someone was
watching and they were like well I I
want to I want to be a part of this how
do I how do I be a part of this how do I
acquire one of those
coins oh
I'm not sure how to acquire one of these
coins these particular coins are just
kind of the the
beginning exactly they were created at
uh project 33
2013 and you know that was they were
meant to be the bank for the first
project they were exchanged to sell the
glass that we created and uh their
intention is that they're the seed to
have the resources to take the first
role with the with
Hardware interesting and no do you have
a plan on putting these out as that like
getting you know auctioning them off or
getting people involved to to invest in
these coins in order to get the project
started or um I do in the sense that I
would like to exchange them for money um
you know and it's just open to up to now
I've primarily given them away uh to
people that I felt great gratitude for
MH um you know and they've
been I don't know if useful is the right
word for that but certainly something
that's uh made me feel good from time to
time yeah
absolutely well for sure I can see that
because I mean for my perspective just
from hearing about this I I mean I just
you're a humble guy I I know for a fact
if I photographed these and put the idea
on the website or on on the internet put
it out in the world it would be very
short time before people were emailing
me and being like like how can
I yeah at the original project 33 they
were $1,000 coins
so but so at that project someone could
come in and do some work acquire a coin
and then at that Festival they could go
and buy a snack with that coin that sort
of what you're suggesting not so much
when you say they would do some work uh
they would do an exchange yes so at the
festival we would set up at like yeah
exactly so take the example of we bring
project 33 to a festival it would be
like
a
um it would be like a side stage
basically where people would be able to
come and uh I remember when I was at
Coachella once and they had a one of the
whole stages at Coachella was run on
human power and they had all the
batteries set up and they had like rows
and rows of like bicycles and they had
like these hand cranks and the the
entire weekend that DJ stage and behind
the DJ stage they had like a giant
hamster wheel there someone was like
running on the wheel all the time and
they had huge storage batteries and they
ran that stage for the whole festival
just off of the human power powering it
it was cool cuz you'd go at like 4 in
the morning and You' see that guy on
just like when I first heard of this
project I I was I was more confused I
thought it was something like okay so
you buy these coins you get entry into
this project that you create this
incredible piece of art and then that
art is auctioned off and it raises more
money and it creates another project
that's what I very similar to the
concept yes um very cool yeah well it's
definitely neat and it's it's out of the
box and it's definitely right up your
alley you know you're always uh sort of
pioneering new ways of of doing things
which is great cuz not that the old way
of doing things isn't great either but
it's just nice to have new choices yeah
you know I'm telling you it's kind of
like what I was saying to Matt recently
about why I was like man your strains
are all so amazing and great and he's
like it's like he took his own ego out
of it instead of thinking that he was
going to be the one to choose all the
best strains for like thousands of
people who use it medically he used all
those thousands of people to pick the
strains he got them to tell him what you
know that was a huge that was a
huge with the H strain we we asked the
members to choose like the top three
phenotypes and it was completely
different from the one that I liked
right right so at that point it was like
it was like a light it was like holy cow
I have no I I have no you know I've
learned making these decisions I've
learned it as a photographer the picture
I think is the best people don't
generally
agree you know and I'll do the
experiment I'll be like I'm going to
post this one I don't to like it I'm
going to post this one instead of this
one the odd time when it's perfect it's
perfect and you know it's going to be
the one but many many times I'm it's
just neat to get over your own ego and
involve other people I really liked when
you were talking about doing that uh I
guess like a class where you're kind of
teaching people how to do the um rello
the rello that's that's very cool so you
would like C could you could like custom
make these for whatever Festival so the
festival organized ERS came to you and
said we want to implement this into our
Festival
somehow uh yes so be a custom custom
thing at be yeah major collectible I
mean I'm just I just know and I'm not
sure if you understand this Matt in the
glass world like people collect Millies
and not even ones that big yeah and I'm
not sure cuz I'm kind of even out of the
loop Lev where I'm not sure if they're
collecting them to put them on future
pieces or they just want to keep them
just as Millies in like cases right well
I'm getting the thumbs up from the big
glass collector that's in the house he
saying yeah one thumbs up they do they
do collect them just for mes yes no they
which which means without even as a
currency this is a currency because it's
marel who made them it's a colle yeah
it's just wild man it really does get
you thinking about currency absolutely
and anytime you can make an exchange
where you're not
okay so
currency currency evaluation evaluation
when you when you originally print it
whoever prints it gets the entire value
of its worth and then as soon as there's
a pile of currency sitting it gets
interest charged on it and people start
charging the [ __ ] interest and it's
like the money is supposed to represent
the work that we all do as humans our
blood our sweat our tears our planet's
ability to SU Ain life and these people
say they have all of it and then they
water it down by 50% it's like pouring
water into your dad's vodka bottle like
the every time the interest gets added
on and so they're just like well because
the bottle's full again and we have half
of it your half is now this half and
it's a water down half and it keeps
happening and it's happened so many
times that they've just basically Tak an
ownership of everything uh it's a great
trick
you know so any time that that can be
avoided where exchange can happen
outside of the currency it's like it's
at least taking that one that one
interaction away from the pile of
interactions that's holding everyone
down as a community yeah trade trade do
more trades well it's interesting you
know you have the uh herb and the glass
and the hash guy sitting here and those
are all things that have you know not
always just glass but glass pipes in
particular have had a found in the herb
Community obviously people are mostly
smoking cannabis with them whether we
want to pretend that they're smoking
tobacco or not the majority of them are
smoking cannabis and it's part of the
inspiration and the beauty of the art to
me I always saw them so intricately
connected that it it was true like GL
you didn't really back in the day go buy
glass in like a store or a gallery you
bought it from like a blower if you were
lucky enough to know them or on like a
lot you know right dead lot or fish lot
that's where you could see pipes guys
had pipes for sale and it was and they
were very eager to trade what I noticed
is that people started to collect and we
all love trade absolutely and you know
as a maker I noticed that people tend to
collect multiple Pieces by me because
they're in a sense investing in me as a
maker um and so you know when you buy a
piece for me then I get to make more
pieces and they get better makes you
want another piece and that whole Evol
ution of you know support like a
philanthropic sort of a Vibe is
something that I think is really
beneficial on both sides of the equation
both for collectors and for others
toally totally you get to see you get to
see the sort of development you can sort
of tell where you were by that certain
piece oh yeah I was Lear working on that
technique and exactly and share
ownership in that and be like you know I
helped you get there you know cuz it's
like as an artist you're always looking
to have that extra support to take your
ideas to the next level for sure well
this is definitely a cool concept and an
idea and I I can see it at its birth
right now but um we'll see what it grows
up into at a festival near you at a
festival yeah coming to a festival near
you heck yeah and on Marcel thanks for
joining us man super good to see you and
have you in the house here holy smokes
yeah Matt always a pleasure totally
totally I got to go thank you for
bringing the tripod and I guess we'll
see you in uh Barcelona see you sidec
along with John John B who's just on off
camera right now he is here all right
see his hand is right there about to be
here all right sweet very cool
awesome these real
quick yeah I didn't get that they were
triones they look like agots or
something exactly I'm taking it back
yeah yeah I
would all right well welcome back to
Bubble man's world we have a couple new
guests we lost one guest we uh we got
flab 421 in the house uh Marcel's still
here and John B who was just off camera
in the last video he's uh managed to
make it over here he put some nice
grapes on the table for the effects we
got to give John a shout out for his
grapes very nice effects I'll have a
grape
there and yeah we got the Dil and some
great Gardener dry sift on the table oh
great thank you and Marcel has his
um his Boris silicate coins or Boris
silic coins maybe we'll coin them I
don't know I'm just making [ __ ] up cool
concept we talked about it a little bit
before
and we're probably going to have a
discussion about it now so we thought
slap on the camcorder let everyone
listen in super beautiful day in British
Columbia today the mountains in the
background are just gorgeous Sun's
flourishing it's making plants oh yes
the water melon is joining us over by
John subtle but
there and uh yeah it's a good day it's a
great day ni you up here man you know
like geez it's been a while was good so
but yeah this is uh this is a whole
whole new level of really thinking this
is really cool and I mean um really
getting to know about what you're doing
here is uh quite amazing and you know
and actually more talking about it since
since Matt left was uh really realizing
the whole concept behind of uh this uh
this new currency we were saying yeah
yeah you guys have been in a deep
conversation for the last half hour plus
while we were setting all this up and uh
so you you've uh you've got a little bit
of a better grasp on it John how do you
see it now what do you oh it's a short
explanation short explanation it's um
well it it's about joining community and
building trade and and getting back to
being real and and to getting away from
paper and and and this is more about
you're investing into say I get a I get
one of the the the Starbucks Starbucks
Starbucks I get a Starbuck and you know
let's just say this particular one here
I paid $1,000 for
it but I mean you know now that I have
the Starbuck is the value of it is what
I see value with what say someone like
like flave Dave he's got uh he's got a
cool pipe that he really
wants but he really wants one of these
and we're not talking about value
anymore we're just talking about what we
feel is what it's worth and so I we wind
up trading and I trade him for my
Starbuck and he gives me a nice moreel B
and it's really cool I got that thing
for for a little while now and and and
and now someone wants to maybe uh trade
that and and and and it's interesting is
is where I'm getting the concept from is
is it's really it's about the value is
the way you see the value in right and
it's not really the value of it's the
individual who sets the value on it that
value could be at any any price and that
value go up as that coin is traded more
and more right so it gains value by what
it
represents exactly the energy people put
into it and that's really what you know
I'm always asked what backs the currency
and they're like well Marcel are you
going to back the currency can I just
buy any piece from you with your
currency and you know the answer is that
it's it's backed by the community and uh
the platform that I'm trying to build or
that I am
building excuse me the platform that we
are building is uh designed to enlist
the community in actual creation so uh
you know when the show comes to town
it's a cross between a glass blowing
workshop and a music festival fairly
small intense environment and people are
exposed to to uh information about uh
currency and exactly how
directly uh using a currency is holding
us prisoner as a as a
population and in the attendance of that
everyone is enlisted to actually stamp
the coins and create the currency itself
so what happens is there's pre-support
where people are knowing about the
currency and they advance the materials
and supplies and fundage that's
necessary for the show to be created but
each creation as these were created at
project 33 in 2013 By a community of
artists who came together
freely as these were
created um you know they're now going to
support uh the creation of the project
um directly but when people
come even even if it's not make AE they
could just be part of a line of people
who are working to move glass rods down
get them hot and smash them with a press
and make pressed coins for lower
denominations like we're talking about
these as $1,000 coins because they're
marked with 100 star bucks so with the
100 on it you know 10 to one whatever
but we could make a Millie with a
smaller denomination but for a very
small denomination we have glass pressed
coins and I also have Penny p where
you'd actually use like a vending
machine type format and be able to put
in US currency and a penny and turn the
crank and it presses out like the lowest
denomination so as a participant in this
show no matter what your skill level no
no matter what your ability to
participate in the art making process is
we have an option and you can be part of
a team and if you're if you're on the
team and you come to this event you've
invested your time and you've uh offered
your time to be exposed to these ideas
and when the coins are done at the end
of the event all of the excess is
distributed back to the people who are
attended so we have our plans of what we
what we as an event need in order to get
to the different shows and make it to
the next shows and the Planned expansion
but the excess is beyond that are
designed to be distributed so that
everyone who comes to these shows then
has the icons they have a start book
when they can take it back to their
community and and share the idea ex
share the
idea it's very cool idea so many
different ways it can be done too even
as you're explaining it to me my own
mind is coming out like is just coming
up with these other Concepts and ideas
based on this idea exactly that's what
it's doing you picture you picture are
like people often like a more simplified
version cuz this is the this is the top
like fullon like the information
knowledge drops with the permaculture
and all that that goes beyond just like
glass collecting and trading but to
bring a concept like this back to Glass
collecting and trading you know for a
blower who might be low on funds and
unable to acquire like the right amount
of uh glass rods or oxygen or whatever
you know a blower that people stand
behind and believe in they could put out
their own kind of unique coin you know
and and and say you know this is a
collector's edition I'm selling them for
$200 a piece or whatever and you know if
you want a piece later on in life for me
I will actually take that at as $300
only me the glass door only I will give
you $300 off it's just a it's like a
trade currency it's like a personal
currency of just you know I'm you as a
collector you're supporting the
integrity of an artist and sometimes
that uh an an artist who's having
Integrity may not be
supported fully because of some of the
choices that come along with that oh
yeah high integrity low profits right
exactly each event is is is going to
create its own unique coin and only so
what we're talking about let just say at
the last blowing uh competition that
actually turns into that weekend turns
into creating a bank and that whole
weekend the all get together and they
create so many bit you know they they
create these coins and they create a
bank over the weekend where then over
the weekend you have the seminars and
it's the whole event and people are
learning and they can use these to learn
more things stuff and we can have the
different uh you know there's so many
ways the system is going to actually
generate money you know because it's
modeled off of the system that's holding
us down so effectively it's going to
generate resource in all all different
ways just it's going to encourage people
to share their resources with each other
but as a community skills and stuff
right and so you know he's talking about
the glass blower that might not have
enough glass you know it's also I was
thinking of the permaculture farm that
needs a tractor totally you know and
some of these things to like back up
these ideas with you know to create
because we're a community of bringing
the community together instead of
trading on this you're trading Us in
resources or
right and improving the spaces that we
that we are at well it sure does you
want to
trade you know it's like here we'll
trade but I wonder how many coins that's
worth but but at that exactly what's it
worth to the person that has the coin
maybe you can trade CU that might be for
me a great trade oh that's awesome
because with this I'm going to be able
to trade uh I'm going to be able to
trade the the the next couple bales of
dirt that I need to grow my next crop in
order to do this or whatever it all
depends what you see the value you want
and one Co it's it's just with that one
coin but it just keeps filtering all
it's not money we're trading back and
forth understand we're taking money
concept out of it and it becomes part of
a b
to who we are well part of the assertion
with the money and the reason to go
after the currency is the active
interest is constantly watering the
money supply down so every time somebody
like you or I put our actual human
effort and time into creating
value and then put the money in the bank
to create security for ourselves or our
families like that starts generating
interest and the actual generation of
the interest no matter who it's paid for
Waters down the effectiveness of the
labor that's been done by every single
human being on the planet that generated
real value so that's how the scam works
just because of inflation and we all
like we know this on an intellectual
level but
the illusion of what you said earlier
the true cost of objects right you know
the cost to our ability to survive on
the planet I mean what's the the air
conditioners they were running off of
Fukushima in Japan were you know Chang
people's lives and made them much more
comfortable you know and now our ocean
ISRO right they all tie in together they
all tell you MH want to grab that little
last one I'm not much the nail yeah car
we are society today it's it's
um it's about giving back it's about
helping one another and educating and
and trading and really finding the
genuine people that you deal with them
this brings not only the glass floors
but the community together as in the
Comm cannabis Community is is is I know
the community that I link with so much
and and we're all different part of the
community but this this is just creating
another economy
for the Next Generation right you know
what I mean it's it's it's creates an
economy that draws people together as as
opposed to an economy and a currency
base that keeps people apart like the
current one the current one creates
divisions inherently within itself for
the people because of the amount of lack
of I should say diversification within
the individual wealth levels perfect
example we're on a way to to Spain for
tomorrow it's going to be awesome trip
and I had to go get some currency
exchange and that currency is worth a
lot more than our currency where this
currency value was set
on what the individual and what we have
to work with one another as so doesn't
leave you feeling very good does it when
you trade a currency and and it's just
like yeah you get like this much it's
just like like exactly but with this you
you get rewarded with the currency that
you're trading this is a reward you know
what I mean I know that's what I'm kind
of feeling you know when people say to
you are you going to back this currency
your answer every time should be who you
are that's what's going to make it real
exactly you know there it is right in
the nutshell that's the that's the sound
bite right there that's it like yeah
you're the one using individual make
back this that's why money is unreal
yeah we don't need Banks to tell us to
back this we don't need governments we
need ourselves we need ourselves and
that's what we're talking about this is
bringing us we need our individual
skills and if you don't understand what
that means understand understand that
money didn't say build the deck that
we're sitting on right now but people
built this deck for the illusion of
money y so it was their labor that built
this deck the illusion of money that
demanded that they require payment
absolutely of monetary terms such as the
American green back before money people
just traded in Nepal half the country 12
million people still just trade they
have trade books and if you help me with
my fence I come over and I help you and
dig your well if I help you dig your
well might help me and move some rocks
out of my yard to another area like they
they they live in a jungle and 12 A2
million people in Nepal absolutely don't
use currency but I mean at the same time
it's beautiful thing it's a beautiful
thing it's they're only poor when they
try to use currency yeah otherwise they
the poorest people in the world are the
happiest people that I see cuz it's not
about money it's about their
surroundings and they once again trade
and we give back and helping one another
this is a great concept too because
right now so many people are putting so
much money into glass
pieces it's a great concept that puts
money into glass borrow and the
community but expands it and allows it
to like he was saying earlier like buy a
tractor for a permaculture farmer you
know or even you know something next
level like helping you know someone with
with a pro a medication or something
that b cannabis for your medicine see
this the Synergy that we're having right
here you guys are talking about all
these ideas that can happen like this is
what the goal of the project is is
to bring people together have the people
themselves do the labor to create a body
of currency and distribute that currency
and move
forward uh with linking up and
networking from being at the event like
you guys are both at the event the
permaculture guy and the glass blower
guys and they've got it's not about the
currency like when people come and
realize what a sham the currency is and
then turn to the person next to them and
say what do you do like that's the aha
moment for this project and that's where
when we make that happen we're executing
the vision right I like that it's um
there's a there's a quote that that just
reminds I'm just saying if you come to
an educational seminar with man and John
V and and at the end of the you use a
coin to get in and at the end of the
seminar you actually get two two coins
when you leave right so you can take you
can go to the next level seminar and
bring somebody with you so it's like a
propagation of knowledge that
multiplies right so now we're it's it's
and and you'll find more value in that
because of what you're giving and
receiving and even though it's not worth
money but it's still worth the knowledge
and Ed education that you're getting so
in reality it's worth a lot more than
money mhm I mean you have I got I got I
got a coin from our educational weekend
seminar with with with learning how to
make bubble whatever you know what I
mean have a bubble man addition or
whatever it's it's it's about yeah I I'm
really totally that's exactly it it's
like on a full Festival level you'd have
all your different activities and you'd
have people that if you sat and you did
the course then you would receive
gratitude icons it's basically the
thanks from the people with the
knowledge for taking the time to learn
from them and propagate the knowledge
further so it's not for some reason lost
and as you go around this event you'd be
getting two coins so you could keep one
or you could bring a buddy to your each
of your next you know next levels of of
education is one way that we had uh
visualized it that's one it was just
another C St because that's what um I
really like doing is the educational
part on what my concept is and stuff
like seems like what we're moving into
naturally in this last year everybody no
well just you and I in particular and
the education thing like all of our
YouTube videos are basically educational
videos people need to hear it and that's
what people like and so this this is
also an educational video this this is
it's an educational experience where
people are coming together and part of
the entertainment you know is we have a
music stage but we really we have a
glass blowing stage you know and so the
the local glass blowers are going to
come together together and make work at
each of these events where everyone's
making the currency and stuff and so
that's that's going to be the star
pulling everything not just making the
currency but even like a side project
that we can market with the currency as
part of a way to get people to exchange
to use it to people who want to collect
not only will people want to collect the
collector edition currency but they'll
also want to support the project but in
order to to support the project you have
to collect the currency but it to get
the things that are made from the
project you have to give up the Curr
give up the currency so it's kind of a
way it's kind of like giving back yeah
you you laugh too I liked it too it's
kind of like it's kind of like well if
you want do here and the funny thing is
to the to the organization to project 33
the coins are always going to be face
value so you know there may be an
exchange that happens with the uh what
they're worth but as we deal with them
as people buy into currencies so say it
comes down the road and there's a really
beautiful project 33 piece that's been
made and it was like you know 2,000
start bucks is what the cost is and so
you have to figure out how to get 2,000
startbucks so one way might be
to exchange directly with project 33
which you know you would be P paying
face value but you don't know which
coins you would necessarily get back
because we're it would be like kind of a
functioning Bank like we' be constantly
taking coins back in order to give
pieces back but then sending coins out
out in order to show gratitude for the
raw Supply and cost of moving
theing regionally what artists are there
it'll be a different coin and so you
could give in say like hypothetically
speaking like two Brandon Martin lead
coins and get back at the end of the day
when you trade back in you could get
back a Jason Lee lead coin or something
like right and as the um as the market
evolves [ __ ]
you got a good thought there I I do I'm
trying to express the thought okay so
the idea basically is as the coins are
collected and people are like this is
now part of my collection and I'm not
going to negotiate with it that's going
to be what backs the currency that's
exactly like what the government gets
when we all put our money in the bank
totally all of a sudden they have all
this money to work with and so when
these are collected and we're forced to
just keep printing more and more and
more of them and create more of them and
they keep getting collected that allows
the war chest for our idea to propagate
itself to get bigger and thicker and
more powerful and so that's really
what's backing when it comes back to
what's backing the coin you're backing
the coin you know and how you back that
coin is by collecting it and what
happens when you collect it well this
organization which
is this this it's not an organization
it's an artistic idea it's a cry still
being that's being birthed that you
know it's joining here joining people
it's it's going to yeah it's going to be
a beautiful thing um and uh you know and
I I'm eternally grateful for being able
to play a part in bringing this idea uh
to
us but anyhow it's I would just add the
filter for people that aren't quite at a
point in their life where they're really
ready to hear what Marcel just said and
by hear I mean kind of understand it and
be inspired by it Marcel's not crazy
he's actually just like well ahead of
his time like he is he's ahead of his
time I've known this dude for like
almost 20 years and he's just always
been ahead of his time which is awesome
because his time has been catching up to
him he's not like a hundred years ahead
of his time he's just he's about 5 to 10
years ahead of some of what you who are
listening right now and I don't mean
that in an insult of way I just mean
like truly the dude is like even I'm
listening to him and earlier FL was like
what do you think of this idea like what
do you think of it and I'm just like
well dude it's Marcel so like right now
I think that he's struggling to voice
into
language what he really sees and he's
just able to squirt out little bits to
us and so clab was like oh yeah yeah
you're right you're right and I was
that's the way I see it like he's I have
faith in Marcel that if he has a project
in mind that it'll only have done good
in the end I never hear oh yeah that
that thing flopped large for Marcel that
was a huge flop so what I'm saying as
bubble man to you guys who are listening
this would be something that if you hear
more about or you have a way of hearing
more about it you should definitely look
into it it's going to be it's going to
be something you're going to hear more
about whether you like it or not just
it's just going to be up to you whether
you want to be a part of it there no
than a Bitcoin it's no different
conceptually it's just something that
from the heart and the Soul you want to
back a little better from the glass
community and you can hold it I think
exactly it's pretty pretty beautiful
actually I think I think it's uh it's
it's just something real and it's made
by real people and your for real intent
and real knowledge and and being able to
actually I mean
it's a pretty cool it's a pretty cool
concept is when you when when you really
start thinking about it and actually
talking with yourself for the last
basically hour about really getting in
depth about it and stuff like that is is
the whole concept behind this is is
about connecting communities and
connecting people and being able to
really join us as a whole and
understanding it isn't about money it's
it's it's really it's here it's it's
really it's about trying to like learn
to trust the Integrity of the people
around you to do the right thing and
pass the resources on that they need
need to get down the road to do whatever
it is that they're trying to do and how
about explaining to people who are who
are watching that really have little
concept of the glass world and the glass
community and the collect collective
value and whatnot but the simple
explanation of like what these coins are
and how they're made can you give that
to us just a quick couple of minutes you
know because I mean I know what A Millie
is and everyone here does but some
people watching might be like what are
those that he's holding this is a a Mila
fiori it's a cane has a picture in the
crosssection so it's built up from the
center outward uh to have a picture in
it yep you kind of stripe them on
there's several methods and then it's
pulled from a large piece down to a
smaller piece and it's sliced and
Polished yeah so he's like pull the cane
into a tube almost and then it's like
you just slice it into pieces so all of
these were part of one long cane and so
that's why we have all different sizes
because part of the cane was thicker and
part of the cane get smaller
right as you were pulling it so kind of
like pulling something apart we get the
smaller ones and you get a lot of them
are the same size but you can see the
different dimensions and it's uh well
you know it's it's very unique and at
the same time it's
uh I don't know I think it's rewarding
when you when when you get something
this is not like a a dollar that you get
from the you know I mean bank machine
this is it's got more it's more real to
it you know what I mean and even more so
for the people that were actually like
if you could actually be a part of
creating that's that's what that's where
it becomes more real to it you become a
part we're going to become a part of
creating one oh yeah I can see it
already for our educational seminars
yeah there you go our cross country
educational seminars will be brought to
you by no I'm just joking to you soon
borrow coins no no but I
mean it's it's a it's a way of if really
um and then the more festivals and the
more that you have bringing together the
more people are wanting to demand them
because it's creating more people bring
your out together so the first one
starts and then the talk get going you
have to do a second and then the funding
comes for the third because we keep
creating the bank and every time you
have a festival you create a bank of
people come to create that and then
those people and and you'll see it over
time growing that everybody's going to
want to come to the festival and all of
a sudden we're going to well okay we
only got enough people to here we got to
stop here we got too many people
involved in this going to be
with that'll be you know part of the
challenge of maintaining like full
accessibility of you know how do we make
this uh throughput process where like as
many people are able to like participate
as possible CU currently it's exactly
the opposite they're trying to make as
few people participate as possible in
the creation of the system where we
track everything and really we need as
many people as possible to create uh to
participate in that system so that the
focus becomes focused and we can focus
on fixing things like the planet and you
know just basic Sur basic survivability
things I mean if there could be any
one any one thing that makes me uh
really upset it's the wealth gap between
the very rich and the very poor you know
I mean couldn't we just like close it
like 50% from each Direction and call it
a day like that would be you know a huge
Improvement and there would still be
huge amounts of wealth on that original
side anyway I mean it's not like you're
going to be 12 it does seem a little it
does seem ridiculous when you9 billion
yeah like when you got 99% of everything
to give up like 30% of 99 and be left
with that like oh well I mean seriously
maybe it's just like no one needs a
billion dollars maybe if we just had
millionaires that the wealth would be
more evenly
distributed well and I think that's one
of the you know one of the things that's
most important with a gift economy is
that you don't hoard resource so if you
make a big uh come up you make
$100,000 like in the gift economy you
would immediately redistribute that
wealth and the way that you would see
benefit in your life would be that okay
I just had 100 Grand handed to me on a
silver plate and I gave 30 grand to
three friends and they all three went
out and started businesses you don't
think that your life is going to get a
little bit more fun when you're three
three best friends now also have boats
and you're on the lake having a great
time and you all have the ability to
like interact like so by rather than
saving that you've incre you've tripled
your security because now if something
happens to you you have two friends who
have got your back 110% as well so it's
almost better than putting that money in
the bank which in the bank it's being
used against all of us loaned out to
people so they can pay three times the
value of the negotiation they made for
their piece of real estate you know fake
piece of paper right and we all have to
go through banks to buy real estate and
we all have like family and friends and
resources that are in the banks and
that's why the banks have the money to
loan us so we can give them all that
money you know so the concept of keeping
energy in play uh is really is really
core to the gift economy and how it can
work work to where people just don't
have to work as hard cuz you're making a
more efficient system we're creating a
reong hole pretty damn
cool yeah yeah it's it's it's really
cool I don't think the government's
going to like us but you know what we
already know they don't right now so
it's okay and it seems like times are
right for change doesn't it um we that's
that's the whole thing the change and
what's going on I mean this this this
beautiful plant's making change and and
people make change and and this is
another change and this is about about
working with another and being real you
know it's the concept is is is just so
crazy CU it it just it's so organic and
how it's going to grow right and and
that's that's another thing of all it's
organic and it's the it's the people
behind it that create it and it's us
that make it real I mean I believe as
easily as a handful of people could ruin
the whole planet we can all simply wake
up and change it and change it and make
that impossible you know there's there
is no need for
apocalyptic interventions it's it's as
simple as people making simple
choices all at once taking a conscious
leap into the new paradigm just
believing in each other
100% there is a conscious shift
building it is difficult man I have just
like gone through a week of not having
that totally centered in my heart and it
was not you know the most beneficial to
My Life um
but you know it's difficult I mean it's
not like it's not easy to be happy all
the time to be positive and support
yourself in the in the right ways and uh
and always make yourself available for
others in positive manners to help them
all the time
but if if isn't it true that hash makes
all that so much a little bit easier
hash always makes that easier that is
with question there is no question about
it
um full m what's that especially full
melt oh I was going to say that I
thought you said it's not the full melt
oh it melts yeah man come up here for
the hash for sure the hash is fine I
have hey do you want to hear something
weird like freaky trippy sure I used to
live back then two doors
over two doors over from where we are
right now the house that you used to
come to so just that hot tub out on the
back box that filled the whole lot is
the house between now you no no not not
the one right on the water remember I I
lived in Lion's Bay for a while I lived
here and I had a deck out on the hot tub
you came a few times oh I did come up
here I remember we were driving I was
like Z and Slinger Slinger lived in that
house for a while actually two doors
over that's awesome this is a great area
I can see why you've rooted in here for
sure it's beautiful there just no take F
there so yeah know there's no which is
also
great we can go and pick it
up sometimes I'll take the wife out yeah
Drive the way west 25 minute drive going
for
some oh yeah well I hope we gave you a
good download today on such a beautiful
day hit the email listening to Marcel
and
um thank you for taking the
time know that the start buuck is uh is
a
start yeah yes it'll only grow from here
oh it's going to grow 100% it says on
the coin a Starship in every garage you
know and that's really the the backing
slogan of the whole thing and when I
find myself wondering I come back to the
to the basic slogan which is a Starship
in every garage God that you can it's
pretty insane that you can make pictures
like that and then like
words are
cool it's just
awesome thanks for watching guys see you
next time on Bubble man's world
pretty
[Music]
cool all right Starship in every
garage wink