[Music]
I Le to the
pro of
dying and I know re
[Music]
soon I'll get my share of what's
mine yeah I
know re
get I'm going to get it
now and I
know
soon sure I'm going to get it
now I know we
soon get I'm going to get it
now yes I
know some tend to read books with empty
pages
but i s the right as read the book of
life why living the days based on
[Music]
illusion with
delusion see man L way tell now my
inflicted
[Music]
I Le you the
proess of
dying and I know real
[Music]
soon I get my share of what's
my yeah I know me soon I'm going to get
I'm going to get it now yeah I
know
soon sure I'm going to get it out and I
soon get I'm going to get it
now yes I
know rock me rock me rock me
[Music]
ra me out there on the
floor rock me rock me rock
meyy rock
Meck me I want no
more me I no
[Music]
I'm going to
get I
know
soon I'm going to get it
now sure I'm going to get it
now and I know real soon
I'm going to get
[Music]
it so waterall
in but I enter it with a bucket
in I shouldn't be giv up un conquered
bound
[Music]
here I
say it's a b that already been fought
and
one my
inflicted
w i Le to the proess of
dying and I know we soon
I'll get my share of what's
[Music]
mine I know real
true get I'm going to get it
now and I
know
soon sure I'm going to get it now and I
know we soon
yeah I'm going to get it
[Music]
now some tend to read books with empty
pages but I saw the right as I read you
The Book of
Life why living the days based on
illusion
with illusion I see mankind Los
way my
inflicted
W I live to the proess of
dying but I know real soon
[Music]
I get my share of what's
my I
know I'm going to get I'm going to get
now and I
know
soon sure I'm going to get it
now and I know
I'm going to get I'm going to get it
[Music]
now yes I
know
soon yet I'm going to get it
now and I
know
soon sure I'm going to get it
now and I know re soon
get I'm going to get it
now I
know rock me rock me rock
[Music]
me rock me up there on the
floor rock me rock me rock rock
me rock me rock me till I want
[Music]
more me still I want
some prophecy positive and profitable
reg your
life that was so nicey
yeah dude you kidding me that was just
nice yeah was nice was really nice