[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome to Bubble man's room I am
visiting uh my family in Manitoba
Winnipeg Manitoba and this is actually
the room that I grew up in from around
12 years to around 17 16 17 before I
moved out so yeah this is my little room
there's not much to see really I'll kind
of give you guys a little tour once we
have a dab but what I thought would be
cool was to do a little dab in bubble
man's room so I got my dabs right here
nice variety I got a little headband
left over
still we scoop up a little bit of that
oh yeah when the rosin is the right
texture it just cleans up so
perfectly all right so yeah this is
literally the room I lived in when I
started smoking cannabis and in fact
today not that it's that exciting but
it's part of my history I was thinking
of taking us down just down the street
where I smoked my first joint so I
thought that would be kind of fun and in
the meantime I got the mother ship the
gold denail and we are ready
to
rock all right headband Rous and dabs
first dab I've ever taken in my room in
fact aside from maybe some hot knives
that I did years ago in my uh closet
here I didn't smoke very often in this
room because it's on the same floor as
my parents and uh it' be pretty pretty
easy to get caught so uh my mom's down
by the pool right now hopefully she
doesn't come up and catch us but for now
bubble man doing bubble dabs in The
Bubble Room
Ros and bubble
DBS window Tech always good to blow your
head out the window even though it's all
blowing back in when you're puffing at
home you know it's amazing people ask me
how I got into this how I how I found my
passion for cannabis and it really
happened in this area in this home
another home that I used to live in with
my father and his uh wife as well as my
step sister and my step brother uh we
used to live just down the street and
I'll I'll try to get you guys over there
as well cuz that's really where it
started as well in the back puffing
joints uh in the back little shed always
had a blast there and uh always got away
with a little more as many of you guys
who uh come from divorced families know
when the family gets divorced you
usually uh especially if you're a
teenage boy you can get away with some
[ __ ] and I did get away with some [ __ ] I
was talking with my step sister the
other day about uh having plants growing
at my old man's house back in the day
which was a little bit crazy to say the
least all right secondary dab I'll show
you guys out the window real quick not
that it's that exciting and uh I'll try
to make this video a little bit like
puffing around the peg maybe that's what
we'll call it puffing around the peg it
started here for bubble man at this home
when I was uh about 14 years old smoked
my first joint down the road and uh well
I really never looked back after that
did
I all right let's give you guys the huge
tour of this amazing
bedroom that's it look I've even got my
old uh skateboard painting still
up and this is where uh you know the
early days were formed for the bubble
man just out the old
street we have a stop sign right in
front so we always had mad action in
front of this house there's always cars
non-stop there's actually three uh stop
stop signs out in front of this house
but enough of the stop signs out in
front of my house we will see you very
soon and I suspect the next time we
light this camera up we're going to be
where the bubble man smoked his very
first joint ever here in Winnipeg
Manitoba so stay tuned for that we'll
catch you guys in a
bit hey guys bubble man here uh I'm in a
unique place right now that I have not
been in a very long time this is the
very location right here by this BFI can
this big garbage can that I smoked my
first cannabis joint ever in my entire
life so I thought it would be kind of a
neat thing to come back here get the
mother ship all loaded up and do a
little bit of a torch rip on some bubs
and uh it's quite quite a few people
there's trucks over here that are
working and there's a bunch of people
over here that are working and I am
behind some
stores um Bibles for Missions over here
and uh I think we got a hair salon over
here so I just figured let's do this
let's have a rip in the spot where I
literally have had my first rib so it'll
be interesting to see if we
get if we get some people looking to see
what I am doing but
uh first time I ever smoked herb I was
14 years old I was with my good buddy
Steve
maoy and this was where we smoked right
by this can in fact so that's where I'm
going to smoke
today that's where I'm going to smoke
today and I've already got people people
watching
me all right so let's see what we got we
got
quartz then we got
bubs so first things first let's have a
little rip a
dip it'll be interesting to see what
these people think I'm doing back here
cuz I'm sure people don't regularly come
back here to uh smoke anymore city has
dispensaries and other uh types of uh
lounges that you can go and actually
enjoy your camp and and you're not
forced like I was as a kid to come to
the back of an industrial neighborhood
and smoke next to a garbage can but alas
it is part of my history and I wanted to
share it with you guys so we are going
to share
it all right here we
[Music]
go torch is very low right now
all right I got to backup I'll be right
back all right that torch was completely
out but
luckily I've got a
backup it's always good to have a backup
when you're uh looking to have a blaze
session in the first place you've ever
smoked in your life I got cars coming
back here I got people it's all good
we're going to get this dab done
whoops most people probably have no clue
what the hell it is I'm doing and I
prefer it that
way to be
honest think they're just doing a little
cleaning behind me right
now all right well here we go guys
well there it
is probably the first time I've had a
puff at this location since I was 14
years old smoking my first joint so I
know it's not very exciting but I
figured I wanted to share it with you
guys and uh I guess there it is we have
smoked at bubble Man's first spot we'll
talk talk to you soon bye-bye hey guys
welcome back we are now at the in at the
forks uh I don't know if it's like a
four-star restaurant it's a fourstar
hotel it's a pretty nice little spot I'm
no longer at my mom's place over in the
east of Winnipeg but I'm here on the uh
edge of St bonfice and in fact if you
can see in the background there's a big
large building with four posts and to
the left of it uh there is a cross that
is the hospital that I was born on this
is a very cool little area the fork all
sorts of Little Shop set up and you got
the Children's Museum right across the
way and tons of beautiful places to go
dab outside which I'm going to go do
after this but I figured we would start
it off with a
dab inside the room I've already done a
few of these let me tell you we had hash
church today which was a nice church a
little bit slower than usual uh everyone
was kind of in a party sort of space
with chalice last night and we didn't
have quite the amount of people that
normally come in but uh still a great
panel still some great discussion and uh
yeah I look forward to next week's hash
church for sure where we're going to
continue the hash discussion continue
the discussion on Rosen uh the efficacy
and the safety of pressing in screens uh
if there's any chemicals releasing if
there are plant foods that are left
behind in that plant matter and then
rosin and how is that affecting it so we
had all these different discussions
today if you watched P church it was
pretty
awesome um hopefully I'm going to bump
into to maybe one or two people locally
here I also uh love the idea of going to
Vapes on Main it's just on Main Street
which is just right behind me maybe even
tonight I can head down there and uh you
know maybe see the guys do a little
interview talk about what it's like
having the only Vapor Lounge in uh
Manitoba in Winnipeg and of course share
some dabs with those guys so my denail
is just about up to Temp it's at 570
degrees uh I've got it set today at 720
uh however what I was talking about in
hash church I I've lowered it from my
normal 750 to 720 and I dropped it right
below 600 so it's actually at
615 right now and that's where we're
going to hit it let that quartz get a
little
bit
warmer always nice to have patience for
the dabs have patience for your dabs
people so yeah I've been here in
Manitoba for about a week uh it's been a
lot of bugs there's definitely a lot of
bugs in Manitoba I've noticed even
thinking about going up by the river
tonight I think uh you know if the sun
goes down uh which I hope because it's
about 34° C out there which I don't know
it has to be 90 90 something degrees 85
90° it's definitely warm all right so
here we go
Beauty well that Rosen dab is going to
get me
going I was looking for some uh butane
to get into the big shot gt800
here unfortunately we're going to have
to go Manitoba style and rock the giant
propane tank so we'll see how that goes
we'll we'll go outside and we'll go uh
hit some dabs I got the new uh titanium
Banger so I think I'm going to bring
that with me this time and leave the
quartz at home and uh of course I'm
going to bring you guys with me so uh
why don't we head out there and see
what's going
on hey guys so just standing out in
front of my hotel room here and I
figured we'd check out the river for the
start start of the day it's pretty early
do a little bit of a wake and bake down
by the water Winnipeg Styles and then
later on today we're going to hopefully
hook up with my buddy Al and uh maybe go
byy Vapes on Maine which is the new uh
vaporizer Lounge here in Winnipeg and if
I have time I'll also go byy the
dispensary and check out what they've
got going on remember this is the city
that it all started for me so it's kind
of exciting even though it may seem a
little boring to you guys let's go puff
a bowl
it's a big
shoe so I guess this is the celebration
Circle it's kind of cool how they have
words carved into
the all right
the North Portage
partnership all
right should I go take a rip right in
the middle of this
circle for everyone to
see well it is the celebration Circle
River's just over the bank
there H maybe I'll hit a bowl in the
celebration Circle in a bit I'll start
off by the
river seems like a good
plan maybe a bridge
a bridge over troubled
water looking for that morning and wake
and bake
spot pretty cool Bridge
all right and there's the St bunny fast
Hospital across the
way
well
yeah all right guys so I'm here on the
bridge um going to have a little bowl
got the mother ship out got the torch
got the whole 9 yards so I guess really
turn on this torch and see what we can't
get done here I am in a very open public
place but
uh from what I've heard a license is a
license and as long as you're
uh you know within reason not in a super
duper public place and I'm on a bridge
right now with nobody so I think they
would allow me to get away with it it's
kind of hard to tell but I guess the
only real way you know in this day and
age is when the police come up to you
and talk to
you nobody's on the bridge I feel pretty
pretty confident I'm going to take a rip
up here and then we're going to head
down there and take a rip right on the
water and uh yeah just show you guys
that there's lots of great spots in in
Winnipeg for puffing and I wanted to
show you guys a couple of them I've
already been here for over a week and
haven't really shown you guys anything
so
[Music]
yeah all
right got my dabar rozin right
here dab Doodles my
case yeah good
times be good to see a couple of my
buddies today hopefully some old school
friends that I haven't seen in a while
all right here we
go still
warm nice and clean though I'm by the
way I'm using the uh that new deep dish
titanium Banger and I got to say I like
it it's probably the titanium nail that
I like the most here we
[Music]
go not bad decent bridge to I say we
head down by the uh river right to the
edge and uh we have a couple of rips
down there so why don't you guys join me
all right getting her
lit get this titanium heated
up all right I'm finally going to get
that dab by the river jeez we waited for
a while for that one didn't we well
here's to not offending people and still
medicating in
public stoked I think today is going to
be a very good day I have talked to my
good friend Reggie the Rody who I don't
know if you guys remember him he was an
old school guy that was on uh true
Stoners back in the
day he was um yeah he was on true
Stoners back in the day that's where I
originally met him but he was from the
same city as me so I eventually ended up
meeting him in person years ago 12 plus
years ago and you would have seen him uh
on the recent degenerate art uh videos
that I released uh the backstage footage
the sort of behind the scene interviews
that never made it into the actual
documentary but uh yeah check that out
if not and you'll recognize Reggie the
Rody and hopefully he's going to give us
a little tour of the city today maybe
some dispensaries Vaped on Maine and
potentially uh go to a really nice grow
of a friend of his so uh I guess we'll
stay tuned for that I'm really nicely
medicated after a couple of Rosen dabs
so I'm going to walk this River a little
bit and uh we'll catch up with you guys
in a bit hey guys I just hooked up with
Reggie the r here at the forks in
Winnipeg dude super good to see you
how's it going man Wicked This has been
uh like I said I've known Reggie for it
has to be over 12 years oh yeah 12 to 15
or something through true Stoners and
whatnot so he was finally telling me
about this building in the background
that I I was like what is this building
that you guys have I've never so tell us
again this is the human rights yeah the
Human Rights Museum in winipeg and they
spent about $350 million on It come on
and uh yeah I just read in the paper
hardly anybody goes to it and man for
$350 million you think that you could
probably uh really forward the Human
Rights Movement by actually helping
people whose human rights are being
violated oh you would think so you would
think so so what's our plan today dude
where you where are you going to you
have a little idea what we're going to
do here today in Winnipeg well there's a
bit of uh cannabis uh bizes or uh
there's a few lounges in Winnipeg now a
dispensary just officially opened on the
1 and there's a couple others that are
half open type of a thing and uh I know
where they all are we'll stop by them
we've got I've got an old friend of mine
who if he's home has got a love we
canvas in his basement and uh yeah we
we'll have some fun well awesome Let's
uh let's get the uh Journey started so
we can get dabbing yes I all right you
never mentioned that he's there he's
lowkey dude oh he's there he played my
axe he says how bad of a guy could he be
he say what so this is Osborne Village
here now yeah wow it looks so different
to me Queen girl Bob right in the corner
clean grow is still here is he oh yeah
man oh my gosh so this he changed he
changed Cor Corners he used to be on the
outside corner and now he's on the other
side corner okay so right here bronze
place was across the still it's uh next
door right across the street there
the laundr
M all right so we uh just set up a
little photo shoot here with a few
little plants we got the gpp Gary's po
plant that's the one Gary's pop plant
very popular strain here in Winnipeg
hopefully kind of maybe and a couple of
nice glass pipes set up on the table
here for a little photo shoot thought we
would share so what do you got this one
is the pyrology yeah the pyrology
recycler and you really like that one
you were saying eh uh it's got great
ratings awesome it rips we got a
Mothership uh Fab egg in the Middle with
the Buddha in the
background and then we've got looks like
salt in there is that Merc very cool
Merk rer colab very cool wow that is
really quite
cool I like that throw them in a can
rure
Tech that thing just gobbles dabs too
really well we're going to hit them
all so we start our adventure yes sir
let's do
it let's get that little recycler in
action boom boom Shaboom
booah hold
no hey hey
[Applause]
hey tasty flow
rosins all right guys so we're back in
the car here heading to are we heading
to Vapes on Main no it's the old Vapes
on Main it is the first open cannabis
dispensary in Winnipeg is it's I for
medicinal marijuana headquarters don't
quote me on that but cool first real
dispensary in Winnipeg though yes okay
and uh July our friend uh bill bill
vandergraph is going to be meeting us
down there tell us a little bit about
Bill uh bill is a retired Winnipeg
police force I think a 30-year veteran
of the Winnipeg police force uh he is an
outspoken member of leap law enforcement
against
prohibition uh bill has been arrested
for growing he used to supply him
himself his father his daughter with
cannabis wow his his dad had ALS uh I
think Bill is PTSD I'm not positive but
uh and I forget his daughter's ailment
but she has something nasty as well wow
so really stepping out really stepping
out from what he knows 30 years on the
police force to become sort of a can
well I guess not sort of but really a
cannabis activist well he's heavy
especially I'm sure getting busted was a
big part of it but uh although be very
well may have supported leap before that
I'm not sure well it'll be interesting
to get a couple questions to Bill and
see uh where his head's at now today
today how the rest of the police force
look at him today the new guys the old
guys and uh just find out if the air is
changing here in the in the center of
Canada in the uh in the
Prairies pretty excited those are the
questions we're going to ask Bill and uh
we're going to head down to that
dispensary right now so we'll see you
guys when we get
there so just on Main Street there's the
fort Gary Hotel over on the left
the forks where I'm staying just on the
other side of this
building and then I guess that's really
the big city center right there hey with
the Richardson Building and the port of
Jermain Port of Jermaine 40 below
anybody come down and have a good time
sure sure don't try to
force yep you can definitely see the
influence of the Ukrainian culture here
in Manitoba with a church like that
hey that's Russian
esque big too too make a great grow
room all right so we're just here at the
place there's the medical marijuana I
like that they've got a nice big
uh they're uh definitely obviously there
I like
that so we're going to do this guys go
check out Winnipeg's first dispensary
I'm so proud of Winnipeg for pulling
this together it's uh been a long time
coming keep in mind it was over 20 years
ago that we did the hemp activism that
led to cannabis hemp being grown uh
legally here for the first time in over
73 years and that hemp's been growing
non-stop ever since so uh hopefully we
can get the herbs uh going as well and
make sure that that never stops as well
let's head in I definitely love how
pronounced their sign
is so that's them guys if you want to
give them a call 204 586
4899 if you're watching Bubble man's
world I'm going to give you an honest
review of this place and the people here
and I have a feeling that they're really
good people so uh let's go check it out
well let's just get set up too so that's
okay oh yeah no let let's check this
place out Crack US Open all right we
have a doctor willing to
help hey how's it going good yourself
welcome to ymch ymch good to meet you
man I'm bubble man hi my name is Mark
I'm a volunteer here um it's Winnipeg's
first disc
dude I'm so impressed that you guys are
pushing the envelope pushing the
boundaries and uh you know making the
steps that are necessary to allow people
that currently are being say let down by
the current license production
facilities now I'm not blaming the
licensed producers they have their hands
tied so tightly uh that they're unable
to make extracts they're unable to
produce Edibles and I'm sure that you
know as well as I do that um the best
way to use cannabis a medicine isn't
always to smoke it that's right I agree
uh the extract form is um very helpful
in medicinal ways uh the current uh
regulations don't allow total freedom of
uh human of of our human rights and um
and for it is our right to decide what
we put in our bodies um you know let's
face it one can actually debate that the
Draconian law the narcotics act from
1923 was uh introduced because of a
opium issue that we had in Canada they
threw a marijuana prohibition within the
cardic act and one could actually say
that these Draconian laws are creating
societal ills today and that this is a
wonderful medicine that cures cancer
helps epilepsy I myself been diagnosed
with post-traumatic stress disorder I've
met a lot of individuals from the
military uh that is doing wonderful
success there's been in scientific
research how the cannaboids help uh the
brain and its memory function to
actually delete the trauma um from
individuals for pts that's huge I mean
that's uh it's pretty incredible to
think that cannabis is the plant that
has the backs of our soldiers of our men
and women that have gone uh to fight in
Wars around the world uh both in America
and Canada and when they come back it's
not the government who has their back
the government whose Freedom they fought
for it's the plant who the government
has been trying to eradicate uh since
you know for close to 100 years yes and
getting back to licensed producers uh
I'm with the licensed producers that I
found out that are radiating the product
which puts fear into my system I'm
extremely healthy individual um I
believe in uh high protein uh High
upline diet um and I do not want any
other um process done I I like organic
and I really want to choose I should
have a choice my constitutional right to
choose where I get a healthy product and
nothing that's been tampered with even
from the largest licensed producer in
Canada so uh you know you you want to be
safe and this is all about medicine and
health um and you want to be safe in
what you take in your system and not get
anything illegally from gangs off the
street you don't know what's in that
product and you want to they have to
have the opportunity not to wait 5 days
for your medicine because what happens
if I need my medicine now so
dispensaries lower crime uh they help
people in need we have people coming in
here with four stage cancer M and the
CBD oils doesn't even have the euphoric
uh psychoactive uh effect it has
completely it atts the cancer cells and
it's amazing what it could do for people
so well it's great to see you guys are
are doing it up and it's pretty
relatively new you guys have been opened
just this month correct yeah just we uh
just since July 1 July 1st excellent
well very cool is there a little bit of
a menu we can peep out uh yes and we
have a menu and well yeah but it's
everything's it's an ongoing projectc
it's getting bigger yes wonderful
wonderful we have we have a a large
variety of pushes we have uh um produce
stuff like alien OG uh we have purple
kush we have pink Kush uh we have SAA
like Juicy Fruit uh we also have uh
bubblehash which is uh very popular
amongst U patients uh we also have the
CBD oil for people who love to sleep and
ease the pain and don't want the
euphoric effect um and so and we're
we're getting more Edibles um we're
getting samples from dispensaries in
Vancouver and we're working with other
people in the business um especially
from Vancouver because it's a successful
model the legalization in the states in
Denver Colorado and Seattle Washington
these are successful models on raising
money to help with infrastructure and
lower crime this and most importantly
increase quality of life in sick
individuals and prevent sickness in
healthy individuals my my 74 year-old
mother who's suffering incredible pain
from arthritis uh and she has incredible
anxiety I'm taking her off larzipan
she's already off it and she's taking
cookies um baked goods inestables and
she's actually doing a lot better she's
sleeping and she's not uh in chronic
pain anymore that's awesome so this is
proof I have people coming in here
saying my wife is cured of cancer from
the CBD oil and people are actually have
real testimonies and that's that's the
real thing so we always like to tell
people that it shuts it off and that
they should be careful uh because if
they have that cancer in them it they it
can shrink it and sort of shut it off
but I would still maintain uh a a fairly
solid saturation of my endoc canabo
system meaning I would still orally
consume canabo potentially maybe uh
extracted in uh maybe a coconut oil
daily just to prevent that cancer from
ever sort of growing back and and taking
root again uh that's that's a great
maintaining program um definitely it's I
I mean it's it's part of a high alkaline
diet I mean when uh you do um get
diagnosed with cancer they do suggest to
have a high alkaline leafy diet first
thing and go and we're talking about
cannaboids this is the only plant in the
world that produces it it works great
with our body and it helps heal so this
is um something very positive and it's
becoming uh mainstream and it's becoming
accepted as in today's society what we
do need is politicians and we we are
having politicians like the Vancouver
mayor uh accepting the regulation um and
we and Justin Trudeau the leader of the
Liberal Party politicians like that need
to think for the 21st century and they
have to have the IDE
ideation of getting rid of societal ills
in a productive
manner well said Mark uh very well said
I I appreciate your time we're going to
check out the place a little bit maybe
go sit in the smoking room and hit the
denail and uh I just want to thank you
guys for for doing this it's a really a
big deal to put yourself on the Line
practicing Civil Disobedience to show
that uh that your community is worth it
thank you very much and thanks for
dropping by it's a real pleasure to meet
you awesome all right so we're going to
head into the members only area here
we're going to set up here Unity how's
it going guys I went to University but
not for very long no because I took my
Volkswagen Vance advice on a hit of
mushrooms uh and it was VW VW VW do you
know what that stands for in
University voluntary withdrawal Ah
that's hilarious that's how you leave we
are repainting please don't do this
we're repainting this this is this is
horrible well whatever it looks nice for
now it's where we're going to set up and
puff it's got to start exactly it's got
to start somewhere so we're going to do
a little bit of
rosin hey
want you want water or something uh yeah
I would let's go get
Waters Way in there man all right guys
welcome back we are in the smoking room
The Vapor Lounge of the medical cannabis
headquarters and it was started by Glenn
who we have here with us wanted to thank
you for having me here dude uh he was
actually an hour away in uh gimly
Manitoba and heard that we were here and
wanted to make it down and and hang out
and do some educ with us so uh yeah I
totally appreciate that you came down
and you vibed out with us man that's
awesome I would be stupid for me not to
come right yeah well you know honestly I
was telling Mark earlier that uh two
thumbs up to you guys for standing up to
open a dispensary here in Manitoba in
Winnipeg uh it's really pushing the
envelope and I think it's right on time
with uh Vancouver mayor uh regulating
dispensaries and I think that uh your
timing is literally perfect and I
applaud you uh for doing it because it's
still Brave in this part of the world it
you're really uh you're putting yourself
out there yeah but you have to do for
what you believe in right yeah and I
believe in this and believe in that
people it helps people and once I
started helping people I couldn't stop
yeah it's a bit addicted isn't it yeah
and so how did you get into uh you know
a brief history I I assume that you've
had relationship with cannabis for a
while started smoking at 9 I'm 54 so we
got we got some some Decades of of
cannabis uh use under our belts so what
what really sort of sparked the idea
that you would start a dispensary here
in W because there was no one doing
anything to educate people and move
ahead with the dispensary yes uh there's
other places in winipeg that open up and
they're doing a great job
but I don't know I just I just felt they
had to do this get the education out
there to get the education out there to
find a doctor willing to help in wiip
Pig and I'm still hunting doctors
doctors doctors doct that'll be the
endless day I'm educating my doctor
right now and uh helping we're getting
an incredible amount of uh people in the
senior
category um ages uh 55 and 75 years old
even older uh coming in with ailments
and asking for health and knowledge so
we're assisting and um I'm even even
providing my own doct here with uh
that's a good call that's really where
it starts you need to educate the
doctors locally and uh I would
definitely urge you guys to pull out as
much information as you can from uh the
local Sunday show I run called hash
church it's a a panel I'd love to have
you on Monday actually come to yeah
absolutely come let let us know what's
going on in Winnipeg it would be a good
way for you to get your message out let
people know in Manitoba how to get in
touch with you and uh just sort of kind
of meet you through this unique platform
that is uh the bubble man's world really
yeah appreciate so I guess today we're
going to sit down and I I told these
guys I would show them a little rosin
Tech and I got my little rosin kit here
I've got the uh the little mini hair
straightener the raw um parchment paper
and of course the bubble bag screen now
the straightener has to be flat it has
no edges to it whatsoever yeah you want
it to be flat and that's you'll see
right away when we do this process now
we're going to do a little bit of
headband hash it's got a real nice smell
to it it's a 120 headand is my favorite
oh nice yeah it's a it's real nice oh it
smells like the oh yeah it's got a real
rank sort of dank some some pepper
pepper smell some oh yeah nice e
spicy it was Dwayne right that's right
right I didn't introduce Dwayne and
Kelly I did introduce Kelly earlier but
Dwayne and Kelly are also here with us
and we're uh we're just going to make
some rosin let's do this we'll use a
nice fresh spot on the screen so you can
really kind of get an
idea and uh and how good is this size of
screen to this is a good size screen
this is a 25 micron um the hash itself
is a 120 Micron so this hash was
collected in 120 Micron screen so all of
these glandular heads would be larger
than 20 microns and smaller than 160
microns which is the other next bag
above 120 if you're familiar with the
Bubble Bags they start at a blue bag
which is a 220 goes to a green bag which
is a 190 and trim and trim identifies it
well this is uh the trim does identify
it on the bags but the bags are all that
one color so you'll get a blue bag a
green bag 190 then I thought a red 160
the one that's right above this the
orange 120 uh 90 which is black 7 which
is gold 45 white and then finally the 25
which is this size screen is a purple
bag so the bags come with these as
pressing screens to dab the water out of
the hash to prepare it for micro planing
or seing which is another show
altogether but yeah we'll just get this
wrapped up in a little kind of
ball looks the P pretty much Little
Ghost little hash that's exactly what
it's going to be a little hash ghost so
it's a good idea to put press it too you
can kind of see just from pressing it
that the oils are already starting to
appear on on the tiny amount it's a very
tiny amount so you know it's not like
we're going to get a huge amount back
but it'll definitely be enough that
you'll see it on the parching table is
uh are we plugged in with the uh the
hair straightener should be okay we are
plugged in
yeah all right so you guys got to see
that simply enough right there's nothing
oh no she's not warm at all no no don't
worry I can turn it on okay and it when
I turn it on it can only be turned turn
on for a small amount of time before
it'll get too warm so I'll have to do
the pressing and then we'll turn it
off e up
so here we go with this now you'll hear
it sizzling night
potentially but you'll also seees start
leaking out of
these the
paper the top yeah the sides oh yeah
it's all right so that's one
okay now now do you that's a nice smell
yeah it's like beautiful oil with no
solvents like made in a fraction of a
second that's Bey
smell plus is good work
out yep and just a small little amount
of
hash and we've got dabs wow boom dabs
and then uh a tiny little puck oh W of
hash that you could then take and you
could put that into a coconut oil you
could soak this cuz there's still oil
soaked into the pressing screen you
could soak and recollect that either in
an Ever Clear I would say is probably
the safest a 190 proof Vapor evaporate
out the alcohol and you'll be left with
like glass like literally like very
potent medicine that you could once
again stuff people would have been
throwing away produce a highgrade
coconut extract with it and you know
some kidney and liver cancer can you use
a larger amount than you just did
yeah yeah you can my friends are using
50 60 G at a time and using giant
t-shirt presses getting
like yeah this is already been stepped
up this is just the baby version you
know let's a kit version this is just
for fun like we just did this
city yeah well that's what I'm saying
look at how T it is this is like
[Music]
nice all right here we go little head B
down for
you that three star bubble hash Seven
Star wow wow wow it's always fun showing
people rosing for the first time's that
for
sure it's not bad hey guys that's really
nice and how like oh yeah this is this
is right in front of your own eyes this
is organic as like there's no you know
what I like about this there's nothing
as adults we are able to find the safest
way to do things easier than we were
when we were kids and so what I love
about this is that the younger people
the younger generation that were just
yesterday even blowing up making butan
not the best way to go about things blow
kids blowing up is by far the worst
thing that's ever happened in me
cannabis world before that it was the
DEA it was the
that's why Health Canada is smart and
and we're allowed to produce uh uh
resins and oils but without the butane
process because because of its dangerous
activity to well you don't want to be
blowing yourself up or whatnot this this
is just much
easier man it's t cleaner it's so
tacky yummy you ready Mark oh
yes here we
go that was quite the
ring
awesome over to Kelly we just got to
basically wait for the Dabber to cool
down each time because it's so hot it's
melting
yeah oh yeah we got the Dil we got it
all here we got the tur we got the Fab
EG we got the Fab EG we got the D limine
from Horatio Delbert representing in
Manitoba I think that uh now can you
travel prise prise with your medicine on
the you can now luckily because um for a
while as you guys know the Owen Smith
case in British Columbia which really
cracked open derivatives for all of
Canada based on seven uh Supreme Court
just justices who just decided was all
oh yeah all seven of them voted that it
had to change I love you Supreme Court
Justices and that derivatives had to be
allowed but before they did that how
that case got to the Supreme Court was
it was given um a descent I believe it's
called out of the Supreme Court of DC
which is the provincial Supreme Court
three judges uh they took the case there
and one of the judges basically struck
down the law changed the word dried to
just marijuana and for a couple of years
in British Columbia we were allowed
derivatives and extracts I've been
allowed them in for my Canadian license
for several years now and now it's
Federal now it's it's Federal before I
was not allowed to bring my concentrates
to Manitoba or to Ontario or to any of
these other provinces now
I can go anywhere in the country with my
derivatives of any kind and it's all
medical candies and it's all it's big
deal perfect timing for ymch to open up
and that's the reason now you can come
and show us stuff like this here yeah
exactly safely yeah and at risk to no
one cuz I mean we're well past we're not
we don't need to put you see everybody
like we can't even start a fire with
this okay this is safe
no chemicals no preservatives it's easy
it's all organic and
natural yeah agreed and uh that's what
all of this was made from was from
squeezing out hash with a good friend of
mine d420 K shout out buddy and yeah we
pressed that out made some beautiful
rosin and it's been doing me great I've
left it open in the humidity it hasn't
buted up oh that that was a nice creeper
I like that you like that headband right
very oh yeah it feels
yeah yeah
yeah first time I tried it was pull that
a little closer so we can get closer to
Jo you heard of C cannabis is living
medicine and first time yeah it's first
time I tried to head B I was there
okay as a medicinal use
it I just use cannabis for all reasons I
love its industrial applications I love
it medicinal applications it's
preventative applications it's
recreational ation I just love it it's
it's a it's social initiative as well
for people who are suffering anxiety dab
it up it's nice to be hitting dabs here
in Winnipeg at the really the first
dispensary the
ymch I like
it this headquarters all
right careful with the Fab
next the host here all right the host
with
theie
that yeah very f 25
M not now how much how much can you say
like get cramps out of this um square
piece what do you mean like like well
not like from extracting well as many as
you put in you mean you could reuse it
of course over and over that's why I
told him you clean it alol to save the
the whatever's left on the screen W and
how much is a piece of this cost oh it
sells for like10 or12 online wow yeah
just it's a tool that you can just use
it's not
like oh we we got to throw them away
that would be a shame well no I no yeah
no that's that's good to know that's why
[Music]
ask good thing to ask
absolutely open dialogue well that was
wonderful and delicious was great to
share uh some raos and dabs with you
guys show you the process which I
suspect in the near future you'll be
able to come down to the uh cannabis
headquarters and uh potentially pick up
some rosin of of their own I believe you
will be so you can do it with flowers as
well so you can make flower rosin and
you can make hash rosin and can you use
the same screen for for both you don't
even need a screen for for flowers you
can just put it bre there close it just
understand the smaller the bud you use
the higher the yield seems to be the
more bud you put if there's not enough
water or moisture in
the steaming it out it has a further
distance to travel you want to use dense
dense yeah you just want yeah it's nice
to even some people take and kind of
press it up to get it pre- ready for for
pressing Al will be able to walk you
guys through that when he comes back
he'll press out some buds show you what
you've seen it once now you'll be able
to riding the bike ring bik just don't
over press or you'll get a very very
dark product hash is always going to
produce a darker product so you'll get
something like that right whereas with
uh you know with the bud you can get
clear and and yellow product very easily
and sativas are probably best to work
with they they all work great all the
plants that have resin will will you'll
be able to learn a lot about your plants
and the buds by how much sometimes
you'll take a butt and you'll squeeze it
literally get nothing and that is not a
good
s before you buy herb you should have
someone sitting with
a see what I get cuz sometimes you take
a button you press it you open it up and
it's insane what it looks like it's just
oil everywhere other times you get like
almost nothing that's and that's the
word of God rather than some sales look
the crystals
on how much res do we gete what what do
you mean I just let me pull out my hair
[Music]
shaper [ __ ] man your hair curly what are
you talking about well I don't use it on
my hair as you can see I use it jaic
yeah product Checker well dude it was
super awesome sitting down here with you
guys and really appreciate you hanging
out with us and uh I appreciate you
coming man yeah I want to definitely get
the word out and we'll have you guys on
hash church one of these weekends you
can let us know how it's going keep us
us updated to for sure to the fight here
in winneg and if we need be you know
you've got a lot of people behind you at
the drop of a dime if uh things get
rough and they start causing problems
we'll make sure that we get uh all the
right people behind you appreciate it
very much awesome GL thank you yes Mark
nice to meet you pleasure always good to
sit with Kelly oh yeah you can't forget
about way great support yeah for sure
awesome I need all the support we can
get in Manitoba here yeah well that's it
and this is my home uh Province so how
can I not support uh where I'm from
thanks for watching Bubble man's will
guys all right so I'm here with Glenn
the owner of the dispensary here in
Winnipeg I keep forgetting the name it's
the ymch your medical cannabis
headquarters your medical cannabis
headquarters okay I like that I'm never
going to forget it again so he's going
to show us a little bit of the bud here
and I lik what you just said there about
uh if people aren't happy with the
product that they buy what what do you
let them do exchange it or if they don't
want it if I don't have something they
like I'll give them their money back
well that's pretty sweet right there all
right
beautiful very nice very nice and
hybrids have come a long way as us
Canadians are very famous for
experimenting and connecting the best
bud together beautiful
beautiful so we got that one was what
Alien OG Alien OG and then this one is
pink cush pink cush the golf
balls what you were saying nice to have
it that way hey yeah and then he's Grape
God just going back through them this is
really pretty can we and fragrant can we
sample a uh extraction of a bud
like to squeeze it you mean on parchment
paper uh possibly when Al gets back he's
quite good at that I wouldn't want to uh
mess anything up and then this one's the
PK yeah p and I have some nice rockar
here too oh
rockar all right yeah very fragrant very
aromatic grown properly nice uh Crystal
nice white ash see oh there you go
beautiful flushed it proper yeah nice
and clean so that's nice to see that you
guys are producing some nice medicine
for the local people to come and access
yeah that's really nice beautiful I
think I'm most impressed with grape God
I really liked it yes me too it's one of
my favorites anything with the fruity
name would be a gra this one concentrate
right I'm going to I'm going to purchase
this one nug that's why I touched
it you don't need to purchase it you can
have for being a guest I'll get my card
here look at that
beautiful very
nice awesome now
uh now we're maybe going to go squeeze
some of it and turn it into rosin for
sure not maybe we
are hey guys bubble man here I just
wanted to give you guys an update on
your medical cannabis headquarters in
Winnipeg as well as Glenn uh it's
Thursday today I'm just uploading the
video today I was trying to get it up as
a puff Wednesday for a Winnipeg puff
Wednesday uh but unfortunately that did
not work out and I have been in touch
with Glenn and mark from the
ymch uh on Monday I believe or Tuesday
the police came in and asked them
politely to stop selling uh cannabis
they agreed because they were so polite
that day that they they told them that
they would stop for two days and that
Thursday today they would resume uh I'm
going to put a link into the comment
section of this video so you can check
it out and it's uh so to come back to it
um they've been told to not sell
cannabis by the police today is Thursday
the day that they're going to start
selling again and I'll keep you updated
I'll put that link for the CBC story uh
that they did on Glenn in the ymch and
we'll keep you updated and anyone from
Manitoba please if you can support the
ymch whether you use cannabis
medicinally or not it's a good idea to
give uh the Winnipeg Police a call and
and let them know that you definitely uh
as a taxpayer of Manitoba in particular
would prefer them not to waste your
money uh harassing people that are
really just doing good for people in
need um yeah terrible to hear Glenn
sorry that you guys are going through
this but you have a support on Bubble
man's world and we'll hope to see you
guys real soon keep watching Bubble
man's world
[Music]