hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
welcome to Kingston Jamaica and welcome
to puff Wednesday's yeah it's a puff
Wednesday and of course we're we're
missing some of our regular guests
Johnny B and flab and D 420k are all in
Canada right now and I miss you guys and
I'm thinking about you guys but I'm here
in Jamaica in case that so today's pop
Wednesday's gonna be a little bit never
ever gonna have sloughed motorcycles rip
it down through the streets of Kingston
we got Emancipation Park that we're
gonna go down in and maybe talk to some
people later on and see what their
thoughts are on ganja God you use here
in Jamaica and what the government's
about to be doing in regards to amending
the laws and allowing the people to use
it as a medicine
pretty exciting times here in Kingston
Jamaica so why don't we start this puff
wednesday off with a puff wednesday rib
despite coming
for a bowl as I do not have an extension
cord for the [ __ ] and I haven't got a
torch yet for the club banger
thanks again dark crystal glass and
Canada DC glass CA for your killer ports
bangers they're thick they're awesome
and they give a really tasty hit so what
else can I say about them puffs
Wednesday what are we going to start it
up with we've got some flow og little
ninety micron we've got some flow og
little seventy-three micron you've got a
little El Jefe at 73 as well some
granddaddy Larry oh gee that's the one
we're gonna hit this morning we also
have some lemon death pie it's a more
global G and a few other things but I'm
feeling me granddaddy Larry OG in here
it's just unbelievably stuck in here
I'm very happy to have the ship let's
just make sure you have I guess this
will be our carburetor today
alright well pop Wednesday in Kingston
Jamaica bless up
well that's a pleasant way to wake and
bake here in Kingston Jamaica I have no
real idea what's going on today I think
there might be a Kabakov pyramid later
Kabakov pyramid show along with marcia
griffin and some others at the Randy
Williams Center so I'm pretty excited
about the opportunity to get it over
there hopefully Tony's going to join me
and who knows perhaps Tony Tony will
come out and join me for a little bit of
a wake and bake puff here I'm gonna have
one more little hit Lemmon death pie
sounds good the lemon def pie as well
all right eleven week and baking in
Jamaica it's one of the rare times that
I'm actually in the room alone we
usually have a dozen people or more so I
thought I'd start this puff Wednesday
out by literally even if we don't go
anywhere in the least what I'll do is
I'll just share everyone's first puff
that they come into the room for it like
I said hopefully we get over to
emancipation apartment the camera and we
can talk to some of the people that are
just walking through the park get their
opinions on what they think the gun to
laws here in Jamaica and whether or not
it's time to change the whether or not
they're embracing this opportunity for
Jamaica so all right here we go death by
[Music]
yeah that's the stuff it's gonna be a
good puff winds they keep watching I
guess this is Wednesday bubble man said
that I have taken full meltdown first
thing in the morning so I I'm gonna try
out this news silicon carbide now yes
they tried it out for the last couple
days and I you know I actually kind of
like it it's better than it's better
than definitely better than titanium
I haven't had I haven't had really a lot
of time to mess with temperatures and
things like that and compared to course
but one thing is it's got a very even
distribution in the way the heat
vaporized the full melt and it was
really easy to clean and it hasn't
unbelievable taste I think these are
probably gonna end different place and
all the titanium that you see out there
but yeah we've had a couple puffs
Wednesday you might see I see a couple
new people
here we've had prophecy richard spice
and total different managers bands and
artists stop goodbye we've got some
different parties to go to a bank and i
think there's actually one of the event
what we got on yeah
tonight we have cabaco pyramid and
marcia Griffin's and like some other
artists and then the next day I think on
Bob's birthday we have chronics nomads
and cabaco pyramid and then the next day
the day that you leave there's a big
concert that's also a Taurus Riley and
cocoa tea and Marcia again on Saturday
the on Saturday yeah yeah I'm gonna
appreciate it yeah dude wakey-wakey
[Music]
it's why they call puff Wednesday to
thumbs up for to tears down well hey
what's up its puff Wednesday a bow man's
world knocking keeps Jamaican came
Jamaica ready to do it
[Music]
because it warms up so I'm gonna hold
control he's gonna melt it a little bit
first if they went to go I'll tell you
mine you'll see it's gonna turn or die
and it's Wednesday it is you think oh
and it's worth one is this
just getting it warmed up a little bit
so the wax it plays away yeah it just
kind of heats it up into a more liquidy
state and then you ready
taking a trip on the mothership it's
just telling heavy a little bit about
the prana line so what that does is make
categories so instead of saying one
string to help you catalogs strange
groups so this one would be sativas that
rth seems TLC eight yeah this one is
high CBD yeah that's like CBD the THC
remember pureplant profiles so it's like
taking cold pressed oil so it's a rock
is raw concentrated forms of plant
cannabinoids
terpenes and everything
all right and then this ones
she became CBN is there one he should
hit before a dab or just after death
this right here is the p1 it's been
activated so if you like if you like the
way which I'm guessing he does because
I'm not sure I've ever seen heavy
without a spliff in his hand actually
you almost dropped that right on the
ding of the phone yeah it was pretty
cool
all right now it's time for that sort of
like bones when I take a few minutes
ladies thought they might have some
Center pants at yeah all right no
perturb that once I drop whatever you
looking for that point
all right like that in a second or do
you want to try business ie so give it
about I'll give an example
Hugh Rowland's look you're smoking maybe
a grant 3/4 on the ground so that's
going to be like 50 to 60 milligrams of
THC exactly so what I gave you
and usually lose
70% of the effectiveness by just smoking
this year's Combusken not vaporizing and
we're not doing so this delivers at 99%
sublingual
for militants of two drivers it's your
blood
this you have to look at
in sections of 60 milligrams she smoked
the joint right
that's like the equivalent
the drives you
percent more to get the same
[Music]
No
you [ __ ] old
laughs that joy and
so it gives you the cleanest
yeah sublingual so it's glandular right
your blood
let's offer let's give them that dad
time to death so you might feel a little
bit more mellow
well that's just dripping it dripped
right onto the table in fact that's why
[Music]
tastes almost more like a steam pipe
yeah then one of my favorite mothership
a yeah I mean
gotta still me that's it
[Music]
how's that for a puff once ya [ __ ]
even know you know
[Music]
Oh
thanks for you I just I was just gonna
say give thanks for the music Marlon
respect
and he's gonna hit a dab
- smooth vibes
mater banner
[Music]
you play instruments as welcome on
guitar and stuff big jumps and all nice
you'd be wicked
[Music]
it sounds great
so once it was the first time you've
heard this
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah
[Music]
turn it on the youth say turn it on the
youth
[Music]
all right hey guys welcome back to
bubble man's world I'm sitting here with
a friends from a few years ago now I Amy
you vacuum the house give thanks man
he's really good to see you
i met i ink ii maybe three years ago
here in Kingston and he was he was
singing that I actually met him through
his juicing company that he had going on
so he was a blessing in the sense on he
chase irregularities yeah exactly
that's right was a gem nisha that we
would snow it was like tortillas
Tony's that's right what they chose it
still around her yeah the huayra still
there what their chief ended the concert
cross-country say goodbye it was like a
concert series oh all right well anyway
a couple years have gone by and I guess
you're doing long time music now you
know we know what stopped you the music
you know Jerry you know as impossible
mentioned in her
I mean really that's even like it's a
struggle whether you would be wanting so
I always I feel so in other words a
means of capital Katya
education is a plan that's that's all
yes that's the good work that's why it
would immunity and the juice as well
mm-hmm Liberty right there I mean I tell
ya it was a huge relief to me because I
don't really like to drink pop or kind
of sugary drinks so it's a bonus I think
well what do we have here come in
pineapple ginger yeah this is fine aqua
this is pineapple and ginger this is
pumpkin pumpkin are we use society
that's the milk piece it's super
delicious is all I can say the pumpkin
is the most delicious drink is the one
that got you tricked me out yeah it got
me go on a hard board even when like
different artists would come through I
remember like cocoa tea came over at one
point or seven down there's none cuz I
came to like a drink
and I think he was sitting there like
what did these guys gonna offer me to
drink
yeah and I he was like what do you have
I'm like I got June plum beets
pumpkin and he kind of looked up and
he's like pumpkin
yeah give me a pumpkin yeah it was like
pour a glass of adamant right away he
knew as well he actually recognized that
that was really good juice yeah very
gentle so aya has the gut recipes he's
able to mix it up in the good ratios
that I'm super appreciative so yeah I
want to thank you for coming by I was
somewhat amusing yeah I'm a juice but
the concept was said Samia wild wasn't
my fault from younger fella Josiah Samia
will elute most of my food from a boat
me and a boy under file or chairman
emeritus aha yeah it was a little puta
Union OC to them say oh you survived
over to attune atomic energy street like
a street with my bookie for the keratin
build mobility cane every second like a
24-hour clock so my code is 24 so hasta
mañana familiar green pepper fat awesome
I passed on tambry no dents Emma Thomas
assumed home Manami amiably no song
joong chromecast bananas Russian McCain
yet no caption Samia goblin of some
mango antosha Managua Casa
iris Tamara [ __ ] awesome Pokemon Irish
mush right a non-monogamous make a peep
[Music]
yeah get back sighs I'm a big time movie
what's on the program too boring for us
well what's on the program for right
this minute is a puff Wednesday puffs
down with kidís I we just came from the
building respect listen though
listen live so we've got a little bit of
mothership fun for you tomorrow is
Thursday I'm not sure what's on the
agenda for I know Friday would love to
go see the nomads in Kabbalah pyramid in
chronics every ten percenter but in this
day that's some kind of automated you're
just 15 minutes from here
which fun okay well that's I'm sure that
we take time to go right over here those
are no comments and therefore since we
working on
okay this is something is that what do
we wanna prototypes again make sure you
don't touch it figure the others you'll
know when you know this isn't a kiss his
first rodeo on the dev's
double it up on that it's gonna be real
nice hit this is a new substitute off um
it's a ceramic called silicon carbide
and it's a very hard and very tasty no
release of any sort of off gassing at
this temperature just really clean it is
always can hang tough and puff as tough
as the next guy so this puff winds they
just keep going I kind of thought it
might have been over but we're still
going on puff Wednesday and we've had
I ain't you the juice man came gonna
hook me some juice I have the pumpkin
juice I have June pump and I have a
pineapple ginger and I you just brought
that Wednesday's what's going on in
Jamaica with God right I don't know wood
paintings at the moment it seems as if
we're good
they legalized bus the errors no we said
that we worked out is nicely Oh
participle players
and the reason agnostic it was that or
suggested the farmers get 180 companies
and their work in cooperatives
foreigners as investors we want to
compare the split to joint venture
photographs with them this is what they
were at that conference so you're there
was it a to three day conference two
days two days okay another little bit I
suppose we see so that's health justice
okay I'm learning all these ministers in
industry and our worst commerce yeah and
then even maybe another development mmm
weird um Wallenberg Albert right see
right will join us for a little example
don't you guys remember
yeah well just kick kids is telling a
little bit about the conference that
just happened and what these guys were
talking what they were offering to
started collogues farm there's an acre
at a time with creating coops and then
joint ventures so that foreigners that
come in and can't just start their own
projects but required to make partners
and so that all sounds pretty reasonable
but the job's not the JumpStart
excellent it's good to see that things
are moving forward each time we come
back there's more to be said there's
more to good so let me know what you
think of the juice I think my Amy's got
it down they make some really nice juice
Tony wins they've really and this puff
Wednesday if I manage to go out tonight
with these guys to SS I'll grab the
camera do a little footage the walk is
just the function of either 2031
finished like 12:30 so if we do go it's
just nice it just seems like what he
goes to learn the next morning it's
harder for me to go this is how this is
what happens I'll go to the show people
go you have to show whatever it's
awesome and I'm like who's playing Oh
Susan was supposed to play it tonight
I'm like sees my sisters play tonight
and then it's like a one o'clock two
o'clock three o'clock four o'clock five
o'clock six o'clock seven o'clock eight
nine ten eleven twelve o'clock the next
day noon that's what sizzle it goes on
the same I got there the night before a
7 plus TV yeah you gotta have the
cardboard to go to just catch a few
challenge madcap no cat now anyway
respect thanks for sharing
with us yeah it looks good and but what
no we terminated is a community
prevention also you said for instance 55
years of one acre apiece
[Music]
go spike this 20 hey what's the advice
the farm tomorrow I'll come see what I
mean there's other a jump start or
whatever what I take fun I'm in the
moring
we saw something yesterday at the vet
Gmail something else suppose both mature
body that was fruiting kind of look like
Oprah but like bigger like string beans
rice means yeah so yeah it's there's a
chiefdom object before that kind of
quite an extremely adjustable see
because the party is like it
[Music]
you know yet
that would not suffice
it's talking about the Miranda tree for
those of you that don't know about it
you can google it it's em er ing a mor
more Ranga yeah mor yeah it's like an
essential food sources well he can
google it and look it up it's definitely
well we'll do a little video when we go
to kick assistant world and I'll share
it with you guys
they can see a lot of that
medicinal herbs to the pinkie back in
this process with style once again to
the quiver with a single arrow everyone
aquiver with sure canvases the mane is
quite a few the arrows of cannabis
relations with been linked you mentioned
about broccoli and tumeric and other
compounds like garlic or whatever
but mantua's is so-so
yeah what other kind of shoes have you
co-tenant forward without kind of more
Colette I wrote under itself
well our movement asano so predator is
just what I make sure the mites pick it
up when I managed
so you have something that one farm as
well
yeah two or three hours earlier again
it's trying to get my bagel but then I
protects to a whole bunch and then I get
a bunch of 1 2 3 I realize I'm not
giving any taxes even though she is
calling me on taxi he's talking texting
me calling you will catch up with
kidness tomorrow we're just gonna keep
placing bowls and maybe head over to SS
so we'll catch you guys in a bit
that's it love keep the faith
hey guys just heading out of the Pegasus
here we're gonna head over to double
eyes which is at coyopa which is just
down the street here about 10 minutes
I'm just rolling with a couple of
friends here kiddies
[Music]
oh just pulled up the tunes
[Applause]
music there's kavacha right there we
were hanging out with Appa Shay
[Applause]
Billy slices
[Music]
guys I'm with Carl and we're here at a
nation books and we're here at dub wise
boy so you guys are sharing the vibes
with the Buffs these guys have some
great books I wanted to show you guys
real quick
they got horror gays marijuana
horticulture and got all sorts of
incredible books on the Empress and the
Hayley Selassie and all the different
histories of black culture and
Rastafarianism of Scottish Rite
Freemasonry but then they also have
hashish by Robert Cornell Clarke look
there's my fingers holding up a piece of
hash so very cool about that so you guys
bring this around to all sorts of
different people to educate them with
books nice I like that I like the
t-shirts as well I remember think come
on look at that the sensimilla technique
this is great dude by Keio 1947 to 1978
Wow very cool
[Music]
we are allah-allah innocent Edith shakes
the once punished on road for a Monday
every Monday six two one six two one
Spanish Town Road wicked Monday yes all
right cool respect my respect
[Music]
bless up Carl
[Applause]
[Music]
everyone the word machine
steamer pop Wednesday puffing on the
chalice Kingston Jamaica dub wise
[Music]
[Applause]
Wednesday
[Music]
[Applause]
oh yeah
Oh
[Music]
[Applause]
well guys I'm just splitting the venue I
got my trippy stick going hard
awesome puffs Wednesday have a great
time listen to some beautiful reggae
music at dub wise want to thank kidís
and the nomads and prophecy and all the
great people Ziggy man for a great set
and see you guys next time on bubble
man's world he's how