[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world welcome to
Puff Wednesday I think this is a puff
Wednesday and welcome Thomas my new um
colleague and business partner Dash col
League uh at Grandmaster LEDs uh if you
guys saw the recent video on Grandmaster
LEDs uh Grandmaster level YouTube
channel uh as well as BC bubbleman's
bubble man's world channel we did a big
video announcing that I'm now working
with grandmas LEDs I've actually been
working with Thomas for some months now
kind of in the back end of things this
is now us putting the tarantula Borg
lights that he has brought to with him
into these two 5x5 tents we've got our
pumps we've got our Reservoir off camera
and we've got our tent expert Johnny B
uh if you haven't been here before
you've seen Johnny B and I build and put
tents together so we're going to blast
these out I guess here in the next uh
half an hour to 45 minutes and uh yeah
I'm really excited to mount those lights
I'm really excited for the lights yeah
and Johnny B brought his light meter of
course yeah we get to talk about white
recipes we can test some stuff out see
this is what's really cool is really
seeing new technologies come to Market
and see what this is this is G you okay
we gotta do just wait let's do it let's
do it all right here we
go put it right on top of that Bo from
my understanding this goes that's
last same with this that's probably the
[Music]
inside
joint
pieces okay so the L I said these must
go in height Johnny stop it you said you
weren't doing anything I haven't done
this before as you can see you're doing
everything
John what the heck I you have some
dabs um give me a um like I said um
what's nice about doing tents and doing
this for so long it's really quite easy
we'll start with a base guys and really
just quick and simple everything has got
to lock them always have them to the
inside so that way they don't get kicked
or pushed on the inside so always make
sure they go on the inside when put
bling like EXC saided I guess I've done
this before I think you've done it a few
times is there one other tall one is
this it right
here that's a one now I'm looking here
so I'm seeing some bottoms here so this
here's got a bottom and bottom so does
look right well because it's not two of
them are ones and two of them are twos
are the ones in the twos exactly the
same yeah they oh no are they yeah the
same one all right we're looking at here
is on the bottom have these these have
to be the ones in between no those ones
are going up too stacked too high oh
okay that's that's what got me but look
on the bottom here John we need to have
the two opposing are ones and the two
opposing are twos I don't know why they
have it that way but so they got ones
and two just make you got a one you got
a one there I got a one here I got a two
here okay well that's a two and then
this
one which I'm almost almost certain it's
a one yeah it's a one so I'll just
replace it with this too maybe it means
nothing but you know what let's just try
to follow the simple
rule follow the rules that goes up the
other way see on the bottom gotta I see
now so there's
no three and a three and a
three and a four or sorry here's a four
oh yeah I need fours four first four
first this must be funny to
watch it's like yeah we haven't built a
tent in a while but been a little bit
but
hey there's a
one I guess we're going to need to do
our ones
again yeah so which ones are ones these
ones right so a one will go here as well
want to get another
okay this do all come together guys this
is the magic right here watch the
confusion watch oh yeah right off the
bat this doesn't line
up these this isn't right
okay this
one I
think you can just hold that for a
second goes like
this told you there confusion coming on
this last part you didn't even get to
see it damn damn I don't think that is
that's tripped out they saw it they're
doing it they're watching a little bit
of the madness that's going on in my
dirty ass
garage there we go make sure you flip
that back the screen cheers Johnny
B now these are just go up top our top
so we got two and one big one right
across the middle here comes the fun
part yeah totally funest part is
actually putting the tent over this so
that's the one that goes right across I
think it's the bottom right here that's
the bottom okay so that's what we need
to slide over yes we're getting there
we're getting there so check it out that
one's a t and they want the te just one
half of the te to go in like this no we
got to go
underneath it right pull
back whole
thing
lift
that just realiz we need a tray for
you supposed to
be um is that the te go
up
Hurt No G everything's solid it's gone
don't stop don't try there you go this
will tighten
up pull this down don't worry about the
PO don't worry about
the the bottom stop
stop there the bottom zipper we're going
to have to deal with
too
which is
[Music]
fine
okay hey I'm stuck in
here someone in there yes I'm in here
Johnny Be zip me up we in there you find
him you see where we can get him out of
there where'd he go yes open the window
you
try window in there these are weird you
weird it's a black
box no this side over
here over here we oh there you are there
I am there I was in here I
know there you go I was in here okay so
should we bust another tent gentlemen
bust another tent let's bust another
tent no where the scissors
at I appreciate
that
mentioning it this already comes with
the bottom plate the only thing reason
why I mentioned the other thing is it's
nice to have a hard tray that you can
screw in a hose that then leads to um uh
a sump
pump like you spin it it's two so then
I'll put one of my down we already have
one ends you don't you only need to put
that on one end and it has to be on the
right one or it won't line up this one
can go right here that's the beauty of
knowing whether you did it right
enough no I just I think it's easier
than you we don't have to risk any this
is this is the Learning lesson number
two now now the best part open this up
prop they make this so you can open up
you know have to do this [ __ ] we just
did let's make sure we do that's kind of
what I was hoping oh totally butchered
it last time yeah a total butcher like
stop we couldn't have got my T any direr
that's for sure so let's take a look
here this going to be this is the bottom
plate take a look the bottom cuz it's a
t remember the Bottom's actually in the
middle if you look at the yeah the the
bottom is in the middle the bottom is
right that
way come right out of here we going well
the Bottom's going to go up it's going
to wrap
around okay
the team so we got to open this
up there's the botom
the
we getting this boys I feel like we're
doing it I feel like we're really doing
it know if you kind have fun while you
know building
some Lego tents with your
buddies are fun these are fun I'm explow
down wait keep it
simple nice about this this one comes
off on the
floor get you on this side
here this corner up here this corner
here
tight well would you look at that and
now we just walk this around walk this
around
get check your
partner come on out here take a bow guys
everybody Mark Thomas Mark come on out
here just a second I'm going to
[Music]
finish done P okay ready Let's Take a
Bow there you
go that was F out well see that's how
it's done good job guys awesome brother
here this is better we're just having
fun we're just having fun of a tent that
was fun let's get that light out boys to
me it's all about this light no offense
to the tents and the pumps and the
thises and the thats and the
reservoir but this light
careful too it might be oh it's upside
down surprised it made it here okay got
this tent what's that completely flip
the tatter what do you
mean oh it's totally upside down I was
just going to say it matter if we flip
it upside down no do you know what
there's a hole on there's a vent on the
bottom of them like they put them on the
ground yeah just flip it let's flip
it
oh that's done pretty s
boom pretty good good
job they missed the flip all right now
we get this
ridiculous this right here is what
brought Thomas and I
together Tula board the tarantula Bor so
why don't you start talking a little bit
about this Beast so this is the world's
most diverse sophisticated light it's a
four Channel light that has the ability
to do anything spectrum that any company
has ever made before and spectrums that
no one has ever made it can go Bluer or
redder than any light has ever had the
ability to go and it also is the very
first LED light that can do an HPS
Spectrum dude it's so sick it feels good
it's heavy it's a is this 54 56 it's
5600 and you can see with the diodes on
the cool Channel they got we've got Evo
mint diodes with EVO 301h diodes and
this is what allows us to to achieve a
double blue wavelength with a 437 NM and
450 and this is our warm white Channel
That's 2200 Kelvin and then we have 660
NM and 730 NM di temperature range of
this light it's 18800 kelv to 9,000 kin
but we can make special units for R&amp;D or
on request that go up to 12,000 Kelvin
the reason why we don't have it 1,800 to
12,000 Kelvin is because you would be
using one driver way more than the other
and trying to have as much balance as
possible so there's a lot that we can do
with this light we can do anything we
can do any how many preset spectrums we
have 60 to choose from but there's
hundreds that we can actually do wow and
what what's really cool about our
controller that just finished this week
um we can literally do multiple
spectrums throughout the day so we could
start the day off with our base spectrum
and then 6 hours in switch it to Blue
for an hour then go to Red for an hour
then back to our base spectrum and then
we can have 730 nanm on until like after
the lights go out so 730 nanomer is in
HPS lights it's not in most LED lights
you can use it to put the plants to
sleep after the lights go out normally
it takes 2 hours for your plants to fall
asleep this does it in 15 minutes this
allows you to finish your crops 3 to
seven days faster we've even seen
someone recently named Mitten master who
finished a crop two weeks earlier
testing these things out 14 days which
is insane that's a big deal for a
commercial outfit huge when it comes
down to power efficiency everything
drawing smiling as he was talking of
course I'm smiling get over here on
camera Johnny I was you a little
conversation Johnny got a lot more
knowledge when it comes to the lighting
than I do whole thing looking at smiling
and stuff like that talking about really
love about the light what you talk about
it's the multiple Spectrum what we're
looking at and controlling those
spectrums and be able to take in like
now think of the future think it it's
100 years and you able to grow canvas
cucumbers peers Tomatoes that's what
this lightel to do it can grow all
different types of products it it can
lead R&amp;D if you're trying to test what
spectrums are the absolute best to do um
this it there's universities that are
going to be using this across the world
to be testing stuff out so dude can we
talk a little bit about the efficiency
of the light and how it plays into
rebates in North America sure well so
for efficiency well you can it doesn't
have to be the most efficient to qualify
for a rebate um but it's got to be over
2.1 micro moles per Jewel but why this
is so important um is the efficiency the
efficacy of this light so you're getting
the most amount of light per watt so say
for example I can we could put in any
company Spectrum except for this light's
going to put out more light per watt now
when we were designing this light we've
changed this design three different
times actually and like this thing took
over a year to actually develop with us
constantly changing it or running into
different obstacles we actually started
with four different driver boxes cuz
it's a four Channel light and we just
realized it was was creating too many
connections for us and there were just
so many different things that we changed
and there was uh we start we actually oh
sorry no no you have't I was just going
to you keep going as you're talking as
I'm looking at this cuz of course I'm
excited right I want to get this thing
turned off dude how about this ballast
see that's what we're looking at that's
our driver box and we designed it like
this so if there's ever an issue we can
just swap that out I like it I like it a
lot so this what you're talking about
the drivers that are in there yeah it's
got four it's got four it's got four
different drivers we use infant Tronics
which is the world's best drivers and um
we just don't cut any corners and it's
the best of the best that's and this is
like a if now if you have the
infrastructure to be able to run these
because it does can it's possible to go
up to 1500 watts even though it's
designed to run at 700 Watts so it does
you do need a bigger infrastructure to
run these but the diversity and the
Competitive Edge that you have is just
it's endless power Le 240 if you going
to run numb so we have one option of
being able to go a driver set that does
120 to 277 volt that auto converts and
then we also have 277 to 480 volt oh
perfect so you got both consumptions
yeah you you definitely well you can we
can do any plug we can make it
compatible with any country didn't
someone ask us for 347 recently yes talk
about that well do you know what it's
what did that mean well 90% of actually
large facilities are on high voltage and
they're using the 347 I don't personally
like messing with it myself if I could
avoid it because when you get high
voltage if you get a shock you can it's
high power it's high power it can really
hurt but what it's efficient it's it's
it's more direct power and it's it's
more efficient but you also are freeing
up more amperage and that's the big
thing about high voltage so if I'm going
from 120 a regular plug to 240 I'm
freeing up double the amperage in my
panel so wa and when we get into
amperage we talk about that so when we
used to run old HPS bulbs and stuff like
that so many amps are using for startups
so we have to turn different lights on
because we blow fuse boxes all the time
we used to have right well you know St
Evol like the aach with this starting up
what is this oh um I'm just try it's
going to be roughly on sorry on I'm just
trying to think on one it's going to be
about 6.8 amps if it was running at full
power but you you never would run it
that's running at 240 it's going to
rough run about 3 and 1/2 amps if you're
running at sorry at 240 can you daisy
chain these up and control them with one
like single controller or you can you
well you for you definitely can daisy
chain them they have an RJ45 Port so
that they connect and they also are um
we've actually just developed a new cord
so that you can actually daisy chain the
lights together so it's uh say here's
one option right here we got so basic
yeah the these are RJ45 so they just go
so what's kind of cool is about with any
of our existing lights they have a rj14
port and when we were designing our
controller we wanted anybody it's going
to hook up to a troll Master it it is
compatible with a troll Master if you
want but it's also we designed it so our
controller so it can be used with any
existing lights that we've ever sold and
anybody else like we basically made it
so it can be compatible with any other
ones yeah we have dude what is your deal
trying to make [ __ ] compatible that's
not how the world Works everything's
supposed to be incompatible so it drives
you it's kind like an apple you can only
buy Apple at least things that work with
one another dude listen that's that's a
nice Vibe right off the bat because it
sort of shows like look we're not you
know let's just create
compatibility let's I'm look listen I'm
excited we're going to need to figure
out what we need to get to hang that
light cuz I'm sure there's something we
need things yeah yeah I'm going to turn
it off for a second but we'll be right
back all right just turn put it in some
ratchets here real quick this all comes
with the
light let's get the other one set up for
the other side
and then it's just a matter of putting
the other one on the other side that's
easy that makes like single person I
can't wait to see this thing light up
dude that's going to be bright it's
going to be
bright I got to get some cannabis plants
in here well hopefully next week we can
get that going oh trust me dude I won't
be waiting much longer I got some seeds
for it I won't have
yeah I think life cycle botanics is
going to have some Cuts ready for us oh
nice maybe get some de bub in here for
the first run ility guys and checked out
that place it was awesome with been
doing at lifestyle Botanical it was it
was really sweet so that was a really
cool you want to come over here Johnny
and you can line this one up you can put
this one up here John oh no no
no so this is going to go right
there I know this on myself it's much
easier do with two people to be honest
yeah yeah for sure I'm enjoying this
although I definitely liked his style I
could EAS do that myself together that
was awesome yeah yeah yeah that was
awesome absolutely
now you just bring it up oh wait we're
got going to have to get the driver in
first well we're going to go right to
there oh yeah where you going to put the
driver up top right on there you know
what I think I think we can get it
higher without the driver so I'll just
send you an
extension wait we're going to just turn
it on though we'll just get it like
we'll mount it it like this just to get
it fire my God you could put the driver
on the roof of the
tent yeah I guess so look at that some
decent coverage that's the kind of
craziest looking tent LED light I've
ever seen actually well we actually have
a light that's designed for a tent
called the Tren lent ultimate that's 56x
56 in that goes into the very Far
Corners that has a special diode
configuration to have the most
uniformity or the best uniformity that
the world's ever seen nice but this is
more for Marcus to kind of play with
Spectrum tuning well that's what I'm
looking forward to looking to manipulate
see what I can find in the world of
resin yeah you want to manipulate it to
have it ooze more resin yeah absolutely
and without question this is going to be
the best option sick well you know what
what I'm doing actually even at my own
place right now as I slept out like four
different lights talking about exactly
what you're doing right by seeing those
light spects and how we're doing this
exactly what the future is being because
you can create your own spectrum and
take a look at how it's going to
produced for us I love it absolutely I'm
excited well let's get an extension cord
and plug this in just to see perfect
what's going to take a second you might
as well just stop push-ups Johnny B's
alarm just went off oh [ __ ] sorry man
you don't have to but we do in man all
right let's get let's get going boys
Johnny face the camera over there I was
going to get Johnny on the military it's
well happens it's it's it's it's push up
time get in here well I'm going this way
oh yeah oh there you go okay all right
here we go ready go 20 yeah keep going
see it's called a pattern interupt guys
this looks great he's like yeah push-up
everybody here's in good shape no my
shoulder I can feel you know what you
know what's awesome you know I do 10 20
40 trying to keep up with Mark
here push no touches the ground I didn't
seen that no touch the ground I still
did 20 yes I don't think I did yes it's
hard to get your nose to touch the
ground when you got a hat on it is a
little hard you know I got a problem
with my shoulder that I just diagnosed I
didn't know now we're doing push I just
like I didn't know I had an issue with
my shoulder can feel that dude that's
funny that's done one go do you need
like three each one or no no just one
spine just one in the middle yeah one
spine you get that one one in the middle
y you sure you need one no I'm good you
good here you go no I just got to do
that just plug it in this side oh
than the blue part A
moveing I fall I almost fell right back
like there's nothing I can do well at
least the tent caught you [ __ ] [ __ ]
there's know where to go
okay okay now wait where's the plug now
is the what plug it in there's the plug
down there plug's right here where's the
plug we want to plug that
in and then we're going to have to get a
extension on call we have
to locate
it
interesting b b very
interesting getting this
done oh yeah let's get the should we
hang it with the other cords first you
know what I mean and then we'll here's
the
manual for the
Borg and it goes through and shows
there's pages and pages and pages of
light frequency spectrums you can see
this is the double blue he was talking
about you talk about the far red 730
nanometer it's a whole [ __ ] ton of
presets whole [ __ ] ton of presets
interesting I'm like I've never been
more stoked to light up a light I I can
say
that all right we got this light and
Driver mounted it was pretty easy mostly
all done on camera just need four people
to lift it up that's it all we needed
was four people to four people that's it
or three disabled people where the their
fourth person I missed that oh you're
two people Johnny there
you okay
so then we're going to need another plug
for the there we go ah oh what do you
got
there so we can control them all we so
we can first start by controlling the so
that's the 9000k
channelo this crazy insanely blue damn
Bluer Than any light has ever been able
to go and a commercial fixture yeah and
then okay so here is the warm white
Channel this warm white it looks very
similar to what HPS is yeah it does
except for HPS also has um 730 nmet in
it so now this is our 660 nmet this is
really hard on the
eyes oh
man without glasses it's I know it's
it's really blinding oh my God it is
terrible and Johnny B's got his light
meter out and he's doing some
measurements all
R oh it's 419 one minute warning you
know more what on so that's an all Red
Spectrum so there you guys go there you
can take a look what's going on here
what he's talking about and I'll add the
far red to that actually the far red now
so well with with that with I'm I'm
going to redo it again there's the far
red so you can see added the 730 so you
dump that in there so you can we can
have fun here guys now let's add the
warm white to it okay now we're going do
sorry this is the it feels like warm
white because that was so red even
though it says command has been finished
yet so now you can see the coming up
doesn't it really show up on my camera
I'm surprised that more doesn't come up
there is that is that what what's on
right now right now I'll do it one more
time is it if you hold it at different
angles will it change no no that's what
you have there right now
okay and then let's uh it's weird it
just doesn't want to show up on the
camera it's just black now let's see
what happens if you put it all
on cuz it's
oh look at all the green Jesus wow I
just wish that I could see it better
it's so weird now yeah I have to zoom in
so far to see the light meter there we
go it's got that double blue far red big
green wellow yeah we could have a lot of
fun with this guys get better if I look
at it this one
mhm so really manipulating in all
different light spects and here's what
we're really seeing here guys so now you
can see this go down just where go there
and L check this out so he just all red
so yeah this is just the far red just
far red that's pretty cool to see and
doing that on the Fly I give me some old
blue 731 nanometers okay so now I'm
going to go check out over here it come
over
here see see the spike of blue oh I see
it all right so that's going to be for
sping and what we're looking at we can
talk there's lots we can talk about all
kinds of things I mean if we would have
had light like this back in like when we
were trying to using all these and
stuffers we were growing in 2ot 3ot
areas so you had to get certain you can
use light to manipulate plant this is
what's so beautiful of what so excited I
I'd be so excited I would yeah this is
like just how
much can you just imagine for like the
first 20 years of my growing if you have
an issue you walk you open open the door
and you're hit with a heat wave cuz you
didn't know you had a failure look at
that look at that that's that's all blue
with tiny bit of red so understanding
you can have so much fun and look at PL
and once you start understanding what
the different you know spectrums have to
offer what
the learning proc then it's an endless
amount we literally have to just test
and of R&amp;D and are you are you testing
for how well it grows the Cannabis are
you are you testing how well it grows
resin or are you yeah how about your
fruits and veg are you testing to keep
your plant shorter are you trying to Str
make your plants stretch keep your
plants shorter it's it's pretty much R
can actually stretch it with far red so
you longate stem create Leaf expansion
we're this is all it's pretty exciting
it's exciting cuz when I was in like in
Mexico I went to I went to when I was in
I took my light meter all over the world
so I've seen all different cool
spectrums and understanding yeah so this
is and then going be a lot of fun this
is yeah this is a lot of fun dude it's
awesome Borg the Borg tarantula yeah I I
appreciate it I really appreciate what
what's going on here and just the
technology and what's happening well
let's get that second one hung man I'm
excited this looks so good I can't I
can't believe how good it looks man we
should hopefully have this thing up and
running within a week or so oh I'm going
to be absolutely on it we're going to be
pushing all right final tent lit
up oh man I know it's so bright you have
the shades on your head dude I didn't
know I didn't know where they were I on
the other hand see where's yours you had
yours on yours are mine are yours no
there's two extra pairs yeah no there's
two pairs he's wearing one and you're
wearing one no there's a third PA no
there's two pairs one came with each
light oh I know I brought a pair too
though brought that's me I just had a
pair on you took yours off these on all
right so this is you know just Jerry
rigged for now we're going to get this
we're going to get this light set up
properly eventually all the extension
cords all of this stuff will be kind of
out of the way but this is is just the
beginning of getting a couple of 5x5 I
don't even have enough extension cords
so that's why this one's dark while this
one's light but we lit them both up
everything's working the drivers are
working on both of them sitting here and
get askk in the Sun going to get some
cannabis plants in here the heat in the
very near future what do you mean you
can Envision it plants growing this put
a string system in here do like she put
a scrog system in your form make it
really nice get single top coals with
this make it really nice and a scrog it
you know what I think I'm just going to
play around I'm just going to play
around going to have a good time these
tents are cly I'm staying here they they
have these clips that you can clip on
for hooking up to tents I just first
time I ever saw them recently they're
kind of sick so that just have
everything grow right through he's going
to have it running with a grow link
sensor so like everything is completely
automatic and we're going to be having
them as a guest to talk about it and
it's mindblowing like I don't I can't
represent what it can really do it's
just so cool it's they've got they've
got Incorporated AI into their system
and thought of every last possible thing
that it could do so beautiful well
listen guys we're going to write say say
sayara here peace to Johnny B who
brought his light meter thank you so
much D it's cool to see that Thomas from
Grandmaster LEDs you're gone I have to
like there you are boom thanks for
coming out buddy and helping put this
all together my pleasure and I'm well
I'm bubble man and uh stay tuned to
Bubble man's world because we're going
to be showing the weekly progress with
these lights the different frequencies
that we're going to use right down to
the resin coming out of the bubble bags
and the dry sift screens and uh hope to
see you
soon peace out everybody peace out peace
keep
pushing