[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
we are sitting here in beautiful British
Columbia on my deck actually with uh
Brett from West Coast concentrate in the
house and we've got trees Maestro here
from uh online I guess I met you
originally in Jamaica but before we were
doing periscopes and seeing each other
uh through social media platforms and we
totally hit it off he was one of our big
helpers along with Ross and Austin in
Jamaica for the Cannabis Cup there Tony
and I definitely couldn't have survived
without the help that Cameron uh and uh
Ross and Austin gave us so it was uh
it's great to have you in BC dude oh
it's great to be here first time out
here so it and with your beautiful glass
oh dude I was pretty surp I knew you
were coming up to get a heady piece from
the boys I had no idea that you were
bringing also he pieces so maybe you
want to give us a quick little rundown
on the two pieces that you brought here
yeah absolutely so this first one here
is the Technicolor dream cycler made by
Cory glass uh that's Cory cottenham Cory
glass on Instagram Patrick Stratus
that's Stratosphere glass on Instagram
and Nish and that's Nish glass on
Instagram also um this was made for them
about a year ago uh just the the classic
uh double Klein recycler and then on the
other side of that we've got uh one of
the first uh Stratosphere tricycler
prototypes um not quite sure if that's
the first one made but uh we have an
inkling that it might be so yeah with
the big old puking beagle the big old 30
mm puking beagle Banger the skillet
Banger yeah that is the glob stopper as
they say totally ridiculous so we were
thinking today we were going to do a
little bit of bowls out here on the deck
and we also thought maybe we'd get the
Drone out give you guys a little bit of
the footage from my deck off the Drone
and then take it up north to Shannon
Falls this epic waterfall that uh is
always beautiful and cool on a hot day
like today to just go have a session y
we've got all sorts of West Coast
concentrate resins along with some
concentrated X here that we're going to
be hitting throughout the day thanks to
West Coast concentrate and to
concentrated X for uh for making such
nice products here we got some beautiful
stuff man i' got that green crack God I
got got the PK 90 first 90 from you guys
I ever got I went and had breakfast with
Adam the other day and he was like have
you ever gotten any 90 I didn't think
you guys had a 90 bag they're coming
dude I love to hear that let's start
with the pk9 for that very
reason yeah we understand that those
heads are a little bit more desirable so
I started running them and it's
phenomenal oh wow isn't that beautiful
definely going to have to uh photograph
this but after we hit it cuz uh this is
not one of those situations where uh
where we're not going to be hitting it
first yeah you hit it on the next 90
batch there no problem exactly get it on
the next it's actually quite just in the
middle of greasing up now from uh being
uh beautiful and uh powdery so you want
to start us off Brett I can do that get
that out of your
way
yeah nice move with the slide I thought
he was going to pick it up I was really
definitely impressed with the slide give
that a little twist off the top there
boom
you got a hole right
here this piece hits really deep and
thick when I dry hit it it was just like
glug glug glug glug glug you don't
realize it but the two tubes on either
side are the recycler Chambers where the
water's filtering through it's pretty
damn cool it definitely delivers a
pretty heavy hit deep deep yeah deep J
yeah it's definitely one of those pieces
that you can feel I haven't even
actually hit it ever dry hit it now
twice a year ago when Stratus brought it
to the hotel and I photographed it in
Vancouver I have beautiful pictures of
this pipe actually I'll pass your way
cuz uh well cuz you're the keeper of the
pipe these days much yeah absolutely you
sticking dirty [ __ ] in there I didn't
all right I didn't on you if you noticed
I scraped it and managed to get it off
without really digging and creating a I
dug a little bit but it's all right oh
yeah the hashm diligence here I'm
learning it's the photography it's
nothing else it's the anal photographer
it makes no sense in any other way that
people out in the world would be like oh
yeah bubble man says you should scrape
no no it's totally only for photos
otherwise I do exactly what Brett just
did so all right here you go I feel kind
of bad that it's like you're last in
this tour but hey I've enjoyed it a lot
already true enough but not the West
Coast well I guess you have enjoyed the
West Coast as
well oh yeah melt on that what would you
say Mel's definitely on point tast is
definitely true to a PK
which is always which is always
something too when you run a strain
through water you're just hoping that it
carries through its you know same
taste what do you
think I think it's tasty as [ __ ] yeah
beautiful always those strains that have
alcohol soluble Tarpin that transfer
through in the water process they don't
Lee out into the water they stay true
all the way to uh the end product and
it's
just it's a wonderful thing when that
happens it's a wonderful
thing I'll give you that thank you very
much down
here probably shouldn't have left that
little guy out in the sun man is it soft
I
know it's 18° today it's got to be 18°
look at that little bit of
bubble oh yeah that's there for a
while yeah Che out to everybody in
YouTube land buffing bows on the B man's
deck cheers to you is this the first
time you've tried an for us as well yeah
good and what a great place to be
hitting it there's really not not too
much of a better place to be in it I'm
really looking forward to heading up to
Shannon Falls and seeing if we can't
pull off a really beautiful drone climb
up the waterfall to share with the
audience and of course we're going to go
have a session up there too beautiful
place it's really cool uh there shaded
areas cuz the Mountain's So High where
the waterfall comes off of and it's a
lot of big rocks and you get a Mist you
get actually quite a mist from the water
it's really pumping which I suspect it
is uh as we got so much rain and snow
all season long have you been up there
before oh yeah you've done a video with
d up there I took D up there before yeah
I've been going up there for years so I
haven't done many videos other than just
the one with with d420 k um but and
that's on our Sizzler as well the
Sizzler yes yes that's that's where I
seen it and I'm definitely excited to go
up and check it up always he's down with
a good waterfall on a nice day I think
we're going to go Green Crack God 120
that uh that 90pk superb Brad cheers to
you and the team how the color on that
one Phil by Phil Phil shout out to Phil
full melt certified by the bubble man
and I would say the last one was
definitely a six-star
yeah I would definitely call it a
six-star yeah grown by Phil some of it
was extracted by Phil some of it was
extracted by us nowadays who knows the
team's just working as hard as they can
to get as much uh te six star out there
get it out there to the people man see
see how we can kind of do yeah we can
move that one so the gcg in general
seems to be a lot more stable thank you
sir you are welcome do you want to
switch do you want me to hit this um
it's up to you yeah you know what we hit
this one round so why don't we go do the
Fab EG for a round let's do it and then
we'll uh we'll do some torch rips on the
on the skillet guy there Green Crack God
super stable wicked wicked wicked color
on this I'll have to go through some
pictures and find uh find them to add to
the video cuz of course everyone always
loves those macro photos so they can
kind of see what we're seeing oh
absolutely like you say it's uh it
really is God's word when you uh when
you put it in front of the lens right
yeah it's almost seeing what you're
trying to describe in taste and flavor
and in star rating right you know this
for thank
you oh yeah dude it really is a way to
unveil there is there's no getting small
dabs of this there's just big DBS that's
what I was trying to tell you that's
okay it just kind of comes out of the
jar because we're sitting in hot weather
just comes out as clumps versus and it
looks nice and and grandular and Sandy
but as soon as you put a Dabber into it
whatever's touching that Dabber comes
out with it and whatever's touching that
comes out comes out with it as well
exactly so is that due to uh bursting
the triome head like on
contact I would
say man that is so
tasty at 120
oh yeah really nice taste yeah the juicy
G is something that we get to run enough
of and it's it's always a pleasure it's
always like damn look how white that is
when it comes out of the bag definitely
not uh never mad at running the 120
let's get Cameron on point for that it's
crazy too I'm noticing just the color
difference in a 90 to a 73 a lot more
these
days they're definitely different Siz
glind
heads definitely
and you pick whatever we're oh we should
do
this actually no let's do
MK yeah I'm going a MK going he wanted
to try the uh strawberry
banana concentrated concentrated a I
always like trying that cheers guys yes
nice size dab yeah came out like that
yeah
exactly really excited to head up to
Shannon Falls man I got to say me too
I've never been super nature and
beautiful and although I know people are
like oh you're
your deck is beautiful in nature it's
just it's still nice to get out of your
home and into other zones and this
waterfall is definitely one of the most
impressive waterfalls oh wow that resin
incredible you guys heavy
right I think the gcg is definitely
heavy in turps and heavy in the in that
head slapper oh yeah no no question
great rip off yeah me too R too big one
bigger than I would normally have taken
because and you took one right before
cuz we mucked it up and had to edit it
out we didn't even have to tell anybody
that but I did and I might even edit
that out so you may still not know we'll
see we'll see we let you
know all right are we doing this yeah I
guess we're going to hit this last piece
here we got the torch where we can kind
of maybe get this guy more out of the
place move this over and uh yeah we got
this which is good to keep separately
there is that how you like it see you
had it that's your carb capab right so
have that accessible and then uh oh yeah
we were going to hit uh well this will
be the ultimate test really to Skillet
out the strawberry banana let's do it
and do you want to torch it for me cuz
you know the Banger a little bit better
absolutely
absolutely I'm not too good with Banger
temps just cuz I'm super on the eail all
you know what I'm I'm going to have to
apologize too I usually use the little
tiny baby torch so uh if I we try it my
lungs will be the guinea pig all right
right lighter the better
usually there you go there we go these
torches that's why we have the D Nails
yeah it's definitely why we have the d
nails and once you get torching outside
in the bright Sun with the wind a little
bit blowing with a little bit of Cool
Wind yeah you just kind of like the cool
down ratees way quicker certainly a
guessing game but it's a fun one to play
when you've got got great resin yeah
exactly this looks pretty
good I
appr dry sift or bubble dry sift nice
that should be plenty hot perfect should
I wait or should I go in i' give it
maybe 10 seconds okay 10 seconds it
is and this is the curve yes it is all
right and you use that to direct the
flow of your resin on the inside you let
me know when you want me to drop it go
ahead
boom perhaps a little warm it's
all crazy a little warm but you need you
need warmer for sift and bubble
oil so you tell us 10 seconds not enough
15 20 I would go 50 you
yes beautiful
yeah the the uh prototypes are are a
little bit cumbersome compared to the
more modern
tricycler right I think he scaled them
down to around uh 10 in now got to talk
pretty loud when you have the torch on
just sorry yeah uh I think Stratosphere
has scaled these pieces down to around
10 in now versus about 13 where it's at
right
now it's definitely a big boy but it's
it chug is nice the 4 second rip I did
hit out of it because it was so quick
quick um was very nice a tri cycler I'd
give it give it like
10 I'll give it 10 you give it give it
like 15 then give it 15 why not I I
personally like smoking resin out of
lower temp than higher a lot of people
tell me oh if you use a Q-tip it's waste
I'm like I don't know about that waste
to taste yeah I just like taste that's
why I smoke I like the effect too there
you go
still strawberry banana it comes through
nice perfectly hit yeah even with me it
was a little hot but that that
strawberry banana comes through yeah
mine bubbled beautifully yeah so let's
get one for cam here do you want me to
CP this then we get to head out of here
oh
worries to sh
Falls not too far this is my first time
trying the uh strawberry banana from
concentrated deck I'm really excited
about that it's
nice shout out to DNA for the for this
flavor giv on the bubble too the double
the double the double bubble and sift
thank you you tell me when you want
it at 10 seconds
yeah a good test too find if you put the
resin on top of the Banger you'll see
how the resin reacts that that's a good
way to see how hot it is oh yeah
especially if you've like pressed bubble
already when it's powder it's a little
bit harder cuz it takes longer to melt
you ready I'm ready oh it Happ you got
to give me another
one here put it on do it yeah didn't
realize how his hand there you know [ __ ]
left and a and a right hash problems if
I could tell you how many times me
personally I'm a little bit more clumsy
especially if I'm dealing with a little
jar after you know 20 TP dip dabs yeah
and uh yeah I've spilled a couple jars
delicious spilled left a couple jars out
just so anyway we're done with our
little quick three dab sesh we're going
to head up to Shannon Falls we're going
to show you a little bit of the view off
of my front door here um with the Drone
and we're going to drive
[Music]
oh
a
[Music]
then we're going to drive up to Stanley
uh sorry to Shannon Falls and give you
guys a little show over there so why
don't we do that see you there guys see
you there boys and girls
[Music]
he
all right so we just arrived here at
Shannon Shannon Falls uh just talked to
a guy out in the parking lot who had a
drone we've got our drone and apparently
it's totally legal to film Dr drones
here so that's pretty cool should be
good e boys oh it's going to be great
all right I'm looking forward to it this
park is just [ __ ]
[Applause]
beautiful a cool enough thing piece of
paper in your pocket look at that
waterfall you guys beautiful gorgeous
it's definitely
windier over here it's a little bit
cooler and cooler
God look at that tree it's [ __ ]
beautiful pedestrian access to
Gondola that's
crazy didn't realize the gondola was so
close it's recording recording what do
you want recorded just me talking a
little bit all right so we finally uh we
finally got here to Shannon Falls we
actually got here twice we got here
we hiked up almost ruined Brett's nice
shoes and realized uh I didn't bring
this cable that connects the phone to
the controller which basically connects
the whole thing and so uh I guess the
point of the the thing is is that we're
back now after buying a cable in
Squamish and we're going to give you
some of this Drone footage so we might
even have a few dabs but for now we're
going to the Drone footage so hope you
enjoy
[Music]
free mine and
Ro free mine and live free mine and Ro
come in and free your mind and dance the
stress the
stress
distress and save your life oh yes
distress distress
distress distress distress
and your life
yes
like yeah and gra you like a rat oh and
treat you like a mat they will you like
a KN a KN and they will misiz R my
people before you realize oh yeah they
tell you dirty Li they will show you
like a dice the ice distress
distress distress
distress and save your life for yes
distress and save your life
yes to keep you down you and show you
all
around you always we in every to sound a
sound so you got to listen to yourself
and know which one you must choose and
which one you must
use don't get
confused oh no no free and rock free and
live free and rock free your mind and
dance the
stress the stress he stress he stress he
stress and save your life oh yes he
stress stress
distress stress distress
yes and save your life for
yes step step at the right place walk
walking out the right
L moving at the right place move
skip skipping on the right place run
running out the right lane dance dance
upon the right dance uh-huh
Dess
Dess distress distress
yes and save your life oh yes be
stressed beess
beess beess
Dess and save your life
for
Dess
distress
distress and save your life
for so what did you guys think of that
experience that was the craziest
technology experience [ __ ] narbar yes
we set that [ __ ] up high we flew it over
the waterfall we got it pointed towards
the chief the gondola the ocean I think
you guys enjoy the footage in the
meantime we are eager to have a session
we're going to head over just around the
corner to the picnic tables and we're
going to do some
dabs
peace hey yo
B why Timber Ro feel good give me
[Music]
a jam one man home grown man real home
purpose of the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the we that to the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we let I
view the
time with is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying we have been traveling to kingst
20 M hours sleeping on like the clock
fresh vegetation with trees and with
[Music]
flowers give me one Bigg and if it's
bigger big I give me
[Music]
pass
pass I make pass pass pass and
[Music]
then the now before BL that cuz come
make off and pass that pass that pass
that
now purpose of the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the mind
all right so we got to our Jam spot
we're going to get some water from the
from the waterfall we've been filming
we're going to we're going to Puff
through a little of that water you need
me to do it yeah thank you yeah
man but it's such nice cold water it's
is ridiculous so clean and
clear as you can see it comes from that
waterfall so sick eh
[Music]
oh
yeah all right so uh we thought we had
it all set up but unfortunately I forgot
one cable for the denail or the
dabinator and uh because of it we're
going to go Banger torch torch Banger
style this time around and uh why don't
we start with that green crack God 73
let's do it mighty fine idea is that not
a good idea you hit some of that
beautiful rosin you got there that's
good you like start a Markus oh sure if
you want to torch me
out I was thinking of just using the jar
for the carb cap on that to be honest
that's perfect
yeah GRE up the hatch a little it carb
it perfect yeah it's pretty greasy now
so that's kind of what gave me the idea
the idea of just being like just go for
it so that was pretty [ __ ] awesome
Drone footage it was I was pretty stoked
on how that turned out I'm sure it's
going to look real lovely on a 4K
screen we get to go almost right away I
give I got to apply the Drone it was
real amazing envirment out here smell
the soil in the air the humidity yeah
it's pretty nice sitting right beside
the walk the end of the waterfall filled
up the B water with some water from the
waterfall so yeah all in all great day
good s we're about 20 minutes from the
city yeah a little bit of a
hike work up that was
beautiful real nice taste hit it right
around the right time and uh I think if
it only taken that long we should have a
couple oh yeah making them nice red I
seen
that this guy just pulls out a booger
the side not doing Q-tips today I just
no Q-tip today it was good it was good
anyway I've got the camera angled so you
can see Shannon falls in the background
hope you guys appreciate that this is an
easy place to find if you're coming to
Vancouver and you want to check it out
it's just north of Horseshoe Bay about
30 minutes just south of Squamish on the
way up to Whistler on the SE to sky
highway the 99 Highway
right off the
highway boom
boom well the Banger never lets down
when you got the torch uh and the and
the quz Banger it's just an easy way to
make the session happen no matter how
many times you forget your goddamn
cords you can always go back for the
Dil all right R up this is West Coast to
light
[Music]
he
here once again we got the uh
Technicolor dream cycle from nishe
Stratosphere and dude I love it it's
nice it feels like uh happy when you hit
it it's kind of like a I don't know
going to the
circus can do that for you it is just
another
[Music]
do a little round of
rosin do it we got here BR this is some
PK
R this is the PK Rod yeah oh yeah that
been in my pocket all day
still got a little bubble this is going
to be a little bubble rosin
uh make it so your R are still
clean a dirty B thank you yeah we're
really toughing it out here guys we're
doing a lot for it's
tough
one probably
that is the advantage to actually
heating it up to that point where
everything's just clean and baked right
off some people are probably cringing
that we're not q-tipping it but uh some
bangers are just disposable bangers that
you use on tour and when you're out and
about and you don't always have your he
nug jar that you now put Q-tips in so
it's the he Q-tip jar
yeah I definitely don't want to smell or
taste Burn smoke from the end of the
head on that g so how you clean that
perfect I'll give it a good 45 seconds
yeah I would for sure it's quite an easy
thing to feel with the back of your hand
and even the palm of your hand it's just
too hot is too hot that's how I Accord
the hit we don't want to uh be wasting
all the efforts that the grower the
processor has put in making this
wonderful resin and isolating it for us
by putting it into a PO
taking a sweet time you think the cool
air would uh cools down even faster
being towards big it is it's thick this
is a Dark Crystal Banger so that's also
just to keep with the team here yep um
and uh that's just keep of the theme
Here Canadian artists so I decided to go
with another Canadian forz flower and
that's the verdict on the PK
Ros it was a banger oh a delicious there
was quite a bit of bubble still on the
thing as
well so it
was right on point grab him in
nicely well we made nice nice little
video here boys I think it's going to be
good Drone
footage melt
footage beautiful yeah beautiful British
Colombian day
and gabs coming
up is actually quite
quiet they
talk
yeah cheers everybody
well I'm really looking forward to
uh getting the video edited looking at
the footage and checking it all out it's
going to look good really nice might
have to make one more trip up to swam to
grab a hard drive otherwise my
alternative is driving into West
Vancouver thank
you [ __ ] st came up Cameron I'm
looking forward to you getting your new
piece and we'll do some more filming
with that yeah picking up a nice rainbow
rello tricycler from Farm the Sunshine
Coast it's the one if you saw the last
video I did at the Sunshine Coast with
Cory and nich and uh Jade uh
[Music]
you