[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
John B is in the house Mr Burell and uh
puff Wednesdays it's another puff
Wednesday isn't it gorgeous outside too
I I love puff dude this is pretty much
one of my favorite puff Wednesdays yet
because it's been 20 years since I've
grown an actual crop and it's been 20
years since I harvested an actual crop
and I've never taken my own plants and
just wash them into fresh frozen so as
John passes me over the
tools we are getting uh ready to open up
the tent here and pull out the first
plant for a fresh Frozen bubble bag
run can't tell you guys how stoked I am
on
this we got this
lanky Astro Boy all falling over and
what not look at the size of that too
yeah it's a nice beefy nugget nice
smaller size the structure of the bud
alone is just beautiful it really is uh
a nice looking plant what we're going to
do is we're going to take it upstairs
and we're going to show you how we get
it ready for the freezer and then uh
we're probably going to have a little
session while it freezes probably freeze
it for about an hour and uh from there
we're going to run run this whole plant
through the bubble now and through the
uh eight bag original Bubble Bag kit it
does smell so good doesn't it it's
exciting oh yeah so good all right well
let's catch up with you guys back
upstairs uh out on the deck right
on
all right guys we are back up on the
deck it's a scorching day isn't it
John's just e feeding his endoc canabo
system it fell off it's tasty it is a
had you know just it looks so good I
actually looked at I was like dude I
can't believe how excited I am to cut
this thing down so today we thought we
would film the process of us just
preparing the plant for freezing um
we've got the container that jeez I mean
I've seen this container a bunch of
times I think it was full of My Little
Pony the time we went to Whistler wasn't
it yeah and then it got filled with
medic C push and Astro Boy and now it's
um now it's going to be Astro boid no
that was your uh fresh Frozen birthday
one so was Astro Boy before yeah that's
what I mean yeah that's what I it was My
Little Pony it was it was my Astro Boy
medic Kush and now Astro Boy again so
this Tupperware has seen some good fresh
frozen so so we know what we get out of
one of these Tupperware containers yeah
and we also have the scale I brought my
scale with a little bucket that I have
teared I can put about 300 gram in here
so we'll let you know what the wet uh
vegetative yield is on this uh once
we've cut it down so you want to just
start trimming some nugs in there Johnny
what the first one I want to hold this
up right this one looks pretty
good
booya I mean you haven't done this in 20
years booah
so just beautiful Boo get that big top
sucker and show them I know show them
that I'm so excited actually to get to
that oh yeah
that's beautiful oh there we go there we
go that is a nice little fatty right
there I tell you beautiful
looking
excellent so we'll just get actually
I'll keep my fans
separate this I will actually trim down
to
buds
one
two
three this thing's just hitting the
ground plump four and
five man that's a nice little fat nugget
right there it's beautiful show it in
there W awesome are you going to join me
and cut some of these down that last one
was a little bit heavier that definitely
uh added some weight to our little uh
our little bin this is beautiful my God
is the flavor nice on this get right in
there jump it in dump it in nice to be
doing this with you John you were really
you're really quite integral in
getting me back into growing getting me
back into having the ability the access
the equipment all I did was uh open a
door for you yeah but it was a it was a
very a door that you've already known so
well I still muchly appreciated you
opening it I'll tell you still do and
you can open that door too and you
should learn to grow like we're doing
here and the best thing about this is is
this is exactly what you need to do to
produce real medicine is is what we're
doing this is the the cleanest and the
freshest and probably I would say the
most efficacious way of for consuming
your endoc canabo well this is the
equivalent of ordering the pizza and
opening the box and eating the pizza not
the box with the pizza we're really just
people are sitting there watching and
they maybe thinking is this really worth
it is that really worth it well if is it
worth it to extract the medicine the
thing that you love about cannabis the
reason that you're growing it is it
worth it to extract it so you can
acquire it in an unadulterated fashion
I absolutely think so man this thing has
a lot of uhct on it and how it is and as
this is gradually filling up I'm going
to say you're going to get roughly about
350 to 400 G of froze of wet out of this
which in in return is going to what I
equal out to what I always do got about
12 G or something yeah excellent yeah
exactly 10 to 12 gr that'd be surreal if
I even got close to that just from the
one little plant but and and actually
this was the little one there is that
great big one in the in the other
pot so much
nicer you really just feel that barely
touching these nuggets and just getting
some nice clear oh hey
beautiful let's see what we got here
ding sure some nice nuggets first time I
grown in a long time it's hey you're
chopping down your own fresh and and and
the best part about it is you're about
ready to run it got to give thanks to uh
TGA bad boy subcool
Jill thanks guys for doing what you do
don't let the haters get you down I see
them hating on you guys and uh you guys
are inspirational you know I want to uh
I want to get on doing a little bit more
of uh what you guys are doing with uh
the way you care for your patients and
your customers and the way you promote
and you know get all these uh toys runs
and food drives and awesome raising
money for for the young guy with the
with the tumor it's just great it's nice
to see that they give so much back to
the community and uh yeah it's
inspirational it is that's really like
awesome I didn't even
uh that's what we all like to do
absolutely everybody feels good when you
help somebody oh that's where that's
where that dopamin you know you can't
get it until you give
it man super super stoked on this John
oh all these nuggets are so dense and so
wonderful barely barely touching them
you know they're going right into the
freezer and uh that's you know this is
the easiest way of trimming too like me
you'll see with my last video there all
I did is I cut down my plants cuz I'm
only growing them about this tall and
put it directly into the freezer mhm
which you got one downstairs at the
above a c I think you'll probably do the
same thing
I a whole plant fresh Frozen whole plant
absolutely it's kind of kind of fun I
still got to run that I'll have to do
that um probably
tomorrow have to get uh good old
uh Mike and hey over ah yes yeah he's uh
learning how to feed his endoc canabo
system been doing amazing it's important
it is so important and some of these
fans are just coding so lovely still
going to separate them do a fan Leaf run
and a bud run can only uh improve your
quality when you do such things get off
the biggest fan
leaves and just prepare your
herb for extraction for
isolation very excited this is exciting
yeah you know come on I haven't done
this in uh in 20 years and and when I
did it I never did it like this you
never froze it no and I certainly didn't
know about
washing it's great it's awesome man
you've done so much but you've never
washed your own weed that you've grown
so that's like that's like a high five
yeah it's happening today with you
Johnny get all these fan leaves I think
I'm going to waste some of this out just
to give everyone a little idea of what
we got going on so I'll tear this bucket
okay let's turn it
on all right so there we
go start throwing this bucket
up
200 250
don't worry about that all right so 243
fresh right here 243 nice oh yeah yeah
that's not too bad like we got just uh a
little bit more here yeah oh man just a
beautiful sunny day here going
on planes flying by boats going by it's
uh it's it's the place to be on the
water right behind us I'm sure we're
going to be doing a run pretty soon
doing that oh we'll get out on the water
this year for sure and 100% looking
forward to a couple of boat runs dud
it's a fresh frozen on the yeah we'll do
we'll do a proper this time where
everything's working we'll get some
power we'll get some power we'll get
some power and it's amazing how many of
these little popcorns just exist once
you think they're kind of already it's
done and said with it's like no no
there's still quite a few of them well
popcorns like what I'm doing I've been
saving all of my stock over the last
year or two and um I'm going to make
some
um hemp concrete out of my stock nice
can I do that you know I'm going to
mortar and put a bit of a barbecue I got
bricks from my tearing down my one thing
I think you know what I'd like to make
something that I've grown that's a good
idea it was just brick and I've been
doing it for years just saving it and
hey this is going to to get run once I
get enough of it I'm going to do all the
stock and fan Leaf in one separate
Bubble Run I'll just yeah all the fan
all the stock I'm going to run it just
to show people you know what's possible
when uh when you're resin is is coating
all over the
plant fresh buds here and uh we're going
to pop the lid
on take it down to the freezer there's
the last of it take it down to the
freezer and uh I guess what we're going
to do is sit and have a serious session
and we'll let this get Frozen that's
sweet and when we come back we're going
to run it I'm going to run my first crop
plant in over 20 years awesome dude we
see you guys in a
bit all right so we're back down in the
garage and this is going in the fridge
freezer freezer in the freezer not
messing around with the fridge John's
got a nice little
space made and
doesn't want to get off my fingers cuz
it's
sticky all right there we go see you in
a
bit John and I are going to go puff now
I need a medicate let's go puff let's
that's fine
okay
for
all right well awesome puff Montage John
that was like some uh that was some nice
ripping all over the place wasn't it it
was some fun you just a quick uh you
know three four rips a piece and boom
bam boom we're back in the house and uh
we're still giv that uh fresh frozen
some time to become full fresh frozen
it's it's not quite Frozen enough so uh
we decided we would make medicated
Pizza homestock why not Mega ill shout
out to Mega ill and Mark cloid for
turning us on to a great concept I have
to admit I had never even thought of
medicated pizza before so we have our
ingredients here we've uh nothing
nothing too crazy we've got some a
couple of different types of uh sauces
just purchased sauces nothing homemade
we've got some crushed garlic some pinea
apples red pepper you got some of the
veggie ground beef there and some
almonds mozzarella cheese tomato uh hemp
parts and a little bit of balsamic
vinegar to top off the fresh leaves that
we just removed from the astroy that
we're about to run so some of these are
coated in resin but just in case there's
not enough we've got about a half a gram
of some astroboy dry sift to throw on so
we have a real Astro Boy medicated Pizza
and then we get to run AST boy and then
we're going to make the Astra boy fresh
frozen so how sweet is that s so uh if
you want to grab the top one here John
that will be you I'll take the
bottom and uh we're going to make some
medicated Pizza I'm going to go right
into the sauce with my
sift I'm definitely going to um
get right in here I'm going to get this
cheese going cuz I like a little bit of
cheese on the bottom I don't know other
people do and best thing about the
cheese it helps absorb the
THC all those can oh
yeah that is for certain so you
definitely need that um melted cheese in
there super simple to medicate Pizza you
can uh you can soak your sift uh in an
olive oil and and uh you know lightly uh
Olive o uh rub the crust with the olive
oil which I have at home which I uh do
quite a bit yeah you do the medicator
that way excellent
excellent all right so let's grab a
little bit of this
sift all right I'll put that right there
that's my
sift get that in there
good throw a
little
garlic in
there love a lot of garlic in my pizza I
have to
admit get a little bit of the Sifty in
there o That's
nice just melts away into the
sauce oh
yeah
excellent all
right get uh a little bit bit of
Pineapple on there I'm a bit of a freak
I like the pineapple can I borrow the
knife thank you sir you like the
pineapple I get right in
here get some sift on your on your pizza
pie excellent it's kind of fun isn't
it yeah I'm getting a little extra in
there might as well doesn't hurt it's
not going to hurt not going to hurt
could destroy you but it won't hurt
you am I right uh you know what it'll be
very well Med
kated I kind of got an idea how much I
use throughout my day
mhm and so this is a actually I found
this in your fridge and I kind of liked
it excellent and it's
um basically veggie Ground Round but
it's the Mexican style so to me was like
having a taco pizza oh yes you had the
Tomato there and stuff like that so I
was like hey you know
what just put in little little bits of
the Tomato
throughout I definitely am handson with
pizza what's next um a little bit of
cheese I
guess I'll go over complex on my
toppings will probably put a little bit
more sift on top of
cheese so I got some on the bottom and
some on the
top all right a little bit more
sift need some pepper not too much of
a pineapple
guy well pineapple and everybody meat
might be a bit strange
yeah um oh some
leaves I'm going to take this big daddy
big leaf right in the middle
there I'm going to get into some of
course hemp seed
Hearts so this is just our medicated
piece and the best thing about with the
hemp seed Hearts it helps digest a lot
better
yeah I'm definitely going to be doing
hemp seed Hearts right on top of these
leaves
man salivating at the thought of eating
this pizza in the near
future you know what what a great way to
spend an afternoon so you know basic
just a little bit of
pasas and myself like I said I use um
medicated
oil and dry
sift the nice um Added Touch of um some
asoy on top a little drizzle of balsamic
vinegar on
mine just over the
leaves yeah you know what I'm going to
just give that a little splash it smells
so good last time
I'll throw that little knife on there
too
excellent
so a little bit more cheese just to fill
up the the corners small
cracks like now we're going after the
cheese well I just looked at you had 2/3
of it on there I
figured just joking wow see that did you
see that 2/3 2/3 but look we are we are
about to uh put the medicated Pizza nice
job here she
goes so the best part about this is
really is you can really feed your Endo
canomo system and I think we're going to
be saying this quite a bit because of um
Dr David Allen
talking more about how um eating more
canabo with the hemp seed hards and with
the oils and even the leaf there's so
many different ways you can actually
ingest cannabis as a medicine we've be
doing it all through history just we
really forgot about it consume them with
a essential amino acids and there's just
great ways of being able to uh the plant
gives us everything we need it's almost
incredible to really think that it can
clothe and house and feed and
protect everything you know it's quite
amazing your pizza looks great John you
know what I'm quite excited I yeah I
like the color that you got with the
leaves you you got you need a nice big
green one in the middle there there you
go look at that now you have the whole
that's a
Fibonacci look at that one off at the
end there there you go
Fibonacci all right so you know what
we're going to eat these
pizzas first we'll show them coming out
of the toaster just to show them the
finished product mine will be ready in
about 9 minutes and John's will in right
after that and uh we'll show you what
they look like thanks for watching
people want to see the people in the
industry
right
go
ahead
sweet
all
right
oh I can help go fresh slea on here
too this is the way we like to
medicate much agreed dude I got to say
this is a nice way to take a break in
the middle of the day after some hard
ripping and and uh yeah eat a medicated
Pizza there's nuggets and leaves on our
pizza it's perfect oh nice and crispy
beautiful all right
well time to cut the
pizza this is a great little pizza knife
I'll tell you that
much you need to get it
cut it will do the
cut
oops I'm just enjoying the There You Go
sir flavor of that leaf that I just cut
up enjoy Astro Boy enjoy the asro
boy
wow that was
delicious my first bite was the Astro
Boy
nugget was it I got to say this will not
be the last time I do
this Bona Petit John Bona
PE there's my right
there
mm that's definitely a thumbs up thumbs
up pizza we'll see you guys in in a
bit well that was a pretty good pizza
scarf definitely um scarf that one
though I uh got some good effects pretty
soon after finishing it actually nice uh
nice Vibe on the uh medicated Pizza
little bit of sift little bit of freshly
pulled sugar fan
leavea and a few little nuggets did the
job so uh I guess next
up fresh frozen fresh frozen fresh
Frozen and uh that's what we're working
on is well we know how much we've
weighed out of it mhm yeah about 260 270
G of wet of fresh yeah so it's probably
you know a quarter to a fifth of that so
let divide
by probably 60 G of of dry yeah 60 gr so
see what uh see what we get from that on
uh some uh nice full milk fresh Fen
looking forward to it we're going to uh
veg for a little bit here and then we'll
fresh frozen down with you
may for
Johnny all right hey what's up guys
welcome back John and I got uh pretty
high on that pizza you know what we
actually had na we melted out there we
we had we we of course dabbed open 420
and um here we are you know yeah here we
are we're going to finally run this
batch we've been kind of wasting uh
takes a lot to get ready you know we
lined um here's one cool thing we did we
lined pizza boxes with parchment paper
and on each box we marked them 190 and
160 120 120 90 Micron 73 73 and of
course 45 and 25 so I thought that was
pretty uh pretty cool you know inside is
uh lined with the parchment paper
unbleached so we'll be able to easily
put our resins on there with lots of
room for it to sort of allow the
cardboard to close over it be protected
no dust no debris and uh course sucking
the moisture through the top end and
exactly so today we're going to use the
bubble now I've got actually a bunch of
new um Bubble now prototype um M washing
machine bags this one's a 20-gallon one
and you could actually use two of these
in the 20-gon machine and it's just sort
of one of uh uh my uh my manufa act's
old designs he sort of revamped it and
he's actually thrown his uh label on
there for the first time when you start
seeing Acme label you'll know that
that's been my manufacturer for the past
12 or so years and uh yeah he uh helps
helps make uh makes make the product a
little bit better for you guys out there
so here's another flatter design a nice
big open zipper in the middle you can
just stuff that full this is also for a
larger washing machine kind of a cool
design not something we're going to play
with today today um although he does
have a smaller one right here that could
potentially fit in here a little bit big
compared to uh the barrel shaped bag
which fits just perfect but a lot of
people are using different machines a
lot of people are using larger washing
machines so we wanted to start offering
the marketplace um some alternatives to
the standard same old same old bags um
today I think I'm going to go with my
old standby um I've got quite a few runs
to do so I'll get to the Prototype bag
uh probably on the second or third plant
but for now we're going to use the
barrel-shaped bag and we're going to
pretty much do it just like we did with
yours John we're going to stack ice herb
ice herb ice herb right to the top nice
and I'm thinking uh Bubble Bag Originals
we've got the three tiers um Bubble Bag
lights these ones uh are the the the the
money saver 150 bucks uh for a eight bag
5 gallon kit John's holding the bubble
bag standards these ones are an eight
bag kit as well you get all the colors
um it's about
$275 for an eight bag kit nice and then
the the The Originals which is you know
the best of the best uh those retail for
3.40 uh for the eight eight bag kit so I
think we're going to use the ogs we just
put those over there The Originals for
now and uh here you hold I'll let you
hold that I will get some fresh frozen
in the ice so this we put a few hours
ago we going to grab a little bit of
your neighbor's ice I grabbed a half
half pound bag out of there thanks uh
thanks guys thanks neighbors we put a
little bit little
nice put a little layer on the bottom
there oh yeah look how beautiful that
looks that is frozen oh she's nice and
Frozen ferocious we love that we do this
is so nice want to hold it up actually a
little bit higher that' be awesome there
we go get another batch of ice on
there all right and a little bit more
herb I could do this all day oh look at
that big n show them that that's a
nugget right there got to go show them
that look at that that's the top guys
the top the top ah very nice sticky on
my fingers even when it's cold nice and
Frozen nice to do nice to do couple more
in there right oh yeah peel off that
layer there we go do a little bit of
this ISO great big Half Moon ice we love
our half moon ice I was just going to
say half moon ice so you know M reader
big bucket oh
yeah so this is one whole plant which is
the best thing about it how much resin
can we get off of one plant we did wear
before going in and uh we're going to be
uh smoking her after maybe at Champs yes
we'll definitely uh we definitely will
be doing that we'll put that last little
bit of ice and then I also
have the last little bit of this store
bought ice can go on
top just a little bit to top it off
there we go all right and for your first
fresh frozen run the honors sir zipping
up your bag ah yes thank you sir Jon
thank you sir John I mean this is kind
of like um history you're making your
own grown yes fresh Frozen bubble
awesome 73 can't wait so nice and we've
got our nice chilled water 5 gallons of
it sitting also packed chalk full of ice
it's uh definitely
4° that ice is not going to be melting
away on us so I guess uh go with pouring
a little bit of this in first I'm
sitting back watching this whole thing
happen what we got there I'll
put make sure it's good to
go water everywhere all right not a ton
ton of ice in inside the machine but a
decent amount nice job you hit the that
perfect it's like you've done that
before i' top it off just the tiniest
bit bring it up another inch or
so close that
up and let's go for a little mixing I
say 4 and 1/2
minutes 4 and 1/2 minutes 4 and A2
minutes time to do a rip huh yeah catch
you guys in a bit
all right so while that's over there
mixing it up we thought we would show
you guys even though I'm sure you guys
have seen this a lot but for those of
you that haven't why all the bags what
order do they go in that's what we're
going to go through right now there you
go a lot of people always want to use
the 190 and go right to the 45 it's true
there's a reason for this people listen
so we go in an order the this it's a
seeve stack the 220 is the largest bag
the blue bag and it goes down through
220 190 160 120 90 73 45 and 25 the
first bag you put in in a stack like
that of course is going to be the bottom
one the 25 that's a purple bag so we'll
get that guy in
there fits in nicely into the bubble
bucket yeah help me wrap that around
there perfect we could actually lift
that one up even a tiny bit there we go
perfect y
second the 45 micron
this is our secondary
bag dump that in there bend it over go
ahead
awesome
yeah second bag complete next comes my
favorite uh John's favorite is the gold
73 I like the 73 wearing the 73 today on
my shirt I think it gives me my Pain
release with my with my medicine with my
medic push and that's the 73 that works
for me and you'll find the bag that you
like the most some people like the 45
some people like the 160 yeah I'm a 90
fan 90 and 73 I I kind of happen 120
them all I know right it's kind everyone
but I mean the one that always runs out
for me is always the the 90 70 then the
120 the 73 it's the order that lets you
know really what is the best and what
you want so we're at the 90 this is my
favorite almost exclusively it's just a
good bag you get some fire in the in the
90 all right crack that
open getting a little bit tighter on our
with all the bags we put in now we put
in
four so it's good to keep the so
remember spreading it up these 90
120 7390 the 120 that the following you
don't take
out you don't take out what do you mean
well I have you know cuz I do work at a
local hydroponic store and they're like
oh we just used the 160 in oh so you're
talking about leaving the bag out of
even using it yeah of course you never
take any bags out in fact I'll just to
reiterate always use all the bags it's
going to help you understand more of
what's going on each time and it may
surprise you sometime and if you if you
cut yourself off from that and you just
use a few of those bags you don't get
the out do they ever have anything
inspiring they they're like oh mine
doesn't smell like that and you don't
want to hit it kidding of course not and
they're excited like well uh yeah I just
I got the three B I want you to hit this
it's like well why would you do that
three bag system I was like ribon yeah I
mean three bag system was something in
1999 2000 oh I think I heard that b stop
over there excellent well we'll rush
over there once we uh finish with our
last three bags how about that we've got
our 160 left we just put our 120 the
orange bag in after the 90 Micron there
we go this is our 160 it is red we're
going to get that in there and then
we'll literally walk this Bucket over
there and we will filter some
hash I might even do a second run almost
immediately with that material just to
see how efficient we've been always a
nice idea to check some people like to
run and run and run and run I'm going to
do two runs and then I'm going to soak
my material um in a coconut oil and do a
little extraction like that something
that I haven't done that I'm going to do
next time myself I love the idea
everybody's talking about the Rick
Simpson Oil and stuff well you know what
coconut oil guys yeah and not not just
using your shitty uh you know I'm not
going to only use the left over bubble
material I'm going to use some of my
good dry sift and some of my good bubble
to actually produce some nice uh coconut
infused oil I think we should pull this
one down a little bit more it's tight
but we can do
it try and do there we go it's coming
nicely sometimes all it takes is a
friend to give you a hand here well it's
also how well you like on this side I
pulled mine down very well because you
see how it goes down below the bags on
this side the way he's the way the bags
are added and this little metal piece is
catching up on his side so we could have
easily removed this little metal piece
but uh we kind of spaced it but that's
the reason the bags are are catching up
cuz John had the whole metal piece on
his side so yeah there you go one more
bag and we're good one more bag yeah
it's not too bad it's only up a little
bit try to keep that one up as high as
we can go ahead take your side first
there we
go perfect yeah this bag's a little bit
wider I keep that nice and
open yeah just leave that like that
almost like a little bit off the tip of
the lip and it lifts the screen up for
us now this is the 220 bag we are using
a 220 bag in the machine over there but
it's never a bad idea to double up on
bags I like that even if you had extra
bags in your kit like an extra 160 or an
extra 120 you could throw them in there
and you'd be surprised at what you uh
might find yourself keeping from the
next screen even though it's the same
size screen shall we run over there you
going to follow me over here I'm going
to follow you over here we go walking
right on
over look at those plants just doing so
well up there they're happy they're very
happy ah
yes look nice oh it smells so amazing
all right so we're going to use this
little guy as our table there we go so
we can get everything lifted up so you
guys can see
it get it up
there all
right sure that's all
organized all right so yeah I guess
we'll have to first have it a little bit
lower just for the drain let's see what
we got here o nice col Koolaid colored
water excellent smells amazing yes well
let's run it
through some Kool-Aid colored water
right there very light light light
pinkish color we did a very short run it
was 4 minutes 4 and 1/2 minutes maybe
and I'll probably fill this back up with
water plug it in over the Over Yonder
towards the end of our um batch all turn
it on again so I'll let it sit without
water I'll fill another bucket up to
cool it with ice water and then I'll do
one second run once we pull this we'll
just do another quick run and see if uh
if there's any yelds there at
all
excellent oh it smells amazing Divine it
does smell I wish I had my spoon because
you know I would be drinking that right
now yes you have cup yeah I'm going to
pull the hash out of it and then you can
drink as much as I want to drink the
hash though I know you do it's all good
you can it smells so ni you can drink it
once we pull the
still smell awesome still smell flavors
yeah absolutely all right so that's done
let's see what we got here the mixture
perfect yeah buring it real good it's
not sitting in any water it's cool I can
get rid of this
guy have him plugged
in Over
Yonder we'll get this guy up here right
in between us now is this where we're
going to do our cleaning right here
right here this is where our cleaning is
done so this I'm going to switch sides
cuz I'm going to be cleaning over here
okay and then what I'll do real quick
I'll get R of here is I'll move a few of
these things out of the way mostly
cannabis plants telephones and
such and I'll make a little bit of
room cleaning right
here um basically you know microing I
should say not cleaning
here's we're getting ready here Johnny
here's your micr planer perfect SW for
it ah yes my SE my SE that is my SE
there we go we're sing now and and
reason why is because we saw the microp
planing and I think we were damaging
those heads I never was into
microplaning yeah no no never got into
it no I did I'm not against those who
were into it I don't claim that they're
destroying anything I don't think
they're degrading anything worse than I
am I just don't I don't like the way it
looks under the macro lens I don't like
the way it makes me feel when I go into
that world and I see those heads just
ripped mated like I I I did it I we did
that video you know what I will always
use the sift yeah I like the SE I like
the SE so little bit of uh 220 there
nothing much might just wash it what
like to do oh I know what we're going to
require all right so we set up the
pressing screens inside its own box um I
got a paper towel laid down to absorb
moisture so we've got our um our spoon
and we're sort of ready to start
collecting we got a little spray bottle
nice um we can start collecting bags oh
you know what would really be nice the
small bucket that we used last time to
flip all the bags inside out that's the
last thing I will be right
back all right I ended up getting that
bucket super important to have this just
to be able to flip the bags over we are
likeing a bucket I've always liked the
bucket you know it's just a nice little
little option this one's a little bit
smaller than the actual size of the
screen but I mean how convenient is that
that's so
convenient a little spray mostly
contaminant did I tell you how much I
love this spray
bottle dude use it all the
time it's a good little
bottle all right well little bit of 220
not too much to see there on the
camera basically
nothing yet something but always yet
something it's resin basically
nothing but something the tiniest it
just shows at the work bag that was
initially in there do you want to take
that with the bucket for
cleaning
okay all right so as John's doing that I
will lift the next
bag also very little there
little well that one's almost
nothing there you go s thank you thank
you this one is is even less John even
less very little 160 which makes a lot
of sense when you're running fresh
Frozen um
you're not using a lot of dry material
it's fresh it's Tricom heads are
breaking off and almost nothing else and
you're
uh you're not going to see too much on
these in the 160 all you know what's
going to happen we're going to just get
the
goods
160 and 190 bag almost
nil wow
yeah like we're talking
nail here we go just a tiny little bit
of contamination on there the slightest
little amount bar barely able to scoop
it out with
a with the
spoon barely able to scoop it
Johnny all
right pretty clean even getting them you
me all right so you got a little bit of
my first actual grade to see collected I
remember then when I did my one 45 was
amazing yeah you got a nice
45 we're going to see we're going to see
fresh
frozen this one's got a little bit of
blondes hash on the
screen as one might expect from the
from the 120 very very small amount as
well all
right maybe a rip amongst that one give
that one a clean cuz that was an actual
nice
grade go
buddy all right find micron
nice
little
amount there Frozen
bubbles
[Music]
okay little bit more
more this time around getting a little
bit each
time this is some creamy
goodness not a huge amount but a nice
nice little
puddle sure looks incredible for
color-wise almost yellow oh wow look at
the color of that yeah that's totally
amazing tiny little amounts but
wow what a
color clean our
spoon and our
bag inside the other bag this is a great
tip you want to get that that resin off
of there and not
uh not all melted into your screen there
go Bud looks like it needs quite a bit
of forced water on
there number
all
right PR
cumon so we have quite a bit of fresh
frozen to still run I've got like four
five more plants John has oh jeez at
least two or three full batches as well
don't you John oh yeah yeah I have year
freezer full toys and two bins two full
bins ready to go go for for
John so we're going to do this first run
just to see how effective we were I
really didn't break the Nuggets up so
we're going to get what I would call the
best of the
best awesome there we go a
second yeah I'm going to do it in my in
my different uh all screen
bag
let's see go
there just to give it that last little
rinse inside the bag before
you that's nice and cold water it's so
cold it's not very sticky yet but I
suspect once the water evaporates off my
hands but it could get a little stickier
well that water really is Rose Colored
you see it in the white
bag grab that little bucket from you
cheers all right nice little puddle of
next
all
right give that one a little
spray able to spray out a couple of tiny
little chunks of contaminant in there
nice blow them
out puddle
of 45 just a little little chunk
remember we did a very very light
mix and we did uh very little breaking
up of the product so once again look at
45 yeah nice big like I have 45 was
amazing yeah it's delicious I think the
watermelon just got a
different um I try not to make any
assumptions based on a couple of runs
yeah
running I
might yeah we'll know so much more and
plus you'll have like covered it bred it
with this bred it with that you know
what I mean like be interesting I like
seeing this right
now yeah it really is I'm excited to run
that again because I know there's more
material in
there I saw it with my macro
lens all right L 25 Micron that last
little
bag yeah I mean they looked a lot like
most of the tricomes I
photograph but I guess that's uh could
be deceiving
too who whoops we're coming around I
think we just made ourselves all the way
around here nice last one missed one
there that's the last one the last one
that's the eight bag system we got the
egag system I got the last one right
here
that looks pretty
cool the little drying bubble bag the
little drawing Bubble Bag
scene all right so oh we got this 25
micron last but certainly not
least get that over
there just not need drying
system now that 2220 is made it around
it's already
dry
Perfect all right here now you can have
a drink of your
water
oh some just wanted to drink my bubble
I'm just looking for is like here how
that The Bu
excellent all right well uh I guess
we'll get to moving some of this water
out of the
way my back that's pretty good eh look
how awesome it looks high five far yeah
dude I like this one's already dry okay
yeah because it dried on my back nice it
pushed up against my back and then let
out all the water but I don't mind
getting a little wet especially when I'm
making bubble hash so uh we got
ourselves a nice little miniature yield
much smaller than I was expecting
actually but you know this still could
be 2 to three gr and we might have only
run a couple of ounces dry so there's
probably still another 3 to four G on
that material I I would say those big
buds that weren't broken down yet and
breaking all those buds apart it was
just kind of throw it in there let's
just do get the best that we can get so
now we're going to do that while I let
this still absorb itself from the water
cuz it's not ready yet to be sifted to
to be seed sorry um we'll leave this for
about maybe 3 to 5 minutes if that and
I'm going to go prepare the machine for
a second run so I will sweet second run
yeah second run it will be nice and open
and he'll be able to see what Tri you
want to put this into uh under bucket
I'm not too worried about it just want
to get it done and I want everyone to be
able to see what we're
doing
so
yeah all right that's so the zipper
doesn't open in man does that thing work
you do not want this thing opening up in
mid
run okay oh look at that one big solid
butt yes it
is I'm going to break these off they
they're coming off so perfect just
stripping from this stock
yeah we're definitely
um I can already see we can just see all
the tries in there look at that excuse
me if I could just get my hand for a
second to grab another big negative
sorts there must be more big ones in
here oh yeah these are there's a big one
if you
want a big new
Jay you can see these are all just full
of Frozen ice in the middle is kind of
cool when you break them apart they're
all Frozen yeah they do they split and
have ice all throughout them yeah all
the way through the sunent that's why
they break so perfect you don't I've
actually never done this before so it's
really cool to see us that in the middle
of the buds there's like just like
ice i don't think I need these scissors
no we don't
I more huge nuggets nice Frozen
nugs it's definitely nice and easy to
break them
up quite a bit our our smaller so it's
really just those few large pieces that
we needed to break
up let me finish it up
there and I will
get the next batch of bags
ready oh look at this B I found here
excellent we like those big and in the
center it's like these little yeah just
it's it's really cool to actually see
this way I've never looked at it this
way that's cool taking these buds apart
and how it's still just nice and Frozen
in the middle you can see how the ice
working away in here we are cold all
right so
Frozen I love the way I can just access
the bags through the uh through the spin
wheel through the spin wheel yeah maybe
you can get yourself a spin wheel I like
it it's a good
idea just happen to be just happen to be
hanging around just happen to be hanging
around
I wonder how many times not a standup
comedian well this is definitely
um getting more broke up there all
nicely broke up now all right I'll just
pack another bag of ice into that I have
one more bag of ice that'll one more bag
of ice pack in there
and we'll do a nice quick second
run see if we can't
up the anti on our our
yield not that I'm personally too
worried whatever I get is the medicine I
get and I'm going to be soaking this
plant matter and coconut oil afterwards
doing this the two batches through the
bubble bags and I still have more plants
left so it's just new ground not a lot
of people really can tell you how much
resin they get off of a plant you know
that they
grew
awesome oh you pulled the last one out
see I was leaving that one for you I see
a bunch more look at this one look at
this giant one I'm trying joking no
you're doing killing you're killing it
this isn't your first rodeo although
that's a pretty big butt yeah have you P
that one I just dug you just said it
wasn't my first Ro you don't know how
many Ro I figured you've been to a few
though
couple all right
so we got this plant matter all wet and
goopy breaking these buds down a little
bit by finger they're very cold I
suggest doing it when they're cold all
nice and Ice Yep they're not sticking to
my fingers whatsoever nothing at all
that's what's really cool if you
actually want to grab the bag of ice
just behind
you get rid of this guy over
here we'll get him in
there
beautiful stuffed it I love that stuffed
it that's what we like to see it's all
about the ice the more the merrier the
colder the more heads fall off yeah you
want to ensure your cold temperature so
I mean obviously it's going to get to a
certain temperature and then it's going
to Plateau but if you can get it to
4° four yeah four is
great 4.2 brittle 4.2 and then we will
use our chilled tarpine Rich water that
we filtered through a 25 micron to
remove any sort of little bits or bats
that would have been from the
last all right going to drop that in
there how's
that take F right up dude dude I Like it
Like A Perfect
Pull I'm just turning it around now
great at the top that's okay a little
bit little bit of Overboard on the Rosé
water but um I might take a siep to that
one now so we've got this we're going to
do our seing we're going to start this
up we're going to catch up with you in a
bit when we pull the next
batch all right
[Applause]
here
we're dabbing while we
bubble dabbing while we
bubble I forgot we were
on I like
that it's
real
just mixing up more of the
medicine
[Applause]
so second run you know we left that out
for the tiniest little bit there I was
like oh it looks pretty fresh I'll just
leave it out and then I'll I'll I
thought I was a pretty good judge of the
seeve that [ __ ] is the Gummi gooiest
most ridiculous it's just completely
stuck to the pressing screen snot I had
to go uh put it in the freezer and we're
going to have to se that one so that's
just the way that is and uh I guess
we're at the point where we're going to
do another drain the the watercolor was
it Rose before yes but now it's uh it's
mocha it is kind of mocha isn't it it's
a mocha it almost looks
creamy it looks like a mocha cream all
right here actually why don't you get in
here and then I'll put that there and
you can come in stand right there and
we'll drop this in here we have the
mocha cream pie coming in
here there she is see how it came out
purple at first that is mocha M I'm
color blind that's pretty cool it's
definitely not the same uh color that it
was when we started with the first bat
so it's creamy
though just stinks the h
oh does it ever smell so good it's great
doesn't love that and what's interesting
what's going to be the best part about
it is actually like what I've done on my
second rent at my house I've actually
saved it dried it up I have it all
sitting there and one day I might have a
test it and worth looking at it but you
know what photograph it too I can
photograph it that's what I kind of plan
on doing with this he photographing it
after I ran it and seeing uh seeing what
we got going on can always do this with
the machine there's always just a tiny
little bit of water that'll Fe fit in
the spinner disc at the bottom and just
lean it
over get it all
out get some cold water awesome I like
the idea of just getting this out of the
way right away I unpluging it for you I
know how you like to do that you're the
man you're the man best assistant on the
whole
planet always is more helpful than
helpful I used to work
outr okay so I guess we will start start
again we got the screen we got the
squirt
bottle we got the bucket so we're a
little more of a longer mix that time
and we did break the buds up more so it
doesn't surprise me that there's a
little bit more contaminant not like you
want to be all excited seeing this bag
full
but
awkward 220
all
right the puddle of the
220 you know I'll photograph it we'll
see what it
is and I will definitely spray the [ __ ]
out of it awesome this is the bag we do
not put in this bag this is definitely
at least the bag there's usually a
couple of them yeah we don't often do it
with the next one
either but it has happened on a river
yes on a
Riv yes yes on a river no I even mean
like on purpose like it was worth
it all
right most of the contaminant got caught
up in the uh in the 220 there's still a
little bit here in the 190
just enough
to just enough to make it noticeable
when I put all the the grades
together
excellent thank you
sir yeah just a few little chunks pretty
much the same color as the bag very
green is it
green little bit green little bit green
but you know what I when I think of the
coconut oil this is all just
perfect you know there's medicine in
there yeah and I want to make all the
grades of the coconut oil I don't want
to just do it with my worst I want to
take some of my 90s some of my 73 some
like 120 sort of experiment with uh the
different
grades all right
so
160 a little bit
more tiles
are much more substantial than last time
but still quite small then again it
could have been you know
only uh well it could have been as
little as 40 G that I ran if you do if
it's sometimes it's a quarter sometimes
it's
1/5 the
amount and I definitely did give those a
lot of water the other
day might be something to experiment
with John what would that be uh cutting
down on the water about 5 days 4 days
before you cut your fresh frozen down
stress it out produce more
resin and and
uh yeah potentially uh get a lot less
water weight in the fresh plant matter
because it doesn't have
it well we definitely um you
sir all right 20
bag this is the one we're going to have
to be careful with this is the one we're
going to want to be very careful
[Music]
with we haven't managed to strain any of
this bubble yet because it is just so
it's also a very nice day so we're
actually working in a pretty warm
environment I think I might end up sing
it all but we'll see what happens once I
pull there you the 120 out here thank
you
John
definitely got a lot more
that yeah 100% twice as much three times
as let say at least three times as much
this is the 120 this could be even four
or five times as
much so definitely this second run is uh
giving us a lot better yields after
breaking up those buds because they were
just those big solid nugs that you
showed that we showed you that we just
threw in there just TOS right in just
toss them right in that was the whole
idea wanted to get the maximum since see
and then that first would you like to
clean that um yeah you can dump that in
there
so because it is the 120 and the 120 is
so nice we're just going to give it a
quick
little rinse just like
that
excellent next up is the 90 and you know
what it actually has a little bit of
hold this time
around after a little bit longer of a
mix pardon
me what's that bud if it's got a hole
that means that's a good sign always a
good sign yeah absolutely
little bit
anyway nice to see something
there in the
90 got a little bit on the side of the
bag
there perfect chance to use the
mister don't catch it back up
this has a real nice color to it this is
going to look
surreal that's going to be
snot ah the definitely that's that's a
once again yeah I'm so much more
enjoying the second
R yes well it's always a good idea
top it just shows you know what I mean
hey we're here showing you what
uh well just you know what how else do
you know how efficient you are you just
assume well a lot of us just do assume
so this is why we have to first don't
succeed R it again and I think the first
one was a success so one is crazy that
will be like the first sift I think that
is some of the most the way it just cure
it up in there oh I know I'm excited
it's like it's like first bounce with
dry sip that's
it does no truly that's exactly what I'm
uh first bounce with fresh frozen I'm
feeling that I'm feeling that as well
it's exciting making some fresh Frozen
with my buddy
John little bit of contamination found
its way in easy to get the finger in
there and pull it out when it's that
small looks like a single piece but
there could be another oh I think I see
another I think I see
another this is never a bad idea to do
don't you know if you can see it and you
can access it just get it out don't
think oh I'll wait till later when uh
when it's out on the parchment or
whatnot I already know there's only
three bags left CU I'm running out of
hooks ah
yes that is a good way to know isn't it
it is
oh
yeah this one's almost a bluish
Ting oh there's a little bit of
contaminant too always nice to be able
to use the spray bottle for just
that I was looking for this healing tool
walk in front of I'll pull it out I'll
pull it out with my fingers like I just
grab it yeah I see that's a pretty big
piece of whatever it
is there it is right there you can blow
it right out you going blow there you
go so definitely seeing better yields on
the second
round I found a a bug in the in the
last that wasn't a bug it was a stigma
hair stigma stigma stigma a capitate or
a pistolet sorry stigma hair all right
so this is our
73 we certainly did up our yield by many
many times I'm anticipating this 45 is
going to be like two and a half
minutes yeah I know it's not going to
fit on the pressing screen I'll tell you
that much that's what I'm looking at we
already know that so as looking here now
we're definitely seeing uh twice as much
as our last one so we're getting upwards
of uh it's twice as much right now yeah
before I pull this bag which will
probably make it three times as
much and this is the great thing with
water extraction if you feel the need to
just keep running your material there's
no one you'll know when the quality is
down it's not like you just want to keep
getting you want to get quality right
now we're pulling
quality you know I I could probably even
do a third one
yeah but I'm going to do the coconut oil
so but doing the coconut oil is just
going to be our method so some people
might coconut oil exactly but it is a
great way to get this stuff into your
body just eat
it all right here we there we
go big 45 that Weir have the bags out
there we go come on
was being a bit
weird holding the goods here nice 45
beautiful spray that up beautiful
beautiful oh a little bit of contam
there now she's
gone but yeah I'm I'm seeing yeah the 45
is just the watermelon loving the 45 oh
yeah could be that sativa in
there cuz that looks
creepy that look Beau
oh
yeah yeah I guess we better give them a
little s sight here I think that's about
three G
there even more maybe
yeah a nice a nice yield for a small
fresh frozen frozen batch for one plant
you know we we're looking at maybe
getting another
screen
well we will yeah we're going to put
that right into a CER right now and just
hash
it
woo so that's a nice little pile guys
yeah this is a real nice pile yeah
definitely um excited decent yield this
is the kind of yield you get off of when
you run uh like a couple hundred
GRS of of dry material oh nice big fat
45 like that but that's surprising to
get it
out what were you going to eat it I was
s in the B man I got to you know what I
got to treat this guy better the next
time I have a spoon full of resin he's
eating it you know what he's eating it I
got to feed this guy's endoc canabo
system he's working overtime all the
time so I much appreciate it thank
sir 25
micron it's water
steady lifting the water allows or
lifting the water with the resin allows
the water to push down and fit through
the screen without being
blocked much quicker way
of draining the bag you don't want to
wait for this to happen you want to help
it
happen
I think the best part about this is we
cut down that plant at around lunchtime
and here we are getting close to dinner
and I think we might even do a hit off
of
it so
um you can't crop your weed and dry it
and get it all run in one day that's for
sure nope this way look at the 25 look
at how nice and white it is there's a
lot of it
I'm going to squeeze that over here the
25 I find is the one you really don't
need the spray bottle for it's like Silk
the spoon moves it around
perfect the
silkiness the silky 25 silky
well we definitely have
uh
pulled uh by looking at there there's
there's spoon for
John all right excuse me
[Music]
what
see this here alone should be a drink in
your local store
someday the flavor is amazing it's like
a Kool-Aid that you've never tried
before it's so good it's nice I really
enjoy
it bubble bubble a bubble a bubble
a I mean this would probably go for like
$50 a
bottle yeah you can get it here for
free
yeah this did the same thing this is
snot done s it up sealed awesome um
let's show them what it looks like okay
and then uh we'll take the camera we're
going to show you guys what that looks
like so here's our 220 190 160 120
9073 45
look at that
45 it's
nice so I guess freeze them up get the
seeve out or the uh microplane I should
say we're going to be microplaning this
PCH there you go you want to spin that
uh around a few
times this is how we dry our bags is it
tightening that's awesome
so just to add finally that we've
cleaned the machine out the bubble now
machine is all cleaned out and rinsed
bag's all Nic and cleaned the all screen
bubble nail bag is is nice and clean
we've separated the
ice from the plant matter so this was
the 250 fresh I'll dry it out and I'll
let you guys know what it was
um in regards to dry weight and I'll
also um microplane uh the resin was just
too sticky to uh be able to see that
especially with the warmer temperatures
it's pretty much snot yeah it's pretty
snotty so um I'm not sure if I'm going
to do it tonight or not pro probably and
I'll make sure I set up the camera when
I do that just going to be simply
microplaning it onto each cardboard uh
Pizza Box on top of the parchment paper
and then I'll stack them and uh probably
photograph it with the m macro lens nice
do some melt videos there and this video
will be complete I'm coming back for the
Melt video oh of course yeah absolutely
I will make a point on not smoking this
hash until I smoke it with I'm going to
sleep downstairs and put the coton just
to make sure yes excellent good call
good call you know I'm a
very shady kind of character
so so we got our uh our water that we
used our tarpine Rich water you know you
can do what you want with this some
people claim uh they they praise feeding
the plants with it I think today that's
what I'm going to do give my plants a
little bit of uh a little bit of this
bubble water um it is quite cold so I'm
going to let it warm up a little bit
before I give it to the plants probably
I'll give it to them tomorrow uh in the
morning nice yeah so loving this uh
bubble bag uh
wheel very
cool we'll uh see see you guys at the
next step yeah happy hash making that
was a long day medicated
Pizza major bowls beforehand major bowls
during and after um we're going to do
major bowls now I suspect and uh I guess
we'll see whether or not we're going to
do that um that micro planing you go
yeah I'm kind of interested in seeing
what we got cuz after actually doing the
first and the second run I'd say what
our yields are well I don't know I'm not
going to jump out there but by just by
looking at what's seen there and stuff
like that you know you pushing probably
you know anywhere from 7 to 10 I'd say
we got probably around 7 G which is not
too bad when you think that was a
smaller plant I only had six of them in
the tent the tent could have easily fit
10 of them I'd say at least eight one
plant yeah one plant and we actually we
don't even know say you did seven yeah
exactly we're guesstimating but it it's
a neat idea of what we're doing we're
focused on how much resin that we got
and the profile of that resin I'm not
worried about the yields but I love the
idea of sharing with you guys how much a
plant yielded not in vegetative weight
first but resin and then we'll let you
know the veg numbers we'll make you go
through and do the math and you'll start
understanding the value of the plant is
in the resin not in the diluted plant
matter so there it is awesome okay well
M planning up
next okay just to show you one last
thing um I got all the ice put away and
frozen in the freezer so I can use that
ice again um I took all the plant matter
out of the pl plastic bag and I've
actually got it inside this pizza box
right now so this is the bud that I ran
the whole plant I'm going to uh dry it
out and I'll weigh it and then I've got
a coconut um extraction that I'm going
to do so I'll show you guys that and uh
yeah pretty stoked on all of this I'll
uh show you what's up on the microp
plane
next hey guys welcome to Bubble man's
world the final stage here after
whipping off a fresh batch of uh fresh
frozen Astro Boy with John yesterday um
I did leave the hash in the freezer it
seemingly some of it won't even freeze I
I pull it off the the uh pressing screen
and it's just the goopi I'm so excited
to get this hash broken up so um we got
small amounts uh maybe four or five g
once all said and done we'll see but uh
I'm going to get I've got our boxes here
you can see that each box is marked with
a mic on and each box is lined with
parchment
paper so we'll keep all the parchment
folks out there happy all the anti-c
cardb boarders but I can still use my
cardboard all right so I've got some ice
packs here these are cryle pack they
don't leak they don't produce moisture
on the outside they're [ __ ] awesome
and then I've got another one here that
it's sitting on as well this one's a
paramedic this one gets hot and cold and
uh yeah just nice to have the hash
pushed between the
two and I think we're going to
start with the 220 actually let's get
our gloves
on always nice to protect the
hands from the resin you got to be
careful when you're wearing gloves and
you're microplaning that you don't get
too close to the planer um and PL off
any of the
plastic so this is our
220 breaking up quite nice cuz it really
is just mostly
contaminant there's going to be a little
bit of resin in there but not too much
not really too too worried
about how that works out
okay
excellent so couple of little chunks
with the 220 not too
worried so 220 190 160
120 90 73 45 25 okay so we can throw
these into here as
well these little guys
here
all right there's that
190 very small piles on these almost uh
almost nothing there at
all but it's what we got so we're going
to run
it I'll just add that I did freeze the
microplane it does help to have this
thing as cold as
possible okay
so
we've got our 190
160 and we're going to go next up to
120 it's a good sign it's cracking I
hear it
peeling almost immediately I feel it
stick to my
fingers that is some nice
hash loses its cold really
fast man can you smell the goodness woo
tell
you been a while since I actually made
some fresh frozen that's
just just all going to stay here I'm so
used to making it for my
friends never a bad idea to give the
micop plane of whack to give it a
clean nice small amount of 120
now you got to see how easy it is to
have the bubble in the pizza box line it
with parchment close it up the the the
the desicant of cardboard will work
without even touching just having that
moisture getting pulled out from the
whole full uh covered
cardboard so this one's the
90 this one we're going to stand up for
get a little more serious
oh yeah starting to starting to stick
right
away so sometimes when the when the
resin starts to stick especially with
this particular microplan you can just
gently bring it over the microplane and
you can
actually when you think All Is Lost and
all is hopeless you can still get that
resin broken up that's not too bad I got
a little bit on my
fingers it's uh it did lose a little bit
of its
uh I'll be able to freeze that and pull
that resin off no
problem I have a nice light microplane
this one is just called microplane um
the bumps are very small it doesn't rip
the plastic it doesn't shred My Fingers
um you do want to pay attention
depending on what kind of microplane you
do have because some of them will shred
shred your
fingers all right so there's our
[Music]
90 and I'm going to do a quick refreeze
of the material because I find that it's
getting a little bit
warm and uh we'll be back to uh
microplane the 73 the 45 and the 25 and
then we'll get it all put away I'll add
some photographs of the final material
and uh hopefully we'll do some melt
videos and we'll just keep on uh
processing the plants out of my garden I
have two more Astro boys I have um a
baba chm and I have a medic Kush uh as
well as the My Little Pony but that's
still uh quite a ways from being done so
we will get back soon here all right so
I refroze the hash this is going to
happen often when you're when you're
doing microp
planting um so we got number 73 next up
to
that great sound of that coming off
quite
proper and they're nice thin patties so
they're oh there we go that got me
about I think I was microplaning for
about 4 seconds before the hash decided
to turn
into a nightmare to work
with that's
okay long as you can get it broken into
smaller pieces you're you're okay I I
really do prefer my seeve but I made a
mistake with this hash in the sense that
I allowed it to sit for a little bit too
long and it just gums
I've never actually
uh produce resin of this level myself
but I haven't been doing this for 20
years so reminds me of some very well-
grown resin I'll tell you that much that
fresh
frozen
really all
right tap make sure you're not losing
any resin
other than what I've managed to lose on
my glove there which I'll be able to
crack and snap that right off never a
worry
there can always get it
off it's also a good idea why we wear
the gloves if this was on my fingers it
would be a super
nightmare all right number
73 sealed and
dealed last but certainly not least we
have our 45 and our 25 so our 45 is a
real nice Patty came out real solid and
lovely fairly thick it should hopefully
microplane out
nice this microplane
is
definitely gummed up but
working this is usually more along the
lines of how microplaning Works those
other resins are just insanely sticky
this one's actually allowing me to grip
the 45 and really grind it
down and you can see that it is and can
be a bit of a messy messy
job the microplane is going to need a
good amount of cleaning after this I'll
tell
you all right get those pieces as small
as we
can
ah clean cleans the microplane up real
nice when you give it that little whack
it's it's always the same you kind of
feel that uhoh I gummed it up it's all
rued it's not going to come
out just get it cold give it a good
whack it'll come
out this is filling up
nicely I'd say I'm definitely close to
having to clean this thing cuz it's
barely planing at this point
all
right little reverse planing there
coming in through the bottom of the
plane wherever I can access
the little bit pieces of bent
metal and generally if I can like I've
mentioned a few times I'll try to leave
the right amount of moisture and if I
have the time and the temperature's
right
it really was that it was too warm
yesterday we had about 14 or 15° uh
Celsius which must be around 70 or 75
Fahrenheit just warm enough to to make
some problems with the with the
hash this is the last real part once you
can get it into
this you
know that your hash is going to be
drying properly and that's a good thing
to know once you've you know grown a
plant for several months process the
whole thing live no
trimming it's nice to know that uh
you're doing it as right as you
can all right I think we're
good
45 and our 25 which
I you know
because it's such a thin
Patty it'll probably go into medibles
and I've just used all the room for the
one that I had for 25 and 45 I'll just
place that right down on there it's the
one patty I've actually believed could
potentially dry without breaking it all
up now I don't suggest doing it but if
you have to do it it's not the end of
the world um it's going to it's going to
still turn out fine um you can still use
it it's still medicinal and uh yeah I
mean if you if you have the space in the
room great idea to break it all up if
you don't the 25 micron is the one you
can kind of get away with without
worrying about uh without worrying about
potential moisture problems so there it
is nicely
microplaned uh spread not quite as thin
as I like to I did get a little bit more
here than I would have I could have
spread more out this way but
uh it is on the parchment it is sealed
in the box and just like that I've got
my 220 190 160 120 90 73 45 and 25 all
microplaned up and
all easily held in a hand you can place
these wherever you want in your house
they're not going to be getting dirt or
dust dog hair they're not going to be
getting knocked over by
children these are easily to to put away
and to leave and to allow to dry um the
humidity is fairly High here we're
probably looking at about 35
40% I'll get these into a room that is
about 30% humidity I have a dehumidifier
downstairs and I have the room sitting
at about because it's in the coldest
part of my house it's probably around 60
65° Fen right now so that's where this
stuff's going uh thank you guys for
watching this is the first of of of my
garden I'm I'm going to be running all
my plants so stay tuned this was the
first Astro Boy and I'm drawing the the
Cannabis right now I do believe it's
going to be less than a couple of ounces
it looks you know it barely fits uh
fills the inside of the pizza box and
even today it was shrunk down quite a
bit more so it makes it our assumptions
of the higher yield that we thought we
were going to get there's that
prohibition based mindset sneaking in
even with me and John um always thinking
that oh we're going to get this much
we're going to get that much you will
get what's there if you know you're
efficient and you know the job that
you're doing you know how to do it you
will get what's there so the final thing
I'm going to show you on all of this is
I'm going to show you some macro
photographs of the final product I want
to show you some melt videos of the
final product and uh then we're going to
I guess these will be separate parts
from this video this is the final part
of this video um the next video I'm
going to show uh coconut oil extraction
I'm going to take the material that I
have have wrap it in a
cheesecloth um put it up to a very very
low boil like just a boil inside a
double boiler we'll heat that coconut
oil up we'll stick the cheesecloth in
there with the uh plant matter and we'll
steep we can soak that I mean in a crock
pot you can leave it up to 8 hours you
can get the job done in about 2 to 3
hours just on a stove top and uh that's
what we're going to do next on the video
so I hope you guys are loving this stuff
and there's more to come so thanks for
watching Bubble man's World
[Applause]
Peace
who knows who knows who knows who knows