[Music]
all right boating with flab how do we
roll flap
awesome
boating with Pelican cases
[Music]
yes normal so he just came out a little
shopping flavus keys oh it's great dude
hey let's hit the boat yeah beautiful
day on the dock and my boats just been
sitting there for the last week there
she blows I'm gonna take that out and go
have some fun
we can go look for some oh I just saw a
big splash out there I don't know what
that was but could have easily been a
dolphin or a seal probably a seal more
likely than anything with all right
let's get on this bad boy need a hand
well here let's do this first let's pull
the boat in I like to leave it on a long
line so it sits off the dock all night
Marcelle mm we get the big end i don't
untie it yet whole you're tying your
shoe I'm like don't untie it yet Dave
I'm gonna have to pull it in again yeah
all right well we're not sure where
we're gonna go on this little adventure
but pack up this boat and head out we
are in Tzfat ah boat bound bro and we
got fat glass this is that what I'm to
understand yeah we got a couple pieces
from earlier today that we thought you
know we got some water features on
Marcel brawn pieces out on the boat now
that's what I'm talkin about what a
special day we got
oh well I brought this one that looks so
sick
looks even more beautiful out on the
water
beautiful hood that is sweet and it's
with us coming out with us today
so nowhere do you want a head bro want
to head over to the islands you want to
head to Gambier you want to head to
Boyer really easy on the back end you
want to go to hock at bay right across
the way
yes all right well you got that you want
to put him back away dude it's got its
own cable actually made some water we
can pump out of it all right as long as
we can move in the boat oh we can go and
everything else is good to go
dude on the boat with the glass
oh we're gonna head over to gam here and
well of course you guys are coming with
us so let's get on it
all right so got to a little set of
islands here deep in the house sound
just in front of the back end of Gambier
up in the North End where anvil islands
and Diamond Head are towards Whistler
and you can see this little island is
just teeming with happy little life we
got birds
we got seals
they're chill
[Music]
but bubble man's world nature right
cool
cool guys
hard to hold the camera steady and give
them a good show I think we're just
gonna go around I think you'll be
packing bowls real soon that's what I
think
well here we are amongst the seals the
mountains and the ocean and the flavin
aiders loading the fat glass so I kill
the boat it's gonna take us over to bird
island there and I'm not sure if I want
to go around the back of Gambia take us
all the way around
let's go back over in Hanover and hit
another bullet Bowen yeah another one
okay so we'll go to Hockett bay then
yeah all right so we're hitting the bowl
here though start this session up we've
got Marcel amazing seals good dirty
window you guys are probably picking up
on through the Sun but okay skill the
sake and the lighting skill
I'll tell you
it's we're out into the ocean
champion and it's still lit I'm not sure
I've ever hit a piece that heady on a
boat honestly
yeah
right here
it's a truck well I mean I'll my hands
yeah you job
have a tote that's really we've hit the
Marcel I think we're either gonna head
over well let's head over to and then
it's a quick boot right across to Bowen
Island and on our way back we can get
[Music]
so this is Hawk at bay
you want to go pop it
maybe mark in this
how you feeling with the Phoenix
it'll look so good on the boat
just unique you know we don't always
take these pieces out like this
pushing boundaries here
we're taking the peace to a place that's
of equivalent beauty of it
all right but I think this is where
we're gonna hit it awesome
[Music]
yeah this is real it's real sweet ever -
dude well real sweet so hock it BAE all
right all right so we're like like on
rocks dude
I did them right there I'd say we're
eight feet away we just about [ __ ] the
dog
so we're gonna have to be careful it's
pulling in pretty fast
[Music]
think
we're gonna be puffing and it's gonna
take a little while so I think I'm gonna
have to pull out a little bit I can't
believe where we just were dude holy
[ __ ] I look down oh it would have been
brought my vibe down
oh for sure killing your hai no like
[ __ ] around either and so I think I
recorded all that yeah I did
awesome here well start it over so I
don't have to seems like all right well
you guys missed that but I pulled this
up I set everything up and then we were
like literally eight feet from the rocks
the boat the wind is blowing in pretty
strong yeah so I guess we're gonna have
this quick session you require hashish
bringing us back to our rocks licensed
yes good we take a nice long break in
between rips around all stoned
well not inconsiderate I find that
cannabis makes me more aware and I'm
less likely to want to do anything like
drive or operate any type of heavy
machinery when I just don't you just
want to sit around for just sort of sit
here for an hour after music tiny little
Hockett baby looks like they also have a
Marcel custom piece and they're wearing
a Marcel shirt and we're like we've got
the Marcel Phoenix and we have a J Lee
shirt on well no I think I don't think
it's anything to do with that I think
it's that my position I feel pretty good
about it
nice herpe hit though right master be
hit perfect flame placement right on the
hashish Terps boat Terps pretty close so
that's the thing once again sideways
there on the wave banks you're done just
since you turn the boat off
awesome well we're gonna chill here in
Hoggett Bay for a bit and we're gonna
find ourselves another spot to go for
sure maybe Bowen Island alright so we're
just driving making our way I guess what
would you call this straight straight
between the straight straight between
the straight yeah exactly
this attaches West Vancouver the water
to Sunshine Coast and then you can
escape out through the back end there
which
Vancouver Island I guess Paisley and
some other islands are back there as
well so
[Music]
I'm Johnny's not here to chase the mind
he's already here to do its purpose of
that without the trapping complete
Stumbo 20 miles away sleeping on the job
would but nine o'clock to watch fresh
for the tuition we cheese and we throw
out all right so let's start that over
again so this house is an island on an
island it's separated only by a small
little area and the land the land is
just right under that water and that
water goes into a cave you see that day
of the cave and that's his driveway
that's how he gets on to his island
where he has his home and his windmill
so that is pretty effing cool
I thought I'd show you guys that how
baller is that yeah sweet my girl rock
so this is Bowen Island on our right we
got Vancouver Island in the background
hot island see a big boat cruise
probably one of the ones from Holland
huge Love Boat type thingy
and horseshoe base right over there
where the fairies come in from Vancouver
Island bunch of sailboats out we're
gonna rip around this corner and pull
into the Bowen Island marina government
dock there that I can pull up on and war
to
all right so fluffs steered us into
Bowen Island marina here we've got a
ferry that comes in here once every hour
hour and a half it's a real nice little
zone always quiet in here you can kayak
in here you can hit rips in here give
the lighter
lie down in Chains brother and I should
have I got to be mine but you got to be
man if I pull this off
this would be one of my favorite hits of
the year right now it's just so nice the
sunset
[Music]
I think that might be my favorite hit of
the year love
I'm happy to be a part every dots right
in front of us
yeah I think Languedoc
you want to come take a front yet um
yeah for sure
nice
[Music]
I'm gonna do a little s pattern to slow
down so you guarantee make it
you can do it man I'll slow down if I
have to
I got real lucky
[Music]
I almost forgot these guys so we're just
doing a little photo shoot here we've
got the pieces set up on the Pelican and
we've got the mountain range in the
background so we're kind of doing these
little sort of showpiece you know here's
the fish mm peeth piece on Bowen Island
right on the ocean Pacific Ocean what
story from a shadow they're guys really
beautiful epic historical piece in any
aspect of how you look at glass in the
last 15 plus years
there's the man with his glass sweet
brother all right well that was fish mm
and the photo shoot that was real fun
we're uh we're gonna head off Bowen now
we're gonna head over to this island
over there Boyer so that's what we're
doing thanks brother you didn't even
really say hi to Bowen too much small
little marina a couple of nice sized
boats there though
and this is where the ferry comes into
snug Cove but more on that later packing
them up I like how the Phoenix is just
sitting on the back of the boat in the
Sun I love everything about that maybe
we should have a quick rip here at the
dock what do you think I think that's a
pretty good idea okay Laurie here what
do you feeling like ripping there you go
sir guys we'll start with you you're
right in the in the sun.star again great
this is some D 420k og cush
need the lighter oh no you had it you
did oh he's got a memory he's saying yep
that's what I did
Wow is it nice to be on the dock and
chillin though hey yes
they're not having the wind blow your
view on every half-second yeah that's
real nice
yeah let it grow
bub rips on boats
pumpka pumpka
amicable bumper to bumper to bumper and
then report bunka the bunka go from the
cinema sometimes I made our time now
Fiat so quick and easy I great cross
that when the same tycoon boss is not
here to trick the mind it is only here
to do its purpose of time ganja is not
here to change the mind it is only here
to do this purpose of diet when I
imagined oh dear Rodya be some cups
sitting up the blood and semen a lyric
in our TV trucks what you menara believe
in the lives and tell me your grams and
car start upon the scene
you see reality Avalon at 25 believe I
mean and this walkie-talkie
[Music]
buh-bye
did the perfect roof on top
and it wasn't my father
father it's rough spot we are do funny
but here right what about dog ever drive
on top
gumgum Whistler is one of the first
you'll see it is the first island you'll
see in the middle of the house sound as
you're driving by the beautiful ocean
come out from ocean bay and this is a
pretty good island in the sense there's
very small community that lives on it
very small like maybe 20 houses maybe
even a dozen the whole back side from
here all the way on and all the way
around is completely on in half
it's always icy bald eagles
seals see
some Dolphins around here it's a very
active nature zone I've even seen this
wall right here when the water goes down
full of purple starfish like a thousand
of them so it's a really really
beautiful area but just you know the
different types of trees the jus
douglas-fir and our beauties it's just
beautiful
look what more can you say really other
than maybe we should hit a beautiful
glass pipe with some really nice hash in
the setting of this
it's probably good idea claps shaking
his head up and down yeah yeah I would
have to say that that's pretty good at
night
all right
so you were saying about Amsterdam um
we're gonna be taking a lot of fat class
to Amsterdam we're gonna have a lot of
really really melty hash a lot of really
nice prices and even today whether it
happens or not one of the ideas I put
forward to Craig Gregg sorry and
yourself was that we would shoot some of
the glass that would be in the gallery
show and that we would and that we would
take some really beautiful photos of the
pieces in nature in these sort of
settings you know high end photos print
them G clay prints you know not too too
big but not too small and then do a
gallery show with like I don't know if
you're doing a half a dozen or a dozen
pieces or ten pieces or what it is but
you know and then have a picture for
each one that's hanging in the gallery
maybe the piece isn't for sale maybe
it's for sale but you can't afford it
the picture might be and it would be a
nice collab to if you bought yourself a
piece like that
throw the awesome photo in it these guys
absolutely that's my skills are 54 to 1
let's go hit in the fried boat yeah
perfect into a beautiful day my friend
really really really this is awesome
Boyer Island right behind us we've got
the mainland attached to Vancouver over
there and Ville in the background
Tantalus range way in the background
those sharp edgy kind of mountains and
just haven't saw black dusk earlier it
was so clear we're going out yeah
that off my lap there this would be the
last one a good day did we hit fish mm
no good never even put water but she
came out for the ride I gotta hit it
we'll do it yeah do that right now
I think so I mean why wait how are we in
the back there from the island beautiful
oh what's that oh you have a liter of
water in this thing so yeah if you were
missing water we could definitely sort
it out and then we're floating on
oh geez I don't know what do you think
800 trillion metric tons or something
yeah now we're slowly getting seemingly
pulled we are Hey
[Music]
thanks brother sorry to be a pain in the
butt dude but it's fish 2004 fish 2000
I'll be a pain in the butt bro I mean
come on so happy you know I've spent
time actually with Marcel in this sound
on kayaks over the years he used to come
up and we'd chill out and he was one of
the people a few people actually that
would come out on the kayaks
did I get the last one well it does
because we're looking for the lighter
Luton actually you know what you did
yeah cuz I felt like I just literally
took a hit there's a seal right there
beauty of the day I mean honestly in
this moment really for me the only way
to make it you know a slight bit better
would be to see the pod of killer whales
or the pod of dolphins come in yeah
not even to hang out for long even if
they just ripped by oh it would just be
like so for those of you that don't live
here but that might want to have this
experience you can go to Horseshoe Bay
there's a place called sewells marina
sewa LLS and sewells marina rents these
little boats and they're perfect for the
job of getting out on the house sound
ripping around to all the spots that
Slav and I just hit today
there's maps on the boat that shows you
specific names and where you're going
and it's very easy sound to not get lost
in I would only say that it isn't a lake
there's tons of dead heads and trees and
you can really muck up your boat if you
don't pay attention but what have we
been out on the water for two hours come
on that's good
we were on Gambia you're over by anvil
in the islands we were on Bowen and if
you don't stop like we did it only takes
you like thirty minutes to do it all
well yeah exactly
the real the real fun is in the stopping
[Music]
Wow look at that it's lit no you have to
light it all right so you ready for your
90 micron you take fall now we're just
float in a perfect little spot here
aw do do these perfect fish mm in the
sunlight the color to all the different
colors of the day curl you're just hot
yeah they really do I really do it
almost feels like we're anchored the way
we're just sitting there if it's all
pretty much just stopped and this is a
beautiful panoramic Vista oh yeah what's
going on which we're gonna share right
after Flav takes his RIP because this is
the last rip of this particular session
it's been an absolutely wonderful puff
Wednesday I'm really sorry I didn't make
it down to Mission for the Pacific
Northwest garden supply vendor day I
made it to abbotsford that was pretty
close but i'm glad it worked out that we
got to get together yep
great to have a session with your
downtown some lunch hit your place get
my place come down here and then do a
little boom boom boom almost like rabbit
John yeah so good dude well once again
dude thank you for your hospitality of
all your beautiful glass and hands for
the let's show them what they're missing
[Music]