[Music]
oh yeah
oh yeah yeah
who is that is that johnny [ __ ] bee i
just figured i'd hang out here dude what
are you doing out on my deck with all
your screens in my kitchen table well i
ate for one um
i need some i need a hand
first of all dude dude [ __ ] right
brother
it's nice to see you or half of you yeah
it's nice to see half of johnny b he
used to be much uh more
he's less but in when you when johnny's
less he's still more
a lot more he's still more i think
there's more of me now that there's less
of me yeah that makes more sense so
listen right off the bat this is a very
exciting video i've been waiting to do
this for a while now uh this is the
quintessential dry sift video we're
going to talk about uh the dry sift
wizards methodology that he uses with
the 60 and the 90 mesh that's awesome
we're going to talk about the um 200 and
the 110 which i've been showing for
quite a while with karting which kind of
became you know came into this static
thing with a dvd and some parchment
thanks to me's
then that kind of grew and people i
think jungle boys and some other people
were wrapping paint rollers and
parchments uh and then recently steven
marick uh from team dry sift was really
posting a lot on my facebook group about
this nitrile glove method and i i had
seen it over the last couple of years
just glimpses of the picture of the
glove with resin on it
someone had sent it to me on instagram
and
i never really thought much about it
uh and then lo and behold steven came on
to team dry sift and was really getting
into this conversation uh the process is
going to be shared with you here today
john has some absolutely
spectacular looking cannabis uh that he
brought over in boxes it's freshly hung
tell tell us a little bit about your
cannabis actually um you know um we know
what's great about this one as i kind of
knew i was coming here so you should
check this out
so i'm getting a hand here dry sifting
so check this out 57 degrees
45 this is going to be
the four month cure
so we're going to grab a screen here
buddy's going to help me grab a screen
right now we're going to grab a 200 use
screen
200 ooh that one's damaged
we're gonna have to find another 200 to
use screen we're gonna go grab a screen
we're gonna put this in the car we're
gonna go head over to mark's place we're
gonna grab a 200 screen and we're gonna
head over to bubble men's place we're
gonna grab these plants we're gonna put
them into bins and we're gonna get going
i got my friend here helping me out just
because i can't actually do it
um
that's going to be the uh
oh my god it's just your complete
blanket told you guys about it yesterday
um
animal cookies
it's been hanging for four months
smell anything
yeah yeah of course you do
okay we're gonna get this going here so
now that you guys saw that you uh get
what we're working with here we're also
going to show you
um a little bit of footage with the
camera up close of each of the cultivars
so we're going to go through those
cultivars right now you know i pack
these up as a house and uh after a four
and a half month hang
you guessed it four and a half month
cure
ooh nice cardboard box johnny you like
these
all nice and it's still cool inside you
can feel how nice and cold it is in here
nice
dude
this is called the biscotti oh
is this the biscotti that one there
these aren't
they aren't
yeah that's the scottie cake and this
here is the medi
well that's the med yeah and this is
biscotti cake
so this is a biscotti crust cake
and you can see it's just like it's just
glowing with crystals i mean it's really
just like and now
when you get a really good look at these
strands and like i just can't wow i put
my glasses on dude
oh it looks nice johnny i'm i'm
impressed
this is four and a half months cure this
is proper hang dry this is no screwing
gun this is a slow
cure because when he talked about dry
sift and when i listened when the skunk
man sound was talking about how like the
three and four month cure was truly the
resin exactly shrinking the heads before
you go do the work or you do the work
exactly and it's kind of like you know
what and then you know things happen and
and uh you know flooding in abbotsford
and then i wind up hurting my back and
that's why they've been hanging for so
long but what perfect timing i think it
was meant to be
truly meant to be
on this strain here do you want to put
these ones away first so you have room
to pull those ones out
i don't want to we don't want to keep
them all so cold although it is nice and
cool out here like it's definitely not a
long day look at the box look at that
look at the first bounce in that box
see i know did you see that
isn't that amazing oh my god i looked at
that and i'm like that's why i put them
in these brand new boxes guys
but i mean
it's like
first bounce is just the most amazing
and you can see how that happens there
so we're gonna get these going but you
can just see
lots of good resin coming off of these
oh yeah
now
oh i got it we're gonna throw some of
this in here just in case we want to do
some fresh you can see that's some uh
this is pink goo and that's just like
killer guys
little pink little johnny b
thank you
and good here now
this is going to be
that's more pink goo
and that looks like some more pink goo
smells delicious
and
this is going to be animal cookies so
you can see the color of it and the
difference though so it's the cookies
cross with that
this was a bc bud depot run so it's an
animal cookies from bc bud depot
i can definitely see that there you can
just see how that is now this has got a
real creamy flavor to it but this this
pink goo and the media as you can see in
that biscotti cake is stacked are those
the ones you're most excited to process
i'm really excited we'll start with
those because we're gonna have to trim
these down get the buds off break the
buds down do the sifting
um and we'll kind of break it down into
into components we may get to all of
them but we'll definitely do the top two
so what i did was those first ones that
i i did trim they just this is the first
mouse that fell underneath so this can
actually be cleaned up already but
that's first bounce sitting there
so that would be the first bounce and um
yeah it was underneath the screen
all right so uh yeah i was out actually
looking for a small 250 micron
round
because that's nice when we when we go
through this process and they'll we can
do the redistribution naturally through
the 100 um 110 lines per inch which is
about a 150 to 160 micron and this is
the very simple process that most people
know you use your first screen this 110
mesh or lpi
which is about 150 to 160 microns that's
the screen that the flower won't go
through but most of the other stuff will
the bottom screen which is a 200 lines
per inch or mesh which is 70 microns the
magic screen that's the one we're going
to catch the good stuff on that's the
one we're going to do this nitro glove
trick on but before we start that i
wanted to talk a little bit about the 60
and the 90.
this is an old process from california i
believe
i'm not exactly sure who told the dry
sift wizard the process but i heard it
was a guy in california
um so the tricep wizard shared this
technique with me quite some time ago
you can see a piece sticking out right
there do you see that it was just
sticking straight out and that's
interesting because this process
are very large screen holes very
different from this um
160 micron to 70 micron this is actually
a 250 micron on top you can see through
this and or sorry on the bot on the top
and then on the bottom you have a 250.
it's actually should be reversed it
should be the 250 on top
and the 180 on the bottom
so i believe that's how i have it
90 is
one's not marked in the 90s yeah the 60
is the 250 and it's on the bottom
and the 180s on the top i think we need
to reverse these
this process i haven't done for a while
and so i don't want to get it wrong
[Music]
this um
like this
there we go and so
what happens is everything falls through
the 250
lands on the 180 underneath and
i guess the heads go through
and land on the bottom but on the 180
screen you see these little like it
looks like little trees that are planted
in the screen it's a neat process we're
not going to do it here today but i can
explain it to you very simply you're
going to take some nice dry material
toss it across the top screen i would
have this screen flip the other way but
we don't have the risers right now that
way when it's like this it protects the
flower on the inside and it's not going
to kind of end up all around your
wherever you're working your workspace
is so this process is a very quick
first bounce process where you just
throw some material on you don't
manipulate it or work it hard in any way
shape or form
the heads are going to fall straight
through the contaminant falls through
like this and it gets stuck in the holes
of the big screen on the bottom and you
end up with these it looks like a like a
little area of trees miniature trees or
something so very cool process these
screens are available at
freshheadies.com and bubblebag.com
um but really the ones we're going to be
using today
are the 110 and the 200. and we
mentioned earlier how it you know the
history uh leading up to stephen sharing
this process as well as a couple of
other people i wish i could remember
their names that were sharing it on
instagram shout out to you guys as well
and this is a very simple process where
you're doing the static process that we
learned with the dvd and the parchment
except what we learn is that the
particles will all become charged in the
static
buildup of i guess us touching the
screen and doing circular motions or
whatever
and so
um
you need more than just that you also
need the pressure of your hand and i'm
going to show you guys the whole process
here in a bit we'll start breaking up
some of these flowers break them up ju
however johnny likes and then we'll lift
up this this top we're just crushing it
yeah whatever we'll crush them up crush
them all out
like we're just whatever like there's no
like boom let's crush it whatever we
have underneath we can do the process
for and see what kind of piles we can
end up with see what kind of a melt
factor we can end up with
that's what i'm mostly interested in um
so yeah
for me
this is not about first bounce this is
fresh plants but like we said we're
gonna eliminate the first bounce and
just completely crush it this time
so it's like chucking these plants on
there
and so we got two plots in there my
friend
yes so you just want to do one cultivar
at a time so
now we do have these scissors that you
can get from your basic um kids drawer
yes that's where we pulled those out
from all right so this here as you can
see this is just garbage that's all the
biscotti
cake all right so you can smell it
and it's definitely got um
it's got some nice resin production
there going on
you know what
i don't know what's best about this
tell me is in reality
you know what this is not how you should
do this
if you're going to be saving these buds
but we're actually collecting all this
resin so
i thought the scissors was a great idea
until i did one cut like that and i'm
like what are we doing
isn't that easier
that was a lot easier check this out
and always go towards not behind if you
go towards you're just going to come up
very
easily can see the resin just like pile
it's nice and dry
so it is properly cured this is four
month cure this came in here it was if
you saw the humidity levels on it so
it's really nice and i'm pulling this
apart and i can feel how juicy is in the
middle there because that's just like
wow
dude there'll be a lot more resin on
this what i would suggest after we do
this is let this material dry out much
more
and then uh and then we can get uh you
can get cause there's it's still got
some freshness to it you know oh yeah
i'm just like wow
beautiful material i just don't want to
break heads
i just want them to kind of fall off
yes
so there's a few here that were nice and
clean but like the inside of that is
oh it's beautiful
i think with the best part about this is
actually you would put it on the screen
like that yeah let it sit loose the
temperature out right now it's nice and
cold it's dry give it a couple minutes
it'll dry right out again because then
when you get that weed in your front
joint you go use the bathroom and you
come back with a little bit too dry
right so i mean right now because it
just came apart with me freshly in these
boxes let's see this box under here for
this nesting we're gonna open it up so
we
more packed with a really nice dry
because get
humidity but i guess a little bit in the
box because the boxes are closed it's
more cheering again so we're actually
sweating the weed out you have these
stalks right so this is like a constant
support system of moisture for the
flowers and this is what's being so nice
about this long cure being able to keep
those stalks at that level so
i mean if this was bone dry this would
dump
so hard
and we would have all of this resin off
in a very short period of time
but it's very fresh i didn't realize
quite how fresh it is so we're going to
kind of play it by ear
we'll leave it sit for a little bit see
if we can't get it a little more crispy
because it's it's very like marshmallowy
it's just after four months cure to boot
yeah it's really nice i don't like i'm
just like i'm blown with how how the
center of this is so perfect dude i'm
blown
like i'm really blown oh i'm right in
the middle of it look at that
yeah yeah i'm just because i'm i'm
actually surprised i thought this was
just going to crush really nicely over
the screen so it's nice and dry in the
room it was sitting around the 57
percent and then it went dropping down
to 46 there for about an hour or two and
i put the boxes abroad in here
so uh
i'm excited to see what it dumps
yeah me too
well what we can do is just to protect
it from
any kind of debris or
let's put it out like that
and we'll be back in a bit
all right so we're just going to collect
this herb it dried out a substantial bit
more but there is a ton of resin on this
flower right now and i'm sure john's
getting out the resin that is just
sitting off of the flower mixed in with
the plant matter but there's also
popcorn size nuggets that are absolutely
completely coated in resin so i think
ideally we'll wait for this material to
get much drier
then he can grind it up down into a much
finer powder
and do this process because with this
nitrile glove process
you can be a lot more um
rough with the material knowing that you
have a methodology of cleaning it out
that's um you know much quicker than
that dvd case
okay so that actually we've waited
another 10 or so minutes and that
actually kind of worked in our favor
broke it down a little bit more and kind
of ground it gently on the screen very
very gently i was like screw this [ __ ]
man let's get this resin off dude let's
get it off so what we're gonna do now is
we're gonna take all the flour off of
the screen
uh get it into its bag because this
flower has a lot more resin i mean john
was just saying oh i could roll this
into joints and share it with friends
have giveaways and stuff and it would
certainly be very decent joints even
with what's cute look at the resin on
here but there's a ton of resin like you
you die for this someone said here you
want this to be like i'll take this [ __ ]
do you want to grab the bag
so we're just making sure any
heads that are stuck to the bottom of
the screen there
dude
yeah that looks good
okay so let's keep it protected until
i'm prepared he's like that looks good
i'm like that looks more than good
it looks quite lovely
so we'll get a nitrile glove on here
let's hope that this glove is all
operational on the good side i'm gonna
get right out of the thumb so i can't
like block it yeah i'm going to
wipe this
the reason i do that is
is this is
cold metal
so i'll actually keep my hand on the
cold metal just to bring it down a
degree or two so it's not the warm hand
nice
that's a great idea some people won't be
able to do this process and some will so
we've done a single screen dry sift here
um we're now gonna i actually i'd be
remiss if i didn't show you with the
camera so if you want to lift that
screen gently for me johnny b
um i'll come over with this and give
them the view of the diamonds across the
screen right now
so you can see there's contaminant in
there as well
it looks like little stems inside the
resin
but we're going to get rid of all that
all right looks really good johnny b
thumbs up
okay
so
cool that glove a little bit more
cooling down the glove
and then i'll get you to pick this up
and just maybe put it over to the side
old hand on the on the nitro glove and
literally just doing like circular
motions to pick up as much of this resin
as possible there's tiny little bits
of contaminant which i just saw move the
resin doesn't move but the little bits
of contaminant move in the in the minor
wind yeah the mining
i'm watching it i'm like i'm just like
staring at it right all right here we go
i think i'm gonna give it a go
see
heads
um
okay with the thought eh
see the difference and now how it looks
yeah
oops
make sure you stay wherever you belong
so that's all heads now
yep
i can see just like all going over here
which is like people
but i mean
clumping a little bit which is not ideal
and now probably because of the heat
right now right yeah
but we can collect those as its own
grade
now i used to do something would you
change the global maybe at some point i
would change it right now because we see
that when we're doing with the with
within with parts we go a little longer
we start doing that and i see
exactly
yeah i don't think we'll be able to do
too much more because of these clumps
yeah
so we'll uh
be good if we had a clean card like i'm
really happy with the amount of resin
from that right now and then that quick
clean that i would normally spend
ah at least 20 minutes half an hour
doing only took about a second
it was pretty quick it only took a
second
it really did only take a second didn't
it yeah
it was kind of nice here these jars
actually came from horatio he gave me
these but he's kind of here with us
right now nice do you want to throw some
of this in there that's why i pulled
them out
probably a good idea get that in there
and out of the sun
i got like right away i was okay let's
get that out of there
if you saw that face
like
no i i would i just it is like like the
best first balance of the world right
now
johnny b
with the fresh first pounds
all right so here's a couple of batches
for you
this is the seconds and this is the
first oops
you know what's best about that we just
talked about that
that's this is the thing with heads and
you can just clean them up like never
feel that oh
i spilt them and they're all dirty it's
like get them back onto your screen
do the process again if you feel that
there's some oh i'm sure this one okay
i can see that you can clean that up
whatever you like
so you know what's gonna be important is
the type of glove too because there are
gonna be different i like the black
these gloves that i have are terrible
yeah yeah this is not the glove
you want nitrile not spelt with a y
first of all i like the black ones and i
use them at my um
at my facility and they really work
great
um yeah it's i've never used it myself
but i know that the black one we can try
it i'm just curious
for sure
make sure you mark your resins and put
them away and uh yeah we'll get to uh
the next bounce all right so what you
cutting up there johnny b some ping poo
thank you
some pink goo
thank you maybe we'll come check it out
with you real quick see how nice this is
i'm going to get rid of some of these
bigger families on here yeah but i mean
they're nice
where'd you get this cultivar from um
this actually came from um i'm gonna say
the fraser valley okay that's what i'd
be saying little fraser valley dank
razor valley tank that's where all the
fire comes from you're looking for that
gas you know where it finds all right
well we'll be back when all this is
broken up
well john's just doing the final touches
on this pink goo and uh you'll notice
that he doesn't have gloves on because
this is his medicine and he loves to get
his hands dirty he loves to smell the
herb he loves to feel the resin and
taste the resin you can feel the
you can actually see the difference from
the form of cure like you're saying and
they're where the raisins they're
they're just so
absolutely you can see with that last
stump too even the bees are coming up
yep remember doing this at champs
johnny's just picking up the last oh
yeah i remember the video charlie's just
picking up the last of the uh the flower
here then we're gonna lift up and we're
gonna show you what is on top of the
200.
okay guys there was uh some noise that
ended up happening which is funny
because when we first went to start the
video there was like three digger
machines banging and moving rocks but it
somehow miraculously stopped when we
started now it seems like someone's leaf
blowing and then the wind and then the
wind is also like
absolutely bonkers so we came inside to
do this i've been holding on to the um
ice pack here getting my hand nice and
cold
getting prepared yes cold is good we can
remove this top screen if you like i
actually don't need this and then what i
was going to do is put the camera down
on the actual screen instead of on us so
i'll do that right now
a little closer
[Music]
and then straight down like that
looks proper
it looks proper
okay so i'm gonna try the different
glove this time
the green nitrile glove
it feels good it feels better than the
other glove i'll be honest that glove
had a lot of ridges in it yeah that the
resin was getting stuck in because this
one i can tell already does it's nice
and tight yeah exactly you want a really
nice tight glove oh yeah that's
important guys okay so just cooling my
hand with the glove right now
and we'll see how this goes no it's not
moist at all it's totally dry nice
i can feel it doing the thing that i
don't want it to do
balling but look at that
yeah falling if we can get those little
balls picked up
and removed that would be amazing
because it's definitely so i think what
you do is as a colder room
yeah exactly just do it
already this is really high quality
resin too we're just trying to get the
message out i'm gonna do a bunch more of
these videos hello
and uh
and as you can see how i'm doing this
you do it like carting over as he's
doing that and you can actually pull
those heads out as you can see what i
was doing here so and it's actually why
i use the 250 is because if it was
way past you know even being able to do
what you're trying to do we could
collect all of this resin pour it
through the 250 gently
you know like flour mill it back onto
the screen
and uh
be in great shape that way look at the
color on that by the way look at that
wow
just beautiful yeah really nice
so yeah i guess it's going to be kind of
more of the heat in here
yeah exactly so we'll make sure we go
as cold as possible as again any any
little bits you see
that around that you can just even pick
up glasses hey check this stuff out guys
i have this here
you get some glasses i have some glasses
there you go they probably can't see it
because right now it's right on the
screen
so get this going again really quick
that first one dumped just amazingly but
mine it is like minus one outside or two
actually about three degrees mm-hmm
here's a question somebody's looking for
like a light rub no i'm rubbing pretty
hard i'm ready
i'm pushing contamination through the
screen oh okay so that way i was kind of
curious on like wow
like see that like i'm i'm actually
gonna take a picture of your hand at the
same time because that's quick because i
want to get it off my got it yeah it's
already gone like that you don't want my
warm hand warming up
you're melting your resin to my hand
there you go so that actually makes a
lot of sense get it off the hand quickly
and using the cold pack which is really
key important i'm seeing that actually
with that second round it's good for
people who don't have a cold room or
don't have access you know it's it's
another way to do it i mean we're doing
it in the warmth but it's still you can
see the process is still working it's
it's totally working like it's totally
working like this it's melting a little
bit it would be more efficient if i
didn't have these little balls that are
popping up they they really keep the
process because what they're gonna do at
this point is they're kind of balling up
the rest of the resin with yours yeah
they just start collecting like
snowballs and
which that's gonna melt like crazy it's
got a nice little you can make potatoes
in little hash balls
yep
it's really a nice pile though like the
color beautiful pile
and you can see underneath there so
they're always pushing through
underneath on that on the underneath
there yes exactly we'll have that as
well so
should i try to give you a camera shot
pull it off oh
of course we're doing one more shot
one more shot you should be able to pick
up some of this and then you can just
carve these uh
it'll be like the seconds here see of
course like a hundred percent you
probably even do a third on that i
honestly believe if you close your hand
up one last time then
oh yeah because i don't want to lose any
i don't know we won't because everything
that's here you're still going to smoke
you'll be surprised at how good it is i
already know
yeah this is not the stuff on the top of
the screen is not by any means stuff
that you're going to throw away no no no
we already know that the the magic is on
the 200 remember that the magic is on
the 200. the real magic is on the glove
well the real magic is on the glove now
that is the truth
can you just put that in there for me so
yes sir i surely can just fill that one
up there
oh this this is really nice resin this
is everybody said this is some of the
nicest resin i've ever grown which is
the the that goon i think this could
even by looking at the whiteness this
could be the maddie those last two i
really because they're so close together
oh that's exciting
normally i'll jar i would get a jar like
this off of my whole room
mind you i wouldn't be crushing it how
this is happening so now we'll also just
do this and you'll be surprised there's
still some great stuff here
and really the real proper way to do it
is to run it through the 160 again yeah
i wish i had my 250 screen because it
comes in really handy for that little um
work like this
yeah i've misplaced it but what i would
do is i would take all of this yeah and
i would put it on that 250
and all the resin would fall through and
all the little balls would stay on top
and then you'd be able to do that again
and then i do another great one for sure
i think you could eat one more uh
possibly but after
like
now
you have to make it really even okay
well that worked out really good
actually well that's the separation that
worked out really good you can always do
that when you're doing the sift and i
used to learn enough from doing a lot of
sifting because of course you know the
dvd you get these balls on there you
have to change the dvd over all the time
so i was getting this one doing the dvd
shouldn't get these balls on here to be
honest this is a warmth issue it's a
warm picture 100
100 being inside the room right now we
already know that i that's a thousand
percent what you said mark it's a warm
fishing yeah thousand percent the only
issue is that this wasn't so damn good
it's falling into it already wants to
melt yeah
and often when you clean it and it
doesn't ball the stuff that's left on
the screen that doesn't go on the glove
is still killer it can still be totally
melty we've seen that on top of that 110
screen all those balls and we did that
one but scotty cake
yep and it was like a bunch of balls on
oh it's falling up like look at how fast
yeah at this point it's hot in here
and and just for the final there but i
can't even feel this on the screen at
this point here i would stop sifting if
i was in my room and wait to come back
because to cool it down yeah because i
could feel that just using the card at
this point now
from the glove to the jar from the glove
to the jar
from the from the from the leaf
to the screen to
i like it i love it
shitty um try to get yourself good
brushes because you don't want these
little well those brushes were thanks to
your wife i know but these are not these
are not not for this quality this
quality resin deserves a much nicer
brush i like using the horsehair brushes
that's what you actually got in the
beginning there and i was getting yeah i
used badgers badgers nice see let's talk
about the different ones that you want
to use so that's good to use yeah my
wife just bought me a shaving kit years
ago and again it wasn't like i went out
and looked for badger
jesus look at the difference i know
let's take a picture of that yeah i mean
it's just like i said he's like let's
take a picture of that guys you're
definitely getting a close-up of this
and seeing the difference
and it's epic you can see the difference
with the glove tech and then how things
are clean with that
it's a it's really phenomenal
and this of course is the night
well why don't we
yeah that looks really good i mean in
the sense clear not as good as i'm
trying to know it's clear uh yes exactly
okay so
now what i want to do real quick is for
us to sit down and have a bowl let's do
that
awesome all right hey johnny we did
forget to show what was getting pushed
through the screen
and so this is all you know i would call
it contaminant it's definitely not pure
heads it's more than likely um
you know all pistol-lit hairs no sorry
systolic hairs decapitate stalks
cecil stalks
um i'm going to try and get photographs
of this stuff with the macro lens so you
can see the different grades what was
like ended up on the screen as
sort of balled up
hash and then the guys that you know
this stuff right here which
we almost owe it to ourselves to just
show a little bit of it in the sun here
because it's just
looks really nice
it works better than just really nice
really nice really nice
okay so well you can have it all right
it's okay i'll collect all of this
none of these heads will go to waste
but i do think it's time to see just how
well
these can melt
oh i'm doing the double screen double
screen double screen
what are you hitting
a big jar
from like the epic of course
which that's the big one there yeah nice
they definitely have like very different
color sequences just three different
photo sequences yeah you can see it you
can see the difference on the first
there's the first this or the one at the
end that you did in that last class yeah
yeah you could see that difference in
how that is so there's actually a
different difference with a separate and
how you're doing that oh yeah so you can
see and then this of course is at the
end they're all gonna melt you know that
right so a thousand percent oh yeah
i'm gonna like go home and take that
piscotti cake and just put it all in the
brows and i'm just gonna squish it oh
nice yeah it's called like clarity but
you get like an 80 to 90 plus percent
it's [ __ ] awesome right yep like
isn't that like what you would do you're
like what are you gonna do it's
definitely what some people that's what
people think are you gonna wear let's
see
what are you talking about waste there's
no waste i was looking for like
something to scoop out of them a little
something was pass me one of your
business cards
there you go johnny b
scoopy dukes
give yourself a little scooper
oh that looks pretty good
my goodness
i'll try to make a little video for you
guys so you can see it up closer
i'll just go ghetto styles with the uh
with the phone
you know what
now the last time we did this in 2012 we
laughed so hard we spoke so here's what
i'm going to ask you to do not light it
with this handle and cover the entire
bowl but light it with this hand and
come up from that way and then
we will get this whole thing on video
was it appropriate
i think it needs to be a lot bigger
yeah
all right well i'm gonna dab one of
those that looks oh look at this
beautiful my hands just like stuck
together dude that was like on i'm gonna
dab it
straight up oh look what fell through
that's why i'm gonna dab mine because
that is too good for screened
smoking it is too good for screen that's
why i double screened it
and that's why i was like you get to the
next level so sometimes you make it so
fine
every time when you do the nitro glove
i feel like
i'm quite excited i'm not gonna lie
i'm quite excited too i'm not gonna lie
because you know what as he's doing like
he did for me i'm doing the same for him
yeah yeah bang it a little
there we go oh there we go
are you ready
i'll put it in with this and then i'll
kind of get out of the way right away so
you can get the footage see the footage
is is this does it does it this is cut
is it you can see the heads and i'm
going to say we need a bigger dab tool
to be honest
i mean this is going to be perfect for
me
i'm going to hit this around 650 because
it is sift
yeah
do a quick dunk in the iso here
definitely left some residue on here
more so than a normal
well that's something about sift you
always get that and i'm gonna say no
matter what i'm always getting more
residue from sift with the flavor
i mean it cleaned real nice of course
you know i had to go in a little bit
deeper oh there you go here let me video
that as well dude i just dabbed that dry
sift in a turp slurper
i got you
i got you johnny
whoa
that was harder to
that was harder to light than i can
possibly tell you i know my fingers are
stuck to my bone
oh it smells like amsterdam
dude
very nice very nice headspace on the uh
on the resin hits that's just uh
beautiful i'm like definitely not for
everyone you know you might say like wow
you took a lot of flour and turned it
into a very small amount of resin but uh
john does this all the time are you
kidding me i took my flour and got twice
as much resin than i normally do exactly
so not only and you have a lot more left
i have a lot more left this is this is
exactly what we're looking for is
exactly what i'm needing at this present
time in my life so i can get me through
until probably until september till i
get my next crop right so it's
understandable it's in my medicine to be
able to have the separation have this on
hand when i truly need it is the best
part for me right now and i appreciate
you brother oh dude i like you so much
i really needed to actually sit down and
go over this and uh
this is gonna be your next bowl
yeah absolutely dude i'm super stoked um
super bait actually feeling pretty good
i think we're gonna wrap this video up
i'm sure you'll see many more of these
videos to come and uh yeah thanks johnny
b for coming by with your beautiful
resins and we did a nice isolation on
them and now you can take uh take it all
back home with you and like i said i or
like you said i hope it lasts
well into september for you because uh
it's one thing to want to get baked and
feel kind of like yeah i feel less
stressed but it's another thing to
lower the threshold of pain of chronic
pain to a point where life is doable it
brings it to that extra you can
obviously
enjoy the beautiful skies relax read a
book you know what it's uh it's what
works for me
hell yeah johnny dude save those turps
man that's what it's all about for me
yeah yeah we're not gonna let any of
this go to waste we'll be doing a
cleanup right now um thanks everyone for
tuning in and watching and
see you again really soon
peace out everybody
[Music]
uh
i don't smoke they talking that's why i
don't grow up
[Music]
[Applause]
and he is