[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am of course bubble man and I am out in
my world I'm out here early early early
um I'm going to be meeting up with d
420k today and I'm not exactly sure what
exactly we're going to be doing but I
suspect it's going to be involving uh
bowls and Adventures um one of the
things I've really been most focused on
uh on Bubble man's world lately and I'm
not sure if you guys have noticed is
promoting a healthy lifestyle promoting
a lifestyle outside of just sitting
around and uh you know maybe playing
video games on the couch or just
watching movies and not that I'm against
those things those are wonderful great
fun things to uh you know use up some of
your time with but for God's sakes get
out there and be with people get out
there and session get out there and do
you know uh BC is such a do place we
have an incredible amount of Epic fun
available to us let's just say for
instance right now I'm thinking to open
up the mother ship that's epic fun have
a little bowl with you guys got the
Taurus with me today a little bit of
water right here behind you nice full
bottle tell you when you go out on the
water you really want to make sure you
have a lot of fres fresh water with you
because uh the salt water is surrounding
you but it's pretty much useless yummy
little wet the whistle
there all
right all right all right all right
so got a new bowl today I'm really all
about the quartz you guys know uh
especially when I'm out and about
otherwise I love the silicon carbide and
the sapphire but Dil sent me this uh a
few days ago uh it's a brand new um
offset deep dish
bowl you can see it comes apart real
nice and it's just got a 144 hole that's
going to go right into my mother ship
now I do have a DC quartz Banger here
that I could easily rip as well but I I
haven't ripped this yet so I thought
this is my opportunity this is the one
you see it goes in real
nice boom boom could use a drop down on
that if you're uncomfortable with
putting a titanium nail into your pipe
whether it be a mother ship or any other
pipe I to totally understand where
you're coming from if I had a denail on
this I would 100% drop this into a but
for a quick little torch I think it'll
be okay I've got my hybridized
sublimator denail carb cap I've put the
top of the sublimator carb with the
bottom of the uh titanium uh denail one
it's got the D right on top
there and then I've also got oh man I'm
really loving this Dabber that Dil sent
me thank thank you so much guys I love
the feel of the wood in my hand what can
I say it's just a nice nicer than the
the feeling of uh the metal it's just it
fits like a pen or something you know
and then I brought myself a little bit
of
headband
rosin so this has gotten a little bit
dark but ooey gooey it was made from
some nice nice bubble has and the bubble
hash was very dark so I'm not overly
surprised that we've got a pretty dark
product here but uh I'll tell you this
product is is
strong no doubt about it so we got
ourselves a nice rip there uh this might
be my last denil or uh non denail
session on the boat I'm really close to
getting the denail hooked right up to
the boat I'll probably end up asking for
an extended whip might even put it right
here in the front so you can just plug
in the whip like that I think that would
be pretty cool let's give it a shot
shall
we so nice big torch nice set Bowl not a
big torch I mean a nice a decent Siz
flame coming off of this thing right now
it's really hard to see when you're
outside of the
sun give it a little bit of a seasoning
the best I can I know I'm going to have
people oh you didn't even season it oh
blah blah listen I don't need to hear it
torching it up real nice we'll get it
nice and seasoned for you okay change
that color as you can see it's going
nice and purple as I torch it
give it the best seasoning that I can
cuz I sure don't want to taste any at
all
metal so this is why we season the nail
get it nice and
piple oh yeah she's turning nice and
purple I guess probably this wasn't the
best bowl for me to choose when I'm damn
near out of propane or sorry when I'm
when I'm damn near out of butane and uh
the torch is running quite low but you
know what that's okay we got her she's
nice and
purple think she's off gassing anymore
but we'll see we'll just continue to hit
it if those purples to come in what they
do is they kind of come in the purples
and then they disappear so all of that
is what we will call the seasoning of
the nail you don't want that any left
over so you can see my nail went
completely purple and now she's almost
clear
again all right give it a last little
base to clean out the
bowl I'm pretty impressed this is pretty
much the
first well I don't really even have a
torch nail so this is one of my first
Nails I've actually had to season most
of the time they
I use the denail in such a low
temperature I just what I would do is
I'd H hook the nail up and turn the
denail way up and that seemed to do the
job so I've never actually done this
with the torch to season her out but uh
she looks clean more importantly she
smells clean she's starting to go pink
now a little
[Applause]
bit all
right seasoning of the
nail derbs
that cool down a tiny
bit so nice to have you guys out here
again I think we're going to be doing a
lot of boat sessions this uh summer it's
just so easy the boat's right on the
dock and it takes me all 5 minutes to
leave my house get in the boat and then
be out in the middle of the water which
is kind of surreal no one around
wow does that carb work
good unbelievable taste on that
headband you can actually taste
it like in your lungs it's not just
tasting in your mouth it lights up these
taste buds that are deep deep down in
your tongue I can feel
it like the taste of it right here and
it almost reminds me the taste of like
the first time I ever had dank the first
time I ever smoked weed that was like oh
my God this is just the most amazing
taste ever you you all remember that
feeling we've all had it where we've you
thought you knew what good herb was and
then someone gave you the
absolute chronic
fire and uh you hit it and you have this
minor uh Epiphany almost a religious
experience and uh that's pretty much
what I'm talking about with this right
here that was so godamn tasty very glad
I seasoned off the nail got rid of that
little coating that was on there and you
could smell it the tiniest little bit
but I'll tell you that hit was
Perfection really really
nice man I'll tell you I tastes like
another one and another one and another
one and another one that's what that
tasted
like
well has a
little kind
of view of the house sound here so we've
got the mainland that attaches to
Vancouver and that goes down and then
you see this little Island right here
that's Boer and then between the island
you can see there's a
fair now that fer is coming from this
island which is called Bowen Island just
this part of it that other little part
is a is a different uh
Island that one there and then beside
that you've got Keats the flat one in
the background which you can barely see
is the Sunshine
Coast and then this giant right here is
like it's a big one is called gambir and
Gambier has a little friend at the end
called Anvil all the mountains in the
background are the mainland but the
front one Anvil this big front one which
is not the one in the background that
tip that you see that's a little on the
bottom half of it that's actually the
mainland again that's Elfin Stone
National Park on the Sunshine Coast so
little bit of a house sound lesson there
for you guys um I'm going to just float
around here for a little bit maybe read
my book puff some more bowls and I got
d420 K coming down on the harlay so I'm
sure we're going to end up going and
having some fun either biking maybe
heading up to Squamish maybe getting out
on the boat but we will make sure that
we share some of it with you guys we
enjoy you guys and uh we're happy to
have you guys watching Bubble man's
world and d420 K's channel so keep
watching see you guys in a bit all right
guys I have just picked up d420 K on the
dock as you can see this is him not a
three-dimensional hologram this is not
this is the real deal this is the real
deal it's all D 420k and bubble man
today we're going to be ripping around
we might see some other friends and
folks we're going to go look for some
marine life we might even get on the
Harley and rip up north I don't know
where this video video is going to go
but I believe it's Wednesday is it
Wednesday so why don't we puff oh no
it's Tuesday is it Tuesday it is Tuesday
well then we'll do uh a puff Tuesday
we're going to head over to that Island
over there and get the rig out so d420 K
can get his morning rips yeah get his
his wake and bake on you know I woke up
this morning to about 6 T where you at
what you doing thought you were going to
be here this morning and I was like what
so I laid back down after about an hour
cuz I was was up late and then I got
more taxs where are you what are you
doing I thought the morning was was
you're coming up the morning so I got up
cleaned my mother my mother ship [ __ ]
right up proper and then uh packed my
bags grabbed a couple of wicked
sandwiches nice vegetarian one for my
buddy and a meat one for me cuz I'm a
meat eater and that's it [ __ ] a dude
well that's awesome I ripped out didn't
even rip didn't even rip before I left
it's 11: still so I guess that's
considered morning right it's afternoon
is after 12 it's before noon man so we
are still in the morning we're going to
head over to Boer and uh we'll catch you
when we get
there all right we made it we're kind of
in this little pool of water that is
trying to hide from the wind the wind is
Wicked Strong coming in from the south
up north and uh we're what 20 30 ft off
the shoreline oh no we're we're we're
more than that 50 at least 50 yeah good
that's what I like to hear
Darren Forge this [ __ ] up first hul of
the day for me very nice very ni I'm
doing a nice big rip wake and
bakey this might be the last you have to
hear that annoying sound of the torch
because we're going to try and get the
denil working in the boat real soon and
once that's happening uh I doubt I'll be
pulling uh the tor out
[Music]
again this is nice that we're kind of
locked in here oh good using the carb
cap
Dabber
combination it's a big [ __ ] rip
D cleaning my bowl off for my last hit
one nice thing about the torch is you
can just clean that nail till it's
literally like
dry there you go that was a nice
rip good rip
[Music]
oh my goodness that was good that was
delicious what a
rip I almost should have turned my back
I lost a good portion of mine right off
in the wind but I smelt it the headband
so nice very nice tasty tasty [ __ ]
rips dude holy so we're going to do a
little bit of a combination sort of fun
stuff day today I think we're going to
get on the Harley and do the boat do a
little combination of the two yes I like
that idea I think uh that'll be a little
bit different from our last video where
we just literally booted all around the
sound and uh you know from Gambier to
Bowen from oh it's good from Bowen to
what yeah no I was watching it earlier I
had it right on the front and it was out
balancing on that I'm so scared about
these things you know when I before I
got these I didn't want smoke out of
these because it was they're so
expensive and good looking that's a good
thing to always take off I find that
when it's left on that you forget it
sometimes cuz it looks like such a piece
of the pipe yes I've seen them get moved
real quick by people and those kind of
blow off when I've done that and
actually forgot it's been so gooed up
that it's stuck so I had to heat it up
to pop it off so I was lucky I got lucky
a few we're pretty close here now hey
yeah we are like how close would you say
that is I'd say that's a good 30 ft 30
ft 25 I'm going to move us a little bit
yeah I would too just so you know don't
collapse into the Rocks yep let's see
good idea it says it's only a few feet
deep here as well 30 ft deep 70 ft deep
50 ft deep I don't see no bottom
activity no it's not that easy to see
bottom around
here let's see if uh one of these times
I'll have to dive down and see if I can
touch the bottom and bring up a rock
what it's only what 200 ft some some
spots well if you're going to do that
I'd bring you over to a spot that was
like 5 600 ft so you could really
impress us really impress us that would
that would be impressive holy Christ
could you
imagine I'd come up like a big old red
snapper my guts and everything be
popping out of my [ __ ] mouth and my
eyeballs will be blowing up and yep good
times good times too much wind too much
wind that's what I'm saying right there
we got too much wind why don't we uh
head around this island a little bit and
see what we can see we might see a
little bit of uh see a little bit of
goodness
torch d420 k out on the boat doing uh
ofz dabs if you can see what he's got
going on there his uh ofc carb cap is
his Dabber
no we aren't claiming originality here
we just saw other people doing it
thought it was
cool yes exactly I seen someone doing it
and I thought [ __ ] that's what those are
for not just a carb cap there's
something to stick your dab to and put
in the bowl right down to the thing and
Bam you're [ __ ] in why not instead of
taking your dab tool dabbing it in
putting it down grabbing this putting it
on stick your hoot to that I forget who
I seen it off seen but I seen it on the
Facebook and it was [ __ ] perfect it
just clicked I put it on clickity click
Mothership fam it's perfect Optimum
flavor Zone I just found that out too
ofz Optimum flavor
Zone
Dage all right you're filming and I'm
dabbing so ooh yeah that's nice look at
the clarity on that Holy
bazooka very nice very nice very nice
very nice can't not sure if you can see
it in the sun there but uh he's very
beautiful so we've got this we've got
that where did we do with the whole shot
the big shot she's right
here just hand that over to me when
you're it's probably a good idea hey
just go it underneath yep Hard
Times Hard Times doing
this I'm going to go for the uh sort of
dual cab it up as you dab it up sort of
thing here see if I can get this
right and that tastes so really
delicious surp surprisingly great flavor
off of that uh titanium you know there's
a tiny little bit of difference from the
quarts but uh I mean it's really
surprising what a great hit you get off
that tie that tie
nail
sweet seems like the wind's almost died
down a little bit
D I'm still recovering from the last
drift oh yeah dude beautiful
awesome all right guys so we just made
it here next to the this giant military
ship and it looks like they're having
some sort of a little meal on it or
something at the back there there's a
lot of officers and uh nice outfits and
stuff all sitting at nice tables and
such so kind of a cool little
thing kind of
cool big
ship what do you think of that
D [ __ ] neat man look at the size of
that you get a couple picks yeah Wicked
that is awesome look at that thing I
mean holy [ __ ] the back deck is hundreds
of feet long that is
incredible I wonder if they're
dabbing in a perfect world we would roll
up and we would be the dab crew and we'd
be like hello yep dab crew here we're
here to deliver the dabs we put down a
[ __ ] hoist we pull up have our mother
ships huh [ __ ] that was a bit of an
adventure driving over here wouldn't you
say yes it was it was we got into some
Nar there I think it was from the ship
doing a little bit of a turn you can see
how the wood out there is disappearing
and then and then appearing and then
disappearing and appearing that's what
we really have to watch out for look
behind us too look
how
beautiful blue sky oh there's a few
puffy little
clouds pretty beautiful though perfect
well I guess we'll uh we'll truck over
and maybe go to check out Pam rocks
where all the seals hang out and see if
they're what they're doing today have a
float and maybe another dab a float to
floating to all right all right it all
right so we made it to uh Pam rocks
here see we got a little bit of seal
action on the Pam rocks sorry about the
Shady camera work it's hard when the
boat's moving to uh do good camera work
and uh I'm only willing to go so close
because this is the ocean and there are
all sorts of other rocks up in and
around this area
we could go a little closer to these
ones over here though you guys
like
[Music]
are oh come now my brothers
all R to the call for
one one United
World One
World which man cries are
heard my cries are heard then
why then why why can't the
poor W hey the poor they've been crying
out for this many thousand years their
vibrations are Trav to
other so come now my brothers
all ready to the call for
one one un united world for one word for
the you in i i crying out for Unity
that's what marus said who that's what G
said
yeah now for those of you who read the
book they call a prophecy it's what the
prophet said oh yeah that's what they
all said hey
hey oh
he
[Music]
W come
what what what what you going to do with
a judgment so near at hand what you
going to do tell me now yeah what you
going to
[Music]
do for the blood blood blood blood blood
blood blood
the
PO it's crying
out it's crying out oh
[Music]
yeah all right so we are packing up here
we just got to the dock and uh holy [ __ ]
he think I'm a ninja or partly partly
ninja so yeah we're going to uh we're
going to to get on the bikes let's let's
get off this boat all right
buddy all right let's do this
and that sure was a great day though out
there
hey beautiful beautiful look at the
clarity on the uh on the water near the
Rocks here you can see the big fish down
there
swimming over to the Rocks little ones
see those little ones there's big ones
in there too here is that oh yeah
okay guys so we've made it from the boat
to the bikes the bikes to my house we
realized that I didn't have the GoPro
completely charged and we wanted to take
you with us on some of that ride up the
highway cuz it's going to be [ __ ]
beautiful it is going to be y I mean
everywhere we've been today has been
beautiful yeah ni SM like this Astro Boy
Mother Mother Nature at her best she's
just loving life yeah sweet skunk behind
you congales behind me they're uh
they're happy so I guess we figured we
would do a dab with you guys got the
ninja nail right here gu we got a trio
of ninja Nails right here with the uh
Mothership plugged in using the super
high-end 5 gallon bubble now Bubble Bag
bucket to uh to hold the mother ship
made with recyclable plastics I'm sure
people will be commenting on that can I
offer you a rip there D absolutely you
can oh is it gladly take a rip I so love
not having to turn on a torch dude I'm
I'm not a big torch fan I really have to
say well you know they're they're
necessary when needed yeah but they sure
do [ __ ] a lot of noise wish I wish I
didn't eat them I love the idea of like
the Dil just being on all the time
wherever I am whatever the situation is
Boom there you go Dil action sir thank
you nice jobber I'm going to have to
bring up my denail and get that case off
for you the zebra wood the zebra wood y
it goes with it
nice autographed by the Dil guys and I
think it's number 37 or 137 or something
very cool yeah yeah we figured we'd do
another a couple of dabs here before we
got on the bikes uh we'll take a little
little uh little rosin check after all
that boating you get a little bit of
wooziness but uh I really look forward
to riding I love riding with Darren we
ride right beside one another we don't
really do the front one behind the other
kind of thing and we'll rip you know up
here to Squamish and uh I bet you we do
it in about 20 25 minutes
tops so that should be
fun oh wow
greasy greasy see
Ren DA's probably a little warm too
still working though I'm kind of amazed
actually nice that it pulled it off that
warm you know such flavor that head
flavor killer wow yeah I'm hitting
something different OG nebula
but kill her
y that's the stuff right
there well the GoPro is pretty much
charged
up the bikes are Wai
waiting and you've got dinner
arrangements for later so we should
probably rock and roll yeah we should
that was a good quick quick
rip let's do
[Music]
it yeah s ni say stick to the course now
let's stick to Life's course now and
Don't Stray away
now two days that come yes and seasons
pass man and man give thanks I
[Music]
say to be here on this journey that I
and I are on
now I want you to stop the way you're
living can change your
ways let's start
over there's so much so much to be
done I'll stick to the course
now won't stray away now stick to the
course now and don't stret away
now so on your mark get set and get
ready
now starting from a b c come on let's
make it
right starting from one two three
mathematics it no
lie hey children I night I
night now The Voice Voice of
Truth Remains the
Same today today
today as
yesterday it never
changes never
[Music]
Chang as the message in the
word you've never
heard it Remains the Same unless time
change
harsh reality of Life come home to
you you're not hearing the message in
the
words now you see the rest of my words
are coming to
pass stick to the course
now Don't Stray away
now stick to the course now
Don't Stray away
now so on your mark get set and get
ready
now starting from a b c come on let's
make it right you're starting from one
two three mathematics it don't
lie so Jud your sons and daughters let's
Unite
Play Your Part and don't let them sell
you a 6 for a
n and don't let them sell you no nine
for a
six you see them
so
Sublime that they will for it off you
you
you they will give you water to carry in
a basket
oh so on your mark get set and get ready
now you're starting from a b c come on
let's make it
right starting from one 2
three mathematics it don't
lie stick to the course
now and Don't Stray away now
come on play a part now let's play our
parts
now Don't Stray away now stick to the
course
now children I night
now all right guys we just made it to
Lynn Canyon in North Vancouver I don't
know if you've ever been here no I
haven't you're going to be [ __ ]
stoked dude this is an epic epic place
this is a they've got a suspension
bridge they've got some Cliff jump jumps
that can be done there's really
beautiful Trails the only one Downer
part is is there's definitely going to
be a lot of people so knowing D and with
the sessions that we're going to want to
have we're going to have to go off the
Beaten Track no problem we'll bring you
with us and uh we are constantly off the
beaten path [ __ ] right let's get
going all
right
sweet here these will be the types of
signs we see here at Lind Canyon cuz
this place is [ __ ]
extreme so what does this say extreme
danger this is a cliff right here like
about 800
ft so many many many people have died
here at Lin
Canyon running here too they've died
hav't they oh you can die even just
sunbathing in Lin
Canyon I think there's a rock down here
that has a it's got like a plaque on it
where a woman was just you know
sunbathing and The Rock released off the
mountain
and landed right on her was her spot
where she never
left right we're into the busyness
now I thought they were broccoli I know
look like
broccoli moving
[Music]
water everything
down oh my god look how [ __ ] busy it
is this is ridiculous it is I was just
thinking that well we're going to have
to wait a little bit cuz people don't
this is insane
someone left their Bud looks like yeah
no their bud that's terrible hopefully
they find it this is the baen travel to
Dempsey Road and it's a 15minute trail
we're not going to take it but I figure
we might as well hit over here so we got
baen Powell Trail we got Lin Valley
Dempsey Road 1 km 40 m we got Gross
Mountain Sky rod that's 10 km in 3
hours and 11 hours to get to Horseshoe
bath 35 km crazy so there's some people
standing over there on the other side of
the cliffs you see her
yeah just doing photography I
[Music]
guess are we checking this out D this
seems to be the place for us hey seems
to be ni out of the way really quite
nice little TR Trails I don't know if
we're going to be able to hit water I
don't know if we'll get down that low
but if we
do we'll hit some Bulls down here
buddy nice
yeah such a [ __ ] sick little Trail
hey beautiful down here nice and
cool walking some of that intense heat
from the Sun
right beautiful down
there all right I think this is
it might be a way to
get over the
fence it's pretty nuts dude we just
going right down to the water yeah let's
try cuz it might take take us down to
the water it might not there's a big big
ass fence right there
too so yeah probably what a lot of
people do is they just jump
over yeah there's a path right
here shall we spot number
one all right this is how we do it
jumping over
fences [ __ ] a I'm going to put d420 K
on just in case just in case I do a a
header yeah just in case you tank
bro well [ __ ] a duck there's a whole
crew damn
straight yeah let's head over let's head
over to this one I
think going to have to go to the water
[Music]
and up
never come down to this part of the
canyon I've always gone
around pretty nice little
pools all right
here water
bong
rip bong
rips all right got the
tourus set this up on a tripod and have
a little
session okay pause it out hey guys
welcome to Bubble man's world we are
back uh we're in Lin Lin Valley Lin
Canyon Valley this is a beautiful like I
can't even express how amazing it is in
this little area we were going to take
you guys over the suspension bridge but
instead what we did was we came down the
staircase as you saw cuz you were with
us and we found a bunch of kids on the
Rocks behind us you can see them between
us and they're doing little Cliff jumps
and stuff into these pools over on the
other side and we've got all of our gear
we managed to bring the dabbers the
[ __ ] torch the bowls the pipes the
[ __ ] tripods the cameras the
batteries the the cards the keys the
everything and we have enough for a dab
each so I guess let's [ __ ] get to it
see holy
[ __ ] that's serious [ __ ] torch right
there
bro [ __ ]
awesome get that nice and orange hot I'm
not sure what's going to be louder right
now the the torch or the water behind us
it's raging pretty
good loud wise
here you go thank you boss thank you
man all right we'll give that about a 20
to 30 second uh little spot you can see
some of these monster Boulders got
things balancing precariously it would
be nothing for someone to walk by that
thing and for it to release and that's
it it happens it happens out here it's
very [ __ ] important to be aware of of
your surroundings up in this in this
area all right here we go
proper great
proper that was proper you want to heat
that up and I'll get you sorted yes
sir I'm going to let the Dabber cool
down so I don't mess up getting all of
your hit all righty clean this
out oh yeah good stuff I wasn't sure if
that was just going to be smear or if it
was actually like a big hit in that
corner and it was a nice big hit well we
got a hit each a nice hit each nothing
nothing too
shabby what's
that right
brother DA's the G
420k by the river pretty [ __ ]
spectacular there a bunch of people in
there right now they're all uh going for
some jumping so I don't know probably
going to sit here for a bit and be baked
we're going to go up back up to our
bikes and get the rest of our hash so
that we can maybe try and hit a bowl on
the suspension bridge if we can it's
going to be hard who cares let's do it
bro you I'll hit it you camera or other
way around I don't mind I'll do it and
uh otherwise I got one other spot I want
to take D2 so we're going to get there
soon all right
so we're here on the top of the Lin
Canyon suspension bridge we finally got
it so it's empty d420 K is right behind
me and we're [ __ ] heading over this
bad boy man I haven't been on here in a
long time nice to see the bridge empty
too yeah that's the one that's the
waterfall
one 60 to 70 eh I don't even want to
look down and look at this one look at
this
[Music]
one yeah that's
insane let's walk a little
further these guys pass I want to have a
look at that yeah it's completely
psychotic what's
that yeah it's a little little mini pro
suumer model now do you guys go down
that thing like a water slide not that
they go down the actual slide there it's
called BM so how tall is that one down
there up here buddy well my thoughts are
uh [ __ ] absolutely blank absolutely no
thoughts it's just nice and Serene and
beautiful and it's pretty [ __ ] sweet
broing the sun's sure mocking with my
lens though there's a lot of dirt on
this lens and it's all catching in this
in this bad light recharging is what it
is hell yeah don't really think about
anything
yep we should head out all right
hear that I always said nothing's
prohibited so we can climb over the
fence anywhere we want we can oh really
yeah that's what I asked them cuz I just
wasn't sure if the rules had changed on
that or if that was still the same or
oh yeah totally
nice park
rangers oh it goes to show it's the sort
of BC Vibe right they've got a great job
they get to spend the day in here are
you recording yep he said the one guy
was uh had lost 17 lbs already yeah just
walking it and then they got these
beautiful boardwalks set up throughout
this
place like how quiet does it become
within like a few hundred feet yeah well
even less than that yeah
[Applause]
you can get hard heavy if you want to go
up up that way and then this is the way
I always went to Twin
Falls we can go have a dab at Twin Falls
sounds good to
me take these guys for a little hike
through the forest
[Applause]
you can see the pathways that lead still
into the
forest you have a pen in your tote I'd
like to sign my name on
that I
don't you might be able to use my Dabber
though to carve it in
so it says we're in an ecologically
sensitive
area got to help protect it what was
that ripping
around those squirrels yeah oh yeah look
at them Tree Tiger just having a blast
the tree tiger we call them up theg
they're so big just ripping around eh
tree tree tiger loving life the cheat
tiger RI I'm loving life on these
boardwalks some sweet sweet [ __ ]
uh sweet
digs it used to be all rocks and like I
loved it don't get me wrong but it was
uh much easier to twist your ankle or
trip got the
bench is the greatest metaphor for life
you get it out look at what you put into
it all
right nice to have a bench right in Lyn
Canyon we
could we could we've got the power
dude we've got the power and the
rosin we just don't have water right
nearby but as I said that I saw an empty
bottle in
the
yeah p
yeah hey go grab that bottle it's a piss
jug bro I'm not touching it eat the
yellow sow [ __ ] piss jugs everywhere
clearly Ricky and Julian have been here
earlier good job yeah he's all about the
piss buckets piss jug yeah piss
jugged oh did we get off the path here
what
happened this is what it used to be more
like right here sort of naughty roots
and
[ __ ] naughty
na super naughty
all right I think this might be the spot
where we're going to jump
out if I am correct it's hard to
remember I swear it's been 10 plus years
since I've been
here Yep this is where I used to climb
down although we can go down lower
before not we don't have to go from here
but yeah I used to see see how this
there's a little thing that goes right
into this River runoff I used to follow
it right down but there's a better spot
up here this is a good bench for puffing
on too though it's where the old trailer
used to come
from isn't it this one fits just right
it's nice it's good to me it's
nice all right we've officially stepped
over the chain Ling fence and we're into
the Nar well we're not supposed to be
yeah so I don't know if it's this way we
want to go or that way we'll have to try
one way and then if it denies us we'll
shut her down and try another way
especially carrying this [ __ ]
camera all right all right and here we
go this is what we got
to [ __ ] so beautiful in
here so sick what you can do is you can
jump that's about your only real option
right here to get down it's got to be 20
ft so I'll have to climb back up the
waterfall
what's up
D pretty sweet looking pools ehy y I
might do a periscope right
here dude look at how awesome this
is now that is epic you got to love BC
it's cool that we're at Lin Canyon
because we've never been here on Bubble
man's world before and it's one more
cool spot for you guys to notch down on
your little calendars bucket lists one
day to get to BC come to Lin Canyon the
cool air that's ripping up this Canyon
right now is beautiful you can kayak up
this you can do cliff jumping some of
these pools are 20 30 ft deep and uh
they're pretty safe for jumping so one
more epic spot let's go check out D on
the
bridge all right so we skipped the
bridge there's the bridge right there
we're going to come back to that we're
going to go we're going to go down below
right there bud what's that right there
hole in the fence and everything oh yeah
you old hole in the
[Music]
fence that one was easy
huh the old hole in the fence
wow look at this for a a
[Music]
lookout
sick you know dude this might be the
spot we sit down low I put this up high
looking down like this at us and uh we
don't interrupt those
kids you
did even though you might think you were
calling for the opposite yes I was it's
okay dude we're doing great do you want
me to carry that no you have both hands
it gives you both hands no you need one
I got one I'm good all right I can't
argue with that that was like hard to
argue with yeah you can't I mean you
could I could definitely make an
argument for it
but what's the point though hey
all right so dude this is pretty
sick pretty [ __ ] sick
indeed so I guess you can go right
through here or right down through
here high mountains of
the there and we Shield it from the
noise yeah we're going to do that I
think flatface
they
[Music]
living you're stuck where you
are as life goes
by as life goes by yeah goes
[Applause]
[Music]
by turn your St
[Applause]
around get your engine in
here and leave the stagnant
waterers
behind leave the St some nice pools here
stagnant Waters behind
[Music]
rock
music rock
music New
Horizon New
[Music]
Horizon woo let me tell you that was
close guys definitely getting pushed
over by this giant rock it'll be
interesting to see Dake this corner cuz
it is
toy have to get down
a little bit lower
maybe and here we are at the
headquarters
boom so
[Music]
sick just beautiful as you can see Lin
Canyon crystal clear
waters some people hanging out up there
but by all means we can hang out down
here why don't we do half our session
here and half our session at the up uh
at that crazy waterfall view
sure
sure well we found our spot
D yes we did more rips for us I'll hold
the Banger if you like sure
[Music]
sweet little right
yep that'll do it that will that'll do
it
propa yeah
man draw and dabs so you might not be
able to hear us very well so I'll talk
up loud as I can we are at the bottom of
the Twin Falls waterfalls in Lin Canyon
and we decided to have half our session
over here by the nice calm Waters and
then we're going to climb up a little
bit on a little ways up up where the
lookout was down to the waterfall and
we're going to have a a hit there too so
I guess we start with
this ready yes Mom is this you or me you
first it's me
first good to go
man it's wicked cool in here too isn't
it almost forget what a hot day it is
out there oh
yeah cool yeah be surprised yeah I like
the cool it bit get the heat up like
it perfect
going to get one of those for you my
friend there you go
bu so beautiful in here I just can't get
enough of it it's really spectacular
it's nice
here definitely nice sh
beautiful adds to the dabs adds to the
dabs
horiz New
Horizons for new just new new and
greener
pastures seek New
[Music]
Horizons all right guys so uh we're now
perched on a little sort of Lookout
about 50 ft over this uh this Twin Falls
pretty sweet little spot we got here
we're going to uh hit a dab
clean it up man clean it up real nice so
nice clean yeah turn all this [ __ ] off
just nice let Co down nice yep what he's
saying is he's just letting it cool down
real nice I know that we might forget
and if we talk towards the waterfall you
might not hear what we're saying but uh
that's all we're saying all right that's
hot as CL thank you so much well go give
that one a 304 second in yes yes
absolutely God is that just amazing I
think urge to want to go over yeah jump
jum another epic spot in British
Columbia awesome
Manina cleaner
cleaner
water
C the
water listening to the
[Music]
mus you got to listen to the
messing the
[Music]
mus let it you
walk
[Music]
the let it
Ro rock
[Music]
change rock
you seek New
Horizons new
Horizon see New
Horizon New
[Music]
Horizon
just I don't know if he just climbing up
the waterfall
or he's going for a
jump oh he's putting some stuff in his
pocket he's walking out on the rocks
sitting on the
waterfall now he's getting up
that's what I'm saying jump jump jump
we're watching we're
waiting looks like he's lowering himself
down into this
little stash
nonetheless none the
less all right well that was pretty epic
down by the water yes there's the bridge
that was down above where we were
looking down and we going that way yeah
that was sweet anyway we're going to
climb out to the bikes and go hit the
road so feel free to join us
extreme
danger should
think this is so much easier than the
way here
all right
we made
it time to get on the road
[Music]
Another Day In The
Life just another day another
day is he doing good
today is he
trying to change his
[Music]
ways now room wasn't in a day know
everything just another day
just he's here for a moment in
time he's
gone he's
[Music]
gone if a little time he has he's such a
destructive
one now lives given freely to L ises
[Music]
ises and living
experiencing Liv
on day in the life of
man just another day just another in the
life of
man is he doing good today now is he
[Music]
trying just another
day the life of
man now is he
trying to change his
way trying change the way
[Music]
I give two years hearing of this and
that this and
that like all on one know
yet taking in the breath of life now I
can use the Breath of Life
for either this or
that life's given
[Music]
fre just another
day the life of man is he doing good
today or isas
[Music]
trying another day
just just another day
[Music]
open your
eyes open your eyes your
eyes do the road of life is so
rough rug and and the you carry is so
heavy
[Music]
heavy it
it now the load that you carry is going
to get
ligh as the road of life gets
bright though the road of life is so
rough rugy rugy rug and the load you
carry is so heavy
[Music]
heavy whose load is
heavier and need a
pushup to get
over give him a hand if you can if you
can yes you can
[Music]
it it
and arise arise from your
Slumbers
arise All Rise open your
[Music]
eyes go the road of life is so
rough rugy rugy and rough and the load
you car is so heavy
heavy yes you got to be a
so if you want to get
ahead
[Music]
warise now
open your
eyes your eyes your
eyes open your eyes your
eyes the road of life is so rough now
and the load that you carry so
heavy so you carry you carry
on carry
[Music]
on open your
eyes open your eyes your eyes
it's my life it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
life we're coming from behind behind
[Music]
Spirit you and
warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors dring from
behind dring forward at this time
[Music]
so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and I come to turn the
tables turn the Paradigm around yes
deprogram and
[Music]
reprogram free mankind
hey yo
baby Tim feel good give me
[Music]
a one man home man
real weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we time VI
the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of dying
we have been traveling to King 20 M
hours sing on like the clock fresh
vegetation with trees and with
[Music]
FL give me oneg
andg pass pass pass
I make both pass pass pass and
[Music]
then pass that PA that
now up the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the man
it is only here to do its purpose of
dying well I imagine on the road some
cops setting
up TRS man man we me and F upon your
scene inter in my bra that and behind
your scene me and my te have another
25 we smoke it up clean
my
[Music]
now pass
pass make pass pass pass and
then pass pass pass and
then I make pass pass