[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world
everybody and welcome to Puff Wednesday
pu Wednesday with Johnny B dude it's
been a while hi you know Johnny B of
course has his own channel these days
over at uh John Bell uh is it is it John
Bell on YouTube yeah it's just Johnny B
Johnny it's not Johnny B it's John brell
John brell awesome perfect well dude
here we are um first time in a long time
you get to check out some of the rosin
that I squeezed out on the press and
we're going to discuss today uh a little
bit of Canadian politics in regards to
uh recently the power change that we had
here in Canada and we're here on Davey
Street at The cchq Vapor Lounge the
upstairs Vapor Lounge and uh we're just
going to film a little sequence today
the West Coast concentrate guys are
going to join us and uh jeez I think you
should start it off with a
rift what do you think
I'm I'm not saying definit you're not
saying no you want me to squeeze your
one out there nice little piece of rosin
that I pressed out for uh to check out
that's not that's that's not a little
piece I can show you let me show you
this nice little piece of r that I
pressed up it's about about
KS you know what it's so nice to have in
the background because I can
just hear him saying legalize what's
just recently
happen yeah I think both Bob and Peter
of course it was Peter Tosh's 70th 70th
or 71st Earth strong the other day I I I
think he was 70 or 71 or he would have
been had he uh still been around today
so I celebrate that we go little rip for
Johnny B now that's tur
Rich tur brdge puff Wednesday so we're
going to cruise around we're going to go
chill with the West Coast concentrate
guys today we'll probably grab a bite to
eat might even check out uh the other
cannabis culture uh Vapor Lounge and uh
just have an all around beautiful day
puffing
bowls right now of course there is the
background is the Blue Jays game which
is like the first time in 30 years or
some ridiculous thing that they made it
to close to the World Series I guess
they have this one more game what's up
yeah World Series it's a big deal for
people that care about this sort of
thing Johnny B and
I in the alternative group I knew the f
i KN I knew they were got in and I know
he's talking about legalizing cannibis
and I know what's happening in the
cannibis but in in in the realm of
what's happening in baseball not as much
unless he was puffing I would know hear
you you know so well here here's to a
nice uh Puff Wednesday rip with you
Wednesday and of course I decided to
bring my beautiful ball rig but you know
what we're going to probably use this
somewhere else because uh of course we
got a dual denail set up here and uh
Mark was telling me more about how he
has a second one set up because he's
getting I I know it's kind of
interesting when you explaining it to me
and I'm asking him a question while he
does his Great Big B to that is what
friends do just so they know that when
they're finished they got to start
talking it's awesome yeah basically uh
I unplug it at
620 throw it into the base
unit this one's turned up to just over
1,000° oh cool okay I like that it'll
heat up the bowlt really the only thing
we're missing right now is a Q-tip I
have been using Q-tips and I don't have
one on me if you have one that'd be
great beautiful so it's always just with
the Q-tip Tech of course you see how how
clean that that washes out check it out
I know and then it's just matter of
really giving it that last little pump
of air it'll probably be less than 5
minutes and we'll be able to uh a lot of
people when I was using the Q-tip they
freak up like what are you doing I'm
like clean out the residual clean out
the residual youan about carbon and it's
not lighting on fire it's interesting
how this isn't it does the job you know
I mean the the nail itself has only
really turned up to about 600° so I've
even kind of cleaned it up out of a bowl
that was uh close to 800° and still
haven't had that do the same thing so
Q-tips guys yeah the Q-tip definitely
works I hate to call it a tech cuz
really all it is is taking a Q-tip and
cleaning a bowl with it it's hard to
give everything a name with tech
now but uh it does the good job and uh
especially this is a tech yeah this is a
tech that's huffing certain ways in
certain what do you think of that new
paper instead of partment haven't seen
this before well you know the thing I
like about this is that it has no
special coating uh unlike parchment
which is silicone coated and the
parchment coating comes off uh in the
heat pressing of the of the rosin as
well as the constant opening and closing
it on the on the on the oil what you get
is you get that coating starting to
release and people can see it in how
they start noticing that the rosin isn't
coming off nice anymore it's starting to
stick to the part you almost seek into
it that generally means that your
coating is gone and I don't really
understand exactly what's happening but
I know enough that if the coating is
coming off in the hash or I don't want
to be smoking no pretty much if it's
coming off is it going exactly that's
the way I feel about it for sure so um I
don't know let's have another couple of
little rips of some West Coast
concentrate maybe
here yeah that's what I'm as you can see
I'm always
curious curious curious oh yeah going to
have to turn the nail down too that's
like I'd like it that you uh drop me off
these new little
uh bags cuz I I I don't have any I just
have the
[Music]
regular we're just filming oh we're can
to join and hit it uh sure come on in
and join as long as you're not trying to
hit uh solvent uh based extracts this is
the solventless quick I I saw the look
on the face that's cuz that that's what
everyone has all said he just like what
do you
mean I know you mean yeah but you're
welcome to come puff some bowls with us
we have plenty I'll show you what I got
just green smoke that much Shad really
well here have a hit of this this is is
that or no this is some bubble
hash uh here we got to just give you a
cool down on the nail here what was your
name bro Adam Adam
I'm Adam Works downstairs uh if you want
to come down and check him out he's down
at the uh I guess it's the cchq Davey
Street huh there's been so many names
over the years that I have to like ccmp
cchq sister what was her name that she
bought it from for a while
sister and then before that it was hemp
C but even hemp C had all sorts of
different
Creations it was like I've been around
since '96 or '95 but it kind of all
started and let me tell you there's been
a few
incarnations which is great props to
mark emry for keeping it alive don't get
me wrong it's just for me from my
perspective I'm at the point where um I
just I I I I appreciate the flowers even
only to
vaporize West Coast concentrate crew in
the house hello hello puff Wednesday
Wednesday right on I'm coming to sit
down I just got to all we're going to a
few more bulls and then we're going to
rec uh welcome the uh the West Coast
concentrate crew in the H we in the
builds Perfect all right guys we're back
with the West Coast concentrate to
partial crew we got Adam and Brett in
the house good to see you both what's
going on guys thanks for having us
Johnny absolutely yes you get to be on
our first puff Wednesday in a long time
he man it's excited it's nice you know
it was just it happened so naturally and
then it just sort of petered out as we
gained more interest in our own channels
and producing uh different shows and
whatnot but life got busy yeah people
have asked just everything just so busy
it's unreal you're crazy busy I'm crazy
busy busy always good man these guys are
crazy busy you guys are crazy busy just
making half you know what it's it's
because of this crazy country that's
awesome and so we have three different
perspectives here and I'll say three
different perspectives I'm a unique in
the sense that I have all three
perspectives uh but say I come from the
perspective of the idea of Consulting
for a licensed producer these guys are
uh producing hash on a dispensary level
Johnny B is a patient let's have a
discussion about Justin Trudeau and the
federal government and how that's going
to affect all three of those platforms
in the canas industry yeah I mean 100%
you know what I'm saying patient uh uh
local Grassroots dispensary industry and
of course large large scale uh license
production facilities for uh Canadian
citizens these are the three things that
of course I think I speak for all of us
when I say uh I welcome them all
definitely I'm going to say as a patient
that's exactly what I want to see I want
to see access I want to see access from
someone that I trust it's a local I like
I like to shop within 100 miles of my
house I support local economy so I want
to support my Farmer or my friends I
also want access to like that and I need
it can I go to a pharmacy and have
access granted in that way or some way
or a form where if I have the same
standardized over and over or do I
choose like I choose I grow my own I
make my own Med gr medicine it's won't
gain Med but you yourself know how much
time and energy that takes mean I'm I'm
I'm not working I mean all the other
patients out there in the country so you
you need to be able to have your own
license a patient perspective there's
John's perspective right there he
absolutely requires to be able to grow
his own but on the side note he loves
the idea of having it available both
through dispensaries as well as through
the LIC producers or no license or NOC
if every way growing you know time or
basil in your backyard you want to grow
it by all means I'm sure there's going
to be some kind of PL count or some kind
of Maximum that you're allowed to do but
it's kind of like everything what we
have now
people tomatoes in the backyard people
go tomatoes in the backyard and then we
can also buy them from King Market we
can get them from that big the big Vine
company where they have big warehouses
going going to have all different types
of platform but the best thing about it
is hey he said he's going to legalize
canvas in Canada and you know what and
and he's going to do that for the
recreational the
medicinal for for preventative
industrial exactly it's how it's How the
jobs be readily available for the
community how are they going to be
access and and then how are we going to
be able to be able to stay in this
industry that we all all love and are
passion it's an exciting time right
because there's so many people that I
mean I don't we sit what we do I mean
this right here know he's about the
passion and the love of a plan and I
mean that's what I see I see a lot of
good people in the room in the places
where they have but then there's a lot
of people that aren't in that for that
reason very true so I mean we're going
to see every end of it now that's for
sure but we say the shark used to be
circling they're there're they're in
there and you know what there's a big
money involved and well this is the
thing it's big money and that's my one
worry when when Adam says or maybe no
license in a perfect world yeah there
would be no licensing but you can tell
that the the profits that will be
produced will be on scale with the
smartphone Revolution yeah guaranteed
and there's no way that in some way
shape or form big business government
Grassroots business everyone's going to
want to get their
hands legalization one to2 billion yeah
they're saying it's a 5 to6 billion
industry if the LPS get in and Legalize
It um I'd really like to see patients
being able to grow their own I'd like to
see LPS being able to you know um sell
resin that's distracted I'd really like
I'd like I'm for all of it I want it to
all be a goal I want everybody to be
able to grow their own uh to extract
their own resin and if you don't want to
do that you can come to a store or an LP
and buy your extracted resin um but
that's the best part about it we as in
like myself as Mar where we get able to
go and no one can ever
access they can't access what we're
sitting here just doesn't exist in any
of the clubs like and I me and then in
the street there is just no absess of
this type of medication understand so
much you need the access so the access
is more BR and with the big LP is not
larger production maybe because people
are so with with the with you know the
yields we get from our extractions I use
full plant matter you crazy I put in
Fire get up fire I don't use Shake I
don't use I use everything you use your
medicine exactly as in as in for
commercial L they're going to use the
buds here they're going to use that
there so I mean where there going to be
a point where actually need get true
medicine and use the whole time it will
be everything because
see how it goes I like the idea
personally of being able to see the
positive effects of a cannabis industry
in like what Bruce Lipton said in the
CBC this morning I read a quote from him
uh saying that uh when we see the
airports that this tax builds and when
we see the bridges and the
infrastructure that will be the most
powerful thing that uh cannabis
legalization in Canada uh will show in
my opinion and just stop making
criminals at this yeah that's it that's
it that's it I don't feel like a
criminal you know I don't I never really
felt like a criminal I mean I because
you
said we're going to catch up with you
guys in a
bit all right so just bumped into Chris
Bennett here guys and uh I wanted to
just stop real quick on this puff
Wednesday we we got to have a puff up
there but we didn't film it um oh that's
cool hey yeah I when I got it I kind of
was like what is this weird plastic
grinder thing and then when I saw cuz
here's the thing about stores and Boll
this is the mighty vaporizer here these
guys kind of don't [ __ ] around when it
comes to uh like efficiency uh they're
they're German of course and uh I I was
like I saw the little plastic grinder I
thought I'm not really sure I'd ever use
this and then when I saw how it fit into
the unit I was like that's some smart
[ __ ] so as long as you don't open it
upside down which I've got the stone D I
did it the first time actually I'm not
going to lie so I wanted to ask you
quickly about your feelings in in
regards to uh Harper being gone and
Trudeau being in well you know I think
I'm so stoked to see Harper gone I
thought there was a possibility still
might hold in CU he has such a solid
base but uh pretty clear of that all the
new voters out there uh um picked up the
torch and got him out uh Trudeau you
know like I had been a pretty stun
Trudeau support up until he supported BC
51 and then it was hard for me to do it
you know um I think I you know I think
it would have been that it would a
little bit more NDP influenc I don't
think Justin's a bad guy I think he made
a mistake on c-51 got bad advice
pressure uh um you know that was a hard
call on the on the Canadian public you
know the reality is when you're a
politician at that level if you don't
make some uh personal compromises in
your world viiew then you're probably
not going to get to be prime minister of
this country right you know what I mean
uh um so you know I was disappointed in
the c-51 uh um talk and stuff like that
but I think he's you know I think he's a
decent human being I think you know seen
him in personally seemed like he had a
good vibe and uh you know spent a lot of
time here in BC and I think he's honest
about legalization I'm worried that
under the libs it might be a little bit
too corporate for most people you know
uh um and I would have liked to have
seen the NDP there for that to kind of
make sure of a more of a kind of smaller
business and stuff like that who knows
you know what I mean and he seemed to be
supportive of dispensaries he seemed and
he said the personal growing comments
when you know we compared to brewing
your own beer when he was talking about
medical marijuana and I'm hoping that
pulls through for uh things and you know
like if we have some sort of model poose
to what we have for liquor with uh um
restaurants and things like that having
some liquor licenses and uh craft beer
and uh um Cottage wine industry as well
as the big things then that would
probably you know keep most people
pretty happy I tell you what though
looking at Oregon when I was just down
there on the weekend in Portland
legalization just looks so fabulous you
know what I mean you see like Billboards
uh uh with you know gum cannabis bears
and opening of new dispensaries and uh
and then picking up newspapers the
Georgia Straight style newspapers and
more than half the advertising is all
cannabis related you got to think about
how this affects the economy overall you
know I'm not talking pizza sales it
always has affected the economy overall
people it was just in this sort of
underground that it was squeezing into
the economy in places that people
couldn't really see clearly and I think
now that
it's yeah now that it's lifted up out of
those sort of Shadows that we'll be able
to see that very thing I was talking
about it earlier when airports and uh
you know infrastructure and all these
things start actually getting produced
here in Canada from taxes that were paid
on Canada that's right that's right you
know and it's it's going to be a huge
boom you know what I mean Colorado's
already making a 100 million bucks you
know what I mean it's like the mighty is
such a good vaporizer yeah yeah end T
delicious I ended up putting my volcano
in the closet and now I'm just using the
m so much cleaner too what kind of
flavor you got there that's Renee es
almost has some berry berry flavor to it
HP hash plant 13 huh very nice very
nice anyway I just wanted to stop and uh
have a quick talk with Chris Bennett
we're going to continue on our way to
the next place for puff Wednesday
but let's do that bro never stop asking
please yeah Matt Matt fried his in the
rain a
that's all right so we've made it to a
nice little Park here in Vancouver I
guess what is this English Bay uh it is
yeah English Bay right here to the to
the side of us ocean uh Galore and we're
probably going to make our way a little
closer but we just figured we would stop
in a bunch of cool spots and uh have a
rip yeah this is basically the entrance
to Stanley Park we're right behind the
fish house if you've ever uh want to
come check out this restaurant who knows
we might check it out later ourselves
how about this my back and this walk and
I got a medic yeah you you take that rip
you got about 25 seconds I got a time
and we got I got the time we got the
nice little and you know what just so
you guys know yes I forgot something
it's all good we forgot the ofc but we
okay so I'm just like we're going to
make it work we're making it
work all right there it is that's
working right there
John a solid 30 second weight on the
dab the end of that's working all right
as a car oh there you go
how you doing lat come on Johnny B come
on walking through the
city you know what with this new
platform and and the new I I feel look
at me look at the smile it's like Canada
oh can
good all
right heading down here to the water
this is called second
Beach that's very
app how are you guys doing awesome
beautiful
day all right this has to be like the
smallest beach
ever I love it great little
spot we're about to have a nice little
session right here on this big tree
maybe this one over
here hey this is not a bad little puff
spot I like
it I like it a
lot yeah we we're just cheating by
living here go have a couple of seats up
there Fu there we go all right guys so
we are at second Beach here in Vancouver
sitting by all these these uh ships that
are just sitting in the port or waiting
to maybe gain access to the port you
guys know the area better than me yep
beautiful area yeah it's pretty sweet
this is where the fireworks happen I
know that much I don't know barge here
and uh yeah we're just figured we'd set
up a little session here on the beach
not sure if you guys can see but there
are a couple of cops on horses way in
the background on the beach and uh we're
hoping that they're going to just
continue along their way and uh come
right by us here so we'll be able to
maybe ask them a couple of questions on
how they see uh the Chang of the
government's affecting the policy that
Canada has uh on cannabis and cannabis
uh you know legalization versus the uh
the prohibition of it should be a good
question to ask them if they come around
yeah see what they think of Trudeau in
the meantime let's smoke ourselves silly
on a puff Wednesday well you know what
it's nothing like being able to come in
Vancouver on such a lovely day and with
the beautiful boat host in the
background I've eting there so much with
you dude dude it's a puff Wednesday I
know so
there now we're puffing over here on
that and soon we'll be puffing over
there Puffs everywhere Puffs everywhere
telling you straight up so yeah glad
John brought the ball rig out with the
torch and the uh the courtz Honey Bucket
very nice to be able to be out here and
just ripping dabs with the Amigos
cracking dabs off of that rosin no turs
added no chps added very stable might I
add no chps added beautiful extremely
stable
yeah they are now on the sidewalk and
I'd say they'll probably be here within
3 or 4 minutes so we may want to at one
point in time put the pipe away and just
kind of see if they want to uh do a
quick little interview when they come up
here one more Ripper for you all right
sure we let the I'll take a rip I'll
trade you you want I'll take a ripper ah
you know what just open the case and put
the rosin back inside the lid where I
had it I can do that that'd be awesome
timer here for you ah yes you got to be
careful with the timer too when you're
outside by the water and it's blowing a
nice wind uh you might not want to wait
the full 45 seconds that you're used to
waiting but wait uh a little bit less
cuz it does cool it down a little bit
faster out here for sure how we doing
for
proximity it's always quite nice to be
able to just sit back in and you know
talk more about what uh or about what
we're doing most definitely it's a it's
it's a great time you know we're we're
all really lucky to be where we are
right now and to be able to sit here and
really feel feel no no worries you know
it's a good feeling well let's see what
the police have to say woohoo Johnny got
off and roll that baby back off
Wednesday
[Applause]
well it looks like we didn't get to ask
the police our question they seem to be
in Hot Pursuit of
uh oh well next time I
guess they always go up my street always
oh I had no idea must just be
the get then I guess it's time for us to
find another spot to puff and that's
what we're doing now
dude yeah you're taking us to our next
puff spot I am Brett's leading the way
this is uh fall in
Vancouver spring is gone Summer is
gone winter is soon to
return and we are deep in the throws of
fall little squirrel dude have a little
friend what's up little
dude he's small yeah he was
all right so we have made it here to the
apartment overlooking Vancouver I guess
this is the West End West End you got uh
Stanley Park right in the back here nice
beautiful trees as far as the eye can
see you got another little bit of shot
of Stanley Park through here the little
Lake
there and then some beautiful fall
colors what's up Johnny B check this out
all right these fall
colors I was like he just pulled this
out and I was like you got to get in
those
this that's some that's some that's some
that's some Seven Star right there you
need to have two screens so those holes
are too big I can get you some screens
that are much
tighter take
them turps t
t sorry I had to all right where's the
Mother Ship it's
um say Johnny B
so your
Michael just coming up on
420 8
minutes make her an eight red at rip
there Johnny it's going to be a long
one I like to let it melt
quick little shaky shimmering
TS wow that tastes amazing
[Music]
all right so we just got to cardos uh
after a lot of puff Wednesday we like to
eat some delicious food so this is one
of the great places in downtown
Vancouver and uh we're going to take you
in right
now right in the marina
here really sweet
sweet what's up patio or oh I'm uh you
know what I'm good
wherever here we are at cardos
how we doing boys delicious I'm pretty
we just ordered up some goodness didn't
we getting some walk goodness Little
Bread Little Bread action little carbs
we got the Yachts
outside yeah this is going to be
good uh I guess that's the remnants of
our salad that's all we have left rest
in peace these guys still haven't eaten
can you
tell I'm hry hypoglycemic are you hry
angry get that camera out of my
face all right food has has arrived
gentlemen what do you got going on there
I got the harbor burger with some bacon
on it and all Johnny Be looks like he's
going healthy I am I'm little bit of
halet what do you got going on the
salmon cedar plank oh the cedar plank
too that looks fraking good you got the
steak I do and I got the salmon
burger the Sham on Burger so we are
going to eat and then we will puff puff
puff
Wednesday oh man I was just whistling it
hey what's up bud
so we we two now guys I'm thinking we
might get a bit of Sun at L I think so
got
H whatever we don't need no stinking Sun
I think the sun is gone gone
om you ready Johnny
B yo what's up guys we're oh careful
jeez don't get destroyed little SP you
going on hey go over here yeah follow
her we're going to go this way I never
been down here before ever well I have
been I just can't remember well here we
are now get I'm getting old it's puff
Wednesday and we're here we're always
trying I always say we have to do
something always unique and different
and one thing we don't do is walk along
the seaw wall right have we I don't
think we have I've is the first I've
done it on uh just with Chris Bennett on
his boosted boards but never actually
just hanging out there's the seven sails
like that look at the birds this is
sweet very nice down that little epic
spot right there that's correct that's a
nice
place not too shabby right
all
right the port of Vancouver
Lookout celebrating the Centennial of
Stanley Park nice little
spot a nice
270° under the seaw
wall gearing up Johnny B
I hear glass is that a Mothership you
have there I happen to have a mother
ship all right well sounds good this
sounds good do I have a Dabber I and you
know what I got this little dabbing tool
from somebody and I keep it in my right
here all the time I just like wait a
second Beautiful awesome stuff well the
in memory of violet RG your favorite
walk in all Seas from the to to the
point Bill 1994 1919 we're going in
memory of violet I'm going to Puff a
bowl for her right all right gentlemen
we've made it we finished cardos we did
some puffing at the apartment we did
some puffing by the ocean we did some
puffing in the park under the trees
puffed everywhere we did some puffing at
the vapor lounge and now we are at
Stanley Park we are very close to the
infamous um Lighthouse where a lot of
people come and pull up their cars and
have a puff while staring at Weston
North Vancouver what's up seagull got
you boy anyway we got the city in the
background seven sales the fluorescent
lights of Vancouver are starting to
light up the shaw Tower the Cactus Club
uh the uh newspaper uh what's that
Province The Province Province yeah
awesome we're here let's do this one big
dab each and we're going to call this a
puff Wednesday epic puff Wednesday and
then these guys are going to head down
to the cchq on Davey and they're going
to hold their West Coast concentrate uh
full melt Wednesdays West Coast
Wednesdays W West Coast Wednesdays
awesome you can check these guys out on
Instagram West Coast melts uh West Coast
connoisseur and you can follow the West
Coast Collective for any drops we're
making or new products coming out no e
on the end of collective though and
Johnny B is uh weedmas 420 and of course
I am BC bubbleman check us all out on
Instagram and in the meantime uh we're
just going to finish up these last few
dabs of the evening it's just a
wonderful beautiful evening kind of
ocean nice and calm helicopters and
planes leaving every 5 or 10 minutes oh
yeah sea uh the the sea fair going back
and forth It's good beautiful out here
at night yeah I kind of wish I was
coming to you guys' night right now man
me too every Wednesday man I'm going
nice you going to come hell yeah hell
yeah he's down for the free melt hits
you know what I came into town because
there was talk of hash I needed to get
out of the house well we have the hash
we have it done a puff Wednesday and
it's always a good reason and you know
what the reason was is is just because
for you guys
it's neat that these people running by
right now they're joggers they were
looking at us like what the hell are
they doing and I was looking at them
with the same look like what the hell T
dopamine so a whole different TC is
working a little harder is that heating
up it's actually heating there you go do
you need a dab on there I got it all
right got it all right the difference is
is is we talk about the bodyone teeth
you got to talk louder they won't hear
the body's own tee Runner high so when
you're running you got
grease did you get
one the D everybody out here dve on the
seaw wall who are running or puffing are
all doing the same thing you still got a
dab on there all
creating what was
it Ros rosin oh [ __ ] I wanted to hit
here I'll get this one to uh I'll SM it
yeah here you go Ros wrapped it bubble
the bubble
flag you just had a rip I miss on the
bubble
I see I'm the guy that gets to get the
fifth HP because I got to I got get wait
no water in the ball rig so it's just
it's just it's just like no water in the
ball rig
no we're surrounded by water we
surrounded by water I all right let's
finish it off we've got about 2 minutes
of video time I can see that my uh
battery is turned red now so just in in
case this does cut out yes Happy Puff
Wednesday yes Happy Puff Wednesday
Johnny what you doing I don't know of
you it was it
was still too hot awesome he hit that
hot nice that was uh that was a legit
hit it was so legit it was too
legit W maybe not too legit that's like
some 1990
[ __ ] no the two legistic quick but yeah
the dry pipe too such a nice piece I was
like I probably should have gone and put
a little salt water in but I think this
there was a weird like water not
suitable for swimming sign so I figured
if it's not suitable for for swimming
should put we probably shouldn't filter
things through our lungs I'm see all
those big tanker ships in major boort
absolutely it's Vancouver's right there
man definitely
no all right we got one more dab coming
oh is it you or Marcus uh he's having
I know I'm aware I'm paying attention
this your time thank you
sir so you avoid the 5 Seconds the no
water is way too hot it no water but are
you also heating it up to Red Yes W it's
hash was it red when you it's hash and
we're right now R you're you're
good you tell us well I see it's burning
nicely you can see that
nice I could just tell by looking how
white that was and the GL I guarantee
you know what it might have been a
little hot but because it's hash you
like to bur a little hotter when you
doing bubble then with r or with like
shatter you sure got to be careful
carving this bowl with this [ __ ]
carve I don't suggest you do that at
home anyway awesome guys that is a wrap
puff Wednesday hopefully we bring
another one to you guys very soon I can
already hear the bubble man theme music
going on in the background thanks for
watching Everybody right
[Music]
peace had to say highway on you see the
person on the side of the ship where the
opening is there's a person on the ramp
at the bottom in red
yeah let see the levels
and
cool definitely goes that whole bottom
where that
Lev look at that guy dude he's literally
climbing out of that ship right
now
trippy
very it's pretty cool it's like right at
of Mad Max kind like it's first of all
if you were on a boat you would even
feel a more humid humility a more humble
sort of like oh yeah that thing just
cruises by it's hu it's like 10 stories
tall
man that's
definitely in the least it's
trippy I just can't go quiet you know
what I mean yeah like especially cuz
think of this think of how close you are
to here where your bed is can you
imagine what that look like going that
thing is bigger than the building you
live in dude can you imagine what it
looked like one underneath the bridge
cuz br