hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome to Puff Wednesday I'm here
with Johnny B and we're here at the cchq
Vapor Lounge uh on the second floor
filming our episode of puff puff
Wednesday today yeah they just kind of
finished up with their um they've been
doing a lot of shows down here today
haven't they filming down here they uh
marijuana man just finished his uh uh
show I believe it was with what's her
name that does the show with him Kush
Queen Kush Queen Kush Queen how's that
for a m
so Johnny B and I are here we've got the
uh Red Beard perk and we've got the
mothership and uh we're just going to
you know share a few bowls with you guys
and share a few stories there you go all
right so why don't we start it off with
a couple of rips Bud okay here I got
some good hash of course you do you've
been making it eagerly lately I've seen
like I just cut down everything and put
it the freeo that's very citrusy right
there I know the conso is doing amazing
Jamaica looks like but um can't wait to
see the bar was down Johnny B's got all
the strains going in his garden I'm sure
you guys check it out at John H Bell uh
YouTube I think if you just search John
Bell you'll find his
channel yes I do have some videos up
there several we've uh doing some
testing and just having some fun and
fighting with pwy Milo and mes and
everything else and you know what it's
just things that happened with gardening
and oh the shitty things bugs are such a
bummer
how do we know is a huge bub it's
happening a lot quite a bit with a lot
of people out the season just our
humidity levels just jump through the
roof our summer temperatures have
dropped and we're starting to get that
sort of fall rainy weather starting to
come in so it is actually like the first
week of October so it is absolutely yeah
so yeah I guess we're going to have
another pass church Sunday this Sunday
you're going to uh show up this time and
make sure we can get you in the room and
not lose you I was there fully in spirit
fully in spirit I was um I was
actually in the
chat and as you can hear yeah we're just
in the Vapor Lounge right now so tons of
people are coming in it's going to start
getting busy in here soon so we'll
probably just share a few more bowls
with you and and finish up but uh yeah
what's next buddy be well you know what
you hit
one sounds good sounds
excellent to good stuff going
on you guys want to hit a dab with some
full melt
bubble sure we're going to invite a
couple of strangers over to uh hit some
bowls with
us come on over here they are come on
over guys come on over and girl we're
going to do this puff Wednesday we're
filming our YouTube channel Bubble man's
world puff Wednesday so pretty much
you're going to be viewed by thousands
I'm taking all right yeah you can fit on
the couch you can probably squeeze you
in on the side herey good here man
perfect there you go even on camera look
at
that all right Mothership ripping oh
what's this one so there's no oil in
this at all we only do bubble hash yeah
we're doing bubble has and dry sets
really okay but they dab and they melt
into a liquid okay I yeah it should be
good it's
intense where you guys from I'm from Cam
Loop I just moved down here help us
thank you very much oh right on cam
loops I using sublimator so all right
this one's a dil so the mother took poab
yeah you the sublimator so um you're on
hot TV you're on CNC you're on
everything else now you're on Bubble Man
Hice yourself I didn't I last time not
on Bubble she was on Bubble man's world
yeah she was hitting fl's uh got deppy
um um look what happen I just grabbed
thisa and I didn't even realize it was
stuck there can you imagine if I bu out
oh you did all over the table with the
other one just a little bit oh it's okay
we we'll smoke it that like the isn't
that nice want to finish that one off we
give you a fresh I just want to see
tast so Johnny Johnny grew that resin
and processed himself oh really really
it's really tasty I like it it's really
tasty of course I like I know tast is a
lot really really big thing I like taste
heck yeah taste is very very which one
should we give the next gentleman from C
this one here that would be the uh the
med that's the cush that's a really nice
cush you is that what you just tried no
I think you gave him
watermelon how was that I don't know
what that was what was it was it tasty
yeah but what was it it was this it was
it was the 90 Micron cush 90 Micron cush
weird no like a good weird it does it's
almost fuy yeah it's like fru FY it's
like a life food we need to get a car
cap happening on this see I said that so
no one has to comment in the comment
section you guys need a carb cap see I
said it he said it there you go I know
we need a carb cap carb cap we get there
I get it I already know I'm ahead of you
man YouTube comment I'm ahead of you
things are like
$4 what's car CR really we already had a
paper lounge and thought maybe
Johnny but they have suat they have
volcanoes do you guys have vs yeah you
guys can come check out the Vapor Lounge
downtown Vancouver right on Hastings
near cambi address West Hastings cambi
307 West Hastings 307 307 and it's a
pretty sweet spot couple of floors Vapor
Lounge inspired by I'll have you know my
original Vapor Lounge which I had on
Commercial Drive in the early 2000s
called the melting point oh it was in
2001 2 and three 2002 3 finish that
off we had the inhalation station of
vaporization that's what our bar was
called that's the most scientific name I
like it that was a good one it was a
very good name we had like six different
kinds of vaporizers on the table at the
bar and I'm I'm still too young to
remember that I'm only 22 that's cool
like like hearing all that was like oh
it was like 2001 damn someone's got to
be look at that cash just dripping down
the dripping it was Dripping it's just
like Oh I'm a Flo
that excellent well we managed to film a
little puff Wednesday John I'm pretty
stoked about that we weren't sure if we
were going to be able to give you guys
anything but here we are at cchq at the
vapor lounge and just poing bowls oh
yeah best thing to do also it is
Wednesday today but on Tuesdays we have
Jam night down here oh really the key in
the key of green yep jams in the key of
green apparently it's not because the
key is green the key for the jam door is
green I always thought thought Adam
chose it because it was the uh the herb
in the key of green you know appar it's
a good story too you'll have to ask Adam
you come you have
to that's a good idea maybe bubble man's
world will come down and interview Adam
and talk about that and maybe f a little
Kia green Jam night one night see what
happens all right thank you see you guys
yes right on you got to get back to work
back to work we're just kind of back to
work we're going to do another round I
think we're going to hit this one this
time this is more cured out this some
more cured out like about a year old
watermelon got that one you
have fully equipped with everything is
labeled differently like jod said she
goes oh you have like a rainbow there I
said yeah well that dripping again
you're dripping too well someone said
the other day you need to get a
container
that's not too bad these rubber ones
worry me though they have like compared
to the silicone ones feel this feel that
I have one that's called um yeah these I
have one that's called concentrate
that's silicone feel this oh my God conc
it's
rubber no I don't
think a
container and lid like one of those lip
containers kind of R through the lid and
the inside is oil slick resistant
but there's no corners like the corners
are rounded I actually just finished
building
my I got it all set up I don't even
smoke oil my hash is always just my
brother gave me like an old here I have
this for your birthday different way my
friend owns this company and I like to
support them and I kind of I don't think
people were putting hash in these before
I really sort of started putting full
milk in them
and it's for oil I'm like no it's for
everything man it's notop B Little P you
made them no like High
thing I don't know where I don't know
where he got that how do you like The
Hive Hive isn't that bad actually like I
like I'm more used to using like uh
Titan meals from just friends in general
that's had but like I don't know I
really like how it looks it's just like
when you uh drop sh just like at least
like a black scorcher when you obviously
didn't do it right so like if you like
tried to low temp it and you don't do it
right you'll know when you start [ __ ]
up when you just drip a little bit and
just go black and it's not like burning
it properly so it's just like you can
tell me to [ __ ] up I like cuz like with
I found with the titanium cuz like I'm
still really Nee dabbing and everything
right so like me too how long have you
been maybe a couple years I haven't
really been dabbing that long I've been
smoking but the weird thing with me is
in a sense I was dabbing without dabbing
I was like hitting full melt bubbl dry
sift for the last 12 to 15 years uh on a
super tight stainless steel screen like
Fanning it with a with a be line or
something it's just bubbling and melting
so basically I'm dabbing but it's like
it's not you know it's a little more
archaic okay I see this is
like oh I see I see but not even like
with a lighter I'd be more like even
even that Bowl's too dirty for me like
if you look at inside the bowl like
there's that's a lot of flavor stopper
i' keep a real clean Bowl have real
clean screens and just take like fresh
hit so it was literally like taking a
clean fresh hit just just people are
going to be like oh bubble man you're
such a snob or whatever but I'm just
it's just no it's true it's a true thing
flavor like I'm I'm more of like a
straight up like I'll take a balling
I'll take a dirty tote I'm one of those
guys could sit there and just do that
I've taken many yeah yeah you can did it
all through my 20 you always do it but
like sometimes you just want to sit
there and just have a really nice clean
tooke sometimes it's just really nice
yeah absolutely even this is too dirty
for me right now and I only am using
titanium cuz my whip for my quartz is
broken so I've got a new whip yeah I
rode over it with my chair and severed
the piece like an idiot so the good
people at Dil have have sent me a new
whip and I have multiple really nice
spooking bee quartz bowls at my house so
this won't see I'd like to get the
little drop down too I don't really like
the idea of putting the the ti nail
directly in even though it's it's fine
it works but we had our conversation
last time about the potential of
breakage and I know you took it and and
then the heat oh whatever it's all good
man but they were just talking I was
just downstairs and it should I should
get a drop down for this too and stuff
like that true it's true and it's if
we're going to be doing certain for this
would be nice right a little piece that
just went so this nail was right here
that would be pretty sweet cuz then it's
just the nervousness of putting it in a
in a in that Mothership
joint it's like definitely I was talking
to flab today and I was like what do you
think about the etiquette of like do you
know putting uh this into someone's
Mothership and he was like no no no you
can't do that he's like you can't you
just have to like you can't do that I
think I call you guys me I'm Mark that's
Mark I'm Kevin you too Kevin Lee right
John this job and this is the bubble
man's world
audience there about 20,000 of them out
there that could potentially be watching
and uh yeah if you guys want to come
down and chill out and bump into bump
into guys like these guys guys like us
I'm going to find you guys I really like
this yeah you'll find it bubble man's
world out Wednesday World Wednesday we
do lots of fun there of course I have my
own and it's just it's John hello or V
420 you'll find okay all right for sure
for sure and for sure you know the best
part is is uh we have fun we do yeah
Sunday Sunday we do hash Church on
bubble man so it's it's a live stream
wherever you're at you can just click
into that through Google Plus or YouTube
weekend that was really watch it yeah
made a little dry sift and talk to talk
to John and his neighbors and talk to
Horatio about making oil with delimine
the tpine instead of uh butan okay and
spoke with Darren about dry sifting and
I mean there was a whole bunch of great
people in the in the room the D lemon CS
no there you go man yeah actually wanted
these are the
lemon calves okay yeah that's 100 Mig
mixed into coconut oil that okay look at
that you take one or two of those a day
you take One A Day 100 a MIG how how was
two um well we've been taken one I've
been G one from no but the other day you
said you took two I took two I how was
that um it wasn't the lhl one that one
was the other one testing different t
Okay so oh those those were the sativa
CS yeah that's what you said the sativa
CS they were really good Mike took one
yesterday and he he said it got him
through the day very well excellent
serious are
the yeah John broke like every bone in
his body not really but pretty close
what happened I I tripped and fell 28 ft
and fell on the concrete and I hit my
head on the second floor broke my neck
broke on my teeth and threefold
unconscious and then broke the hip
shatter the arm broke the ankle you know
some pretty major injuries but you know
what um bounce back out here educating
talking about how C medicine why I'm
here talking with these
people and and and like we all are every
person that is consuming canas is using
from one way or another reg for a
medicinal reason right the M like I say
it's a mouse regulat
system it's the healing of the nation as
Richie says yes it's the healing of the
nation no so just different ways that
we're looking at exploring our medicine
this was something that he was just
mentioning about thetio and I was like
we talked about those Cs and of course I
wanted to bring them and show you guys
right so it was something I thought
about today because it's something that
the first caps and T caps were
definitely uplifting and uh of course
caps would be good fighting fighting any
kind of disease or condition um this is
the way to go um full plant profile this
is what I love about the Canabis culture
just everyone wants to just looking more
into it it's just like we always want to
support more and looking like to
different just different the
possibilities are endless one cannabis I
mean I said I'm wearing a hemp this is
everything I'm wearing everything yeah
of
course wear not not you today but I mean
yeah oh that was nice we should finish
it off with a round of the seven-year
cured I'm G for that so this is Master
cush that's that I've seven
years pretty sick it's actually I I can
see I remember when he first had it it
was a big slab like
this a couple years ago now that slab's
he's like yeah you
got
remember the rim to heat it up a bit and
we'll drop it in there takes a few
seconds because a lot of the Turpin over
time evaporate out at room temperature
so you get a kind of a slow melt almost
like a lava but then as it as it as it
accesses the oils inside that have been
preserved it starts start bubbling and
melting at that
more really a unique taste almost
perfumey on this s you'll like it yeah
you'll definitely like it I mean puffing
I mean have the pleasures of being able
to Puff a little bit it's
nice than good stuff absolutely but we'
like to
share don't you Noti that when you when
you light up a joint the first thing you
want to do is share it with somebody
it's a good
thing that's ofure everyone just wants
to share
there you go
man take a few seconds to
draw
so
excellent all right well one more rip
for Johnny on the seven-year cure and uh
we're going to call this puff Wednesday
a day thanks for joining us and uh if
you want to bump into us one day come
hang out down at the uh Vapor Lounge at
the cchq 307
West ttings West
tastings I thought you having some
troubles without without I loved it I
needed you your show was amazing I
required your help and there you were as
always Johnny B let me pack a bowl for
you all right guys thanks for watching
Bubble man's world we'll see you next
time