[Music]
hey what's up guys welcome to Bubble
man's world hanging out with Johnny B ER
fellow apparently they call me that and
uh we just got back from the Allard
trial we were watching Zach Walsh
actually a friend of mine that I grew up
with in Winnipeg testifying I guess he's
a PhD now or has a doctor or something
yeah he's done some uh he done some
studies uh like upward to like some
large number groups and and I was
Finding how the judge not the judge
sorry uh the crown was trying to [ __ ]
and he's not even Crown they're going to
call him the defendants he he was a dick
dude he really was a dick he was so
trying to discredit how can of was
therapeutic and that's why I said
Priceless Surprises I found he was
trying how how are you trying to say
that cannabis has no therapeutic value
and and this is what health Canada keeps
saying and over and the guy goes well we
got 600 people doing this we got these
studies doing that and he's like well
yeah but if we look at the numbers and
the percentages and you say well are you
accurate with this it was it was it was
the way he was trying to do things that
in my opinion it was
like oh it's right here well I feel the
same way dude I feel the exact same way
that it was just uh he was just trying
he was doing this passive aggressive
thing where he was trying desperately to
piss him off to to yeah get him to say
something get him to make a mistake to
get him to to say something that he that
he shouldn't be saying to to get him to
say a mistake and it just it just didn't
feel very I don't know I didn't like it
at
all why mention of it right now because
came across as a bit of a dick he was a
dick and it wasn't the the regular
prosecutor when not even see proest he's
a defense lawyer right now because we
have health Canada we have the federal
government on trial they the defendants
we are yeah the prosecutors we are the
prosecutors we're Prosecuting them so
they have to defend themselves so we're
going to CL need to be prosecuted the
government are the defendants here and
that is the best part about this court
case yep torch thank you thank you
brother yeah you know little bit and
thank you Alex in Germany I know you got
your screens buddy and I'm happy we're
puffing out of your bong here in British
Columbia yeah M I was just a little I
was nervous
you a got the carot C going on so right
now I'm in this lovely um Ren a car
because some idiot decided to drive by
my truck with a ladder and scrape the
whole side of it I'm getting a whole new
paint job so we're puffing the [ __ ] out
of this car puffing they said no smoke
they said I don't smoke no we're just
vaping yeah it's complely different
completely different so we got our hit
ready for you here I got to show you
look at the speedometer
280k awesome where in North America can
you do 280k I'll have this for you I was
going to say um between uh Mission and
uh I mean between Alis and CH yeah yeah
absolutely maybe even one one section of
the SE sky highway SE Sky uh right by uh
Furry Creek when it goes uphill and it's
a big straight straight straight Hill
you can get a car going 280 up there hey
I'm going to come visit tomorrow yeah
there you go I got the car Saturday give
a shot I just took a Tesla for a ride
this morning he that sounds like you had
a pretty awesome trip dude it was really
Choice really choice tell you guys a
little bit more dabbing full melt hash
that's the best part about it you guys
see it cleaned all the time I'll tell
you guys a little bit more about the uh
the Tesla another time I might even go
do another run and uh yeah just
interesting you know get away from gas
get away from oil I mean I know the
Tesla still has a fairly large carbon
footprint for all the batteries and
whatnot but hey forward motion guys
Forward Motion I got some hash here too
Johnny B if you want to maybe hold your
pipe cuz that's sketchy what I'm going
to do look at that I got this nice
little um thing right here I got the
torch right here a little bit better
yeah so I got all of D4 20K sift that he
gifted me I know it's insane it's going
to be a good PP one is it plus I have
Matt's Barb his warlock his CBD Renee I
have uh I just have a whole selection of
stuff don't leave home without your meds
I sit in court I had my my my meds right
beside me yeah I had mine you can you
can see me with my mighty vaporizer I
think I still have it in here I love
that people are being turned away for
having their medicine but people like me
and Mark who put it in containers that
were airtight and were smellproof had no
problem bringing their medicine in with
them and can go anywhere there we are
anywhere we want with it there's the
mighty right there if you want to pull
out a nugget I'll pack it for
you I I've um yeah this is ready go you
know what we're going to hit the hash
right now telling you if you want to hit
a [ __ ] awesome
vaporizer it really is pretty awesome I
happen to have some nugs on me guys
that's what I figured you would and I've
got the hash so I can load us up a
couple of dabs while you're hashing and
dabbing loading up a couple of mighties
it's a pleasant unit I haven't recharged
it I hid it uh all day yesterday I
started on the mountain before on the
mountain we hid it in the hot tub we
took it up to the mountain and we had it
in the bike park or sorry I keep calling
it The Bike Park that's how warm it is
up in Whistler right now up in the uh
snowboard and ski park you go I know you
don't smoke flowers but oh Vape some
with you this is smells great some cushy
cush this would be the
nyush had some a with me but I I didn't
I have these uh this thing has a
hilarious um it looks like a grinder and
it breaks in half and then you put the
bottom half and you screw it into here
and it makes this big circle and then
you can basically grind weed with your
grinder and dump it right into this
piece that it fits perfect and then the
center hole pulls out and all the weed
funnels into the middle I it was quite a
unique uh little thing although I didn't
use it and I'll tell you why I didn't
use it because I found the medtainer
just like this was
perfect I going to stay over here let me
help you out with that it works very
well on the original volcano too so I'd
like to see that it works very well with
the new Mighty and I'm definitely going
to be getting one um 100% I've already
saw it uh I was over at a pops of course
and they had just brought them in I was
you though um I hit the small one not
the big one not the mighty though
different had the other one the other
had an app hooked up to cell phone this
goes onto the cell phone you can click
that on there and look at how Qui look
at how quick that climbs but simple too
look at the battery too two bars out of
six and I used it all day yesterday in
the gondola on the hot tub in my truck
on the top of the mountain so you can
see it climbs nice and fast this is what
I had in uh in the case today in the
Allard
case and uh wasn't in the last
Courthouse you your Trippy Stick we just
passed that over to Johnny B I'm you
know my favorite number is 420 but it
set for 393 all right well I'm going to
load myself up a bowl here we got it
down got we got hash everywhere we're
just sitting in a lovely parking lot uh
over top of uh what's this what sent is
above us I don't have any idea man okay
I really don't I'm not sure you drove in
here yeah I just I'm just a passenger in
the car and I have to say when I'm a
passenger you said what eat here and I'm
like we can't park here so I backed up
and parked in here I pay very little
attention
to the my surroundings when I'm a
passenger it's good to just relax yeah
don't have to worry about it
all so we're we're actually seeing how
long it takes can you dab or can you hit
the the the the good old Mighty well
you're good to go you could start
hitting Vape hits right now it just
hasn't reached full temp I I'm going to
go right now you
can I'm going to go not far behind you
here
sucks to you hitting this dry that's the
one bummer we should have put some water
in it I'm sorry that's okay I I just
find when you carry a Dabber and hash
and medtainers and weed and a bong bag
and a bong and the nail and the
Dome all these different things it's
like thirsty might as well throw in a
bottle of bong
water maybe if I keep a bottle with just
bong water in it I won't drink water or
you could get yourself a bottle of water
that you could drink when you're thirsty
and you could get another bottle of
water for your bong when you need to
have
rips what do you say I'm saying it might
be just gave me a bong rip there it is
look at
this I told you it's a killer
unit I'm sold on it it's got a huge
straw gives Wicked rips tastes
superb
what nothing some D 420k nothing like a
really good puff down after you been
sitting in court I mean
wow and the best part about it is you
know what it's being tweeted live so at
least there is some kind of footage on
it yep I'm tweeting away saying my
little two bits of what I
feel oh cannabis culture too is the sort
of the big they the main media outlet
for cannabis that you can you can follow
their Twitter accounts follow their
uh Facebook and uh check them out on
their live website they're updating as
we
pop it's it's the that thing is just
killer I got such a good flavor from
that last rip on that thing I'm still
tasting it it's like
wow well it's sure a nice uh it's
perfect that they waited this long to
come out with the perfect unit it's a
nice addition to a hash session it's
giving you those big tasty hash
rips there's something to be
said for
vaporizing big tasty rips of herb while
you're doing that I'll tell you it's
almost like uh
a
full full cycle all the way around you
know the hash got me quite a ways around
but this little bit of herb resin which
is still just
hash I'm uh I'm of course hot air
extracting with the little Mighty unit
so little Mighty you guys can check them
out at uh stor and Bickle the volcano
good people that brought you the volcano
if you're in Canada or even if you're
not in Canada you can check out my buddy
Jonathan at uh the puff
wizard where's the puff
wizard I believe it's the puff wizard I
always foret wizard puff I always forget
the name I'm such a punch punch in
Wizard puff I think it's wizard puff.com
and he sells all sorts of cool
vaporizers and stuff so I'll put his
Link in the in the comment section of
this video I think we should load this
thing up and head on up and have
something to eat yeah I'm down for that
so we'll see you guys in a bit these all
right hey I just pumped into Horatio
what's going on we just had a nice lunch
that was very delicious and uh I heard
you were on the Adam dun show today it
was a good show check out the Adam dun
show uh from today if you want to hear
about tpin htio was in the group talking
and uh I guess now we're about to
Johnny's a little bit excited like a kid
in a candy store because uh well he why
look at me I'm running he is finally
getting his denail I ordered him up a
ninja and we're going to go pick it up
at the
at my office at Fresh so guess let's
jump into this car Johnny Johnny B's got
here check it out let's make our way
that's the 280 km car 8speed that you
can drive in North America all right
well I'm just happy to be be a part all
right we just got the fresh headies
we're going to go get Johnny via denail
what's up Angie
hey are you excited Johnny I got two
daers in my hand right two dabs we're
excited yes thank you thank
right in the office Good To Be Good to
Be what's up squish what's up what's
going
down how was Amsterdam awesome
excellent oh I'm excited to uh hear
about
it let's see what we got here for Johnny
B I pray this is his thing and this
isn't all
just what do we got here we
got I don't know hold that
okay hold that Johnny Be look
[Music]
holding take
this take
that I'm just taking it over
here let's get it into the open area
brother uhoh we're going to see it how's
it going good to see you welcome back
thanks
squish squish holds it down here at
Fresh headies she does not [ __ ] around
no look at all the machines got to have
some structure somewhere hell yeah I'm
excited for John to open this thing up
here I'll take that okay and I'll get
Horatio to open that htio ratio's in the
house we're not sure this is just I
think this is for a thing I ordered for
John if it's not then it's something for
me and it'll be a funny video cuz John
thinks it's for him I have no idea what
that
is y oh it's
yours it's yours
yay wow is this really happening is this
the moment we've been waiting for yep
you know that you know I've been waiting
for this uh we know how upset you've
been I basically just bought one like I
never got that denail back so it was
just like well let's just get Johnny one
you don't have to do that that's just
for okay let's see what we got here good
all right so he mentioned
these are for me and this one's for yes
you get one exactly no you do this one
he wanted to make sure I got which was a
silver one nice thank you Brian that's
so awesome and this is you buddy look at
this all built in ninja style you got
your Dabber Click Boom your power cable
which should also be right there it's
right next to you power cable and then
of course you have a place to put your
bong well you know what's really nice
about that might fit your little yellow
one yep I think it'll fit fit it I think
it'll fit it real nice real nice there I
think it got itself a home i' be waiting
to put look it matches and I mean it's
meant to be all right John there you go
buddy this is where John answers his
phone while we're filming it's a
classic it's just one of those things
you know it's just and it's dead deot
awesome well let's have a session with
this bad boy let's do toilet paper
toilet paper really
all right guys we made it to the freshh
Hy Warehouse here we've got uh bubble
Nows stacked up behind us hoodlum
jackets over here uh screens over here
and of course Johnny you got your new D
now so how's it going is this exciting
Johnny just opened this up obviously you
guys saw him open it up I want to plug
in knock yourself out Knock hey shut
just get it wared up here let him pick
this up off the ground
too he even match my D now go for it
ready still got a few more power buttons
ready yep step one now turn it
on there we go one now plug this Dabber
in now here's something cool about what
we got John here two things here
actually first things first is the new
deep dish Banger I believe Brian was one
of the guys that helped design this unit
it's got a little piece for holding the
uh holding the bar of the the heater
this goes in yeah right like that Dil
will be on the front see the words there
it goes and then you want to turn this
[Music]
on and then you'll also most likely have
to turn this on which will start giving
you your temperature increase so check
this out how this works is this wraps
along the bottom like this I'm going to
turn the other way around you want it
the other way around yeah no problem
just cuz I'm going to say that's going
to turn in and then boom and it just
sits like that and that's your deep dish
banger so that's exciting we got water
in the bong now this bong I'll tell you
a story about this bong this is number
one out of five Mike fro collaboration
with Martin bizel from rwer and he
actually signed it check it out signed
number one of five Martin androo 2003
and you're giving this to me too
noing out for things today now we got
you no no no no no I'm kidding no it's
going good so then the quartz Banger as
well fits on there on the deep dish
Banger the quartz carb cap check that
out boys nice fit that fits perfectly I
smell the beginning of it heating up too
which is yeah just cleaning off the
element and getting that out it's at
360° so far so climbing so quick how
nice is the Ninja nail you know what I
thought was really cool cuz I'm looking
at think this is really cool and I was
think it'd be cool if if it was on the
side here and goes well then that would
compromise a lot of things well that's
why they didn't do it yeah no it makes
sense but then but then I was like
pulling up this really oh so softly and
this ninja note for me and it came right
out came right out exactly I'm not going
to do it right now because I put this
back in here but this pulls right out
and it's this big yeah dude it's like
let's get some dabs ready here we go
htio is hooking me up with something
this up this is some mku Seven Star
Seven Star I haven't tried the Seven
Star yet guys I'm going to try the Seven
Star you smoked it no I I haven't seen
no I haven't seen John live resin what
do you mean
you must have
tried yeah but it wasn't the live sift
I've never I haven't seen you that's
what I thought he was saying no earlier
today he was no there is no live Sif out
there that dude should be showing up
with you getting warm you're 710 in it
710 load your when do I stop this thing
wow that is a pretty Co P stop you let
it you know what I think you'll get more
of the
dish that's what I was I just went to
put my fingers there and I was like how
do you yeah so you push it up and then
yeah you get more radiant heat well
that's it cuz it wasn't just quite going
up enough with the other
one can get it up a little bit more no I
guess it is supposed to go upside down I
guess that's enough
I I guess it radiant catches up yeah
okay there we go that's sitting a little
bit better always learning with the new
tools quite a few times when I got
different um New pieces from Dil I would
always even well for instance when I put
the sapphire insert on my titanium nail
and I it didn't go right in and mine sat
on top yeah well that became a tech that
people started using but Brian said you
just did it wrong and I said no I didn't
do it wrong I asked you to grind down
the middle part yeah so that it fit
flush with the edges and when you did it
got it got wider and this the insert
didn't fit anymore so it was just kind
of a funny little seven star dab on the
ninja through the rure give it a go let
me move all this out of your way so that
you're not worried about uh about your
uh about your line your whip this is
exciting Johnny you'll have to drop it
right in there look at that deep dish
isn't that nice now come on watching it
bubble and boil and melt like that was a
nice uh little addition wasn't it melt
video time for Johnny B
dude you just Banger Johnny B has like
one of two of the deep dish bangers that
are here in BC right now maybe there's a
few more it's hard to say move this
camera up a little bit
more how's
that well we're going to get that a
little bit of
a I remember I closed my eyes when I did
that because someone did a video said
close the eyes did you I got it I got it
in my eye in Jamaica that's why I just
that was a bummer see I I learned from
his video to close my eyes while blowing
inside when did you press that this is
already ready where did you come from
right there I pulled it out of here and
then I just pressed I was like where the
hell did you press that [ __ ] to have a
long yeah you didn't have a long one now
we need some parchment let's press you
up something real oh wow yeah look so
cool on the for SP Mir it's awesome you
didn't get anything WR Johnny let's just
put this all in one
I don't know if I'm going to be so lucky
with my finger press your finger press I
don't know if it's going to finger press
I doubt it it
should don't doubt nothing buy the
pressure feel I'm not a finger presser
typically I just change the Dabber to
bit the dab size I
want on over
there that's nice it cleans real nice
with the Dabber oh yeah you can clean
the residual that's that's on there you
can see the the dish is way below the
neck of the piece which I got to say I
like go I got one you want
this we have many dabas we have
da well that was super tasty and awesome
I have I don't think I've ever had hit a
Dil set up to a big RAR tube like that
this was the first color section that
Martin bizzel had ever pulled so he had
only blown clear glass before 2003 when
he did this pipe with Mike fro that's
cool pretty [ __ ] cool man that's
pretty cool I don't know why I keep
trying to load more and more more
because yours looked like a big slab of
freaking flesh and just lowering in the
Boom so go for it bet here let's go in
for a nice little uh yeah let's get
something on the little bit closer okay
so apparently her isio wants
to dab the [ __ ] out of me all right
that's not too bad you know Seven Star
let's do it barely held onto the nail
okay all right let's see what we got we
got the the deep dish
got to pull off that car he's falling
up hold in hold it
in hold it
in hold it take it smoke it clear it
there we
go something like doing a sesh I was
ready as soon as you inhaled I'm ready
to be like so what do you think about
that MK Ultra is it like the MKS you've
tried I only it's been a year since I've
seen it and now I can't even remember
what that original CBD
Renee do you want to have a hit of
that now this one isn't the Supreme like
liquid melter yeah but it has a amazing
head space that I think that you will
enjoy well I was already I mean I
haven't that I think I wanted to ask you
but then we were when we were together
just we were talking about it was me and
you talking about strains that are
really hard on the nail and I was soorry
not the nailed the screens and I was
like I wonder what that CBD um strains
are like cuz it's not a guarantee that
it's going to be heavy on the sticky
right but with you being you know
familiar with great Garder stuff
everything he does is going to be the
sticky version of The Strain when it
comes to the turp so sure is that uh one
of those ones that needs that Winter's
day or is it a reasonable um I never
really played around with this sift too
much but it was it was fairly reasonable
from what I from what I got to
play here we go John's in the background
coffin
awesome deep dish Banger rips I like
them I got to say
yeah that's a slow one eh when you have
a lower melt quality on your on your
sift or on your bubble hash for that
matter there's just a period of time
where you're kind of waiting for the
oils to heat up within and sort of press
out which brings me up to you know um
you see you hear these kids on Instagram
we're taking Buds and squishing them
between parchment paper now Rose and
Tech yeah well it's I guess it's a sort
of a rosin Tech really this this guy
called squishy buds I think was one of
the first people to do it and yeah he's
basically melting the resin off of off
of buds that that are then coming to the
surface and sticking to the parchment
and it's funny cuz they're getting dabs
off parchment just from squishing buds
well the bud if I saw it and I was like
well if we can do that in the grow room
if we could get wipes could in and just
keep that
up just if like if it takes three plants
to get a guy a personal everyday dab and
he just keeps wiping down the strain for
like 6 years I'm that's a double thumbs
up the D the dab plant but if it's like
I just got some fresh Buds and we're
just going to kill them and crush them
then I'm not but my thumbs are so up for
the Perpetual half gr Harvest per day
that would that would be a tech worth
worth saving worth wild yeah the
parchment way well I I talked to Matt
and I know that he knows uh compassion
the guy who uh originally did the
tech blow that all over our table and
onto our hash so I thought I would
invite him into hash church so I'm going
to get his email here in the next day or
two and I'll invite him into hash church
as well as squishy buds from Instagram
and we'll have a neat little discussion
on uh you know when he first started the
process which I remember it was
legitimately to milk non- melty resin
glands that were thicker wax membranes
uh and just melt those oils out of them
using this double boiler technique with
boiling water in a in a glass
bowl the thing is that's those texts
that really help extend your product
when it comes that's kind of why when I
first heard I'm like what they're doing
what to Bud good good bud crushing wet
but now you throw out the Perpetual
Harvest and it's back into the Forefront
as a great idea oh there it is thank you
thank you what do you want to get in on
all right what I want to get in on is
giving you guys a rip you're next I know
there's all these rip trades where
everyone's trying to get the next man
high on what they got what's going on
yeah but you know what mine mine is cool
because I often give people other
people's hash I'm not so hung up on
getting everyone to try my own cuz I
know it's pretty killer but this is d420
K's orangey diesel just a it'll be the
best flavor of hash that we could smoke
during this session I thought we might
as well throw might as well throw it
in there we
go it's pretty nice the way that uh
heats up the the quartz and just gets
that whole dish nice and really
hot of a interesting Vapor style rip to
it than uh you can basically throw like
two gram of hash in there and just let
it smold bubble away like crazy and have
like 10 people just keep hitting it I
mean that's better than where I was
saying be best in the how many dabs you
can do you can throw two gs of melty
hash in there a gr probably and you can
just line people up yeah like you might
even eventually suck clear domes right
into the neck see that's that would be
the most up and that rip that's like
going so good and all of a sudden you
feel that moment where it
clogs well this is the first of many
sessions I'm sure that we'll be doing on
Johnny's
denail so we're just going to keep at it
here guys and uh we'll catch up with you
guys in a bit back to
back hey welcome back guys we are now
back at my house in my office and uh
while we were at Fresh headies well we
came across something didn't we yeah we
came across this Beast that you see
before us here this is the ham gravity
bong from I'd say 2002 2003 2004
somewhere around that time ham came up
with this design came to the Cannabis
Cup and it was actually the first
Cannabis Cup that anyone knocked out
almost as many people as we did he was
knocking people out left right and
Center there's actually a guy that
passed out at Ham's table I'll never
forget it he hit it and then he passed
out kind of on Ham's table but then
rolled over to the guy next to Ham's
table and that guy just had a ton of
Glass on his table and the dude passed
out and rolled over his glass probably
broke like three or four pieces in an
instance it was
this thing is no [ __ ] joke now I was
trying desperately to set it up I'm
going me just see there might be one
piece one last chance this is my last
chance right here if we can find this
little piece that I may or may not have
and this is um an adapter that I'm
looking for right now uh this adapter it
turns I think it goes
for an 18 to a 14 but I'm not going to
end up finding it guaranteed it's I mean
I'm a pig I don't know my office is
terrible in my every drawer every drawer
is just full of hash and glass and then
more hash and apparently that piece is
gone I remember having it for a long
time unless it got put into this
top
top this one has a lot of different
things there are all sorts of good
things in here I think one day I can do
a video on what's in your drawer all
right so what this is actually this is a
this is a 14 to 18 so it's the opposite
of what we need if this was 18 and this
was 14 we'd be in business we're going
to get one of these for next time
because we want to be the first to set
up the electric nail and the gravity
bomb however that's not going to stop us
from lighting up a piece of beine or
getting getting a maybe a torch lighter
do you have your torch lighter up here
Johnny Be I a torch you have a torch I
have a torch you have a torch all right
so got for some reason I I came up here
Bowl right here with nothing but I
brought my torch all right the only
thing I'm going to require is a
screen all right so yeah let's give this
thing a shot we got the screen here in
the top of the bowl this is a huge drop
down on this bowl not a drop down but
the uh you know the m
piece it's bigger than what you normally
see on a bowl that's for sure well most
of them are both that big yeah exactly
so you can see so you can see it's
double size monster that's your so let's
go for Uber tasty Uber Uber tasty Diesel
and big you know we're going to go for
much bigger of a rip than normally whoa
whoa who
really yeah
you maybe
okay
so yeah we got that in there loaded up
with some New York City Diesel from d420
K and I guess we're going to need a
little bit of beline which is always
close by we got the
torch I like the idea of having the
torch nearby you know what let's do the
torch just because um it'll ensure that
the full the full rip I'll take the
first RIP just to show you how it works
okay and to give you an idea
um monster rip I'm scared like what was
that five times what we normally hit
yeah in
a crazy strong super smooth
I just said he just like took that like
a
CH okay all right so I'm going to help
you out
smaller no the whole point is showing
you how big of a hit you can take and
how clean it is and how awesome it is
huge this is
definitely oh you put more in there
right yeah like up yeah brother
apparently um this is my first um ever
ham gravity bong RI Gravity Bone rip
someone was like no I saw you do one
before anytime you're ready buddy you
can just drop
it
perfect pretty good pretty
good you get pretty good eventually you
won't even have to put your lips on the
thing first time most people do it but
how's that I was scared to drop it like
how you did cuz I'm not used to it yeah
to be honest as do it often you start of
start getting this you kind of got it at
a bit of an angle and you can we've got
it really full of water for a super
awesome rip so I don't know I think I'm
going to take one
more I think I'm going to take one more
dude let's see what else we can try
maybe some CBD Renee from the great
Gardener
wow it's just like it's
a yeah remember you can't do that John
yeah that's why it's just stop so one
here's here's the thing about a gravity
bong it's not a good idea just to go up
and down with it cuz eventually what
you'll do is you'll break it or with
this particular unit it can't go down
with the bowl on there's a tiny little
hole can you see it right through there
yep so that little hole allows for when
you push down for the release of the air
and for it to push the smoke up like
that but if the Bowl's on it that hole
is plugged and of course the only place
for the water to come is up through the
stem and out the top of the the bowl so
I've definitely seen it done would have
that P is now hitting me isn't that
unbelievable though wow dude we just
took like I was actually like cuz I was
telling work I wanted to get out of here
I not you know my back was killing me um
that is the best medical
device just saying I mean this is what I
do I medicate and I just got
medicated I want to bring this to the
courtroom and say hey judge this what I
do this is how you do it this how you do
it this is this is 8 G of weed done in
one
hit I do three of these a day that's my
24 G boom boo yeah so good you want one
more brother yeah I'm going to have to
all right what's the CBD Renee get your
CBD levels
up
whoa It's the thing right away that you
you understand too it's a different ball
game when you're playing with the handam
gravity bomb that's not like a different
oh man so I'm just like I'm staying the
nights
tonight what happens after you have
meetings I'm going to help you out with
this one all right here I'll lower it
for you over
here and ideally just put your lips
above it but not right on
it and then you it'll it comes out with
quite a
force oh does it
ever that's a huge hit you guys have no
like you guys watch us we always do bong
rips we're always hitting it on a dil
stuff like that that was like a crack it
out of the park the old days we used to
call them out hits um that was twice the
size yeah ham thank you ham check out
ham Waterworks and uh thanks for
watching Bubble man's world guys we had
a good time today uh we'll talk again
soon we'll see you guys again soon hey
was P Wednesday today we didn't even
know the
Wednesday have a good one guys
[Music]