[Music]
all
right well welcome back to Bubble man's
world uh John B in the house as always
he's pretty much moved in
downstairs
stand I'm home now and Morgan who hasn't
been with us since the great dry sifting
with the mailman brother yeah over on
the other end of the house by the peruga
we also have the Astro Boy the
watermelon uh from uh TGA and bad boys
breeding back in the day and we also
have higher end in the house off camera
but he has brought this absolutely
incredible Mothership and you want to
give us a quick Lowdown on what that is
just off cam crushed opal ball exosphere
crushed opal ball
exosphere it is definitely completely
once again I don't think I've been this
blown away since you brought over the
Marcel Fab egg this also has that level
of just epic quality and what are we
puffing out of it today John fresh
frozen fresh frozen of this watermelon
has turned out absolutely beautiful like
for whatever reason it's it it has
definitely opened my eyes back up to
after seeing so many strains just not
produce melty resin the watermelon the
astroboy and and a lot of TGA strains
are definitely full melt certified I'll
be uh this is
um well the best that I've seen yeah
it's definitely like a 9 point something
you know on the on the level of of
bubble has have you hit it yet Morgan I
have actually you think of that tasty
yeah and strong
we should definitely do it again we
should do it again well we're going to
do it again we're going to uh we're
going to hit this mother ship and I
guess really the only thing I need to do
we got our yeah we're rocking on the Dil
so that's good this is a little trick I
learned back in the days of
old on well you know what staring at you
have to see how these Opals are
suspended in this glass it's it's really
it's I've taken some photos and I'll
will insert them into the video amazing
so while you're staring at those he
didn't really be able to see what was
there and with the sun reflection right
he's been hitting bows already off
camera before we started this uh you
know what I haven't actually hit that
many you guys are definitely up on me so
I'm going to start this session by
moving this guy a little bit closer
we'll keep him on the uh on the pad and
what do we got 90 and 73 or 120 73 yeah
90 well maybe we better start with a
73 just a little one just well that's
all you need with this really I mean uh
well as you can see it's just
like he got a little bit of wind there
he lost about would you say one third
Morgan yeah yeah he's
nodding yeah so he's just got the big
but that's here go John why don't you
have a bowl give it a
shot give it a shot of that 3 it was
tasty delicious the pipe is actually uh
this is a pipe that would suck a lighter
out for sure or a beeline the amount of
chubble that it has is definitely
uh pretty darn
incredible mother ship just constantly
knocking it out of the park this purple
is that
uh it's unbelievable look at the even
the stacking of the bubbles is so nice
coming out of the disc perk that's a
flower life disc
perk
wow very
nice very very very nice can drive one
home for Morgan need oh it's just such
beautiful resin I used to like do a
little bit of glass length nothing like
this nothing like this it's very cool
that uh that not only did you breed this
strain but but you also brought this
glass so thank you thank you look at how
that just you can see how that clear
Dome so perfectly on there just gorgeous
like wow Lord have
mercy yeah and depending on how the Sun
catches the Opals just at this angle
when I pulled back every opal in here
went red really I I leaned over a tiny
little bit and now they're all green
you know you move another little angle
and you see more Blues but like yeah
right over here at this angle from the
Sun coming down
red I'm seen nice Blues just amazing
colors on this one here I'm amazed at
the level of perfection that they've
acquired from the distance of glass that
is encased around the opal is almost
they're all just perfect it's that's
what I was memor and
33 Opals 33 separate Opals in case all
around the piece there's another one
here there's another one right on the
bottom below the disc per didn't get to
see that I had missed that one as well
when I was doing the photography that's
pretty cool that it looks tiny in there
but it's probably all the same size mhm
and this one's really beautiful as well
that's like half in there gorgeous a
little egg on both sides e like it's it
looks like half but it's on both sides
even gorgeous in I'm going to hit it
again and try not to miss a
third well here I'm going to leave all
right all right here you go 120 in the
I'll do my wa we got yours saved right
here is it the 120 or the 90 that's the
that oh that's the 90 sorry oh wow now
I'm excited look at
that perfect
execution oh
yeah what do you
think are you doing okay over there oh
yeah yeah Morgan's loveing life yeah he
sure man that's
tasty that is absolutely there's
something about hitting some of the
nicest resin out of some of the nicest
glass and you know everyone always
thinks they have the nicest and when I
say it's the nicest I don't mean it's
the nicest because we have
it it's just literally some of the
nicest resin I've seen long time that's
next that's the that's your next one
that's beautiful Con in the house we got
the congales
120 micron
with a real nice orangey reddish color
to it pass Super lemony sativa smell
thank you kind
sir there you
go
perfect the congal
73 man these are just all beautiful
we'll definitely give you some camera
close-ups on these as well as some macro
photographs and then that congal 90
Micron really nice ni
bubble higher end the name does not
deceive it is not a
misnomer he's higher end higher end
glass higher end
hash wow and really you guys do that how
do you do what I I used to be able to
like CH like that but
that's well we're using it more for
medicinal purposes than the uh the
standard just getting ripped purposes
it's true anyway we're going to continue
to Puff on this incredible piece that
highend brought by uh check out high
integrity glass art on Facebook and uh
yeah they definitely have some of the
most
unique uh Mothership glass here in
British Columbia and uh keep watching
Bubble man's world peace peace
guys just Congo
Congo Congo
we we always try to leave but you know
sometimes it never
happens well see what
happens it's the editing I'll just I'll
now I'll add this part in front of the
end and it can be like the uh the the
speed fast forward like Mouse
[Music]
voices sometimes it is okay wait a
second here we should have done
this
we were just talking about oh that's
nice not doing these big rips and the
way that last one came
down didn't look like it was that
big that's all
I tell you that's all I
need was a
ripper love the congales love that
lemony land race exotic
flavor it's
a it's a strain that has been held quite
closely here in British Columbia but
we're get we're happy to to to be uh
acquiring it and to sharing it with the
people that that deserve it I mean it's
a cannabis Trin right these things
generally are to get out to the
world and share that's what I love about
how the Watermelons worked oh this is
tasty I mean how many years ago did you
breathe
that wow oh
706 7 eight years
ago and here we are sitting with
it growing
legally it's really great puffing killer
how is thato that's comos well I just
done like two in a row going for three
not that one little dab hey no doubt I
took a lot in that
other I actually took the first one and
then that one dropped onto the element
so I like picked it
up it was a little abusive of me are you
ready for one Morgan he's ready I think
one more yeah one more and we'll kill
you should we I was going to say
ninja that sounds like
fun we going to do some public
presenting tonight oh
nice you know what I there's no reason
there's no reason for um anyone to think
that cannabis would uh limit your
abilities to do those things at
all
Mainer if you're going to knock over
anything on the
table the empty plastic container is a
great place to start but not just anyone
this is the coalition 10 yes I saw that
exactly kind of a a special one it's a
symbol of what we fight for
absolutely very cool very cool that's am
watching it oh yeah oh he got the ninja
I oh you hit him with the 73 watermelon
I just did a little touch water Lees or
Congo melon Congo melon the water leaves
did you own cross yeah go just made up a
new strain just made up a new strain
yeah well that was really enjoyable
we'll probably continue to sit here and
go through all the different microns of
all the different hashes but uh I really
want to try this seven this is Puff
Wednesday and it's it is Puff Wednesday
yeah yeah it's just we' got our
watermelon hanging out with us
here blooming in the beautiful
day we'll see you next time yes we will
we'll see you next time
peace
[Music]
guys