[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
welcome Johnny B in the house actually
I'm in his house right now thanks for
having me dude well you know why you
don't get on to this end The Woods Too
Much actually I'm telling you a long way
it's been a while since I've been here
and it's definitely been a while since
we filmed together I thought our
audience deserved a puff Wednesday we've
been so busy we've been busy you've been
busy I've been bus concentrating on
certain things you know what uh life we
talk every day yeah we do every single
day lots of uh lots of things going on
in the world of Johnny B and bubble man
if you guys follow hash Church you know
a little bit about uh our company in
Jamaica cannaboid research and
development uh of course myself and John
have our own company's here he's
maintaining medtainer Canada and I'm
maintaining fresh headies as well as FH
filtration and you know we figured we
had to make time for a puff Wednesday
I'm out this way on a bit of an
adventure John said he'd join along and
uh we're going to head out to Hope Hope
BC and hopefully have a nice little
session out that way we've got some
pretty epic Beauty between abbottford
and hope so I think we should be able to
stop by a river you know the area pretty
well we got we got we got we got Bridal
fall there's a few cool places actually
let's try and stop at them yeah no it
definitely be a fun little Adventure but
uh that barber button I'm in John's made
some beautiful dry sift here of Matt the
great Gardener's Barbara bud and it is a
contender this is the LED Barber Bud too
oh nice is that the dry sift that's the
dry sift very nice that was my whole
little thing and I was you know now you
can you can try the difference between
that one
and very cool very cool well here's one
for you buddy you start start us off I
just use that empty one as a carb
cap good idea yeah it works real good
seals right on
there that's nice too really
nice lovely going to have a nice little
Adventure today I'm not sure where or
how it's going to go but uh I'm pretty
stoked on it we've actually got a pizza
it's just about to come out of the oven
here right away probably it's yeah it's
pretty much
it's flashing yeah so that'll be good
we're going to uh M that down on our way
to Hope oh that looks so good so
good oh SM that smells them yeah you
know what nothing like oh I first thing
I'm looking at and you notice how that's
the first thing that you did is you
protected myk yeah I understand I know
it was like I didn't think you were
going to bang it but I figured just in
case my hand would be there I've got the
flower matate as well as the mighty
vaporizer as well that we're going to
bring with us on our journey John's got
some beautiful Jamaican from uh The
Strain that I gave
him uh jeez V last last May it's been
about a year maybe a few months after I
cracked this this was the first plant
that I found it looks super dank and
beautiful real nice lime green color a
very almost odd smell and taste I can't
I don't even know how to describe it I
need to get back to know it it was
almost minty when you opened that
oh very nice we've already squeezed a
little bit through uh and made some
rosin and we've hit that already but uh
I have not hit this Barb so why don't I
do that you hit Barb no I just mean now
we we filmed this once already and the
mic wasn't working so now this is our
second attempt at it it's a little bit
different than it was the first time you
guys will never know what we said the
first time because we we won't even know
I don't know lip readers might know you
know what so you can do little cut no
I'm
Kidd oh here's some other hash I wanted
to press this out too so so what's been
happening is pressing out Tash is what's
going on um pressing I was thinking
about pressing pressing this is some
really nice 45 smell this I was think
about maybe pressing that for us to try
that that's I got so much of it I got
like that's the stuff that presses the
best for me I'm telling you so I'm more
getting into pressing the cash now cuz
for me all I've been pressing is Bud as
you can see um well it'll be a good idea
actually let's press some of that
because I forgot to mention um uh the
gentleman I can't remember his name now
his name is dank Supply Company at least
one of his companies he's got this cool
kind of logo on the T here he sent me a
couple of these Tes sent me a cool
t-shirt as well I'm I'll wear it one day
and and and mention him but he sent me
some of these sarama pens which are
similar to a Trippy Stick at least by
appearance in to the The Minis and uh he
just wanted us to try them out so I
wanted to give you one you can give it
your honest opinion that's so
unexpectedly cool it's like yeah we'll
let you know uh I mean aside from 5
minutes ago when I gave it to you and
then I know and I was surprised then I
was going to say it's my birthday but
you know what like I'm I'm just you know
I'm I'm surprised like I was like it's
cool right like yeah it's nice to get
the gift you know I love to destroy pens
I mean see whats I'm really hard on them
too I have to admit I still have found
trippy and Apex to be the ones that I
usually roll around with but uh um I
tried boss boss uh recently it worked
pretty good until I broke the globe I
saw you had a broken Globe over there as
well several I've broken the the glass
on most of the unit so I'm not calling
out any one company they're all you know
doing their best and it's really all
about doing research uh there's so many
different pens I personally don't think
of a pen as something that I want to use
every day but in my life when I'm not
around this and then I'm out and about
and maybe the torch just ran out at that
point it becomes a great option or if
I'm in a concert or concerts that's what
has been the key player lately I'm
meeting maybe meetings were good too
Safeway Lup you know Safeway lineup
movie theater depending in the movie
theater um these are all good options
for the pen so uh we give you thanks
pench and we will be honest so stay
tuned for that and what do you think
let's go eat this pizza and head to Hope
I think that's a great idea all right
cool let's do it actually after a rip
you showed me this dry sift this was the
combo yes no h H what's that um that
would be the
HPS uh Barbara and that would be the LED
Barbara that one way pressed up this
here is the
Congo yeah this is
Congo your LED is way way stronger of a
smell I know that's what I say it's it's
got so much that's what I was but there
is but there is way more of it too h no
but it was like that when I I even got
more resin from the LED it was was quite
surprised I got like 2.4 G uh of uh LED
uh sift and uh like static clean and I
got 1.1 of the HPS and I found uh it was
a real learning experience to be honest
um I I I spent six months on that
project and uh I I learned uh that um
like the medic Kush with the Daner buns
didn't give me the yield that I was
getting in the resin as in when I have
the two different there uh I get more
rosin from the HPS with the kushes but I
get more resin with the um like the
Barbara with the Congo with the My
Little Pony but so always best to have
them both so so it's really it's it's
it's really dis playing it's I'm just
seeing right now the variety of Lights
maybe and not choose one over the other
I just tested six plants the light to
see if it worked yeah that was the first
test and uh so you know what it's
working so um now it's uh dialing it in
and learning more about it so uh I'm
sure they're changing new bulbs already
and they come up with different this and
that and yeah I see Brad Higgins always
posting unique things about bulbs oh
yeah watt bulbs and stuff like e yeah he
got some cool stuff definitely well
we're going to head off on this
adventure we'll bring you guys with us
so get ready I'm doing a rip
guys this the
view we got the
river the bubble
man so we're heading up to a waterfall
yeah very good we were a little bit
worried we didn't have have a torch this
is the endless problem with dnails not
having an inverter to run the power of
the denail or not having a torch to heat
up your nail we've got the denail no
inverter we've got the the dabs no torch
so luckily I remembered that I had
grabbed the mighty and the flower mate
so we've each got our own vaporizer
John's got some beautiful herb and we're
still going to head up here I don't know
why we feel so compelled to have to Puff
for these videos but I guess it is a big
part of the videos the puffing aspect of
it so we are going to have our Puffs and
we're going to head up there so yeah
join us it's going to be a
[Music]
h
w oh
[Music]
a
there are no boats around I think you're
very accurate
[Music]
Yep this is beautiful got a beach over
at the far
end nothing like see living right I mean
really dude I kind of wish we had two
100s in the back like that girl had two
I would be so much and we just be like
let's just
the little kids that we are hey hey look
at look at them like big smile beautiful
this is nice dude this is nice we could
uh maybe set up a little session over on
this
log all right
well got uh trusty old uh little Rosen
n yeah
buddy yes I just picked up this dirt
bike for my son and my daughter I
suppose that's what John and I were just
talking about it's kind of Hardcore to
have a little bike like this Trails
literally right over
here Silver Lake angling regulations
release all fish bait bands single
Barbie's hook all
right all
right
well we're going to set ourselves up
here and we'll see you guys uh in a few
seconds
hey guys all right we found ourselves a
nice little Lake here Silver Lake and uh
we looked everywhere for a torch we
looked everywhere for a inverter to
power the dils that are in the truck
over there we didn't find one he even
stopped by my dad's house we did we even
stopped by John's dad house he
apparently brought the torch and the
inverter to Uma umaa Yuma apparently of
all the things I don't even know where
the hell that is but sounds like it's
hours away so we decided with the flower
mate and the mighty so these two little
Dodgers are going to be our sessions do
you have a preference here Johnny B um
you know what closest one to me yeah
whatever you like um which was kind of
funny is as I was running out the door I
grabbed a medtainer that had butd in it
perfect cuz that's exactly what we need
right now a medtainer full of Bud
so good on you oh do you want to just
squeeze it up and break break it up in
your medtainer style you know what I
guess we're just going to grind it get
us some pow pow get us some pow pow man
beautiful mountain Mountain back here on
the back side like that is some epicness
for
certain think P right into the mighty
there too won't it yep there's actually
a piece that they that it comes with a
little sort of plastic grinder piece
that screws into it and then it's got
the grinder that fits on top of it and
you just grind it right into the unit
but uh I just always used the medtainer
and just kind of done this going to like
okay that one just goes oh that's I like
this look at
that yeah I can tell you how that works
too yeah yep so you got uh I've never
tried these before so it's pretty
cool your herb will go in there okay
you'll just screw that on top of it
you'll hit this three times it'll turn
on and then I think you hit it a couple
more times each time you want to raise
the temperature of 5 or 10° okay so to
to raise the temperature and yeah that's
hey you know that's can we can we stop
stuff on there t no no the one thing fit
in else you got in there so I just
turned the mighty on pretty simple push
the side button the digital display
turns on uh it's in both Celsius or
sorry it's in the the the temperature
that you want is in the bottom and then
the temperature that it's at is on the
top so you can see it going from 63
upwards to climb towards 203 so got this
one on celsi so this one's a quick three
clicks yeah let me just make sure one
two
three 1 two 3 4 five it was five so
there it's
blinking so I believe it blinks
until it gets up to temperature okay and
then um once it gets up to temperature
you can hit it a few more times uh and
you'll change like it goes It goes from
Blue it goes from uh blue uh to red or
to Orange to Red so you're knocking over
your buds there or what that's what
happens when you don't put the the the
lid yes back on I guess the lid won't go
on without this piece on that would be
nice if it had the Dual lid properties
though three part system did you have
butt in here already uh yeah I put some
in there oh okay great so perfect that's
going to go like that and one two
three all right there's yours good nice
mine is just getting up to 200°
now so mine's good to go
right should be getting there
yeah oh yeah
right
away nice nice flavor I like
this I like them both that one was a
little more confusing for me cuz it took
me a while to realize I could tap it a
few more times and get the temperature
up but this one's just really easy cuz
it tells you literally you're at 199
you're at 200°
C it's kind of nice sitting here doing a
nice V way pin on the lake beautiful
view it's nice out it really is I mean
I'm definitely uh I've never been to
this Lake before so this is actually a
first for me coming to this particular
Lake little bit more of Johnny's
neighborhood than myself so uh he
pointed it out and said we should make
it up here you know what when we drive
out we'll uh take a look at that little
waterfall that we talking about that
sounds great I'm sure you guys want to
check it out there are so many endless
places in British Columbia just like
this literally any River any Lake
any sign that you see to a waterfall or
is generally going to be of of of epic
epic Beauty you know not just uh not
just your average but really beautiful
oh yeah there's tons of nuggets down
there I know I there Lots I like how
they they sit right in nice on the Moss
though don't they and what's really nice
is because these are all Little Rock
Hard little nugs that I was getting
ready for rosining yep I don't say Rosen
anymore I say rosin oh you're on the
rosin yeah
nice getting them ready diing these
little nice little nice
flavor you know I think next time we
should come up here we should go for
swim that'd be nice a little bit cool
today it'll definitely be um in the
summer we're close we're getting really
close to the summer right now that's for
sure it's uh mid Midway through May
camping ready to start camping will
start for a lot of people that already
has started still cools off a little bit
at night and some of the mountains still
have snow on them not these particular
ones but there is one right in behind us
over here that's covered in snow so it
just depends on how high up you go you
can usually find it even in
August it's nice to get away you buddy
cheers brother yeah oh we have to go eat
some lunch after this or something got
to get the uh
got the got to get the boat too I don't
know if that's going to happen today but
these are all the things you got to do
in summertime when BC and the weather
changes so beautifully it's time to get
the toys out time to ensure motorcycles
and get the Argo ready I got my pie get
the Argo out yeah get it all fixed
up you get just see in the mountains how
things have broken away and you see how
it just
reallyy nature is yeah it is for sure I
know you guys can see it in the
background too can see how the big
chunks are just like sliding off and how
you can see how it's landed and the
devastation underneath it and how it's
knocked off just it's cool to just see
how and I said we're going to be sitting
here and you what's just going to happen
bit of earthquake B chunk fall off we
see it in the back country often we see
Avalanches we'll just be staring at the
mountains and then all of a sudden
you'll just see a little Avalanche start
not huge ones I've never witnessed giant
ones or anything but I've seen some
pretty awesome little mini ones you know
nice like waterfalls of snow snow
tumbling over the over the cliff side
looks pretty damn cool cool yeah
definitely I wonder where my dog is he's
just cruising around right there come on
or here you go
buddy oro's digging this little bit
windy out today probably mucking up with
our audio a little bit but uh we're just
going to hang out and finish a few more
Vapor bowls maybe find that waterfall
and uh we'll bring you with us each time
we do we hope that you like these
beautiful epic uh Mountain scenarios as
much as we do anyone can sit in their
house and take bong rips we like to
bring you guys on an
adventure well guys we just had a funny
experience we just rolled up to the
Cactus Club one of the all-time
favorites for food on the west coast
here pretty delicious menu I would say
wouldn't you it's an awesome menu we'll
show it we'll show you some of the food
when we get in there I don't usually
share too much food when we're eating
but we'll do that and uh what did we
find
John in the door of my truck a small can
of of butane and a blowtorch I had the
mother ship and the DC Banger so I
suspect he had some rosin and some dry
sift I've got some of uh LH and some
full melt I guess we're hitting a few
bowls here in the parking lot before we
go in well you know what we missed it on
the lake so well the lake was nice with
the VAP though I have to admit I was
really quite quite happy with that I was
reallying kind happy too but you know
what
boom boom Shaboom boom boom Shaboom so
there's nothing like doing a nice little
denil M it's not even a dil see I I like
the Dil so much let's heat it up right
on the bottom okay so I'll give you a
little uh it's a two-man job sometimes
too mad to heat up the nail it is the
best part about
this we're in the parking lot of the
Cactus Club oh I know the minute the
session's over we are inside to eat eat
it's going to be the Mad mouth I'm so
hungry and thirsty thank you sir you're
quite welcome sir so I guess probably
wait a few seconds for for that rip well
we have um I'm not too worried about
them um you know what they're probably
puffing yeah worst case scenario they
aren't and they could just whatever
that's the joys of licenses and
medicinal and exactly you
know that that looks tasty
so keeping it
real she's having a cigarette she can be
maybe she put some oil on that it looks
like she might
[Music]
oh nice uh low temp dab right there it
was really nice it's still actually
hitting a
bit burn that off yeah just hit it right
in the in the bottom there I grab me a
hit there too you a nice little size hit
here y
and then we'll do one more each of the
LH I love that that's the that's the
lobster butter isn't it and we'll go in
yes this is the uh the only
real L that I
hit I love how Oreos just got his head
like literally right there he's just
hanging out he's just such a good dog
good little dude he's a good DG he is
he's he's a great dude all right brother
there you go thank you my friend
boom boom
boom there's nothing like so tasty so
smooth so delicious no irritation and
and and just quite nice it's beautiful
just like that I think we're going to
follow it up then w we we talking about
that and how search about you know a lot
of people try not to cough for a minute
but when you're smoking the half
and the Epic you don't cough you don't
have to worry about trying not cough not
unless you take some you know oversized
rip that's really you know it's going to
make any any person cough we're not
really doing that we're just kind of
lightly
medicating lightly medicating micro dabs
really I mean not really micro dabs cuz
the these are much bigger than the dabs
I give don't worry I'm going to scrape
that off for your hit I know I'm to a
smile on my face when I just saw that I
was like that's going to be nice I could
have helped you out with that that's
okay if you notice it sits perfect on
the three the back two prongs I love
that un I definitely like this little
unit it's um I'm going to cool this off
quite a bit more for the um the LH due
to the fact that it doesn't really
bubble it's already the oil melts
obviously because it is a liquid already
even if it's a solid it still becomes a
liquid instantly water hash and dry sift
has the wax membrane that wax membrane
takes a little bit of time to break down
start boiling and then gain access to
the inside so I think it's always a
better idea to leave it a little bit
longer than you would with the uh with
the dry SI or the wet wash not the rosin
though what's interesting
is I never really used to let it cool
down I justed to hit it really hard all
the time and learning from what
everybody is doing it's just the best
part is is really is is going down to
those temperatures even trying lowering
my Dil the other day down to 500 and
then I was turning it off and I got
really nice hits around 630 it was
really tasty so I was finding some new
temperatures for myself too that was
literally a perfect
hit I just took I think Horatio would
even be proud of me well you know what I
guarantee Horatio would be
proud I mean he's it's it's like his
baby he's a scientist he sits at home
and spends hours and days doing things
and thank God he's doing the good work
right now I'll tell you that guy he he
is definitely doing some amazing work
I'm hoping on doing a part two with him
in the upcoming months I don't know
exactly what he has to share it's always
on Horatio's terms I just eager to to
hear from him and when he gives me the
call we'll I'll hit him up and we'll get
we'll show you guys the next uh the next
part of the inner sanctum all right
Johnny B yeah let that one you know just
to sit a little bit you can put this
right
here for this session to come can even
see smok in there a little bit oh that's
my reflection
nice I'm excited to eat I'm not going to
lie damn excited to eat
nice little rip
there fely tasty all right guys it's
time to eat we're going to go grab some
food we see in a bit so the chicken
wraps have arrived yeah chicken wraps we
got um
uh what are these the the squash ravioli
with prawns and candied Sage Le prawn
Trio ravioli tunaki tuni that's a sweet
fine tunaki then I myself am having a
Caesar
salad with a little piece of salmon in
it and that was the
flatbread all in all quite delicious
we're going to finish up here and we'll
hit you out with the next session see
you in a
bit all right so we are here uh with
enrio from sublimator Johnny B and I uh
were on our way back from jeez where
were we not what's up Bubble World hope
we were in hope that's bub the world
right hope Bubble World and I hoped all
day did show up and there they are it's
true we were late we were probably like
45 minutes to an hour later than we
should have been they were Paving on the
freeway they were Paving on the freeway
oh is that the re okay okay know thought
I thought they were giving your starters
at for desserts oh yeah even although
were standing there to leave and we were
waiting to get our food packed up that's
when we really started feeling the sort
of like listen we really got to leave
and get there now especially cuz we were
going to have a wicked session when we
got there but also cuz our friend was
waiting for us yes so without further
Ado tell us what you got going on here
dude cuz this is all new I'm actually
glad you brought your older unit with
you mhm uh we had to revamp it and give
you all the stuff that was missing that
we came up with lately so we have we
have the V4 which is ATT attachable to
to my you're already ex unit you put
this here and the carb cap is directly
on top of it like this that I like so
you put it on our new sublimator
glass that's pretty sweet yeah yeah it's
all heavy glass uh it works with
anything works with the sublimator or
you can actually smoke out of it if you
still desire to and uh yeah basically
that's it so uh what we do is we'll take
like a t of a gr because it also worked
with weed so you can see so you've got
this thing all heated up and ready to go
absolutely I'm sorry I was waiting for
you so I have nothing to do so oh of
course I'm going to jump in there all
right John so I'm going to move this for
you right here so you can try it
without so now you're on low T oh
yeah nice nice nice That's good oh you
got your carb cap you would you still
lift it out or just lift the carb cap uh
you can lift the carb cap or lift the
whole thing out it's up to you either
way whatever your too you went too slow
on the on the in on the intake Johnny
too slow that was perfect it was perfect
for you oh yeah
so tell there is a particular
particularity to the sublimator and I
know where enrio is coming from because
I find myself when I use it and I get
everything right I'm super happy then
when I don't do it right and it doesn't
work I'm like oh [ __ ] what the why is
this thing not working and every single
time it's happened it's been my own like
lack of paying attention to a certain
variable like you saying leave the carb
cap on I can guarantee you I would have
left that off yeah a lot of people do
leave it off but if you leave it on
you're just going to have a different
Thermo thermodynamic to your unit if you
have a carb cap that is cold and you put
it on that which represent about 15% of
the mass represent uh in front of you
here and you put a cold cold carb cap on
if you'll cool off you'll cool off your
unit right away you want to have the
same uh effect that if you just lift it
up and once you put your organic or your
soft organic or or or or hard or resin
uh once you put your carb cap on top it
will create another reaction on top by
having the the the cap also heated up by
also oh I can't speak today what's wrong
with me no
but no I got you and and for for me one
of the things I noticed in a in a big
way where a lot of people thought that
it was all about the sublimator wand and
I kept trying to explain to people I'm
pretty sure that bowl is as as important
that is the because I always noticed if
I didn't keep this that perfect
temperature you'll just vaporize yeah
this was just to keep it at that
temperature and get it to that
temperature but most people really think
this wand is the sublimator unit no the
sublimator the wand is actually the
first the first part of heating up the
heating up your your uh your herb and or
your concentrate and uh mixing it with
the the most like the highest how can
you call this the mixing it with
the the most um what do you call this um
the most thermal radiant that you can
but passing it through a lot of uh it's
a little too hot for us right now so I'm
going to bring it down a little B
apologize oh man that was a beautiful
head unbelievable like for how well it
vaporizes or sublimates I guess is more
of an accurate term but it really
is quick and fast and it gives this
punch that you're kind of you just don't
get from most units you know what I've
been having fun with I've been throwing
my 25 hash in there that doesn't melt in
the bottom oh yeah and that kind of
stuff well it's like a pre this is like
also a rosin machine in a sense except
you can just hot air extract your rosin
it creates it creates rosin as you go if
you don't use if you don't use um if you
do not use um if you do not use a like a
a BHO or anything like this and you just
use your flowers what you will
recuperate from here is uh is quite
delicious it's going to be for more and
this is nice and open so I guess you
just pull out the plug that the bowl is
going into and dip in with a little dab
tool yeah for this one yes normally on
our units yeah on our units like this
one here you actually we actually have
like a a little uh okay do you have one
of these uh no would you have one of
these I wouldn't say I'll you up right
now give a little shot so let me see
that little guy so there you go your oil
actually accumulates here and you can
redab your oil and like I'm saying if
you're using only herbs no hash nothing
just herbs the the the the resin rosin
that you'll get out of there the
extraction the
the re uh the re condensation of the
fragmentation the fraction that we're
doing here is uh is delicious it's just
delicious I'd go as far as saying it's
even ridiculously medicinal cuz it is
the very thing that I used to remove a
big nasty mole on my neck two
applications 5 days it fell off dude
really this mole dried up like a raisin
and fell off with rosin with the reclaim
out of my sublimator bro you got to be
kidding I'm not joking I've told the
story like 10 times it's a true story
even my wife and when I say fell off
like with surgical Precision there's no
there's no Mark I just I took off the
Band-Aid and I was like w where is it
and then I looked in the Band-Aid and it
was there the mole that was on my neck 5
days prior wow with that uh reclaim and
but I was mostly hitting herb and hash
so it was a concentrated version of
those two you know yeah resins just
building up in it and I just never have
the chance like you to have like quality
hash so I'm just like with herbs I I got
good hooks for good herbs but the ash is
just a way out of my uh you got to you
got to do you got to be professional
this is a hash making machine did you
get your second one yet Johnny so what
we're going to do here Johnny is we're
going to put a little bit of herb inside
I'm going to do a double decker for you
on Little T got a little G you ready
John so that's just a little piece one
two three go my man
boom rocking it out sublimator crew oh
yeah and Kelly from neutral life who I
literally haven't seen for 25 years 20
years anyway oh yeah there's a lot of in
there don't that's good put that back on
put that back on a little bit it's going
to taste like well that's that's the
waxy Bernie part that's the part you
like yeah not too bad yeah I do the
first 10 the first like you're hitting
the king's hits exactly that's what I
normally do that's very
nice like yeah not that normally Mark I
can speak very well I don't know why
today you're asking me question and I
feel like I'm a little bit you know on
the slow side I think you're doing fine
man we're all getting sublimated up yeah
and yeah you were talking about Kelly
Kelly neutral life my associate yes 35
years in the business first uh first
hydroponic shop in uh Canada I believe
that's pretty incredible if I'm wrong uh
somebody uh he's definitely goes way
back I think I first met him 25 plus
years ago through one of my mentors Ron
hickey who also owned a a shop in
Manitoba a couple of shops called
Nature's nutrition back in the day so
that was uh
these guys are the old school guys that
have been doing this for a while
pioneering this
[ __ ] well nice and Blaze they'll tell
you that much the sublimator never
denies you of an extreme go bring it a
little harder if you don't mind there
you go now we're going to get you a real
good
hit I don't know you guys do that man
that was a good
one super tasty on that
what uh how many temperature notches did
you turn that down uh no I put it to six
uh for this one I put it to six um last
one though the first one that we hit the
first one was uh the thing is I first
heated it with the torch so I was a
little bit uh a little bit lost on where
I should go but you know what we should
try right now was it a little too hot
Mark yeah no that was perfect the first
one was a little bit too hot that one
was like full tpine deep in my lungs
rocker of a hit I'm satiated I'm
wonderful John you want to do a big one
Bree hard if you know a little bit
faster it shouldn't be too much hard and
fast hard and fast there you go I swear
it always affects you in a different way
when you puff uh instead of the way you
would the way someone requests that you
puff it's quite a nice uh uh change of
pace if you can just you know get out of
your comfort zone and go here and I'll
puff like this I'll never forget the
first time I hit Horatio's
LH and he was like all right I want you
to take a real slow long hit it'll take
about 20 25 seconds hold it in for a few
then exhale I never hit like that but I
did for him and it uh it rocked me I'll
tell you the difference uh the reason
why I'm I'm telling you to breed a
little faster is just because we have a
lot of mass and this thing is like a if
you if you don't cool The sublimator
Works a little bit differently is you
have so much hot Mass when you put your
100 milligram of organic if you don't
cool it off with air Som yeah there a
sweet spot you have to throw a little
bit more hard uh breid a little more
arer to go through the atomizer also if
you make it [ __ ] atomizer at the certain
at at the proper PSI will you have a
better uh atomization of your or
fragmentation of your product your
product does have in in common with mine
I have to say you give yourself a nice
one here um what I find it has in common
with bubble bags is that the users
really are required to learn how to use
the unit and use it properly because if
you don't it doesn't give you the
same benefits you know I'm always most
stoked hitting the sublimator with enrio
because he knows how to use it
perfect so but it's pretty simple once
you got it you need about like two three
HS and then you got it for sure you got
it I mean like for the dab it's not very
difficult you just put it at the it's
just with the herb with the herb depend
if you have the dab master or this one
this one's a little bit more mass the
thermodynamic is different we got to
work at a lower temperature and how
often will this turn off every hour but
if you just do this uh uh see he had a
little
normally wow it doesn't he doesn't even
turn off right now in front of me oh
just because I I broke that little knob
Ah that's what it is okay I'll give you
another Knob right now normally you have
one hour every time you just got to pass
in front of it click click and uh you
have another hour normally okay so at
any point in time if you go click click
it extends it for an hour yes okay so
that's very good for me to know I find
that I like my unit to be on all day yes
and just have it on and whenever I want
to go to it I it happened a few times
where I went to my the cator and I was
like what the heck I was like oh it's a
good safety feature well you remember
the first unit M's always yes uh was was
difficult I apologize for interrupting
it was difficult for us to keep a unit
that was functional like
247 2-year warranty on it the diod would
not last right so I ended up having to
to exchange a lot of unit at the
beginning because of these mistakes that
I let people leave it on 24/7 you sleep
9 12 hours so it's just conveniently on
for you I have one that is on at at Al's
house for like 9 months now it's been on
it's been on we're just testing like
it's on we pass it's on it never went
down really on the but um I I shut mine
off at night but I do tend to leave them
on like in the day for but now that I
know that that's really convenient cuz I
can just hit that every 50 minutes I'm
right sitting right there on my computer
anyway it's not like it's far away no
it's literally right here the way we see
it is if you forget to reset your button
for an hour it's probably time to stop
smoking my man yeah but it's just here
exactly true enough yeah I'll remember
for the first 6 hours just around the
seventh or e8th hour I might start
forgetting well that's awesome dude
really quite a nice little rip on that
pipe what uh let me show you something
else now okay all right let's see now we
got this pipe here yeah let's check it
out and uh we're going to take this
piece hey where did I put it oh it's on
the table already this guy yeah yes I
was
how's this work so we're going to take
this here we're going to put it on the
stand where I put my
stand we're going to put inan like this
uh we didn't show people also the we
should have sh you have all you have for
dabs is uh uh we have some hash we have
the l l maybe we should try a dab of L
here before we try the other one sure
yeah is that okay with you yeah can I
try please may I try please show us how
it works you can push that off on I like
giving it into dry sift oh yeah we'll do
that a little dry sift dippage never go
wrong with that so like this yeah get
yourself a nice round that's a good one
for sure oh that's a very good one oh
sorry that's going to be your that
always happens yeah the next one's
coming out jeez it's just like pushing
itself out there so you see when you do
the dabs
yes some low temp action
oh that's a nice
one beautiful that
woo monster dab that tast like licorice
I that one's really going to hit you
yeah
dude yeah that's what is that that's the
lhl that's the L to the H to the O
that's that's the decarb THC and you
just took a pretty huge rip of it so
turn like that was a medium siiz rip and
it was a head rocker you took a great
hit I'm impressed honestly the the L has
a kick it's very strong I have to say
guys I mean
uh L yeah doesn't that hit you hard
distill it distillate so he heated it
all up through an rotovap and basically
got a very small percentage of the pure
pure pureness out of it and Le left
everything else in it so it was you know
he lost quite a bit of material W in
that process
so this is decarbox totally active you
could eat it you could rub it on your
skin it's already active before we heat
it up it's definitely uh how you finish
the session with the l no I'm sorry we
got another session to make oh nice cuz
I have to show you something you have
the one we going to take this oh you
didn't try you did try you didn't try a
double decker of L did you uh just a one
I don't know did you have Herb in there
no but we should try a double decker of
it well if you want let's do it up I'm
going to put some Congo in there though
I don't mind Congo that's for sure I
love the cono oh got the
car don't forget locally they can come
here and see you oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah there you go they can come see
us I get the unit here even see you
con con Johnny look what I did that's
okay I spilled that already it's not a
big deal I just love the smell on that
Congo much like uh your medy
lights you smelled that already this one
no I have three types of Congo at the
house and they all smell different it's
the same Congo it's just different
Growers
all different rooms I apologize rep that
it's and uh one of them is the best weed
I ever smoked in my life this one is
more the
the
the who grew the best weed you ever
smoked in your life I cannot say well
prop without without uh because I
haven't smoked weed with uh with uh so
many many people but but so far GS is
the one that I got that's got the best
tasty weed wow but that's
GS mhm so do we have a dab ready for
this uh is in a l dab is this for you is
this for John is this for me this is
going to be going to be for you double
decker all right just what I needed
that's what you needed HH M that's what
I side apparently all right
that's so if you don't mind going to put
this
here never mind there you go all
right put it a little harder than normal
and you'll be
good we got one more run here take her
Johnny I don't need to smoke myself into
a
coma how was
that I prefer the king's hit as well I
have to say not even that first little
boom little boom yeah
how would that but when you dab the oil
and you expand the oil you make it go
through the process and lay it over the
bed of weed yeah uh that's nice it
creates uh it makes it last much longer
it creates a different type of feeling
inside you get hit by two places get the
fracking of the weed and your oil on top
and oil is [ __ ] I feel like I'm drunk
well I I rarely hit more than one in a
row I'll just get one and I'm good to go
for a while if you really want to get
yourself ripped puffing two or three
those in a row is uh a good way to get
there and you're welcome to hit more if
you like it's a what I'm going to do now
is I'm going to wait for this to get hot
you're going to do a torch torch one
we're going to do a little torch here
M that's how you do it right there many
minis the torch the the on the ghost of
her head what yeah it's a small torch I
should be it's a very small
torch hey it's nice it was in the door
once you're
at absolutely I just seeing where you
were like heating it from there well the
thing is like you can eat for a longer
time just the head till your atomizer
gets
hot or you can heat up the torch and
your atomizer at the same time till
they're both hot H it's up to you but
once once it's at good temperature
it's it does that in bowls there's like
that one little 10 that 10 mil Highly
Educated Bowl I have it uh or sorry no
it was this it was the hive ceramic Bowl
cuz you're supposed to kind of heat it
in a nice even way and I just found
every time I put the torch near the top
of the hole it would go and blow out so
obviously I never really got to use the
unit I was worried about holding the
torch in one spot and and breaking the
ceramic so I understand well like this
one doesn't seem like the the best uh
glass piece to
the torch with well it's a pretty fancy
one for sure with all these different
arms coming off of it and whatnot
frosted on the bottom too with your logo
yeah sound blasted
in I think we should be ready to try
something here all right show us what
you
got so what I would do is I would put
this
here oh don't worry about it the we
in so this is the camping version there
you go
I guess that was not hot enough that was
just o tasty though oh yeah it's like a
really low dab hat tast it oh I'll tell
you I still felt it in the head oh yeah
for sure yeah but I would have just uh
heat it up just a little bit longer Mark
you would have get a real full
sublimator hit like you just uh well
Johnny will show us how to do it my
torch like I said is a very small torch
and it's really for for smaller uh
titanium heads and yes yes yes I'm uh
I'm realizing this as we
speak uh we had oh I didn't even give
you the right weed anyway I give you
that we instead of that one well I had a
great hit Johnny B's up for the next
one can't forget about Johnny B on a
puff Wednesday and we are definitely
puffing on puff Wednesday today we've
puffed well we've puffed at John's we've
puffed next to the lake we puffed here
in the vehicle oh Cactus Club yeah
Cactus Club and then we' puffed here so
it's been a good puff Wednesday so far
and uh sublimating both with the uh
plug-in version and the camper version
the torch version I also like that one
you had didn't you have one for like
putting for the fire yes yes yes yes yes
that was pretty
cool we uh we used it the the campground
version man you had one that you could
put in the coals of the fire and pull it
out and I was like man that's pretty
good a campfire
version yeah he always puts the same
amount in just a perfect amount he knows
exactly how much herb to put in now
these are the difficult variables do you
find are hard to share with the audience
or your customer base when they're is it
difficult to get across to them like how
much herb you need to put in or is it
just a simple showing them a
video uh normally I just I show them the
video but normally we try to go a01 like
a tenth of a gram you know so they can
weigh it out yeah
very cool very
tasty well I'm ready to enjoy my
sublimated High check this out always
high as [ __ ] after hanging out with
enrio One Bowl after another I feel like
I'm at the Cannabis Cup right now and
we're like 20 people in a row but it's
just really me and John boom boom boom
boom boom boom boom boom boom so now I'm
going to make you one of these so you
can try it directly from
the and one more you see now he's going
to am I going to get in line all right
yes get in line for your headit and we
have to remember in Rico every once in a
while and give him
one once say uh what's what's good with
this unit is actually if you don't have
dabs if you don't have if you only have
dry sift with you or some ash or some
herbs uh you could actually just use
that machine you take a little tent of a
gram you put that bad boy right here you
put this here and there you go Mark
enjoy
tasty from the Congo for
sure and that being the titanium is so
much more lighter
now
beautiful no it was good no kisses so
and what's beautiful about this now is I
kept a piece of ash from earlier and
without reheating it up right now I can
just go
ahead and dab it up that's nice thing
very
nice woo I tell you like I just turned
three shades of
red very good dude killer unit as always
definite
improvements I'm looking forward to
[ __ ] trying out all these toys for
certain
well you'll be able to try them for a
bit as long as you want there you go
excellent and they can check all this
stuff out at subl suca yes suca on our
also they'll be able to find them
wherever you tell them to if they get
your
uh code code there you go Mar code it's
really important to have that if you
want to have access to all this
beautiful material for much cheaper dude
definitely stoked on uh on that unit
that is a level of high that is uh well
it's no wonder why people are always so
busy at the events uh waiting in line at
your booth to get a rip
yeah it's getting uh it's getting it's
getting there I mean uh yeah we're we're
very happy it's it's hard to believe
within two years we've come along it's
by it's by in everybody's by being in
everybody's face and absolutely one of
the first second ones also having a
quality product yeah we have our shop
also in Al The Grove that uh you can
check it out it's on supper. CA you can
check it out and you can come directly
to the shop and buy some suppor if you
desire to that's the ideal way right
there well awesome dude thanks for
coming on bub
manff wednes witho Johnny B always a
pleasure sorry I'm doing this the wrong
way hey M hi M awesome guys thanks for
watching Bubble man's world we will see
you next time on Wednesday
[Music]