[Music]
hey what's up everybody welcome to
bubble man's world Johnny B is in the
house and welcome to puff Wednesday
perform I think it's pop Wednesday so
without further ado let's puff from
Johnny B's got this incredible little
slinger piece that you guys may have
seen me post from Barcelona or you may
have seen slinger or flab or some other
people post Johnny be picked that up and
it is a beauty so I'm happy to hit it
I've only hit it in Barcelona this will
be my first time hitting it in BC we're
gonna do a little rosin squishing today
a little well I mean he's got a little
bit of flour here if you wanna okay so
this is some goji shark very cushy you
know this is my favorite oh yeah no it's
your face and you have that amazing new
press yeah I've got the pure pressure
long's peak press that I've been using
for the last couple of months I hooked
up with those guys and I've been really
happy with it I am really happy with it
serious engineering on this press for
those of you wondering oh is it better
than this is it better than that it's
very specifically perfect for commercial
production it's not something that
you're gonna squish you know a quarter
ounce here and a quarter ounce there
we're not but taking it on sweida
squishing it oh we're gonna add squish
that in one shot
absolutely one shot will do the ounce of
weed I've got they sent me wonderful
tools they got big scraper tools here
specific bags fit inside their plates
they've got these molds here that you
can do pre pressing with if it's real
nice and then of course it's got a
magnetic bottom that pops up cuz it just
a
this is not not to make Roz and
obviously this is to pre-press your bag
sometimes they're big and fluffy and
they sit better if you can just give it
a nice little pre-press so I've got the
two boy 2 by 9 and the 2.5 by 9
pre-press which we'll do on camera in a
little bit we've got the bags that they
send and the cool little tool here first
I was like what the hell is this but
very simply put you get your bag on
there you push that through it flips the
bag inside out and it puts the seam on
the inside of the bag so it's not gonna
carry and hold the oil when you press it
out of the machine this is very simple
but a very very cool little addition I
also use it for if you want to pass me
that funnel when I get the funnel going
you can keep that one when I get the
funnel going and you'll see this on
camera in a little bit as well I kind of
I load like this I scooped up the bud
and then I use this will just push the
body through to fall into the bottom of
the bag and we'll do that ounce in like
seconds so not like with me when I just
grab a bud and tighten it up and squish
it very different very different that's
why I was just so kind of like I had to
check this out because a for one I like
pressing everyday but yeah sometimes
pressing everyday it's like you get out
it's kind of like cleaning that banger I
think you like 15 minutes you gotta get
a going on prep everything absolutely I
press the pound of flour yesterday I got
ninety four point eight grand return of
rosin and I know guys that have blown
with butane they get like ninety nine
hundred 496 so what we're saying is
don't do it
well yeah you don't unless you really
want to and then that's your prerogative
you know what it works but I'm here to
do always say oh you don't get as much
when you press yes you do with the
proper equipment exactly and that's the
problem is all the time we've been kind
of but
things together not actually having this
proper equipment and it looks like we're
starting to see that happen now yep
excited for that
he's got the timer going which is
awesome and this is like the dual
Wallbanger so it's a banger kind of like
inside of a banger and a banger banger
the banger and at first I was kind of
like kind of like it's yawning how it
was working the stuff but I'm happy with
it it's not just like everything else
you do have a future as bangers old
today you were telling me your chest
banger it's kind of like a relief for
you to use I don't thing as much yeah
and you don't have to worry about a
chassis but we do have the chest
Buster's here both work we got the chest
Buster's which are just another new
branded q-tip so they're just you know I
guess the specialness is that they are
organic cotton tips so yeah they were
gaming the q-tips are organic great
sorry
the Chaz Buster's are spun to the
highest possible specification mounted
on a paper stick the natural flexibility
of these gives gentle and precise
control organic cotton G OTS ICA Italy
certified lint-free dual tip design
optic white and bleach free 100% plastic
free and biodegradable well that's a
good idea
and then he's even got a tip for the
best results use Chaz Buster's with dark
crystal glass cleaner wrong got some
right here there you go so we're sorted
for your Chaz de chazzy not that I think
we're going to you can hit that now go
ahead I've got you over here here's your
card cap
little niche in the house that's the
Acapulco gold from lost Gardens to go
give him a follow on Instagram loss
Gardens
yeah it's not lost its lost oh all right
not to ruin your joke
Howard ill extreme in their hilarious
let me clean that up for you yeah it's
really cool to see everybody in 420 not
to check out a lot of the different
gloss that was there it was really cool
all the new booze that was happening so
yeah the last time I ran into you it was
we had a little rip on the puff go that
was pretty cool I kept them yeah you
know it is what it is I see a ton of
people I got a black it's cheap Chinese
crap it's like I don't feel that it's
cheap at all I use an iPhone which is
from China and it's probably one of the
most technologically advanced tools I
have I get camera lenses that are that
are made there I get all sorts of things
t-shirts and clothes and I just see
people hypocritically claiming that we
can only support one group of artists
from one specific country whereas it's
like man whatever if you know some
people can't afford $4,000 mothership
and for them buying a cheap glass pipe
from some how that's gonna where they're
gonna break it they can't afford
anything else it is what it is you know
at the same time I like to support glass
artists I love to support guys like
slinger and other artists that I've
superstone appreciate yours learn about
a few different things and talk to her
and be able to purchase them what I
would say is like piece of history mmm
should I look at it because like Dave
would say I got gas glass addicted
syndrome right Dave definitely does have
that and he goes how that you know just
being around the glass for
to see the the difference in each
individual and just seeing the work that
they do you really start really
appreciating the individual one
whatever's going to really see the art
and learning about it I mean I'm just
fascinated to find all of this great
little products like sinchai strips 25
do let the thing right come on that was
the conversation that began the whole
like we're gonna be cool if there were
machines that you could do this with so
we are going to press some rosin today
we're gonna press an ounce of Johnny's
buds
we might even press an ounce of my buds
afterwards just to do a couple of
presses the stuff I have is a solid 20
percent yield err we'll see how this
compares in regards to that and we'll
take you through the flow of the peer
pressure we'll take you through the
recipe and how you set up the machine
doing the pre pressing filling the
screens and it's really all pretty quick
what I do generally is a quick one
single press a couple minutes once I've
done that I'll do a second press of the
bag for two three minutes and I usually
get like another little bit you know
like from 20 grams 25 grams I was
getting 4 to 4.5 grams of my first run
then I'd do a second run and get almost
a gram
thanks like five point four grams of out
of one press so five sounds of it I'm
going to beat I'm shooting for seven
times there's 30 grams here I'm hoping
for 7.1 grams see what happens I think
it'd be pretty cool wouldn't be bad it
wouldn't be good of you but but it I was
just gonna be shooting so 20 second heat
up minute and five second call down that
was perfect it's a perfect
one thing I like about it is it's just
gonna hit that again yes I figured you
would let me clean it up for you later
I've learned is it just have these
little bad-mouths um and protecting your
but these little key things and making
sure when you do have a nice pipe you
make sure you keep it for the rest of
your life you need the scar some
Scottish Dutch and I cannot I kind of
like the whole thing behind it mm-hmm
and all my pipes are quite bigger from
the t.y pipes and my mother ship stuff
like that so having a nice little carry
around yeah okay had some bubble - this
time yep I'd say double about no I've
got a ninja down on the side for myself
okay you got you a nice bubble hash with
some el jéfe and then we just gotta heat
it up and I gotta do the timer for you
[Music]
maybe about 16 17 seconds seeing us I
didn't have the timer going right away
I do like the rotating around
they shout out to Colton's crew for the
t-shirt I purchased recently off of them
to help send Colton to DC says Colton's
crew on the back there alright so that's
that's a great thing damn rice with a
next plane of TAC cameras et so right on
shove it to Wendy and the whole Turner
family awesome people
Colton of course is Crohn's disease
sufferer who has become an amazing
incredible voice and advocate for
cannabis and Crohn's disease and yeah
put that [ __ ] into remission and he's
he's doing really well still great
little bubble and Michael he just did
his uh all his MRI see the three days of
testing problems cancer that there are a
couple years ago which sounds crazy to
us but think of how many times that guy
went to the hospital tumors in cancer
out of his body sent home told money you
know to basically pass away years ago
cancer-free so he's his office every
amazing actually it's absolutely amazing
routes for Johnny B so we're going to
get pressing I'm gonna go prepare the
pure pressure here get everything
organized and then we'll actually sit
back down at the table and we'll show
you the quickness of preparing the ounce
of bottom getting it into the screen and
getting it ready for the press
Jones gonna [ __ ] himself when he sees
cuz he's pressing a but at a time it's
like compared to the one that we're
gonna do today
puffin Wednesday bro I love it
all right so we're gonna prepare Johnny
B's herb what is the name of this earth
again this is OG shark so that's on the
island
long story short rockin the nitrile
gloves I got myself that was scary
that's how they do that [ __ ] at the
border when they want to like give you
the rate they're gonna be looking for
this never gotten it hurts all kinds of
spots I mean that's the nice way to open
up a jar seriously
absolutely it smells great pop it down
so we're gonna actually I don't you
think you should do is we should wait we
should tear it yeah it's so we got to go
back in the jar am i bad can't tear this
without but being out this is called
teamwork this teamwork there's a puff
Wednesday teamwork we're doing it up
got our hands in the Nuggets here we
haven't done this in a while put it
around some weed
I know what we've been well we have just
not together
it's the Johnny B bubble man bromance
clear on puff Wednesday oh you too buddy
you too
so let's tear that out there you go now
you can do what you just did and maybe
we edit it and it looks like we just did
it the first time maybe not though
probably we're not really very deceiving
like that so we've got 30 grams 30 grams
I'm looking for 7.1 in return all right
well I don't think it's a bad idea to
just do that this stock oh not just that
one big one I can push them all through
they all have a red resin on it and you
know
it's all gonna be in reality yeah I
guess the stock goes how president
Harmon
absolutely I can just see certain the
way I prepare it in the kind of this is
just like I pull this out of a bag of
weed I had a quarter pound of the sweet
actually like diagrams and I weighed out
30 grams because I'm dying to see the
difference what we're gonna squish one
squish is all it'll take Johnny
so I got these two tools right here this
is my workflow right here we should be
good I got this one piece in your hair
well there you go you're gonna eat it
that's tasty so I get it in the funnel
they're just a matter of poking it
through oops
grab that one trying to be like I want
to press that a little overzealous there
but generally turn it around show them
not show them what's going on see see
this I'm gonna be feeding now why don't
you keep the debug this Sophie got like
this isn't gonna pack the bag a little
bit I'll just get it's good stuff all
right so I'm not a big presser
I always just squished the button that's
me yeah yeah I'm never gonna use the
bags I'm really not I have to say this
is much easier in a sense my workflow
really is like this okay fine
there's two or three I think it was good
but then as we both dropped buds now I
thought you know what I'm not even gonna
get this [ __ ] though but like I was
saying I don't really use a bag and
that's only because I'm only bleeding
pressing a couple Grammys named Revlon
for
years four years a couple years it's
mean that one who knows finally are
using it on your hair as well they're
dumb I'll be straightening this side
I'll be definite the haircut that's
Justine all kinds of weird things I was
going for that Justin Bua oh nice nice
what I'm kidding
alright go the last little bit in there
looking me for so I'd be space like
sitting out yeah like 30 to 35 grams I
think so perfect
guessing over mfab geez big nose yeah I
was glad to eat it
no I said 30 G's really different just
like to me it's that's what it's worth
because it's well it is 30 G's 30 grams
geez geez sound cheesy buzzing man
probably both cord definitely got this
bag stuck to the max so yeah I've never
had the pleasures of squishing anything
really more than they don't probably
like helps a weave I just kind of like
squishing of course and we've used a 73
micron bag 73 micro yeah this one's a 73
so then we're gonna go into our pressure
here this is basically what this does
let me just drop that in there check
this out yep it's right in there and
then I generally just give it one of
these it's just nice and pre-pressed
prepared I like and now I would always
fold these ends over you just well you
can fold it over all you want and it's
just gonna pop back over so when we fold
it over is when we put it in the press
we'll bring the plates down we'll slide
this in always leave it up top so you
have something to grab the bag out of
it's really a bit more difficult
otherwise you don't want to have it
upside down that was a tip that I got
from the Sasquatch Ross guys nice so
they do that all the time and I like to
keep it out so it's not like you know
when it goes down I don't want that
piece of screen over so I'll kind of
push it in and make sure that it's
really on top of the bag and not at the
edge if anything that's at the edge it's
gonna absorb Raza okay yeah so I think
we should go press this president okay
we are here in the bubble man's office
aka hash Church central we got the long
press turned on we're going to I'm going
to take John through this really quick
I've turned the plates on here a lot of
people are gonna say that's too hot I
press a to xx + 1 50 30 so well they
trust me it's gonna be fine we'll give
it a good check out we have proper
moisture content in our buds and I think
some people are dealing with some very
dried out herb in which case this is way
too hot of a temperature there you go so
we're gonna go to recipes and we're
gonna go to the chocolate push which is
what I was doing recently we're gonna
change the weight cuz it's 30 grams so
how bad in there we've got the fact that
it's flour material
Keith's hash not available back to flour
we've got the bag size set at 2.5 x 9
the micron set is actually 72 microns on
this one
slow tempo the 50% humidity it's
probably even higher isn't a sixty four
sixty three sixty three sixty percent
okay 62% 62% humidity our heaters are
both on we've got three stages right now
a minute
in a minute but we'll see how the flow
is okay if the flow is over we'll just
stop it at stage two so we can go save
and run now it's ready to press as you
see up here and generally get that set
up so I'm gonna show you a little bit of
my workflow I've got my pure Frankie
rosin bags here so here we go right here
here's the bag this bag goes in very
nicely right into here I take the top
and I put it into a magnet ice and I put
the bottom right here into the little
clip and we've got our bag so what we
will do here actually get up to this
part will show you that here's our
toggle switch over here that's gonna
give us our pressure we are sitting at a
hundred and forty so we should be good
for maximum pressure I'm gonna push both
of these five four three two one zero
now it's starting up the fact of how
everything comes in together where it's
actually showing the micron size to the
amount of weight to - that's right now
so now I'm releasing the pressure it's
not a hash so you can actually pretty
much release the majority of the
pressure instantaneously so you can see
it coming out right away within 30
seconds is generally when you see it
just lift it up cuz I think we're gonna
have some nice flow
oh I'm excited yeah nice to squish it's
falling you're gonna fall
yeah we're getting a nice flow so this
looks like a solid 15 to 20 percent
yield although there's a little bit more
flour than I've been squishing make sure
that it's not gonna go off the end of
the paper I'll let you be in charge of
that actually should be fine lift it up
a tiny bit and it'll stuff low will will
thicken up and cease very nice thick
spots don't seem you have a cell phone
the timer there and everything so just
yeah it's done in a minute so far in 45
seconds leave it up you have to do this
so if you do that there's no way it can
flow but that's a good problem to have
sometimes I'll pull way more of the
paper out as well I kind of there's a
couple of ways that I do it sometimes so
well this is super exciting because a
for one for five days exactly so oh yeah
I guess we could probably stop that soon
the flow looks pretty good
maybe for twos I got a good buddy that
owns one of these that's a thumbs up
it's dripping in the back - this is a
real good producer dude I said this is a
killer producer so I wanted to bring it
here alright so let's check it out we're
gonna stop the press yeah yeah I think
it's pretty good I guess we could leave
it
let it finish off whoa yeah and telling
you dude there's a bathroom
we have many pack trips whoa many many
back trips that's pretty cool yeah
you'll get lots of chances to take this
thing that's cool
mmm perfect so we'll stop the press got
that open hold the top of the bag for me
I'll get this out here we go well let's
see what you got there Johnny deep um
that would be squish I like the back
squish I've never had a back squish
before yes like little trikes Yeah right
right
all right so I'll set this up and I'll
collect it for you real quick you're
first all right we're gonna collect I
just collect with a small little
highly-educated tool and I'll give you a
quick show on how I do that
[Music]
yeah we're about to put this on the
scale to give you guys an idea of what
we got it's great 6 grams from 30 I'm 30
that's great
oh yeah that's like a solid 20% 2 grams
per 10 20 20 20 so it's the same yield I
was getting off the chocolate cush 30 30
20 percent return my straw which is
great and you know what generally I
would do a second press just to see
what's left well I don't mean we'll do
that let's do it 6 grams a solid 20%
return and we haven't even done the
second press yet we are running out of
the battery on the camera so we're gonna
do the second press off the camera but
at the end of the video I'll let you
know if anything came out of that and
I'll photograph it and yeah it looks
good actually the last thing I want to
do is this I want to get this here for
Johnny B come on
I saw it sticking too right on the end
right on this end where I was gonna open
it there's that's where it's sticking
that's awesome
that last little bit off there we don't
need to be leaving resin behind on
parchment paper just ends up being lost
forever
nice and clean take this over my messy
office and into the D mail it will go
[Music]
this isn't either this is just a cool no
heat whatsoever just making yours a nice
little there it is let's go check it out
in the Sun okay so there we have it a
little hole from where I dug out the
piece of parchment that you saw fall in
it in otherwise it looks real nice it's
better at this angle probably where I'm
in the Sun in here oh yeah great color
all right great job Johnny B you got it
going on here want to hold that all I
did was like find this killer resin that
like you know when you get that smell
like it's in the hospital together the
one that works for me you'll find that
strain too sweet six grams in Johnny's
pouch so we'll we'll see you next time
on puffs Wednesday everybody made the
film L bless your bowl sooner than later
yes we better do one hit
is it everything you wished send more
awesome I'm ready are you ready medicine
out of the slinger
[Music]
light light hit for me we heated it up
outside and I think the banger cooled
down a bit but still it's still quite
lovely I guess that's all she wrote guys
[Music]