[Music]
he
[Applause]
all right welcome back guys puff
Wednesday with John
B that was kind of fun it was pretty
cool we just went and dropped off uh
well you guys all saw what we just did
we just went to Air Canada cargo dropped
off uh five mothers the Betty Kush which
is going to secure John's genetics and
his
strain for himself and for anyone else
who finds it as a beneficial strain uh
for pain management uh for anything
really but for pain management is what
John's using it for so I guess we've
gotten those plants out of our truck
yeah and now we're just sitting here at
the airport planes are in the background
kind of taken off taking off right now I
think that might be the Air Transat one
look it out there it is boom and here's
another one coming lining up so we're in
flight path Park this is just on the way
into Richmond from the airport we're
about 10 ft below sea level right now
which is kind of trippy are we 10 ft
below sea level that's about 10 ft below
sea level yeah so I'm and the ocean's
right there so it's kind of trippy to
think we're a little bit below the level
of the ocean so anyway why don't we have
a sash John um I would love to do that
I'm with you I'm with you I didn't find
any water but you know what I'll hit
this thing dry all day I got some orange
juice we're not going to use orange
juice in the Hitman I don't think we are
I don't think we are it's not going to
happen I'm going to make a little wind
barrier here here's how we block the
wind and uh we'll torch up get ready
what are we going to get into we're
going to get into some uh oh jeez what
to get into well like we do we do I'm
going to smoke yours and you're going to
smoke mine I got some 120 here we go
look at this little guy FedEx coming in
hot the bottom a little that bottom
defitely kind of cool being in flight
path park that's going to happen every
once in a while while we're doing this
little session so um I'm going to start
with what you put me right in front of
me here which is of course watermelon
fresh frozen I'm basically bound and
destined to smoke all of John's medicine
that I helped him make well you know
what told him I couldn't take any but I
would damn sure smoke it all as we hung
out so that's what we do we get to smok
it all right see that little bit of wind
is actually helping we got to watch the
wind here but we are in the flight path
so we are getting oh got planes landing
behind us path Park got a moon
beautifully half half full moon up there
in the sky oh look at you look at that
you know I used to come here when I used
to be like 16 17 years old and we used
to actually just park our cars here and
sit in our cars and lie in the hoods and
well they took that away from us and now
you got to park and they made I remember
that yeah I remember that laying uh
putting the you know driving up on the
car just on the grass there was no Park
yeah I'm going to just grab the Bon
again well you should there's no need to
wait for me you've got your own scene
happening over there this is just my
little SC got full m
dry you know what I'm I'm going to top
it off with a little bit of DK 420
because I am supposed to be smoking uh
your stuff right now and not my
own there we go thanks DK once
again so it's going to be a little hard
right now to use the beine I'm actually
going to be using this uh lighter so you
know what we are in the wind so it is
windy that's nice m
Hitman rips in flight path
Park no complaints there no complaint oh
that smell great I what was that that
was number four number four well pass it
over pass over some number four we
always know how good number four tastes
and
smells all
right number four number four is so good
it is it's one of my I would say it's it
is definitely the favorite of the of a
lot of the strains that I have other
than medy and watermelon and my little
just real
nice real nice
strain good old flight path Park What a
Beautiful Day dropping off moms we're on
our way to Mega Hill Pizza right after
this where we will pretty much do what
we're doing right now except we'll do it
indoors while eating pizza while while
eating pizza let's get a medicated Pizza
this time maybe hey lightly medicated
lightly medicated yeah we should give
that a
shot oh my gosh was that tasty that was
like a vapor head sometimes hard to get
the nail hot enough and you get these
light light really nice Vapor ribs
I like the really nice Vapor ribs it's
something that I was just you know over
here taking a look and and enjoying I
mean
uh beautiful day but we just did and a
beautiful day you what we just did was
really kind of cool when you think about
it you know what I mean I I'm feeling a
little bit more safer knowing that um no
matter what happens with the
program I uh will have access to
something that I use every day but I
mean well that's key it's a great thing
to to do like I I just I had I had to do
it so you know all you haters out there
about certain things you know what you
got to understand that standardized
medicine is needed for people who are
suffering from different disease and
conditions and are sick and dying so I
mean we got to look at Great access and
the world is changing to a legal
cannabis sure is every
day just got to get this little
windproof here oh it's getting Nic and
heated up nicely windproofing The
Hitman we're going to be hooking up the
D now pretty soon oh yeah that's exactly
what we're going to
do that was
perfect
there it was
wonderful well that was three nice
little rips here at flight path
Park we're going to pretty much maybe
have a few more off camera and make our
way down to Mega ill pizza so next stop
Mega ill Mega Hill Pizza we'll talk to
you guys soon
peace more ribs ripping in would you
like some house I would love some would
you like hting a bong or you going dab
I'll dab it up there you go thanks so
much so here we are standing on the top
of the Arctic Circle is that what it is
I think so I would MOS Russia Europe
Asia we're on top of the world John nice
John I like get on top of the world it's
good to be on top of the world with you
buddy yeah nice where is uh British
Columbia well we North
America this looks like Vancouver Island
right here I would say that would be
Vancouver YVR you're standing on
yourself I'm standing at YVR here we are
man look at that big Sund dog around the
sun right now can you guys see that I
don't know if you can but it sure looks
cool that's pretty cool what they've
done here I've never seen this before
yeah this is kind of neat kind of
walking over
here walking on top of the world man
[Applause]
go down motion I
know next
stop Jamaica is that Jamaica
Jamaica we go to Jamaica that's not that
far flying I I understand now next
[Music]
stop I love you I love you I love
you give thanks for the morning rising
sun SP bre of Life of
man it's all about your D to relax and
free I want to take a dab with you
because I'm feeling
good it's all about your da relax and
freeing
move see I want to di with you because
I'm feeling good
yeah rise up this morning feeling in the
mood to dive away
today dive way
today I saw my good friend he said to
me one will keep the doctor
away it's all about your relax and free
and
[Music]
I been a few times I think this would
been my second actually no no my thirdd
because I'm feeling good yeah all right
make it ill make way for the I'm
ready surprise makers of
today fire torch to the glass blades
your troubles away load it up load it up
let us burn one down and pass it
around it's all about your D to relax
and free move
I want to take a dab with you because
I'm feeling
good it's all about your da you relax
and free
move see I want to Da with you because
I'm feeling
good so if you ever take a d before take
it easy if you know say you're one time
beginner take this advice from the DJ
seek medical help if you don't feel
proper then don't one them prescribe
realiz
let's
delicious we've made it to Mega ill
we're hitting the Dil and we're about to
order up some pizza so that's what's
going
on we took clones we took clones earlier
we shipped plants off with airic Canada
we are now at me eating cice pizza what
else we doing that's a pretty good day
pretty good day I'm going to hit it up
with another rip of uh I thought this
was sweet skunk it's actually Jack
herrer Jack yeah full m
dry that was who had
that so you know what's really cool was
actually going to Air Canada cargo
dropping off those plants and all my
form it says five live
plants talk loud five Liv talk loud
so apparently because we're at Mega ill
I was just talking about dropping off
five live mother plants at air how about
me driving down the highway with the
plants breezing out of the top of the
container as the lids blew off oh that
was the beginning start that we never
showed you guys yeah that was fun that
was fun actually it was a little epic
I'm Sor freway pull over things down
hurry up we can do this later it was
yeah okay we should have L them down but
you know what I'll send down to see yeah
it's all good they're all way to uh its
next destination exactly so more bowls
pizza coming talk to you guys
soon hi welcome to Mega ill awesome
thank you all right menu's here guys to
check this
out all
right I'm settled dude just like that I
am settled as well yeah yeah
waam bam it's the weed guy heard what's
up buddy turned around stopped
everything I was doing two crazy guys at
my place yeah dude how you guys doing
thanks for coming down just got
here you're going sit down we have a SE
dab dab up with something
lovely something dry Sifty perhaps we
got um he's like uh well we're ordering
some pizza dude with it back one second
just got here take care of a couple
things Jack Herrera or sweet skunk uh
sweet skunk
sweet Gunk I just love that pineapple
citrusy flavor that's waiting for you
signature I'll do now I suddenly don't
have to go
it suddenly don't have to go and finish
up this gu has magical properties like
that all right bro here you
go oh yeah it's m away beautiful fresh
edes yeah t the light yeah dude
nice Cloud you still be your fine
establishment here today it's everyone's
fine establishment come on down you know
I've only been a few times but the last
time John I were here it was literally
the perfect restaurant
experience like a few friends that we
recognized I just wanted that Amsterdam
experience here just with their own
style Amsterdam does not have this
experience yeah it's like I'm not
dissing on Amsterdam I love Amsterdam
but this is like uh you got your own
they're not covering this in the media
because it's Amsterdam like covering it
cuz it's new and it's different and it's
unlike anything that anyone's got going
on I'm super stoked with all the
coverage man I just like magazine
unbelievable Allen yeah I was just like
okay this is just completely he got more
bananas and more bananas pretty much the
most bananas anything I've ever seen
that wasn't like Mark Emory yeah you
know what I mean like he always went
right to the Wall Street Journal and all
these ridiculous but like that Time
Magazine and Jimmy Fallon and and it's
all good publicity there wasn't any like
uh this place should be shut down or
anything that everyone was like I love
David Letterman was like oh so they like
open up a pot play silon Pizza in
Vancouver and everyone just started
cheering slight pause and then it was a
cheering it wasn't like laughing or
anything was like
yeah I was like wow that really went
home to me as like what kind of this
place is so I mean but they have pizza
places in Cambodia that serve wheed
pizza just kind of just doing it here in
North America Cambodia as well right
it's like Vancouver has its own unique
Geographic by right we have the Epic
mountains just you know they're right
out the windows there just on the other
side of these buildings we have epic
beautiful mountains we're in the city
that we just came from Richmond where we
were at like flight path Park watching
the planes fly over us and hitting bowls
there right know and you literally be up
to the mountain in a matter of 15
minutes from the ocean yeah from there
it was 10 minutes 15 minutes to get here
another 10 15 you're on the mountain you
want the you can go to the valley and
get the farm feel in abidur and very uh
Alberta Lake Whistler oh I know Whistler
Friday one day i' what's happening
Friday stowboard festival for 10 days
Tellis Festival starts and that'll be 11
or 12 days of absolute complete chaos
I'm thinking Saturday is the best day
they got de Soul planed great he hasn't
been a Whistler in a long time he like
honestly like 10 years I would say yeah
and uh got um from schollen Members
there's a couple guys yeah Prevail
performing right so that's my agent so I
should be able to get us backstage for
that he's a good dude for sure I
snowboarded with him randomly just a few
times by accident they love Whistler
yeah yeah well it was actually on
Cypress both times oh yeah like every
Bud's like yeah that's Prevail I'm like
do Treads that's awesome and thanks for
the coverage to actually hington post
picked it up too and oh we couldn't
believe it someone someone wrote me that
and was like oh yeah your videoos on The
Huffington Post and I'm like no that's
Mega ale probably just a picture of our
video something my friend like no man
it's like your whole video I was like
ripped it and used it yeah I couldn't
believe the variety of news that was
coming in here like we had uh my buddy's
like dude you were on Omni News he's
like I had to explain to my
mom like that's awesome sweet scun F
John okay right on
Mark all right great to
see
boom all right well we're B going to
order up a couple of pizzas and we'll be
back in a
Flash that's not our pizza is
it special piz that he already made made
pizzas John yeah um they came in and uh
they were like okay so they made some
specially made pieces here guys wow this
looks I wish I could have some but it's
got meat all over it maybe that one
piece over there if you pulled the
pepperoni piece on the back off of
it yeah I could probably eat that
it's all garlicky and stuff that looks
delicious I'm going to try
it I have to
say this infused Pizza cuz this one's
the infused one they' stepped it up a
notch guys this is amazing Pizza you
would never know this is infused this is
infused oh we're getting
baked you wouldn't know it's so
good give me that apparently they put a
grand of crystal on it but we'll see
what
happens be careful
mus all right my vegetarian pizza just
showed up and I have got to say I am
stoked this is
nonmedicated the nicest
um vegetarian pizza I've
seen com out dude with the
arugula yeah just making sure you know
where they are so nothing gets tipped
over
I don't want on
the no not
that we're trying to decide whether the
herb is uh the the pizza is medicated is
it medicated
Tim okay so
I four
slices I just ate four slices as
well yeah well
you
have we're should we have a bed May
cheesecake cheesecake cheesecake has
arrived happy times here um my
cheesecake arrived as well looks
delicious so Mega ill Pizza Not Just
Killer Pizza medicated pizza but killer
desserts this is a non-medicated dessert
but after eating four pieces of
medicated pizza and puffing many bowls
of dry sip I think this is going to be
perfect so super
stoked b i PE there
John weet guy has shown up at our table
here not rolling on that one yeah we
arey okay well first of all there is uh
regulations and that's number one there
got to be 18s to get in here and number
two uh you have to have a doctor's
diagnosis or federal exemption so I
don't see what the hell he's talking
about clearly didn't read the article or
the news let's hit this rip on his
behalf
one
Med that was some sweet scum
dry smoth
too I think uh I'm going to follow it up
with one
myself Slide by the dabuccino there I
need dude the
dabuccino thank you [ __ ] cool man so
cool I just like things that are useful
yes AB you know like the the like the
light
on it sh the night those little tiny
pocket LED flashlights saved me many
times in the bush looking for
something
like John so quiet you muted
him a long day like what happened Weir
like it has been a long day a good long
day what a
day I got you covered you got me covered
yeah ready to go lemon OG lemon
OG like ninja dab boyfriend girlfriend
BBG kids sh these days rockar
Bubba and one of the bvgf again the weed
guys got to have his
weed that's really strong rolling them
all
up oh so uh 420 is on Sunday and uh my
kids almost 15 going in or is in high
school and uh so it's like oh poor 20's
you know coming up so what do you think
about that she's like well everyone at
school is just calling it praise and
Blaze praise and
Blaze wow I was like that is awesome
p Just hidden
BS like they owe us money here at
me BS like they owe us money that video
you
guys have thought coverage for pizza and
H well why
not we need to we're going to hit you
hard you hit me hard is that a tri
factor I have two different times at one
time I bu like a 40% like 60% get
it yes oh on the over the
[Music]
glass great did you like the ninja dab
coming in off the off the uh well I kind
of knew it was coming so be more like a
tag team ninja dabs where you're like oh
have this to it's beautiful delicious
okay please not too
big
ninj n my
friend hopefully D to the airport
OU always pop on the way in you know
always having PR you get off work you
when are we going to Nepal and uh that
going happen I think Nepal will be after
Jamaica when you going to Jamaica in a
couple weeks all right Mark's taking off
thanks thanks so much man L you VIP
status for this guy forever so come
check out Mega Ill give me the address
646 Kingsway in
Vancouver on puff Wednesday puff
Wednesday yeah epic day Mega ill
all right John what a [ __ ] epic day
epic day probably one of the best puff
Wednesdays maybe yet I think it's one of
the most epic puffing ones days from uh
cut and clones puffing bowls dry sift
puffing bowls Mega ill delivering plants
that were probably on a plane right now
they will be loaded on a plane right now
yeah dude well in next Wednesday we bid
you AAR and uh have a puffy Wednesday
and we'll see you next time peace
[Music]