[Music]
hey guys bubble man here welcome to
Bubble man's world uh I am here sitting
in traffic at the current moment next to
a postal vehicle one that probably has
cannabis in it thanks to the
wonderful uh programs here in Canada
that you can buy and ship herb through
the mail and of course tons of
dispensaries are doing it through Civil
Disobedience and I support them as well
anyway today I'm going to be heading
down to see uh oh d420 K I see some cops
ahead of me now are in
action uh we're waiting for a train
right now so here comes the
popo looks like they are going to go
bust people that are turning around and
cranking illegal 180 so we'll see what
is going on
there anyway in the meantime I'm heading
over to CD 420k we're going to have a
real chill day I'm not exactly sure on
what level that's going to mean what
we're going to do exactly but uh yeah
we're going to puff some bowls eat some
food tell some stories film a little
video and I figured I would just start
this video off right here in my truck
while uh while I was sitting and waiting
and watching everyone do u-turns postal
truck says [ __ ] no I am out of here here
bro she's doing the 12-point turn as is
the minivan looks like their uh the
train just stopped right in front of us
so uh we just got people turning around
and going the other
way I think that's what I'm going to do
too see you guys at
De all right so I am now on Commercial
Drive heading over to d420 K's Place
pretty cool spot in Vancouver if you've
never been um very eclectic little area
lots of cool little shops course
checking out for
sure heading up the stairs to the top
floor the penthouse of
course go puff some bowls with
D should be
good
hey what's going down how's it going
dude good you I'm doing good man looking
forward to uh I'm looking forward to
filming or not filming whatever bro
whatever whatever
hey guys made it here to d420 K as you
saw when I walked in the door and he was
eating strawberries yep is that what you
were eating strawberries strawberries
good to see you dude good too bro good
to see you we've had uh our technical
difficulties getting everything going
today but we are here at de's uh City
Apartment we got three flavors of Tarpin
along with three flavors of rosin that
uh you just pressed out pretty much yeah
Ed the hair straightener perfect the
little clamp and what flavors we got
we've got train wreck Locomo which is a
New York diesel train rack cross very
citrusy yeah it's very o and the O the
O so we got three nice things I've also
got three nice things that we're going
to put together with those three n n
thing or nice things I've got the Jack
Frost tpin the OG Jack Frost we haven't
had this in like since we started it's
been a year since we had this one was
that on our um T Gauntlet oh it had to
be dude the Jack Frost oh
oh super special super citrusy and just
really what a what a [ __ ] you can
taste it when you smell it yeah it's
this one's intense this is one of those
ones that I think if I had a big enough
bottle and you took a big enough whiff
it would make you feel sick it's so
intense yeah you know then I brought
that Yoda Yoda was the one that did that
to me made me feel sick in my tummy my
tummy Clementine Clementine Clem
let me tell you let me time's going to
do as fun I know she is oh
already wow right what is that what is
that you remember when we were doing the
TP de call it oh yeah trying to smell
what you're actually smelling trying to
putting it into words and experience the
actual like what is that it's TS that's
nice that's nice is that nice jeez
that's uh that's impressive right and
I've managed to take a drop out of each
one and drop it into the clear the clean
vial so we don't have to dip into the
fresh FS lavender skunk from s oo that
one has a real nice unique very like oh
yeah even from here I'm smelling that
right now and it's
ridiculous oh my God you know what's
that turps they're so nice to smell it's
like when when I've walked in The Grow
rooms and smelled and and just and gone
up and and seen these these these Frosty
nugs and and touched one of
them and then smelled my finger yeah and
it's that that know that's how fresh
dude I'm telling you preser nice that is
wow Blue River wow Tony tpine well why
don't we start it out I think Jack Frost
should go with what's the first one
train wreck train wreck so train wreck I
say we do Clementine
okay um your Locomotion I say we Citrus
it up even more with Jack Frost I think
they're really going to um go nicely
together all right that orange and that
Jack Frost lemony and then I'm thinking
OG and that lavender skunk yeah right
yeah that'll really kick the OG up all
right take it to a whole different uh
different level why don't you pull off
the first hit of well whatever you
yourself want to start start with all
right we'll
just a little clean give it a little
clean it up a little bit
there all right you got your back a
little bit there we
go oh yeah that's a nice press it looks
stable as what would you like I'll take
the first one um larger small or medium
medium's good yeah we're going to do
three in a row so three medium should
give us a good little
Vibe little head space and then that was
which one train rack train rack so train
rack we were going to put together with
Clementine Clementine yeah all
right oh my darling Oh My Darling Oh My
Darling Clementine I've not hit this one
myself yet I'm just going to do a nice
little dip not going in heavy
heavy oh thank you come
on Clementine for the win d420 K going
in deep on the train rack Ros and dipon
Clementine tpine
profile hard to lose on that one for
sure through the Klein with the clean
drop down and the denil and the puking
beagle puking beagle sorry I always like
to say his name puking because it sounds
weird to say puking
but it's the name of the company right
nice staple raws and real pull and
snap how was that Clementine that was
very
nice wow that just gets the this part of
my head right away just kind of there's
a pressure not a heavy pressure like a
headache but like my brain's been hit
with something with something that's not
part of it here it's very nice I'm going
to join you do
that yeah I did a clean on the on the
bad boy cuz uh I know how you love your
clean rigs to smoke out of and clean
drop downs and you know especially when
we're hitting oh my God isn't that nice
oh i f
just wow you know what was nice about it
true which is a surprise to
me clementine was
incredible it was the undertone Taste of
the train wreck that I got on my tongue
and my throat a few seconds after
nice that's really nice dude train wack
Clementine I would say that's a that's a
good combination you know what's going
to be nice is when we have it set up so
that the we have our vapor lounges at
our nightclubs day clubs whatever
smoking areas that that we allowed to do
this like so legally that it's just like
going to a a winery or whatever listen
it'll be when you don't have to bring
can you imagine as a Wine Drinker having
to bring your
glass how absurd that is so it's like
imagine you get to the point where you
go to your joies and you order your food
but afterwards you order up your mother
ship it's like you know what I want to
hit a Taurus sub n in if you don't mind
like it would be a cool thing the way
these places have money invested in wine
and wi and alcohol
culture get it invested into cannabis
culture because we we're a legitimate
economy we're a legitimate Marketplace
man this economy [ __ ] would change
everything well look we did it anyway
you know Mothership exists regardless of
whether what about the places where
you're wine you can bring your own
bottles of wine yeah and pay corking
fees and pay a corking Fe which I would
pay to bring my own rosins or my own
turs I would pay that fee but I don't
want to have to bring my glass I really
love the idea of these you
know a proper high-end Lounge that can
offer you really nice glass do little
big I was going to say that's a little
bit little bit small
that one's
nice good job I was going to ask you to
do that didn't have to you're
professional well i' had a little
influencing on that from the
professional see when I step by the line
you don't see the stuff off camera guys
he beats the [ __ ] out of me oh yeah I'm
violent
violent is Wayne Brady gonna have to
choke a
[ __ ] [ __ ]
those turbs were
sizzling very nice I got very very
nicely medicated off that first dab I
mean right away I did a lot of shoveling
yesterday melting
snow melting snow shoveling the worst
kind very very heavy how was that Citrus
Galore blew your lung
out what's going on with the flavor
profile there
get a big enough rip I think it might
have been a little bit too big I thought
so
too I I can do it two Big's better than
two small let's be honest that was
uh it's amazing how the turps are that
Citrus on those turps Jack Frost bro and
then the Citrus undertone of that
Locomotion the New York diesel train R
cross that very caloes if you haven't
had
these C it's very Calo orange like you
wouldn't believe very orange and uh
wow what a [ __ ] treat that
was I love how the turpins are so strong
and then the raw and hit you afterwards
like you taste both profiles both
flavors to together and
separate wow yeah there's that Calo
coming in that New York City Diesel
flavor at the very end of it right at
the end of it
actually in my cough it's not just in my
mouth tast it back here it's
cool and I love when we get together and
hit
turps that was well usually when we get
together we're hitting turps ring or
hash and pigging out almost seemed like
a bowl of of of
Bud like more than a hash or oil or an
extraction it seemed like a full bouquet
of flowers that I just somehow and I
can't say that I vaporized it or or
smoked it cuz it doesn't taste like that
it tastes like I ate it like I just ate
a couple of ounces of
Bud we the [ __ ] stuck in my teeth but so
I can see it dare we uh finish it off
off with a lavender stunk and an OG of
course I mean we might as well I'm not
going to hit this one as large as I did
the last one I me cuz I just don't think
it's necessary you know the one thing
the one thing I'll say it's always fun
to hit big rips but I will say that
while filming and trying to make each
scene happen especially with TP dips I'm
always happy with a small to medium one
one day we will have to film a show
where we just take monster ones and and
the show will be about how destroyed we
get my very first I think debut into the
YouTube world oh yeah that was that rip
Jesus Christ yeah just I know that was
nuts see that's the thing you start we
were excited about dabbing we were all
like let's just blow our heads off oh I
[ __ ] shotgunned her man double barrel
oh I know I've uh good I've seen
it all right so lavender skunk our final
Blue River tpine cultivar these are all
available actually right now at Blue
River extracts. CA um Blue River
extract.com Tony's company is down right
now but um they they should be up again
soon so if you're in Canada give us a
shout TS
turps oh yeah that lavender skunk is
very unique it reminds me of a bud I
can't remember remember the name of but
I absolutely grew it no I know I did too
that's what it reminds me of just that
it's so trippy Bud that we were touched
that that that history of our history
was you know it's still there in the
memory of the smell and whatnot but too
bad we didn't have the gc's and we
weren't testing for the turpine profiles
I would have loved to have known that
information back then and like IM it be
now well that's just it
third rip d420 K TP rip bong rip TP dip
[ __ ]
yeah coming at you
live through the mothership
clim oh my as soon as I start exhaling I
don't even want to Exhale the whole
thing cuz I want to just keep it in my
mouth chewing on it like a [ __ ] good
piece of food crazy taste
right [ __ ] yeah plus
plus the OG Kush rosin is strong it's
narcotic like wouldn't you say that
combination that was your fa just wait
just wait you're going to you're going
to [ __ ] no you just wait you're going
to pee a little bit of pee there just a
driblet y wow what a taste
this got me a little excited I'm not
going to lie I'm G that uh impress the
hell out of me the after taste as soon
as I started exhaling my to I could
taste yeah that there's something unique
in there I would say that
there's something in there that we don't
see very often there's a tpine in there
that's I bet you they're going to say is
like oh that's a rare one rare one or
one that's found in a much lower Ratio
or even more possible is that it's a
combination of two or three common ones
in a unique ratio wow
yeah deep deep in the rabbit hole deep
in the rabbit hole we're going deep boys
so listen I'm completely well no not
completely fried I'm really quite
enjoyably medicated I would say oh yeah
but hungry medicated I'm hungry so we're
going to head down here we're on the
drive eclectic place all sorts of cool
little restaurants and stuff and we're
going to pick one bring you with us
briefly we won't be filming a ton in
there cuz it's kind of awkward and weird
but we will definitely show you the
place on the outside and show you some
of the food that we order and uh then
we'll be finding ourselves another spot
to have a nice big session cuz we got
more turps to try so
let's do that all right buddy all right
we are
outside walking over to marchello's this
cool Italian pizzeria place that has
this uh oh huge Woodfire Pizza Oven big
big wood fire pizza oven yeah it's oh
hey what's up I don't know who that was
but she's waving to us and she's excited
I think she thinks she was on film she
probably did yeah she doesn't understand
I'm holding the camera backwards but
that's cool that's okay I liked it so
yeah marel for some pizza and some
salads cross here boom get hit yeah get
it all on camera [ __ ] right iy BC I
the winess you ever go to the red
burrito no the red burrito Che no I
haven't all right I like the uh I don't
know it's just I don't know there's
something about it that I haven't tried
it yet right maybe that it's just too
accessible yeah just too right on the
corner burritos I don't trust it almost
I've never really like burritos anyways
I like hard to get to
places I like the good places yeah and
I'll go to wherever they are to where
how to get to them because that's the
whole trip man that's what I like about
to ride in the motorbike in the summer
used to be the stripper bars now it's
destination to the restaurants beautiful
and places to dab yep awesome yeah all
right well we're coming up here all
right so we are here at
marchello's boom
excellent
excellent very good good for two just
for two y all right I think there's room
for us there is there is you guys didn't
have a reservation or anything did you
can I film that oven with my video
camera oh yeah for sure go for it yeah
it looks so beautiful okay thank
you yeah so check out this incredible
oven they have in this place now that is
a pizza oven
that is so
cool beautiful really really well done
on that oven for sure that yeah it's
pretty cool put you right here clean
that table Pretty Good Vibes in marel
wouldn't you say Valerie our waitress
pretty on point pretty cool nice big
open area the oven is obviously pimp
we'll get our pizzas going in there once
we order and I'll make sure I film him
making the pizza a little bit get it in
there and in the meantime we're going to
check out these menus
[Music]
Caesar salad in the house with some
fresh Pacha bread Pacha
bread this shit's going to be
delicious at this pizza p what do you
think of that so we did mozzarella and
TR toy off with one bread I'm like what
no I was cooking up your bread there
there you go right there and I brought
the Verde dip too for for dipping just
try it out see if you like it too cool
thank you okay you're welcome enjoy
different cheeses yes so see which one
okay and you guys got extra
plate all right freshly back from some
delicious
food going to uh going to hit some turps
I guess maybe uh should I may I maybe
would have to hit that lavender skunk
one last time because I'm not taking any
home well sure none of that's going home
[ __ ] man problem bud do you like that
one too much yeah I liked it too much I
had to take off sound I to B it he's
like sorry dude I liked it what it taste
the the smell and The
Taste literally brings you that brought
me that
nostalgic feeling back of of like hold
on of being in in in one of the first
grows that I learned how to cut clones
and seeing these strains and everything
like that that were just phenomenal
that's it took me way back wow I almost
got it on that one I almost saw it I saw
like it was weird bro I went back in
time I went through some doors I saw a
glimpse of a face I I was
like that's what I mean nostalgic that
is just that's what these things do
these these tpping profiles trigger
memories
that have been long forgotten
about but you also get that feeling of
being back then it's just [ __ ]
it's impressive stuff this
[ __ ] I guess it's
uh it's a bit of a time
traveler little
dab what are we dabbing on
well I think you should hit the star dog
it's the newest one that I just loaded
up I mean you've already hit um the Jack
Frost the lavender and the Clementine
and
stardog is the last one I didn't have
another Dabber to fill this one up so
we'll have another we'll have to find
one more clean Dabber at one point but
uh I do have one
on in the meantime let's get you star
dog up oh my
gosh perfect thank you so much there's a
little rip for
you this Tangi and then our last one is
Tangi so how's that for a nice little
end
flavor can't go wrong with
that all right Tangi
up they can balce those little
caps keep that right
there how's that
star
hog it's nice subtle yeah it's not a not
as a citrusy flavory it's a it's coming
in late yeah but it's
cushy it's got some deep tones I can
smell it I'm about to hit it right now
actually you know what that
cushy earthy dirty but like good dirt
taste yeah that's what smell stank
[ __ ] earthy that's what I taste now
it reminded me when I opened it a little
bit of the Long Valley Kush in the sense
of how just
utterly deep it is in those
tones so let me try a little star dog
with a little rosin rip because why not
[ __ ] yeah
[ __ ] good smoking good smoking this
stuff yeah there it
is almost no taste on the exhale on my
second
breath get that earthy
gness yeah it's quite different quite
different I I think if I did an evening
for people of
tpin it would be important to start off
with the subtler ones earlier yeah and
hit with the really powerful dessert
ones I mean I guess it's why we don't
eat the chocolate lava cake for the
entree or for the appetizer well I'd
like to ask the world why why not why
not dessert first well we just expl we
just explained exactly why with the
tpping metaphor which is that if you
blow your senses with Jack Frost Tangi
Clementine lavender skunk and then you
go and hit subtle ones you're like [ __ ]
I it just wasn't quite as like mhm I
think that it's I think that we would
have gotten more flavor from them prior
to say although that star dog is strong
in my mouth right now like very strong
and that rosin we were hitting is sfog
Hash Rosen oh FR OG yeah kind of a Fran
ogre good mixture with the star dog but
uh what do you say to Tangi my friend
well I say let's [ __ ] do her should
we Tangi up and Tang up I love breakfast
for dinner I do breakfast for dinner a
lot I do it a lot yeah now I don't do
dinner for breakfast that
much I honestly for breakfast I don't I
it's happened a few times well maybe
maybe left over Chinese food that's
exactly fried up heat it up for
breakfast like usually put an egg in it
too right make it
breakfasty it's always sort of
breakfasty I love breakfast for dinner
breakfast for dinner yes I used to love
this bacon gravy my buddy's mom used to
make break bacon gravy and pancakes for
dinner interesting was one of my faves
that's a good one yeah it was
good all right let's get this Tangi in
it want to try this other rosin this
Ultra rosin 25 micron stuff yeah also
very nice gold color to it it looks very
golden very golden
color it's pretty I think it'll dab
nicely with a little turn and that's 25
micron bubble hash yeah Rosen pressed
into that
right it's good now is now we were
talking talking earlier and about the
kushes and all the different resin size
heads and all that sort of stuff and
what were the best and what are the
worst and you know but really there is
no best or worst no it just depends on
the strain and it depends on the person
and what they like yeah cuz some people
I mean like with anything right some
people want their steak well done and
some people want their steak medium rare
they're very different I don't eat steak
period but I know the people that do are
very pissed off when it doesn't come the
way they want it so let's just say
people are
particular
no so that was the
Tangi tped up on the MK Ultra hash
rosin very
nice very nice I'm going to dessert down
too that uh little dessert that makes
you just close your eyes I noticed you
did that I
think just wow I really like that those
ones that do that to me that close my
eyes sure now it's beautiful what I was
getting at with the the different Micron
sizes would it be more sativa likes that
are the smaller heads that are really
good or is I I think the generalization
has not been as easy to find I think
that because originally the first time I
saw really small heads was from sativas
or narrow Leaf drug cultivars grown
outdoors in Australia under a Tropical
Sun and the 25 and 45 Micron hash were
like the best it was like that's where
they got the most and that's where it
was the best and it was like the
intensity of the Sun the heads were just
smaller but they were still killer still
killer still proper I didn't see that in
sativas that were grown indoors they got
bigger so I wouldn't say that it's SA
saas I would say that it was some
sativas that were grown in a tropical
Sun that I you know what I mean cuz
that's basically what happened I started
I started saying to people I think it's
from like sungrown sativas and that
dropped to it's sativas sativas have
smaller heads and indicas have larger
heads and I was kind of like as the
years went on I was like you know I'm
not sure that's really super I think we
might be generalizing a lot in that b
too much yeah maybe it and maybe
creating the wrong assumptions that
people are like oh I don't even use that
bag cuz uh you know I'm do I'm using
just these certain cultivars and I
shouldn't get anything and it's like no
no no just use all the bags every time
it'll teach you what you're doing and
it'll show you what's going on you won't
be able to know without you know all the
different bags because I have people all
the time contact me and say
uh oh I I I you know I don't usually get
that much in this bag and all of a
sudden I started getting a lot it's like
did you change the cultivar yeah yeah I
was using a different well that's cuz
they're all different man you know yeah
I bet you've heard some of the [ __ ]
stupidest
questions
but I know know I know you answer them
answer them nicely but my good some are
just probably just like Are you
seriously [ __ ] asking me that yeah
really that
was an amazing
rip to do another
rip lav SC I had one it's [ __ ] it was
delicious it's [ __ ] that Tangi was
super fire though yes absolutely for how
light it smelled in the
jar cuz when you have a lot of it it
smells really strong but just in 10
drops I didn't think it smelled that
strong I even opened the other jar to
smell it it's there it's just the taste
is I really like that
taste tpine
fiend going in for the TP dip there he
goes finishing it off I got to get back
it's starting to get dark outside but
always a pleasure to come into the City
and rip it up with d420 K blaz some
bowls TP dips bong rips [ __ ] yes and uh
eat some
food get out on the drive and check it
out [ __ ] yeah [ __ ] yeah right on
awesome guys thanks for watching Bubble
man's world we'll see you next time