[Music]
take it one day at a time and fulfill
your dreams
please
always remember your theme
all when things get hard and lean
hold on to your faith and fulfill your
beam
[Music]
Stay Together
just like in the days of patient
remember
[Music]
he's coming from
believe in yourself my friend
[Music]
a little table action yeah it's so
perfect dude yeah this is ridiculous
I know it makes it pretty funny for
hanging out in here
it's hilarious
I wanted to get one I was so close to
getting it but someone bought it before
me on like uh the whistle buy and sell
there the Craigslist yeah one of those
little outdoor projectors and I was like
wanting to like carve out a little like
TV in the wall and then have the little
projector here it'd be so funny if like
someone to come in and they'd just hang
and watch in the show oh my God just for
a laugh and a video of that clip what do
you see in here but that's because we're
in the dark
we got the uh
Carta II
we're gonna go one two three four five
one two three got our colors going on in
here so now we can see a little bit
better
nice that's rad
oh yeah
it's really great hash is going to be
mad cold and snappy
yeah as expected I'm gonna have to
kind of gently
gently convince it to come out of the
oh yeah I did a pretty good job there
nice little derb here we'll hold the
light in
so you can actually see the derb
we're going down buddy oh that's it this
piece came off
something's going on eh
all right perfect we've got two derbs
stoked to be having derbs in your igloo
I'm glad you're here to be
sharing some more dabs in a new Igloo
new location it's wonderful so we'll
drop that into the Magna Carta
close that
and then it's as simple as one two
that'll cycle through the temperature so
it's at 160 right now and it's climbing
189 to 12 220 230 it'll get up to like
450 and then the one on the right side
yeah we'll turn on the timer yeah I was
gonna say the timer on that cool yeah
this looks really cool in the igloo here
I'm not gonna lie
I usually give it a couple seconds to be
at temperature before I start ripping
oh my God is that good
yeah
that smells really nice candy still
learning The Sweet Spot you know not to
pull too hard
to make sure I keep keep it going for at
least a minute
it does taste like candy
smell
I don't do enough Igloo rips in life
so this feels great
Whistler
for the win
good
that's how small that was yeah the stool
whoa it looked bigger over there yeah no
it pulled right up so I can put it into
my like backpack
okay here
's we're all rocked him out dude yeah
Q-tip
to cleanliness it up
cleanliness is Next to Godliness as
Skunk Man Sam would say there we go
keeping it fresh well I notice you keep
a very clean Igloo yeah as I tried to
maintain the best of the abilities
let's do a little Airbnb
to make sure it's clean for the next
tenants coming in did you crush an
Airbnb up here the igloo Airbnb
I can't even imagine
you'd be crushing it
got a permit for it
it's almost like a little bit of snow
dropped in it uh
yeah I could hear it crackling like
water oh I gotcha
time to put in more hash
and one to it give it the old one too
there's a little hole in there you can
carb too and it's a weird Sweet Spot
yeah once it vibrates yeah it'll be
ready to go again
oh yeah you're doing it you're doing it
man
this guy's a quick learner
this is just so cool dude
a whole other room over there
it's like a slow sipping
more than a blast ripping although that
was a pretty good rip
I got a nicer from that why was that
ever tasty
oh yeah it's still on the palate
strawberry banana from DNA genetics all
new flavors coming in courtesy of
concentrated X
nice to have some diverse that's full
metal bubble wow there it's not rosin
that's full melt bubble he's a awesome
dude
loose temperature now but you can hit
the button twice again to get it up to
town
yep that was it
that was it
you guys could get a better idea of just
how ridiculous this is because it is
absolutely ridiculous
okay
wow dabs in the igloo
dude as if you have a giant pillar in
your [ __ ] igloo
psychological support
yes exactly it helps certain people have
okay let's talk about that certain
people right away have a thought that
this thing is going to collapse
do you I don't feel that at all no but
teach their own with their fears
psychologically with being in a confined
space I can understand how some people
would feel yeah yeah they don't want to
be travel zone they don't want to be
trapped I get it but it's like do you
feel trapped no because I spent all my
time digging it too
it's structure to have integrity to
support and yeah yeah it's just like
once all this solidifies it's like it's
bulletproof yeah for real
all right well we're gonna head outside
after a couple more dabs
spots
[Music]
for that sprinkling oh yes
yes
[Music]
twinkling send me