[Music]
hey what's going on everybody BC
bubbleman here sitting out on my
deck got a plane flying overhead you
might be able to hear uh just wanted to
do a quick unboxing video I got a little
box from my good friends at puffco got a
shout out to uh Chelsea and Jolly Roger
for this absolutely incredible kickdown
um we're going to be having Jolly Roger
come on to Hash church here in the very
near future and he's going to be telling
us a little bit about the new projects
uh projects that they're working on the
new products that they've released re uh
released
recently and I want to just open this
box so we can see what's going on um
with uh what Chelsea sent
me oh
boy all right so this just showed up the
other day at my door looks like it's
looks like it's a good amount of goodies
here for sure so first and
foremost we got the
new Peak Pro brand new looks like the
blue version um might as well open her
up and check it out do a true
unboxing
um you know been loving my uh my
electronic devices been loving my puffco
I've got the puffco peak Pro I've got
the puffco peak I've got the
proxy and a few other products from
puffco uh pipes and whatnot that they
sort of fit into so yeah oh here we go
couple of nice little stickers on the
side they want you to cut sort of
verification of like how you know your
product is brand new these little there
we
go these little stickers oh look at that
just like just like the OG I've always
kind of thought this was a very unique
and original case I've never seen any
other case anything like this uh very
easy for sort of throwing it into a
backpack and it's just durable and
strong you don't have to worry about the
pipe itself on the inside having any
problems well that is pretty slick I'm
not going to lie and it looks like they
put in that looks like a an a 3D XL Bowl
to me I could be wrong um but it really
looks like it no I would say that is the
3D XL Bowl it must just be the standard
that comes with the pipe now nice little
handheld unit nice color um I got to
give it up to puffco
for normalizing hashish use and live
hash rosin nor normalizing it for the
masses because let's be honest the
majority of people don't have access to
dab rigs they don't have the ability to
just like you know torch up a a quartz
Banger um so they've been doing an
incredible job with bringing access to
sort of regular people that want to get
into dabbing or want to try it as an
experience so beautiful beautiful little
piece right there nice little glass on
the inside there 3dxl b feels great in
the hand I'm super stoked about this I'm
definitely going to have a mad puffco
session at one point in time that may be
a part of this video it may not be a
part of this video I might just get the
unboxing part one done uh and then we'll
do some other videos uh in regards to um
you know showing it being used so comes
with the charger cord right here and
then they also give you uh a few little
Q-tips little four four pack of Q-tips
and that's just uh for those of you that
have never had a puffco before uh
they've got a cool little
um a cool little insert that fits right
into the bottom right here so this
little piece pops open they used to have
a Dabber in there as well oh there's one
on the other side and there's the Dabber
so I've never seen that I've always only
seen one of those little inserts uh get
the most out of your Peak Pro download
puffco connect and unlock deep
customization like VAP control Precision
temp settings mood lights Etc so when we
have the session um we will get into
that we will download the app and make
sure that we uh that we get into uh a
showing that so there we go for that and
put that right back in there actually
that went the wrong way it's very
specific way fits much better like that
then right over there all right let's
see what else we got
here puffco
actually this is not oh I see it's got
to go in there exactly as well I'll tell
you if there's a wrong way to do it I'll
do it before I do the right way I'll
almost always do the wrong way comment
if you're like me and you always do it
the wrong way before you do it the right
way uh trying to get this moved over a
bit so it's not blocking and then I'm
going to pull some of the other things
out here that were gifted so let's not
delay
you get out what you put in so this is
the new puffco pivot and I'm not going
to lie I've been very very very excited
to try this one it looks like it really
produces some interesting Vapor it's got
a really nice size um atomizer on on the
inside and
apparently it is small it is not a big
unit at all so see if I can uh use my
nails to get into this little
guy you think I would have uh
well you think I would have maybe
brought some scissors or something but
sticker comes off pretty easy so there's
that didn't rip the package I don't know
why but the OCD part of me is always
bothered when I take these little Moon
stickers off uh and they sh and they you
know take off the label or they take off
uh part of the package so that is not
the case here except it did a little bit
on the bottom there so this is uh the
pivot let's see what we got here oh
there's another one on the top
interesting all right well we'll get
that off as well a true unboxing video
to show you exactly what you're going to
be dealing with when you get yours I
believe they sold my goodness I believe
they sold out in a big way when they
released this product so I'm just going
to kind of put it back together I opened
it a little greasily so when you open it
up on the front you probably want to
hold it like this so you can pull that
off the instructions are right on the
top they've got their QR bar code as
well so once again enter here in about
four different languages and then boom
would you look at that that is a nice
little unit little bit of plastic on top
that we'll pull off
here W that is tight on there too very
nice feels amazing in the hand I'm not
going to lie it feels really amazing
there's the battery aspect to it it just
connects really quick to the battery the
battery is ultra light it almost feels
like nothing it's uh it almost feels the
same weight as the atomizer so we got
that and then you just pop that open
it's a nice little silicone piece that
stops over the top and you can see
there's your big atomizer right there
not quite big enough to fit my pinky in
but certainly a bigger atomizer than
I've ever seen on any um you know type
of handheld small device such as this so
that is incredible I guess inside the
box they've got more Q-tips and another
um USBC for charging little bit of
desicant there as well I'll get rid of
so that's nice just fits in the box
right in the
bottom that is really really nice
looking I can't wait to get these pivots
going you know I was watching all of the
the advertisements that they had for it
was kind of saying look we know you
hardcores are out there I mean they they
puffco understands that their products
aren't going to be an exact replication
of a dab out of a quarts Banger what
they're trying to do is that's the bar
and they're getting up to that bar and I
remember the first puffco pen I tried it
was a solid pen the battery lasted for
damn near forever but it certainly
didn't um deliver the hit that say the
puffco delivered when that came out you
know a couple years later
uh and then even more so when the puffco
pro came out the peak Pro uh and then
even more so when they released the 3dxl
bowl uh I remember the first time I hit
the proxy I I heard Roger say uh or it
might have even been Chelsea uh say it's
a it's a sipper not a ripper and I saw a
lot of people using these tools like
they were that very thing I saw people
loading up enormous dabs hitting it you
know leaning back so that the the the
the atomizer wasn't straight anymore it
was at an angle so now you've got rosin
that's being pulled in through this
suction going into the atomizer holes at
the top that's supposed to be for airf
flow and I saw a lot of people ruin
their units and then complain that they
weren't working and I've been guilty
myself of ruining electronics and
complaining that they didn't work I've
also become aware that that my using of
the piece of electronics
incorrectly is what's responsible for
breaking it more often than not my last
puffco with the p with the XL 3D XL Bowl
lasted for my God it must have been a
year and a half and I probably put a
thousand plus dabs through that thing
I'd have to go online and check exactly
what the number was but I put a lot of
rips through that thing before I finally
had problems with the atomizer now I'm
cleaning the atomizer right now I'm
finally cleaning it the proper way not
just cleaning the outside I'm soaking it
in alcohol I'm going to dry it properly
uh and then I'm going to see uh you know
what uh if I can get it back and working
this one's really nice I believe this
one is slate so there's the color
difference right there they did send me
two of these so I'll show you the
other unit right next to it the black
unit you can see there's a very very
substantial difference in those two
units right there so I can't tell you
how excited I am to start hauling on
these especially for snowboard season I
used to carry my puffco with me I've
even carried carried the proxy with me
I've carried other units with me that
have glass on them and one of the things
I'm looking most forward to uh this
snowboard season in particular is to not
have to carry glass on the mountain but
still be able to get a rip uh as James
from puffco said the other day where I
can get my head straight where I get my
head the way I want to get it so really
excited about the two PE uh pivots
obviously excited about the puffco peak
Pro uh and then they also sent me this
little go little little dude the glass
adapter uh 3D chamber included so this
is a little adapter that allows you to
hook up to one of the pivots through the
top uh and put it into a a pipe through
a a I believe it's a glass uh grommet
we'll see here in a second because
obviously everyone has differ size glass
grommets there's 188 there's 144 most of
us nowadays are using like tens and
eights and even fives I think I saw in
bestest tedes pop out a Fiverr the other
day which was incredibly small we put
those over there so we can kind of get a
little bit more actually I think this
one will go real nice there these ones
will go real nice there there we go so
let's see what we've got
here I think it's just
a yeah one of these kind of releases
we'll just have to it's very nice tight
fit it doesn't just fall out uh By Any
Means you can see how tight that is and
once again on the top are your
instructions as well as your QR code and
here we
go this is nice so this is almost like a
a composite it's got the battery
connector which is
interesting I'm interested to see how
that's going to work and then uh it's
got the 14 it looks like that might even
be a 10 and this might be a 14 so I
guess what you can do is you can pull
these out right I'll show you that real
quick so you can pull that that right
out it goes in very easily and it pulls
out very nicely it's like a silicone
mold and then you can put in your your
10 so that's more than likely the one
that's going to fit my pipe right
there and then let's just see what it
looks like with one of these cuz I'm
mildly confused I
guess okay so how do you do that you
just go like
that so now that's the
battery I'm
interesting just did to figure this out
I don't know why I can't figure it out
it can't be through just the battery
because you got to be able to take a rip
unless
ah mind blown so I'm sitting here going
well okay like I get when you take this
off you have the battery but this this
is the coil this is your atomizer this
is this is where you get your hit so I
was super confused when I just saw that
and I thought okay so you add your
battery to it what what's that going to
do where's the actual
rep right there there's your actual
secondary Bowl inside the little L with
the glass piece so you just put your dab
right in there you close it up you set
it all your settings are with one single
button um which is really nice because
it's got this bar of color that I saw on
their ads that it looks just so slick I
got to give them a shout out for how
slick of a product they have released
here so love the ability to Interchange
the different sizes of um mail um pieces
mail glass pieces and that's just so
cool I can drop that right into my pipe
and at the Times where say my denail
Universal heater is not heating up or my
I don't have it turned on and maybe I
have no gas in my torch I'm not I'm
moving away from the torch and I think
one of the things that puffco has done
incredibly is creating an atmosphere
where one can can can dab live hash
rosin or full melt bubble without the
use of a torch and you got to admit for
a lot of people that torch freaks people
out so I am really really
loving uh this particular particular
piece right here I'm just going to take
it all apart and put it back together
the way it was so it fits in the
packaging nice and
easily and we'll put this back to that
you could they just fit together so
nicely everything closes so nicely that
is extremely small I mean that is I can
almost hide that in my hand completely
if I take the bowl off I can hide the
battery pretty much perfectly in my hand
that's a nice little Ripper that beats
any pen I've ever felt in my my hand
right there so I'm really looking
forward to uh hitting some of that
concentrated X full melt bubble out of
that I'll definitely be playing around
with the puffco pivot glass adapter big
shout out to Chelsea for having all of
this stuff sent out to me you've always
been so kind and so generous and uh
taken such great care of me so uh it's
my honor to use the products that you
guys send me and turn people on to them
uh my daughter works at a dispensary
just down the street in Horseshoe Bay at
happy Isle and they actually sell the
puff Co product so that's pretty cool um
let's open the final thing which is the
travel case we'll open the travel case
and we'll see what's going on here it's
good that I have this
one somewhat of I wouldn't call it a
nail but I have a little bit of a nail
right on my middle finger that's the one
that's allowing me to open all of this
stuff so just make sure I've got all the
Plastics put away all right we've got a
nice little sleeve here that the p the
case just slides out I love the Retro
look of the case this reminds me of some
old school like pencil case that I had
in like
1979 uh pops open real nice and easy and
as you can
see just has a spot I'm guessing for
everything so I guess we're going to
have to see I guess the main part is um
for jars and then I guess right here
yeah that looks like that so you kind of
got your spot right across the top that
you can put your uh your unit I'm
guessing that this might even fit
um it's hard to say I know if that fits
that like that or no getting to know all
this stuff I guess it probably fits the
adapter I could check be nice to have
the adapter in there as well not that I
I would need it but uh I mean honestly I
can tell for
myself um for the mountain especially I
mean for you know for cruising around on
uh that's pretty cool that damn near
fits so without the glass piece it
absolutely fits in here a little bit
kind of sort of sort of I guess you've
got that little piece right there so you
can kind of go like
that okay so there's that still more
room very cool very cool little case uh
fits probably like three or four jars
bars of your um of your hash which is
always
convenient and uh I got to say man good
job that you guys have done on this it's
really really nice equipment um I'm
hoping on getting a puffco code for you
guys but in the future uh in the future
where you can get maybe a little tiny
bit of a discount but in the meantime
just go head on over to puffco.com uh
and you can get any of these products
off of their website and uh I know some
people have been like oh I got a bad one
a long time ago and I didn't listen
they're an exceptional team they're
going to get back to you in regards to
their customer service uh if you have a
unit that's not working or something
went wrong with it definitely do
something about that get in touch with
them make sure that uh you let them know
because a company can't fix uh what you
don't let them know they need to they
need to be told they need to be you know
l in on the fact that something's not
working I know selling Bubble Bags over
the years
uh we've had some warranty issues and
the people who need to get those
warranty issues that reach out to us are
very happy the people who do not reach
out to us end up being pretty pissed and
sometimes I'll see them like five or 10
years down the road and they'll say yeah
I bought your bags and they one came
ripped or something or something
happened you know really we haven't had
many warranty issues since probably 15
years ago when there was this rubber
coating that the manufacture just
started putting onto the inside of the
nylon without telling us and eventually
over time that nylon that material would
chip off and come out and so we
warrantied all those bags over the years
so make sure if you do purchase a puffco
uh product that you give their customer
service a chance if something goes wrong
with it and if nothing goes wrong with
it well then just enjoy that piece of
equipment uh as often as you can as much
as you can uh and in the
meantime big thank you to Jolly Roger
and the puffco team thank you guys so
much I am literally going to go in my
house and start playing around with this
and tomorrow when the Sun rises again if
we get another blue sky day uh I will go
out of my way to making my way back to
you guys so that we can get uh get a
little puff puff going maybe even have
Johnny B come down we'll do a little
puff Wednesday in the
meantime the Sun is setting over the
Pacific Ocean it's a beautiful day here
on the West Coast of British Columbia
and uh thank you for watching and may
the full melt bless your
bowl sooner than later peace out
everybody