[Music]
well welcome to Puff Wednesdays Johnny
be's in the house and you have tuned
into bubble man's world so what's going
on in bubble man's world today first
things first I wanted to give you
sir your Apex swag bag from Sir
bird bird wow you know
what I was watching this so now um now
now we have we finally have matching
hats yes considering John and I own
about 20 of the same t-shirts oh wait a
second
21 I I
might 21
thanks for this for the T-shirt bird
jeez I feel like I'm kind of in the dark
here I got to almost move forward a
little bit and have a puff you know what
that's the problem we haven't popped so
you know the quality of the Apex pen as
you've already hit it but uh I think
you'll enjoy that just to have as your
you know what this is I'm super stoked
because I did uh spend the day with um
new DK 420 and Sarah Sunday there are
last actually was on BC day and we
puffed this thing hard all day
then the next day we ran into you again
we puffed hard
again and then a few days later I ran
into Mark again and it was still puffing
the battery hadn't quite died I was
super stoked even I had it for 5 days
before I did I was amazed so you know
what this is awesome I got a full kit
it's got everything in there of course I
got the pen I got the the Dome I also
got another oil Dome I guess that will
be for nicotine um I'm only puffing hash
so that's why I won't exchange your pink
one for another one oh that's okay I got
the charger of course we got the battery
that's going to last four or 5 days four
or five days and the herb chamber so you
can vaporize some of your herb that's I
didn't even know I had an herb chamber
so you know what I'm definitely going to
be checking out this pen um I'll
definitely uh you know be puffing on
some herbs something that you don't do
but I do so I'll maybe I'll see how this
works out I'll get back to you about it
and uh we're always talking about
looking for an herb
pen sweet yeah
dude very kind of Mr bird
and of course the next the next Apen
Apex pen giveaway uh I won't be doing
through Facebook I know a lot of you
didn't like that I apologize that uh I
certainly had no malicious intent when
uh when choosing Facebook as the means
to figure out the contest but what we're
going to do for the next contest will be
to guess the weight of a pile of hash
that I will post in the video
so um yeah awes but you got your pen I'm
stoked you got a nice bronze one there
with the yellow 73 well you know what
it's my favorite silicone chamber got an
extra silicone chamber in there extra
charger green one here I'm definitely
going to have to
um well I'm going to have to crust some
watermelon over some screens to put this
new Apex pen at one point yeah well
we'll get to that what I wanted to laugh
about was back to the T-shirt thing cuz
I know cuz you mentioned something about
the T-shirt yeah and he's got his
Barcelona t-shirt on we were in
Barcelona t-shirt shopping together a
couple of months back maybe even six
months back I don't know it was in
February so wherever it was March
February yeah um anyway it reminded me
that uh I still have videos to edit from
Barcelona so the next one will be number
eight which will be a visit that we take
to go visit Javier for medical seeds but
before that we found the video of John
myself and
jibs we thought it was Puffs puff
Wednesday and we started to do a video
and then our friend reminded us that
it's not even it's Tuesday today not
Wednesday not today today but back
months ago when we were in Spain and so
um we've got that clip it's a nine
minutter why don't we let them watch it
I I think you guys can get a laugh of
this one all right welcome to not puff
Wednesdays with bubble man John and jibs
here in Barcelona Barona I guess we
thought it was puff Wednesdays we were
going to like do it up and have a show
and uh then our friend Jazelle who's
from Barcelona off camera hi
gelle she uh she said John's telling her
we're going to film puff Wednesday and
she's like why you puff every day and
yeah she kind of reminded us that it's
Tuesday
so oops we got the carve cap on that bad
boy it's smell nice though no I'll go
get
it I'll go get it while you guys
puff uh we've had the pleasure of uh
finding a lot of beautiful hash here
meeting a lot of nice people while here
in Barcelona I agree like I have to say
you know like for the most
part I guess I would call us somewhat
pot snobs hash snobs for sure we like
the certain level of quality jelle's
laughing at us on camera understatement
is to say the least but um people have
had some really nice stuff I mean even
really nice hash even if it's not the
the best melt on the this particular
stuff I love the color love the texture
great
it's just nice smoking some different
hash this is exotic hash we're hitting
right now I'm not sure if this is the HQ
mix or the Africanized or the super
silver there's three of them that were
red you know the Shish berries were
white but these three were red I got the
Shish and red hatch is something in
Canada and in the states that we
necessarily don't get to encounter very
often at least myself personally very
true so it's really nice to see the
different resins the different genetics
and enjoy just enjoy them all around
well I'll tell you when I saw the
Africanized bubble and the fact that it
was red I I believed it you know what I
mean like if it would have looked like
the Shish Berry or any other normal hash
I would have been less INRI by well for
sure you know it's like you can put a
name on something and make it exotic but
it doesn't really make it exotic you
know th this is what makes it
exotic I was told this was the
strongest and the fastest the shishu ber
was the most expensive on the menu as
well at35 a gram uh the Africanized
bubble came in at €20 a gram Super
Silver Haze was 30 I
believe
and the HQ I believe was H was 20 20
yeah the HQ mix was 20 there was 20 25
yeah it was all within you know a
reasonable range all great quality yeah
I mean considering the same price for
herb if you did the math even for their
cheapest her was $7 a gram their most
expensive was 11 if you do the math of
you know 10 G per gram of bubble herb to
Bubble you're looking at 100 plus dollar
70 to 100 plus dollar for a gram of hash
so we actually got it quite a bit
cheaper than if we would if we would
have bought the weed and made it into
the hat and they both understood that
there um David and Eduardo both were
like slow education you know the Spanish
people still have a very hard time
paying uh 20 or30 for a gram of hash you
have to understand the hash culture here
is from Morocco uh Morocco is literally
a Stones throw away from from this
country across the water and so a lot of
hashes comes over here average price for
Spanish Moroccan hash is about $3 a gram
they're mixing it in with their tobacco
and they're smoking spliffs with that
now imagine these young guys opening up
a beautiful place and showing people no
no no if you're going to smoke it smoke
it pure and in it's €30 a gr 10 times
the price that they they're used to
paying for hash not to mention they
can't really smoke it the same way and
it doesn't have the same taste and it
doesn't so these guys have an uphill
battle in my opinion but the fact of the
matter is fighting it head on the fact
that he was willing to take dried cured
beautiful buds and be willing to stick
them in ice and water to get that return
quality back and he said that Shish
Berry was beautiful he said he showed me
pictures of the nugs that he used to
make and we uh actually got to even try
some I got to try some of the herbit
it's just the same I photograph I I sat
with the breeder who bred all these
strains uh while I was photographing
them his name was Danny and spoke with
him a little bit about how he went about
he's been doing it for eight years now
how he went about breeding his strains
and selecting and whatnot and just was
all around impressed um the herb that he
had that he showed you in in the jars to
for us to run uh David the Russian guy
he basically told me it wasn't good
enough quality for a shop and I'm
looking at this Bud gr I could have
easily run this through this shop he
could have just easily put it on the
menu and run the whole kilo right out of
the shop but he was like and I was
impressed that he said this I couldn't
believe it he said you know it was
because of you you know we watch you and
we follow you and you're Perfection and
everything has to be the best and that's
why we want to wash this butt and not
sell it on our menu and I was like holy
smokes man that's like twice as much
money lost for him to for him to have
that kind of Integrity level of
dedication quality and the customers I
mean I'm con convinced but most people
choose profit over integrity and thus we
have what is called you know and I say
this in a way I don't call it the entire
scene but the BHO scene in Brackets
which is not Vern Phillips which is not
like the high-end guy k triome
technology these guys are actually doing
it on a level that's that's that's
unique and different I'm talking about
the
98% so these guys really impressed me in
that sense they only want ice hat Tony's
in the house Tony in the house all right
you're going to have a puff with us on
puff Wednesday Tony oh it'd be great if
Wells Fargo could communicate to
Spain Tony's having issues but we're
going to get his issues sorted out we're
actually on our way to Medical seeds
here right away we're going to go see
Javier who won uh first prize for the
best water hash uh at spannabis and I
believe he won also maybe a second for
his uh oil extraction but I I don't
quote me on what extract it is I don't
know if he made it with ISO or butane or
what his Sol was but water it no he won
a solvent one as well Javier won a
solvent and a solvent bu no kidding yeah
he won to
kill yeah just coincidentally the guys
that we sort of we sussing out and
feeling and and and feeling good about
meeting yeah they won like literally
five or six of the uh of the what 15
cups that were giv away they won is this
me or is this you okay I think you'd be
lining yourself up a hit and then just
take it no no all right man puffing in
Barcelona with jibs and
John now if he slips the other side over
he need out
we ninjaed them
up and you got the this is the AF think
that's AF
Afghan kind of give you a good Mo this
is the African
I and this
would yes and we also have super silver
haze uh HQ uh
mix which I I suggested to them that
they call Lucky Day cuz it's a canono
profile they'll never see again right
it's when they take certain hashes and
they mix them all together they call it
their HQ mix I said man you should call
that stuff Lucky Day because really
whoever buys that it's their lucky day
they're never going to find that canabo
profile ever again you know where you
mixed in like some OG and some sour and
some emerald and some Tahoe and you just
had a little bit of this other one that
you threw in some those quite frequently
end up becoming my favorite batches I
having to do it a lot myself listen
because that gets us to a point now
where we're not just extracting resins
now we're like Alchemists or something
and we're Mi exactly we're making our
own blends of cannaboids you know that
is cool particularly in the way of just
looking for a different relief you know
having all your different kinds and
that's great I like a lot of about 45 I
like the toilet it's 10:00 it's 10 11 oh
that the 11 get 11 get 11 things they
let us know every time what time it is
up here in Barcelona so I guess we're
going to finish off with a few more rips
and then we got to get jump in a cab and
go see Javier from medical seeds get
this day started uh I guess we're going
to wash some uh resin today sounds good
excellent all right guys well keep
watching I'll talk to you soon well I'm
kind of all for John's idea in which uh
we crush this herb that he put on the
screens in front of us I don't know
there's a boat 50 or 20 or 70 G yeah 70
grams
together so I don't know we got the
screen set up we got the 250 and the 180
which is the 90 and the 60
LPI so we have the 60 on top as it is
the smallest number it'll be the biggest
whole size if measured in in microns
that's how the LPI to
Micron uh it's confusing isn't it yeah I
no it's really good that actually
measuring this because even I've been
confused gets confused and I've taken
pictures of them backwards and I was
like yeah so thank you for explaining
this well we get into the Micron sizes
we know that microns are easy it's uh a
250 would be a big hole going down to a
180 to a 160 a 120 a 90 a 73 Etc if we
were doing bubble bags or whatnot um it
goes from bigger to smaller but lines
per inch works in the opposite way of
the actual size of the hole how many
lines per inch measures how big the hole
is and it generally works in the
opposite way so um you know 250 Micron
would actually be 60 lines per inch
whereas 180 Micron would be 90 lines per
inch and it continues down that way I
have the 70 Micron here which is 10 and
no sorry a 200 lines per inch as you can
see right there on the 200 200 so we're
going to take some of this herb and uh
yeah just get some quick hits let's go
for some quick hits get some quick hits
I love quick hits so this is the
watermelon that um basically that I just
finished trimming up and
uh
Hey and this is just the
easy get a couple quick hits God does
that smell good
[Music]
this is the nice little popcorn two
screen method
[Music]
here all right let's check we know this
method the way lighter you are the way
higher the the quality will be so uh
yeah nice and
light hold that up for one second so
that is one grade right there that's
down on this screen but remember if you
lift them both
simultaneously
gently very gently gently gently what
will be left on top of this screen will
should be of the highest quality you got
my brush there yes it is excellent so
let's see what we got got
here now that is some glistening stuff
oh yeah I mean ridiculously
so uh let's get the macro camera on that
right now all right so a little bit of
heada for Sir John here we go it
some full melt
trones just the head
is how's the taste on that well I do
know one
thing organically grown only low temps
low humidity tasty as hell that is that
is by far some of the most resin plant
that I've actually grown um had some bug
problems so I went down to 65° at night
70 during the day and uh with that we
got some amazing
resin definitely the turps are
definitely amazing too and Next Step a
little bit colder see what
happens let's make me a hit
100% I think this stuff is not dry
enough for this re real type of dry
sifting I think if you dry this out even
more you'll uh you'll find that it
really releases those heads well maybe
I'll have to do that we bone dry and
then I'll crush it over the screen and
see exactly what we get out of this
yeah
exactly that's probably good right
there oh guarantee it is going move it
right over grab that little butt up
there we put it right back where it was
oh that's all
right and
over and we are kind of a little bit
blocked by
the a little bit of contaminant floating
around there but I'm able to get that
out
all
right nice
little hit for
me here you
go here you
go camera down now we can even do the
the after this we do the flick the flick
the
flick got to remember the
flick oh yes the I love the brush it
seems to work very well def going to get
myself one there's the simple brush
that's all you
need all right this is just a little
mini hit but a hit
nonetheless we're going to get some
bigger hits out of this 100%
super tasty and
lovely all right let's give it a
flick the
flick now I can definitely see the
amount of contaminant on the screen
right
now and some very big
[Music]
heads see you got to get a
brush wow that actually looks really
nice and clean too well I think these
ones look even
nicer so that's definitely uh well well
let's get out the macro camera and see
there you go that's coming up okay we'll
do
it let's do do
[Music]
it going down it's going down
nice
taste Astro Boy TG
genetics can't go wrong with that uh
we've got 420 approaching
quickly we're going to do a little 420
dabad doodle you're going to pack your
your new Apex pen yeah I got it already
up and working it's getting all nice and
red in there I got some of the mku fresh
Frozen that I just
did of course you can oh you got yours
kind of sitting there too yeah mine's
just smoking away this thing's Wicked
like look at that look at me I'm just
like dumping hash
everywhere so just a little baby rib on
that
one do da
as a little dab as well what we got here
we got a two minute War couple minutes
couple minutes yeah all right says
48 so yeah we got a couple of nice hits
of the water melon I think uh we
realized that the bud was just not
really dry enough when you're when
you're this is a hard thing it's it's
hard enough to commit to put your buds
on a screen and and grind them all up
but the true commitment comes in will
you actually dry that bud right to bone
dry to the point where it's not really
going to be that good for puffing like
in in joints and stuff it's it's really
being committed to you're using it in in
hash making yeah well it looks like I'm
taking it back home I'm going to get a
nice and Bone and crisp dry I did that
last time let it hang for about a month
and this time well it was hot out and
then
uh I guess the bag started sweating a
little bit so back to the old screens I
got the same set sitting at home so I'm
definitely going to go home I'm going to
throw that popcorn on there and uh we're
going to Bone try that out and uh
basically come back with it all nicely
crushed maybe I'll film it and then I I
can uh come back here and I'll clean it
next puff Wednesday excellent yeah and I
still have to do the fresh floen of the
same strain in uh in the freezer so
that's 280 G of that and I think uh
because of the weather right now and it
being cool out and it's raining I think
I'm going to get to that batch maybe
tomorrow myself and uh I know you got
some backup yourself is there is my rag
next to you there I had my rag up on the
table here that's okay it's hard to
clean the Dabber without it this Dabber
gets nasty this thing like a too wow
that thing does hit like a
champ it is a a serious machine that's a
b bong brand I know right in your
pocket like K St in your pocket yeah
it's a very nice little thing we have
going on you can get dabbed the [ __ ] out
with a piece like
that well um wow I've been dabbing quite
hard right now remember in Spain when we
were dabbing out
yeah let's think about
that understand you're in the other
room ah you can
close dtfo dtfo DTF o
like apparently John has been dabbed the
[ __ ] out when's the last time you
traveled to Europe with your friends
John
dabed we're here at G13 Barcelona Club
and John Bell has been
dtfo yes ladies and gentlemen he has
been dabbed the [ __ ] out what do you
think about that jibs uh I think this is
pretty great I think this is the second
or third location of where he has
straight just passed out today now in
California everyone would be laughing
hard but here in Spain it's just called
Siesta
CEST see you later
[Music]