[Music]
Jesus can't believe it snowed yesterday
that was a little bit crazy wasn't it I
know like [ __ ] just that blue out of all
constant it's constant this whole
winter all right are we kind of even or
are we off I'm pretty sure we I think
we're good oh you you want you want it a
little bit I think we're good man I'm
always like looking to see we have the
same amount of space on either side W
epic view behind us all right welcome
everybody to Bubble man's world and of
course welcome to Puff Wednesday puff
Wednesday Johnny B is in the house for
this puff Wednesday and I'm pretty
excited to say that after so many years
of people bringing me dry sift to clean
that you you brought me something that
was
worthy dude so shout out to your buddy
who produced this lovely Trikes and grew
and listened to you putting screens
under his uh material we've got some
beautiful dry sift now it was AR
originally this was originally what I
got to work with and I'll show you that
in a better angle as well as well as
photos John had cleaned up a little bit
of it already just a little so he had uh
you know a nice little chunk
here and then um I basically went
forward and cleaned the sort of low
quality the low the seconds that he was
left with and I did this here and so
what this particular puff Wednesday is
going to entail I suspect is us talking
about this dry sift and of course us
enjoying this dry sift oh I mean there's
a little ball in there because you just
touched it with your finger and it just
went right it was amazing how fast this
this uh product uh melted in your hands
uh you just touched it and it was
literally clear almost opaque Amber and
the best part about all this is just
just this part of this is is how fresh
this resin truly is yeah so I mean we
went from I I I've convinced convinced a
few people to start trimming with screen
just just trim over the screen just take
a look at what you're losing yeah and he
calls me up he's like dude you got to
come check this out so the beginning
stages he took the 60 the 90 the 120 and
the 200 and just trimmed over top of
them and put it all together that's what
we got there right then I came back he
had it all on these screens and I did a
little bit of cleaning and I did
original cleaning that you taught me
right which is using the 60 the 90 the
110 and then cleaning on the 200 sure
well I pulled this off the 200 nice and
it showed him a little epicness and I
thought you know what to really show him
the true magic would be to come and see
you like that that that that alone would
just happened there so sticking the
Dabber on here and getting it hot and
then putting it into the sift as it
melts around it was pretty
awesome give me a little dab right
definitely a little
dab pressed it's very light and fluffy
so it won't be an oversized dab but I
figured while you're chatting away over
there about the beautifulness of this I
just got a puff Wednesday you just got a
puff onnes what I really really enjoy
about this guys is of course this is
organically grown this is grown with
many one so it's my one part growing
Bloom that I really really get behind
and stand behind and and it really shows
and Mark will will contest to that
whenever I bring resin that I've grown
with the certain nutrient what I do we
get these awesome gland heads and I
think it really do is just maturity
taking it to day 63 day 65 finding out
when it stops drinking all these little
tips and tricks that ensure that I've
learned just from talking with you over
the last four years right I've had to
make sure that I have developed
triphones
and you know what as he's doing that and
he's looking for the the cap if you
don't think I'm jumping in here right
now and doing my own little dab yeah
it's
like on that just a beautiful thing
right here right
now s to leave you hanging Johnny Be I
cuz I left the Q-tips sitting right over
there in the recycling bin so I couldn't
see them I I saw them with the
sunglasses I thought he's looking for a
carb cap and then I started using the
carb cap I'm like he's looking for a
carb cap I'm like he didn't do that 500
Q tippers and remember to always clean
one thing I've learned now I've been
cleaning my uh my thing and I actually
managed to pick up some of the goodness
oh nice yeah uh I was when I saw a
friend and he had a jar of it a bottle
of it and I'm like dude can I have some
he's like sure I took
half perfect well let's get you a nice
big rip on this that was really nice
yeah see I just tried doing that fail so
this is I'm learning we're holding on
the bottom is getting a little bubble
going on there and that bubble is
actually that's like the end of the
Dab's got a
bubble there you go Johnny B get your
proper
Styles you deserve oh man look at that
we're going to do macro uh video for you
to see the Melt Factor on this tiny
little bit of char left over on the
Sapphire Nail at the end of the hit but
very little compared to the quality of
the actual resin it's not always that
you get resin of this quality you know
and it's why a lot of people have a hard
time making that six-star bubble hash or
making that six-star 99.9% gland head
ratio dry sift because having the
material first and foremost is what's
going to move you into the next stage of
actually being in the game and now being
in a position where you could unveil the
quality of that resin I mean what do we
got three different piles we got three
different piles of epicness and then two
piles of contaminant mhm and then
there's one way that well it is nice to
have you come over and say hey I got
some resin can you clean it up I'm happy
to do it well we did that there last
time we got to see the difference and
there was hardly nothing well that's it
there was nothing the last resin that
you brought me it was like I went to
clean it and there was literally like
nothing like not even a dab worth of a
rip so it was kind of interesting
because I thought it was really really
good
sift exactly you know you never know and
it's funny when people think something
and then you show them otherwise and
they're kind of like wait a second wait
a second whereas today you know when you
brought this I knew the second I saw
that it was going to be fire but you
were like no no clean this one and I was
like well okay it's the shittier version
of want to see that now and now it's now
it's what I cleaned is much nicer than
that you look at that color right there
this is the difference and you can start
seeing that color change dude we're
going to turn this into this so this
except this pile here is going to be big
huge it's going to be probably like it'd
be good I should weigh that to find out
what percentage of heads we get out of
it because I bet it it's 50 to 60% we
will We it yeah well no exactly and we
and this will be detailed we'll detail
it out with with a photo essay at the
end of this video we'll be able to show
you the pictures of what we started with
the weights of it and that'll kind of
make this a fun interesting video well
you know what it get to show you what
you can get and what the screens that I
get from you and what they can possibly
work what I'm able to accomplish with
just screen
yeah well dude like I said you did a
great job on that it definitely looks
fire when I was showing my bunny and you
know what I Ed the best part about it
what I use to clean this was at Tim
Horton's dut box and I was showing him I
was going over I said you got a cut up
because I was pulling out what you have
in here I was pulling out all the leaf
matter that they mix into it and they
didn't know how to do that so I
everybody's got a different way of a
different way of trying to do their
sifting and what you showed me I've you
know came up with little ways of making
sure to pull the contaminant make a
little bit easier and uh you know what
that's how easy it was to do this but to
get from here to this
stage with the static and using the DVD
in the parchment would probably take me
about a week yeah it take a while I do
that or I can come here how long was
that I don't know 15 minutes I think it
took 15 maybe maybe 10 I didn't have set
up I I was trying to catch an ant with
your son oh so that that's what I mean I
didn't know cuz I was you know we
catching that quality time with T man oh
he's awesome it's awesome I was
explaining to him how he went into the
hole and he was going to come back and
then I thought he'd never come back
little bugger did ended up to be at the
end of he got dabbed out with a wet
napkin what do you think of this hot
Dabber technique well you know what I
thought that was cool because you had a
bubble come on there and then you dipped
into it right there you got the
bubble and it's like
boom and it's really hard to pick up
this sift because it's just like I don't
know it's like all you can do is really
melt it you know when it first snows out
and it's really really nice and it's
powder and you you look at it fluffy
powder it's fluffy powder and as it
settles and as the day progresses it
settles and gets harder and harder well
that's exactly what's happening here
right now it's fluffy and in about an
hour it's going to be stuck to that card
dude well here's to you Johnny B A
little
rip you know it seems like just
yesterday I was watching the RCMP rifle
through your [ __ ] put you under a and
threaten you with uh jail yeah doesn't
it seem like just like yesterday it was
oh
[ __ ] and which was coincidentally enough
one year to the day where they announced
that we won the injunction correct um my
my my picture with the that bra on only
the Paul Leaf was on the front page of
the Global Mail all across Canada right
and on the same day A year
later I got pulled over and was
questioned if I had been smoking and do
you have any cannabis in your car and
I'm like well I if I were you I would
have said you know funny enough I don't
which is extremely rare extremely rare
it's so rare I honestly can't believe
you didn't have cannabis in your car I I
was I when do you not have cannabis in
your car one Med XL with one bud with a
B the pack in the console like and I had
nothing on me and this is also a brand
new car it's three weeks old take it no
no the best part I I love this part cuz
you guys didn't get to see this part of
the video tell us okay so at first he
comes up he he comes to the the
passenger side so people think I'm in
the passenger side I was in the driver's
side it's the way the camera was set up
on the dash and he thought it was part
of the car it was mirrored so I look at
that and uh he comes to the passenger
side and U my girl rolls down the window
and he looks in he goes um you know you
blew a red light back there and I'm like
no it was green it was oh it smells like
cannabis in the car you have any Canabis
in your
car and I and at first I said no right
and I go oh wait a second there might be
some in this medtainer and I handed it
to him I go there smellproof grinder so
you can't smell it he opens it like this
smells it goes whoa pulls back and hands
it back to me and then asks me and I
said well I'm a patient through and uh I
go since 2012 it says is when uh you
know we started the injunction so I'm
protecting on the injunction well um up
until I can verify with health candada
you're under arrest for cannabis
possession damn and I'm like pardon me
he goes well you're under arrest for
cannabis possession hand him my driver's
license he goes I'm not going to charge
you remember that strict thing I'm not
going to charge you for running a red
light well so as the day as this
progressed he went to his car I'm
watching in my rear view mirror as
another cop car pulls up I notic two
cops and he started adjusting his camera
now here's here's the kicker I live in
Alford which is a private police force
but was pulled over by RCMP right at the
at the exact time that the federal top
cop that was put in charge of the
Cannabis [ __ ] what are they call the
task force yeah cannabis task force Bill
Blair was actually in abbottford that
day doing a a talk I didn't even know
that which is guaranteed why those RCMP
so we had RCMP there they pull me over
and when I see them going through the
camera I go you know what Facebook live
p dude when I saw it first I was in
disbelief I thought is this from like 6
months ago or oh they yeah 6 months ago
it happened again before this same thing
and it's something I'm witnessing I get
pulled up behind I'm driving a brand new
car that is a company car it's
registered under the company you're
feeling like they're watching you I'm
feeling like you know what like how but
I guess you do put videos up on YouTube
for people to watch well yes but I mean
I'm doing but not to be but not to be
harassed by cops you should just tell
them listen man got a YouTube channel if
you want to see what I'm all about you
can watch it I update it all the time in
fact I'm on Facebook live right now if
you add me on Facebook live you can
watch you doing what you're doing to me
his that anyway so you know as I'm
looking in my rear view I see what's
going on I hit Facebook live because I
think you know what this is good this is
some [ __ ] such a good move that you did
that so uh I never thought it would get
like you know 25,000 plus hits in a
period of like 24 hours hell yeah
there's like 800 people watching live I
people watching telling me that cuz I
was going to the mom cup the mail order
marijuana cup and everybody was waiting
for me to get there but tons of people
shared it like hundreds people shared it
over 500 everyone shared it everybody
shared it that's how you get those views
up you got to share those videos you
know and
unfortunately you know it would be great
if people shared more than just our
dramas and the bad [ __ ] sh share the
information so understand this and I
talked to the lawyer about this I got
pulled over in a company car what was
registered under my company so and the
first thing he asked me is it smells
like marijuana now speed back 6 months
prior to that I got pulled over in my
truck with my Dad pulled up and goes it
smells like marijuana both times there's
no marijuana in my car this time there
wasn't a medtainer the last time I was
with my father there wasn't you sweat
marijuana though I do I do sweat it it
does come through my glands so so the
question is is as being a medical
patient as being a medical patient and
and the advocacy that I do am I is it on
my record when my come up they go oh
check for can because now this is
happening um I got a message that's what
that's what you get for being a cannabis
activist I mean cannabis activist
because because because I'm a medical
patient and I use cannabis for my pain
what you get John I I I got I got two
hours of my time taken up I sat in that
and and this is the other one I said so
when I sat in the back of the car that's
what you get that's what you get that's
what you
get so uh I sitting in the back of his
in his Tahoe and this Tahoe has got a
police dog in it and it's barking like
crazy and then as I'm sitting in there I
can see his computer screen right yeah
and it's dudy trunk R the marijuana girl
someone pull over with marijuana
marijuana so his whole screen so this
traffic this traffic officer was not a
traffic officer at all it was RCMP Drug
Squad because Bill Blair was there he
was on a back road driving down the road
and you know what I pulled up beside him
and knew he was beside me didn't click
he was RCMP until after the fact I done
the video and left and went why was RCMP
there
they're feds so they're feds they
gowhere they they go anywhere they want
and back road doubt I doubt the RCMP
even have traffic cops I think they're
all federal agents I I I would actually
almost say you know what I think he
actually got something got something
that's that's like the federal task
force like they have down in the US
anytime you get busted for any sort of
like illegal drugs it's the RCMP even
when I ended up getting busted in west
Vancouver years ago it was RCMP RCMP
ended up coming in I got charged fed
it's not like a provincial crime it's
kind of confusing and weird but uh well
the bottom line is I'm sorry that you
got harassed that really sucks but I do
hope that uh you'll enjoy that big old
[ __ ] dry sift d i just hooked you up
with you it was so nice to be able to
sit here and do this D but yeah well we
got we got a nice uh couple of carb caps
if the one gets too
hot very nice melt on this it's
definitely a five star for sure maybe
closing it a little bit of char at the
end but uh
it's still pretty damn clean I'd say
it's I'd say it's a solid 98 there's a
tiny little bit of contaminant in there
that probably makes up the 1 to
2% uh I did do a very quick quick
cleaning and so uh who knows maybe when
I have more time when I clean this
one I'll take it to that next level
because it's for Johnny and my's head
it's basically head stash so me you and
my buddy who grew yeah yeah and you know
all the other people we puff it with and
and the best part about it is is he's
the guy who's going to Puff it too he
loves this stuff and and being able to
being able to actually finally show him
what he's been losing the look on his
face dude was like this he's like are
you kidding me I've been doing this for
20 years I like I know you throwing away
totes he goes wheelbarrows I said to I
tot he goes wheelbarrows dude heads
wheelbarrows this is what you Growers
are throwing in the garbage get yourself
a set of screens well here's the thing
this is what some of you Growers are
throwing in the garbage in fact I doubt
not a lot of people have that same sort
of mentality of the old school sort of
just you know I called it hilly Bill
hillbilly growing and I don't say it as
like a like a negative cuz I'm a
hillbilly I love that country hillbilly
action but the growing way of that sort
of like real loose and real sort of just
like w we'll just get her done it's not
always going to produce this you know
dealing with commercial Growers there's
a small percentage of them that even
best part he hung dry this everything
that I talk about is what he did yeah
you have to if and he got this why
because it was just the way he cured it
the way he grew it yeah the genetics
just the genetics everything there's no
unveiling of anything if if they don't
put it there in the first place you know
I'm telling you man a lot of people have
brought me sift in the last couple of
years and this is the first time in a
long time that I've been like been like
right on that's nice you know I saw the
look on your face you want me to clean
this I'm like well yeah I don't know and
you came up like this that's the good
one where last time the good one was
what we could it wasn't even a pile it
was like inconsequential I was really
really surprised
so once again the last one was
commercially
grown right more or less uh dried on
screens and not hung dry we should show
them a nice macro um
uh hit on the sapphire of this dry sift
oh my do I I I think I think you guys it
won't be this hit because I'm going to
be cleaning up the dish like really
clean but we cut as I'm about to take
this rip they're going to be seeing this
melt so if you want to like talk about
it Johnny B the Melt content I think the
best part about how this melts is how it
puddles right away and it swirls around
the bowl and goes into a really nice
liquid you can see it bubbling and then
you can almost see it dissipate so we're
not getting the great big huge bubbles
it kind of just kind of goes like water
it looks like
water and at the end of that see that is
my favorite cough you you get it in all
the videos the first video we did were
cleaning dryft in 40 minutes dry clean
in 40 minutes when we used to rip it so
hard it was like we were trying to get
like a like a pulled muscle in gr I know
[Applause]
like true true true true do that but I
mean it's come a long way and learning
exactly uh the proper ways of well I say
there's no proper way the way that you
like the way that you the proper ways
the proper ways because there's times
and temperatures some people I used to
like at higher heat but now that I'm not
such that harsh chronic pain anymore my
Pain's different now the lower heat
seems good have you ever seen me hitting
anything now at 710 at 740 anymore cuz
cuz I felt like that that higher hit hit
Me Harder this is more tpin and I can
see how the tping are being able
modulate and help me better that's why I
like the Sith so much it's because it
gives me all those flavors that I don't
get beautiful macro photos of this stuff
as well you can see glistening gland
heads mixed in with the plant matter
tiny tiny tiny little bits of plant
matter in there um with a little bit of
uh maybe citate stock solid 98% hash
with uh you know done in about I mean
realistically done in about four or five
minutes so I guess we'll end it with
that killer puff Wednesday say Johnny be
nice and short but sweet but but look at
how sweet that is and we're going to
continue doing some puffing here well
we'll sit and we'll puff for a bit I'll
clean this up so we get the bowl nice
and white and we'll film a really nice
macro rip of some dry sift hitting the
dish of course we're not going to carb
cap it so there is going to be a little
bit of a waste someone's going to get
that sort of uh you know carbless Rip
but uh we do it for you guys so I hope
you all enjoyed this little episode of
puff Wednesday might throw a little
Drone footage in there but uh we'll see
you next weekend hopefully for hash
church and hopefully next Wednesday for
another
episode see you guys next
[Music]
time one man HR man
real the purp after weed to the mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I've been traveling to kingst
[Music]
hours trees