[Music]
we have fun welcome to bow man's world
everyone about coming to puff Wednesday
huff wins then they see anybody and a
place you've never been so long and I
feel like I haven't spent the last 7
days with you so what are we doing today
we're at my office we've got a couple of
beautiful Luke Brown psychedelic
visionary art if you want to check him
out go to spectral eyes dot its spectral
eyes yeah he's got all this psychedelic
art you tell me it's insane well nobody
could for sure that was Alex gray and
he's friends with Alex gray and he's
he's definitely a visionary psychedelic
artist and I supported them back in the
day when we used to hang out at the
gallery and what we're here today for
however is John and I are gonna smoke a
few bowls while we're at my office we
were just down here grabbing a few
things got some meetings in regards to
new ideas new companies new concepts
that we're gonna be working on in the
near future here but I thought this
would be a good opportunity for us to
come hit some glass history and so I'm
gonna bring up the pieces one by one
we're gonna start with Marcel number 399
now Marcel blew this back in 1999 it was
the third piece of three that he did in
the year and well let's just say it's
completely epic
it's got a great pull on it dolphins the
whole nine yards once we hit Marcel
we're gonna go hit the OG max Poland now
I may or may not have bought this for
max in the 90s I can't remember if it
was actually in the 2000s that I bought
it but max did this double bubbler this
is quite a nice little piece for max he
does giant pieces now it's got the
crushed opal you know this is a decade
plus before dohsa or any of these guys
we're crushing the opal just really cool
unique double bubbler and we're gonna
hit that little piece of Max history and
then finally I'm gonna hit my upright
piece I wish this was clean but I got to
show you this anyway this is a prototype
piece that Jason Lee sent me years ago
this might have been sent to me in 99 or
2000 I can't remember it's an upright
doubler it's right when he learned the
seal that allowed him to make those
double bubblers actually I'll show you
one real quickly just because we have
them this one's a slinger and it's
actually a Tripler but if you guys
remember these pipes and when they came
on the market we started selling them on
overgrow and stuff that's this seal when
Jason made this seal and showed slinger
and a few other blowers and they started
showing other people that really opened
the door for this double and triple and
quadruple public concept this bond was
one of the first ones and it was an
upright unit double bubbler chamber up
their secondary chamber here
cool little ziggity you know marble
style Jason Lee and just think he's here
a little opal in there and he's actually
got a middle ear right on the top of the
piece so pretty cool stuff historical in
my opinion kidding the old glass that
the glassblowers you know it was the
beginning of all of this it was the
start of all of this so we've got our
three pieces what say we start with well
let's start with Jason he's right there
I just would like to say wow
because I never knew yeah that is so
cool I mean we got in class education
today absolutely which is John said you
liked it hit some fresh bar of course
awesome we talked about the coming up
I'll let you clean that tell me we don't
put our dirty skillet tools into our
supremely clean dry sifted resins and we
just give it a quick little flash with
the lighter a white with a rag you
finger some rags good if you use a lot
of that dirty if you're hitting it a lot
though I have to admit like that would
be ridiculous trying to wipe it always
with your fingers if you have a rag
you're still a table stay clean all the
time if you choose to clean it with your
fingers nine out of ten times when
someone picks it up it'll be dirty and I
say that with my own experience because
I was cleaning my with my hand too now I
have the rag and man I'm loving it check
it out clean skillet tool so what we
notice is what we get this phone cools
dirty is because we're hitting a Dean
now like exactly just solid and then
when you pick up nice hash with that
deep with that scooper he end up we
ended up getting a little little blobs
of contamination inside and this one's
yours buddy
Oh put a smile on my face and when you
get that smile it just means I just
decreased a little bit there's a little
carb hole always happy to get Johnny the
first rip of our puffs Wednesday day for
this guy's here you go
we're puffing yeah right off the bat
because it's a Jason Lee the thing just
pulls proper he's got wicked talk
chamber action going and the bottom
chamber is troubling away nicely that
kid is gone perfect rip
that is it smell good just in this
container the perk of that is amazing
and this is old John I mean and that's
amazing because I try to talk about that
with other people that is the frequent
write days how 13 different pipes no
nothing like this but the perk is
everything it makes it so much
dysfunctional to me I'm not interested
in a pipe that's extremely artful but
doesn't have the proper function you
know we miss the boat okay Jason was
always about his function the bubbling
and everything the seals to be proper no
it's definitely uh well for me it's
first time I hit it I hope somebody's
been hitting it solid in the last the
last few years but I'm guarantee was
well used years and years ago I always
loved this is like over your favorite
pipe real nice well it's got three front
Milly's as well I forgot to mention I
mean imagine this pipe was really more
like a fun pipe he wasn't really
producing it to sell it as a prototype
alright
so Jason Lee we salute you serve
excellent glassblowing is always and
happy to hit some of your history here
that is libo for those that know him
personally so next up we're gonna max
down this max about doubler is
completely clean 100% beautiful clean
and so you'll get a nice fresh hit out
of that John you can tell us so fresh
right I'll take it for LTP hit first
thanks brother it looks like a
fabulously so function just a design and
the uniqueness
here's amazing it's just it's really
neat it's almost like a cloverleaf in
this side here yeah
cat wait these yeah no it's some way to
look at when we look at different art
meetings have someone max max I Oh
what's his name great guy - the great
son of a man
yeah exactly that was the old school you
know about yeah and all those guys if
you look at Marcel he's got his sign
right in the Martin oh yeah always
signing Lee Bo was more like he would do
his if you look at a million if you look
into Mellie and they're not Billy you
won't see it probably but right in the
middle is a tiny little J this [ __ ] man
that's just like a Picasso or a
Rembrandt or or or efficient exactly so
then maybe Hamilton the works of art
know the beginning of what people
started the painting I just never before
and just never picked any of them up
hitchhiking on fish to her before
that's how I met Jason Lee that's when I
met marbles later I met max viage marble
slinger and I met Marcel via marble
slinger as well he would bring these
guys up from Bellingham when they all
lit they're back at 9:00 I guess the
late nineties oh I'm just like watching
this epic poem melt bone look just so
nice on that plane but it sounds like
she's perking do you like
and it's a pleasure to sit here with you
and behold the hip knees I've beautiful
works of art that you've kept safe yeah
I've been protecting them you know I've
had a lot of these pipes for even a good
spot he's 58 15 plus years you know
every day this pop Wednesday's a special
occasion because I'm sharing over here
absolutely and that's pretty much you
guys are our inspiration and all of us
you write such nice comments for the
most part and we just want you guys to
know that those comments are really what
drives us to wanna so appreciate do more
shows and well show you guys more stuff
and you know once we realize we're not
crazy and that there's people that are
actually watching and enjoying this
well then we're happy to you know
produce more shows for you guys so John
and I are going to be back in Toronto of
course in a couple of weeks for the
next-gen conference that's gonna be June
26th and Toronto at the convention
center you can check that out at Green
Rush financial conferences calm come
check us out John speaking I'm speaking
and a whole slew of other people will be
speaking them I'll take you on that now
maybe next Wednesday I didn't look at
that whole list and I could just say
we're so low excellent yeah it was quite
the list I was looking at today with the
amount of talkers and the booths and the
people that are getting really involved
in the next but not so low for people to
come oh no nothing right okay we're
almost sold out for booze and for
speakers a speaker let's disco we're
actually taking a look at
can actually take off the speaker's list
right now because someone get it so
that's different that doesn't mean you
guys can't come to the show and get in
we're sold out we're not sold that we're
not so well we're definitely ready for
you guys to come meet us and you know if
you do want to get a booth there with
your company you guys can contact John
and Green Rush team because they're
pretty much almost done but yeah
definitely get going Green Rush
pineapple are most common click on the
booths and we'll see you can get you in
but um today how without that laughs
that we just fill those last little
booths booths
I like the way to say boo that's
actually it sounds like booze booze no
no I can see I can hear it itself I love
the subtle differences of language
particularly accents and different
cultures I love traveling to different
places and then you know just of course
either you're trying to learn their
language which of course you'll have a
harsh accent on your end and then if
they're trying to speak English but it's
not an English first speaking country
that that language barrier can be
interesting so we have there our
Americans here with us next a boot not
that I feel like I've ever said a boot
but who maybe idea and they a boot hey
how about a bong rip June and I've got
some many he's many Kush grown by you
it's your medicine my fluffa right here
like you're gonna hit this huh you know
why this is other thing I'm so
appreciated was the Marcel pieces and
and I didn't even know who the gentleman
was or what he was opposed I think he's
amazing he met Marcel can have met them
and the first time I met him mark gave
him my first plant of my little pony and
he tried it he never tried Marcel gonna
first so he had a little jar we were at
the cup a chat treating yourself and
Marcel came over I know Marcel since
1999 he's a whole time friend of mine
but I haven't seen
in those last few years because he
hadn't come up to the u.s. all right to
the Canada I hadn't gone down to the US
for for quite some time so it was the
first time I'd seen him in a long time I
didn't have anything on me except John's
little jar he was standing next to me
and I literally just so exciting me just
pulled out a nugget and gave it to
Marcel and John was kind of like really
but at the same time then you were like
well that's Marcel yeah I'm great hit
man that looks good on there that nice
little Marcel Butler such a pleasure to
watch someone hit this pipe you know I
guess the way the smoke comes up through
the chamber and backlights the dolphin
and all it's just a really old school
favorite pipe of mine that yeah could
you imagine the value of this thing on
the open glass market Wow many a look
and of course some you load me right up
there well you know it's your medicine
you know what's your medicine always be
generous with you shared it with me I'll
eat sure she I'm admiring that beautiful
bike you know I just did a nice rich
woman and Wow you know what
well you just grew which was my baby
push yeah well it was amazing he grow it
just like me yeah well I just did just
exactly that I pretty much simplified it
don't have to put too much attention
into it it's not a lot of people want to
make it seem like it's very difficult
and I will say this we are growing at a
certain level one of the things that I
can tell you that I'm going to help
inspire John which will be in the very
near future is producing true organic
buds where we produce actual living soil
with ends
the whole nine yards you can't get that
from a food the same way and well yeah
don't test it will just be like a hat we
find it shouldn't feel like I will throw
attention it's not a we're gonna stop
doing what we're doing will have those
tents doing that but I love the idea of
this soil that you just feed water yeah
but you and that we could together mix
up this soil choose our recipes build it
up you know and then and then do the
same thing yeah you know it's a quiver
right it's dry sifting wet washing it's
all these different things not everyone
wants to buy a food some people love the
idea of of creating living soil and a
really great book to read if you want to
learn about soil is the secret life of
soil there's also the secret life of
plants both of those books are
exceptional if you want to understand
how plants grow and help clients process
we all have our Bibles some of them go
back 15 20 years and they sit on the
Shelf from there to me it's my pleasure
room oh yeah absolutely love books I
look at all your books in the background
and all your all the stuff that you can
see that you can read over the years
that taught me the knowledge of what it
brought me to where you are right now
it's it's kind of cool sitting in your
office to look at all this yeah we're
not here awful enough but it's like
sitting in the yeah I can see that I
mean one day you will but I mean it's
just looking around laughing it's it's
it's a bit of history sitting in here
was here but you know what it's like you
know this is this is how do you be bald
and be gained and listen to that bubble
definitely a very nice bubble hush
barely nice I wonder why because it
bubbles so yeah there we did it John did
you ever see if you see the bottom of
this guy
anyway I will take the camera and do a
close up of all the pipe so you can see
them a little closer up John and I just
wanted to share a few bowls with you
share a few stories from the office and
uh I guess we're on our way to get it to
for a meeting maybe we'll have a meeting
and this meeting isn't gonna be more
involved than what we're both meant to
both that's 73 90 120 and things coming
we can't say a bunch right just yet it's
exciting it's really exciting that the
really the true medicine is certain to
be able to actually being really
researched well then recognized and
recognized and seeing all these people
that are coming oh wow it's really cool
so keep watching but a man's world and
PUF Wednesday's will be back soon this
is just the first part guys peace
alright welcome back to bow man's world
guys we just bumped into mr. Dana Larson
original editor from Canada's culture
creator of sensible BC and just
all-around awesome cannabis personality
in our community Johnny B's in the back
seat always and uh you know how how are
things going Dana what's what's going on
these days in the life of cannabis
activists well sensible BC still super
busy order office is just across the
street here in the Dominion building we
moved into a bigger space we're not
doing any referendum specific stuff
right now but we are working away we got
municipal elections coming up this fall
we're gonna try to beat some bad mares
and reelect some good ones focus our
strength there and that'll be a good
practice for us for next year when we
got the federal election coming up yeah
and we're also gonna do a convention
this fall as well in late September I'm
gonna try to get two or three hundred
people to come from around the province
a few from each district put on an event
to have some socializing some panelist
I'm talking and I want to work also as a
group on actually writing the law that
we want to get passed so we have a
specific law federally provincial e-even
municipal bylaws we should be writing
those as well as ourselves
the group in the culture so that we have
specific proposals because we leave that
stuff to the people who don't know what
to write they write stupid-ass laws
right so you should be writing you know
what are the right bylaws for a city to
if they Fanny I don't know what we
should be coming up with that stuff so
that's what we're working on anyways and
awesome people want to get involved
check out sensible BC CA or come down
and say hi we got lots of volunteers
doing stuff and so yeah it's good
awesome well that's [ __ ] killer and I
guess the next biggest thing really on
the on the everyone's minds here in
British Columbia is the the return of
Marc Emery yeah that'll be awesome yeah
he gets out late July then there's gonna
be a period where he's released from
jail but he's back into the immigration
people it's a buffer zone of what's yeah
eight weeks or something well hopefully
less than that I mean it could be as
short as a week or two it could be a
couple of months one of marks friends
from prison went in that and he was
there several months but even his
paperwork organized and Marc does and
certainly his supporters will be calling
the check on and then amino acid yeah so
I'm hoping it gets out sooner but but we
don't really know it's gonna be at least
a few weeks but by August mark should be
bout and back in Canada they bring him
across to Windsor take him across in
Detroit so it's kind of weird so we'll
be flying out to Windsor on short notice
whatever we hear that he gets out and I
wonder what how many people will fly out
for that yeah hopefully a lot and then
mark will be maybe there for a day or
two but come back to BC pretty quick and
he's looking forward to getting back to
work and getting things going he'll be
at the store working there and he wants
to do some speaking Marc likes to talk
and a lot to talk about these days so
and I think he's gonna do some touring
around BC and around the country and
then maybe around the world that people
can sponsor him to go places he's not
going to be like the rich Prince of pot
a lot of people listening to like the
media has always listened to mark the
the level of media that will come I mean
he was certainly you know he's been on
the front page of The Wall Street
Journal he's been profiled on CNN he's
been in several other you know
international media kind of things like
that
Tsingtao news and stuff even so yeah
he'll be it'll be a big story and I
think he's just looking forward to
trying to
get back and keep being an activist
again or enough to get really stopped
being one but being free and being able
to work and talk to people and it's been
just enjoy yeah you got a five-year
sentence he did did he get time off for
good behavior he did some time here
before he laughed he did like a couple
of several months here and that all
counts against so he did about four
years in US prison I think it's comes to
just under four years out in there and
then with the time here and got time off
and everything else but it's an he's had
some rough times you got that it would
sit mmm SRA that lay that virus that was
pretty really kill people and it's quite
common in prisons and hospitals in that
and you know that's something he'll have
with them forever and but overall that
was probably the worst thing overall
he's been good and he plays bass guitar
and I write so wild he'll be the jam
nights I feel like him and Tommy Chong
should get together Tommy Chong do a
lead guitar market on bass guitar a
little bit of accompaniment taking turns
Thomas guitars yeah dude telling stories
and doing jokes and things in between
their music I feel like that I mean I
don't know that I just think that that
will be pretty fun if that were to
happen I think people would love to hear
that they're both funny entertaining
guys in very different kind of ways I
think that it wouldn't be very hard to
put together considering marks coming
back and you know Tommy's gonna come up
and visit him yeah for sure and Tommy
Chong was always like he wore that free
market t-shirt on every single agency
every single thing you know he really
that was huge supporter yeah was good so
that's all been very good so mr will be
great to have mark back and getting him
high and everything will be a lot of fun
I mean he's gonna get pretty baked on
his first stop back here he said a long
time to have his tolerance go down so
we're gonna have to work on that when he
gets back well I'm about to work on mine
right now I've got the little mini
hitman rig here I've got some
award-winning Barbara Budd
little barber bud did that is something
I heard that being mentioned that the
date of the man said took first place
for the dry sipped nice the drive sip at
the expo there yeah and this is what
we're popping right now so he grew it he
fumbled it and then I cleaned it up
Barbara bud have to famed Canadian
journalist Barbara bud exactly exactly
not a lot of people might know that but
it is
don't eat her up enough for you oh oh
you do these little pipes are insane
everyone Johnny who always Wednesday
yeah we went for a nice dinner we would
say having a little bit of a meeting and
learn something from that
yeah was yourself yeah you got to do
these things well Matt just posted it
recently on his page if you want
something done you gotta do it yourself
of course I added but sometimes you need
to ask your friends and I it was kind of
a joke because I cleaned the barber
forum that he entered in the Champs but
it's true sometimes you do need to just
get it done yourself Oh Johnny
it's pretty incredible to see how far
it's come in the last 20 years isn't it
a no like compared to when I first met
you I think I remember you sitting on a
window still you were working on some
little computer they di think you might
have had a big beard at the time does
that sound familiar I don't actually
have to think about the first time I met
you but those are all things that I
would be doing we kind of were like oh
mom but it was really like meeting
someone that oh I'll probably never
maybe see that guy again that was just
the first time I met you and it was
literally back in the day
well we haven't changed the law yet but
20 years ago there was no legal hemp
growing in Canada
no it's prolific really there still be
needs to be a lot more butts growing
there was no very little medical access
there pretty much none I guess 20 years
ago the BC compassion club Society and
Ted Smith and if the others would just
get just starting to get going yeah 79
like 95 you know yeah so around that
time things were getting going
wasn't Hillary doing like the driving
around on her bike in 95 or what that
was all still nice that was right in 96
yeah that was I moved here in 96 but I
used to come before that as a Manitoba
hemp guy because we got our license to
grow hemp between 94 and 95 we used to
bring hemp paper and hemp cloth and
different things to hemp BC and that's
how we met Hilary that's how yeah yeah
we were the Manitoba hemp guys you know
we show up with the Hays which was
knocked over though I did yeah it was
from Winnipeg all right
yeah didn't they bring all the hemp
seeds in a Concorde jet or something was
that the is that you guys the
consolidated growers and process that
was you guys right they got the hemp
thing going but that group didn't
succeed as an organization helps
kickstart going it definitely got
everything into the grocery stores and
the food but it really sort of stunted
what we thought hemp was gonna be which
was the fifty thousand commercial
products and the fiber and the plastics
and the metals and all those you know
commercial products that you could
produce it's sort of turned into even
the biomass for us the seed originally
was more like let's run our cars on this
not let's sell it for $16 a bottle for
healthy food which is great I love that
idea as well but now it's so expensive
that biomass isn't there there's no
there's no way to use hemp seed oil to
run your vehicle on it because it's like
like this work that you know sell 10
times the price of gas so it's just it's
just too expensive so yeah it's it is
what it is you know I think it'll move
forward I think a lot more people are
the infrastructure for 50,000 commercial
products and for hemp is no great feat
that are no small feat that is like
billions of dollars of infrastructure it
doesn't just fit into current
infrastructure that's already there no
absolutely for the seeds it's easy
because you can process the seeds with
very little technology but making fibers
hard and making fuels really hard like
especially biomass fuel it's not hard
but it needs a lot of converters and
local things and not one big Pro that
you need to build a lot of little
processing stations for sure ya know
it's there's it's no small feat to
actually start extracting out all the
different parts of the hemp into
cellulose and fibers and the seed and
how you planted and how you breed it and
grow it those things to me never really
happened they just it kind of they let
us have it and then we were so happy
just to have it we never really did the
big commercial push to start getting big
companies to come in and be like look we
need these for
because it's happening on a smaller
level one thing that's got to change
is this got to be not Health Canada
running it it's got a big recovery
category hundred percent and all the
things they were worried about when it
was first legalized they talked about
people growing marijuana in the hip
fields we had to watch out for that at
all these worries and it's been a long
time now nothing bad happened not a
single hemp farmer has ever been accused
of anything like that so they should
lighten up the rules now and make it
more accessible and put it under
agriculture Canada and get Health Canada
which is bad at all regulating medical
marijuana which should actually kind of
be in their jurisdiction they're
terrible at regulating hemp which has
got nothing to do with Health Canada at
all like why are they they're not
they're not it makes no sense it makes
no sense for sure hopefully we
eventually get that happening so Health
Canada just steps away from cannabis
completely I don't see them really
having a position in it it should be
provincial and should be regulated
differently and in relation to the yeah
it should be well that's what I would
think Jeanne the farm to grow corn we
should be screwing when you know it's
gonna be a lot of stuff moving now in
here but I think that's it we can say
it's fully legalized when farmers can
grow any potency of cannabis they want
in their fields right that to me is kind
of the endgame right if we can go to
that point and it can harvest the
trikona medicine people won't buds will
become a niche product for a small
minority of people at that point it'll
be about resin and you can make very
pure resin from outdoor crop it's harder
to make perfectly manicured buds
outdoors but who cares but you can make
stuff like that and you can make it for
a buck a gram if it was being grown
outdoors that very potent levels you
could do it you can do it well if after
whatever could be that's that the bucket
gram was my retail price including taxes
in retail I think the wholesale you do
from with ten cents a gram that's I
rubbed you some rough calculations but I
think that level of even if I'm off by a
large amount those are still those kind
of thing this is this retails for like
fifty to eighty dollars yeah so those
things are but like the oils and resins
usually and those are you can make pure
quality products high quality any
cannabinoid profile
throw it outdoors incredibly cheap and
then you could use all the other parts
of the plant for all the other aspects
as well harvest the seeds or dopamine
seeds but harvest the stock or whatever
you'd be wrong in well you heard it here
guys this is what we talk about this is
what we do on Bubble man's world we bump
into our friends we talk about the
things that we love and we share a
little bit of our passion with you guys
so I want to thank John B and Dana
Larson for hanging out I have got to go
pick up my daughter so this show is over
for now but we'll see you later on below
man's world
[Music]