hey hey hey what's going on there
Facebook
family coming at you live from well I'm
coming live from the Shannon Archer
Memorial and Shannon Archer is a young
woman who was in her 20s and was killed
in a car accident on the Sea to Sky
Highway they rebuilt the highway for the
Olympics in
2010 and they created this little Zone
here and it's unfortunate because the
phone is just barely barely barely
holding on so I don't really want to uh
to move it around too much but uh yeah
I've got my Mothership here I'm in an
absolutely beyond beautiful area
here you can see the
ocean out there yeah good morning good
morning good morning but I've got
everything like super sketchy balanced
right now so I'd hate to have my phone
break while I'm doing a live Facebook so
let's just do some bowls shall we help
hope everyone's doing good this morning
this afternoon or this evening depending
on where you are in this wonderful world
of ours going to have to pull out a
little pull out a little rosin here for
the for the session get the
torch I'm going to do some dabbing I
hope everyone's doing good yes it's
absolutely beautiful here and it's puff
Wednesdays hello puff Wednesday I
figured it's Wednesday it's puff
Wednesday maybe we should be puffing got
a little of rosin that I'm able to
thankfully grab with my hands because I
forgot my
Dabber yep yep yep not even sure where
it is to be honest but luckily my rosin
is so wonderfully cured I can just pick
it up with my fingers that's nice got to
like that hey edu how are you doing Drew
Roberts in the house bill hitch hitchon
hitchon I always pronounce your name
wrong do I always sort of thought it was
hitch coin but I'm just seeing that now
is not correct welcome Spencer and
Michael shot smoking some cherry pie
just finished a few dabs well that's
what I like to hear I'm just about to
start a few dabs and thank you to Snick
for this super [ __ ] killer Snick
shirt that I got recently this is the
Snick Snick Barnes shirt corrosive
flammable oxygen snake pretty cool hey
what's going on jibs John buy I hope
you're joining us for a bowl this
morning congratulations on all your
successes at chalice it's time to
[ __ ] get lit
bro welcome Alex finle from the UK
representing in the bubble man chat room
right now I hope everyone's doing just
wonderful time to get time to get a
little melty here with my new
brothership ceramic Bowl I've been
really liking this brother ship I'm not
going to lie not the pipe itself but
the the honey Bowl the honey uh
[Applause]
bucket all right chalice was awesome I
saw man chalice looked amazing props to
douge you know the guy takes a lot of
heat from a lot of people generally
people that don't do [ __ ] or ever get
anything done in our community those are
the people that are uh bitching to Doug
about what he's doing so we got to give
the guy
props all right heat that [ __ ] up nice
and nicy
yeah that's what I'm saying dude douge
killed
it oh beautiful dude always nice to be
pulling down green houses dabbing on
some Amnesia Haze full melt six-star
well that is definitely a good thing no
star rating on this it's just
Rosen Brighton cannabis club what's
going on Anthony good to see you good to
hear from you I think it's time for a
little dab what do you guys say we ready
to rip it up a dunk shall
we wow
beautiful give you guys a little bit of
a an idea of where I am right
now I'm on a
cliff that drops way
down down down down to this beautiful
[ __ ]
ocean that is the Pacific Ocean right
[Applause]
there wow that tasted so good that was
Master Scout rosin from the West Coast
concentrate
boys really
nice hey Bubble Trouble dabbling in Mar
Marbella no other cannabis event even
remotely
compares
yeah you know I used to say the same
thing about the toker's bowls when Mark
Emery threw the toker's bowls now
obviously the this was 13 or 14 years
ago and not on par with what douge is
doing in any way shape or form but it
really was back then better than any
cannabis event that you could possibly
like by a
mile so the puff part sick view no no
the puff part's not over Dude the puff
part has just begun we're doing a little
bit of puffing we're doing a little bit
of walking i' like to give you guys a
little bit of a view of where I am and
what what what's going on not just
chatting so yeah it's nice to get out
you know I saw a thing these uh recently
one of the great reasons to go and visit
parks there was 10 great reasons to go
and visit national parks and you know
one of them one of the ones that really
sort of that I connected with was that
it brings out your inner child you know
it brings out your inner child to get
into um epic beautiful nature whether
you're hanging out on the ocean or a
lake or under a waterfall it's just so
inspirational to be able to be in those
environments that uh yeah I implore all
of you you know if you have the ability
if you can you know go for a hike go hit
the
park that's a little bit muggy you know
it was raining up in Squamish where I
just came from but uh as you can see the
Sunshine Coast has blue sky right above
uh you can see the clouds have opened
right up that is the Sunshine Coast and
they do call it the Sun Coast for a
reason they do happen to get uh quite a
few more uh days of sunshine than us
welcome Sam high and Derek Wood Thrush
good to see you
brother yes sweet going to get down with
your next puff view is awesome yeah dude
that's what I'm saying I'm glad you guys
are enjoying it it's uh it's pretty
freaking beautiful I mean on all levels
and then there is uh of
course uh right there is the cross where
Shannon was uh
I guess it's just where they ended up
putting it when the first Highway was uh
was was taken down so even when you're
in Epic Beauty you're still reminded of
the humility of Life the fragileness of
life we're all here for such a short
period of time even me talking to you I
could [ __ ] step off this Cliff right
now and crack my head open and be gone
forever so uh you know treat the people
around you and in your life and the ones
that you engage with even strangers as
potentially positive as possible we're
all going through through things and
we've all got stresses but uh it makes
it easier if we have a little bit of
empathy and compassion for the people in
our immediate surroundings and even
those in our extended
surroundings Hey Ron Jones you're
welcome most welcome most welcome how
are the stars at night Jim good boy
they're epic epic that's what they
are oh Spencer I'm so sorry to he bro
I've had it happened as well I
definitely wasn't saying it like lightly
making fun of it or anything uh I had a
friend jump out of a tent on acid in the
middle of the night and he he forgotten
that he had put his tent right on the
edge of a of a cliff and he dropped uh
like 50 ft and passed away as well so
it's it's scary it's scary how fragile
life is you know we get caught up in the
day-to-day stresses little things I saw
someone I think it was Addison actually
who's going through some things right
now uh Salo Salo from Chile uh in
regards to um what's important to you
what are you grateful for he asked what
are you grateful for and you know
jokingly I replied great hash even
though not really jokingly obviously I
am grateful for that but not quite as
grateful as you know Todd McCormick was
when he was in a wheelchair and all he
wanted to do was be able to go to the
bathroom and wipe his own ass and get
back up and walk
away these are the the the humble
lessons of life um you know Mike Tyson
said if you are not humble in this world
this world will dress humility upon you
you so I choose to be humble rather than
to have it dressed upon me that [ __ ]
scares
me I got a really nice Blast from that
rosin hit and it is sunny the sun came
out so strong right after I hit that I
wonder if I'll be able to balance this
again
without breaking
anything
sketchy
oh I think that's the best I can
do yes Derek I
agree awesome Ron you know I'm grateful
for the panelists as well I do really
have to give it out to them it's uh it's
been a little bit of a difficult Road
and dealing with all the different
personalities and trying to keep
everyone happy and we've lost a few
along the way but uh I think for the
most part it's a pretty cool Core group
and uh I just I'm extremely grateful to
all of them for spending their time and
coming in there's no side deals or any
payments going on it's really just uh
they're choosing to share their time
with all of you and it's uh it's
exciting you know the fact that we even
have an audience like Todd said we used
to shout at the top of our lungs on the
sides of street corners and to be able
to have like uh this sort of Technology
available and then have actual people
like you guys that actually want to hear
it it's incredible man Master
Scout
Master
Scout flower rosin not always hitting
flower rosin uh Horatio didn't go
anywhere I just stopped sending him the
link we sort of had our own experiences
our egos clashed a few too many times
and I just started feeling silly sending
him the link we weren't getting along
and I have nothing bad to say about him
and I I'd hope that he has nothing bad
to say about me but uh hash church is
bigger than me in htio and so uh I just
wanted to keep uh keep the Purity there
without uh any any negative feelings cuz
I can honestly say that the panelists if
they're on hash church I'm 100% okay uh
with them and and I'm comfortable with
them but you know when you start your
thing it's it's just an ego thing really
it's a bummer but uh it is what it is
and my part is is that I play 50% of it
I'm I have an ego and he has an ego and
our ego started to
clash and uh yeah you know it probably
released him to have more time he was
always so stressed out about not having
enough time hey welcome MC West Mike is
another person that I I would love to
see come into hash church as often as
possible uh and I'm sure he does you
know when he comes in he lays it down
and he shares the knowledge and uh what
more can you ask for
really yeah Kyle well you know it's a
trip right cuz the ego is
um it's kind of like who your
individuality it's your you know it's
your choice and it's the voice that
pushes and directs you it's your little
motor that runs and so it's important to
have an ego uh I'm sure that probably
where we come from before we are born
and probably where we go after we perish
uh is a very egoless place where all and
everything is connected and it's you
know it's not this unique uh aspect of
life which is to be fractioned off into
this Singularity which is your own
uniqueness which is your ego so I'm down
with it um I don't mind it it's good to
keep the ego in check but I'm definitely
not someone that is tries to have no ego
because my ego uh is my passion it it's
the thing that uh that that drives me my
driving
force yeah well we come from the truth
and we go to the truth and uh so this
experience is kind of a unique small
small experience where we're outside of
that and there might be other things to
explore uh so many people are trying to
get back to where we came from or get to
where we're going going I'm more focused
on being here where I am and uh just
exploring that while it while it occurs
you know from our limited experience
what we know about it is that it's uh
it's very
um it's short it's very short so enjoy
it while it's here live life eat well be
kind have empathy and compassion and of
course enjoy incredible phyto canabo
whether for the recreation or the
medicinal or even the preventative uh
all different aspects but definitely um
all accessible through cannabis and its
resins yeah Ron exactly oh right on
Chase do a fat dab for bubble man I am
pretty stoked to have done this little
puff Wednesday I'm nervous about my
phone falling and breaking it kind of
shifted a second ago so uh I may come
back and do another dab and have another
puff Wednesday party too but in the
meantime I feel pretty good with that
knowledge drop uh short but sweet I hope
uh yeah that you guys have a wonderful
day and uh pretty incredible that since
I started
this sun has come out so
beautifully thanks for sharing your time
with me everyone I do appreciate it and
uh May the full melt bless your bowl
sooner than later peace
out