[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
here in West Vancouver right on the
water you can see the Lion's Gate Bridge
in the background and there's a ship
that's coming through right now there's
uh basically you've got West Vancouver
on this side here and as you go over the
bridge you end up in Stanley Park which
is that right there I of course have my
fab EG with my Banger which I got from
DC glass thank you Dark Crystal glass
and I guess today what I'm going to do
is a little a little show on just
traveling around Vancouver and West
Vancouver and ripping bowls I obviously
have my license so if I go to a private
area a public area where you know no
one's around and I'm able to do rips
Without Really uh being in breach of any
laws which is
awesome um so I saw this deck out here
and I thought this is where we'll start
the day we'll do a couple of
rips couple of rips out here and then
we'll head into maybe the mountains
maybe go up to Cypress or maybe head
over to
grous I don't exactly know but we see
what happens we got a couple of Japanese
people coming and we'll see what uh what
they think of this
all
right Japanese people get ready for a
dab because that is what is happening
here
today all right here we
go
I suspect they're curious as to what it
is I'm
doing maybe we better have another rip
and let them let them
see yeah I think that's a good idea
they're stretching right
now I almost want to move the camera and
show you guys because it's so
funny Good Old West
Vancouver
all
right and now I've got a bird as my
guest here the bird is the
word what's up bird what's up
what's up this is a Brave
Bird
anyway that concludes the first part of
our session we will catch you in the
mountains well I was just dumping out
the water from the Fab egg and man if
this little bird didn't come check it
out it's like he wants to take a rip
want to take a rip
buddy there you
go there you go there he's taking a rip
just being silly hanging out with nature
this bird's getting a little closer
now he doesn't want to hit this guy to
get whatever it is he's possibly
getting thought it was kind of
funny all right so I am here in the
Beautiful Lighthouse Park trees
everywhere behind me above me really
beautiful Park Lighthouse Park in west
Vancouver nice to be able to come do all
the trails lots of people walk in their
dogs um I have been looking for water
and I've literally found the smallest
little trickle right
here
so without further
Ado I
guess what we're going to do here
is try and get
water into the Mother
Ship here we
go all right let's see what we can do
here gentle gentle gentle
Mothership adding the
water get in there it's all rock here so
you want to be real careful with uh at
the last last one I was I used ocean
water if you can
imagine last time here last little bit
guys for all of you cringing out there
in in the world of
YouTube that wasn't so
bad now uh here's the question do we go
down or do we go up I think we should do
both let's go down first have a quick
rip then we'll head back up I found a
really nice spot in the forest where I
wanted to share a rip with you guys so
let's do
that all right well looks like we found
the next spot for
sessions uh you saw how I had to put
water in this
thing but we're going to get those nice
bubbles because of
it so
without too much further Ado let's torch
up the
Banger I like the quartz because it
seems to hold its heat for a long
time I can hit
it I still manage to get my dab ready in
a
hurry there we
go all right so
get the
Dabber and of course the zash
shishi which is going to be an important
part of
this all right
so this is called multitasking here
people pay
attention
yeah it's
rip respect to this monster tree that's
bent over next to me here you can see
the size of it it's
huge and uh I think we're going to head
down a little bit more we're just right
at the Pacific Ocean and uh yeah I think
it's probably not a bad idea for us
to wrap this up and uh go ahead out
there and have a Bowl in the open ocean
and then I'm going to head back up and
have a bowl in the middle of the forests
so wanted to get all of our bases
covered and I think we're doing a pretty
good
[Music]
job
w
get on there later
maybe we got another
ledge might as well go down one more
ledge right
people
slippery I think we're okay all
right okay all
right put that down for a
second all
right well I think this is a good spot
for us to maybe set up the
camera and have a rip or two I think I
might want to hang out at this spot for
a little bit in
fact oh that's not going to work is it
or maybe it will let's
see got the
torch get the dab got put back inside
I'm guessing no I've got the Dabber TI
it potentially we have everything we we
need all we need
is the hash and oh my goodness it's
right
here oo can I can I access it without
dumping the whole
lot that'll be the
test
oh all right so we're at one of the um
outer Cliff faces of Lighthouse Park
this is a a great place for many people
to come it's right off the post of an
island over here on this side behind me
and in fact right behind me this island
in my hand right now there we go is hut
hut Island I've only gone around it once
myself on a boat but it was pretty cool
and uh yeah I say why don't we get right
to business here got the hash and the
Dabber much closer this time let's heat
up that
nail s
good
I don't know did I Pooch
my did I Pooch my torch let's find
out oh here we
go I fixed it who's this little guy here
see this
little this little guy here he was way
over here and I needed to put him over
here let more oxygen through the hole
there well there you go I'm not very
good with the torch I will
admit that'll be interesting for whoever
is walking above me right now to stick
their head up over the ledge and see me
down here with the Fab EG and the quartz
Banger and the creme brulee
torch a
nice it was nice could see whales could
see Dolphins I don't see either right
now but you
[Music]
could
that was a good one tell you with the
glass on quartz carb cap there that was
probably the best hit I've had so
far
yep best one so
it's one thing to hike through the
forest on a lovely non-rainy day it's
another completely to bring your Fab
egg yeah we roll with our FB bags
through the
forest climbing up Rocky super sketchy
terrain takeing my fab bag for a walk
all right guys so this is going to be
the last place that we hit a bowl
together while we tour Lighthouse Park
together uh this is an easy Park to find
if you want to leave Vancouver you take
the Lionsgate bridge and you go left on
onto Marine it's actually a right and it
Loops you around back underneath but you
follow that into West Vancouver and you
just keep going and going and going and
I mean you go for quite a ways past the
fire department and all these things
before you see this little sign on the
left right by the bus stop they'll say
Lighthouse Park I'm sure you can find an
address in directions if you Google it
but uh there really are some spectacular
trees in this Forest so it's uh it's a
great place to come walk your dog or
walk with your girlfriend or your
buddies and just uh yeah enjoy a few
rips while you're doing it so I've got
my Dabber all loaded over
there mother ship's ready for one more
rip and then I had uh a call with
Horatio Mr D lemon himself and he
thought that he was going to rip down
this way so I'm going to maybe go eat
eat a little lunch after this and then
I'm going to hook up with Horatio and
I'm not exactly sure what we'll do but
we'll probably sit down dab hang out
talk and it usually gets pretty deep
with Horatio I think he's got a tarpine
thing that we're going to do so you guys
will definitely want to stay tuned for
that as that's going to be fun balancing
my Dabber full of dry sift uh CBD Renee
for those that want to know
finding the glass containers to carb
this angled uh Banger
perfectly got to give props to quave for
coming up with that one one very
impressive dude um obviously people are
going to come up and start jacking it uh
qu is the originator um DC glass has
done a great job though with uh with
representing a pretty darn good uh nice
thick cour quartz Banger so there you go
for that wonderful I'll leave you with a
little bit of the
forest
all right well hey guys I'm out of the
forest I'm in my car and lo and behold
Horatio is here what's up welcome dude
what going on it's like you just
appeared rather than actually just spent
the last two hours yeah racing down the
while you were out you know puffing
tough off water ocean Forest it was all
a drive for me just are you going to be
here in 2 hours I'm like maybe maybe I'm
like I don't know if I hang out that
long but uh we've got some excitement
don't we what uh we should let them know
exactly what we're going to do here next
bringing out some stuff once we we got a
little hot box session and then probably
heading back to the lab yeah do a quick
little rip here and then head back to my
zone and uh we're going to pull out a
bunch of fun stuff and go through a sort
of tarpine experiment with Horatio so
that'll be fun yeah got some things
still frozen in the pack oh yeah yeah
see if I can reach for it this is where
it's at people uh the secrets Ling here
ah yes it's not easy when you got to
keep things Frozen no it's the zebra
stripes though that actually preserve
the Turks that's why I got it yeah the
zebra zebra stripes are
actually I I'm pretty sure it's a
scientific fact at this point that zebra
stripes um preserve tpin you can do that
and then if you get pink piping then you
pretty much it'll never butter or white
out straight up it's I heard that the
pink piping is is quite important for
the non- buttering out Factor There You
Go sir all right give you a little
Ripper of this like ancient bubble hash
let's do this just make sure there's
no I know how to smoke those don't worry
about it I'm not giving you any ha to
see what I'm saying took those out like
a
champion and then we use the glass
jar to carb we learned that
today on Mothership 101 with bubble
M nice
nice nice nice
Ripper yeah it's been good BC Style just
every once in a while it's been raining
here the last few days so it was kind of
nice to just get out still cloudy and
dark but perfect for just getting out
and spending a few hours in the forest
ripping away while the police you know
do their thing out on the street and
drive back and forth we just uh they're
not worried we'll just continue to do
our thing
if I saw anybody else hot boxing at the
mall I don't know you want to torch that
one up yeah yeah hot boxing at the mall
we can't be the only ones hot boxing at
the mall in front of the bank I think so
in front of the bank yeah especially
after the Epic places I've just been s
yeah and then it's like let's just hot
box in front dude just pull over just
pull over let just have a session in the
bank right up in front no one's worrying
about the glass or the Torches or smoke
effects
all right no we're just chilling in the
car dash truck I don't know what you
call this
thing the other way the other B thank
you sir Dy Shane that's good hash I
tipped it and it never spilled a
drop still going for this plastic
Tech
yeah oh that tasted so good that was
like Astro Boy or
something
wow well that's good um we're probably
going to hit a couple more of those but
the next time you see us I have a
feeling we'll be somewhere different
yeah out of the car how'd you find the
carbonated water hits that was a
surprise I only had you know what I
didn't mind it the first dry rip I took
of it was not good it was
like kind of grabbed oygen
but now it
seems it seemed fine it'd be interesting
to see what the carbonated water filters
versus non-carbonated water but then
again at that point you could get into
the different PHS you could get into
reverse osmosis you could get into dis
distillated I mean yeah well you get
into distilled water that stuff is
literally stripping everything it comes
in TCT with so it has an upside and a
downside you might find all the turps
are in your water yeah I I think as well
that I have a little bit of a worry when
it comes to distilled water that it
seems that it would strip more good than
bad I mean I use it in my process but
I'm using it in a spot in which I
already know what it's going to do but
it definitely I would rather experiment
with carbonated water or other not that
we're going to go around refilling our
bongs with soda anytime soon but um it
is one of the unique capacities now that
you're pairing water with another
molecule of carbon
it's true you know today just walking
around with the Mother Ship really had
me realize like first I went down to the
the right to the ocean had no water was
like well there's a whole ocean full so
I I filled it up from the ocean uh I
smoked an ocean dab saltwater rips
saltwater rips then I went into
Lighthouse Park where it was just dry
there's no water anyway and I was like I
just kept going deeper and deeper and
deeper and I got to a point where there
was this little like Creek of dribbling
Spring Water rips yeah then I then I got
that in there filled it up through here
yeah and now I'm with you and we're
doing carbonated water that's so [ __ ]
up it's really quite [ __ ] up so
probably we should do some type of water
when we get to the next Z I don't know
maybe plain water I don't plain water it
it could be exciting it could be boring
today maybe artisian spring well I'm I'm
looking there's possibly baby tier water
baby that could be pretty exciting
Unicorn oh made from baby's tears I I
mean when you get really rich you could
do a bubble run with baby tier water
crystal crystal results like a 20 gallon
batch
yeah cuz cuz you know me dude well we're
going to get it's the comments that are
coming over the baby tier water that's
true well you know what right now what
we're really doing is we're working on
an upcoming episode of reading all your
um um how would I put it douchebaggery
comment hater raid comments reading just
the nastiest meanest comments that you
guys write I want to an episode I don't
know who's going to be in it with me but
it'll be funny and we're just going to
take about a dozen maybe more write them
all down and then we'll go through each
one and then we'll kind of talk a little
bit about what it takes for a person
like for a person to watch a particular
video maybe it's a 30 minute video and
maybe you know the part they're talking
about is at like the 28th minute so
these guys have watched 2third of the of
the video you know they must have gotten
something more out of it but this is the
thing that they choose to comment on so
explode yeah why is that guy squeaking
his chair
though yeah it's interesting anyway so
we're going to have that that'll be up
and coming and so you're going to hear
us making lots of jokes as we get to
that episode because we want to get uh
we want to get you guys uh commenting
with your best comments that you
possibly can
so I guess we'll see you soon peace out
all right guys Horatio and I are out of
the car and we've head over to high
integrity glass art who is uh shy and
off camera right now actually doing the
wonderful job of heating up what did you
call that piece spinal CL the spinal
clim the spinal
Klein okay then spinal
Klein I was excited to uh to get the
pieces over here it's a right-handed one
I'm left-handed but that's okay it still
works
perfect time to be destroyed after a rip
from uh the
congales
yeah that ought to do
it spinal
Kleine very nice you going to rip one of
those ratio oh
yeah
I often get really great quality highs
visiting him in fact similar the one
time I did hit LH I got a really nice
rush off of it it was unfortunate cuz I
had to leave my wife called me almost
immediately after and I was like
literally like okay I guess I'm driving
now something most people don't really
want to do like I got rocked good in a
good way not like oh I'm uncomfortable
but just really much the the same way I
get rocked when I take a nice hit from
something that's uh that higher end
passes over that was congales 90 Micron
yeah so that's the top of the top right
there grown to pure perfection um uh
flattened out on parchment paper about 3
minutes ago just to show you what she
looks
like rip for
ratio
that little ofz is the optimized flavor
Zone got to admit I like it uh first
time I was passed one I was very
confused but it's got a little uh little
lip in there and you're confused cuz you
put this big piece the the tube down
into the uh quartz so very cool ofz
beautiful isn't that just a lovely
flavor on H I don't know the dabs are
big I think it's the dabs well it's a
big dab for sure but uh they're not
small dabs I was tempted to take half of
it but after I took half of it I was
like well me too there was a moment
where the you're like wait a minute
there's a full dab still on this or a
dab and a half yeah and then I'm like
all just finish just finish it just
finish it it through I mean you're
hitting at a such a beautiful piece it's
it's almost like you deserve to hit a
rock and roll dab on the day that uh you
hit a piece such as this it's got that
sweat out Mothership on the edge there
that's really
nice
always always top quality at high
integrity glass art let me tell
you super
sweet one of your percies oh yeah yeah
nice yeah that's about the size maximum
for me with personal if it gets any
bigger than that I it doesn't belong on
my desk it seems like something I'm
going to hit
myself it's incredible how actually
handleable this pipe is for these
spinals you know like you can
actually put your fingers on each spinal
column and
Scott everything he does I think uh
Precision so ridiculous hey
Scott deppy for the win
boom
brother ex that for a dab
rag pretty damn sweet all right so next
up the brindle Farms mix guava and some
other
things here we
go
oh that was much more reasonable that
was I'd say a third the hit but still
very tasty very nice always happy to be
puffing on
that super
sick it's like a machine over there just
cutting off just I feel like we're just
like sitting here okay he's working it
over there I like me some guava about
that it had a real nice flavor to it
what else did you say might be in there
sweet blue sweet
blue love those blues man I'll tell you
the blue suede shoes that the triome
heavy extracts guys the melts that they
had in Amsterdam this year it was
unbelievable like blueberry yogurt it
really did have a unique like I wanted
to make dry sift with it well there you
know those like there's those things
where I'm like the name just matches the
effect to the point you know you believe
um without having a even skunkman Sam
was like what's that like everyone that
smoked it or smelled it was like what I
want to try that so right on guys props
on that I think it was a contender too I
think it took like second or third at
the uh Legends and then I saw them up on
stage as well at the Cannabis Cup and I
don't know if they Ed dabad do but I'm
sure if they did they would have cr
probably gotten some type of award there
as well they always seem to be in the
top top
rank man is that nice
eh take this
that well that was nice I didn't know we
were going to do another rip In This
Very spot you're driving maybe next time
will be somewhere different I'm not
driving for like 4
hours hey guys Horatio and Bubble Man
man back again we just uh finished up at
high integrity glass art and he just you
know annihilated us with three Wicked
hits uh really nice piece that we were
puffing out one of the Scott deppes
always a pleasure to hit a Scott deppy
piece it's nice to see that spine piece
personally yeah absolutely so partio has
pulled out some of his train wreck uh
dry sift which sorry to show you my
nasty dirty nails but let's just see if
we can't show you the quality of
that
can we get close enough
or I think the front camera wants to
give us the love but we'll show you
another angle of that you can see we're
sitting in front of my tent here got
about six little plants in bloom couple
under the Lush light over there got the
2XL Dominator up and uh got an HPS
between Horatio and I so if you want to
light that up
Horatio
where did I just
do lien up the Mother
Ship oh this looks like a really nice
color sticky as [ __ ] too that train
wreck is that was the hardest thing I've
sifted so far it was ready to
smear okay I'm going to need to that was
a cold
sip ooh this is going to be a nice one
and you're going large oo you can go no
wa this is yours baby all right well
you're going to hold the piece for
me Don Shan Don
Shan a got no
car
oh nice nice nice sift on that one htio
good job too there's a tiny little hair
on that guy if you want to clean that
off yeah we'll get you a rip so yeah we
got
uh what do we got sour G atomical
Haze um watermelon over here we got U
Congo Afghani and Barb in the back Congo
right here in the front then Afghani on
the left side and just over to the right
is Barbara you can see they're already
producing nice little round heads at
only 2 weeks into flower they're even
outshining the Astro Boy over there
which uh will of course look really good
when it's finally done it's uh it always
does sorry about the shaky camera here
guys it has been a little bit of a cell
phone episode but I figure better
something than nothing right all right
let's do this
sticky I was not ready hold this for you
all right got
that yeah I wasn't ready either I stuck
the Dabber in with one hand holding the
phone I was like oh yeah this will
work oh we're going to film another
video after this aren't we hell yeah we
got let's tell them a little bit about
what we're doing well I brought by some
wet undried Bud the dried bud
that comes from my turp isolation
process just kind of actually being able
to go wow I see what is lost I see what
is there um before the drying process
which a lot of us don't get to
see
puffing in my garden with
Horatio good
times so that's good we're going to uh
finish up this video saying thanks for
watching and joining and hopefully you
puffed a bowl at least every time we
puffed a bowl and uh yeah why don't we
head up to the office and film this next
level episode of TPS and herbs and sifts
and lhos let's do
this TFO TFO see you guys in a bit
[Music]