[Music]
well welcome to bubbleman's
World medtainer John in the house and
this lovely lady would you like to
introduce her John well it's actually
your introduction this is the watermelon
this is the watermelon this is the Astro
Boy from TGA genetics and it was
originally bred accidentally actually by
bad boy who had he was breeding I can't
remember the three strains that he had
in the male pollen but he basically came
up with this bad boy uh the Astro Boy
this is the watermelon feno and um we
actually if you watch the video of me in
Nelson or in Proctor when I was with my
good friend Ron hickey we were making
bubble together outside in the snow and
we ended up making the watermelon bubble
he gave me a cut or two and I brought
them back and spread them out amongst
friends John and myself and John managed
to grow them up really nice and big and
healthy and pass some out and then I got
mine uh nice and big and healthy this is
one of mine right here actually that
were uh [ __ ] I love these little plants
man oh man I got mine in flower I'm both
incredible structure on that plant too
like the the arms you know the the arms
are so strong on these guys right here
these particular side branches I'm
really impressed with the beautiful I
got all these beautiful and just and
clones you can cut off of it are just
for me and this is just one of my little
uh my little babies that I got going on
I I don't have too many plants I'm
allowed to have a 98 in my license but I
I'm one of those few people that are
actually using the license just for for
medicine and not using it to pay my
mortgage and stuff so uh I only have
like seven plants going thanks to John
for uh bringing them over um and I also
have the watermelon bubble a bunch of
the watermelon bubble actually from from
the watermelon yeah so this this is from
my cutney trip see if we can get you
focused in there oh yeah real nice so
that's some 73 Micron my favorite right
there so I think we'll start you off
with that John if you want to pull
yourself out a little hit and I will get
the pipe over to you over there great
thing about the Dil is these uh nice
long whips that they give you with it
it's always move the hash out of the way
of the whip yeah yeah the Whip's nice
though in the sense that it's not so
first me I'm going to Puff the
watermelon beside the watermelon puffing
the watermelon beside the watermelon
very nice
nice
rip all right so some 73 for John there
you go what else we got here oh here's
um actually this one we say second run
on this one and it was the 90 Micron 90
Micron second run you see the quality on
that you'll see that not too much of the
powder is falling out it's pretty much
crunchy crun take care on that like like
two months yeah there was like a 2 and 1
half month cure on this particular stuff
so I mean this hash particular two to
three weeks of of just drying get to get
it into a situation where it could
cure all right golden scoop so yeah it's
uh when I when you look at it it's it's
crunchy it's beautiful and then if you
push together it's just perfect so yeah
it's uh you wouldn't think it's bubble
hush you would be like wow what's
this just want to give a shout out to
subcool and Jill the TGA crew they've
always been sort of family they've
always really um uh backed us and
promoted bubble bags and the and and the
way of of water extraction and they've
always been just good people sharing and
educating and and passing on you know
great genetics like
a plant like this I feel is is a special
plant it's a very special plant so I
guess um we've got our injunction
Happening Here in Canada we're hoping on
the 18th of March that we're going to go
to court and we're going to find out
that our uh licenses will be extended
that's pretty much what has to happen
for us that's what's going to happen and
before that John and I are off to Spain
for spannabis so if any of you out there
are you know going to be in Spain you
can come check us out what Booth will
you be at uh probably the plan ofur
Booth plan ofur so I'll either be at um
medical seeds I think that's booth
number 78 cania kabia yeah I'll be at
cania or I'll be at the hoodland booth
as well as another potential booth that
I'll be at as well so you'll see us
walking around you'll see us there if
you're if you're around come say hi if
you've got some beautiful hash please
definitely approach me we're going to be
filming a little documentary with uh
Tony from River Rock you can come puff
with me and yeah of course yeah you can
come puff with John as well but we are
filming a documentary and we want to see
the best hash that we can see so if you
do see me and you and you feel that you
have something you want to show off make
a point on stopping and showing me um
you want to hit some uh more of this
water n and John I think there would be
something we could do how about this F
minute run five minute run yeah I mean
that second run I just did was great
pretty pretty delicious actually a five
minute run yeah this is a first the 5
minute run people might well the amount
of mixing that happened for this
particular batch was 5 minutes so it's
just like the first first mix yeah it
didn't yeah it's the first mix it didn't
mix for you know the best mix a super
long amount of
time pass it over that people always ask
about that you know I always people ask
me and because I mean oh I like this
m nice get a nice whiff of the plant
while you're that was probably the
nicest dab I've ever delivered the dab
over a plant have you dabbed over a
plant lately
darn fine darn
fine denail rips with the watermelon
plant yeah you like loaded that one off
for me yes I always like to be generous
with my good friend John who's helped me
so much with my grow tent and all my
equipment and help me with plants and
get me my license and yeah you know what
super thankful for just like everybody
for
all all want help one another That's it
man that's what it is that's it thank
you look what you've helped me with I've
learned so much on making hashes and
proper extractions and really taking a
better look at how I'm growing my triome
and not you know what I mean I talk so
much about it but well now you're
focused on growing tricomes more than
growing
plants I take a better look at it 100%
because you're using just it's
definitely now I'm just my like my my
next videos are all on just I'm taking
my whole everything's going to Hash I
like the sounds of it's beautiful you
know what fresh froz and we're going to
freeze whole plant freeze the whole
thing yeah that's definitely what's
happening to my entire this whole plant
right here when it's buted out I'll show
you on video I'll be taking it I'll be
potentially hanging it over a screen and
doing some light bouncing of the whole
plant over a screen collecting the very
very finest that we can separating any
stigmas or cyith hairs capitate stocks
um uh pistolet hairs any of those things
will get out we'll have the purest of
the pure of the pure and then from there
I'll probably uh wet wash the majority
of my my crops and I might make a little
bit more dry sift depending we'll see
what happens there you go yeah I'm
pretty excited about it let's hope that
we can continue to do it oh you know
what let they're saying there in the
local papers and stuff you know a lot of
the Mayors aren't taking a look at these
small Growers that are growing a few
plants and stuff like that you know
they're not saying it's legal but um
like ourselves and stuff like that you
know there small little medical grows
for medic
mhm you know what take a look at law I'm
not going to get into the whole we've
talked about this on our previous shows
but absolutely pay attention to the
courts on March March 18th and then wait
for outcomes on the 31st hopefully and
let's just pray and uh you know what uh
we're getting close here to 420 I think
and and our next and our next puff
Wednesday is going to be in Barcelona
yeah we'll be arriving in we'll actually
be arriving in Amsterdam for our next
puff Wednesday so our next puff
Wednesday could potentially be in
Vancouver
in Amsterdam and in Barcelona so how's
that three country puff Wednesday I like
that coming at you
soon and of
course a nice carb
C works well I like that one it's got
the little arrow on the head so just in
case you slip you get a little bit of
[Music]
a oh that watermelon
I know see how H you tonight cler
beautiful that's what did to me the
first
time so good so big shout out to Bad Boy
and the TGA crew subcool Jill Ron for
growing this great resin
here and and sharing you know it's funny
cuz he was at my place when bad boy gave
him this cut and so then I end up going
back I get it I give it to John John
takes it to his house he cares for it he
cuts them makes more clones brings a
couple over here and now here it is
again so this is the wonderful thing
about sharing cannabis and I want to
extol upon you the importance of never
hoarding genetics I know you seed
breeders think it's a good idea don't be
a feared uh everyone should share the
genetics do the best job you can
breeding what you've got to work with
but don't feel bad if someone takes your
hard work and and does something
different with it crosses it with
something or makes something that might
even be more interesting than the thing
that you made originally with it maybe
it'll be less uh nice than what you made
originally with it but share those
genetics out there do not hoard strains
it's very important uh if we're going to
claim that this is truly a medicinal
thing and a gift from you know from the
higher Powers then it's a great thing to
share so I'm very happy to be a part of
this little circle of sharing the
watermelon so it's very nice yeah
absolutely you know I got her in a week
four flower oh yeah it's looking amazing
hey you can check her out on John's
Channel um just just my name John Bell
John Bell on YouTube uh you can usually
link it I think i' I'm following him as
well if you can't if you're having a
hard time finding him you can find him
through my channel as well but uh he's
got some great videos of his crop on
there right now of this watermelon I'm
filming it right from you got one and I
put four into flower perfect and so this
is where this would be right now but in
week four out about this bigger and just
looking amazing so you know it's uh
awesome I think uh next to spin next to
Spain so we're going to see you next
week uh we'll probably do a little bit
of a fun show of us heading to the
airport and eating a bunch of caramels
and being all baked on the plane and
then Landing in Amsterdam and we got a
couple hours so we're going to have some
friends meet us there and have a big
session at the airport and then we'll uh
jump on a plane and go to Spain which
will be like a whole other like okay now
this is it's on it's on and I I suspect
that on that flight to Spain we'll
probably Bunch bump into some friends
from from Amsterdam that are also
heading down to Spain it's it's it's
it's the day before spanis exactly yeah
no exactly so thanks for watching uh
we'll see you guys all
soon peace be well
[Music]