[Music]
all right Johnny take two seeing as
though you're in a killer Rush we're
filming it's
snowing you know
what sweetly utterly disgustingly okay
ridiculous I didn't bring the dry sift
you no dry sift no dry sift I didn't put
the hits on each Dabber the way I did
last time so we will stop again we will
stop again
all right Johnny
B we going a Dabber take take
three take three my brother snowing
out it is snowing
out all right hey everybody Welcome to
Bubble man's world welcome to Puff
Wednesday with my good buddy Johnny B in
the house this is our third attempt at
filming this small sequence as the first
time I set up the camera I had left it
on time lapse so if you want to look at
what our our first session looked like
on time lapse this is here now there it
is yeah and so uh in the meantime I was
thinking maybe Johnny B and I could what
we wanted to do was come out and show
you guys a it's snowing like crazy here
in British Columbia right now been
dumping all morning it's been dumping
all month yeah I hit it has well it's
been dumping all winter we don't get
Winns apparently we did this year yeah
that's what I'm
saying it was next level it definitely
snow maybe once or twice tops it's been
snow every every single month of the
year we should start seeing the polar
bears in the bab pretty soon I'm telling
you they'll be back they they're coming
back
apparently come on there we go so there
we go we were talking
about me not getting a TP dip last time
so we're definitely taking care of that
this time good call good call Swiss
tsunami just the way there you go the
way life
works and the way things happen since
I'm wearing the Blue River shirt I'm
also be doing a Blue River dab sounds
like a
plan oh yeah
so one thing we've realized turps taste
so much better when it's cold though
yeah
not we're completely kidding but you
know it does add a little added extra to
the shiver three attempts at this John
that was pretty fun I like that
because I only had one dab though so
this is three attempts two dabs
3 plus two so that means we're going to
do five more there we go see there's a
system to our system well our plan was
to come out here hit a couple of dabs
move ourselves inside where we hit more
dabs show you the quality of the dry sip
that I separated it into these different
piles and then maybe if we still had
time to take the lower quality piles and
send them through the sasquash uh
unfortunately I only have my V1 set up
right now uh as I'm still waiting for
the foot pedal on the V2 but but
uh we still can
press there we go little bit of look at
that little little sizzling on there
from the ice that dripped
through these are ice
dabs ice dabs beautiful let me clean
that for you we're definitely getting
ice
dabs so best thing about this I'm a
little thirsty I got a little bit of ice
right
here it's actually slowing down a little
bit the snow's changing we had these big
white flakes now I see stuff melting
around me yeah little bit of warming up
happening well you know what it is
March it is March but I'll tell you what
they say about
March in like a lion no in like a lamb
out like a lion I only have heard that a
million times due to my birthday being
in March his birthday's coming up it's
true yeah it is it's at the end of
March isn't it yeah it like I'm leg I'm
not going to give it a
days I'm not going to say
it well there's one thing that's pretty
cool about this whole
scenario it's a great time to make hash
cuz it's cold up like you know how hard
it is to make dry sift to do your
sifting when it's like 33° though to 32°
and you're sitting it doesn't go over
that well so when it's snowing on it's
cold pull out your screens pull out your
bags this is the best time to start
making and and actually processing your
hash keep it cold we always say these
two you always told
me yes indeed sorry I'm just counting in
my head so that's
okay cuz the cell
[Music]
phone well that was in the first
episode I like that this is the under
the table dab keeping it warm making Mak
it sure he's not getting the extra added
snow dab like I
got he do not get an ice dab he's oh he
might so pretty
much everybody's headed to Barcelona
right
now yeah everyone's at spannabis
spannabis maybe you're there right now
watching us do puff Wednesday in the
snow and you're probably in 30°
weather
well we're okay with
that cuz we yummy I hit the Tangi we got
the best hash and TPS in the world right
in front of
us kind of works out that
way well some of the best as well that's
the beauty of sharing the knowledge and
helping educate others as to how to do
this that you can be anywhere in the
world and have the greatest hash in the
world
we're going to head
inside after some tasty dabs and we will
see you in a few
peace hey guys uh I'm back inside now
unfortunately Johnny B is no longer with
me that kind of sucked we blew a bunch
of time and um he actually had a um
situation arise where he had to go back
to his office and take care of some
business so I don't know um we ended up
breaking up the dry sift uh ended up
with 60 G of heads versus um I guess
just over 42 G of what I would call
contaminant but still a squishable
product I really wanted to squish it for
you guys I thought it was going to be
kind of fun but he told me off camera
that he actually wanted to give it uh to
the gentleman who produced it so that
makes sense that he would want to see
the quality differences and everything
that got separated so maybe next time
we'll get to squish that in the
meantime I just put a little bit of my
really high-end dry sift in this little
packet just a small amount Maybe a half
gram maybe a gram I don't even know how
much it was exactly but I figured we'd
do a little sasquash press I've got my
V1 back in Action as I'm still awaiting
uh the foot pedal to set up my air
compressor to the V2 which is actually
just at the foot of the um tripod here
so I guess waste no more time let's uh
get a little squish in and see what we
can produce from this dry
sift
ice
reaction
satisfaction 73 night
[Music]
miziz
night
50 k Cru Manu
[Music]
D
askar Mana herbalist The canab
Specialist Mana herbalist
her
[Music]
special pull it upse and give it a sliff
him turn around
I yes and I also
got all right so that was a fine little
squish ended up with this sort of
buttery like substance took some macro
photographs of it to give you guys a
little bit of a better idea as to the
Quality uh of what we're dealing with
here I didn't weigh the first amount but
it was a very small small amount of hash
probably less than half a gram and it
looks like I got almost half a gram back
so good return I would say
pressed out a little bit of that dryy
sift as
well which we can see the quality of
right here although better than that um
better than that I can show you the
unpressed hash uh there was 60 G of
heads if you can believe it and uh here
is my
chunk kind of get an idea of the quality
here let me see if I can't get in even
closer for
you here we
go all right so as you can see by the
color not by the smell cuz you can't
smell it but I can
attest there's a difference in the smell
of 99.9% gland head when you clean it up
and you get it to this perfect perfect
place that uh you just lose that
whatever that sometimes it's almost
haish almost greenish almost plant
matter esque I've seen it in bubble has
I've seen it in dryft butth this is void
of all of that it's a very very Sandy
and thick texture when you touch it it's
hard it's not fluffy and light it's
really thick and hard so why don't we do
um a quick little rip got the sapphire
all cleaned up here as you can see
hitting hitting a little warmer than
usual actually it's at 660 de I'm
usually more out of
580 but um with the dry sift I like to
hit it a little hotter um with the rosin
I usually turn it down a little bit so
why don't we put a little of this dry
sift mixed with a little of this buttery
kind of cake batter
rosin there we
go nice dab and then let's do a Blue
River tpine I've got a nice selection of
TPS here um let me see we've got the
Jack Frost the Clementine The Swiss
tsunami the Tangi the karma [ __ ] and
the lemon tree um I want to go Karma's
[ __ ] it's just one of my favorites I
love that uh Neville wreck I believe
which is in
there nville wreck crossed with the rd1
I
believe all right here we go gearing up
getting
ready for a puff Wednesday without
Johnny B I don't mind telling you I miss
you Johnny B it was kind of like pretty
fun we're having a good time out there
in the snow it's still snowing like
crazy by the way and uh off you had to
go so I'm going to cut this puff
Wednesday fairly short not get too much
further into it other than enjoying a
nice rip of the Rosen press and the dry
sift that uh I cleaned up so please join
me if you have your rig ready three two
1 let's do this
actually maybe just
maybe I can get even a little bit
closer the portability of these nails
get a little bit closer and show
you
the the bowl all right here we
go
that was a serious
rip that was a puff Wednesday rip thanks
for watching Everybody two thumbs up
[Music]
reaction
give me
[Music]
this
know I
I
[Music]
give