[Music]
funny bone but it's in my knee
it's a funny time okay so welcome to
bubble man's world puff Wednesday with
Johnny be in the house you know what
congratulations thanks dude thanks you
guys to meet my little boy come over I'm
gonna busy myself you know of course be
enough see like I'm in the dark so yeah
being a new dad but will be sooner sorry
to interrupt
I'm just saying it look you look good
well thank you man
well and of course I decided to make
hash and I want to come over
and bringing of course what I love so
much is the Medicus dude I'm so stoked
in your Medi cush I'm 73 right off the
bat right to the 73 right to the 73 it's
Tufts of course I decided to mean it
really nice well today Joan and I are
going to make some hash huge surprise to
surprise you guys we're gonna make some
hash we're gonna do we have excellent so
this is crispy and pour some dumping in
on that stream over there so we'll
probably show you doing that of course I
got really not too much dry screens but
this is something I wanted to share with
you guys we wanted to do a quick little
well show you a little trick we've
showed it already a few times and it's
uh it's a quick and easy way to access
near pure Glen Head dry cept and in
smaller amounts john was gonna do it
here last time he was here but the herb
was a little bit moist totally taken
home and dry it more he's dried it out
real good so now it seems like we'll be
able to we'll be able to see the results
along with you guys and I think they're
gonna be pretty good results because
it's really nice herb and that was
delicious delicious you wanna hit it
with the never
he quit the job okay yeah then I think
I'm I'm good I'm risking it here right
now
accident I'm not gonna choke though so
my only dunno I think you gonna choke
it's a pretty wicked hood
here she goes
the flavor saver who doesn't make quite
a difference so yeah we're looking
forward to showing you a little bit of
that hash that John brought here I'm
gonna photograph it with my macro lens
just look at it it's unbelievable
this is no truly beautiful beautiful no
it's a really pretty thing that's gonna
be a popular shot already I can tell
well you flipped it upside down and
that's why we're not pumping it and then
our good friend Mike who was on the show
not too long ago came with me did a
little boot up towards Squamish yes he
brought me the God the Oh God crossed
with the purple metallic haze Wow it's
got some terms so let's get you a rip of
that see what you think of that this is
a congratulations on your new Sun hash
which has been really cool to receive
that's pretty awesome yeah
all right we got super melty nice just
presses into a most beautiful
transparent most beautiful piece
mine still won't be maybe guesstimate
yeah his is like three or four months
old Wow yeah
yeah yeah forget it's for you John right
I'm ready
John's ready
if you gonna give me that whole thing
are you well it's just me major boiling
nice to share dad UK friends today is
actually a sad day on the memory banks
for me so the anniversary of my father
and his wife and their accident nine
years today nine years where you say too
bad a speeches I'm speechless was a
great hit
yeah so there it is
that was the Oh God purple metallic haze
it takes the God bud can you taste that
that very pronounced I don't know I
always compared it to that weird purple
gum that tasted like soap that they put
in your mailbox and like the ladies it
was like a marketing campaign any you
guys remember that smooth gum tasted
like soap free gum showed up in the in
the mail weird Canadian thing it'll be
interesting to see if anyone remembers
that I suspect that we will have people
that do remember it and not only that
they'll even name it that's great why
don't we go recover and we'll set it up
here so we can we can dry sip some of
this butter real quick and then we'll
whip off a quick batch in the Buffs yeah
okay all right so it's time to do a
little quick dry sifting we've got the
two I guess these would be what three
feet by two feet or is a one foot by two
foot two feet by one foot I'd say these
are you can pick them up at fresh head
acecomm
and the dry six section and this is a
ninety ninety lines per inch or mesh
count and a sixty lines per inch or mesh
count so those numbers of cords 60 is a
250 and 90 is
180 so they're counterintuitive numbers
from micron
however these little screens offer a
nice ability to acquire a full melt dry
sift pure 99% gland heads and a really
quick amount of time so we've got Johnny
B's astroboy here awesome awesome so
that's a real small small amount we
dropped you know less than an ounce onto
the onto the screen and we did it in a
way where we really cost very little
friction whatsoever so let's just check
it out to see what fell through well
that's very very small about it looks
almost all like just pure heads so let's
put a little bit more on there so we
know we've got well I guess I could try
to card up the bottom first let's see
what we got I'll use the method 7
sticker the good people at method 7
sounds over oh yeah super super small oh
it's there ready
all right nice I haven't crushed it
either I get some of this crush on there
some of the crush how long did you drive
this for um what about specs we've been
sitting in a bowl since the last time I
was here thanks Allah yeah which was
what a week or two ago
uh yeah a week ago last puff Wednesday
it was actually hanging for about two
and a half weeks it's been two weeks ago
because I think my son was born on the
last pump one doesn't mean so me two
weeks so last plus Wednesday before you
saw this one it's soy okay
I was thinking out loud in my brain
without saying anything
yep today I'm camera back and I just to
see what we got this time around quite a
bit more has fallen it really looks
almost all glandular though it does very
small amount of contaminant there
although I guess on the Camry you can
see it is much more contaminant let's
see what we got off the bottom
well there's more visible there this
time around
definitely color on that quite lovely
there you go yeah you know just then you
could do that over and over and over
again by moving the material gently you
can also get the second batch that's
just sitting on top I just give that the
flick the trick test leak check and once
again you can now fold with you see how
flexible this yet since we don't big go
for that look at the different colors
even though hey see how the one's a
little lighter finish it let me stand
microphones on this as it goes
you want to make some bubs well I think
it's that time let's do it
alright Johnny B so I'm gonna dab up
some of that the first dry stuff that we
just made
and I definitely did alright well the
smaller pile is the a why don't you take
that one we're gonna go for the end it's
going to be become a little difficult
for you got this
okay okay there we go
one hit here I see too well in there but
melt it out
nice taste
very tasty you can definitely um I'm
getting used to the taste of the
asteroid I love the variance and well
welcome back to bubble man's world we've
we pulled it off we it's the next day
and we've got our energies back and
we're gonna make this hash aren't we
John we're gonna make some wicked fresh
frozen
we got super bubbled up yesterday and it
was my bad anniversary of my dad and my
stepmom and it was just kind of I just
wasn't feeling it but I think I'm
feeling it now everything's right here
and ready so details live yeah we've hit
a couple of reps already as you can tell
by John's slur the slur hid in the foam
AHA well you know what it was it was
actually we went from this beautiful on
god oh god purple metallic haze cross
with some coarse netted cushion then we
haven't even looked at this what flap
left with blah blah lab was here earlier
I didn't manage to get any film on him
he was only here for half an hour but I
am gonna film with flap in the near
future so you will see an upcoming video
of flap and his garden and yeah there's
that I know I saw seven years seven
years seven right hey
what might that be nice
you know just crush it some of that over
some screens and I are you gonna do some
fresh frozen ice a so yeah that's pretty
awesome so first we're doing some dry
sipping with some astroboy that I had
and now we're gonna run your fresh
frozen yeah this been sitting in my
freezer for a while like since before I
went to Jamaica I think maybe even the
first time for this summer strips and so
I actually have two bags of it you can
do all this in one run oh that's gonna
be a decent little fresh frozen run it's
not huge some I thought we might test in
my little pony and I brought in my
little pony fresh so let's see what we
got here - see that's beautiful
[Music]
this is not the happy night that we
talked about go cut the best but it is
what it is make a nice layer for us see
I just moved to hash move something that
I did is I just crumpled up the bugs
laughing come on mmm that smells amazing
it really does and of course mmm organic
grown yeah so nice OG Astro Boy oh gee
thank you so cool thank you
bad boy thank you because I'm me girl
without hope this give me something me
and thanks Ron and that Ron's friend
whose we had to go to the house and pick
up the mothers alright so what the
layers of ice layers of our layers of
ice deserve a bit of squishing on this
because we're definitely going more in
I'm not broken up too big either most
everything's down to a reasonable size
piece might still be yeah it was a while
ago that I cut these down but you know
it's nice you just pop them in the
freezer and wow they break up nice the
resin you guys like really you can
exceed blistering here right now it's
all over my hands
yeah that's the best so that's one thing
I like that Astro Boy the Barbra this is
the bomb that's all I know they all melt
just so beautifully and this is just
another one of those stuff you can see
the raw heads on my fingers I smell a
little bit better count I'm gonna have
one of those coming up one day and we'll
be smell can be able to push a button
you know the smell when we smell oh yeah
this one's crispy that's the bag crisp
crisp and snappy it's like it's freshly
frozen ice dry man this is makes me
happy
[Music]
and you guys think Johnny B is well
deserving of a rip
[Music]
I'm going for all of it you're scuffin
that bad oh yeah
so probably each bag weighs roughly I'm
gonna say about you each bags about a
half a pound wet
so that's won't be a pound of wet so
probably looking at about a quarter
pound of dry you can definitely see that
that is some killer killer fun I've done
a couple of times you always got to make
sure that you tie this bag yeah tie the
zipper it's kind of important pretty
darn important if you don't want the
thing leaking out into your I mean I
still use a 220 bag as you can see in
the bucket behind me however I was
talking me about that because I haven't
been I mean picking the bag would do the
job for me but I've been instructed nope
well I mean I'm not instructing no I you
know do as you please
[Music]
so this is what you should be doing
without your fresh buns
it's what John and I like to do anyway
you know a lot of people kind of can't
wrap their heads around it but we always
go back to the sort of education that
we're seeking it's like if you ordered
pizza you want to eat the pizza well if
you're growing herb you want to use the
resident Wow look at how green that came
in right away John Trippi ok well let's
uh let's get her going here we go let's
go her what do you say six six to nine
minutes
nine minutes my last time I did go check
it out with the smell smell-o-vision
yeah that's right real nice color on it
too yeah this is gonna be delicious
that is some terpene rich bubble hash
water and we're definitely gonna be
taking a sip of it once she's done
mixing up and we're ready to pull the
bags I like I like your actions Jonathan
I like it all right well this thing is
just stopped mixin yeah I've got excited
it was good I was like why does myself
put some nice colors beautiful color
beautiful that is a good smell I have to
say that's [ __ ] if it's me so I guess
rather than wait any amount of time
because we know there's no reason to
leave that [ __ ] soaking in water for
longer than you need to send being
collected immediately look at that no
maybe I could not turn in then show what
we're used to seeing you know
you gotta love Johnny beat alright so
here we are with the Congolese and some
Sorrell plants from Jamaica with the
Ortega in the background it's not I'd
introduce everyone it's not growing in
my garden yet it's not the Congolese is
being amazing we're definitely gonna do
another run on this almost immediately
perfect I think it's a good idea I think
so a loud annoying
although I guess let me just leave this
right now rather than look is it right
now it's not in water first
we'll pull facts and then we'll get this
guy riding that way they can kind of
stick with us while we're pulling the
bags otherwise at that time if the job
didn't do some work now all you gotta do
is pack bowls actually is different
Ward's you get from what's coming out of
this this is right here why I have an
MMA are license this is the entire
purpose I grow cannabis
I wouldn't say mainly I would say only
to procure the glandular trichomes heads
just a little bit of contaminants on
this one I guess we could still collect
notes always worth something shilling
yeah looks like stigma hair is mostly I
don't think they brought my spray bottle
usually have a little spray bottle see
what happens today we're gonna be
freezing what we get it's gonna be
frozen until probably tomorrow and then
it'll be microplaned
160 is pretty much Mt tiny little bets
160 almost an insignificant amount
your brother sir news problemo
yes usually these fresh frozen runs that
are very you know that they could be as
low as 50 to 60 grams of dry material
show a ton of contaminant in - oh yeah
[Music]
I'm the one that should be using this
bucket there we go Mario's very very
tiny amount much like a dab which is
okay on this bag but I wouldn't want to
see it on the next three
this one just needs to be rinsed first
house it so rinsed all right so now the
120 my color as you can see with the
shirt that I'm wearing drain them slow
so I guess they'll be a little bit of
bubble in this watch and definitely see
it from here
[Music]
what's up well the hash looks damn near
orange when you're flipping it around
that's pretty cool that's actually
pretty pretty cool I've never taken a
good look at it but as you pull that you
can just see all this that's cool it is
it's really cool
take a good look at your next time water
running take a look at the 90 water
before you pull the bag now it looks
almost like you're looking in a lake
yeah it's a really really cool guy yes
rinse yes great way to save heads any
little bits that are on the on the
screen this is a great way to get them
off especially that 120 you over there
with the creaminess that it was you know
clean
all right 90 you this is very here why I
have a license
almost in a day I'm gonna let the orange
love the black I love the yellow isn't a
white smile on my face
the BOK bags a 90 you that's just a
great bag
this is me wanting to help but I'm just
gonna like stay away all right that's
beautiful this little pile there of some
creamy goodness and if you definitely
see a difference in the water and Bank
you see it's less like yeah we pulled
out quite a bit
anyway yeah we actually that's
impressive this is a real nice like
unbelievable gooey pile of like right
now I'm jumping for joy inside I can see
that I'm actually jumping for joy for
and as you can see this Johnny and I'm
just the EO is twice the size of the
money that we just pulled so you know
that that 73 is gonna do with you guys
it's close to three times yes
yeah I would say three times just go
thickness of it right yeah definitely
it's uh it's a beautiful beautiful sandy
color I do know that that's gonna be
some picture take me there oh yeah
that's so nice to be making a batch
beautiful awesome that one in the 73 bag
is the heaviest of the three so far
notice that we're running right now our
a really heavy oh my god does it smell
that this is so incredible so tasty
mmm-hmm look at the way that came up -
I'm not gonna conceal it looks purple
almost I'm seeing I'm looking at just
the way it's though the Y it looks
pretty cool and it looks to be like
potentially more than then the 45 you
know was actually gonna be probably
really good - that's a efficient 1973
about the same maybe a little bit more
than the 70s right but you're gonna be
able to see all this fuss little big
just great as you can see I'm always
speechless when I'm looking at just epic
resin so there's not those little
minutes and I'm just like a brother
pushing back and taking out the same
time all right there we go yes I was
passing it over I could see the niceness
on the screen I was like I'm making a
mistake here
[Music]
all right 45 micron bag drained in about
five seconds that's fun to balance I do
I always balance but that's that's a big
pump bag and you cease water yeah under
the water be to the screams in the resin
stays I said I said 45 nice pulls nice
pulls
getting that at all and then he sort of
clarity pretty nice and I think the last
thing I pulled up this was Astro Boy
that's for sure yeah it's real nice
about six weeks I guess
six weeks of water yep 42 days yeah
doesn't show any difference with
presence of mouth better yeah I think
this residents all gonna really nicely
oh yeah I think I in there you're in the
cam halfway in halfway out
forget the wide angle on Johnny yeah for
sure
take it easy all around the road with
cannabis legalization nonsense I know
it's pretty awesome it is it's really
awesome
we're waiting on all these cool things
to occur in the next you know upcoming
year it's gonna be just exciting to see
what will be exciting is when we start
going from country to country and
puffing on resin like this absolutely
sharing our knowledge rich so these two
that we have right here will be put in
the freezer immediately which I'm going
to do right now
I'm gonna do guys not gonna get very
cute this tank it right into put these
bags right back in the bucket one thing
I do find is when I'm doing my second
right off the back end with the 45 so we
didn't release it from the last one but
as you can see it's quite easy it's
really it's a non-stressful long
strenuous
about a ton of markets back here how
these things ready I'll be able to turn
on that machine now one thing I just did
is I turned the leg inside out but I
always want to have the label when I'm
folding to the outside and not to the
inside where the bags are structured
here so when you put in the bag and
always make sure that when you fold it
over you see the see this a bubble
bubble bags I should say
that would not be good
go with the My Little Pony some stuff
that round actually last Wednesday
around this mark was waiting for a son
to be born I figure I was going to bring
some bubble hush Oh Jonny bees hitting
home just in time for more bags do that
a second well I was working away and
then my back
how's a good chunk
I think I did this one for 14 weeks what
did i do I think it was 10 weeks did you
do oh yeah that jerk waters nice I got
the B right here he's been hanging over
the wasp he's okay
he's cool I'm not gonna bite Johnny
Beast he's just like what's going on
guys he's the commune with Johnny B he's
not getting bit he's landing on my head
he's definitely some of the turkeys in
that water that's what he's after right
now well I want to put those other two
bags in a bucket then we'll get another
bags go in here
makes it other batches in the freezer
freezing away I think there's plenty ice
inside here put the rest in there to
where it does the most work well sure
you have in contact with herb so was
that all three minutes yeah yeah oh no I
left one bag downstairs actually I only
brought up to now it should be fine yeah
especially with this cold water
[Music]
well shall we rock it up for another six
to nine minutes to get clicked you want
clickety-click I do quickly needed a
little I'm gonna I'm gonna guess it's
some type of an OG so no Dave really
likes is over just just and
maybe not
[Music]
so for me I did overpacked
oh no you definitely didn't that's what
I'm thinking Tuesday mine was over
packed a nice - good job by the first
run so you wouldn't learn that for the
first time for me but just by getting
excited the only real bummer about that
is the exposure to the water
well sure cuz you're robbing terpenes
from the water as you wash so those
turkeys I guess yes on
don't take it oh yeah look force to be
reckoned with I love that I have just
enough spots but all my bags I know
unless I would say quite nice looking
you know bubble you got when you thought
you were gonna get the best but you kind
of got that you expect this as your
second batch check that 98 that does
look cost you to let that go
anyone lose the RISM of the day let
alone I do dad you would actually pull
the bag and it would be drying and ready
to smoke that's a new product bin deer
could be within the next 25 years but
I'll never forget them yes it is and
this is the second run and it's looks
great
okay new screen dude screams let's just
tear let's just move this over so that's
just kind of funny that
that concentration of scooping up a fine
big Yankee yeah if I don't smoke in your
hands up in my coconut oil the last time
I use 90 put the barbed rice if of 90
there's 99 percent heads
garance I definitely do not smoke no I
have a lot of it do you make it into you
some products so there's different ways
of getting and I just throw it in the
food at this point it's not
decarboxylated it is so we got to eat it
so I find with the stuff that doesn't
burn that bomb on the pipe does great
well in my food oh yeah edibles and
evening those cannabinoids help you yeah
you know so there's something to go over
real quickly like if you were say
diagnosed and you found out you were
fairly ill and you were looking to
answer the question you know what do I
do
I'm getting this question quite a bit
lately and what I'm telling people is
that the best thing really that I'm
finding is to a join the group on
Facebook the endocannabinoids system and
that's a group of people on there that
are
and like-minded information sharing
information in regards to th-these
cancer shrinking properties and to CBD
and different cannabinoid profiles and
their anti-seizure properties and so on
and so forth that's one good spot to
start but in the regards to what you do
to actually help yourself using
cannabinoids my answer is that you
saturate your endocannabinoid system if
you live in a dispensary friend a city
that would mean acquiring salves and
patches sublingual drops I would still
vaporize I would consume a cannabinoid
infusion of either the rick simpson soil
or a bubble hash infused coconut oil or
you know any variety so much variety but
the main the main point is that you know
if you're really you've been diagnosed
with something serious and you're and
you're quite ill you would want to eat a
good solid gram of those pure
cannabinoids you want to eat basically a
grandma bubs okay yeah it has to be
decarboxylated so that's involves
removing a carboxylic acid ring from the
molecules so THC a becomes Delta
tetrahydrocannabinol and CBD a becomes
gamma dial so these are the different D
acid you know removing that molecule
activates these cannabinoids and this is
how you can really improve the quality
of the health of your body of audiences
off your body but there it is right
there that's basically what you want to
eat that would be Moorhead when the
house come around I want to be eating
the 45 I mean the 73 and the 99% money
yeah so you want to look at the
saturation of THC and that's what they
talk about with cancer so it's really
you can do it with the Rick Simpson oil
is you can do with some people are
making it with what grain alcohol
thank you and I make it with screens and
we do it with screens and you know often
coconut oil it seems to be a real nice
sort of natural way that the dry sift
and the wet wash melts just so nicely
into the heated coconut oil
decarboxylate sit and then allows you to
either put it on your skin or eat it a
bit and and just put it on Pizza
anything you want right it's pretty
awesome
yeah dabs up I think I'm gonna hit a
little of this bubbles up my friend Mike
gave me as a celebration of my the birth
of my son week old one week birthday
party their two week birthday party it's
a good way about to see having you know
what I'm gonna celebrate every week
because those first weeks are important
by myself I'm gonna be hitting the MLP
here excellent just because loving the
Bob hits loving the fact that we just
whipped off another batch we're going to
freeze it up so it's gonna be frozen for
some several hours and then I'll
microplane it up I'll show that off I'm
going to do some macro photographs of
the hash before and after micro planing
Lisa melt videos puff Wednesday not too
shabby
[Music]
I'm holding I was holding the mothership
leg up like this you know that's safe
yeah
many sedating sleep whatever you like so
I'm gonna give you the mo ah MLPs
MLP just pouring it in there it's my
favorite and I can see what's it's in
there but we have mine he's gonna grab
it but it's kind of what's left in there
so it was full awesome feature very very
delicious well I can't believe we just
whipped off two batches of bubble
we got the terpene rich water that's my
personal product right there I'll be
pouring that into my plants and we'll
see whether or not there's any
real ability for a plant to uptake what
do you guys think of that is there a way
for a plant to uptake its its intake of
a particular thing to produce more
terpenes I guess if we understood it
that's possible I don't pretend to
understand it the hash on the back of
that tavern it was a bigger piece there
did you realize that as I'm putting lids
on here as that once picked up and flips
upside down so yeah so here I'm gonna
probably talk dabs that bubble makin and
D nail rippin that's what we're doing
here on bubble man's world nice to see
that the weather is kind of coming back
a little bit it was miserable and rainy
yesterday when we did our dry sifting
we've decided against making the bubble
batch outside mints mints
it's cool - I'm traveling to coffee
you're doing a great job Joe
alright well what else do we got oh we
get to chill while that hash waits to
freeze cool yeah let's do some puff puff
passing and we'll see you guys back in a
bit Chinese hey dude go to the beach I
need to smoke that house John all right
sweet well here you want to take the
camera that's awesome well there's the
button to start this car right watch
mama this one that says start engine I
have mine mine's up here mean groans
[ __ ] that's saying it's your wife's car
tell you if I see
yeah definitely a seatbelt warning click
[Music]
plus it's always watching this so I can
kind of give you an idea what's going on
so anyway I was gonna give you this as
for the birth of my son instead of a
cigar that's that's awesome and if you
feel like puffing it down at the water
so be it
I don't wanna take it home you know D
part two then here no
so I guess so I'm puffing this joint and
one not a better time to puff it up what
time is it right now
boy it was 450 and I'm so was we're 20
somewhere we might be lighting this at
5:00 time perfect that is the birth of
time of my son
well we made it to the water
I guess John's decision is that he is
going to puff is pure house joint so
we're not sure if we're gonna go over
and do it on the dock or sit down
I guess we'll figure it out you made a
decision
yeah you should tough this joint within
the next seven eight minutes all right
sounds good
sounds good I like that
all right so Johnny and I came down to
the o'shale Pacific Ocean the how sound
it's looking pretty beautiful was in the
water yes you bet yourself a sword with
a lighter and everything always looking
forward to pure house joint especially
in a puff Wednesday Sophie the weeks
yeah I think we're at about 510 right
now
Oh 509 here sir all right Spock your
topic that's some pretty awesome
some pretty cool it's pretty cool
considering Wednesday at 5:10 one week
ago I was having a son being born five
days five tenderness congratulations and
a healthy one week you'll be better
and it just happened that way I don't
think it was really fun we just ended up
down here as we spent the last 10
minutes trying to find a spot to even
like the joy mother wanted to get this
beautiful so nice out there today I'd
love to be out on the boat on a calm day
like today it's good to go seek out
whales and dolphins and different pods
of cool different fish salmon will be
coming in I'm sure yeah the trap and
crab and frog
DOX even pretty empty there's not that
many boats on and I really wish my boat
was in the water so you know an idea
maybe you could share what do you guys
doing a pup went they with us in the
comments yeah tell us how you guys enjoy
your puffs Wednesday are you guys
inspired to do something special on
Wednesday and get out there and pop some
inspiration maybe we can do something
different yeah we don't want to just sit
in front of the same old same old spot
so we try and come down to different
venues show you an area that maybe
haven't seen it before
man I can't believe a resinous my mouth
is just for lighting this joint it's
awesome that's one thing about just
puffing on really nice residence
we'd be talking a lot about that with a
lot of people lately and ways asking
more more questions on the bubble hash
on hash on the trichomes how it's better
for different equities and they know
there's a lot of good information that
people want to know it's out there you
can find it but if you just want to come
and pop a bowl and maybe catch a good
tip here and there puff Wednesday's
always a good spot to do it bubble man's
world that looks pretty cool that looks
pretty cool where people hold my gosh
like you're gonna show this but I turned
around saw that put a big smile on what
usually happens after about 2 or 3 puffs
on a pure hash joint after that it's I
always say really it's an ideal thing
for you know 10 people get each get like
two or three really nice ribs you know
sometimes maybe just yourself I'm not
gonna lie I've done it as they know
you've probably seen it on the channel
now I could almost swim today it's such
a beautiful day speaking of swimming
there's kids swimming just literally on
the other side of where we're hanging
out right now surprise we can't hear
them screaming and yelling
their hope for a swim
sure would be nice though
I can't believe what a gorgeous day it
turned out to be yeah we've got some bad
weather
well I'm not sure we've had really bad
weather I'd say it's more like just had
a couple of days of rainy which I don't
think we've had many in the entire
it kind of it was necessary to turn
around but it's nice that even today it
didn't seem like it was going to be that
beautiful that's beautiful it is it's
better left on that joint though I have
to say yeah well it'll just it'll
protect the cherry it kind of cools it
down and the burns are a little slow I
just come yeah you get that - it'll heat
up a bit more it's kind of like a cigar
in that sense I think the big cherries
on there so sometimes they left the ash
build up I'm sure if you guys have heard
that technique before letting the ash
build up and creating a bit of a cooling
effect on the cherry like a muffler
we're like halfway through this hash
joint
I like how you know building up that
that ash to put down the joint is
something mana will be thought about
those little things that we learned
little tips
I love it kind of makes sense because
after he said that I took a nice little
pull and it burned my lips yeah well it
was even the first etiquette of those
hash joints from the first video we
always said don't don't hash it often
it'll pull the cherry off and if it
doesn't pull the cherry off just seems
to make the cherry that much hotter but
it's still tasting great of course
the hash join is just a perfect shape
great way to to puff a big session
public we're surrounded there's people
working on boats over there there's a
marina right over here of course if
you're not much behind this in the sense
of people but a lot of nature you know
this this is like pulling up a rig and
gabbing like Matt we've literally got
burning off here and about two-thirds of
the way through it I could never get the
effects right now it's hey so I was
laughing uh it's okay because the you
know I just couldn't believe that he
steps on a rock this huge rock and it
just twists fully sideways slides is put
into a crevasse and then crushes up
against his foot and he wasn't really
screaming it was kind of like oh he's
just kind of like the character that he
is look at that big-ass that we got on
there absolutely but but when you drop
the joints and catch it in your hands if
you do not be aschoff it was awesome
you know what it's just because we're
being so delicate with it because could
feel this is getting more is this is
when it becomes destroyed and here's the
thing if you find at one point that it
breaks in your fingers you can no longer
pass it that's really the best thing I
can say about the hash joint unless you
have a pipe okay on the pipe that's
different but if you don't have a pipe
and you're puffing on one of these hash
joints and you're towards the last a
little bit of Roach one
the wind hold it like this and add three
fingers oh I see what you're saying yeah
you get that real strong wave coming
right now give it a shotgun rips
turn the way to the wind then you get
shotgun around and shot gonna look at
shotgun reps on the ocean
[Music]
and warm on that roll and I'm gonna go
look at the crusher crown careful to
crack careful I would be strands fur and
fingers too much at that point it's damn
near done but what a great joint that
was this is it stays in five figures now
cut don't pass it once it's cracked no
bill passes so I got it finish it off by
the time it's yours rips all the way
through your garters for the finishing
comes with kayaker [ __ ] beautiful day
I love living in Canada BC live in this
winter we're gonna take you or I'm gonna
take you in bubble man's world up to
Whistler Pemberton we're gonna do
backcountry black home and Whistler
mountain we're gonna do the backcountry
Pemberton icecap so we're gonna do
Brandywine bromb bridge and Squamish
just get you guys into some different
zones on the sled snowboard skis ski
flying want to show you guys a little
bit of this winter activity that I
usually get into and just how great you
know bubble and the whole cannabis scene
fits right into it in my opinion a lot
safer than an alcohol nice job done
puffing that down home
sucks having the eagle head over to that
character it's good couple sloths I'm
chewing on
get known to be good job I like the way
the winds really giving her ribs like
you don't even have to suck on that
together
it's great that's it this is going break
down to the nitty-gritty to the last
breath
see the awesome smoky Toki that's it
guys
alright John great puffing with you on
puff Wednesday hey congratulations
we've got resin freezin in the freezer
we don't get a collator today until
tomorrow and get it then but I want to
thank everyone for watching bubble man's
world and puff-puff pass beef so I
looked over and I could see this little
bit of smoke coming up out of the zone
and this is what we call organic guys
that little tiny piece won't go out it
will just smolder away and I can't hold
that it's gonna burn my fingers awesome
hey guys bubbleman here back with the
final process the most important process
of making water hash the breaking up of
the final patty into powder so I've got
my 120 patty right here it's nice and
frozen so I'm not going to talk too much
because the freezing is an extremely
important factor I've got my 25
parchment star sword my 120 parchment
here basically clean resin on it I've
cleaned my micro planer which isn't the
greatest of micro planers it doesn't
have the strongest little bite to it but
it'll have to do
I also lost my gloves otherwise I would
be holding this with my gloves right now
this is this is really breaking up
lovely it's just starting to get sticky
on my hands now I probably could have
broken her down into a smaller piece
it's coming out absolutely white this is
awesome just starting now to stick to my
fingers which is great because I've
pretty much got microplane down roll a
few little bump ease into the corner
there all right
so super important to make sure that you
get these pieces down as small as
possible these little pieces that are
stuck on my fingers of course probably
won't dry properly that's ok they're
just a few little rips oh no I'll just
hit those on the d-mail sizzle time as I
call it get that little bit of sis okay
so I've gotten myself a tiny little bit
of a bubble stuck on my fingers here as
you can see so what I would suggest for
this is into the freezer my fingers go
I'll leave them there for an hour and
then I'll pull them out now I'm just
kidding
you can do that with this tool right
here which has a little bit of hash
stuck on it give that a little bit of a
whack and then even the finger that's
got all the resin on it can be cleaned
over top of the micro planing to
there we go once
no resin shall be lost in the making of
this hash or harms for that reason
come on real nice
probably cuz I'm sitting in a nice cool
morning rather than the hot warmth of
the Sun that I often like to show you
guys what's going on so just give you a
little a little breakdown on that put it
a little more even here I could have
dried it out a little more evenly but
it's gonna be fine and then I've got my
little chunks over here
come on ours cannot tell you how great
the smell on this is I'm gonna close up
the 120 box and we're gonna move on to
the 90 micron remember this is just the
first run as well we did end up getting
two runs of each all right so time for
the 90 a little remnants of some other
awesome melty hash I think it's Medi oh
yeah let's break off a little bit about
90 you can see how absolutely stunning
that is nice
suggest using smaller pieces when you're
planing so it doesn't heat up on your
fingers
that stayed cool right to the end
my fingers are sticky free squirrels
getting stoked keep him here and he's
like he's doing a nine-day cider
hey I'm getting pretty excited see the
smell on this is flavorful and switch
your upper
corner out there
beautiful
nice powerline D right there my left
very little on the tool it's kind of the
key the more you leave on the tool the
more eventually the the less it'll work
so that's a tiny little bit in there but
for the most part you can see I got the
job done that's because this was in the
freezer the whole time so ninety you get
put away move on to the 73 alright so
I'll be 273 can see I've got the 73
micron written here and then each time I
do a new drop I just write in the date
and what it is I've done three other
Astro boys on this one and a many cush
to other Astra for the mini push this
will be the third got the parchment
lined in the cardboard I'm gonna break
this 73 in half it's already becoming
goopy look at the way the light shine to
that here's some top pretty excited down
there you must know I'm micro planing
the 73
actually one of the nice things about
this micro planar because it isn't quite
as sharp some of the some of the other
models it's a well [ __ ] down my recipe
pieces just with your fingers doing no
damage to your finger kind of sweet just
looking real nice 7373 saying 73
kind of a little bit of moisture on your
fingers tighten a little bit of little
moisture can just make that excess
sticky sticky resin roll off without
actually sticking onto your lunch your
finger so see that's pretty pretty good
for for just having manhandled it out
one more little piece here
it's coming out so white it's incredible
looks quite a nice amber color in chunks
but I'll tell you once it gets down to
being microplane is a very nice blonde
color
pretty good still clean on the fingers
no skin popping off into the hash looks
pretty darn good
well that's the 73 done 45 and 25 left
and then I'll go and microplane the
second run looks like the second run is
a little a little bit more than half the
return I'd say maybe two thirds maybe a
half and I'm gonna put this one away or
three weeks but to me it feels like a
month or months so I'm gonna go get the
45 to do exclusive 45 in here it looks
like it's quite a bit better quality
than the 25 so we're gonna dab a little
bit of this 45 because it looks so darn
good all right so we went and grabbed
our 45 patty see it's been in the
freezer all night and it is awesome this
is a nice 45 patty I'm gonna break it
into a few chunks Wow that was quite a
nice snap mainly because I don't want it
warming up in my fingers before I have
the chance to micro flame it this piece
is really hard I can feel it wanting to
warm up in my fingers but staying cool
right down to the last piece I find it
it is also helpful which I'm just
noticing now particularly with this 45
to have that tiny little bit of moisture
on the outside you saw when I held up
the piece that had almost like a little
little frozen water on the outside of
the hash this is quite a helpful thing
particularly for keeping the hash from
sticking to your fingers and the tool I
mean a little bit of moisture is the key
we know that it's it's the key in
sieving and of course it's going to be
the key in micro planing all right it's
great also coming out very light
Michael cleaning up just lovely
it's kind of apart right here that
you're watching this sort of last
awkward part that many people have the
most problem with and that's why I'm
going to show you all of it in all of
its awkwardness and yes you can mix it
up you can wear the rubber gloves you
can you know I'm gonna be photographing
my resin to clarify that it won't be
full of skin I can tell it's not full of
skin mine and my fingers haven't
released any skin and it all looks good
from here this 45 is definitely
releasing some lovely terpenes
that's relatively clean starting to gum
up a tiny little bit on the outside here
on this side sure which show me that
it's time for a cleaning it's best to
keep your tools clean and not try and
you know force the batch over a dirty
tool I'll clean this tool and before I
microplane the 25-man how do I clean it
I clean it with a little bit of 99% of
isopropanol and that pretty much gets
the job done
you wanna barf there bud and hear the
other dogs barking you're feeling it
don't hold back all right
nice passion 45
nothing wrong with that
some Grammys last up is the 25 which I'm
gonna put in the 191 60 bucks because
what I ended up getting for 190 and 160
was literally nothing I'll try to take a
picture of it it's just a little stain
on the pressing screen next up 25 micron
alright so we've got the last there's a
swag a hash on here - only on bubble
man's world this looks really good
actually it looks more like a 45 or even
a 120 then a 160 and a 1 we'll keep that
for later - bonus so should open my
pizza boxes more often that has been
curing for a long time all right so we
got the 25 micron there beautiful color
on that real nice and light caramel e
we're just gonna do a light microphone
yes I've cleaned the microplane like I
said crystal clear
this is just playing to perfection as I
assumed it would
nice even spread when you're doing this
is very important I still you know
without the closing of the box I don't
think I would use the parchment by
itself just here in the Pacific
Northwest we really have a humidity
problem and it's hard to dry bubble
properly and I find that that's why I
never would put it on a plate or a you
know when he took plastic or anything it
it need to go on a desiccant so I don't
mind this with the box that closes over
it because then it still gets the effect
of the desiccant without even being
directly in contact with it and then
everyone else is happy too because
except so nice off the parchment alright
so there's the twenty five we've got our
variety of gland sizes microplaned up
boxed up so no dust debris hair whatever
the wind whatever it can't happen
it's in the box it's safe I'll take
these now and I'll go put them in a room
that's gonna be about sixty five degrees
Fahrenheit with a humidity of about
twenty percent got a dehumidifier on and
probably let this dry for the next five
to seven days depending on if my friends
don't show up who the from the Seattle
cannabis cup if giddy and Tony and bird
show up and jibs then we are dipping
into the fresh frozen so anyway I hope
you guys learned a little something new
if you have any questions oh there's my
little guy crying in the background I'm
gonna have to go if you have any
questions throw them down as a cut as a
comment here in the comments section on
the YouTube page and I will do my best
to answer them simple process water
extraction you know where to go for your
water extraction needs you can call us
at one eight six six melting you can
check us up at this link right here
actually which is fresh head east comm
and we've got you covered for anything
you need in regards to
or wet washing or basically isolating
heads so thanks for watching he's not
here to trick the mind is already done
Johnny's not here to chase the Maya he's
only here to do whispers of that without
the traveling to meet some boys when
demise I don't wanna sleep in I'm a
jobless pot nine o'clock to watch
freshman admission we cheese and we
throw eyes pop it's a polygon jelly
immovable walk give me a baby from
Milano Zeki
don't wanna see Madonna 103 genome
[Music]
is not to change the minds it is only to
do ganja is not here to change the mind
it is only here to do this purpose of -
when I imagined oh dear oh dear be some
cups sitting up the blood as human a
lyric in our TV trucks well zoom on our
ass believe in the legs and tell me your
grams and car start upon you see
two-pointer
Imogene and the IOC's reality about 25
people mean and this walkie-talkie
[Music]
buh-buh-buh-buh-buh fun pass - pass
and they be put on cast your fun cards -
fun car and if you pick one ba-doop
ba-doop umpire and the bunka the bunka
pass on pass remember
and they broke banka banka banka
[Music]