[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome
to Puff
Wednesday is it puff Wednesday
[Music]
what's going on Johnny B
buddy dude dude how's it going I got
some stuff in here dude [ __ ]
rights glad I didn't put my 120 shirt on
today well it is a 12 day for Hot Box
DNA oh that's that's that's a new one
Amsterdam party it's an oldie oldie so
I'm going to help John grab some stuff
we're going to bring it upstairs and
then we're going to show you what we got
my car just started Jamaican it you're
not
well welcome to Bubble man's world
everybody and welcome to Puff Wednesday
nice Johnny B just got here as you saw I
graded him at the door he had a bunch of
fun stuff to bring up and he's going to
tell us about the uh Prairie Cup in
Saskatchewan it was a lot of fun sitting
there with fulled stew and that caught
my eye I was uh smiling when I I like
what the [ __ ] is that there a microphone
or something I didn't know about and he
got his dab tool full of bubble on
Skillet tool just loaded with fresh
Frozen
the strange
is I'm next of
course be a puff ony without bub a full
m
bubble oh
wow a double bong rip so would from the
Mother Ship right into the if I'm
correct the Nate Dizzle Swiss perk the
the
original oh that was good that was real
nice Double D
oh my goodness puff and
P oh dripping look at that clear Dome on
the outside that was beautiful was it
beautiful
day one thing we forgot to bring out
carb cap that's tasty feeling
it so we got d420 K showing up later for
a uh yeah that's awesome a late night
puff Wednesday be very very very very oh
oh oh oh no no no I was going to say be
very very careful when pulling out a tie
nail from someone's
bong particularly a mother ship now
people that own mother ships are very
particular because they spent the kind
of money on them and whatnot whenever
Flav or um even if Rose is is by I
always let them do it just cuz it's
theirs and it's such an easy thing to
chip this I guess it would even though I
took it out and made it seem pretty
loose and and got you so comfortable you
started pulling it out and I've been
playing with it it would be it would be
all of a minute later that you go to put
it down this is so strong titanium is
very hard very very hard and you just
have to tap the glass and you'll chip it
so we'll just keep it in
there I guess I got John a little
comfortable there being so loose with my
with my un I was comfortable he got he
got comfortable you know what but um
with glass might as well just yeah it
does and and what I've learned about
glass breaking is that uh it's best if
the owner breaks it in all my years of
owning glass I find that if the owner
breaks it that's your best case scenario
anyone else break it's like to break
glass because uh well you know what it's
like to have glass broken and my Prairie
cup got broken you know yeah took it to
the Prairie cup and it got knocked off a
table accident happen and it's being
fixed of course shine glass is fixing
her up and the problem with this a piece
like this is it's not really fixable
it's not fixable it's not really that
you could fix it you could just replace
the cost of it which is like who wants
to break someone's Mothership and then
uh this is an interesting topic what do
you guys think about smoking heady glass
with people um what happens if you break
their piece what if you chip their their
piece what if you do something that they
wouldn't have done and their piece gets
broken what is the responsibility I mean
you know if it's a $100 piece I I guess
we try to fix it maybe even if it's a
couple of hundred piece but do you do
you really replace like a $25,000 piece
if you break it
I think best not touch it otherwise well
we we we we are honored enough to be
sitting with people that we know that
let us puff on 3040 $50,000 bongs and
and around that it's like the bong's
handed I guess I take things for
Advantage when I'm sitting here with you
all the time cuz I'm always puffing on
this Mothership oh yeah well even the
way I did it if we watch the video the
way I did it so loose I bet you in the
video we could see you watching me do
that and have the realization I could do
that because it was less than 25 seconds
later you had this of course you were I
going to do a double you know what it's
a tough one not it's a tough one where
it's you know it's like especially with
a piece like this now Nate Dizzle gave
me this piece on a trip that him myself
uh Steve Hops and a few other people uh
were on this trip I met them in
Amsterdam at the airport I took them to
Amsterdam and drove them um to Germany
to the frankenthal uh the city of
frankenthal which is basically where the
rure factory is and they did
collaborations together Nate Dizzle gave
me this piece as a sort of thank you
yeah and and Nate does not like the
Rastafarian color scheme he it's a color
scheme he rarely ever does interesting
so it was kind of cool that he did it
for this particular
situation so it's definitely a nice
piece I remember when I was first
hitting it it's a nice one anyway we'd
love to hear about your comments uh and
what you guys think about glass and
sharing glass and what the etiquette is
what is the common knowledge etiquette
like for me the common knowledge is
simple if I break someone's piece I
replace it I either pay them the money
value or you know offering to fix the
piece nowadays isn't as big of a help as
you might think cuz the piece might hold
a particular value um that value will be
extremely affected if not completely
lost when someone else touches the piece
and fixes it especially if they fix it
um you know in a way that doesn't really
give Credence to the p P which I I've
seen on a few occasions pieces that were
fixed and I was just like o almost
shouldn't have fixed that well it's like
um I think etiquette would be if you
break a piece of glass if the owner of
the the guy that blew the glass can't
fix it well then I mean it should I
don't know if it would go on from
somebody else if that would be the
decision but I mean personally if if you
break a bong you got to be responsible
for that bom it's a tough one especially
when you're playing around with you know
it's a particular tough one when you
have a group of people it's almost like
a class like there's different classes
of people in the bong world there's
people that are puffing on $50,000 bongs
and then there's people that are
literally puffing on like broccoli pipes
that they made in their dorm room
awesome I support both of them but do
you give the guy with the broccoli pipe
a $50,000 piece to hit that's the
question I would Marcel did I know
others that do on a daily basis I know
others that don't I'd love to hear what
you guys have to think about that I'm
always happy to give people the benefit
of the doubt and pass a piece over
although I was very also eager to be
like even as I was pulling this out I
thought to myself John is going to do
this the minute you oh I knew it I knew
it and I I that's why I was like no no
no don't do that don't do that just such
a strong I can't wait to get the quartz
I have to admit I'm I'm done with the
titanium I'm hitting it mostly because
it's what I have yep you know so I've
been talking to Brian from denail and
they're hooking up some new whips some
new prototype uh bowls and and Sapphire
dishes and whatnot so we'll be able to
try those things out give you guys the
overview maybe in in an up and cominging
puff Wednesday who's to know so what are
you feeling you want to get that Swiss
riing I think we should be Swiss ripping
I don't think you hit it the Swiss rip
yet no I've mean um so let's get you
that Swiss
rip now each time I put it in I'm
like What's the dry LIF over there my
friend uh that's not dry sift it's
bubble hash it's the same as what's on
here oh nice so if you want that again
you're welome CU it was tasty it's Astro
Boy oh is it yeah that's why it was
tasty quite E welcome to hit that again
boy here too there's some on the Dabber
there too I'll definitely take this by
all means dab it up on this beautiful
sunny day these are a few plants uh
congales that uh got a little too tall
uh were a little too hot in the tent
when I went to Jamaica those couple of
times I wasn't really able to care for
them so I pulled them out and put them
on my deck they're producing beautiful
resin and they've got about a 12 to 20
in nugget on each one of them a couple
of them so they should make a nice wash
I think that'll be a Congo run hey just
do the whole two Congo plants I I think
that's an amazing idea yeah I I I will
vote Yes vote Yes on that vote
Yes and in the meantime clean that
Dabber off well not quite see my
throat's a little agitated so I'm trying
not to cough because coughing is
do you watch our videos next video I'm
going to do is just going to be John's
coughing from all of our videos I'll do
like a a split a split of me
going we already did me dabbed out that
was awesome though like that that's a
good dab out session that was a good dab
you know what I mean jet leg and killer
hash yeah dabed me out it dabbed you out
it just that's what just happens it does
we were busy we were running around it's
a high uh it's a it's a High um
bar to keep up with where it's just like
nonstop constantly from one place to the
next all right let's try that
out it's John not
coughing I'm
trying I got a little bit of an agitated
throat that was because I was testing 27
strains in a period of basically 48
hours
when we were at the Prairie Harvest cup
and how did you find the the strains for
the most part um you know what there's
some good strains there there's a lot of
stuff that should never been enter that
was not organic I think if you're
entering into a any kind of a cup if it
isn't organic why even bother to be
honest I mean the flavor is just you can
really taste it and stuff but I mean
everybody's got the good gardening
techniques and uh some uh just want to
enter into a cup and you it was very
very visual with some of the entries and
it was just like why they even enter
wouldn't it be nice if the Cannabis cups
were different in the sense that you
still got to inflate your own ego uh by
growing or processing the best hash or
herb by winning but the judges were
actually people who were sick using
cannabis medicinally and they were given
a 3 to 5 day period where you sent all
the samples to their homes and stuff and
you got real feedback real like sort of
what's the medicine true person feedback
that was that was telling you yeah like
oh I found that it would be it was be so
powerful to hear someone be like you
know I'm just looking to relieve my
glaucoma and that tasted like or it
worked great or it caused an appetite
stimulant or maybe there was chemicals
and they didn't like the harshness on
their throat like their voice would be
so much so much stronger and it would
make cups such a better thing if that
was the the outcome you could somehow
how do we do that I don't know but it
sure would be a cool thing I guarantee
you no one's thinking about doing it
that out of the 500 people that are
planning to do can
I I think the whole thing is is like
July 1st we always talk about as
cannabis day is it's all about medical
and if you were going to hold any kind
of cup I think it should be based around
medical and it should be based around
medicine and having medical patients
like you're talking about being able to
actually judge strains that work for
their condition and then that way we can
find out what trins are working for
different conditions at the same time I
don't the result would be more valuable
yeah you know when you actually finish
it with that information rather than the
results of oh the lemon OG Kush one so
we have to go buy Lemon ogi Kush seeds
and even in in chat yesterday I did a
chat and I you know some young guys from
out east are like I just want to move
out west but I can't even get 2500 a
pound out there and it's just like I
know listen to that I was like dude like
listen you guys are completely on the
wrong page with that worrying about the
price of you know cannabis will take
care of you if you require it to but not
in that prohibition model of like
growing it and selling it for like a
really high price it's beautiful I
figured you'd like that just it's bubs
it
is I love to see it man that's that
cushion it was the number two cushion
that was getting it from my friend
Justin go back two years ago and put
your bubble next to this
bubble the bubble you had two years ago
that you were like happy with I know
what the hell were you doing I have
absolutely honestly what the hell know
what you know what um what it was is for
the most part bags are going to make it
pure for you I don't maybe you weren't
drying it I don't know maybe you were
over mixing it cuz I'm telling you oh I
was 110% the old days everybody was
using beaters we were all getting all
our half inch drills with our big drill
bits in there mixing you grown different
pot no you didn't change the way you
grew pot not at all so that's powerful
to to see that you were like cuz really
that bubble was not like what I would
call what I talked to people about one
thing that I realized is is using an
eight bag system completely was the game
yeah that's a big one I mean that's a
big one the drying techniques not just
like chunks there's another big one um
properly freezing it right away or you
know there there's I like fresh frozen
that's the variable here is is
everything I make now is fresh frozen
whereas before I used to dry out the
herb used the Sugar Leaf right so it it
was just me not really I was I was using
the Sugar Leaf should still produce a
beautiful quality though you know what
it wasn't just it was yeah yeah the
variables that you were variables that
were there right I was trying to take
all my garbage to try and make something
amazing well you've got something
amazing now John I mean all your bubble
is a
nine out of 10
easy isn't it great that we it's just a
matter of variables you know like 120 I
kind of always thought that the real
hard part was growing the weed and it's
definitely the more variable
you know I I talk so much about how each
different Micron smells and the
different turpins and stuff like that
it'll be really nice to see looking at
the different tpin that are involved in
the 7390 and the 120 with the same strin
maybe someone out there's got a machine
different cannaboid profiles too not
just turam 100% let go small I
mean this this particular all be done in
the labs oh and and it has you know I
mean look at today wow congratulations
to
Jamaica wow Minister Golding it's Nots
really nice to see if you guys aren't uh
on the up and up of this I will put the
link to the gleamer uh the Jamaican
gleamer or the Observer um in the
comment section of this video you can go
click on it and read about it basically
Jamaica has um written amendments to
their laws because they are part of the
61 peace treaty narcotics act uh they
can't just change the laws completely
they can amend them and they've amended
for like import export Medical Transport
uh they're letting people out of jail
they're extinguishing criminal records I
mean they're they're they're game it's a
it's a game Cher 100% of what's
happening I mean people that are in in
jail are be charged for marijuana
position simply possession charges and
stuff like that are now basically uh
free it's beautiful it's beautiful it's
happening every everywhere and you know
the world is changing all around this
plant and that's just awesome it's great
to hear it's it's just so amazing really
props to Jamaica and all my Jamaican
friends and family over there you guys
uh really earned this one man holy Moses
that's a big one big
one yeah so we got puff Wednesday you
brought a couple of toys over should we
show a few things look at how beautiful
the sunlight is H yeah it's wonderful
Yeah we actually that box that is
probably sitting in the side over there
it's out of the side remember I told you
I moved it so they couldn't see it no
you can't see the I can pull it into
being
though now this
box is something new that um I can open
her up you can open want to talk about
it yeah you know what it's it's it's
just uh there's been gifts that been
granted to a few of us to take a look at
a new product um we're not really going
to so yeah this particular product is a
product it's different but it's another
LED it's a new form of LED I'll let John
kind of tell you about it in a minute
here but uh uh for those right away when
I mention this they're going to be like
whatever happened to your 2XL Dominator
bubble man what happened to your Lush
light my Lush light was in a tent uh
during the summer the this uh I wasn't
able to care for the tent I was away on
trips um my wife was very pregnant and
has other children and was you know busy
T trying to take care of that basically
uh they stretched out they didn't Bloom
when they were supposed to so I've taken
them all out of the the tent I've
cleaned the tent right up and I'm
waiting for the cooler weather and every
day just seems to be epically beautiful
so I'm hoping that sometime in October
I'll be able to light the tents back up
and that's when I'll get both my LED
lights going and uh at that point I'll
let John tell you a little bit about
this
particular LED light even though he is
taking a bong rib right now well this
particular LED light a for one it works
on
a 400 W power supply it's got drivers in
it it is um a complete Clos loop
system so this here which is so
cool so so cool I guess the best way we
can see you can see it's it's got a Clos
loose system here and it cools the whole
system two drivers on the top that work
into a 120 you just plug it right in and
um from what we read and what we've seen
it gives
um
basically the same power as the sun it's
all has to do with the deflection of the
LED lights yeah he was really he was
really I met the guy as well and he was
a he had a little light Monitor and he
was showing the numbers and basically
like testing the Sun and then testing
the light and uh you know it definitely
seemed that the numbers were as high I'm
not going to go out on a limb and say
that it was scientific fact but we well
you know what we we were you're looking
at I like to try it so Johnny brought me
one over and I'll definitely figure out
a way to get this into my tent maybe
I'll have to grow some real little uh
tiny little plants maybe I'll do a
little see of green over this LED light
or something so it uh shows more lumens
than uh th000 Watt and it uh shows it's
brighter than the sun got to wear some
pretty hardcore glosses method sevs for
sure I'll be getting my hands on a pair
of the LED ones yeah I got my I got my
LED method 7 definely
James from method 7 thank you for these
uh brand new Coupe HPS pluses with the
Zeiss uh Glass Lens much stronger than
the uh plastic lenses that they have but
I thank you for those ones as well iort
you with gifts all right gifts for the
bubble
man this gift happens to
be ah the little bong that fits on the
Apex pen I need to get my Apex battery
and plug it in here
ASAP that's a great little concept I
love it little bubbler little bubbler
little mini bubbler that fits on the
Apex pen fits on a few pens of course
you can see that I've been using mine
like
crazy ah yeah so there you go you've got
the battery right
there you've got the battery right there
John excellent so this actually fits
directly on the little Apex which was
handy I kind of picked it up from a
gentleman when I was at the Prairie Cup
oh yeah it fits real nice in the Apex I
mean come on that's nicer than a long
kind of pen thing I like that you can
kind of hold it in your hand you know
and it's it's it's like the movie
theater carry a torch with you or
anything it's awesome yeah very cool so
you know what I've been hitting mine
like
crazy I have mine all geared up
beautiful
and uh he looks like you've been puffing
Earl I've been puffing the [ __ ] out of
everything puffing the [ __ ] out of
everything so all was it a big Earl cup
did you find that there was a lot more
Earl than most things Earl Earl oil oil
where people no this was this is all bu
dude it's all 90 mic nice no I mean at
the cup though where people lots of
shatters around yeah I was pretty much
um there was another guy that had full
melt bubs he sat in the middle he was
handing it out U being very generous of
course anybody that came by my booth was
able to sample all the cushioners in the
watermelon that I had so that was kind
of cool stew props stew um he totally
hooked it up he had little lights around
there and he made it look all nice and
awesome he brought brought a a little
microscope from uh L of drugs and I
showing people the resing close right up
and taking pictures and people were able
to smell the hash smell the different
tur really start understanding it I give
them a and over they went over to Stew
and the stew got into more of the
education on the bags and why and I was
more about the tpes and stuff it was it
was it was um it was fun great it was
great it was a lot of fun yeah had a
really good time good stuff well that's
great to hear that the fourth annual
Prairie cup went off without a hitch and
everyone had a great
time have to maybe check that one out
next year oh what else Johnny B what
else what else well maybe we should go
have a session somewhere random well
this is where we ended
up we haven't left we haven't [ __ ]
moved but we decided we would share a
little bit more video nice hit yeah you
like that you like that hit it hitting
it up so um we just picked up 420 on
puff Wednesday and I think it just
happened that way
mysteriously totally
yep Ninja
so yeah d420 K and Jake are heading down
from PG we're going to be going to meet
them in a little bit at the Salmon House
on the hill we'll bring the camera we'll
show you the view from the salmon house
on the hill we'll have a big session out
on the outer deck maybe some dabs maybe
some Apex pen hits we'll see what
happens definitely looking forward to
the salmon house on the hill it's one of
my favorite restaurants in all of
British Columbia never been excited it's
absolutely spectacular the chef is on
point and the food is always really
delicious and the view is uh you know
all basically Vancouver I was going to
say you're talking about something so
delicious was that Ninja dab oh yeah in
that ninja dab was an amazing I feel
like you need to be nin dab that flavor
alth I hit it out of the mothership I'm
going to transfer over transfer over so
yeah was about the flavor you talk about
the foods sorry I interrupted you but no
problem BR when you get a flavor of that
type of hash with that type of has I'm
going to do a quick clean in this
because that
reclaim comes off instantly look at that
oh nice when it's
fresh and it's I could see that it was
fresh freshly dripping down the pipe
I'll maybe just give this one a real
quick clean
too always keep your tools clean I think
you recently were talking about that yes
we were talking about it it's hard to
keep them clean all the time I like
that's kind of why I did the grung off
video I got a bunch of haters on it oh
that's the worst advertising I've ever
seen I was like I wasn't trying to
advertise I was just showing you how to
clean my bong and I'm not like trying to
clean it so it's Gallery
clean but oh I think I think what some
people should really realize is is the
reason why we do and post things that we
like it's because it's what we like
we're not advertising it's stuff that we
enjoy using it's stuff that works and I
always just say if it works for me I'm
going to tell you because I like it
especially when comedies are paying
us totally joking no one's paying
me oh that was a rip I couldn't even
finish it that was yeah that was a ninja
hardcore
wow thank you was that nice thank you
very
much I a little squinty McGee going on
here
now no I guess that was me and thank you
Brandon dab flies for the maple can of
candy I will enjoy that Johnny B just
passed that on to me I got the grape one
very
nice was that it yeah it was great
really nice um sorry that was the 120
I'm thinking we're just going to
continue down this road of puffing
ourselves into a
coma we can do that talking about things
we've been talking about Jamaica we're
really excited for them there I can't
believe let me just read that oh where
was it it was it
was cultivate import export
Harvest um research and development
transport sell for medical and
experimental purposes Jamaica just blew
it right out of the park today with that
news BW for it I'm going for it I'm just
going right to your Facebook page all
right we'll go right to the main uh
right where it's the next one this one
right
here that's the one and then it took a
few seconds to to load on my um page
well it is what it is we're going
directly to Jamaica right to the Gleaner
but even that took a while it did the
same thing where it showed this and then
in about 5 Seconds it show you the
article so basically what we're talking
about here is there we go here we go
I'll let you read it out there dude yeah
I'll just read the one part and this is
uh the Minister of Justice uh Mark
Golding the Justice Minister and they're
making changes they're they're amending
the their act okay so while the
Dangerous Drug Act and its regulations
in the Food and Drug regulations of 75
provide a regime for the use of extracts
tinctures or preparations made from
Cannabis the prohibition of the
dangerous drugs Act can make any dealing
with the ganja plant itself illegal
without exception and therefore do not
allow locally grown cannabis plants to
be used to produce extract texures or
preparation for medical scientific or
any other purposes he said stating that
the term of the proposed licenses are to
be determined Golding said we need to
now flesh out the specifics of the
license and Frameworks to go hand inand
once the Amendments have been approved
and implemented a licing a licensing
Authority is to be established to govern
the licensing process for participation
in the medical ganja industry so
basically what he's saying is if I can
find the one beautiful part of what he
said um oh here it is uh that among the
amendments to the act the cabinet has
approved our Provisions for permits to
cultivate possess import export
transport manufacturer sell and
distribute ganja for medical and
scientific purposes under license two
thumbs up Jamaica I support you so we
wanted to share that again and like I
said the article uh it's on it's on the
Gleaner
gleaner.com in Jamaica and we'll post it
in the comments they've stepped it up
like Chile's gone to medical and we've
looked at um yeah uguay did their uguay
did their thing I know Italy the the
Italian uh Army is going to be going
states are jumping on board every states
are jumping on board I mean it's it's
great we're just seeing this plant
actually uh make some dramatic and some
awesome changes as Richie Spice would
say you got to free up the herb yes got
to free it up free up the herb we're
freeing it up I think I going to have to
free some of this resin up I'm going to
free some up as well we'll catch you
guys in a bit at the Salmon House on the
[Music]
hill all right guys so we have made it
to the world famous Salmon House on the
hill Alder grilled fresh sea it says
underneath I'll uh I'll bring the camera
in and I'll let you guys see as we enter
and you can kind of check out the
restaurant this is truly one of my
favorite restaurants uh real beautiful
view of uh just on the other side of the
hedges in front of us basically all of
downtown Vancouver as far as like New
Westminister and the endowment lands
where UBC is it's pretty cool of course
uh we beat Darren and Jake here so of
course we did we thought the right thing
to do would be to dab it up
dab and in the meantime there's just
like hilarious okay what is that a brand
new LR4 HS that's one of the Land Rovers
Land Rovers yeah it's it's a nice car
all right I I can honestly say that I've
never even knew this place existed I
didn't even know about it I'm super
stoked to go and have a nice meal it's
one of my favorites
friends it's one of my favorites yeah so
uh of course m
it'll be nice to uh definitely relax
enjoy some salmon of course that's what
I'm going to have here yeah I had salmon
earlier at Joey's did you I did yeah oh
that one's empty too wow we're down to
like oh here's a little bit of dabs oh I
I didn't even bring mine in I apologize
no don't worry about it I have mine
right here I'll definitely have to um
grab some for the after SES once uh
Darren get just need to have a
oh is that
ever sticky stuck on there guy really
stuck on there good it's a beautiful
thing it is isn't it so I figured we got
to have a dab out in front of the Salmon
House I also of course brought the pure
hash joint at any point in time I
figured uh you know we might all
probably right after our meal I think we
should stand on top of that can no it'll
be right out in front on their deck
of our table oh we have a deck table
outside no we have a table inside and
then there's a deck outside so you go
from your table inside outside to the
deck and that's where we'll have uh
going to be that's where we'll have our
puff all right so this is probably
bigger than it needs to be but that's
how I'm feeling right now I need a
bigger one than it needs to be wow
that's very nice there's the boys look
at that D 420k and Jake C in the house
they're going to probably uh think you
need to jump in the back yeah yeah
driving the big
350 you know what a long drive down from
Prince George it's kind of nice that
they uh happen to be able to come by and
uh they do it they just that involves
work stuff like that which is
nice just torching up that
nail kind of waiting for these guys to
get out I kind of want to see I want
them to see me hit in the rip
but I don't know if I can wait for them
they're slow they're slow I don't see a
door opening
yet
yeah look at the exhale they'll have to
catch the next they're going to have to
catch the exhale well other guy door it
wasn't so of of course always full Mill
quality
just brief silence there for the
Heavenly bubbly and Does that taste
nice I don't think they've seen us hey
d d420
[Music]
k let's see if he hears that in the
meantime I heat you up your dab that's
awesome
dude without burning you don't burn me I
won't burn you oh not even burning me no
I did not he tried burning Me Oh Hey
listen if I try to burn you I would be
burned right now you'll have a burn on
you you'll have a burn mark So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to take a
picture of us hitting this with his
truck in the
background sending him a
pick this is how we pull things off
right here here we go
ready all right here you go sir
Johnny
nice keep her
going keep her
going nice one what do we got there
sounded like a bus or something
something like that oh it's a big pump
truck well I'm going to go knock on the
window bring those guys over here for a
quick dab and then we're going to go
into the restaurant nice all right the
characters are in the house yeah they
are what's up dogs yeah dude let me
light you up a little flammer to go cool
a little bam Bimmer nice how was the
trip trip was good yeah ni nice weather
coming down today that's nice dude we're
about to have nice food oh have you ever
had food here oh yeah I've been eating
here for about 20 something years wow
since before morning I didn't even know
it existed me neither it's impressive
restaurant this this is one of my
favorites and you know what they've been
consistently [ __ ] killer for Three
Chefs in the last 20 years Monica's 21
now yeah and
uh it'd probably be 22 23 years that
I've been coming here 21 she's she's
older than Josh no same age 21 21 go
brother thank you bit you're most
welcome how about a big old fat dab of
the phone out right there you oh it's
always nice dabbing with some friends
dabbing with some friends we've been
dabbing it here in the truck it's puff
Wednesday There's a little little gped
there the Apex very nice very nice got a
gold
Apex sweet it's one I got uh given to
me I use it a lot see a little nugget
hash stuck on
it very proud of that very proud of
that that was good I'm sorry man I
didn't no oh there's yours left smoke in
there I thought you wanted me to clean
it up show you I don't have a pipe with
hash on it right now I have hash what
you got well I always got some Mar this
of course I
do want to look at that one more dab for
Darren oh this Astro Boy no oh yeah we
have Astro Boy we have Astro Boy oh man
dab a Astro
Boy that's some pretty stinky smelling
stuff dude that's got a real nice smell
eh hey we're hot boxing my truck I like
this hot boxing on the puff Wednesday
we're hot boxing on the puff
with all right you got the Astro Boy on
here that's the one he requested oh we
want the Astro Boy the Astro Boy mine's
at my house oh yes please Johnny B has
his here oh Johnny B I love it Johnny B
Johnny
[Music]
B that is [ __ ] awesome look at this
big ridiculous thing yes I want look
talking it's ridiculous we are here bro
it's spell with by the way just saying
[ __ ] calling me out on [ __ ]
my own YouTube
channel them crazy
eyes Okay so this the I seen a guy take
a grinder to this to get it down saw I
saw it I don't need to get it down
either it wouldn't bother me either I'm
going to get one of these 90 is the fire
that's why it's in the red let's take
the Fire or the
120 like you have to ask him which one
he wants you just offered him the fire
Oak do you want to heat him up the
nail I will do the um Z dobbing ooh
maybe less angled downwards you're
making me
nervous I will be first time I ever
watched John use a torch he set burn
something well at first we thought it
was his wallet on fire but it was
actually money inside of his wallet his
wallet was like way over here and all of
a sudden it's like dude you're W burn
money ah it's just mar Just burn that
[ __ ]
cuz money to burn I don't money to burn
I wish I did Johnny B's got money to
burn I have absolutely no I'm going a
pension and if I had a lot of money it
is I wouldn't burn it I'd give it
away I would um make excessive amount
lots of hash brother and I would then
proceed to give that hash I believe you
I want to be a part of that giveaway I
would like uh 12 gam of super uh Super
Silver Haze oh hey uh 12 G of uh Mullen
Bimi Madness 90 Micron you know what
what you know what we're doing right now
is I know isn't that
amazing around you haven't had a chance
to really like the taste on this man
dude wow okay let's go eat I don't no
wow you uh we're going to go eat we're
going to go check engine light we doing
it let's head into the Salmon House
he's like I got to make sure I do that
at least
once you mean that Thing You Do 800
times a
day all right here we go this is
awesome hello reservations reservations
great under Richardson
okay I didn't want to just assume
[Music]
so I got the seat be right here
beautiful thank you I guess I better go
in
[Music]
one din thanks so
much I think I kept it rolling the whole
time I did how do you feel about this
place guys nice spot right oh yeah for
the two that have never been here before
no excellent sorry 420k what do you say
about this menu so far well I say it's
going to be good we were talking about
the seafood chowder for two people
Seafood Tower Seafood Tower dungeon is
crab salad candied salmon and tuna
shashimi aler grilled Sable fish and
tempir prawns baby potatoes and a Thai
curry broth alter grilled two lobster
tails and scallops grilled asparagus
garlic butter sa so just like for for
appies or no no that's going to be for
the main
we're the um we got two
salmon two of those coming we got chili
prawns we got the paner gallops clams
and muscles on each Channel this is
going to be beautiful get any muscles I
think we left that I guess we should
give them a little view of the
restaurant here we got the canoe up top
here which is pretty cool you can't
really see it with the light oh there
it's just turned up
beautiful
art nice view on the
ocean you want
to good times at the Salmon House on the
hill all right so some food just arrived
would you get spring rolls scallops and
sushimi
tuna we got
more deliciousness what do you got
scallops scallops and I got a caesar
salad
super happy right our Seafood Tower
lobsters um what we got Sable
fisho over
there there Jake's got a
trio I got a as well get those lobsters
prepared
it oh my god well I guess it's time to
eat boys can I go the
tow this is joking so good you guys are
topnotch Salmon House on the hill we are
back after a spectacular meal at the
Salmon House on the hill holy [ __ ] [ __ ]
was good was awesome yeah I mean holy go
that was just good all the way around we
picked out harsh we did not buy any
desserts because apparently you guys
have brought desserts is this what I'm
to understand yep so before we open
these should we do a quick round of like
Wicked 90 Micron uh fresh frozen Astro
Boy yes I love it absolutely dessert
hash for dessert before dessert [ __ ]
killer
killer we actually have um we still have
the r sir yep perfect where did it go
why did I put that rag oh it's over by
the camera Johnny B someone else is
getting oh wow you're the easy o easy o
and easy back thank you
brother got our little dabag the funny
thing is we had a whole conversation
about this rag I know then I just looked
up being present it's nice to have it
present it's nice to have a clean D when
you're digging into some fine full mil
bubble listen to my little little guy
there can you hear him yeah he's crying
upstairs that is my new son making he
just wants to be on Bubble land's World
want to
he
mon he's like he's like I need to feed
my
end we'll start with you wow I love that
we'll get a real quick nice beautiful
Banger of some just melty melty melty
melty
beautifulness tempted to go and get the
carb cap over there that I see sitting
behind the sink I think we're good I'll
leave it on here just in case there's
the tiniest little bit of residual of
the alcohol on there we know that
sitting on the carb cap for a few
seconds is definitely going to uh
evaporate that evaporated out pretty
hardcore considering it evaporates at
room temperature I think I see better
these
do trying to hide You Can't Hide dur the
glass no it wasn't more that you know
it's after doing several DBS here I got
to make sure that uh can
see I sure do
wied wicked oh man
hello yeah you love this [ __ ] know you
do so make sure you get a nice uh a nice
reasonable
hit so yeah we're just basically going
to have a dessert rip here real quick
and then it's going to be into these
desserts we'll show you what we
got quick wolf
session and then maybe uh time for a
funny story or two funny story or two
yes there's so many good funny stories
out there I'm just uh going to be about
hash by well they sure could be about
hash I know that
um there there's some funny stuff taste
man
Goode
flavor wow I got a story about I got a
story hat do you want a baby one out of
the thing like a little real small one
you know what or Apex got the Apex no I
want the uh watermel yeah this is it
right here oh yeah but do you want a tin
or this
whatever you want same one you guys are
doing okay perfect mother ship you got
to pull a little hard very very tiny be
messed who knows your friends better
than you that's
right I think this is another thing we
talked about John and I talked about the
etiquette of smoking out of expensive
bongs and potentially breaking a bong
this is a new type of etiquette the
etiquette of Turning People onto dabs
without destroying them if you want to
turn someone on in a way that's you know
it's reasonable and within their range
of being able to
enjoy you don't want to [ __ ] the guy up
so that he has nothing but a bad time
for a good six eight hours because he
can't handle it it's not it's not fair
it's not fair and it's not cool and and
it ruins people so how's that watermelon
treating you over there wow did you hit
it the second time yeah I did oh
excellent that's what did he ever did he
ever yeah oh my's not much left I'm
sorry over
here I could not I just can't believe
the flavor taste oh yeah that's a that's
a killer I didn't need
quar I need that now oh my goodness what
a
ripper big rip oh yeah he's
[Music]
nailing wow there no
tomorrow that hurts my lungs just
looking at like that's mine was like an
eye closer like full on you going to
break sweat you're all good now I broke
instantly I broke a sweat instantly see
when you break sweat forget about think
about breaking a sweat you know that
youve
made your full Andoid system very Happ I
just want to do that
again just watching and
uh for who passing some of these plates
out what did you put down there John
what kind that's a some cush oh yeah
that's what I don't know for like three
months so it's to be number four you I
took cush I it in the astal boy Double
Dipper Astro Boy combo Double
Dipper clear
domes wow oh my
gosh get this man a car
cap he's like that's awesome we're
staring at all that stuff in there we're
like looking at treats what's going on
so here are some of the delicious treats
that these guys brought oh my God you
can't see them they're they look so good
you can see them this one's like a lemon
thing and a pumpkin thing and there's
more beautiful things over here I don't
know what these pink thingses are
chocolatey caramel Sal those are the C
what are they called those are the ones
full the puff cream that's it yeah we
got to try that canoli those babies
right there yeah everyone
needs good
reps cani no no what do you mean no I
I'm going to have one of these
things for you and your fam jeez I got
to
uh on this stuff right pop one of these
oh maybe I'll have a canoli later with
my family and I'll have one of these now
I'm not even sure what it is but it
looks delicious
delous
[Music]
delicious man looks like d420 got the
good one the one he's been waiting for
got the sweat across the forehead too
want to thank you guys all for uh tuning
in and watching Bubble man's world
seeing familiars like Jake and uh Darren
showing up and Johnny B of course puff
Wednesday hope you guys puffed a lot
bulls and enjoyed the show see you next
week peace peace out Happy Metal
cool um we almost forgot it's the end of
the video we'll probably take a few more
dabs just
because well cuz I really want to as
well cuz we can because we can but
before I forget and Darren was kind
enough to remind me um the kind Folks at
method 7 wanted me to pass on a pair of
their Sun resistant look at that D 420k
nice method 7 glasses thank you method 7
so I know you will enjoy those on Harley
those those are a a sun version they're
not really a light version for HPS or
LEDs they have specific nice case too um
lenses for
everything nice that is nice got bearded
dragon on I don't know if you can see it
but the bearded
dragon yeah man that's nice follow me
oh they fit nice too Bo man they're nice
shades man right on are nice thank you
again that's awesome I love I love uh
stuff like this great man that's great I
should have been loving method seven
Sun good guys enjoy these man thank you
very
much time for a dab
on check them out and on the way home
tomorrow on the drive all right so a
little Ripper for
you
bent change the pipe picture every once
in a while yeah there's some really
nice designs on some of those pipes see
oh yeah they're incredible wow am I
zooming in on the screen or no no
staying the same yeah too
bad the Phoenix see the Phoenix in the
body I don't know what Phoenix is well a
phoenix is the bird oh okay see how the
top of it is like a bird with its wings
up can't really see it here it's I guess
there it is though I seen the head I KN
I knew the head was a bird actually
thought excellent well that was a most
awesome puff Wednesday yes epic good
food good Bros good smoking good time
[ __ ] good time man excellent I'm
going to finish it off with a Swiss perk
rip nice and I'm going to
hit what you got packed on
here oh yeah cuz it looks so good oh yes
absolutely
yeah it's so compressed that's going to
be a big
dab big
dabs just greases right out okay I love
that love it love
it for any of you Apex owners
I'm sure you know this
anyways stick it on your stick it on
there you see my Apex bong that goes on
the on the battery Apex bong yeah I'll
have to show it to you yeah I'll be
right back
yeah oh
boy what a good evening eh you get a
good rip off of that yes indeed
enjoyable Buzz though not a [ __ ]
painful holy [ __ ] this is too [ __ ]
much man I'm still a RI yeah oh yeah
you'll be ripping [ __ ] till till till
tomorrow morning man be ripping in your
dreams tonight yeah be Dreams yeah all
right so why wouldn't they send you
something this is the little
bong oh
my a little bit of water coming out that
piece there I guess you got to be
careful not to get
the that's I'm not going to be using
that component anyway I would use the
one like right on there MH but yeah you
just basically take your Globe
off and go right in like
this and
then you got yourself a little D it it's
freshly packed man go for it freshly
packed eh
mhm oh
yeah very there you go
L there you go where do I get
that I'm sure they'll be available
sooner than later I'm not sure where
John got it from I think it was a glass
blower and
Saskatchewan very cool little unit that
is [ __ ] awesome man not bad give it a
go give it a go there D oh look at that
just white e hey guys welcome to Bubble
man's world I'm here to show you a brand
new little addition to the Apex pen
courtesy of Johnny B from the Prairie uh
Cup in Saskatchewan d420 K is in the
house what's up buddy hey how you doing
Jake's in the house awesome dudes so we
are packing the OG cush full melt dry
sift into the Apex pen Y and we are
going to use this little guy check this
little guy
out beautiful little pie piece nice
little bubbler it's
basically take it off all right pull the
Dome off yeah right oh what's that you
got stuck on your there's that's a nug
that's a nugga hash oh nug of hash you
just got a gram and half just for quick
reload right quick reload oh my God yeah
that's awesome but if you warm it up it
softens
up so you can you can
basically just put her right on
and go for it all right do you want to
do the honors I'd love for you to do the
honors I'll uh get the nice
okay that's a real little Ripper isn't
it man what a ripper or what holy [ __ ]
yeah all right I'm ready to join this
party got to like that what's up wow
it's real like comfortable and portable
in the hand it really just fits well
with the Apex pen all right here we go
that thing is so
cool that Apex too with something else
you can see it's giving some rips give
off a big rip oh yeah greasing right up
once again Apex with a little mini bong
attachment giving it a two thumbs up
thanks Johnny for a great gift thanks
d420 k for helping me uh test it
out anytime peace buddy peace all right
here ever got that thing packed I'm
going to have to do my own video on this
specific little guy check for it on
YouTube guys and thanks for watching
Bubble man's world we'll see you next
time peace out peace m
[Music]