[Music]
rocket te in the house rocket te in the
house take a dab haven't seen this guy
since the Cann ofis Cup in I don't know
when 9998
wow these were amazing cups I'm telling
you they don't make they don't have cups
like that anymore like the Pack's party
house was so hot and all of us packed in
there in the police station right next
door it was wild man it was wild so I'm
happy to be happy to be hit up the you
too man all right hey you know what I
noticed you got twin cam here yeah can I
try it out
absolutely little twin
cam engaging twin cam
engaged nice oh there it is are you in
there where's
where's twin cam
fail where is where is well I think
that's me okay I got the to I think all
right well the next one's yours I wasted
a lot of time uh on the twin cam sorry
about that as you can see they're doing
the big speech right now and we're here
at our table dabbing so nobody notices
this is perfect no it's amazing all
right well I'm going to dab you out if
you want to pass the camera over oh [ __ ]
all right so we're here with Ramo the
urban grower what's up yeah dude we're
about to uh We've torched you up good
here we've got uh a nice uh brothership
honey bucket on the Mother Ship Taurus
hit the Blue River tpin Cherry
AK-47 and a little bit of that rosin
from the congales oh and we've got 33
seconds on the
timer I want to thank you again for
coming over the other and you know for
turp Tuesday and doing that uh 10 dab
Gauntlet that was insane oh yeah dude
that was awesome the most TPS I've ever
done ever thanks again I know it was
psychedelic towards the end when we
walked into your house it was
psychedelic we got to do it again we
will with 10 new cultivars okay I am
down I have them already so we'll do it
in a week or two yes all right you got
about 15 20 seconds and then we'll just
do this I'll get that ready for you all
right rmo I think uh I think you're good
to go here we go rock and
[Music]
roll sweet dude awesome
thanks Steve bloom all time you'll see
AR Bubble Man
[Applause]
good to see you up
to with the
[Music]
dab let's get that on
there that's a fine dad I'm done great
is that Steve blooma approved that was a
good one I like that one he hacked he
did a double ha he's ready no no yeah
yeah you know what you're good you're
good you're good you're
[Music]
good Johnny B with the dab Tech
no all right guys I have just finished
at the VIP party for the ICBC it was
really really [ __ ] great I got my
pipe here balancing on the tiniest
little deck overlooking the city and it
is quite a drop down there probably
going to hit this rip right
now here we go
[Laughter]
[Music]
bubble man I'm MH things up for Real
Vancouver City one
love sweet dude so far so good day one
of the ICBC
conference yes I
he
[Music]