[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world doc Atomic is back in the house
how you doing super good to see you
again dude yeah [ __ ] that was a good
that was a great video a couple of
videos I spliced it into one yeah I know
we spliced it into one I was kind of in
a hurry I didn't know what to expect we
were there for hours of things in your
defense I think I had blown through at
least 3 hours of your time that on that
day oh really well you stayed for
probably close to 3 hours yeah oh my God
I know I thought it was like 20 minutes
anyway so what have you been up to since
last we well I brought a few gifts for
you and um gifts gifts from the doctor
yeah well as as you people out there in
gangel land probably know I've been
associated with the Northern Lights this
is one of my favorite one of the uh
there's there's many fenos of course
generation to generation cousins uh
sisters Etc this particular one is very
interesting in the fact that it it show
it when it it it has a classic
Afghani uh finish to it so you'd expect
it to smell skunky but it smells Super
Lemon super Citrus which is a recessive
gene from a sativa past so what you've
got is a short Afghani type Afghani
plant M fairly quick flowering uh 8 to n
weeks beautiful lemon
Aroma uh in incredible High coming in
from both the recessive sativa genes I'm
suspecting yeah and and the dominant
Afghani jeans which is showing in the
structure of the plan and so for the
people that don't really know cuz I'm
sure you've got your Google but the
northern lights and and Doc mentioned it
last time a little bit in the video I
believe that it's it's this classic
afghan that they then bred
into um all these exotic sativas that
were coming in probably Colum I
cambodians and that's right of the day I
mean it's it's hard to nail down exactly
which SAS they were since this occurred
you know in the 70s and people were
keeping bag seed from these strains
these are the same sativas actually that
be became named hay in the by the Hayes
Brothers back in the late 60s early 70s
in San Francisco in Santa Cruz area
those guys were you know collecting all
these incredible sativas as well from
Central and South and Asia and they were
basically those were the the original
hazes wasn't really any one strain it
was just these amazing exotic long
flowering tropical sativa grown right
and then back there what we used to get
from Afghanistan was strictly the
hashish which was of course because of
smuggling Etc um it's only when the
indoor grow thing came into Vogue um the
late 70s early ' 80s and and uh Growers
back then be can disc began to discover
the merits of the high press sodium H
lighting which which of course was made
for stadium lighting sure and lighting
streets yeah I remember actually
probably quite a few years later but I
guess it would have been in the 80s when
people I knew would go and Jack a light
bulb from like the ski hill and then go
go grow a crop in their closet or
whatever whatever exactly and funny
stuff um later on of course um we be
began to develop specialized bulbs uh
one that comes to mind right away is the
the Hilux bulb uh which was originally
made by iwasaki in Japan and they added
more blue to the Spectrum uh because the
regular high pressure C has caused the
plants to elegate oh yeah uh without
enough blue in the Spectrum uh um
there's uh a number of companies are
starting to do that uh to tweak the
Spectrum so to speak yeah I've noticed
that I talked to um I think his name was
Allen one of the owners of
solc and they were talking about doing
these chips that were like 2K and 5K and
10K and they're measured in kelvin now
which is something different for LED
lighting but they're doing these full
spectrum LED sort of hoods that have all
these different chips to try and create
create this full spectrum of light now
there's all sorts of argument online
which why bother having the yellow
Spectrum or why bother having this
spectrum but I I I tend to believe that
the sun got it right and that everything
the sun has we might want in our
artificial light and that potential
synergies are occurring on levels that
we ourselves can't perceive or even our
scientific instruments can't perceive
them well I I've heard I I know people
that are now using LED lights uh they're
very effective very cool
they're quite expensive still I've got
one on the way oh yeah I've got one on
the way in fact I'll make a point on
pudding um potentially one of these
Northern Lights under there so you can
try some of your strain grown under an
LED light yeah I've I've yet to sample
any real product nor have I that was
grown nor have I with LED lighting so I
I can't really say I I just know that uh
it makes sense M yeah I mean I've seen a
friend of mine online Kingston herb uh I
respect him uh he posts quality every
time and he's been growing with them and
he's been showing beautiful buds under
the pink light and he's been extracting
the resin it's melty and bubbly so I'm
uh he was really the one that put me in
the belief that this could be something
that I should try and he was also the
one that hooked me up with Lush and they
sent me a a light on on Just for review
so it's going to be going into the tent
that John Bell is actually on his way
here with right now I've got my second
8x4 uh secret jardan tent on the way and
hopefully you know within a day or two
from that that led light will come in
and I'll literally be able to put these
um my next batch which is uh Congo sweet
skunk Barb and Afghani so that's what's
going in the tent next so you had
another little uh special something
there as well saw Yes uh this particular
strain uh is called
Harmony Harmony now this comes from a
breeder called reeferman who H reeferman
I'm sure uh some of you out there hey
you know what say what you want about
reefer man but he always has the quality
he does so that's let's that's what I'll
say about reer man I'll give you thumbs
up Charles you got the fire yeah and uh
a lot of people
that that he created that got stuff from
him and then renamed renamed called it
theirs and this won't be getting renamed
this will hold the reeferman name of
Harmony Harmon you heard it here from
the doc want to thank reer man as well
Charles thank you very much Charles um
we'll definitely share this with all the
right people and and of course you're
going to get full credit uh absolutely
yeah it's just like just like the doc
will get full credit for his NL I don't
like to change names I I'll just tell
you the background of this is uh an OG
Kush cross to a lemon
thae so it is an incredible plant um G
Kush crossed with a lemon thae yeah
that's nice that's really nice it's got
the most incredible Aroma of of any
plant I've ever grown
it's the perfume on it is incredible
exotic he very exotic and
uh very potent as well offer you a
little rip yeah a little medicine for
your endoc canono
system let's see what we got oh this is
the fire this is the
fire so nice to be sharing good genetics
with friends I'm uh tomorrow I go see
Remo and I'm going to be doing some
macro photography over with him and
we'll probably film a video as well got
to get you over there one of these days
dog yeah I don't think we've met Remo oh
man you guys will get along you should
definitely meet that's what bubble man's
world's all about putting the
interesting characters of the Cana
Community bringing them together here
you go
dog dabbing with the
dock it is
boom
nice
rip so what's going on in the world of
breeding with the doc I know you're
always never
stopping even though you're probably
trying to uncomplicate your life and
relax a little bit you've still got
things in the plans I know I'm trying to
focus down on just right now I have five
strains I'm trying to keep it to that I
I could never figure out people that
have 50 strains or or it's a lot of work
they must have big teams of people well
yeah or they're not all they say they
are but well that's maybe a little bit
more likely yeah because I know it's
involved and it's quite
involved yeah and time consuming and
time consuming because every single
feno or to put it in plain English in
individual plant
um has to be for instance let's say we
we're we're choosing from a number from
a gene pool we're growing out as many
plants as we possibly can and we have to
number them we have to identify them
exactly and we have to take cuting from
them that correspond to that so we only
know four to 6 months later what we
really have so we have to have the
facility to go back to that clone that
was the chosen
one and and then go forward from there
uh so as you can
see the importance of labeling labeling
and and the ability to maintain those
labels you know I had I had just uh last
year U my
helper uh mixed up some
labels and although I'm pretty good at
telling what's what uh it have set me to
no end that I had to spend a couple of
months just to
verify what was what right in terms of
two particular fan I'm just going to
turn that fan off real quick cuz it'll
drive me nuts in the editing you can
keep
talking
go
right but
um yeah I'm uh I've I've mainly been a
Northern Lights man I think it's one of
the most versatile indoor strains around
it's synonymous with your name to me you
know doc Atomic the Northern Lights yeah
well it's because it's it I've had it so
long and I've tried my best to preserve
it uh I found it it has been washed out
a bit um not to slag anybody or anything
but just through my own personal
selection and I've found that I've tried
to keep it as as
close to its uh you know short flowering
super potent uh very uh High yielding
stocky has the taste changed much over
the years uh not really it's it's still
that Citrus
again when we think when I think sativa
I think Citrus I think lemon yeah both
the Congo and the sweet skunk uh
strongly have the strong lemon flavor
yeah the other thing I find about the
sweet skum lemine turine is what it is
yeah is it has a bubble gummy oh a
bubble gummy Aroma that sounds more like
the island sweet skunk yes you might
have the island sweet skunk that's a
hybrid it grows bigger nugs yeah it
looks like sweet skunk on like steroids
oh you'll see the one I gave you you can
grow it big but it'll be um
more lury well see it won't be dense see
here's an interesting thing that I I
have a pheno of the so-called sweet Scar
and then Mark has and other people have
and then they say they're the same but
maybe they're not the same so here's a
way we're going to do yeah we're going
to have three of them in the same room
all bloomed out together to see what's
what exactly you know but of course this
process takes months months and not only
that just being left with the herb in my
opinion isn't an accurate representation
you'd want to then extract resin off of
each one you know small amounts and then
do your denail dab and literally be like
okay like I can just tell you from The
Taste which one is Steve sweet skunk you
know Steve sweet skunk unfortunately was
kind of in the the same uh group as the
Congo that it was protected and then it
was shared very little and you really
had to be someone to be able to get your
hands on on it and so now I think once
more people have it or sorry let me go
back the reason that it was held back
like that that made it so um the island
sweet Gunk came to be which was a hybrid
and I don't know what if it was Jordan
or if it was Cash C Ken I'm not I can't
remember who did the um sweet skunk it's
a very nice strain but it isn't the
sweet skunk and any person that has the
sweet skunk that you show the island
sweet skunk to it it it looks great to
anyone that doesn't know sweet skunk but
someone that knows sweet skunk will look
at it and go oh it's it's got it it's
there but it's not the sweet skunk know
that's how I always sort of
uh sort of explained it that that they
it had something that's sweet lemony
kind of what about the stature of the
plant is it especially a tall plant is
it stretch it grows you know the the
well you can see my sweet skunk out
there look at how stretched it is it's
the tallest plant out there and it's
just super super
stretched just turn that off real quick
so yeah it stretches now the island
sweet skunk I've never personally grown
I've seen it budding and it was also
fairly tall and lanky but you know maybe
some of our viewers out there can
comment in the on the island sweet skun
because I know it's the one that's more
available um I believe Matt from the
great Gardener selfed breeder Steve's
Sweet skunk and that is available
through um the Vancouver Seed Bank the
same place that you can pick up the dock
seeds both uh great Gardener and and the
dock sell potentially I believe both of
them are exclusive to Rebecca at the
seat bank so that's correct uh you check
them out I exclusively sell them now
because there's the the internet is Rife
with
uh yeah you open yourself up to some
real um well just get potential fraud
yes oh right people selling hemp seeds
well are people lifting pictures and
information and calling them something
else to be honest it's the it's why
nowadays it's important to have that
official YouTube page and that official
uh Facebook page because you have a a
port hole for people to go to they don't
have to find you in little places
they're concentrated right to you and
then how you let them know that you're
you is by going and doing a short little
video and saying look I just made these
seeds I'm dropping them off there's this
many we'll let you know when they sell
out and you can control um the people
out there that are trying to be a little
a little bit dishonest completely
fraudulent in fact and selling and uh
seeds that they don't even have it's a
classic well anyways being an
underground guy for all these years you
know I've just learned from Mark about
the the latest the latest and the
greatest yes you know it's all this
Facebook and YouTube and you know
verification it all makes sense perfect
sense to me and the fact that we're
legal I mean listen the only reason
we're not criminals the only reason we
were underground is because they made us
criminals that's right without that
criminal element without you know with
the license on the wall I am a
completely different person I'm allowed
to be more honest I'm allowed to help
and share and educate and most
importantly I'm allowed to connect and
learn because there's a lot of people
out there that are inspired by well you
know all of that energy was sucked up in
being paranoid yeah of course what's
that car door it was the fuel for why is
that car been parked down there so long
that guy drove by four times yeah who's
that guy taking pictures of over there
that's right oh it was terrible I know
listen I was visiting a friend in
Portland one day if you think we had it
bad our poor American Brethren down
south you guys got a good now some of
you but wow I'd say 15 years ago I was
down in Portland for a fish show and I
was visiting my friend and it was on
Hawthorne Street right by the Safeway
and he was in those apartments right
across the street from the Safeway on
Hawthorne and hofor is kind of like the
hippie area Jack herrer son has a hemp
store there and there's a couple of head
shops and glass shops in that area and
so we're just puffing he's got a shitty
little glass spoon and we're just
puffing some herb and I guess a cop
pulls someone over outside in front of
his house and he just loses it dude I
mean running around his house collecting
everything flushing [ __ ] down the toilet
like completely believing that the cops
are here to come and get us and our
little amount of weed it was it was
weird to to feel that Vibe I mean I felt
it before in India when my room was
getting getting searched by the Army and
I had like a qu pound of Charis from
Nepal you know I was like this will be
10 years if I get caught and it will be
like 3 months before I have hepi and
some other crazy [ __ ] like 10 years in
an Indian prison not good mhm
right
well it I flashed back to a story of my
own when in back in this was back in the
smuggling days and uh I had these two
huge pair of boots that were C made yeah
uh kilo boots well yeah they were kilo
and a half boots with the
finest hand rubbed uh creme doar creme
champagne Ash you can imagine from
Northern India like Himel pesh or from
Manali Manali okay Manali Manali yeah
the Manali cream famous Valley so I'm
flying out of Deli uh expecting to get a
flight directly to London and then back
here here and everything was planned
when I got to the airport I was informed
because of uh equipment or some such
changes that I would have to be changing
planes in Beirut Lebanon oh un be knows
to me at the very last moment Jesus now
this is back in the 70s and and there
was a lot of [ __ ] going on there like
you know was the beginning of terrorism
and hijacking and all that kind of stuff
and I'll never
forget uh because we had to get out of
the plane and we had to wait and change
planes and we had to walk through a new
metal
detector and I was walking through this
metal detector and the sound of these
boots going over I'm my God and the
guard is looking straight at my
boots with his
ak47 and his bu thing he was looking
straight at my boots and I'm thinking to
myself as we used to say in the 60s and
70s when we were high maintain man
maintain maintain yeah and he looked the
other way and I went sat
down waited for that flight to call and
the moment we lift it off you're
like so anyway give us an idea now what
was your worry cuz in India for me my
worry was 10 years I'm doing in 10 years
if they find this 10 years for sure so
what was your worry was it uh death
penalty was it life in prison was it 10
you know what was the realistic worry in
your mind most of my business I was
conducting in Nepal MH and I had
connections and I wouldn't have gone to
jail there in where in Nepal no no but
in your fear of Beirut Landing in barut
where you just told the story what is
the fear is it death is it life in
prison is it
what flashed back to me was was Billy
Hayes in Turkey I don't know if you guys
Midnight Express Express okay this was
the exact same situation it's what I
pictured as you were telling me cuz they
have to get off the plane and he's got
all the hash wrapped around him and they
think it's a bomb well I wasn't quite as
greedy as Billy you know and I had it in
my boots and it was quite a a rough go
stitching him in there and by the way
this pure Manali cream was only 1,200
bucks a pound in Montreal in
1972 just to give you an idea where the
prices have gone in this whole thing but
anyway I would be back Montreal and have
three or four or five grand whatever it
was in a small time but back then you
could fly back to India for like 400
bucks and awesome and live in places
like Thailand for well for a couple of
bucks a day and uh that fin that's my
Asia junky holiday yeah there it is yeah
to me the that's what the 7s
was um Goa Goa yes K
Ki jumbla cashmir cashmir yeah and
carala South India what a beautiful
place I uh how far is that from Goa oh
that's down the coast that's a good 10
hours or something well
it's miles huge for those of you that
have never driven across India it's just
a monstrous country I drove into the
north from Delhi up into hardar which is
just near rishikesh Yeah by no means is
it up up up still took a long bloody
time you know and and you get there and
you're just in the Foothills at the
himas you're not even yeah you know it's
like listen man well in India is such a
trip I mean it's it's a completely it's
another world I mean it's really hard to
describe
um uh I'll I'll just interject another
funny little
story I don't know what has anything to
do with it but I I i' landed at Delhi at
3: in the morning and it was like
120° and 98% humidity so all I wanted to
do was go and crash out in a
hotel and uh which I did and and I
thought to myself well I want to go to
rishy cat which was about 200 kilometers
North so you're in New Deli right now
I'm in New Deli right now so the next
morning I wake up and I think okay I'm
going to go down to the public taxi
stand and I'll find a private car or a
taxi and I'll haggle with them anyway
turns out it was like about 25 bucks and
this is for a 200 kmet ride with a
private driver which is not going to be
a 2hour drive for those of you that have
never well I'm going to get into that
okay so I'm lying across the back street
like this back seat like that I'm kind
of comfortable I'm thinking holy [ __ ]
you're in one of these old 1950 Styles I
got some blot acid with me Christ you
know and I thought should I or shouldn't
I definitely and I said I
should I should so I took a blot off we
go little did I know that the main Trunk
Road which link
rishikes was actually two lanes but
there was eight Lanes of traffic of
donkeys of cows of Rick Shaws of trucks
of buses of cars carts of like carts
carts that they've been using for like
2000 years and there's like all along
the side of the road there's people
making tea and selling trinkets babies
man mangy dogs everything just the whole
and potentially a little bit of death
mixed in there that's right and I was
sitting back going like this is like a
IMAX felini
movie times 100 for you young guys out
there F was an Italian film director who
used to make these way out movies he
made that crazy chick F who who did he
make famous that big crazy weird chick
that would like Divine Divine what is it
yeah it was you remember Pink Flamingos
I remember Pink Flamingos I must be old
I remember all of it anyways we're
diverting here again so he's tripping on
acid he's driving up to rishik mer cash
I'm in the back SE this taxi there's
there's eight Lanes of chaos going on
outside we're weaving in and out Indians
have a sick sense about when when they
don't hit any they just kind of
Miss I don't know man we were just
weaving in and out and I was like just
totally tripped w i I thought man I'm I
can't imagine actually I'm over it's
heavy it is heavy were you saying to
yourself maintain
maintain I was saying maintain but the
best thing all we finally got there to
rishy cash he brought me to this nice
hotel and as I walked in the lobby they
were doing Puja which in India is a
ceremony ringing bells and these candles
and these bramman priests and chanting
and I felt like oh God surreal like your
to your arrival too when you're tripping
on acid it's all about like timing and
the you know in that moment and I could
imagine that would have brought a tear
to your eye well it as they
say and it is true with acid or any
psychedelic or even ganja for that
matter set and setting
are of the most
importance in terms of the result of
your experience yeah they should should
definitely be in the same vein of
quality as the substance you've sought
out absolutely and I think when people
have bad trips I think the main cause is
the set and setting were disregarded or
or weren't taken seriously I'd say
that's like 95% of the time yeah the bar
setting let's go drink a bunch of beer
and get super high we're Prairie boys
woohoo it's like
o that's not going to be F I mean us us
just being aware of that fact we choose
to take our ethnog in the proper set and
setting absolutely and we're here on the
beautiful west coast of Canada it's not
hard to do no usually just get away from
people get your small group and get into
a group it's a very personal thing so
you want to be around people that that
you're willing to be uncomfortable
around and sometimes it's a simple it's
why you connect so deeply with people on
psychedelics on anthens because I'm just
wondering Mark you know with all with
our freestyle of talking and
interviewing I don't even know what you
call it anymore is that it's called
hanging out and being friends is that I
mean I don't know are your viewers do
they want to structure I know I think
they appreciate this they really
appreciated our last video and this is
really what we did you know take a
couple more bowls and just uh tell great
stories you know there's there's what I
read from the comments is that there's
some old school dudes out there that
aren't really sharing right now they're
not really and you brought that out in
them they were like one guy was like oh
I brought a a lid of of Panamanian red
to Viet toam one so yeah that's what he
said a lid of pan P so like when I read
that I thought this is cool yeah you
know I when you said that word lid of
course I mean for all you people out
there a lid used to be like a dime bag
or how many joints fit in a lid okay and
another term that I I hadn't come across
for the the longest time was a was a
term called cop do you want a cop which
meant do you want to buy you want to
procure you go cop some herb you want to
cop some herb and I had heard reminds me
of the Child's Garden of Grass well I
hadn't heard that for like since the 70s
and I was I was at a someone's house the
other day and
and I think he was a Canabis uh uh
person yeah yeah of course go figure and
I was there and someone else was there
and the other person wanted to talk to
him so he's going to me cop man go ahead
and cop and you're like and I'm going
[ __ ] I haven't heard that since
1969 yeah where
you he's holding on to that lingo maybe
he was listening to the Child's Garden
of Grass you ever have that comedy album
no you would have heard it for sure the
Child's Garden of Grass okay and there's
all these different like there's the one
where the the like did you ever notice
smoking marijuana uh in increases your
musical ability and then the guy goes in
the shower he's in the shower and
someone opens the door and they're like
hey man you want to have a hit he's like
oh sure
sure so he takes a hit oh before that he
was singing and he was singing really
badly he was
like super bad he takes the hit and then
all of a sudden he he turns that into
this crazy Funk song and it just builds
he's
like then horns and like bass come in
and he's got backup singers and it's all
an album you just hear it but I'm
telling you man like when I was young
getting high listening to this album it
was funny [ __ ] and the the reason that
reminded me of it was because there was
another skit where the dude's like
there's three ways to to get grass and
so one of the ways was to like you know
he's talking to a guy on the street and
he like creates a distraction and the
guy drops his grass and it's like and
you cop that [ __ ] and run it's a comedy
album if you've heard it you'll laugh if
not Google it you can hear it on YouTube
I'm surprised you don't know that Al
well it almost reminds me of uh I don't
know if you remember the fire sign
theater that that's old hippie stuff
right from the from the 60s even late
60s that that was about the dawn of FM
radio I was only born in the 70s oh
there you go the early '70s 73 actually
plus my yellow a great year man it was
Grateful Dead killed it in 73 to me my
favorite Grateful Dead years are 77 73
and 71 I don't know what drugs they were
doing those particular years but um they
were good ones they were good
ones they're probably some sort of haze
yes absolutely and various psychedelics
oh man so what other sativas are you
rocking in your uh stable these days my
stable yeah what are your special
sativas my special sativas okay well
there's the thae lights which was a uh
Tha strin from Thailand of course tlight
that's a spe that's lemon [ __ ] too
that's lemon as
[ __ ] the story of that and there's
numerous other ones I have a friend in
Thailand who's uh he's actually a
carpenter and he he makes beautiful
wooden
Grinders uh I I was putting inlays in
them and stuff and uh I I Market those
and he's also a cannabis fan and we
travel around Thailand collecting
genetics awesome and a lot of the times
I was told I had to wait
and because of the paranoia it's so
going on there sure what's happened
there I I just want to comment on that a
bit is that a lot of these uh indigenous
genetics in Southeast Asia have been
lost to the cultivation of heroin um and
that of course invites
violence yeah oh yeah uh and all that
kind of stuff and then it the government
and the police lump all of it together
as drugs drugs mhm including cannabis
right okay that you know you can be is
seriously in trouble both with the law
and the bad guys yeah if they think that
rock in a hard place yeah
anyway T Twilight's not the newest
tlights are excellent very lemony very
high you collected some seeds in
somewhere in Northern Thailand Northern
Thailand all over NE prenom neom it's
the northeast of Thailand toar H close
to Cambodia codia right the other side
yeah the other side Cambodia and La up
in that area you've got a lot of good
genetics uh I have worked although I'm
not right now with the LA ocean not
quite as strong as the thae I think Tai
you you bring a Cambodian sativa yes I
do I do and I have a Cambodian sativa uh
it's actually from the Cambodian tide
border beautiful it didn't come with a
passport on the Cambo side I was just
going to say it didn't come with a
passport so I'm not I found even when I
was there in the '90s that often
especially in the islands in the
South um I was on colante Y and
collected some of the nicest her i' seen
the whole time I was there and he was
like yeah I get it from
Cambodia he was like it was Cambodia
really oh yeah nice TOA oh man
yeah yeah quite nice so that's nice you
got the Cambodian sativa you've got the
thail lights those are the main primary
sativas um awesome I'm I'm also going to
start to work with uh um the Congo and
the Beautiful uh the harmony uh other to
other sativas from uh different breeders
um good call we were discussing this
before about you know ganja comes from
God and we all get it from somewhere
else so yeah I've never pulled it out of
my ass
no I collect seeds from living plants
but even that plant was planted by
someone someone or something I know and
we could go back forever in the past and
forever into the future but here we are
in this particular moment yeah with
access to these particular genetics and
access to the resources like it's
important for guys like you who have the
resources that have put in all these
years decades in fact uh to continue to
do what they do because you get better
at it well this is true you know and as
you get better at something and then you
realize oh like I've done all this
amazing land I've I've I've traveled the
globe to collect landra sativas well now
maybe I'll use a couple that are that
are right here that I have access to you
know well I think right now in British
Columbia we have access to the best
genetics in the world yeah with the help
of the internet I feel like right now in
the world if you're the right person and
you're the you can get online and and
and show your passion and become a part
of this community it seems pretty
possible for anyone to acquire almost
almost anything you know and the more we
break down that barrier of you know
giving out Cuts with
rules it's just uh you know I understand
the fear that there's not enough for you
but it's not a good enough reason to
keep ganja from everyone it's just not a
good enough reason but that's true of
the business side of anything MH you
know that one protects one's product
absolutely you know I mean to a degree
yes but we're talking about something
different here one of the business side
of it says that but the spiritual side
and you know I hate using the word
spiritual the life affirming side of
cannabis that is which should definitely
be shared yeah 100% And it's when it
becomes a
business and we get into this that's
mine well I talked I talked to someone
online who was like they were like oh
you guys are all into sharing then send
me seeds and I sort of was like well
listen okay it's just like anything we
share safely with people that we can
trust and then the seed business is
created to get seeds to the rest of the
people you know there has to be if guys
like you and Matt and uh breeder Steve
and S if they don't breed genetics and
sell them on the open market then other
people will just produce a lesser
product use the same pictures use the
names and people won't get what they
need to get so I understand the business
aspect of it is necessary but I don't
believe that hoarding or controlling the
mothers should be you know what I mean I
think that it's just uh you know sure
you you work with your strains and
create your things that's not to say
someone else can't take Congo and and
sweet skunk can make something else that
they make you know what I mean if you
want to bring something that's unique
then don't collect a strain that
everyone has go to the land race strains
like you did and pull it out of nature I
did the same thing I literally that
Jamaican strain that I have man it is a
wild one I cannot wait it's a mutant
it's got two branches coming off one
leaf two full growths and a horal phytol
axi with the three leaves growing out so
we love our mutants in the world of
breeding well can I offer you another
bong rip on our way out here doc yeah
yeah excellent you got any last awesome
stories for us or medication we'll
medicate me I'll see if I can definitely
happy to help
this one's M
Wicked
Watermelon from my mentor Ron have you
ever met
Ron you got to meet
Ron Ron's
awesome well we do have a couple of more
special guests today well obviously John
is always on puff Wednesday which it is
Puff Wednesday right now me and Doc are
just starting it off a little early John
will be here probably in about 20
minutes and Matt the great Gardener
should be here also within any minute
now so that'll be kind of fun to have uh
all four of these guys together for a
little puff for now the doc and I are
going to uh take a break and we'll catch
up with you when the other guys get here
thanate thanks for the genetics that's
awesome apprciate it share your
herbs
[Music]