[Music]
hey guys bubble man here and it is Puff
Wednesday uh I'm actually heading down
right now to a little place nearby where
I live it's actually where the ferry
terminal is called Horseshoe Bay and uh
Johnny Be is meeting me down there right
now and what I thought I was going to do
I thought what would be a good idea is
if we took you to a couple of cool spots
uh where we enjoy uh puffing so we've
got uh the Horseshoe Bay Park we've got
Lighthouse well I'm not sure if we're
going to do Lighthouse but we'll for
sure do um oh what the heck is the name
of the park now it's spacing
me it's right near Horseshoe Bay well
it's that that's the one we're going to
go to for the starter and we'll walk out
to the Rocks we'll show share a little
bit of the adventure it is kind of
raining out here today but that doesn't
uh that's not going to stop us from uh
from rocking on and uh yeah I just
wanted to do a quick little introduction
I am now driving on my way to C Johnny B
and I'll be there in all of oh maybe
four or five minutes so we'll see him
really soon all
right all right Johnny be's in the house
for puff Wednesday oh no what are we
doing are we at our spot we're ordering
food dude that's what we do we're at the
olivan anchor in Horseshoe Bay the
camera's totally dead we need to order
food before anything happens so that's
what we're doing we got a pumpkin and
you got water it's not bad not triple
Express good to see you
buddy fantastic to see we're about to
get puffed hard let's let's eat let's
let's SM Johnny be the food just came
what do you got there Caden chicken oh
dude show that food porn off to the to
the camera porn very good I think this
should be here I myself got the crispy
cod
tacos very excited about these with a
little bit of french fries some uh
you're filming I'm Instagram I'm
Snapchatting are you Snapchatting over
there John Snapchat you never stop never
stop never stop all right we're going to
eat and then we're going to pop well
Johnny and I have arrived here at the
parking lot in Horseshoe Bay which is
coincidentally enough where this Trail
starts private property private property
no trespassing danger danger yeah that's
where I'm going don't [ __ ] around there
it is all
right
okay so this isn't a very long trail
Johnny B I think you'll be good to go
just make sure you watch your
step so you don't have any slippages
figured we would
do this spot first there's a little bit
more of a trail here
I guess it heads
in to the area of that
house past that gate there a Big 5 acre
property here this whole Mountain
actually what's up I you know yeah we're
going to have a puff here puffing yeah
that nice let's set our little selves up
look at
this all right so we have acquired
ourselves into the first position
Horseshoe Bay epicness yeah get that
hoodie on there Johnny B get a hoodie
on
oh bit of
rosin sorry for the loudness of my torch
we're D nailist today we're torching it
up John with the
fullblown Mother Ship who the [ __ ] was
that put water in there what no not yet
but I
should I'll do it while it's you should
change the your torch a little bit there
that's pretty [ __ ] trippy
ah Johnny be life just isn't the same
without
you he'll have no gas left in that torch
in about 3
minutes it's a setting on the front
there you go you're getting
closer I'll I'll hook you up with mine
bro if it if you need
be what kind of torch are you using I
got myself a Blazer here it's actually
Flav's torch that he left at my house
he's he always HED up yeah he I think he
left it accidentally but yeah you're
right he does always hook it
up we talking about FL 421 the guy is
like w I almost lost my dab don't L your
dab and don't hit it that hot either
hell no because we're outside I will do
a little bit of a different uh time I
usually let these things go for a minute
to a minute and a half my particular one
not John's quartz but this particular uh
ceramic and so I'm just going to hit my
timer real quick I'm going to look at
that fairy that that I love so much
there we go and I'm going to dab to it
perfect anytime you like my good friend
I'll be right behind you hoodless and
dabbing
here there you go bro I got
you I got you on the on the carb Johnny
forgot his carb today so what a friends
for if not to carve one another's
Mothership Rosen turp dipped [ __ ] yeah
rip correct the water did I say that
properly you forgot the water here let's
put some in mine like I think you forgot
the
water so we're right now at 3940 so he's
like perfectly on
par that was so tasty what was Turf for
that Karma's [ __ ] Karma's [ __ ] for the
win for the win all right I'm coming in
behind you Johnny B I'm at 55 seconds I
think I'm good double capping well D can
that little Sizzle from those turps and
just not just just any tur but the
dip if you're not double
dipping as if D would say triple
dip bong
rip what time is
it that would be a it's it's 416 what
about yours 416 416 all right we got
four more minutes till 420 we're
probably going to do 420 here we'll see
what happens we're doing a 420 down love
standing on the dirt the fact that I if
I was on concrete this very well may
have broke but did you see how I caught
it with my no that was it was the kick
and then I did the I tried to hacky it
like the when dropping your c cap on the
side of a mountain a little hacky sack
might take care of business here here
you go Johnny
no like okay wait a second ah God I feel
so much better after having a puff on
puff Wednesday puff Wednesday is just
not the same without puffing I haven't
haven't it's not the same with ou it's
not the same look at this dude I know
can you guys like
we're ocean bound we're 420 bound we're
going to catch you guys in a few minutes
different
place all right so here we are White
Cliff Park on a little Adventure I've
never been here when I came around the
corner I was like trying to like I want
to like take a picture I was like wow
this is like it's a good spot it's cool
think it's there Johnny I mean it's like
toughen spots for VC I I love it I love
I love I love I love the scenery and
what we can see absolutely
yeah these trails are great this is epic
no dude I'm telling you like super epic
just do a quick peek on the water here
there's little benches
everywhere Tugboat pulling some
trees so yeah this is it Lighthouse Park
but uh I think I
think I think we can do better than this
so follow me Johnny B I follow
oh you okay I'm fine ship's great in the
Pelican case you know it's fine I didn't
even cares
like right
away Johnny Be oh I see this is where it
splits so we want to get over we want to
go back this
way because otherwise there's a cool
little beach that goes down there and
it's real private but I want to take you
to this rock over here and we'll have a
nice little couple of Puffs overlooking
the
ocean
behind beautiful beautiful trees in this
park just
epic nice little Cove right
there but where I want to take us and I
have some beautiful Drone footage that
I'm going to share with you guys uh it's
a much sunnier day you'll notice the
transition but
to the real
[Music]
autic
orous
[Music]
indigenous I food from man planting
Iration where
watering give me full weeks of flowering
full St with the
[Music]
raining what you say Johnny
B right
here
Johnny there you are
there you are that's what I'm I'm
doing I always pay attention to my feet
where I'm stepping I think that's a
great idea I don't really you know this
this looks like the safer
back right along the top
beautiful
wow not bad huh do you want to go over
to that island and walk across those
rocks and then go to the other side and
have a little sash
I have to say I'd be lying said I don't
well let's do it it's a long walk it'll
take us it'll take us 10
minutes we're doing it all right
dude I think we got to our spot Johnny
B like right here that's the safest spot
this is really good right here I think
we got a nice little Zone here mother
ship's
safe I can have a
sit what do you say
bud so we cheated a little bit we
decided against going across to the
island over there and the main reason is
is that a the water tide the tide goes
up and down and when it goes down it's
great and life is wonderful but when it
goes up uh it becomes a little bit more
problematic and we're not interested in
getting caught might be going up right
it always is going up and down so it's
you're 50/50 on that one anytime so we
found ourselves a good spot here on the
peninsula as you can see nice drop down
behind me and I think this drop down I
think this is where we're going to set
up a nice little sesh for uh for puff
Wednesday it could be the last sesh I
don't know if we're going to make it to
the third spot I hope so but if not
let's get this sesh started I have't
dropped all right we made our spot you
get the verd who's this dude dude he's
honing in on the SES he's like what's up
boys heard you guys got that uh you got
that eth that ethical Gro grown dank
like I heard you got some solventless
stuff solventless in the house hey budy
he's like a seagull he's like the goat
of birds that's the best thing about you
know how relaxed and peaceful it is with
the type of uh vibe that you give off as
than just being a pooker just kind of
chilling the seagull wants to hang over
with us like dud these guys are pretty
chill I'm feeling it he's he's happy
all right well we're hitting dry I know
that we're hitting dry but I'm still
getting my turps
out I'm still pulling off
my all right da pad here I don't think I
need a dab pad no dab pad oh well I'll
put it like right here this I do need a
Dabber and otherwise put that down
so you saw the drop of the Pelican case
I did see the drop of the Pelican case
that was that was that was something was
something that was
something oh I know what I need still
risk free my torch are you feeling a
breeze we need to get some dabs first
before I heat this up
actually all right let me get that for
you please do I've got the TPS right
here that we'll be dipping in I got some
of the
rosin from path life path life it's a
path life puff Wednesday actually you
like that cuz I don't think we hit
anything else yet no so not in turs well
and some Blue River that's true and some
Blue River and some Blue River in there
seagull hanging on he's chilling he's
like I've been waiting to see this [ __ ]
my over here ts are right here he like
really TPS TS TPS are real and
rosin yes sir thank you sir
that right here so you know what what
are you guys puffing on a puff Wednesday
true enough love to see your comments
yeah where you're from and what you're
puffing on whether it's a flower the
cultivar of the flower the rosin the
extract some form of concentrate a
mechanical screen separation whether dry
or wet don't matter did you make it
share it with us let us know what you
are your own
artist to dip your D can you dip me
please
do oh yes dou dip
well I like uh I like the uh I like the
two dabs
good I can have both you I was like
really all right I was just did a little
puff down with Dana lison and he had two
joints in his mouth so I had to I've
seen Dana do that before had to get a
picture you know me I do know you okay
you know what he's
like my phone's dead I can't even time
this
one I got one in my pocket oh got gu
there I got one in my
pocket John spends $1900 a month on his
phone taking selfies he was telling me
earlier off camera that's incredible
dude I just
Jing phone bills are expensive up here
in Canada though no joke no
[ __ ] play around and then when they
don't send you Bill for 3 months they
send you threatening text
message I was like
why am I talking to my Skully
F I don't
know you're just kind of uh do as you
need to do kind of guy you know kind of
do that Stu it's in your mouth you got a
pipe in your hand and a torch in the
other dab is quite
important smells
amazing yeah those karma [ __ ] Tarin are
off the
chart so because I have a quartz and he
has a
ceramic yeah I wouldn't wait much more
than 50 seconds on yours total I do W 35
because I don't have a carb oh but you
have the carb cap I do have the carb
borrow that carb cap see I I seem to
forget the carb cap and last time I
forgot the whole quartz
Banger and then I brought the drop down
mine didn't get that hot surprisingly
yeah I'm going to hit it soon here H
soon soon enough so I at least get a rip
and it's not all cold doing the same
thing it's cold out here and the wind is
really cold out here so you definitely
have to adjust how long you let your
bowl cool for a lot to different time
than you would normally in like a room
temperature room it's probably about 50°
that's a big ass boat I'll need that in
about 10
seconds pass that thing right
over the glass is already nice and cool
it was a really nice tasty what kind of
vessel do you think that is I think
that's a sea
bus it's got passengers in it I've never
seen it I'm neither it's got a BC fairy
flag on it does the or a BC flag
sorry no I've never seen that
before wait till you won't I don't know
if you guys can see it I'll get out of
the way Coastal
something
no we have to let them see it that's
cool
you never seen that before per seeo left
well he's like
[ __ ] I wonder if they saw him fly away
he's like [ __ ] John says he's like
[ __ ] well that was delicious I I
actually still have some left on
here well nice enjoyable puff
Wednesday the best thing about a puff
Wednesday is it's the middle of the week
and it's a time that you we can look
back at the beginning of the week and
look forward to the end of the week well
said I mean the puff Wednesday for me is
kind of like that there like okay you
know what the day is over it's 4:20
going to do a puff relax and take a look
at how the first of the week went now
I'm going to look forward to the end of
the week the weekend yes I mean it's a
great it's it's a great day to just kind
of think back and H middle of the week
middle of the week Friday's coming but
puff Wednesday is H yeah it's a nice
time to uh
just travel around check things out get
out that's what kind of puff Wednesday
from my perspective is is to get out go
I like the idea of us not just sitting
in the same spot all the time but making
sure that we're in a different
environment each time to sort of show
you guys and it's really quite beautiful
got to flip the camera
around yeah little BC culture we can
just Flip Flip the
camera show the uh
see him
going he's circling he's going to land
right behind us fall colors are coming
in I wish I had the Drone but I am going
to show them a bit of Drone footage from
a sunny day when there were some kids
jumping off that rock over
there that island is going down
well not bad not bad at all sounds
pretty amazing you know what I can hear
In My Head Right Now bump bump
bu you know the end the credits thanks
for sharing your puff Wednesday with us
everybody Johnny B as always a pleasure
my friend peace out
[Music]