[Music]
all right welcome to poem man's world
I'm here with Mark and Remo the cush
brothers yeah we're over at Remos place
here and we just basically ran an
incredible batch a couple of weeks ago
you can see people cuz we do yeah you
probably saw the video footage and
pictures that I had on my social media
worked out really lovely so we've got
that all the samples here put out and
I've already had a few hits we actually
did a gauntlet a few minutes ago we
smoked them all we smoked every single
one of them and sort of talked a little
bit about them and you'll be able to
check that out on Remos channels or do a
shout-out to your tooth my youtube
channels their burger and were able to
speed our urban rail absolutely I'm not
sure if you can put anything up anytime
soon you might as well come a shout out
to your channel as well the couch
brothers
channels coming up the engine anyway I
thought we'd just do a couple of riffs
for the for the camera and yes you know
what I've got to see this this is the
smoothest bubble passion I've ever seen
in my life like it stinks it's
definitely very nice and that's a good
sign that your hash contains alcohol
soluble terpenes and terpenoids flavors
and tastes that would otherwise
potentially be water soluble which one
we made the bubble you saw the water and
the bottom cylinders
nice color and it had a nice smell to it
we didn't even drink any animal but it
tastes just like cannabis teeth
unfortunately those you know that's the
one downside for water extraction is
that and it's why we don't want to leave
the hash in the water for so long
because it robs those flavors alcohol
soluble beans
end up with that full plate which is
lying which is why your hash smells like
a concentrated paste be that do that
class breathing things of that mom also
simpler completely absolutely you know
to a degree I mean some people like they
want to leave it out overnight we're
definitely still leaving it out I like
the idea of playing around in the future
knowing that I can imagine saving to
move much more this seems you know
terpene full but the idea of getting low
humidity cold environments almost like a
walk-in freezer
we're walking fridge that allows the
toilet of the better obviously these
things evaporator right so any attitude
to whatsoever is going to even evaporate
the water so the coal generally put
something if you're curing your hash
sometimes you blow it back here my hash
in the freezer and then you're
suspending your house
as it was first day
[Music]
I'm happy with how this turned out it's
definitely super flavorful super melty
and looking for natural ingredients and
pictures of the mouth factors potatoes
just got me all excited to take a hit so
that word person 90 absolute first nice
rock tonight yeah from from what I
remember from her last con this was the
most potent and killer of all it was
absolutely in fact the 160 was just nice
the 120 okay Alan I'm feeling that I
felt it like if I was using it more
medicinally like my friend John for
instance we've got quite a few breaks
and whatnot he to me he just feels it
right away when he takes a good grip you
kind of fee as his knees when we eat his
ankles or are pretty quite as much I
felt that from the one after this one oh
here we go turbo death kill surprised me
actually thanks to Bolin
these guys are you doing a supercharged
your joint video coming up here soon -
and they're gonna be destroyed
we are and you're welcome to participate
yes well what I'm going to do is I'm
going to change some bubbles of the else
that's okay to do while you guys are
participating
so that is our screen yeah so yes the
color on this is really nice super super
light it's really held on your blonde
color and like almost as though it was
in a French Lick I'm impressed
well that was so nice
absolutely tasty big tote - yeah
but the gospel is awesome absolutely and
that'll be up on that rebirth channel
there we'll definitely check that out
that's the whole actually turning that
you be able to you know isolating
glandular trichomes cats and I would
like to say that the magic really
happens sure it's nice to know someone
that knows the process and isn't gonna
make any mistakes that's always a big
thing you might pay majority of the
difficulty of coming up with a product
like this happens in the grow room
you're a moral authority to makers you
know can't be control of everything and
making sure things are going right
instead of wrong that's where you get
your phone out patch crazy the banks
themselves they're really really just a
tool go to the ice
I guess this hatch took us polygamy yeah
in the in the long run it's a four and a
half months well worth it for it to go
and you've been there in the hole all
the way through Wow look at Marty looks
like things won't work the delicious man
elastic easy smooth no call yeah really
fun so thanks for coming out and being a
part of the show and yeah thanks for
having me Reno thanks for being here
tumor the best thank you very much we're
actually one puffing we will yeah we'll
see you next time
alright hey I was going Remo welcome to
my car
got a whole bunch of Muji fish place
girls real tall ones over here okay well
we'll follow you to the real tall ones
you know that's well let's see I'm
six-two with a two and a half to three
foot arm and I can just touch the top of
that pole the one over there is taller
yeah
that's I actually have two plants that
are taller
chocolate Cushman D they're some tall
plants
gallon pot
seven gallon pot both all
maybe
and ceiling for sure big size nights on
that too it's got the wolf stuff
[Music]
and then got some way to
like a white ROG there's one on the edge
here we can get to play
get rid of that
here's a way no chief okay
excellent
this room looks great
doesn't take much for you to disappear
and then reappear
yeah it smells wonderful
oh yeah you have a real trichrome forest
here no doubt about it
exceptional we sure have great air in
here Remo
see the Green Hornet LED green
our cycle is in the dark the green light
does not affect the light cycle at the
cannabis plant so we can be in here and
enjoying it without causing your
flowering period any detrimental
they definitely her
well thanks for having me Remo I'm
pretty stoked - always a pleasure to be
here in your grow you know playing
around with the resident
see you soon