[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and more importantly welcome to Puff
Wednesday look at this group of
characters I have behind me Amir is
visiting in from Turkey Johnny B in from
abbotford and d420 K in from Prince
George you know me I'm from right here
in Lion's
Bay and I guess today we're going to do
a quick little boat cruise these guys
are doing their ice cream and their
Waters right now clown and uh we're
going to basically Cruise out to the
middle of the sound it's red tide right
now so I'd like to go for a swim but not
exactly in the red tide so we'll see
what happens we're going to look for
some Dolphins we're definitely going to
see The elusive pure hash joint I've
heard heard that they're out here in the
middle of the house sound I think we got
house joint you said I think we've got a
line on one guys so we'll keep you guys
informed puff Wednesday coming at you
from the Pacific Ocean
today
[Music]
peace
man yeah how sounding it bar
Asher H Wednesday Wednesday come here
Nick
John John
B
[Music]
it's about to get a lot quieter over
here we're heading over behind one of my
favorite Islands Boyer Island not to be
confused with Bowen Island you can see
the water is already getting calmer and
soon as we get
closer it'll be very calm this is where
we bring the kits for tubing and water
skiing and generally this is where a lot
of my friends take their boats and go
hang out sort of in the office do
computer work and other sort of more
boring things that you don't have to do
in an office when you got yourself a
little boat what are we doing today over
there though over here we're going to go
for a swim how about a POP well we're
definitely going for a pop that's puff
Wednesday everything's a puff they're
puffing right
now sh
[Music]
s
sun's so warm you'll dry up quick and
fast look at the red
[Music]
tie should we cross it and get closer to
the uh no why
not might as well
get to the nice green water over there
drippy look at the red tide you guys
wow well trust me you're about
to yeah all over around look at that
blood red water is different blood
red
Slayer wow this is trippy
dude yeah
oh
hey John all the way here yes
did over here the nice nice green
colored water here I
believe make this is
[Music]
still recording awesome
brother all right so here we are
in the
zone going to check it
out here in the house sound guys so
fun beautiful red tide like not sure how
much the camera is picking that up but
we are surrounded by Red Tide however
the water we're in right now is quite
green so looks like de's getting ready
to jump
in woo scared the [ __ ] out of me the
[ __ ] almost put me
in I'm coming to join you you
bastard we're all jumping and here we go
it's a 420 jumping 1 2
420 there you guys
go yeah puff
Wednesday woo John quick puff for us and
um I'm the camera guy today because um
I'm not jumping in the water we all jump
off we're going to throw John in as soon
as we get to the boat yeah that is not
going to happen Okay so I'm jumping in
the boat I'll see you guys later you can
swim back John
be puff
Wednesday you guys going in again or
[Music]
what good times with good friends good
hash on a beautiful [ __ ] ocean on a
bluebird
day you know this is what you say it's
going Johnny
B torture beine he asks me well we're in
the ocean I think we can do the beine
thing yeah well
no nice
[Music]
job it's all about the
hash wonderful all about it's all about
your dbit toe
keep it h all right so I killed my video
camera we are now finishing this video
with the iPhone these guys are still
puffing like the world is about to end
so I'm pretty down with that we're going
to going to light this pure hash joint
if John just put in the medtainer in a
little bit we're going to limp back over
to where I live I think Darren and I are
going to hit the bikes maybe John and
air are going to follow us in a vehicle
to have some dinner and maybe a cchq
session oh yeah and then back up up to
here to do a sunset on the boat I've
already kind of promised my daughter I'd
take her water skiing and these guys I
think they want to come back out on the
boat too absolutely puff Wednesday red
tide Excell right on guys best puff
Wednesday ever epic all right so let's
give you a little
show
good
day it's always a good puff Wednesday
when you got lots of friends in the
house puffing
puffing John got a lighter I have the
lighter all right we're good welcome
back to Bubble man's world guys I'm here
with Johnny B and d420 K
and where the [ __ ] are we this is like
the cauld CER yeah I guess the new
Convention Center is here the seven
sales is over there right on the water
we have Harbor air behind us and we're
in the middle of a pathway so tons of
people are going to walk in front of the
camera but don't worry about it we have
Harbor center right there we're still
going to uh share our hash flip hash
joints
yeah let's try this out we have this
here said
goad right
through
fall all the I got
this yeah why don't that joint what is
this a regular one John uh that would
actually be the Dennis Hopper Dennis
Hopper very nice dry taste is it very
nice dry pull
is oh you know what it's very nice I
[Music]
did F you know the best thing about is
when you need to medicate you need to
medicate you got to medicate and you
have to medicate so that's what we're
doing here in the super busiest part of
Vancouver work oh no
please no I said no please please oh I
was going to say that's okay I said
Google my name I'll just pull out my
permit you got a permit he's got a
permit and we're supposed to smoke in
public property
so it's nice being in Vancouver my road
trip is
[Music]
just it's what couping to day five now I
got another 10 days for a while yeah I
got another 10 days of rideing my bike
onto the island coming back to Vancouver
go go right ahead coming back to
Vancouver we're going to uh look up with
John here and uh take my to Puff hard
we're going to spend a day
together yeah
nice I'll come crash the day he can come
crash the day any
day you know how I roll my buddy my bro
chance he uh he has his license and
wants to get hooked up with compassion
clubs here so John's going to take us
around to all the facilities oh yeah to
all of the good facilities yeah where
they have the best hash the best herb
for medicinal use you
know help your
P
Amica nice all right you guys are
enjoying that doie got the beautiful sun
behind you puff that John
puff puff pass buddy look at this look
at this gorgeous view behind us have you
seen this I see I see all this that's
some City action right there guys I mean
we're surrounded we got planes here we
got we got the mountains behind
us Harbor air if you need to make a
quick trip to the island one of these
planes will do the job for
you that house joint how's that how's
that treating you it treating me really
well you know what because I'm not
passing it it won't fall apart the
minute I pass it it'll be pinched and
fall apart I think Darren called it by
having you light that joint that was the
smart thing to
do that's a nice
thing cuz it literally fell apart the
minute I touched my mouth to it just
from falling in the ocean earlier when I
jumped into the lake uh to the ocean
with have ocean cure didn't you how you
doing man little bit of an ocean cure
we're always good in and out yeah right
out us two medicate no I'm not beening
out chilling chilling CH chilling out
nice washing the
planes departures and arrivals the
gates and then of course these two
characters this is nice really nice sun
on the face beautiful
water beautiful people everywhere it's
just it's nice very nice
here visit but I like my my bush living
in in the
north I feel the same
way all
right has joints at the end of the line
here disintegrating and falling
apart all right
buddy
it's nice to have this
here well I guess this is uh another
puff Wednesday here but we'll be back
when we're back and who's with us will
remain to be
[Music]
seen