[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world guys puff
Wednesday it's Wednesday again already
always Wednesday John's in the house he
just rolled up again and of course John
never rolls up light John rolls up heavy
so what would you bring us today new
stuff yeah what you bring us today on
the new new stuff we keep talking about
like Shades and and and you wanted some
light for your Shades and stuff so after
uh going over some things we found this
and they're Nano does by Sun Blaster so
we actually picked these up and what
this enti is which is so cool is these
reflectors right here that I just picked
up for you that are extra bright I put
one in yesterday in my own little I'll
actually show in video what I'll do
pretty soon but I put one of these in
and the light was just so much more
intense I was like wow I was like you
know what I definitely I want to give
you an option so I brought the the four
footer with two shades or the one two
footer with one shade interesting so
we're going to open this up here check
it out you need uh the little cutting
scissors that I had yeah you know what I
just kind of gave a little tear here
straight all these is you can just kind
of pull this apart and get it out we're
going to slide this out
and as you can see this new shade oh wow
yeah and we got these little things here
so I'm going to peel this off warning
for reflecting for moving so we're going
to peel this off beautiful get that in
there that's a nice little unit It just
fits right over it fits right over right
on it inserts right in beautiful perfect
nanotech T5
reflector excellent wait until you see
the version that my buddy Ron did
probably 5 years ago he wanted his own
kind of this version and he built his
own custom one which he's promised me
one of so we'll show we'll show you that
that's great so we got that you got
these easy little Clips if you want to
mount it and they got the little hangers
that if you want to mount it in a
different way with those same hangers
that we have in the shed but you know
what it's just easy you put it on top of
the D both I think plug it in I'll need
three domes one this can do my one Dome
and then that will do two more do two
right across perfect boom we set it
right on the shade and away we go so of
course I saw this yesterday right away
and then you also brought a little bit
of promx with some uh Coco gold of
course Coco fiber that we're going to
just uh do another remix the way we did
before I've already used all that dirt
from last time but
uh something else too oh what else did
you bring I oh that treat um that would
be um well I I flipped on January 2 in
and came down 420 so that would be the
My Little Pony like I don't know we
can't we have to do the days on it we're
going to take a look at that upstairs
nice excellent okay cool well we're
going to maybe quickly fill up this tub
that I have back
here with dirt and the mix add a little
bit of moisture so I have that ready and
then we'll see you guys upstairs uh when
we set up these cloning trays see you
guys there John has set up the little
onef footer with the Clones that I have
already you can see some Roots growing
in the background there
and I've got two new tubs here with the
two-footer sitting on top sitting on the
Pelican cases how sweet is that quite
stoked that's uh that should be nice
John it's good stuff you know I love how
we can connect them together and the
lights were directly on top absolutely
it's um it's perfect excellent well we
got clones to take so we'll be uh
getting back to that and we'll see you
guys later on Bubble Man's World
Peace
couple of cars going by Johnny
yeah so we're we're here in West
Vancouver behind the Lionsgate bridge
Vancouver is just on the other side of
that bridge and that's Stanley Park that
is attached to and we just figured we'd
stop on the way back from the city for a
little puff Wednesday so here we
are I'm going to join you in a second
John well welcome back to Bubble Man
World guys uh John and I have as you
noticed left the house uh we actually
went to get my laptop computer which has
caused me some major problems in the
last couple of days and it's why I
haven't uploaded a video for about 3
days I did a little one on my phone but
I haven't been able to upload a good
video and even the one I uploaded today
was what I would consider less than the
versions I had made of it prior that
weren't working so corrupted files blah
blah blah blah blah anyway we fixed that
on our way home we decided to stop at a
few spots and show you some of the
beautiful places that you can blaze here
in Vancouver it's a very nice area yeah
so we're in actually West Vancouver and
we've got uh the lion Gate Bridge in
behind us we're just on a well-known dog
path here and uh this is part of the
house sound um it's not a lake by any
means if you pay attention to the corner
of the screen I believe you can see a
giant ship making its way there's a big
giant ship coming in which is kind of
cool I think we're going to Puff to that
yeah absolutely so we've stopped here
we've got the baby cakes on the road
Rock here we've got a bunch of nice dry
sift and the best part is you guys can't
even see it are just the streams of
people walking by looking at us like uh
what the hell are those guys doing is
that John a bumble man from puff
Wednesday I think we're going to show
them at the end here is exactly what's
going on here but um you know what here
comes the boat dude I think I think
we're going to start seeing her time all
right well let's see I've got a little
bit of the um aran's Haze that I cleaned
up yesterday I'm going to actually get
the bong
ready hey you might want to lower it a
little bit there's a bit of wind because
of the wind we're going to go down here
and it just looks better got the little
torch got the baby cakes and got lots of
cool dogs walking by us uh wish you guys
could
see after this we're going to head up to
the Lookout Point on Cypress Mountain
that overlooks Vancouver and give you
guys a little bit of a a view of
Vancouver on a beautiful day with the
house sound and the Georgia Straight uh
it should be really cool oh here you go
we're getting just this one side as you
can see is all nice and hot here
yeah excellent all right well here we
[Music]
go to got that hair out of there
quick nice and um I do believe you're
going to start seeing now this boat that
is a boat ready to go underneath the
bridge is going to be like like feet
from the from the like yeah it's
definitely in the camera right now as
it's going under yeah it's it's it's
pretty cool sounds screaming up there
it's a big ship all right you want me to
load want me to heat you up or load you
up I'm going to you he up heat myself up
give you a little load up what a friends
for there you go and there she goes as
she's going underneath the bridge I'm
going to do my rip here that was my plan
yes we've got our creme brulee torch and
we're hitting that baby cakes like it
owes us money here on puff Wednesdays
and it is Wednesday Today hit all
right nice Ripper
John and I can just use this Boulder as
my
rag that was nice well we're going to
take a couple more rips of the aran's
haze while we sit here but the next time
the camera switches we're going to be
overlooking this beautiful city that's
in behind the bridge so stay
tuned it died off there just at the end
was com
of
all right guys well it looks like we are
skipping the Cypress Lookout we'll get
you there another day but we just got
the call from the great Gardener he just
happens to be like 5 minutes outside of
my house and uh we'd hate to miss him
he's on his way up to Whistler so we're
going to go see him real quick and
hopefully we'll get a puff in with him
so we'll see you
there all right so might as well start
it off with some of that aran's
Haze
nice audience
ha sifted
did you when it comes off like that
clear doen
yep hard to see it's not in the Sun but
oh there it
is there it
is
yeah God it sure smells great in the air
I'll tell you that
much
booya
Shazam thank you cheers it's not the
Cypress Mountain Lookout but hey it's
pretty damn
good and what is it almost
yeah that's funny
like Wonder it's more than I need look
at that
head monster that's still more than I
need but we all need more than we need
yeah I guess that's what
uh what do you guys call it dry sift
Wednesday puff Wednesday puff Wednesday
puff Wednesday puff Wednesday puff
Wednesday I knew I knew it was something
like that that's what we do the cypess
hilm Excursion was all about yeah it's
all the whole day was really about do
John came over brought some some of
these domes and some promix and we
uh we're going to have a session here a
session there talk about whatever we're
talking about probably the next thing
we'll talk about is uh the
nextg green Rush Financial conferences
that uh are coming to Canada first one
in Vancouver
there we'll talk about that next
checking out the Nuggets John's got some
of his My Little Pony and some of the
uh yeah some of that Astro Boy Jarred up
too there you go it's a big Little Pony
what's little about
that all right guys welcome back to
Bubble man's world in puff Wednesdays
hey guys we made it back back working
hard and that was a long day we just uh
had the great Gardener here they just
split on their way up to Whistler and we
thought we would take a few
minutes to blaz some bowls and of course
talk about this conference that you are
involved with John the green Rush
Financial conference that's coming up
here um on May 7th yes this is put on by
NextGen next gen nextg medals next
generation is gold and uh it's a green
Rush Financial conference and and we're
going to bring insightful speakers in to
talk more about uh well hemp Industrial
Hemp medical marijuana doctors lawyers
perspectives uh stock Brokers uh we got
uh people coming from stockh house um
yourself is going to be speaking Yeah
I'm going to be there absolutely pretty
stoked about it you as well yeah me as
as well advisor medical marijuana
advisor yeah we got joy Davies so that's
really cool you know what we got John
Conway of course he's going to be
talking he's going to be really coming
down talking about the laws and
everything that's happening I see Kurt
Tua is on there as well Kurt Tua of
course he is um we got Adriana Herman
from in in the hemp industry Association
so I mean we're going to be talking more
about the benefits and uh basically
what's happening which is this what
they're calling the green currency and
what's happening with the legalization
here in Canada with licensed producers
and of course what else is happening in
Washington in Colorado so there's
there's a big new industry that's
basally coming upon us and uh hey I mean
it's it's becoming legal so we want to
talk more about it and we want to get
more education on it and it's it's great
that we're able to actually now start
educating on an international platform
absolutely that's really what this is
really kind of all about I'm just going
to I'll show it into the camera course
and so we'll uh we this is on May 7th in
Vancouver from 8 a uh 8:00 a.m. till
6:00 p.m. and then there's an Afterparty
and then this is the first of at least
uh several events correct yeah that's
correct we're also be in uh in June the
end ofun June will be in Toronto um and
then we're going to move on down to uh
we're going to try and get down to
Washington State we're talking about
going into Europe to Germany and and
actually really uh being uh well the
leaders in these conferences and really
discussing what's happening in the
industry right so um it's uh really it's
a unique time it's almost like um the
equivalent of starting the Cannabis Cup
but for like the the the medical the
industrial the recreational for for all
of it not just one specific specific
thing pulled out of the hole but to
cover the whole gamut that once the
legality is removed really it opens the
doors for for everything to be focused
on not just the medical aspect or the
industrial hemp aspect but literally
recreational is right in there as well
oh 100% And that comes even down to like
like 420s investors uh uh Alan
Bronstein's going to be there which is
apparently really people want to listen
to and stuff so there's a lot of lot
going on I'm looking forward to it for
sure it'll be uh neat to be a part of
here in Vancouver I'm uh only speaking
for about 10 or 15 minutes but uh I'll
make good use of my time and hopefully
uh share some good educational points on
glandular triome isolation and uh just
this the the production and synthesis of
THC and canabo inside the glandular
Tricom head that's what I'm really going
to try and sort of focus on that's
excellent I'll I'll be uh leading uh
right out of the gate next to Harry bar
of course uh the president and the
founder of NextGen medals um um at first
thing in the morning so I'll be on first
thing in the morning about 8:15 and
it'll be more of a patients perspective
and of course me being the new medical
adviser to nextg and What U basically uh
I'll be introducing more of the dday and
what's happening uh previewing some of
uh some of my uh actually uh news
articles and stuff like that have
happened in the past with me so it' be
really about U my patient perspective
and what I bring to the plate and what
I've been doing with NextGen and
actually bringing people like yourself
and all of us to this really group of
people that really want to talk more
about what's happening so yeah it's
going to be cool man it's going to be
cool definitely so uh if any of you guys
are out and about in the Vancouver area
definitely come check it out if you want
to send John or myself an email uh if
you're local and you're a business owner
we can offer you a free pass to get in
all we require is a simple uh uh you
know sign up when you when you come
through the door with your uh email and
company name and otherwise uh yeah we'll
look forward to I guess next puff
Wednesday we'll be at this financial
green Rush conference we'll be at the
financial green rush so we're going do
it at the Afterparty I think oh yeah no
I think the whole thing throughout the
whole day I'm going to film a little bit
of your speech and I'm going to I want
to see like parts of the whole day be on
Wednesday it's it's actually getting a
lot of media coverage so um there's a
lot of big media know they're talking
with CBC CTV all that so a lot of a lot
of big media but I mean definitely from
a puff one day's perspective I think
it's going to be awesome yeah well
that's where we're going to be next
Wednesday so we'll see you all there
thanks for watching
peace guys let's hit you off of the head
dude we deal with Enlightenment and
spiritual awakening you know as well as
ability
[Music]
manri
love
[Music]
[Applause]
people
brother
[Music]
days
no
[Music]
we
hey
[Music]
far
that