[Music]
going closing hey guys welcome everyone
to Bubble man's world and
welcome to Puff Wednesday Wednesday puff
Wednesday that gate just closed so yeah
the gate it well it just opened we're in
a secure area here Johnny B and myself
we are at the marina and we're going to
be heading down to the little tiny dock
we brought our little chairs and uh we
brought the Drone and we brought the
denail actually the courts with the
Mother Ship not the denail story so uh
we thought we'd bring you guys with us
on this beautiful puff Wednesday it's a
little bit rainy it's not that bad but
we're good with it so this is where we
are right now
very very little
dock here today not much dock at all
it's a private dock it's a very private
dog like our dog it's small we're going
to have to set up our chairs here
somewhere I'm just going oh wait let's
go on that side I think there's more
room without the sign so we can go I can
set the camera up right
here wo this one is the one when you
lean back on your
chair you go for a swim
yes so this is definitely this is this
is some
uh what's the best way to save for it oh
yeah you like that Johnny oh yeah all
right let me get this camera set
up wow not going to lie I felt a little
bit like I was going over the edge there
did you feel that well you you're com
I'm like I had to sit back here but I
was looking at that epicness behind us
guys did you see how
that just coming in it's just we just
got this break it's just so nice
beautiful beautiful figured we'd start
it out having a few dabs usually there's
a gas station on this dock luckily
that's been put away for the winter so
we can have a couple of little dabs
you'll notice that the dock is moving so
they'll be Motion in the camera like
we're on a boat Johnny B's filling her
up with water get her up nice and high
there I brought the quartz XL how about
that for a big
boy size that yeah
hey pretty excited about this actually
we got turps we've got I thought we had
rosin I'm noticing it's not in here now
some rosin right here well perfect let's
dab that rosin into these TPS and have a
couple of have a couple of rips here
while we're while we're on the dock and
talk about all things puff Wednesday
when's the last time we did a puff
Wednesday near the
ocean it's been a while w we on a boat
we we did it on a boat definitely
although no that might have been the
bubble has episode either way we haven't
done a ton of things near the ocean
today we were trying to desperately to
figure out if we should jump on the
float plane but it's quite overcast we
still wanted to share a day with you
guys and enjoy some comedy cuz it's
comedy every time we get together it's a
lot of fun it's comedy and you know what
what B to start this with uh a dab dab
it up I'll pull out a nice turp for us
to dip into the dab
o look at that Crown Royals feeling
pretty healthy white
cookies Gorilla
Glue you know you've been dabbing hard
when all of your turps have gone
yellow be lots of Dipping into those lot
of Dipping lot of Dipping lot of Dipping
all right so that's a little cush
cleaner on that rosin so we could well
you know what and this this Ros in here
guys this is the can ofum listen how
nice the flowing water probably a lot of
the sound right now is that background
that you guys are hearing John and I
probably aren't realizing how loud it is
hopefully it's not too bad we're going
to just hit a couple of a dab each real
quick and then we're going to walk you
guys over to a really sweet Beach that
is uh not too far from here we're going
to go sit on the beach have some more
dabs over there I like the beach it's
like one of those places that it's been
untouched because it is fall yeah yeah
no absolutely we just looked at it and
the sand was perfect there was no
footprints on it it was basically like
an untouched Beach from the weather
exactly it was like one of those those
spots when you look at Fresh yeah kind
of like p a fresh out off an XL quartz
Bucket look at the size of that thing oh
and here's the carb cap guys see what it
says it says bubble man check that out I
that that's that's I kind of want to get
up but I I'll then probably trip then
I'll end up in the water you guys will
laugh I'll be wet it'll be cold do it
for puff Wednesday John okay here we go
I'm you know what it's it's nothing but
fun hey we did that uh ICBC
conference dude I loved the ICBC
conference ICBC conference I'm not going
to lie I really enjoyed that conference
it's the international cannabis business
conference put on by Alex Rogers uh he
does it in San Francisco he does it in
Berlin he does it in Vancouver and he
really organized a pretty pretty cool
event it was not what I would call an
expo uh there weren't a lot of people
there the tickets were extremely
expensive mainly due to the fact that
you know it was a business conference
this conference is for people to go and
do business got me on the like 30 now
yeah I think I'm going to you know go by
my hand right now it's not super duper
hot the nice thing about the XL is that
it takes a while to heat up and it has
more surface area to expand that heat
into so you don't get these tiny tiny
little blops of of extreme heat but I
think we're going to be good I'm going
to dab this here in a second well we're
not running the tower we're going by
feel and we're pretty much good at that
I know I'm better with quartz I have to
admit I'm brutal with that ceramic I it
just uh it doesn't work it's just hot
hot hot hot hot and then it's cool and
then it's cool so all right let's hit
this there you go so the best part about
that ICBC conference really the
international cannabis business
conference and how it was held up with
all the talkers and speakers that came
which I know Mark has got tons of video
coverage of a lot of all these speakers
excellent excellent talks uh even even
on the acidic acid part the compounds of
the Cano in in the planet so it was
really really interesting to see how
everybody came together and and it was
it was education and and and really
business to business oh thank you thank
you brother so you know what it's
knowing what to do and when to do it see
that he's like here I need this I need
that I got to do this got a perfect
temperature on that there was no burn at
all it was all very low temp
dabbing we're still going to make sure
we clean this up real good so if you
want to keep the quartz Bowl nice you
want to keep keep it clean and and when
you don't have a Q-tip and you really
want to dab you know what you want to
Breck in your your bowl over time it's
true it's uh you know I've hung out with
people that take care of their quarts
and I've hung out with people that don't
the and I just I feel better about
taking care of it it looks so nice when
it looks this is a year and a half old
this XL really I've hit yeah a year and
a half yeah let me shake your hand I'm
keeping that thing looking
new OCD
I'm not always like that but with this
particular unit I have been and I've
traveled to Amsterdam to Spain uh to
Jamaica to Toronto to quite a few
different areas with this particular XL
shout out to uh DC glass uh in out in
Ontario for hooking it up this is one of
his so yeah very cool you a little
something yeah you're going to give me
the let me get you a TP dip first there
we go
dipping it's always nice you know what
it's just like here I hand the dab you
get that ready I do that give him the
Q-tips grab you know what it's a nice
flow it's a nice flow and let's be
honest it's one of the things that we
love about cannabis and cannabis use is
that it's very much a flow of sharing
and of keeping it moving through
throughout the group it's never really a
well everyone knows what it feels like
to Bogart something and people generally
are like they feel it right away it's
it's like um like the economy when
people start bog guarding money and then
people around them start feeling that
because the money is no longer flowing
obviously the good thing to do is it's
okay to make money make sure you keep it
flowing when you do because that way it
gets around to everyone that needs it
you know what it's like puffing and
passing I dipped you right yeah you got
dipped that was the best thing about it
though but when when you when you're
dealing with cannabis like I always say
whenever I do that dab or let up a joint
you look for someone to share it with
yeah but you do of course they help one
another out it's that community that
draws us so and that's what I love about
puff Wednesdays because believe it or
not not while you guys are watching this
we're thinking of you guys we don't know
all of you but we've met some of you
over the years at the events and whatnot
and I just think like there's people
puffing with us right now that camera is
a bunch of people I was just at the
Calgary Hempfest and hands down to
Calgary and people came up there puff
Wednesday and they do us from hash
church so the shout out to you guys out
there that were you know watch the good
viewers guys and Calgary too you guys
it's awesome and thank you thank you for
the respect and coming up and just
saying hey
it's nice to kind of be a part of what
you guys are a part of it's great to
have something as an ice breaker to be
able to meet someone yeah you know that
you want that you know I felt the same
way going and seeing Paul stamitz the
other day doing his speak on the
mushrooms I felt like I got to go over
and just shake his hand and tell him
you're a huge inspiration and do the
same thing that I get people doing to me
I see them doing it to you and other
people in our community it's it's just
more of that flow that's the passing on
of the energy that's the sharing of the
energy cuz if you would never came up
and said that to me I might want to do
this all the time yeah right it's it's
it's you guys to come up and say hey and
and thank us that's the reason why we
keep doing this is because of you and we
want to share these beautiful
environments with you I know we don't
have the wide angle lens so you're not
getting as much of the view but before
we go to the beach after Johnny hits
this dab I'm going to get on the camera
I'm going to pan it across the water so
you can get a real nice you know have a
couple of Puffs on your Dube or have a
dab while it kind of pans over and then
it's just going to change right into the
beach shot so I'm excited like that you
see that you see that little expansion
so Johnny B and I have been discussing
potential opportunities for puff
Wednesdays but if you have a puff
Wednesday in particularly that you want
to see done I have a couple of ideas
maybe us going around to a variety not
yet going around to a variety of
dispensaries and and testing some of the
higher quality stuff we could go up to
Whistler we could do the float plan
we could go to the Sunshine Coast
invisible we're doing a helicopter got
to do all these things dude we have to
take a helicopter they're fun all right
I suspect you're going to get a pretty
nice low temp dab the thing with dabbing
outside when it's much cooler as well is
that um I'm not sure where that little
unit went but you can dab with that if
you like I don't know if I put it in my
pocket I think I did I pulled a a faux P
but I hooked you up with the with the
Slinger jar this is actually a Slinger
Marvel as as well so I want to give a
shout out to Marble Slinger if for some
reason you've been living under a rock
and you don't know who Slinger is he is
responsible for the degenerate art uh
documentary but much more than that he
was uh you know he is a really good
friend and I was lucky enough to meet
him in the '90s while he was learning
how to to blow glass and was able to be
lucky enough for him to move up into my
neighborhood and live very close to me
while blowing glass and sell glass at my
gallery and throw the original
degenerate art glass show together with
with him that would become later on the
inspiration for his documentary shout
out to Slinger you can find him on shout
out and a half you can find him on
Facebook under Michael J Slinger you can
find him on uh Instagram as Slinger
Slinger 01 or Slinger you'll find him if
you just do the Slinger Google but yeah
of course it's nice to give a guy a
shout out this is from like
2003 and this is probably from like
200 and maybe right right away when when
I was looking for that I had already
known that I was using this for the
carpet when you were looking for it I'm
like no just give me the jar and even as
I looked down I thought it's in my
pocket isn't it it's in my pocket of
course it is it was in my pocket it's
kind of like that lighter that you
always did exactly all right well we are
going to head over to the beach we're
going to give you a little pan out we'll
see you when uh we'll see you when we
get over there
[Music]
a
here we
go all right what are you blue or green
I can't remember I'm going green green
Johnny blue for Bubble
Man we've got here to the
beach and I'm not going to lie oh yeah
it's fully private there's nobody here
private beach sweet private beach yeah
no this is sweet I don't know what you
guys thought of that Drone footage but
man I was so stoked how that turned out
wow right wow the shot of it leaving the
dock we're going to try and get another
shot for you here but it is raining
quite bad um we were thinking of doing a
sesh here cuz it's so so you know like a
perfect spot but I don't know should we
just get one dab in and maybe go head
over to the boat what we got a boat to
go to yeah we got this giant house boat
over here you guys can't really see it
but uh we could go check that out really
quickly and briefly or we can have a
session here what should we do we did
just get here how about we SES here with
these guys yeah then we sesh over there
because if it gets too wet if I have to
put on my hoodie I like the idea it's
not it's not super bad right now like
but I'm definitely starting to see the
water gather on my
pants I love the cleanliness of this
beach though the way everything's just
perfect perfect you got your water
bottle right here beautiful
booya where did that where' that saying
come from booya booah booah someone's
going to write it in the comments
section yeah I know that's what I had to
Res It wiki I think it came from like
um Point
gray I don't know I remember booya from
point there you go water flip water flip
see that see the catch see the catch
we've been putting a lot of practice
into our water flipping lately I'm not
going to lie John and I have been been
spending hours trying to get it down
we've got a whole video on water
flipping coming out joking see that did
you see that Johnny's a natural I've
been practicing there's really no
denying his
talent hey stop raining kind of It kind
of felt like it picked up even harder at
the same time you know
what I just love beautiful BC yeah you
do you know what yeah I do I think he
does too how about you guys I moved here
dude I I I I did too I'm actually from
no but I mean like on my own as an as a
as an adult deciding I'm not going to
live where I live anymore he was not
going to live there so my parents didn't
come my parents didn't come I wish they
would have but uh yeah I did make a
decision and that decision was to move
away from the Prairies and move to the
West Coast cuz it's just so freaking
beautiful did you dip that in some turps
not yet I'm going to get the torch first
what I need to do is hold on to this for
him I'll need it back right away I need
to then hand it back to
him this is this is what we call joint
effort yeah without the joint I have one
but you don't want one he doesn't smoke
that stuff I don't he doesn't I'm not
going to lie Johnny I will then take
that all right well I will then light
you up here on the XL torch
Banger and and
and the Blaster yep tiny little a little
bit of a stain on the side here just a
very light one that the torch will uh
will remove for us that was my fault I
will have to admit I was trying to clean
but my eyes have gotten so bad I can't
see anymore oh no yeah I know it's like
things get blurry here damn well look at
this I don't know if you can see but the
thing that was left over is now
completely gone so please don't feel in
any way shape or form if you get rid of
most of it you'll be able to clean it
off no problem but if you
leave large amounts of it and you heat
it up too hot then you just end up
oxidizing your quartz nail and it's not
quite as and it goes white it's not
quite as wonderful as it was when it was
new like this kind of like the one that
I have yeah I don't know about that one
I well know I'm just telling you it is
cuz we actually hit it on the laugh puff
Wednesday right right right and I was
saying how I was the guy who let someone
use it and wasn't paying attention and
that's what happens well I hope you guys
can hear us because we are definitely
not close to the camera right now it is
my new camera and I'm suspecting that
it's uh it's kicking butt and us I'm
thinking it's up to par they're probably
think why are they screaming why are
those guys always screaming to it right
oh this is going to be nice I'm keeping
my hand over it so it doesn't oh this
can be you is this me sure wow I think
the last one was a little too light
though because it did cool a little too
much yeah well I was giving you the low
temp but if you want to go for the thing
with the low temp is it's easier to
clean if you burn it then you basically
that's where the oxidization happens
that's my problem that's the problem I
burn it yep you do hit H I'm a hot heavy
guy Johnny Beal hit the Dil cleaning
itself and not even be bummed out that
he hit 40 it's okay like that was pretty
good they giv you a hard hit that's
awesome now hold it right up against the
wall so it could get just like that now
it's dripped off
perfect I'll take that from you
sir hting a fine rip there Johnny that's
a fine rip
and then I'll come in right behind you
and uh clean it
up okay so I have to admit that last one
I got wasn't that good but that
one thumbs up that one was a tasty
Ripper everybody's got the thing but for
me it's I like the thumbs up it's like
yeah hey thumbs up is fine I like the
thumbs very very what was the flavor of
that one in particular uh that one was
mojito MO moito love mojito love mojito
is actually how I experience a lot of
things with my pain and we talk about
this like with with the one there that
purple punch yep that
mojito the flavor with that catomic was
it what Roos was that uh that was uh
Girl Scout cookies rosin okay so right
there it's the Girl Scout cookies I was
like what's there's something there
that's giving me a little bit more and
that was amazing yeah just have to say
beautiful well done well I'm going to
follow you your footsteps and I'm going
to give myself a little girl scout
cookies as I'm trying to get it off the
parchment and it's shattering and
hitting me in the eye and hitting the
eye so it could be a little dangerous
once your your Ros thing gets a little
shy might have to wear glasses safety
glasses yeah for real for real we're
talking about some safety here oh I
think I got hit by some raos and I
actually have
some oh yeah here we go here's the
here's the bit I was looking
for so as he talking down I'm talking
that was the bit he was looking for he
got to exactly what he
needed Booyah I started the booy today
see see what
happens and then we're dipping there
some fine Sour Diesel from
Jamaica oh you hit Sour Diesel what was
mine I told you what I hit you hit I
already forgot I hit mojito and the
Mojito yeah was definitely it's the
tures that really make it make it the
difference probably can't hear a word
I'm saying cuz of the torch and the
ocean behind me like look at this
area oh it's awesome I think oh don't
Johnny short chair don't
fall leaning
back well
done we got a little bit of Mother
Nature with the seag golf LLY in behind
us we got some duck here over here on
the left probably still
and that dab actually did me in pretty
yeah I don't even know what to talk to
these guys about right now you got to
keep it fresh think what's coming up
next Karma cup I was going to say a bong
room Karma cup is in 4 days and I'm
actually very for looking forward to
this event Sarah's put a ton of energy
into it it seems like she's got some
good people behind her I'm going to do
my part and go hang out and get my
little booth and do the tarpine thing I
know you're going to be there as well I
will be there I do not have a booth this
time just because of the way life is and
well you can hang out at my booth no
problem I'm definitely going to be
hanging out with this guy I don't know
what booth number I am I think it's 187
but you can look on I I speak a couple
of times as well I'm on a panel speaking
about craft cannabis which is kind of
cool I don't always speak about cannabis
I usually speak about extractions but
I've definitely no stranger to craft
cannabis and high-end small grow you
know smaller talk about the smaller grow
and then I do my own as well where it's
just me speaking and I I don't know
exactly what I'm going to talk about but
I think I'm going to try and talk about
a little bit of water hash a little bit
of dry sift the difference between oil
and hash you know different ways of
hitting it the turpine extraction the
modulating just sort of everything that
we've really been doing on hash church
and that I've been sort of building with
Tony and all these different people I
think that's what the talk will be about
I don't know I think I think he just
talked about it yeah see look forward to
that talk at the Karm I never planed
that's what he's talking about see he
already said it look forward to it I
want to go hit a bowl in that boat well
you know what he's got this beautiful
boat it's sitting up here it's a giant
house boat it has a slide on it I don't
think you can hear it it's got a couch
on the front oh they can hear me dab
trust me this is still hot wow so
actually when hitting the quartz and and
do he's actually hitting the back of the
quartz with it so then it drips into the
large so this that's a really good way
of what he was talking about when I
first did my hit
is being able to actually hold it to the
back so it drips into the ball and then
goes across that surface what a great
way of getting a really really good hit
I really like that just watching it drip
and go up like that it's actually pretty
cool it's it's kind of you know what it
it was a good way of explaining that cuz
how you showed me he said put to the
back so I was kind of explaining what he
said to me to you
guys I don't know what the [ __ ] this
guy's babbling on about but I am loving
this puff
Wednesday here you go here's a clean one
oh thank you brother there you go that's
what I'm here for I appreciate it I was
just hitting this bowl and getting lost
and I was telling them and I was telling
them explaining how you putting the tool
against the back of the B so it into the
B and then runs across that big surface
and vaporizes that's why that's such an
epic hit with that cuz I haven't had a
chance to well maybe I didn't I can't
remember you want to hold on to that I
like holding things that taste was
delicious that was the sour diesel from
Jamaica waves are coming in beautiful
rain rain is starting to to to simmer
down a little bit but I still want to
take you guys over to the boat it's this
big beautiful house boat why don't we go
sit on that for a little bit and uh
we'll get a little bit of a higher View
and uh we'll get we'll get off the beach
here for a bit how good I'm I'm good all
right okay here we go all right so
here's my buddy's house
boat we're just going to go check it on
out he gave us
permission yeah he's got the couch right
here the cushions are off of it though
Johnny bee so it's not quite as
comfortable as one might think there's
the view off the
front all right Johnny B we have made it
onto the vessel I know what do you think
well you know what I mean it started
from a
dog we went around to a beach now I'm on
a boat now you're on a boat so that's
like the ocean thing this is like the
ocean the ocean puff on could I offer
you a bong rip tur dip [ __ ] yeah hell
yeah let me light you up my friend so
this is quite nice about this I mean the
you know what it's it's such a beautiful
time of year to be able to take it to to
the ocean when it's calm but yet the
storm's about ready to break don't
forget we just had this major hurricane
that almost hit the Pacific Northwest
that shut down all the all the boats
here and stuff like that the other day
so it's calm here right now
and now we're sitting on a boat the
night we were like floating you've seen
us floating on a boat before pulling
bags we going have to do that again one
day pull bags on Rivers we pulled bags
on oceans we haven't pulled bags on
lakes I pulled bags on legs man not not
on a puff Wednesday well not with you
you're right it's true so this this this
could be we got to how I would like to
we should do it in an ice cave you
talked about that one day we're going to
make ice cave and I never thought I'd
ever be able to make it to an ice cave
all right so you got a good 40 seconds
on that before I hit it in as long as I
can the exhale would be so delicate you
probably wouldn't even know an xil
because that would all be absorbed into
me and and the most important part was
that that carb cap that that we found
that I just put down there for you oh oh
you're still a little bit of ways um I'd
give it another 15 to 20 seconds I
probably won't I'll probably give it to
that says 40 it's cuz now actually x 50
okay here we go
try getting that all
in definitely need a Q-tip though I'll
get you one right now all
right all right so I'm jumping in here
into the captain's seats for a beautiful
puff Wednesday vessel puff pretty
excited about it actually I just looked
out the window and there's a big seagull
it's actually raining pretty good out
there I can see that now yeah so that's
sweet that we're in here right now good
timing thank you to my buddy Eric for
letting us sit in his boat that was very
kind of you we're being absolutely
respectful and uh we do appreciate uh
you allowing us to have this little
position here to set up with and uh
share it with our viewers see see I love
that because when I was at the Calgary
Hempfest I went nowh and talked the guy
was running at Sasha and I let him
realize that when he watched the past
church that he will see that I was
puffing indoors and getting people I was
puffing people down in there so I I had
warned him that this already had
happened and to let him know that it was
good for his event cool he smiled I
don't think he was uh already happy
about it but hey we canel make everyone
happy all the time the best part about
it was the people that came up and
showed up
wow I just love getting the nail as
clean as possible
before taking my dab well it's a way to
get a cleanest dab right yeah you know
when you want to make maintain that that
keep that oxidization away if you can
look how clear that that that actually
hole is wow good job on the year it's
been well taken care of all right got
the bubble man we haven't shown this to
you guys yet so we might as well there
it is let's see if we can see that there
it
is there there it is how sweet is that
screenshot screenshot well it was me in
the background all blurry and then it
just said Bubble Man really cool in the
middle so I guess I'll just go by my
hand with the quartz I have a lot more
confidence in it keep looking away sorry
guys it's just really pulling my eye out
this window right now such a
beautiful kind of rainy semi- rainy day
we've gotten a little bit of rain we've
gotten a little bit of just not rain and
cloudy with the little breaks of sun
is there a rainbow out there indeed you
know what what we'll have to do for puff
Wednesdays one time is go to Tofino for
the day hey like fly over early at like
6:00 in the morning and film the whole
thing and film the whole day and eat a
great meal and then fly
back that would be fun Tofino is
beautiful been we could take you to five
different beaches there's all sorts of
things talking about the puff Wednesdays
that we're going to come to in the
future like we just made a puff
Wednesday going there's many a puff
Wednesday ideas you know it's uh we have
we should do it during the storm season
so you get to see it like that's what
we're in right now I know this is the
storm season that's why I mentioned to
female we'll absolutely do that all
right here here we go
guys w we were talking quite a bit it's
definitely a low temp
D but definitely a tasty and amazing if
you were like hitting a volcano that
would be probably on a like a around
like a level five or a level
six so definitely really turpy could
be really tppy tury
head it's just wonderful I know
TPS and then watch how when you're
dabbing and how it's pulling up and then
dropping down it's pretty cool all right
well like John said we've done some dock
dabs Beach dabs boat
dabs we got a little bit of Drone
footage for you
guys yeah I think you guys are going to
enjoy this puff
Wednesday enjoy it I'm like
this the sun's breaking through out here
right now it's just come we should take
them all back now with the sun coming
through I'm in full agreeance with that
you think yeah I'm like let's go check
out let's go check out the back of the
boat
yeah I'm filming it all right
now they're right where
are you going to the
back I was going da I was like Wow but
you know what it is
raining bre there's a slide oh my God
there's a
slide all right Johnny V show them what
we do on puff
Wednesdays I want to see do know this I
want to see you slide right onto those
rocks woohoo oh my gosh you know what I
would definitely have to go get some
more surgery after that stupid attempt
this thing is definitely not positioned
safely for slide use no no this is not a
it's a wood slide too hey that's pretty
cool like he built his own SL at that I
didn't I wasn't expecting that I was
just like I was like a kid in the candy
store I was like check that [ __ ] out I
was like no no this is good I think we
should grab the chairs yeah I think we
should set up right here should take a
look up there we've also got another
higher version of a deck right here so
we could also go kind of chill out up
here with our
seats very cool very we go see the Suns
breaking through look at that just like
oh I need sunglasses
now good
day sir dab oh yes sir yes sir pass
you 100% here's your torch you know what
that right there actually I'm going to
put all this stuff here I have this nice
little natural table that is the slide
so we've made it to the top floor of the
house Bo Boat Ocean behind us Boer
Island pretty awesome pretty epic I mean
you said it it was cool in there but
this is way better this is all of a
sudden the sun came out it stopped
raining it's like how clear the water is
just it's like he will definitely see
that 20 ft down you can see into it
anyway we're going to finish it off with
some some beautiful dabs here uh on the
top of the house boat I guess I should
pull out some rosin I got a little bit
of this canonic CL
yeah is that what you want to hit sure I
mean it's what I have if if he have you
down whatever you got we got to hit each
here SP her up beautiful someone
actually did give this to me Kenan Rosen
D all right well we're both going to dip
into Cherry AK-47 Cherry AK-47 for the
win I mean what are you dipping at the
end of year P Wednesday yeah what do you
like to dip in when it's your last puff
of the puff Wednesday you know John and
bubble man can always kind of trip you
out and pull another session out of
their hat even when you thought it was
the end but let's say this is the end
what are you puffing on which one are
you going to go for is it rosin is it
bubble is it some other form of oil is
it a joint is it a bowl are you Turf
dipping are you bong ripping are you
[ __ ] Yan are you double dipping triple
dipping [ __ ] Yan bong RI I like that you
go sir oh thank you
yeah definitely very enjoyable puff
Wednesday coming nice and close to home
just head on down to the ocean and uh
share The Vibes with all of you good
folks from Bubble man's world now I'm
just looking at this beautiful view off
here you can just see how you have all
the different houses right on the river
right on the river I I live close to the
river right on the this looks like a
river shop there is like a a a well I
guess it's kind of like a river actually
it is thank you it heads down from the
from the top of the of the mountain it's
a creek more than anything okay but it's
up there some of these houses are on the
creek on the creek
yep good
old it's nice nice to be up here dabbing
on a puff Wednesday with Johnny B and
with you guys and with you guys and the
rain letting it happen you know good
good thanks I love this
behind is that Boer or or that one's
Anvil that's Anvil Bowen's over there
right behind you over on that side the
little one right behind us is Boer and
and right across the way is Gambier gamb
and then between gambir and Bowen you
have the Sunshine Coast which most
people mistake for also Islands cuz they
can't tell that those islands are
attached to the mainland so the problem
is with the Sunshine Coast is you can't
drive to it yet not yet not yet they're
talking about it I saw an article in the
paper the other day where they're
opening discussion in all of our
neighborhoods to see if we want them to
build a road from here to the Sunshine
Coast I have the put in a tunnel I don't
know Floating Bridge H or depending on
an area where they can get it down I
don't know yeah Floating Bridge I they
could with the Squamish winds that
happen here I don't think that would
happen well it's definitely something
they're thinking about and I think they
know they can do it I think it's just a
matter of will the Community want it and
will they let it happen and that's why
they're opening it up to discussion in
the community I don't think the
community is going to be too happy out
traffic and then I think some will be
happy and some won't because anyone that
lives on the Sunshine Coast a lot of
people move over there because it's much
more affordable to live in a beautiful
area because of the that fairy distance
and how you can't go in the middle of
the night and how you're stuck on the
island without a boat and you know
there's that aspect it makes the
property much more attainable to
purchase and now to be able to have a
road that goes there it could extend
this area into that area and raise and
prices would go up so so some people
will investment right now would be to
buy on the Sunshine Coast yeah and some
people are going to be happy about that
you're right some of the community
members that didn't buy their house to
uh for profit they're absolutely going
to be like yeah this is kind of a bummer
well you know what what access access to
more beautiful property more beautiful
land for
everyone and that's good we like that
it's really nice to able to share that's
why we share you this with you
guys puff Wednesday in I enjoy a good uh
puff a good puff yeah it's nice to watch
those waves come
in it's nice to feel this really light
rain it's interesting because you know a
lot of people they think it's raining
out they assume the worst they don't
want to go out in it they don't want to
be caught up in it today John and I we
just trucked right into it with with
equipment and drones and pushed through
and uh I'm feeling pretty good about it
foot look at this bubble over top of us
though yeah it's just blue right here
just like right here like look look all
around us as I'm looking you guys are
watching me look around but like really
it's it's kind of pretty cool it's
wonderful Dude puff Wednesday it's
raining all around us except right here
we manifested it dude you make it happen
guys and that's what you have to do in
life you have to make it happen you just
got to do it and that's that's the best
part about we show you here today yeah I
saw someone I saw someone basically
write that recently uh it said the only
thing keeping you between from all of
the things that you desire and your
manifestations is doing it yeah that's
it go do it Bruce leave that
side just do it knowing is not enough of
usly is not enough you must do get her
done get her
done which is another DB for me well I'm
trying to get you a nice clean Bowl here
that's really nice and I'd rather get it
off this way did you give me
that I did yes I believe I did if not it
could be in there I oh I put it right
here you guys would have told me be like
John to be right
there that's
awesome cuz you already know that my you
have maybe have my phone now Like a
Surgeon I'm going to clean this this
bowl it's not here
Like a
[Applause]
Surgeon it's could be the last puff of
this particular puff Wednesday I want to
thank you guys all for uh as always
showing up and hanging out with us we're
going to try and up the ante in the near
future get out to Tofino maybe get out
on the float plane be a couple of puff
Wednesdays filmed in uh maybe maybe film
two or three puff Wednesdays make it the
Tofino
month because if we go there
you're definitely getting a two or three
part series out of it that's what I'm
saying yeah that's what we're saying
otherwise it's going to be like a 4our
puff Wednesday and I don't think anyone
wants that I think well D be like you
know how many people want just said hell
yeah and then other people like really
yeah they're like you're right we
definitely don't want that definely
don't want that we definitely don't want
that oh here take this oh are we timing
this um I can time it for you if you
like or I can just use my hand I got it
here the timer's on probably about 45
seconds and you also got no dip yet so
if you don't mind dip you guys even they
were screaming yeah you're going to miss
Johnny's dip got to get
diping yeah exactly there you go JB
thank
you lately everybody's been calling me
JV you know I kind of like it all right
and my mom I'll thank my mom for that
she comments on everything that's my JB
JB JB and all my comments so even you're
picking up on it so I think that's
pretty awesome all right so you're about
10 seconds out I go a little tiny hot
here and we got you the de the
uh help you out
there all right
I will get q-tipping on that bad boy oh
yeah
see that's what's so nice here
under can you hear it can I hear what
your mind expanding
yeah I can't I'm trying to get your
burnt head off the bowl is it burnt no
no not too bad but definitely like a
little bit like harder than usual to get
off oh hey even that hot I'll torch it
oh just D yeah we'll get it
off I scraped most of it off there's
just a little nice little Edge of
Darkness that the Q-tip was unable to so
that would would have been a hotter hit
is what you're saying a little bit
hotter yeah so that's what you leave
that block in so we just learned
something right there oh no no I've
known that for a long time no no but but
but we're showing jeez it's almost like
I I shouldn't waste this
uh nice hot bowl that I made
we're going to stop this we're going to
reset
this I like it and he's doing one more
dab as well well it's you it's kind of
like getting it all ready for nothing
exactly you can't be getting it all
ready for nothing no you just can't do
that he's watching us from over here
over there everybody's like you know
like there's nobody
here okay
here we go daber da M see M see guess
I'll just do a repeat of that same old
thing repeat let it cool down even
longer than last time CU I want to get
less of
a I want to get a real puddle hit I'm
quite accurate with my hand I have to
say a puddle hit yeah I like when it
puddles I like when it's uh when when it
just kind of drips in there temp low
temp puddling rip something to be said
for it and for me I'm I'm still the guy
that likes a a really nice good hit
there's something to be said for that
too I think it works well for what I'm
dealing with and at the same time these
nice low temp tips well there's no doubt
about this you get way more rocked off
of one of those hard hot hits compared
to a super nice low temp dab maybe
people out there are are disagreeing but
I'm telling you it's a fact no it's a
total for sure but that's the way that
goes and and what I'm looking and and
explaining is is some people are dabbing
hotter because it helps him relevate
this so the temperatures also contribute
to what works for you mhm so well see
that's a minute and I'm still not
hitting this thing dude see he's on a
minute and 15 seconds it's an XL Banger
it's a big thing yeah I remember people
a few guys saying that a minute 30
minute 25 and I think he's pretty much
on par with the hand I'm feeling that
right now he's feeling it yep it's 125
right now and I'm he's hitting the 125
and of course getting right in there
with a carb cap would you do that to
help a
friend of course you
would that was
perfect that's a thumbs
up
well it's been a great puff Wednesday
Johnny B I got to thank you once again
for putting up with me and uh coming out
and filming and putting up with me
always a pleasure to have you guys in
here like we probably said 20 times
during this video hey we like you
couldn't do it without you we're going
to see you next Wednesday um I guess
we're going to be at the karma Cup this
weekend for hash church so we'll see you
in Toronto I'm going to be back in
Vancouver John's going to be in Toronto
on Wednesday so we're going to try and
film a really unique puff Wednesday with
him there and me here and uh I hope you
guys can look forward to that so uh what
do we say peace out peace talk to you
guys soon no
[Music]
oh