[Music]
all right John we've come to the funnest
part of our videos we puff we're going
to Puff we basically we've done all the
work you know we've uh oh let's turn
that into dry sift for our next video
okay what is this medy Kush medy Haze no
this is um number four hcky oh or it
could even be the head definely have to
do that this is the headband I
think we're going that would be another
video all right so we're going to Puff
what's this that is about 80 g of o is
that what that is right now mhm nice
that's
you knew what I like so much he said you
wanted to hit some cushies I need some
cush so you know you've been hitting
your dessert all day long for like the
last I don't know how
long it's just time to hit a little
uh some Med haze there for you too all
right so do you require a scooper um
actually look at this dirty scooper
let's see if we can take a little dirty
scooper of the fresh frozen totally not
dried stuck on the on the unit here it's
going to taste Amato
n in the morning in the
evening have the CB that
[Music]
actually huh
little bit light but not too
shabby for something that was you know
fresh SE hit me with the backup you can
press that
too
Lely chunks here let
me let me get you an oil
slick would be
just so
what a great time we had up in Whistler
I mean honestly that was it was kind of
like I wasn't sure it was going to work
out for
us we went it always does but I mean I
wasn't sure we were just well you know
we found that spot right at the last
minute I just remembering that I uh B
this from you so oh thank you sir top of
that back there good
thanks trippy sticks they're just so
handy
after the
abely right up a
little
ninja I just ninja John
with a nice flat piece of
cush
yes got the old school
1994 fall tour fish shirt on today for
the fish heads out
there why don't you throw on your
favorite version of hood for this for
these next couple of Bowl
RS a great song for those that know
it for those that don't it's a simple
YouTube search
away Hood p i
h that ninja me look at me you got ninja
I got ninja it's ninjaing off into the
well I got to admit um with the denail
I'm more accepting of this sort of thing
happening hits kind of going off the
edge although you can car cap it it'll
just sort of save it
you know a quick little fing carb cap
like that I've got a carb cap on the way
would such a small
amount you're going to get the
[Music]
hit yeah so we're just uh once again
happy to
be
exempt federally happy that we still
have our licenses for March 31st
hopefully further
um but you know right now the the
licensing as it sits it allows John and
I to get together it allows us to do the
things you see us doing and uh share
them with you without the worry of any
sort of negative consequence which
really when you're sharing things like
what John and I are sharing I don't
think there ever should be a negative
consequence I think all we're really
talking about here is actually how to
extract the medicine out of the plant
properly because that's how I'm properly
able to medicate and uh something that
worries me what we just talking about
which is with the program ending with
health Canada's medical marijuana access
regulation program where I personally
and Mark personally can grow her own
medicines in her house while now I will
not be able to access uh making fresh
frozen or making the bubble hash that
I've been using now for quite some time
for my paint control so it's actually um
basically doing all the things we do
yeah everything I'm doing right now
we won't it won't be feasible no I'll
have to actually buy it from a
commercial production facility to bring
home and then with whatever they give me
then I can try and make something which
is but will that be legal I know the
buying it will be legal but once we buy
it and take it home are we allowed to
extract resin from it I think we're
pretty much allowed to do whatever we
want with it within the new regulations
well I know here in BC we're kind of
safe but the rest of Canada is not so
and I think
even yeah I think it's all changing
either way uh it's important that
everyone pay attention that's involved
in this to the Coalition you know you
can check them out at their website uh
mm Coalition against repeal mm Coalition
against repeal is that
dotca doca okay that's the Canadian
version so yeah check that out online
you can also find us on Facebook um
pretty much Google mm Coalition against
um and you will find all the links of
where you can actually help fight for
our cause um donation and uh everything
you can do is drawing awareness towards
um what is happening here in Canada with
our federal system that has been legal
since 2001 for people who are suffering
from disabilities and other ailments
related to their health issues and uh
now we are going to be forced to buy
from basically a commercial producer
yeah our bigger corporate corporate
corporate take over on the medical
marijana they're going to control the
production and they're going to control
the distribution and I think personally
that it's a component that is necessary
for a certain group of our uh population
100% but I think that um you know vapor
bars and uh dispensaries and growing
your own is abolutely a must they can
have they can still grow they can
actually buy legal perect completely
legal so that makes no sense then we got
uguay body can actually grow their own
we're going to have to go do some
filming in in uguay Washington right
over there 10 minutes from my house you
can grow your on legally Legally Legally
we can grow cannabis legally here they
can grow cannabis legally there but I
tell you don't talk about it at the
border between those two places no no
there's um wow wow we've heard some
pretty horror stories about that you
know what I really love right now that I
can look over and see into the gorilla
tent I can see the 4X 2T screen
balancing nicely on the bubble bucket
and the tumble now with the hash
securely on the cardboard and covered by
the
screens it's a beautiful thing I think
it's uh I can't wait to come back after
you come back from your glorious trip to
Prince George to go and uh do some of
your fine work yeah I guess that's uh
coming up on Monday that'll be the next
Bubble Man adventure I'm going to go see
d420 K the dry sift Master up in Prince
George he's apparently got some
state-of-the-art facilities that he
wants to show me we're going to do some
dry sifting some bubble hash making and
most importantly fresh
frozen Back Country sledding oh wow yeah
I'm happy I was going for the high five
but then I saw the pipe and everything
like yeah low five
low yeah yeah you know it's going to be
great just to see Darren he's a good
friend we've uh we've always had uh Good
Times cruising around on our bikes one
of my uh ride
buddies definitely uh loves riding on
his Harley I was actually cruising
behind them in my truck during the
summer cuz I'm not much of a
rider oh was I used to mind you I used
to do a lot of riding I um grew up um
riding motorcycles
[Music]
just sitting here thinking about
um just how great it is to be able to uh
enjoy natural M we're very blessed John
yeah it is it's quite nice and and the
way things are happening worldwide and
the way people are waking up I just look
over here at the Facebook page and
CNN and everything there's just so much
information that's exploding on the
endocan avonoid system there's no hiding
it the body's on T and how it Reg the
central nervous system it's quite
amazing what's happening world I think
it's why we're going to see Canada open
up I think we're going to see more than
even what we're hoping for which is the
grandfathering of The Growers who have
already had their licenses I don't think
that's fair to the rest of the Canadian
citizens I think everyone always has to
have the right to be able to
grow regardless of what year they might
have gotten their license and more
importantly regardless of their a
because we should not be classifying
ails as
certain ones be it's it's about quality
of life so whatever your a is you want
to improve your quality of life and no
one's quality of life is worth more than
anyone else's 100% And like would always
say cannabis theoc cannaboids body own t
regulates the central nervous system so
matter just for better sleep for getting
up in the morning [ __ ] better imagine
just Just For Better B movements a
little bit of TC daily just gives you
General wellbeing all around it it is
something that everybody should be using
just you're not getting high from it's
it's what they want pharmaceutical pills
to be but they aren't you know
pharmaceutical pills are pure and
straightforward poison that just kill
people well PHA is needed in in acute
stages of pain Absolut certain
conditions absolutely but the addiction
of it and the months of it it's like
yeah short periods of time I mean I when
I broke my collar bone they gave me pain
meds I chose not to take them I felt all
the pain it was terribly painful for
about 5 weeks and I just chose not to
take the medicine uh the t3s and
whatever other things they were trying
to offer me just because I felt like the
damage that those would do to my liver
and to my body and the potential
addictive qualities just weren't worth
it to me now I albe it it was only one
bone I wasn't in traction in a hospital
bed in acute stages you know like there
wasio system and we do know it it works
just like um
you get all kinds of different receptors
and stuff like that but definitely it is
something that works very well for me in
my P and everybody else's with anything
we're just talking about this okay good
Lord sweet Jesus you know what you need
to do you need to take a hit of the cush
and I will ninja dab you the 90u flavor
saor why don't you have breakfast and
dinner
all at once John here we go one sec one
sec okay no
sex wow look at that a clear dome right
on the end of The
Da
he yeah but you didn't to me again
oh my goodness this is so damn tasty
that that is definitely that's a
winner the
combination is very nice anyway I hope
you guys all enjoyed the Whistler video
it has inspired another Whistler video I
was talking to dope Industries on
Instagram nice um we actually saw him at
the Southside Diner he when we were
ordering our breakfast and he was a
bearded guy that was sitting in the
corner Devon waved to him so I just
texted him today and was kind of like
was that you I said hey what about a
collab you know with the dope industry
boys and bubble men you know do a video
of us making hash up there on the
mountain but then these guys are in the
background doing they're they're really
good they do the rails and they hit
features and they they do back country
and sledding and so they're all pretty
killer Riders and I'm stoked to come
chill out with you guys and blaz some
bowls and make some hash and I hope John
makes it up as well well I'm going to do
my best but um that country riding for
me is a slow trip with the Aro yeah yeah
exactly well we might be able to get
into an easy Zone where we just uh you
know get you somewhere that's that's
nice and close we see what we can do
awesome so I guess uh we should just
continue on puff our way out of
here another great show always a
pleasure brother uh our next show
actually is going to be this 114 or 15 G
of Packy cross with I think so could
be I'm trying to remember it's beautiful
it's colorful I'm going to photograph it
we're going to grind it and we're going
to uh dry sift it for head stash for JN
so stay tuned for that as
well next time yeah till next time why
don't we uh puff our way out of here
first should hit the the
90 yeah little sure I've hit all three
of
these just a little bit in the tent we
might finish this one off sure which one
we got that's I won't take it all
[Music]
all right My Little
Pony you know what's
funny this is actually the first
one purple I like that you put it in
purple oh this is Ence
[Music]
oh my gosh these are those rid you
brought these to Toronto right yeah okay
I was going to say so John brought these
nugs the chorono and for whatever reason
they dened up in a way that
it's like some of the Dead you could
drive over it with a car for sure but
but everything did all of my we did
everything was rock hard but wasn't this
the one you showed all of us and we were
all tripping out about it yeah yeah so
that was the hard was it not the hardest
one am I mistaken it was cuz I thought
you it
is anyway wild to do that BC cure right
you got the humidity and it's like
fluffy and marshmallowy and then you
take it on the plane it's just like
and then you get into a nice dry yeah
the humidity is just gone it's gone
there everybody's like wow it was just
like you're just like yeah that's how I
grow it it's one more reason how this
thing that is the internet is classic
for which is the Assumption of others
you know I see it all the time where
I'll post a photo of a friend of mine's
pipe and a thousand people will assume
you know I'm a huge baller cuz that's my
pipe and it's not my pipe at all
I see it with a texture of hash people
post the texture of hash and then others
assume that that person is responsible
for the
texture of the hash whereas I think
really what's responsible is how well it
was grown and then yeah sure you isolate
it the texture is the texture it's not
Oil we're not doing Special processes to
it to change the texture it is what it
is people ask me all the time how how
how can I make it waxy how do I make it
sh
it's like you grow dank resin that's how
and people ask me how you get this
killer I was like well I grow
organically I'm happy that you do I use
one smoke this every day works Awesome
every day and I flush for like 40 days
it's that's great it's great and the
plants just give me always full melt
beautiful flavors consistently over and
over and over you sure do I remember
when I met you and we made the killer
dry sift I was kind of confused as to
why your bubble wasn't
[Music]
killer because I
wasn't but you had proper
res that was the
crazy you had proper resin oh um that's
right too because I
wasn't and then that's where I realized
once I
clean I didn't run just a 160 bag and a
50 bag I actually run the8 bag system
and really understand how to use the
bubble bags and the screens and
[Music]
everything start aning like people like
oh man yeah as yeah but you don't stack
that is that is proper 90 Micron and
people like to take out I use a 220 bag
and a 160 B and then go right down to
the 50 bag or the 45 and then come up
with these big rock check this so it's
all
compress and you look at go what are you
doing important factor people that they
don't understand they want the 73 and
the 90 we all do but you have to
understand the other bags are key to get
those bags to be the way they are it's
the difference between the oil community
and the hash Community we smoke a
particular size gland head we don't
smoke 25 generally
a lot of us don't smoke 160 some of us
don't even smoke 120 which I find insane
cuz I love it myself 12 120 90 and 73 or
my three I will smell 45 I've SM killer
45 and you know Crush 45 nothing sure
yeah and outdoor sungrown sativas in
Equatorial you know tropical places
produce amazing 25 M now so they all
have their place uh it's just important
you use them all in order to get the
ones that you
like I know you have pictures of this
but just when you open up this
J thousands and thousands of
littley millions and so you see I like
to this is the same hash I like to cure
in both containers I don't uh you know
although I like glass more I find that
if I'm always willing to learn then I'll
do things well then I then I'll learn I
find if I'm always willing to learn I'll
learn and if I just think glass is the
greatest thing and there's no place for
hash in plastic then I lose any
potential possibility of you know a
discovery what one thing I've learned is
when you carry your Buckle hasing BL J
say like cooler like this and it falls
and all that
Bub so so that's why I've actually more
containers St I like a lot of these
little containers I pack these up good
they're good for the Trippy Stick
they're good for the containers are
everywhere everybody's got these
containers and you know what just U make
sure you put on the bottom like mine's
73910 as we were talking about the three
that we like the most yes absolutely of
course that's an absolutely definitely
your your favorite I don't think yeah
yeah 90 and 73 are my favorite but some
there's some Wicked 120 out there really
really wicked 120
so um I hit that my pony 90 I guess
[Music]
um little dunk I'm definitely well
medicated first couple weeks of um 2014
have
been it's not even mean a couple weeks
don't mean 10 days
wow it's just like one event after
another more things happening with this
uh whole change the
legalization
Colorado I think it's almost
done I thought there might have been hit
there but I think it might be a one of
those
that's
wow yeah that's
strong it is it's strong yeah I already
said that too I was like I need
something strong right now this is nice
but this is more than nice this is ice
wine this is
like like liquid nitrogen made uh ice
cream you know this is like the high-end
dessert at the high-end restaurant this
is every hash smoker just wants to smoke
this until they fall asleep it's so
freaking
tasty I have to say yeah that is the
best I've ever had is that that's tasty
tasty tasty for me I've never made
anything like that until you show me
these way it's just and that's the
beautiful thing when you grow it
properly and you do it properly that
every you know not every strain but
potentially there's a lot of strains out
there that have the potential to be what
I call like the best in the world you
know sure there might be a hundred there
might be a thousand I don't know how
many there's definitely a lot of them
I've seen a lot of full melt out there
years ago I was going to start a company
with a friend called Full melt
genetics and we were just going to
broker seeds that we had assured people
would produce full melt resins if grown
properly and uh so I paid attention over
the years to the strains that do and wow
it's a growing list I'm happy to say
happy to say
[Music]