[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world here with
John H beer fellow on a beautiful puff
Wednesday thanks for coming out as
always
brother always a pleasure to have you
out here I guess today we're going to be
doing a little bit of dry sifting um I
did some dry sifting with d420 K last
week in Prince George and although I
thought it was going to be more of a
video where I would be involved I felt
that it was really cool to show d420
techniques that he's learned from uh
getting his res into a pure state but
today I wanted to go over really more
the technique that I shared with him
initially and uh show that you can
actually card a little bit harder than
what people think you can card I want to
really show the carding process um we'll
do an initial bounce with medic Haze no
this is actually um py headband oh it's
the headband okay great and that's this
right here
yeah I'll be able to take a good look at
it it's going to be the headband of the
Packy yeah so we got a I can't remember
little over a quarter pound anyway that
we're going to uh John will do his uh
gentle bounce over his screen I think
it's always nice to just let uh let the
grower do that initial bounce and get
that that is beautiful Triple A quads
whatever you call it yes number four
beautiful herb the sun really makes it
look good too we'll take a few shots for
you before we bounce this uh we'll say
we'll just put a couple of the nugs
aside first twoo off the top get a
couple of pictures and then we'll put
that over the screen and uh we'll go
through it's going to be a quick video
today of dry sifting um probably should
turn that Dil
on here we go get that going cuz I'm
sure we're going to need a denail hit
sooner than
later all right so we got the air
pressure pump pumped up to about 75 Psi
Psi yeah and uh we're going to just do a
quick clean on these screens cuz John's
noticed there's a little bit of resin on
them from last time and he wants his
resin uncontaminated so let's do it want
to actually hold this screen up for me
and I'll blow it through like this
perfect get that one down
there nice forced pressure you'll see
this one there's quite a bit of more
powder in
here you know it doesn't have to be
every single drop of powder but
just we'll use all the air we have here
I'd rather not turn the pump on so
but basically gives you an
[Music]
idea all all right so yeah that cleaned
us up a
bit can always use your hand as
well over it
too little bit of dust
falling that's aot little bit of resin
head everywhere you can see all these
little heads everywhere so this is our
70 Micron we're going to put on the
bottom if you want to pass me the
140 all
right we'll be back in a few seconds
when we put the herb on the
screen all right yeah just beautiful
nugget yeah well I'm bouncing all the
resin off yeah it's definitely you don't
want to play around in the bag too much
like that but that's uh that's really
nice
that was that
blond all right
well that's cold I'll tell you that much
may out
here chenel
bounce really really nice looking
herb
killing nice I'm quite happy
with you can even see the little resin
look at all the little balls there oh
yeah we got a few hair in here huh I
have cats yeah they usually find their
way in that's why we're getting rid of
all the Chafe hairs are going to have a
hard time getting their way through the
screen so what I normally do is I just
do
this many ways to extract the resin off
the buds and it's a personal choice and
it's directly related to also cleaning
of the resin you know the more gentle
you are the less cleaning you're going
to do the rougher you are I mean after
initially doing this you could get to
the point two or three sifts down the
line where you grind this into powder
and then you run it through a p a tumble
now or a tumbler um 4x2 screen basically
run it through screen as powder you get
a very very low grade
material but there's there's resin to be
had in there so there's a variety of
ways you can even funny enough I know
it's a misnomer and it goes against dry
sifting but you can actually make dry
sift large quantities of it and um run
it through bags afterwards I've seen it
run through through water of course
you're going to lose your water soluble
turpins and it will defeat a lot of the
fact but it's still an easy way to run a
large amount of product into a smaller
amount of product and then run that into
actual final product heads and for me
this is my favorite I do but I love the
foam melt fresh frozen this herbs just
beautiful in the Sun the the the colors
and stuff I'm going pull like my phone
out of my pocket and take a picture do
it do it but even look this see all this
that's I was talking about like how can
I harvest just those look at all those
heads mhm cuz they're not going to go
through the screen so those are actually
a bigger head
totally it almost looks like little
granulars of
sugar they are going yeah see so it's
cing a lot heavier as and that's what
this is all about today showing people
that there's a different way to do it
you're being so gentle here you're not
cting the actual heads through they're
trapped in there so we just do a little
bit of cting you know not too much cuz
there is a lot of contaminant in there
but definitely enough for sure this is
140 microns green there's definitely the
potential that you know all the 160 all
140 or 150 heads in bigger will end up
staying on top of the screen but
generally our favorite heads aren't in
that range anyway our favorite range is
between
120 140 and
70 oh yeah I love I always love just
that first bounce I know it fell through
there that's what I collect right away
and then I start slowly breaking down
these buts excellent so I want to grab
that first bounce yeah absolutely other
than this little piece right
yeah can I see be okay what do you think
take a look underneath there for a
second cuz we're going to like take a
hit of this right now we're going to get
to work it is a hit it is isn't it
that's what I mean it's that first
bounce it's like the best of the best
you going to pick it up so I can put the
screen back down awesome just like that
beautiful beautiful all right so yeah
load her up that looks beautiful nice
gentle sift you can see from 100 G you
got
about one maybe two
rips of this so when you're going gentle
you're obviously being extremely
inefficient in your extraction rate
you're going for the the nicest heads
that you can
get however at one point we're also
going to show you getting this herb down
to a better State and getting it
actually you know some product run
through here and then once we have that
we'll get back into the cing you know it
does take a while so we're not going to
show you the 40 minutes that it takes me
to clean but in a half an hour to 40
minutes I can clean a nice little pile
of dry sift with the cing technique and
get a nice melting uh bubbly final
product so
yeah look at that herb right there on
camera so
um so basically I'll change spots with
you and I'll hit the it's um hit the
we're going to grab a couple nice buds
out of
here just random some randoms just some
randoms all
right denail rips in the sunshine
and the
rest as you can even see it just
flaking very
nice I love that when you break it's
nice and cold out here so when you break
you can just see the dust can hear snap
too yeah nice and dry
sign's nice and just like so basically
John's going to do this for a a little
while longer we're going to um come back
at the point where we've got resin to
work with on the bottom screen cuz
that's really the part I want to show
you today so we'll be back uh right away
so just getting a little rougher now
with the with the herb John's worked the
pile of uh smaller debris worked it down
the way I was showing um carted it out
and now he's got the the smaller nuggets
out and he's going to be you know doing
a little bit more bouncing you know we
will probably get to the point with this
if John wants to get get all the resin
off of it where we will like powderize
this this this this herb and we'll
tumble it for not too too long but for
certainly long enough that we're certain
that we've gotten all the glands out and
then um and then at that point I'll
probably clean that resin for John cuz
that kind of resin it becomes extremely
difficult to clean uh when you got 10%
uh heads versus 90% contaminant
sometimes even higher but uh
uh we'll get to our secondary carding
real soon
sweet my hand
this nice
resin most people wear gloves but I like
to touch my
resin son of
DK 420s res right
there Sharon the lovely herb
and really loving loving these new carb
caps from
Dil really sweet the way they're
machined and they just fit right in the
denail bowl
perfectly I like
it can I load you one up Johnny oh
yeah I'm going to do this part and as
you get me ready you're going to There
You Go sir corner of the screen
secured I know you like
the well either it's gives me kind of
more of that uh
wizard
rander to
left-hander oh what a perfect drop that
was ladies and
gentlemen it's got a nice little slit in
this particular carb cap so it just uh
just lets you keep taking a perfect hit
without
really much
worry sure's a beautiful day out here
[Music]
for as mildly chilly that it
is cuz you're explaining it so just uh
when you do this initial Harvest of
resin heads you get dirt
but we can clean this and you can see
underneath that there's there's stuff
that's worth having but it's still quite
dirty so we spread it as thin as we
can and you end up left with a cleaner
and cleaner product see how clean I got
this one right here in a real quick
hurry a lot a lot compared to well I
think there's a decent
amount and so then we gently card we
don't want to push through a ton of
contaminant but we want those
heads and they just need a little bit of
help to go
through yes vibration would be helpful
in this particular instance vibration
tumbling any of these varieties are
going to be helpful for
extracting all right so we've gotten
that quar pound broken down nicely into
smaller
buds getting smaller and smaller as John
works it it's it's a good idea as he
does this to set like at this point I
would have him separate the nugs out get
all his nugs separated out and do
another one of those gentle carings over
the dust that's left and separate the
cha from that dust card that dust
through card that dust through and then
uh move to the next level I would have
gave in
because that's just what you do with
it's money
we realized
[Music]
I'm gently you know I'm not really
crushing them kind of more
gently these nugs still have a tiny bit
of
moisture sitting for a for dry sift I
guess if we knew 100% that that we would
have dry sifted this we should have had
a sit on it would have been out and dry
I said that the whole time but it is
still dry don't get me wrong no I can
see that it shouldn't be this I like
we're going to dry SI that one day I
said we're going to crush that whole
thing and that's what we're doing what I
want to do except for those Medicine Man
huh your medicine oh why wouldn't
you I won't be else
I might also do it myself
if it makes it over here it's
going no problem and will we run that
through the tumbler later or oh sure why
not prob take down take everything
from I got so I tried doing that and
that's what I have in that little jar is
I took up some of this but the other
stuff all right so you want to just
clean that herb up off the screen yeah
it's pretty much down to nothing we'll
get down to our next screen
yeah tiny little popcorn tiny tiny
little these little hard bugs work
really well for
missing definitely when doing the
secondary screen and we start cting you
don't want to wear a long sleeve shirt
like John's wearing you can see his cuff
going in the herb each time he picks it
up and that's just uh for the herb it's
not a big deal it will get fibers in
there but um for the I personally don't
I just would wear a short sleeve shirt
if you could otherwise um like you said
earlier the gloves and uh just any way
to secure the material and keep it as
clean as
possible Right you want to give the
final screen a wipe before you lift it
yeah a blow even
better this quite a bit one thing I've
realized is you always get a little bit
of flakes on your body and stuff and you
lift it up
and it gets full so I'm just going to
actually pick this up and move the
screen over here
[Music]
give this card a quick
clean there use all the
cards how's the color looking looks
beautiful yeah nice and
light should we photograph it with the
uh macro lens before we oh you should
yeah move it all off the screen do a
closeup as I'm ping this in we'll do a
quick
one how's the color looking looks
beautiful yeah nice and
light should we photograph it with the
uh macro lens before we oh you should
yeah off the screen do a closeup as I'm
ping this in we'll do a quick
one okay
so collected our
sift single screen we've done a small
amount of macro photography on uh on
what's here
[Music]
nice pile of near I would say it's a
good 50%
heads
50% not heads so because we're
collecting this to flip to the other
side of the screen I want to I want to
get the shadow out of the way so I'm
going to put this on the other side of
the
screen got a plate
there there you
go D
du D
du go for clean
one for that last
little little
[Music]
trickle all right so now we've got a
little bit more more in the Sun for you
guys so you can see this is our I want
to grab those two for a second this one
one here sure go ahead clean the whole
screen do do 20 like it's if if you see
dirt get her clean cuz we definitely
don't want to um put beautiful hash down
on a dirty screen so like John just
pointed out if you see a hair you see
anything this is the time where taking
your time is a worthwhile
look at that beautifully stuck to the
plate not moving at all good sign right
off the bat considering you guys know
how powdery this
is we're going to be carting it so I
like it to somewhat fall back on the
screen
[Music]
get all of that off there blowing a
little wind in the in the
hash
so now we're going to do our carting in
order to do our carting Technique we
want to we want to card a small amount
at a time nice small amount at a time
you can hear the sound the resin is
definitely
prevalent and then you can everyone in a
while get in a larger amount if you want
to feel the difference on the
efficiencies of if you feel like a small
amounts just taking too long try a
larger amount and you'll see that it's
actually going to slow you down even
more
so I usually
separate my grade my initial from what I
carred uh this is when it's nice to have
one of those brushes that d420 K has as
well very nice little cards to have
[Music]
we're going to push through
contaminants and we're going to push it
a good amount of it through I don't
doubt which is always the case and
because it's cold right now so it's
actually working quite
nicely can even see it somewhat sticking
the contaminant sticking in the
screen so basically this is a process
that we'll do
uh until we can get the resin as clean
as possible and I've shown this on
camera before I've shown this process of
basically carting this resin back and
forth back and forth and you'll see that
you're
losing
quantity and you're gaining
quality so I'm going to work this small
pile of resin I'll be carting for the
next oh I'd say 35 to 45 minutes easy
and I'll bring this down to a much
cleaner pure product and it already
looks really much whiter than the gold
pile that I have over here when you're
cleaning off the little pieces there's
these little pieces that will gather up
on your cards here you want to clean
those up you want to keep them out of
your hash keep them over to the side
they're a nice quality and they're
definitely not to be thrown away but
there's something that uh will
definitely mess up the carting process
good so so I'll continue on cleaning and
carting and we'll come back and show you
the final product and do a little puff
down all right welcome back guys we're
uh Sun H sun has set and I'm not sure if
I'm going to show it to you before the
video or right at the last thing but it
was definitely a beautiful sunset some
nice orange color in there it was quite
ni and then uh we cleaned up some of
this dryft so we have a few different
piles you can kind of see the different
uh colors this one looks pretty top
grade right here we'll probably have a
few rips of that um that was a lot of
cing whole lot of caring carted for
probably an
hour and this is what we've got so full
melt dry sip we'll show you some macro
shots as
well uh so let give you a pile of the of
the goodness here oh
all right here you go we've taken the
ceramic tip off for the time being it's
over here if you want it I want what's
that want to go deep in all right just
drop her in
nice and bubbly and melty how did that
taste oh it tastes so nice and smooth
nice all right well I'm going I'm going
to make the attempt on some of
that that's going I
needed oh there's The Taste now
wow that taste is
U very deep TK like
a it's
nice very nice
yeah that was beautiful flowers like
about an hour and a bit ago and now it's
just like really
super tasty incredible dry
sift very good definitely a thumbs up
experience uh still more resin to be
taken off that herb it's by no means the
end of it this is what we call the cream
of the cream the Holy Grail hash you
could still run that bud through the wet
wash method and probably get four or
five or 6% return on it you could
definitely even after doing that run it
through a coconut oil soak it in coconut
oil and extract the last of the the
heads that are in there and just
continue to use the plant right down to
the last little bit so you get
everything we don't want people to think
of this is a waste but this is
definitely the next part for me is I
actually throw in a pot with some butter
and boil it down and make some nice for
for Edibles sure yeah exactly as long as
you're getting it with some sort of a
fat and you're extracting that last
little bit of resin then this is could
never be considered a waste it only is
to be considered uh something you do uh
in order to not sacrifice your best for
anything that you're doing I'm going to
bake my stuff in the oven excellent some
tin foil there you go well that doesn't
sound as good as extracting the heads
off with screens and puffing pu heads
very very definitely all
gone it's definitely um the last of the
last instead of throwing it away you
decarbox it exactly that's but uh I'm
not sure how much would be left if you
soaked it in butter oil but probably a
little bit butter and oil it goes into
garbage that's what I'm saying that's
the last little bit so hopefully you
guys have learned a little bit today
that you can card a little bit harder I
know I didn't show a long time I just
wanted to basically show you the force
that I was able to use that you want to
be in a colder environment um you don't
want to be in too warm of an environment
when you're dry sifting and uh yeah
happy sifting let us know how you're
doing in the comments we'll uh talk to
you guys later see
[Music]