[Music]
all
right perfect we're back and Matt's
Matt's in the house how's it going
everybody sorry about that to interrupt
you we'll do it again yeah all right so
we're back we've got a new uh friend in
the house Matt just rolled in how's it
going dude pretty good pretty good good
to have you here man you just met the
dog oh yeah big honor for sure very cool
very cool just watched the video the
other day I was like oh man I got I got
to beet him you know the doctor the the
atomic Haze and was one of the strains
that we lost in the 2004 raid on the bit
Cree uh in in Victoria with the with the
Vicks and that was one of the strains
that we absolutely lost 04 04 so you've
Lo you've had it's been gone for 10
years yeah wow yeah it was great it was
it was super popular well like for sure
hook you up with oh something or be
awesome like we we were a discussion
I'll just jump in here we were
discussing about you know ownership of
genetics if you will and sharing of
genetics I suppose you could you could
allude to like the internet file sharing
whether it's a a violation or whether
it's okay right yeah I guess it is very
much like it right well it is software
ultimately
yeah yeah I mean if you've bred it and
you and you and you work with it and
you've created your own sort of species
yeah I understand that I I feel you know
if you don't want to share it then don't
share it don't give it to anybody and
then say I gave it to you and then don't
you know don't share it right it's like
if you want it and you want to keep it
private keep it private and you know if
it's if it's like a cut that's out
there it's out there there right like
just share it I don't that's how I feel
of it and I'm I'm pretty open with my
genetics yeah just because I for me it's
the medicinal side of it if it makes
somebody feel better yeah then I think
it you know the plant needs to be out
there make it making people feel better
yeah we uh doc took the uh took the Barb
home the other
day so there you go he's got some of
your genetics Barb yeah Barb bar by the
Berry uh line that was one of the
strains that you grabbed from him so
it's a pretty
nice little strin maybe that's we had an
old friend come up to me in London he's
got the uh yellow line really oh yeah so
uh hopefully we'll be able to uh bring
some Pier Shish Berry
back Shish I think was another strain
that we lost in the
vitc raid along with the princess the
princess for us and the vix was the
number one painkiller overall medicinal
strain that we had it couldn't keep it
on the menu it just sold sold
sold it was another one that was lost
completely lost you want to hit some of
that
barb good
Barb Barra this is dry
sift of
course the award
winning just did some fresh frozen
yesterday I saw dude I was looking at
that picture today that piece was like
that piece like solidified like that I
couldn't I put it into the Sie to scrape
it and I and I couldn't I had to put it
into the freezer to sort of Chunk it
back up temperature it's going to be key
is temperature crazy you know I had the
same problem I don't know if you saw my
last video of the Astro Boy Fresh Frozen
that I went to run through my strainer
and then it just
went and just I was like what am I oh oh
put it in the freezer for like 2 hours
took it out smacked it with a hard cold
spoon that was also in the freezer and
it just broke like glass on top of the
parchment so yeah we just left it in for
like 10 minutes or so just enough to
sort of get that gumminess off and we
were able to get it through the SI oh
okay good but uh it was crazy we threw a
we threw a wet piece just through it in
sizzled away but just white it was like
did you see that one shot
same color of theen I thought I liked it
and even commented on it
unbelievable holy smokes I drooled when
I saw it that's for sure and just the
amount just the amount like that that's
that's when I told doc about that's why
you grabbed the Barb when I was like
grab that one because it produces resin
like that's a strain that should be bred
if that is a genetic trait then it
should be
somehow isolated and passed on into
other strains cuz you just you're
disappointed like I was running I have a
a warlock a warlock canonic and I mean
the Warlock the Warlock is up there for
producing it is it makes great dynamite
dynamite hash but I cross it with the
canonic and all the fenals that are
coming off of it they're great but the
hash is doesn't produce the quantity I
put it in the big tumbler that you do
the hour run and you're like the hour
run open up up and you're just like hm
no you know it fills a fairly good
container up but an hour run with Barb
will fills entire zock bag like a half
pound bag unbelievable a half pound bag
I se I've seen it
myself what comes off the the tricomes
yeah the tricomes and here's the crazy
thing in an hour run it's still like 50%
heads which to people okay that aren't
hash makers you might that might not
sound like anything but even by itself
would be that much
stronger I mean with without extracting
it from the hatch just the but
itself I don't know there's something
about smoking the bud that's not as the
flavor in the bud for some reason
doesn't fully carry over to the to the
to the taste like with the with the with
this tan with the new Tangi it does it
has it when you smell it it's like oh my
God it's fantastic and it carries over
in the flavor and with the Barb it
doesn't so much in the bug but the
resin is is just is like phenomenal I
you can smell maybe you know maybe it's
me and I'm and I'm just around so much
other flavorful butd and no the bottom
line is I make a lot of it's a it's a
it's like um skunkman Sam skunk number
one produces resin like that and so did
the strain that they crossed what did
they cross to produce the SLE
stack heard stor stack is also well that
SLE stack stunt cross was the one that
also just produced an enormous amount of
resin so one day we'll be focused on
that when we all have green houses going
and we were able to grow way larger
amounts and there's just like oh I got a
55 gallon drum just full of material I
have to run oh really I have 10 of those
running in the hlc right now see what it
tests at yeah see if exactly little it
won't even be an HSC it'll be that
little have you seen that little device
that you can just like they're making it
for fruits and vegetables it's like the
same idea as a as a spectrometer but
they needed to take a spectrometer which
is like a large tabletop machine and
they turned it into this tiny little
chip took them three years to do it and
it fits in this little hand thing and
it's basically like a molecular sniffer
or whatever they call it it's like you
you point it at fruit and it'll tell you
if there's pesticides used like I know
it's I was just reading online the O
phone where they can send and now
they're like like 30 programed cents but
you can mix them together to make over
300,000 different smells and you can
send it to your friend that's cool send
a picture along with a smell to your
friend like that's the technology is out
there so it's pretty wild I was sitting
on the ferry I was like man the smoker
kids of Tomorrow are going to have what
you they're going to have the whole
color spectrum have you tried this
variety like and potentially spectrums
outside they go look it for it and they
go look it for those smells yeah that's
awesome that's a whole you know when you
turn the flashlight on in the dark room
it's amazing how easier you can move
around you know the metaphor as you get
in deeper and you understand what you're
getting into I can only imagine how do
you see all this stuff I was just going
to say you really taking it to the next
step mean all like even this gear you
know like I've always been a joint guy
okay but now the dabs and the butter and
the and the shatter and the all the
hardware and the tools yeah and all the
talk the six-year-old Master
Kush yeah stable no but it's it's um
what do you call the technological
side Innovation
yes it's kind of
fun might be getting a little dirty and
and I I must say that you really refined
the P by zeroing in mhm on that triome
oh yeah and and the triome
head really cleaning of it the cleaning
of it and getting it down to CU on the
on the island for know for 10 years like
we've we've been sort of dry sifting on
the island for a long long long time and
for us it was always just trimming the
buds on the screen and that's it and
sort of collecting this and collecting
this quality but I've always ever just
had like little balls of it and little
containers of it and the and the like it
was really the cup the last cup for me
you know sort of opened it up to
cleaning it cleaning it to a and getting
rid of the contaminant contaminant
that's in there right really the
difference between s that's where the
high is 90 and 100 once you get up to
those crazy levels even from 95 to
98 that 3% is like it's
like telling you it's insane wow and
that's why the first time I ever went to
skunk man's place and he puffed me down
with that stuff and Rob Clark would
always tell stories of like oh man I
left his place like crosy the other day
I was like oh come on I got to do like
really like come on the first time I
like sat there one night and po I left
so destroyed I was literally just
like okay I understand now
99%
99% especially because he's in control
of like growing that resin and and
cleaning and everything it starts I
think that's where it really starts and
that's what uh that's what I'm learning
I mean I love cleaning resin and and
playing with resin and running different
people's stuff through my bags and
screens but I also love growing resin
for sure man it puts a smile on your
face for sure and now I've got some doc
atomics doc Atomic brought me some NL
some Northern Lights yeah some beautiful
oh dude of course it's yours and um
awesome and the Harmon
which is Froman yeah yeah so yeah pretty
seen I've SE we've seen that on the
island hary mhm it's nice it's nice yeah
I saw it I photographed it recently at
that license production facility that I
went to uh till and so they had
Harmony they had
Harmony and a whole bunch of different
things it was good to see it was nice to
see um nice Bud oh yeah yeah nice
facility
yeah you know not allowed to talk about
the facility but can definitely say the
bud was nice didn't smoke the bud don't
smoke bud photograph the resin looked
killer photographed lots of resin have
to say it was like just kind of right up
there with most of it so I guess the
real the the real sort of test would be
to um isolate the resin and then be able
to try it and then I could literally
that would be a cool thing for the for
bubble man to be able to offer to do
like or even a crew of us you know where
we're like well you know we're
well-known people in the Cannabis
industry and what we're offering is
we'll come in we'll extract your resins
we'll smoke them and then we'll give you
a review on them and you can keep it
private if you want or you could use it
as you know your sounds like a great
idea yeah you know like that'd be fun eh
cuz it's like here's the thing
everyone's bashing these LPS I'm just
like okay fine if they're selling moldy
weed or they're not growing good herb or
they're selling strains that aren't the
real strains then fine then that they
deserve to have people on that cuz it's
important that they they don't do those
things but if there are ones that are
just literally good people they're like
well we're just growing herb to sell it
to people that's you it's like an old
business yeah I would just like to know
which ones have good herb because I
haven't been able to get behind and you
know unfortunately for us to order herb
um as licensed users here in Canada we
lose our ability to grow so they put
that in some amendments so it's why I
didn't I was going to order herb from
all of the licensed production
facilities can't do that either but I
thought I'd do it with a bunch of my
friends if we each picked one well you
could like you can get your doctor to
say sign five different forms right and
say you have 20 gr and you can just say
I'm getting you know four G four GRS
from five different guys and then
therefore you can you can get that many
now it's a hassle to the
doctors still I wanted to do a review
you know I wanted to be able to buy like
I wanted to get like a half pound from
each one
and then run it through my screens
photograph the resin show the resin
whether it melts or Bubbles and
literally have it in a room full of
people where we all do a little mini cup
and just say you know like listen I've
I've been all over the world and smoked
all over the world that's good resin
yeah this one I didn't like that much
but I you know it'd be a nice honest
review and I think some of these LPS
could really use it I think I think if
you're out there and you're in an LP and
you want some professional advice from
people that have been in the industry
for 25
35 think a there's probably close to 80
years in here you know there it is right
there and it's like you know and and
we're not the only ones by any means you
know guys like Ramo and get you know
there's a lot of different people out
there not just even in British Columbia
all across the board that could sort of
I think suit that you know that need
where it's like you have respected
individuals who you know people are
following them on the Instagram and
Twitter social media all the social
media a huge there's a huge uh you know
it's how I give it's how I stand behind
both of you guys like I have to say just
because you're my friends and I wouldn't
be like all like promoting you guys if
you just didn't have things that
inspired me I would have a hard time
doing it you know what I mean like I
have a hard time being here yeah yeah no
doubt it's nice that you guys both grow
the Dank and both breed the Dank that's
important and and I love the fact that
you guys both sell your seeds at the
Vancouver Seed Bank so boom Vancouver
Seed Bank in house we're always shouting
them
out Rebecca's golden I love Rebecca yeah
she just got back from Jamaica herself I
know that's
awesome little
Tangi purple Tangi feno oh yeah there
you go
Tangi Tango won a lot it's it's it's won
a lot of awards I as soon as I I smoked
this it was like you guys smoke that
joint because there's never been a joint
smoked in my office and I'd love it to
be these guys and I'm going to smoke
some dabs permission I guess no no I
already so you smoke that joint 100
under the door so we put a towel in the
door no no no no no I have a fan that
once that joint gets puffed up and we're
not filming anymore I'll turn it off
they probably heard me turn the fan off
at the halfway
point awesome dudes
boom old school new
school yeah smells nice nice oh wow that
Astro Boy tasted really great too Mark I
need some water okay well then I'm going
to get you guys some water Doc's
out Doc's
out all right he's out you hanging out
for a bit Johnny's here uh maybe for a
bit chill for a short I got to head out
town all right we'll do a short puff
Wednesday
session there's the dirty
resin well two have left and one has
arrived puff Wednesday brother puff
Wednesday welcome welcome let's get you
Puff right off it's nice thing here's
some of that dry sift Barb that I
pressed up quite some time ago to uh
think I showed it in a video The Whiting
out of the dry sift yeah I remember give
you a little dunker D it up that'll
probably float right over the hole there
but should be okay oh yeah that's nice
made a little
hole maybe lost a tiny bit in the center
but that's
okay so you just left miss doc while you
saw him in the driveway you'll see so
we'll do a video with him next
time uh Matt doc brought me the Harmony
from reeferman nice which is really
bringing us and he brought us the
Northern Lights I would like to test
that Harmony against the MK Ultra MH
yeah absolutely interesting and the
Northern Lights I think I have something
that has some Northern Light in it yeah
absolutely well this is the old uh the
old Northern Lights oh look at this I
didn't think you were going to pull it
right out of your back pocket well was
not joking about that this has got some
Northern l in it oh very good and so
what do we got here My Little Pony ah
the My Little Pony the My Little Pony
it's a Bubba cam which is a pre Bubba
Kush with a cam for reunion cross into a
Northern Light number five SK and I
talked to Doc about that at the bottom
of the stairs when he came up and he
smiled very nice I said 92 and he's said
he's like that's about right excellent
that's awesome it was which number is
that this is the number four phen one
phen one one okay if you know one I
think I have one of those right now in
bloom down in my tent there you go so
that's awesome very cool we'll get that
uh happening we'll Bloom that up I'll
definitely do a little shoot on my
channel um probably in the next couple
of days of where the My Little Pony is
number one and number four in like week
five you have a camera I have a camera
now Johnny B ordered a camera the same
camera I'm using which is the
x920 Panasonic it's a pro suumer model
cost about 8900 bucks if you want to
check it out on B&amp;H photo.com and Johnny
got it you got the nice wide angle lens
the macro lens which maybe we'll play
with today that would be nice and uh why
don't I let you talk about what else you
brought while I go grab your box cuz I
need to do that the Box showed up the
other day and you know what uh I was
going to wait until puff Wednesday to
open it and at the same time there's the
medic Kush guys oh man now that's
something I can get behind I know okay
I'm going to go grab your box you tell
us about the medic cush so I brought I
brought Mark another medy he did the
last run of it and he was uh talking
about how great the resin was and how
much he really appreciated and he says
it's definitely his medicine he took
some great shots of it some macros which
uh you know he's uh well like he's
understanding is how good M Kush works
for me and a lot of other people um but
beautiful we got one two three four five
six seven eight nine 10 beautiful clones
from not such a small plan I did my
fimming of course not fimming I peel the
top apparently fimming is something
completely different but I do my peel
people have seen it some of my previous
vide so it's being peeled so it's split
my top right there already which is
forcing these bottom really nicely here
so you'll definitely get a great little
bush with this plant special
delivery I got something for you Johnny
Be you going to have to stand up here
yeah sorry about that oh no it's okay we
we put a more comfortable chair in just
because uh well I like to be more
comfortable all right you still tell
talking about medy I was talking about
medy and I was talking about I could
show them how many different phones and
how I was doing my peel and how I force
this down as you can see so this will
really explode up now excellent so and
and he's opening up my box no no I'm
just actually opening the plastic for
you cut so I got your tool there I don't
buy myself much anything ever ever heed
watch so this is like you know what this
is awesome no I've had this box for days
and no uh like uh no plans on opening it
even someone was like oh you should open
it up and charge it for him I'm like no
no no he's going to be opening it
up you brother that's uh it's all snack
it's exciting no it looks awesome oh my
goodness that's
fun there's your card first we have the
mega card so we can do lots of videos SD
card 64 gig you know I'm definitely
going to be doing that then we pull out
the macro the ultra macro conversion
lens I had that one I lost it in Spain
bummer well now we have one that um we
have yes there's the wide angle there's
the wide angle that we are now looking
at through right now so I'm
that there's your Watson dual charger
which I have mine
literally my new Panasonic digital
camera
oh dude yeah so that's awesome so now I
can do some more videos on how I do my
medicine and we're going to do some
videos now even how I DEC carboxilate
we're going to talk about the different
people who different decarbox silation
and stuff I can't wait I'm really
excited guys you're going to get some
great education from uh me exciting and
yes the charger the charger needed the
charger cuz um I basically ordered
everything for John he was like just get
me what I need and then I was like like
okay I'll tell you this is the dream
package right here although I made one
uh fail at not getting him a tripod and
I'm hoping he himself goes and gets one
I've been telling him this for about a
week now since we ordered this camera go
get a tripod go get a tripod even today
we probably would have filmed with that
camera had he gotten a tripod cuz you
you need a tripod well where do you put
the camera well see I have a few tripods
at home but I realized com to think that
I'm going to go need to get a better one
so and I was just curious on on a cple
things I was looking at how yours was
and how it was slid back and forth and I
was reading on on the site there where
they had that one that motions with you
so if you're talking and stuff like that
like that's a $500 tripod 275 yeah well
and then if you look next to it the
other compart component that you need to
make that work that you would wear on
your belt yeah is like another 200 oh so
we definitely not getting that it's
about $500 it's a cool technology I
thought it's kind I personally am
looking for about a 40 to $50 tripod the
one I have is a is a nice I have nice
big manf FR legs with the professional
video head this is a fairly expensive
tripod it maybe 300 plus I'm looking for
something extremely light because of
course it can't carry too much this is
not the one for you oh I don't like that
one I ha it I hate it so I'm definitely
not getting nothing like that I hate
carrying it I need a I need a lighter
one I'm hting swap meat this weekend you
know prob find a nice one that camera
that uh want to give it to Mike he is
loving it he's got his little bag he
camera I think seen a coup pi oh he's
he's snapping pictures like crazy he's
going to document so many things and
that came from the cool kid um in
Toronto at Champs who gifted me the
camera well I have now been gifted a new
camera so I passed yours on with the
help of John to his neighbor Mike and
you can watch them on their videos and
I'm sure you can get turned on to Mike
through his social media and start
checking out some of his uh he has his
pictures that he's snapping my garden on
Facebook oh there we go my garden so
that's where you get all the Mike's
pictures and he's goingon to do videos
on how to uh cook your own food and
everything be kind of cool we're all
about educating and it's really cool so
it's we're actually affecting more and
more people around us and even you're
going to get a camera out there and
you're going to do some videos and help
educate other people best thing about
YouTube is uh we're educating everyone
each other are so did you see your dry
sift here that you brought by wow yeah
no This was um tell you a little bit
more about this guys this is
actually hemp oh yeah yeah yeah yeah so
um the the what we're looking at was uh
the CBD and I was curious of um what uh
is being sold in town in clubs uh they
sell CBD caps and they $3 to5 and we
were curious what was actually in that
so um we took a good look and what we're
realizing is uh well how much of that is
really completely like absolutely
nothing in there would you say I'd say
maybe about 85 to 95% 85 the 95% of that
is pure waste so I I'm really seeing
that this doesn't even seem like a plant
I what is that it's like carpet or
something yeah yeah it's weird so so so
you know what we're taking a better look
at what's going on with what's happening
with the new Industries and everybody's
getting into these CBD caps and what's
out you're hearing it all over the place
but you know what this is what people
are putting in those caps this is what
people are putting in these caps Bey be
very wary um if you can I you can't grow
your own hemp that's the only problem
and but you don't need to grow hemp no
you just grow grow grow your own
cannabis if you if you're needing caps
and if you're needing a CBD product then
grow a CBD know strain and it doesn't
matter if there's THC in it just don't
DEC carboxilate it the THC or the CBD
will still be active you'll still be
able to acquire it through your
bloodstream yes and you don't need to
activate the THC and so there's no
worries of needing a a hemp product
that's grown for food that isn't grown
for medicine exactly or grown for other
things but uh we were just curious and
uh got my hands on a bag nice well I had
no idea that I cleaned I I spent like an
hour and a half cleaning that you had me
clean hemp and no one's ever going to
use it for medicine but that's okay it
was time well spent for the experiment
we'll say
100% it was uh well we've taken a look
at it we see what's there I'm sure you
got all the macro photos and stuff like
that yeah I still actually have yet to
shoot each one the video is waiting
upload so yeah you'll have seen this
video that we're talking about prior to
the video we're filming right now cuz
I'm going to edit it and upload it first
this one will go up afterwards and uh
you'll have seen all the macro photos of
this uh there you go hemp so um just a
little bit of Education out there of
what um people are
being it's this big craze and you know
we me and Mark talk about it everybody's
like CBD CBD CBD so this is this is of
course another way of people uh
extracting money from the second Des
dude I'm excited to uh grow some medy uh
medy cush again you like I got Med hay
growing right now that's nice I got
three of them blooming along with the
OG I think it's a Hos number nine I have
a Hos number nine I have some Astro boys
and I have two my little ponies that are
quite big and stretched out really
stretched out it's pretty pretty fun um
um very very excited on the sweet skunk
what's going on with that um what you
don't have sweet skunks oh I do um I
think I have the couple that rooted the
sour d the one that didn't root for me
was the K right yeah exactly which I
told you I could give you a new one yeah
so when of course right now I'm just
kind of going away so I've uh got I
don't have it's great as you'll seen my
videos basically my whole room's down
perfect well my room's just about to get
started I'm really excited to actually
get everything going today I hope uh
John is going to tell me that that he
brought the new tent I have a new tent
in my truck I have something new today
too I I I also have for you there's a
power cloner there by botanic so you
have this new clone I set the power
cloner up on a table in the corner there
it's awesome so you got that um picked
you up some hard pots of course
excellent cuz you like those hard pots
um there's the oh we have the tent the
the Dr the nanolux the of course you got
the nanolux the nanolux ballast I only
got one ballast this time cuz the uh
Lush people have sent me an LED uh
thanks to Kingston herb for that hookup
and I'm going to put the LED for half of
this tent the LED 2XL Dominator is going
to be in there and on the other side um
will be the simple High Press sodium so
we'll see what happens between um the
two that are on either side and then
we'll see what happens to I want to have
like you know Congo sweet skunk Cong
sweet skunk and then in the middle Congo
sweet skunk great mean so you have one
far spectrum of one or the other but
then in the middle at the same time you
get the combination of the two so
that'll be something that I'm going to
be doing full video full macro
photography uh documentation of so stay
tuned for that and uh what do you say we
get your camera plugged in and sorted
out so that's started and then we go
film the tent hey we got more stuff to
do so you know what let's just start
doing it all right sounds
good