[Music]
hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world I am here in downtown
Vancouver just had a really really
incredible meeting a friend a good
friend of mine has a family member who
is sick with cancer and he's been
telling me about you know different
meetings that he's been having with her
and finally I just said hey why don't we
get her some products we'll find some
oil a couple of days ago she said yes
she would she would be into that and so
we went and found some oil I went
through John BIRT fellow who funny
enough Johnny [ __ ] Dee is here with me
at this table I'm sitting at downtown
and you can see there he is down there
hey why don't you come down here come
down here alright Johnny [ __ ] be as
you can see this table we're sitting at
is absolutely incredible so here comes
Johnny B he's got looks like he's got a
slinger with them I figured you know
what let's see let's see that it's a
little dirty I use it all the time
hey why don't we use it right now I was
just about to tell the story of the
experience that we just went through for
our friend who's got a family member
with cancer and I haven't told them much
beyond that so why don't you come sit
with me and we'll well tell everyone
there's various there's Johnny be Johnny
be sharing a seat bro you know champion
of a human we had such a long table and
I was like I'm at the other end this
thing did that was hilarious this table
is what do you think 40 feet long
that's deep it's a decent table 71 feet
or it's a 42 feet so a friend of mine
has a sick family member he's been
telling me about her yesterday I finally
reached out to Johnny B because nobody
gets [ __ ] done like Johnny B it's true
we know it we [ __ ] know it
and he says yeah I'm on it let me let me
get it figured out I'll go and find so
first of all tell us who you thought of
right away when you thought of the top
quality oil for someone who's who's
riddled with cancer right now and needs
serious serious help you know what what
really came to my mind is I really
remember is back in the days when we
used to make a lot of oils and and you
know a Jim from weeds and you know gob
was so he was helping a lot of people
who had cancer stuff like that and as a
bank I used to make all of this oil for
all of us back in the days and
number one guy and I was like you know
what like I haven't talked to him it's
so long and no thinking you know I you
know I just so long these are some
pretty big people in the industry that
are really helping a lot of people so
I'm like I gotta make a call you sent me
the message I'm like I got this and I
call them I get me a slinky job but
fellow how are you my friend like monkey
say his name because doesn't really want
me to
yeah no problem um but he's like it's so
good to hear from me and I'm like you
know things are good you know how are
you doing he's like you know this whole
legalization and
having a lot of problem
patience and stuff like that well this
is the problem to found any second and
he goes and I'm really scrambling trying
to get proper dosages to people and we
just helped us gentleman and the clone
Hospital this family is all around them
and they were supposed to pass away and
he goes you know it's been three months
he's doing really well apparently his
cancer that was the size of a golf ball
that card is still soft like a sponge
and I'm amazing that's the medicine I
need right now he's like how much do you
mean I said thirty days he goes I got 29
for you 55 percent THC 20% CBD rate for
patients great for cancer I'm like
awesome awesome absolutely totally like
better go ahead he goes okay we have
these suppositories that are working
extremely well and we have someone have
this ovarian cancer and it kind of
really went and it was something they
don't understand why it's working so
well because once you take the
suppository it doesn't show up in your
system you have cannabinoids in it well
because they're doing all kinds of
testing and he's like I want to gift you
the suppository that was really nice say
I had no idea what type of condition
that are found was suffering from or
where the cancer was and just so ironic
that I think that this is gonna be the
key well I can tell you right off the
bat and I was talking to my friend
earlier and sort of mentioned he was
getting excited you think this could
really work and I was like of course I
do it's worked for lots of people why
wouldn't it it started creating this
hope first in him then in his cousin
then in his auntie and and in you know
you could feel it before we left we
dosed her a small amount it was it was a
little bigger than a small amount drop
yeah it was it was a mill and so
that's good it was nice to see her in
the 30 to 45 minutes afterwards okay the
change was very noticeable she was
leaning into her conversation she was
paying more attention you could you
could see physically her pain levels
were going down and she was actually you
know she had hope and she kept
mentioning it over and over again and I
told my friend you know hope is like a
big part of putting cancer into
remission obviously you need the right
tools but hope hope is the beginning and
we left there Johnny B we left some hope
there Oh a big box of it a huge box of
it yeah really good I want to thank your
friend for helping out obviously he's
doing this in it's amazing to me in this
day and age appear crop dogs yeah
pure crop dossier we'll put it in the
we'll put it in the bottom there where
you can look at these products but it's
amazing to me that legal companies are
still not allowed to make this product
available to me John's friend is a hero
for practicing the level of civil
disobedience that's necessary to get
people like the woman we just saw she's
the hero taking the medicine that rakaat
is required why are we not making this
accessible why are we worried about the
bottom lines of companies so I'm
personally very very excited to have
been a part of this today we'll follow
along the story we really hope that the
story continues on with with a you know
there's not going to be an ending to it
but there'll be a continuation and as
long as that continuation is successful
and the quality of life is increased for
for this woman and the quantity of life
is increased then cannabis has once
again done its job and do its job right
away so we need to have a bowl I know
do it hey let's do it this was that was
a little that was a good thing we did up
there your highness I love teaching
people about how cannabis saves lives
and and like you know I would say I'll
talk to her about the decarboxylated and
how of minds of receptors and the work
that we did with dr. Paul Harvey back in
the days and how I got off on my opioid
drugs using just a natural gaba and
converted forms of THC and really it's
it's it's come so far now and we're
going back 15 years ago and now is today
is like we're still fighting for it to
be access
I know true they they just baked those
things so hard pretty crazy the pressure
I had to use let me tell you anyway very
nice very nice experience I'm really
looking forward to you know and enduring
this she was like we need to make these
things available to people like it so
it's so contagious the the vibe of
wanting to help people I can already
picture this woman getting better
creating her own little groove here that
starts singing everywhere you go for
information getting this information out
there like all of you who do the same
thing you know these people who do that
they're always sharing and talking and
we talk about making it normal by just
sitting here out in the open doing to us
we're loud too
did you bring a dabber I took a poke at
you gotta have one
gotten up will you say that's one thing
I forgot husband you know we got your
keys very key we can make this work we
could do dunx dogs we're doing donk
sometimes you have to make the best of
it dude exactly the worst-case scenario
when you don't have a dabber is you need
to take a DAB that's about 10 times the
size of the one you make it's okay it's
really okay right there look at that
okay you know what I have to do
so one thing happened last time on this
is how'd you can season get clean that
well so we got some DC cleaner there
fired up
bring out a nice little business card
even a business card in my entire wallet
no I like to fold them and then use it
to drop the resin in but so that's okay
I can do it another way I love it you
know if i sat here and tried to burn all
this off I'd actually chose my Banga so
you're gonna bear with me guys here I'm
doing the quick clean too but you know
the best thing about this lady was let
me do it for you why is she she was
going on about how she had a kidney
removed and how she was and her pain was
getting so bad and you know what do they
have on hydro morphine it's like all
this bad stuff and she's telling me
about all the pharmaceutical drugs she
was on and then I I date back and like
we know go right back to you Mike
you know talk about a good good neighbor
Mike Martin and I says well Michael
Michael is also on a like a cocktail of
drugs and when I said you have to get
rid of these egos but that's what keeps
me alive so this is what's killing you
actually it's just like it's like
certain things are killing you the
opioid drugs are killing you those heavy
heavy narcotic drugs are clearly causing
more pain and even talking with Elaine
chasey paint she looked me in her eyes
she goes you know what I'm talking about
oh yes and the only person who knows
about chasing pain of the people who's
truly in pain because you can't explain
that to anyways who have done it and
then then she looked at me she goes you
know what I'm talking about I know what
the pain and I know how I deal with it
and I use cannabis she doesn't want to
get rid of the pants and you can't get
rid of pain pain is what we call
manageable but when you're using opiates
you get rid of it that's why you're
chasing paper because pain never goes
away when it didn't with something
that's chronic and and something it's
called being able to manage your pants
and that's what cannabis does for me
every day and you guys see it all the
time it's amazing dude
you've trashed the [ __ ] out of this bowl
John and I said I said it was dirty so
what happened is I needed to do a DAB
no DC cleaner no nothing so it got a
little dirty but I see I didn't I didn't
chose it Susan pretty good it's there's
some Chas but it's in the weirdest place
it's at the top of the bowl but it's
good we're a huge town we're gonna get
it all along and then worry about your
chairs even opening up the container of
hash mode these are the terpenes and and
our eyes letting up she's looking at me
I'm like that's what took my pain away
when you showed up in the hospital it's
true they took hope I can't believe I
was three years ago three years ago and
I want like that like oh that's what
held me in her eyes lit up they really
made her daughter look at me she goes I
can see that I'm go this is what's so
important when it comes to pain
management and fighting disease and
conditions
is the Terps the Terps term do the Terps
I'm about you
for you
how is it only 23 degrees Fahrenheit it
is active if we put this about you know
it's more like a tea fern I don't
actually have a cow that's Kate we got
that class cool right here you don't
have a carb cap okay well here you go
[Applause]
yeah we can move it around a little
better how about for the low temp for
the win
there you go
we can hit you got put a little bit more
[Music]
I don't understand why it's reading the
temperature so incorrectly it shouldn't
be reading it at 24 degrees Celsius 92.9
Fahrenheit
91 degrees Fahrenheit okay clean it
how was that you know how I was just
talking about pain control and how the
flavors up and the flavonoids in the did
you can without post that they just
recently found out that they have found
out that the flavonoids in cannabis
certain flavonoids a and B or I can't
think of an April is known about that
for some years now here tonight but I
think the best part about is is that
they've now put it on paper it's 800
times more stronger than an aspirin
like a whole [ __ ] painkiller coming
on the market Oh natural I know we get
very little from cannabis but I
guarantee with the massive amounts of
cannabis
we're gonna have [ __ ] [ __ ] into this
[ __ ] [ __ ] people
[ __ ] aspirin [ __ ] tylenol get rid of
that pharmacy because look out now so
callous is right up your ass right now
ah gonna remember to take a big old down
yeah which one do you want jeez I
haven't even broken off probably I'll
just pull some of this out or something
put it in yet I gotcha we're at eight
hundred and thirty degrees Fahrenheit
I'm gonna love this I open up one of
these containers the other day and it
had a bunch of terms on it and I got all
of my fingers and my buddy goes here
just put it right underneath your stash
here oh my god I smell Terps all [ __ ]
day and then after pulling off him like
[ __ ] there's a cop right there when he
stuns me in my nose don't be pushing
this will be called dunking this is how
you dab your friend like a donk it's a
DAB it's dropped just got to get it in
there oh yeah you can even smell it and
I was talking about when I opened up my
kiss - yes - me taste that actually I
can taste the rosin so it was really
nice as opening up and talking about the
terpenes and when I actually just gave
her a little smell and her eyes lighting
up I just the whole room and then almost
sounds like I could smell it over here
and it's kinda like a big party started
happening in the room everybody is like
in the Terps it was good it was very
good moment in time and I'm glad to have
been able to share a bowl with you here
like dude seriously yeah I think we're
gonna go do a bit more of a serious sesh
maybe even crush some food because we've
got time to wait before we end up going
in our so yeah traffic's shitty so we're
gonna catch you soon in another Park
near another Beach at a restaurant I
don't know we're gonna we'll be doing
this with our heads back and forth kind
of thing sometimes we'll line up and
other times it'll be a little off and
then other times it might just be like
one of these let's go
hey guys we just came out of car
Darrow's one of my favorite restaurants
right there sorry I'm holding my hand
kind of funny I've got hash in it I
should probably put that down put that
hash down there we go
I lose a little bit there oh I did look
at that saved saved yes you save all the
hash here so Johnny's just we're doing a
little bit of public puffing as we like
to call it you've seen us at the
airports nine hundred ninety degrees so
I'm showing John all the temp tech so
we're checking out nine hundred degrees
it's your temperature John go ahead and
hit it nine hundred you know when I left
inside of it so much of these in the DC
community I know crateros
well you better go get it do you tab
first and then go get it
where'd you leave it I left it at the
table why I didn't see it was just
sitting there as they probably won't see
it up and running all right well that's
a little bit of DC cleaner you're good
you're good no I would hit that right
around six eighty you're good
Johnny be hitting dabs in public with
literally many many many people walking
by well as gonna be blows out his tab
this is the cannabis normalizer right
here with Johnny be cannabis
we can you know what you're gonna be
able to clean that without the 10 M er
because it's a perfect temp job
and that's the that's the joy of using
the temp tech USA that I knew you would
appreciate I do like the temp tech
because you're not actually using a
timer right it's giving an exact
temperature so it's nice it's it's
really really really nice and like you
saying you know it's nice look these
ones in particular we got like the wood
ones how hot was she 420 degrees still
nice I'd like to 420 all right well go
run and get your DC glass cleaner if you
need it I'll wait for you I need the
money
go hobble hobble forth John Coble Forest
there goes my good brother Johnny be
very very good human being
definitely one of my favorite people
should have seen him today explaining
how to use cannabis as a medicine
just being really really open and
awesome with this woman that we met
today to share this information and I
love it I'm stoked to call John a friend
he is a good dude and I'm even more
stoked to be sharing a few bowls with
him out here in the cold harbor area of
Vancouver that's the ocean right behind
us and there's a lot of yachts and stuff
that are right behind this as well so
I'm gonna wait for John to come back but
maybe get maybe I'll get the pipe ready
for the next dam and I have to put the
camera down to do that though alright so
Johnny v I'm gonna pass the camera over
to ye it's kind of like to see well here
everybody going by on bikes and stuff
like that it's very busy and very public
but
you know what's the best thing about
cannabis is people really don't give a
[ __ ] okay people don't hear some people
might but you know what
[Music]
it's not stressful
I think something hideous catch me oh
look at that I got it up to 900 degrees
perfect this job do you have here I'm
just gonna take a quick dab and then
then we'll call it a day here what do we
got we got 680 degrees
it's like this 680 I'm gonna throw both
of these in I'm gonna throw this one in
- yeah
this works really well as a car top got
low-tempo thank you
I would really love doesn't that carp
tap doesn't it work well nice little
effect down
I think she was a little carrots what
was going on she to do the double
headshot
it smells so trippy like just the flavor
sitting here and I can guarantee like
it's just the smell is so beautiful I'm
gonna give it one more little shot so
you could see and that's just so nice
though what we do
[Music]
just chill just give it a little shot
no shot
love the little slinger all right you
know that's why I like bringing he's a
king works well he's Easy Street
I know I hadn't seen him in so long I
was just like I should just buy that
but I was going to my Orca so I told him
I'd have to grab it on the way back in
that same day not later you were like
sent me a picture in your like look at
the pi PI bond I was like [ __ ] you TV
[ __ ] when you bought this pipe super
stoked well deserved this is one of my
favorite spots here just right at
Cordero's with you bad we've been coming
here for so long just chilling here
right on the beach it's not the beach
that's the waterfront beside this is
actually the marina isn't the marina
right here we've got the boats are all
nice
definitely beautiful that was great I
don't know
all in all kind of a good day I'd say
this was kind of like a little pup
Wednesday we had a couple of pups we we
helped someone else just help someone
out we helped change we gave a whole
different life to look at well that's
what cannabis does you know like if here
if you if you know the information that
you have access then it's kind of like
your duty to do those and past life like
she's gonna be that now oh she will be
he's gonna be that for me she's gonna
help so many people yes and that's the
best thing about it is once you it's
like once you show someone what's going
on they just want to show everybody else
that Paul did because I just want to
tell the world how much it helped me and
that's what we do we do this let me get
you in that shot we're gonna say goodbye
here right away but as always a great
pleasure hanging out with Johnny be here
in the City of Vancouver just yeah I
guess this is our puff Wednesday even
though it's probably not gonna go up on
a Wednesday you'll probably see this
like by tomorrow or the next day maybe
even later today I don't know Saturday
but it's a puff Saturday Saturday just
chilling relaxing
whip up seven days a week all right
may the full mouth bless your bowl
sooner than later peace out everybody
[Music]