hey
B why Tim feel good
[Music]
me man home man
real the purpose after the weed to the
mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I've been traveling to kingst
about 20 M hours sleeping on J like the
clock fresh vegetation with trees and
with flowers off
[Music]
stop
me I make pass pass
[Music]
pass pause that
now after the we that keeps me go
the purpose after the weed that to the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine on the road
there'll be some cops setting up them
PL
man we
me interv in my bra St that and behind
your scene me and my team have another
25 smoke it
[Music]
clean my eyes
now pass pass
[Music]
pass
make and
then pass pass
[Music]
I will support
you Che your discrimination times and
you will support
me Comfort my heart soul and mind yeah I
support
you go where we
go yeah
prophecy yes