[Music]
all right well I got to say I definitely
like this venue better than the last one
agreed Outdoors dude good to be in your
backyard and obviously
dude Buck Marcel angler fish um ready
trapping air trapping work I mean the
whole fish around the can and the and
the the teeth and the the the ratachello
marble work for the eyes it's I have to
say one of the most stunning pieces each
time I see it I have a new appreciation
for it it
really yeah you know the lines on this
piece work yep no it's just
unbelievable such a cool thing yeah the
the the trapped opal chips in here and
under here and here under here a lot of
people haven't seen before you can't
really see unless you're like holding it
I could definitely see um Buck if you're
listening to this um I could see you uh
at one point in time adding a small
mouthpiece here for an exhale Tu imagine
you have your
inhale and then you've got your exhale
where you go and it follows it along the
spine and it blows it out of the mouth
of the fish I mean how sick would that
be that' be pretty sick I did it earlier
when we hit a bowl I blew my smoke
through the back chamber here and it
came out but not as nice as it would
come out if they actually had it set up
yeah so that was breathing the smoke so
it's breathing the smoke yeah such a
beautiful piece man yeah I love this
look at that tiny little drop of water
on the tooth kind of made it look
different I was like that's not right
kind of cool too
it's just perfect RPP the yellow the the
faint yellow um in the blue is beautiful
this is a de Darkness pull and they've
just pulled it out further to get these
these different shades okay in in the
have we loaded you one up yet let me
load you one up some fresh frozen 9
Micron Astro
B shit's melting in the sun
yes ah there you go oh thank you
very good I'm going to grab the camera
and show them up close for this
one go
ahead it disappears like
magic
yeah ah that is such a incredible piece
of
glass always a
pleasure hey I think we have another
amazing piece of glass we're going to
hit up next let's go get it say bye to
the
angler you know to take one of the most
uh in my opinions just like it it has to
be technically difficult to pull and
attach glass like that Angler fish with
the technique of Marcel's ratachello
work with the air trapping in it I just
have an idea that it's an extremely
technical pipe and then to be taken back
you know more than 10 years like uh
almost 15 years to fish 2000 which my
favorite this piece could have even been
done I believe in 1999 yeah it was it
was it was made for the New Year's show
of fish and it has the fish marble and
whatnot and the five uh uh
Dolphins right the five Dolphins from
what I believe Marcel had told me was
they each represented a member of fish
and then um he had also he also had um
the sound man and then maybe this was
the light guy CU Paul langu do was you
know he was a very important member of
the band as was Chris corota for
experience for the lights yeah for the
whole experience of that show so cool
well as Marcel when he talked to me
about this piece when I first got it off
a number of years ago um he explained it
that at the time in the whole community
in the borrow scene he hadn't or there
hadn't been the tools and some of the
techniques needed to accomplish some of
the Visions oh yeah that that they had
that's what I was going to say that pipe
that we just hit yeah this pipe
represents absolutely yeah I agree and
to like this is one of my most prized
pieces of art that I have in my
collection um yeah well I have a history
with it I love it yeah you were the
first person to ever ever have it
brought to brought up after it was made
yeah Marcel brought it to my house and
he uh he cleaned it up after the fish
2000 show at the seino Indian
reservation there in Florida the one
that where it went around for like 2
hours Alligator Alley even longer yeah
it was a 7 and a half hour set he was
tripping mad balls and he was like oh I
was pretty sure it was going to come
back but he just send it out into the
Trippers and it would
just he always came back and so he I
remember specifically this for a fact he
came up and he was like the only thing
this piece is missing is your Vibe yes
he was like you weren't at the show with
us and I guess I had taken Marcel to
maybe his first fish show which was I I
believe 9999 in Vancouver where I
miracled which was uh basically giving a
free ticket uh 18 of my my friends into
their first fish show a miracle to all
18 of them that's awesome three rows of
six seats [ __ ] that's awesome yeah close
to the stage and then in the end I
didn't even sit with any of them I ended
up taping the show and I had to go down
on the floor and be in the taper section
but uh uh he was in the group Marcel was
Miracles so I think we should hit this I
think we
should what uh what do you want to Puff
I mean what do you want to Puff is that
a why there so much selection more
astroy it's true it's true let's just
hit the
Astro and this though is this the cured
stuff yeah oh yeah that stuff's The
Taste on that it's like ridiculous it is
ridiculous at this though look at the
color on yeah this one's Prett really
Oh I thought it was for
you ah yes beautiful beautiful piece
want me to carve me all right you want
me to light you sure that would be great
in the least let me drive your
beeline I'm going to build up your flame
a little bit so you're not left hanging
can be a little bit tricky um hitting
with a be line if you're outside in the
room not that I think you're all idiots
but it's definitely like build up a big
flame before you hit out of a certain
piece particularly this one which has uh
what I would say um the last of the
flower bowls this pipe definitely has a
deep punched flower bowl yep um
it's Unique it's different there's no B
you know there's no um pull Bowl this is
just a punched Bowl right into the can
with a tube such beautiful die Crow work
I know yeah the PS are just
so it you want to
yeah yeah do I want to do you I just
can't believe how good this hash looks
in the sun I know it's so lovely and it
is really oh good we just 90 Micon it
all day 90 M con every time a unicorn
dies every time we hit this well let's
kill some unicorn unicorn Killers today
is going to be a unicorn oh it's a
massacre it's a Slaughter let's see what
do we got
[Music]
here
a little more about the pipe though from
what Marcel is saying is um the piece is
sort of
the creative experience where he
um had at the fish show where he
envisioned the the technique and some of
the tools tools that he was going to
need to procure to be able to advance
the the borrow craft and the and the the
pipe baking industry um him and Jason
and everybody when they were doing
Washington and um the the yeah and the
the Dolphins represent the band that
created
the pathway the highway of creation
creativity and this wrap is itself the
creative explosion in genius
everyone's surfing on
yeah let's go up so I mean it's a it's a
really historic piece it's genuinely a
piece of art I love it it's Dolphins we
should go smoke with it on the ocean
today yeah we should actually I have a
case of fits in that's a good idea let's
go hit the boat yeah that in like the
octopus yeah yeah the big the octopus
Phoenix fun too yeah we're going to go
hit the boat see you guys out on the
boat
ocean
[Music]
he