[Music]
hey guys what's going on welcome to
puffs Wednesday straight moving here
second Wednesday in a row dude we made
it Johnny B's in the house that's Johnny
F and B for for those of you that don't
know I'm not gonna be dropping an f-bomb
today the way I did last episode [ __ ]
dropped 20 more knee well I made a game
out of it if you watch the video it said
take a dab every time I say yeah I know
right here pretty girl okay so today's
episode is a quick it's a short one
we're pretty excited we've headed down
to to support level well this is where I
grew up actually we're in Port Coquitlam
right now we're about 50 minutes away
from each of our houses and the reason
we came here is because I said to Johnny
is there any like cash or solvent less
oil available in the
you know stores yet and so he made a few
phone calls I got on the phone and I'm
like calling around and of course I
called my old buddy right and he was
English like we worked at the Green
Cross aside right like he's like he was
the hardcore jabbering I'm like dude I'm
looking for some legal sounds like dude
I'm gone she we just got to never go
away I think that's why I'm calling up
I'm making a call right now because this
is this is just like that this is she
want to talk no more well we're gonna go
talk to him soon so what I wanted to
tell you guys was I'm pretty sure it's
gonna be Whistler medicated hash it's
been pressed into rosin and is now a
solvent less oil so obviously listen
we're not gonna be commenting too much
in the store at the price because this
is the legal regime it's gonna be
outrageous buying stuff like this from
the black-market cost eighty to ninety
dollars wholesale so I can only imagine
what it's gotta cost in there we're not
gonna make it yeah we're not gonna make
the whole purpose of the video but
you'll be shocked we'll show you but
yeah we're hearing but Port Coquitlam
we've got the cannabis store right here
and the funniest thing is if Johnny
moves out of the way a little bit you'll
see there's a policeman right there
break there there's a cop part parked
right here so as I pulled into the
parking lot to buy some legal hash oil
I see cops and I don't even have to
worry about it so this is one of the
good things look John was even saying
when we got here that when he was 14 15
he used to sell or just down the street
and I'm sure at that point in time
it was scarier you had worried about
cops you didn't want to get your [ __ ]
taken away and so this is kind of
accessible to those like John and I who
don't have access to to rosin on a
regular basis but now they can come and
kind of get it if they're if they're a
multi-millionaire and they can afford it
well you can see all the cars revving
here are like BMWs and Jack right so
we're gonna head it I'm gonna grab the
camera we're gonna go in we're gonna be
you in a bit
let's do it all right so burb here we
are and our get our host welcome to Berg
this is beautiful
just avoid any and all people oh this
looks good this looks good
[Music]
so did really good like yeah first time
in the bird nice man just take a sick
chronic shot over the cultivars and you
know that letting you know what it is
and the terpene at least a couple of the
the yeah the dominance is usually what
will display this something has a high
percentage I have seen a public three
turkey cards but it's relatively rare
okay it's nice to see just like I
haven't been in too many of the legal
shops now we're trying to do it a little
differently a little better inform they
give us a lot of literature to read so
we know our our trophy profiles on our
strange types beautiful chocolate
[Music]
like these good jobs and where you get a
customer
popcorn smell smell the absolutely
they're a little bit different than your
make sure they're still secure Oh
beautiful beautiful wrap everything we
keep yes let's see what it looks like
looks pretty cushy how is it it's decent
91 can cross ak-47 purple punch looks
nice do the wedding web browser before
us purple punch cross wedding cake
see this looks really good man
absolutely well we take pride in being
the upper echelon we're trying to
provide for all those black market users
that are still looking for the quality
that they're used to purchase right
everything was different helping me
every day with doing the stuff like that
[Applause]
you know for me the industry that stuff
so we're gonna start
absolutely I mean the focus went from
different strands from different dance
to stray any specific needs now that I'm
not allowed to speak on a medical half
but we still provide that knowledge to
our connoisseur
Oh Khurana sure 100 just see where
explained to me that you actually went
after those Cronus restraints League we
look up we test his solar year the water
to me means like crap and I know the
first thing you said means they hey do
you have any Vova Don absolutely because
you own a new needed moisture to do this
cross monster looks a killer to anything
my broken coast is next level that of
course same dry central 21-day curing
process so how was it
on a bi-weekly level we want to express
yes June fecl DB and federal and
legislation and provincial legislation
have to choose a certain camera destroy
all the product the one part of my job I
must say the word hate word but I don't
like this Frank Ross on what your
definition of destroy is mixing with
kitty litter and we can put it on the
road I'm gonna slowly make my way over
to the rest of these buds but yours eat
your tacos we are we're gonna get to the
rosin but they've got so many more
flowers
Gold just came out for flowers from
Whistler we have to pull gold this is
some organic pierces through the
Acapulco bull the reference is right
that in the past it was quite delicious
that's her pain and just an OG you
telling me certain things I'm like you
know what it's good I'm gonna buy it and
that's my job be sure we have the best
availability for what's available these
days on these you drop the label are
nobody right from leaving like we call
the skills or the gray market we never
call it the block ecology grant
no absolutely the noise has been a
trademark okay I have one of these boxes
very positive transition for us we're
still educating everybody on a daily
basis providing some of the best seen on
this market really yeah okay we're gonna
buy it quality but some of the best
there for sure good good good job dude
I'm glad to you know of course
technologies guys so it's neat to see
you know the machinery that were selling
is now making product available it's
super positive and I mean now they're
coming out with new SKUs all the time
Whistler this week coming forward as we
Tammy Cindy Jackson of course the Cindy
99 the original mother of the jack hair
that crawls back in with the jack so
it's gonna be really hopefully really
delicious I haven't had a chance to test
it from well-being
cutest Ranger game what's being movies
and that's happening before anybody else
see you are educating them absolutely my
job not only building relationships with
a licensed producers providing the best
quality we can for a consumer base at
the same time educational staff and
clientele as well so well the responsive
by some probably can get hi Johnny
excellent all right so Johnny B's up at
the counter and
[Music]
profiling is a pretty confident with my
the rock star yeah really great products
here the only actual true concentrate
available on today's regulatory
recreational market it's the first one
we see and we're buying to ever buying
it because you know why because that's
what we do mix add not only child group
broham proof adult proof really tough
packaging focusing on the genetics but
having the tools and using the properly
are two different things and they do a
great curing for understand the purple
punch remember that in the hospital I
spell that perfect project in my hand
exactly does that want it so sadly I
have been wanting to try the purple
punch since the day well I'm glad you
get now of course the most have made the
best known with Clementine famosa cross
punch amazing genetic
you want to try some of that as well
jealous I do wonderful and I'm gonna get
the chocolate absolutely that's a number
different variations see the best thing
of all is he knows my flavors he knows
what I like and he knows what's made me
tick he's he was there when I was the
beginning when I was eating the
chocolate before me but I went pushes
the concentrates and then when I started
smoking to sip when I met you rose mean
around the whole time so he's got a nose
what kind of works for Johnny be in a
way take pride in being able to offer up
the best service we can as you'll see a
lot of other dispensaries focus on
having a tablet or we're working on the
Digital side of things what we like to
work with everyone as an individual
focus on their needs directly walking in
here with 50 lakhs and comfortable like
to experience you know kinda like what
we're used to big legislation to change
we can sell our apparel but great things
happening already in 2020 it's gonna be
a fantastic
well we start processing this year for
our company so hopefully we'll be
producing some products for you're
excited about that as well I know you
guys found or what's the upper echelon
as well so really that's what I love
hearing buddy seen the upper echelon
like that's one thing we always talked
about was having that killer
that place where you can go and get that
that quality that we've been looking for
we mean screaming porn in the industry
right now Johnny and Carrie were looking
at
[Music]
the car take a look it's a write-off
it's right off including Amex beautiful
visa business whenever you're ready
gentlemen should be prompted for you
there
so there's your cannabis tax stamp yes
the excites number varied bringing
everything will have to pull those off
maybe really nicely John and I got about
30 Soria will send it to a stuntman Sam
oh I have one yeah he wants perfect one
season with crippled ones in the very
gates from each province I have met at
Oba so far from thank you love a bag
that wasn't packaged very long ago so
it's definitely back what I'm really
really can really focus because
[Music]
it's going to do technically the better
we found with the proper moisture
content of course my father's sick on
AIDS all the time being so important
John me with with the flame I'm super
stoked about
we're gonna find Sarah's it's legal for
us to use this okay so I can return this
if I don't like it fortunately you don't
like it you told me really appreciate
all right Johnny B let's get this hat
let's get this party started but we're
back and Jon's buying more stuff I had
to get chocolate so this is a tweed
chocolate bar let me check this out know
what I mean he's sold out within because
they happen on the first day many many
SKUs to be dropped over the next few
weeks and we're really excited about in
the meantime he's gonna call me now in
the burgh throwing out the cash now you
don't see this this much this is very
rare get yourself a chance to steal King
now I appreciated the chocolate that I
ate markets dosage I am fine in the
nanotechnology especially the beverage
beverage lines becoming readily
available that the emulsification
program the way it exists with our own
bloodstream and are under a new
endocannabinoids system for our group we
make it that the tent will be more like
a 30 or 40 milligram that people are
used to is that they've been told this
is 40 milligrams no sure just wait until
when you fit when those companies move
away from liposome based technology and
they get into mesial which is just a
different structure of surfactant that
goes around the molecule it's even more
bioavailable it's actually kind of
frightening I think it's why it'll be
fine with 10 milligram doses people just
don't understand how efficient we're
about to get regional they're eating
like thousand milligrams choco bars that
maybe aren't really decarboxylate and
not really like the most bioavailable
and they think I can do a thousand
milligrams so I should try like 100 or
50 milligrams of just something that's
actually been properly welcome 896 my
friend than plenty you know what a
high-end chocolate bar crush 225 so
infuse chocolate or Undertown you sweet
how many em jeez I don't know probably
eat the hard things like a hundred total
or something
I think the masses
ten milligram per per unit
total so I'm gonna have to eat a lot of
sugar you are mother try there are some
vegan friendly and some sugar-free
xylitol right becoming available over
the mo kio I got to come back
then there goes the man all right so we
are back now if you can't really tell we
are at the world-famous
cactus Club Cafe yeah this is one of our
favorite restaurants but we're right you
know because of this ridiculous scenario
in Canada where you can buy cannabis you
just can't [ __ ] do it anywhere
it's hoping anyone know I fed your house
so you're legally allowed to smoke but
where people are allowed to smoke
cigarettes they should be good it's over
ten feet away from the door we've got a
little table here set up I got the ten
tag I got the mother ship Johnny B let's
open our Rosen
you're gonna need to crack that if you
want
crack that
there you go oh we're saving tax stamps
for Skype man Sam that one's for you
dude man Sam see you know see this we do
things for people you don't wanna be
afraid right away right so apparently
this is some high-tech
okay so this this is cool show that to
the camera up close okay so there you go
you gonna press the side and it's gonna
slide over it so real up close like so
much so there's the case now this Steven
stays in the case it doesn't come out of
the case for whatever reason I don't
know if this is just some hilarious
ridiculous scenario I was told he goes
he's like oh my god I just turned it are
you ready does it turn if you're turned
into some are we doing this together
there's an opening that isn't opening
let's check it out well we'll let Johnny
deal with it and then I'll give him a
hand if you need please keep John I fix
either within the box
push down and twist open I hear it
that's fine that's fine
that's straight fire I'm actually pretty
surprised that I smelt it right away
I'm actually pretty surprised that the
beautiful color the beautiful oh my
[Music]
you cook the dabber there dude it looks
great surprising actually we're here let
me get a
we're going you got some three matches
oh my god that's that's he's got the
iPhone 11 so it's definitely got better
pictures
great
Johnny be it's a [ __ ]
you can take your picture but there you
go now you guys see I've got the problem
because of the alright let's do this
63 750 yeah
look at that you smell that
these hitting rips
dude the first legal broadened in Canada
have you ever seen two people so happy
like this month time your faith I was
waiting for you to tell me what it was
like okay so now the flavor
we cultivar we hidden here
but they must sell it as a cultivar
don't they
solvent free full spectrum cannabis
extract eye teeth I taste my taste
don't mention it right there
I taste nuking in there and something
else that's the flavor
well I'm about to join you and see what
kind of flavor I can get off
look at that wall and wrong
it's getting that happen it is the hard
part it
No
you expect you like it almost
well I mean this isn't oil it isn't
listed I didn't really know what I
expected I hold that it would be
something that because it was you know
fairly expensive
it would be and I I trusted your friend
you've known him for a long time Martis
was trying to make sale and if he says
it was fire I was like okay it's fire
but I didn't know it was gonna be fire
and he's like right away when I called
his like dude you guys are gonna
I'm hidden yeah babe the color looks
great the flavor is there
the taste is there I'm definitely gonna
have to Double Down
yeah I'll get it Double Down you got to
take a huge I didn't want to get that
it's like
where did he get this to hit
of his life from legal I mean not the
head of his life anyone he prays that
she's in the try something he's ever
troppo which is legal
whistler mountain bubble which was
awesome
oh yeah that's yeah that's desi it's all
part because you said dad
it was dang
one more for Johnny be one more bubble
be
so yeah it's kind of wild but now
there's always going to be a division is
it extremely expensive of course it is
are we gonna hope and and and make sure
that things become less expensive yeah
that's the plan it's definitely not
ideal for people I mean don't get me
wrong right now the black market price
of rosin is really too expensive for
most people to purchase it between 50
and 80 dollars a gram there's not enough
power there's not a lot that's which one
yeah yeah but there's house rosin as
well for those prices oh but it still
you can get it is what I'm saying yes
and what I'm saying is it's not super
affordable for people to be able to buy
that we'd love to see it at $10 a gram
now this was this was almost $200 a gram
but we did it for a video we wanted to
see a what was available be I gotta say
it's definitely great Ross I mean this
rosin will get you lit time and time
again I'm not sure you know I won't be
going and paying $200 a gram for every
gram for Roz and I spend that's
absolutely outrageous but
you can't blame the store you can blame
the government and you can blame the
system that's in place right now but the
bottom line is
being able to walk into a store like
that and pick and choose your edible
your flower and your solvent was hash
oil to me was a pretty cool experience
and a glad that we got to do it Johnny
sorry
yeah DVD 0 CBB
tell the camera what's this it says here
it's just total THC 650 point 7 mg total
THC 670 THC 5 5 point 5 point 3
milligram and we
we fly
I'm kind of curious right now
more curious about actually I'm going to
do it
maybe a little warmer of temperature
maybe even hotter I like I like a hot
down then we're going to take you guys
into the cactus Club we're going to
probably won't be able to film too much
but we'll show you guys the food if
you're from BC or anywhere in Canada
there's there's a bunch of these places
across Canada I think Manitoba Toronto
Calgary 8:23 pop yeah yeah you want to
go maybe around 7:00 7:10 is always used
to be my favorite but 680 seems to be
them if by the time you put that in and
it says something you see how fast it's
dropping you're already at 690 the
trucks fast
there we go be hitting that dab like he
should be
dude I'm super surprised at the quality
I would not okay I'm upset with the
price but I'm pretty stoked on the
[ __ ] phone
you know that's crazy if you could just
buy like this
that was sling some Instagram rasa
let's listen see that's a if that's a
sort of foreshadowing of things to come
maybe Canada's gonna have some decent
product on the shelves I know personally
that I'm going to make do and do my best
with my company to process and make
available you know beautiful resins and
beautiful hashes for the for the
Canadian marketplace
well I mean it's on us much smaller part
of that than you might think I want to
say we I appreciate
you know what
why don't I never and I thought this
would be the day that I would
yeah well there you gotta dance let's
score there you got a dad I never
thought I never thought
it's tricky so on January 5th
today is the six On January 6 2020 I got
to try it when we will draw first time
that's history of - I'll never forget
this thing
that's pretty cool
you know I mean when legalization
happened and I went to the store and it
was all herb I was just laying Oh
legalization
and it does look the fast so listen to
this link
I'm not I like how it stays in the box
we're heading in really
this one oh really morning that's
awesome
[Music]
it's tast
you there okay we're coming out of the
cactus Club do you ever couldn't sit in
here and pop this would be perfect so
we're coming out it's still daytime I
guess we could look you know it's not
much of a puff Wednesday if we only have
three pups
oh we're popping so we got to have
another leg pop we'll go have another
little puff over at our spot over here I
think spar and then you know what I have
to
where you going I give the winner the
scat
like
hopefully there's a bigot tall stories
about getting pretty big are you big and
tall that's okay
dude you shred the pounds like nobody's
business I've seen you be all big and
then all of a sudden not way anyway
exactly you always got to eat man all
right
look there's our table John and you know
turned on some lights I don't think
these lights were here you know they may
not set up the camera maybe let's set up
the camera okay we're back we just made
a delicious meal boom makes fairly dark
here you might not be able to see us
that well it's better than the under the
bridge one right this is what you get
and wait a second here
don't touch it with your fingers John
here's the devil
let's get the show on the road got a
look around literally at a parking lot
but this is the ridiculousness of the
Canadian
situation now not only are we
recreational users but we also use
cannabis medicinal and so you think
there will be some responsibility to
people who use it medicinally to have a
place to use it a simple place allows
I'm goin sign have a really nice that we
get up 10 nice scotches but I have to
come outside
here at 960
box is found
we've enclosed about
sounds like the good one yeah we're a
little bit dark I get it but hey we're
doing the best we can maybe if we went
back here we'd be in the light I in the
light yet yeah a little bit a little bit
better
I'll have to deal with me in the dark
how's that
well Whistler definitely
you know another nice thing that we
really haven't mentioned too much about
this experience is that
this is organic that this whistle this
was organic flower that was grown
probably by some of my friends at
Whistler Medical good friends that I've
known for many years that grew prior to
the legal regulations in the black
market there oh gee peeps and it's nice
to see them growing this beautiful
organic flour and then getting it turned
into hash getting it turned into rosin
it's it's not a bad situation at all I'm
gonna hit ice and water pressure someone
sent out
with John Conway goes wow he goes with
the regulation the law
meet and walk meet ice and water heat
pressure you guys are like gonna kill it
yeah and you know what does he go by
your Marshalls love it love it
I'm surprised I'm just I'm happy to
bring this with you guys the up this
show
we've talked about how we have seen
getting beginning epic - cross into
legalization 2.0 on first day it's not
bad
not a bad hit for the first day
first day for us any way that we bother
to go to a store and buy I am stoked
about the flavors I got I'm not full
price with qualities of the rosin and
the flavors and the high that I'm
getting from it is exactly what we're
looking for acid for patients and for
people who are looking for for what they
need like it's there I can't wait to try
the chocolate on that block apparently I
need about 10 on them because
really don't even know what that would
be like we can make with it
chocolate but it was the experience and
I had to get to the experience not how
to really know what was going on I made
even test the water activity inside that
chocolate because it can't be above 85
apparently yeah I'm just kind of curious
right so if some of that new is stuff
that we do something now go take a
really good look at that so I got to see
that one way is yeah 420 heat master see
that was I was a good puff is there a
hasty put sort of interrupt but I think
I think that was pop Wednesday man that
was Wednesday we're not done we're
probably gonna puff off camera here for
a little bit while we head in our own
directions but we pulled one more off
thanks to Johnny bead being persistent
today finding a buddy who had a store
who knew there where we could get some
nice rosin and the first of it on the
bar trip did the first of it on the
market like come on I was pretty cool it
was pretty package December like 13
very cool yeah so I mean this is freshly
made
even being able to buy one
six of them six of them but we know
we're a couple awesome
oh the full Mel blesses your bowl sooner
than later everyone
[Music]
and why