[Music]
hey guys bubble man and Johnny B here on
a Happy Puff Wednesday we have uh we've
gotten down here to the cchq the bcmp
whatever you want to call it and I guess
we got the second floor Vapor Lounge
private private we opened it we opened
it exactly so we have got it all set up
but we wanted to take you to this
beautiful little place called La Tacoria
that's right across the street
phenomenal phenomenal tacos with the OG
um uh uh the jaros the the well the
sauces killer I'm talking about the pop
that is um uh not sweetened with sugar
but sweetened with sugar cane I'm going
say the cane [ __ ] I'm just blasted right
now we're having fun here you know what
that's what we do on a puff Wednesday so
let's head over to laaco Ria and uh get
some
tacos Johnny
B Med
one on the
medtainer
Lako he uh this is the spot right
here all right
Lako so did you see that that's that's
where we're isn't that amazing I can't
wait I'm so happy favorite place let's
let's do let get
line it's not even a lineup you like
that it's about to get a lineup it's for
sure we're fantastic it's good we're
really hungry even with and we're
filming our little TV show that we there
I grabbed some uh uh oh what are the uh
quesadillas with the mushrooms is it
mushroom and kale still I two musroom
and
kale which one's the
ti the spicy ones oh my god I've been
waiting for that one for so long yeah
yeah yeah let's take let's take an order
that and then we'll grab a vegetarian
taco or sorry the tuna
atun and one FR charos you do four yeah
I'm going to do two tacos and one
quesadillas okay the9 be on
perfect oh look at the Jer
to that's what you looking at that we
just talking about yeah the sugar can
stuff yeah I'm very happy about that
yeah you going to get one I'm I'm I'm
going to get four tacos oh nice I'm
going to get a beef chicken pork perfect
well look at that now here comes all the
people one beef yes one chicken yes one
pork
yes one fish I'm not a fish guy I'm
going try the fish we'll do all four the
doing all four awesome I'm going to do
all
four
joh and then I also get a mango Jito I
was going for mango and a mandarin Jito
I'm doing a
mango yes mango for
me so good oh wait a second do you know
why this is the legit why because you've
got the killer
tacos the the music and the jaros and
the people and the people of course the
killer people
this is the best place to
eat how's the jorito Johnny
B oh
my I feel like I'm in Jamaica right
now feel like I'm in Jamaica a Mexican
restaurant I know you're awesome too
feel like
Jama there's the atun tun Taco the
mushroom
[Music]
and thank you
thank you Johnny D with the winning
plate that's definitely a win take it I
got to grab these little horses over got
a little
[Music]
sof oh my
go so delicious I the
so amazing winning we're going to eat
this down and we're going to head over
to the bcmp and have a mad session puff
Wednesday
Styles I'm like cut this one in half
going ining
a amazing brand for the US Johnny Be is
going to town on those
tacos it's hard to beat
[Music]
L really check this
out wow that was amazing John I just
amazing
amazing like amazing let's head out of
[Music]
here did you see the heavy [ __ ] glass
they have in here they got heavy glass
at this t look at a let's head over and
uh get our session going on PO Wednesday
Style thank you thank
youe there's just weed everywhere in
this uh block right there more weed what
we got cross town
dispensary doing their thing selling we
gotp and we're going over there let's do
[Music]
that the bubble Manti r on some of the
car really yeah right there wonder who
that could
be right on the
dash fantastic Alex I did
not but mostly cuz I don't know him
don't
I I don't hang out down here too often
but I have been coming down here for 20
years
priv awesome you want to go grab it
[Music]
I he's got the keys thanks dude thank
you so much hooking us up with the
private access into the lounge they got
their little dab bar setup right here
walk myself in pot
TV
very very
good I guess we're going to be set up in
the corner here today for a little puff
Wednesday and you can always play games
when you come down to the
cchq they got all
their little zones and this is where
Johnny B and I are going to be hanging
out today so let's get this puff
Wednesday started damn
straight all right dude those were
delicious that's amazing good
yummies oops like to be able to see see
what's going on
there indeed
indeed rny B Bubble Man puff
Wednesday we just came up with that
right now that's our new thing we're
going to copy Remo we're going to point
and say no I'm not that well good to see
you buddy I I I Cheers Cheers great talk
jaros
Jos we had a little SES didn't film it
ran overhead tacos boom we're back we're
doing this I'm squishing very delicious
I have no raws in the morning all right
so I had to um kind of get things ready
you're like what's that swaggy weed you
got actually you know what I'm I'm going
to be honest guys this is a jar of weed
that came out of the fridge it was like
4 months old um I saved like stuff that
I really like and um I'm out you like
the flavor of it I love the flavor so
it's going to squish to be a tasty
treat yeah it's Unique and it's Unique
I've kept it fresh with B while Johnny B
is squeezing out the uh
rosin I am going to hit both of us up
with a little bit of West Coast
concentrate yeah beautiful color on this
untouched sfv OG 90
Micron got a single gram of it right
there and you can just see that it is
absolute
Fire Fire on the Mountain so that's what
we're going to be dabbing t dip bong
ripping [ __ ] Yan on behalf of our
brother d420 K
who's not with us today but with
us in
oops in spirit in
spirit I'm looking for that Jamaican
Sour Diesel because it just tastes so
delicious I got some I know you do I got
some giting you some in Toronto Johnny B
needs some TPS I need some I need some
not just any
some Jamaican turps some crd turps yeah
know absolutely dude it's pretty cool
pretty awesome actually double dipping
so our plan today is um to have a little
session here at the cchq they've been
really nice enough to give us this
entire floor privately so there's no
music playing there's no people in here
whereas upstairs the music's banging
there's tons of people they're playing
pool they're smoking joints they're
doing dabs and really God bless them or
whoever your idea of
Creator ism is spirituality bless them
whatever you want to say job bless them
how about that for doing it and coming
and hanging out while Johnny B literally
squishes the rosin next to me as I'm
about to dab this lovely lovely
L bubble hash dipped in Sour Diesel so
one of the things I've been doing lately
is I have been heating my Banger way
less than usual like heating it barely
at all at all like a 10 Johnny's kind of
tripping out cuz he just did that squish
where you get nothing and you're like
what the [ __ ] [ __ ] just happened just
happened nothing you'll figure it out
maybe let it get a little hotter you
know what I'm I'm on the wrong side I'm
done I'm on the wrong side this is going
to be loud I'll heat this up for a few
seconds and uh we'll have a nice little
dab that's a 10-second
heater well you know we don't have to
heat it up for a minute I mean if you
need to clean it you do if you burnt the
[ __ ] out of it and you need to burn
everything off then yeah you're going to
be required to uh that's a real small
little Banger you got there you like
that little 14 or a little tiny guy
looks even smaller than 14 Just Hits on
there like mine's a 14 is it but it's a
giant Banger yours would go inside
mine
whoa that's like dipping bangers yeah
we're definitely going I have to bong
rip this little rousing chip I can't
believe you just got nothing from that I
I know it used to be my favorite
squishing I think maybe it being in the
fridge for the last three months we
changed the something it's just weird
we're not going to discuss that though
actually maybe we should we should find
out if there is going to be a difference
L I'm taking a look at that I'm I'm
really super stoked I'm going to have to
heat mine up now I'm done here we
go I know what wrong with
me
do we have a bonger for you
yet is that enough I can get you one no
I don't have one yet okay let me let me
sort you out Johnny B being sorted it's
most important part friends got other
friends backs well yeah even as you were
heating that up I wasn't sure I did I
sort something up there something's
going on cuz we want you get properly
dipped
dipping I wait a little bit longer on
that one cuz it's a smaller area the
trick with this guy is it's such a big
surface area you can get these perfect
perfect low temp dabs on it so you
notice how perfectly clean that is and
how mine is completely
destroyed
ding ding you could do that Che cheers
your DB but people cheer beer Ching like
Che Z and I did it one time with our our
mother ships and it was like never again
never never again the the I'll do the
Banger all day long but but not the
mother the mother is like I'm pretty
good to go with that yeah I'm
good there we go
through a nice little hippo
piece well played Johnny B amazing the
taste right flavor oh man it makes me
want to hit another one right away I
mean what else are we going to do I wish
you guys you can't try that Jamaican tur
I'm pretty sure um yeah they definitely
available on Blue River extracts there
you go although they did chop us off at
the knees on our Instagram account Blue
River extracts Canada is now gone wow so
I may try again and register like Blue
River extracts CA or something how about
just Blue River tur dips Blue River TP
dips it's nice to let people know what's
going on but um well the problem is is
with the Instagram and with all these
platforms I mean right away when you're
trying to actually you're trying to I I
see a lot of the accounts being St down
from branding and trying to get new
products out there and the way that
things are being pushed on certain of
these platforms and and really all it
takes is one person to say you know what
I like him it's that simple and it's
that simple so one guy ruined it for
everybody it's kind of unfortunate it is
and it's amazing how those platforms
work it's one more reason not to be mean
and nasty to people on the internet cuz
they just you know it's that one guy
that's going to be like I'm going to go
out of my way and make your life
miserable and it
tastes I was a little bit miserable to
see how got no squish with
this first don't squish try try
again
so there was something that smoked out
of there there there little bit of smoke
in there I saw that too it's weird must
have missed a little area of cleaning it
looks perfect
but so this is nice and moist at least
it's not like John said
moist oh yeah these these low temp dabs
you can take them real quick after
heating it up I like that one more try
on the weed that's been in the freezer
for 4 months in a jar with Bova used to
squish quite nicely I'm pretty sure
you've seen it squish in the past and
now now I'm putting full force on this
sucker used to squish quite nicely I'm
pretty sure you've seen it squish in the
past and now now I'm put full force on
this
sucker I'm thinking that smells amazing
The Taste is so good like CU it's just
like I got that little how clean it was
too like
just yeah it's hard to explain the taste
on those on those beautiful tpin like
the Jamaican Sour Diesel is tasty making
me nervous over there Johnny I know I'm
just
like I didn't get anything from there
last
time I know it was weird it and now now
I've got it on an angle and I squished
it wrong and you can see I squish it on
the outside I didn't get a squish out of
it I completely I'm having no luck here
at all zero zero luck on the squishing
let me load you up another six star I'm
done that's it I'm pring it off let me
load you up another six star what
happened there is is I squished the odor
see what I did no I didn't I squished
half but I'm sure like I'm saying I'm
happy to just sit here and smoke the
literal [ __ ] out of all of this Johnny
Be is having some problems today he
might have to get himself a
Sasquatch there you go but what's
happening right now I was trying to do a
squish on the go I'm have eaten maren
chips
oh hey pretty crunchy nothing like being
bummed out trying to squish something
and not getting anything out of it it
happened in Jamaica the first time Tony
and I were there it was substantial let
me load you out my piece here for your
dab I like that piece I have a
brothership made like
that and I can tell you right now it's
not the
same it looks the
same but I don't think it's exactly the
same well that's a nice way for people
that aren't going to ever you know
invest the money into the actual
Mothership to still be able to get
something I really really enjoy the ball
R grips and just the difference in the
Chug and the difference of the of the
hits on the different pipes and I think
you really start really realizing what
hits you get mhm the hits you get are
the hits you get Johnny B how about that
low temp dripped right down the middle
oh my God is that really nice looking
that's awesome just perfect
wow yeah that's a wower for sure oh
there we go see that last hit that you
took you literally decimated it it moved
right out of the circle and started
moving all around the pipe still hitting
like a
chant
wow that's what I call a well turned
rip the way just sat right in the middle
um I I really really wish that we
actually saw that up close cuz that for
us even we were kind of like wow that
was PR cool I can make a video you know
afterwards I'll just get time lapse that
sucker well you know it's slow motion I
think I know slow motion but that was it
was pretty cool on just watching the
difference between the low Temp dobs and
the it dropped right into the center of
the quartz perfectly and then it never
made it to the edges went and then it
sucked back up and went into it it
boiled lovely it's kind of when we look
at those um new bowls that do for tri
ping I guess it's kind of working in a
similar way how it's drawing up and
drawing back yeah there's just all these
different things that people are
thinking but if you think about what we
just saw yeah well that was the
directional that's how he decided that
guaranteed right Someone putting a carb
cap on and kind of moving it around
moves the oil or the melted hash around
in a circle so that's something I really
didn't even think of until right now
we'll make a video for you in the
meantime I think we really should get to
the park want to go the park the Sun's
shining the blue skies have come out I
think we were going to head into West
Vancouver we're going to check out one
of my favorite Parks which is Lighthouse
Park which is a park that requires a
little bit more of commitment and an
investment of time before you get to the
water White Cliff very quickly we were
at the water yes this one you walk
through a big forest and we'll be able
to potentially stop and have a couple of
sessions along the way before we get to
you know that end result which be I
think we're going on a bit of a hike
we're going on a bit of a hike and we're
going to have a Dr own and we're going
to have these cases tripods so it's
going to be kind of like one of those
hikes that's like damn we have a lot of
[ __ ] we should get someone from the
viewers to help us hike this stuff up
I'm telling you if anyone is local and
wants to come help bubble man's world
sometime for filming a puff Wednesday
carry some stuff for yeah just having
someone carry stuff we'll gladly dab you
right out and and and hang with you and
whatnot that's a good idea Johnny be I
was just thinking um I could see the
hundreds of emails that just came in one
more dab each okay I'm just really
enjoying this hash you know what it's
beautiful flavor especially with the
turs and you know what like and I dabbed
it in the same turfs each
time I haven't even changed yours is uh
yours is definitely mine's dried out a
little bit mine came from Toronto oo how
about some orange creamsicle oh my did
you see the quiver did you see the
orange cream my favorite as a kid was
getting those orange creamsicles with
the with the with the vanilla ice cream
in the middle yeah it was my favorite
thing in world it was it wase but to me
a cream when I was a kid was orange and
it wasn't until later that I saw other
colors and was I was made purple and
green I was just like holy smokes like
this is some you can get different
colors cuz I just used to call them
creamic cre but this is definitely
orange creamsicle and it's your dab
Johnny be I'm happy to see and the
bubble you know it's a little bit hotter
than usual I think I heated that up more
than 10 seconds so I like the 10c um put
your hand just above it and you'll feel
like it's almost burning yeah no not yet
too hot too hot yeah you don't want your
hand to burn because those are those
Turing don't need to be burned at at hot
heats they sure change drastically when
you hit them at that temperature and you
know the whole purpose not that say
changing them is a bad thing that might
be part of the experiment you're doing
in the bioassay and I'm sure there's
things to be found in that aspect that
are of value but for me I love the
preservation I love getting it as
authentic as it was given to me by the
plant in the first place that's why we
looked for extraction methods that are
we're pretty good to go I just touched
it
wow jeez good riing Johnny B it's so
it's just puddling on the bottom of the
quartz right now spinning around the
dish and uh bubbling and melting so
beautifully that uh that really only the
bubble hash and the dry sift of the
highest quality do you know you don't
get that same bubbling from uh rosin or
any type of oil you can get a foaming
from rosin but it's not like that
bubbling bubbling bubbling bubbling
bubbling consistently it's quite
different and this will clean up so
perfect not in a rush for John to finish
his hit like I am sometimes if if it's
been hit too hot then it's like I really
just want to clean that off the the
quartz as as possible but but those low
CS like it's such a beautiful flavor and
then it's it's really those tpes like
you can taste them on the end of your
lips the flavor just it's
like it's like a creamsicle it's like
that when you have a creamsicle you have
that flavor at the end you finish that
cream you're like M that was so good
it's like m
well I'm going to join you with the
creamsicle if you don't mind oh please a
little creamsicle joining I'm a little I
I learned something new today I've
always been calling into my phone I
always like call you know pay by phone
call wait he what he means by pay by
phone is the parking in the city in
Vancouver we've got a fairly sort of
pretty cool system here in the sense
that you can use this app well before
the app was the call the phone in number
which is what he's been doing up until
about an hour ago
and I told him just download the app
dude you get the app and then you can
just punch in every parking space has a
number and I'll tell you for cities that
don't have it I used to get so many
parking tickets when I came into the
City and now I don't get them because my
phone basically sends me a text right be
5 minutes before the uh the parking is
going to expire so it's it's pretty
awesome I'm not going to lie it's pretty
awesome I love
it
yeah it's a great place to come and hang
out and relax we got another like the
taco place we were just at look at the
lineup it's out the door now it's oh
yeah out the
door one of the great places to walk
across the street meet while you're on
huffing heart yep and there's been a
well there was a uh Remembrance Day
celebration today right across here is
of course the Centennial or whatever
it's called Centennial Park Centennial
Park it is yeah so that's why they were
all there today doing their thing it was
really good to see I mean over the next
few days we're going to be uh
remembering our veterans and the ones
that lost their lives uh fighting for
what they believed in and the causes
that they believed in was fighting for
our freedom and that's a very big thing
that we fight for every day we fight for
freedom for this plant every day and
that's another big fight that we fight
for every day uh different freedoms that
we fight for people have lost a lot um
people be thrown in jail and they've
lost loved ones and lost lost lives
fighting on the front battle believing
in the cause that they believe in is
fighting for our freedom you know what
there's different ways remember children
children have lost parents and and
parents have lost children you know it's
uh it's a great day to remember though
you know remember the fought and the
fight Was Won guess that kind of came
out wrong but I me that I appreciate it
I always know that you mean well and
when you say something like that even if
you messed up the words a little bit
comes from the heart and we get what
you're saying dude so good on you Johnny
B let's go do the park let's get out of
here let's come let's uh bring you guys
along with this we should do
[Music]
that BBL man set up a machine what kind
of strain you have there why so clean
and
clear come
on da
[Music]
in it's a Time Time Fresh from the
extractor 100% pure
G this clean and pretty like G
W have used this good F just been and
fold good for The Young and the
whole of course he did of course he
did no but people have to make it their
business look at this big
guy I say we stop this right now and
have a dab oh careful of that giant
horse [ __ ]
at the
entrance you throw the chairs down right
here Johnny B and let's have a dab at
this big monster tree I bet you we can
find more mon we are but this is the
first one and this is the one that we're
going to be dabbing it up at how's it
going guys excellent
fantastic my rain jacket we're not going
to get wet the
chair all right we made it guys we've
pulled off to the side of the trail
literally 3 minutes into the trail we've
had five or six conversations few people
from Argentina colia one person from
columia and another person from
Argentina who we just talked with for
probably half an hour really cool people
education is the key yeah absolutely
they were cool people she said he was an
author he writes about Consciousness and
such things so pretty cool you've got
into more of the DMT psychedelics got
you know great great conversations of
course it was good conversation I would
also say so let's hit some cush cleaner
cuz it's just [ __ ] delicious
delicious see how that
works just
saying just saying you know what Tor me
buddy this has got to be probably this
tree behind us we're going to look up at
top
there but it's pretty cool oh my God I
know it's like it's totally ridiculous
forget about pretty cool ridiculous
little dab I I really love this like 10c
heating of the nail all right give it a
go hold it up against the yeah there you
go up against this the dish lower is
better than higher there you go Johnny's
getting the Uber Uber beautiful uh low
temp dab on that one which is kind of
what we're going for make sure that I
got
the oh I do have them look at that
Q-tips in the
pocket this will be an easy one to fill
you did drip a little bit on your jeans
there let me clean that up for you
partner super low temp but that had to
be that look look at the dip I actually
got a little drip next time that's
awesome I can't let it go away no don't
let it go to waste don't let it go to
waste oh that was
tasty all right so I'm holding the cap
he's got the dab nice to be hit next to
this monster tree we got these guys
right here we do we have them they're in
our crew I I love it that you're here to
witness what we're doing I mean it's
kind of fun when we able to take you on
these adventures and show you a little
bit of beautiful BC I hope we have a
nice flight with the Drone some of these
trees are so epic I really want to be
able to show you guys what they look
like uh from the air and I'm not going
to lie I want to see what they look like
from the air I'm pretty like kind of
stoked on
that like four five 6 7 8 9 10 11 11c
heat on that so I mean now you're going
to see this this the dabbing of what's
going on so really just a quick heat and
Qui I was holding on to the carb cway I
was going to man going to you know keep
it you know I like how it says bubble
man on it yes that's a marble Slinger
classic we talked about that one time
before that's why I I I recognize it
little B man marble he gave me 10 of
them and I gave them all the way to
customers if you're a customer out there
that got one of these leave a comment
tell me the story I'm stoked that you
got one take a picture send it to him
with you in it that would be awesome
that would be cool be like yeah I got
one dude so that'd be pretty epic
because it's part of memories and what
we share and what the culture does is we
share and we reminisce about the good
times and the awesome things that have
happened because of this amazing plant
when we just pull over on the side of a
trail and Blaze next to a monster tree
that's probably 5 or 6 hundred years old
at least a couple hundred how many
people you think have sat here and
smoked
one probably half about as many dogs as
have come here and taken shits well
they've done that too yeah yeah just
saying but you can see that people stand
here here's this gentleman right here
walking by us we're doing a nice little
bong rip Turf dip yeah it's delicious
it's delicious it's very nice not too
bad wouldn't be the same without all the
N although I will say that that was not
a woman that was a man did I say man um
woman did I say woman yeah maybe not
well let's go back and we'll find out
you guys can tell us we'll find out
either way both of John and I are really
not worried about it not at all but once
again give it up to this tree for the
[ __ ] awesome dab session look at that
tree you got one I got one let's head
down and get that drone in the air let's
do this
guys I'm just sitting back here I'm
waiting [ __ ] you get all right so
here we go we're going down this way cuz
uh John's being a little [ __ ] who oh
John's not being a little [ __ ] he's
being a pretty big [ __ ] actually just
joking I'm K I'm Ken Johnny B is doing
the he's working it you know what he's
working it he's definitely we're just
having some comedy here off camera
that's why we thought we would turn the
camera on and give you a little bit of
that uh ridiculous Fe whoa on my face as
I trip down this treacherous Trail just
passed a big old tree just full of a
garon mushrooms I needed quite a little
education to some of there didn't he
look like they speak any English oh
really yeah they look kind of confused
all right so seven sister Trail and
Shore Pine Trail we need to find another
good spot this one's an uphill battle
though what do you say I see why we
should just make our own trail go that
way that is a trail the trail kind of
went around and went down this seems
like we're kind of on a like a river
bed doesn't it they went the other way
see even the dog goes the other way
without the
water we went that
way you think the do went that way we're
going this way are we yeah
this is the shortest way takes us to the
water and we can uh we can do a little
drone flying and a couple of
dabs we should have puffed those people
down from Argentina and Colombia that
would have been fun I think it would
have been
nice I think it would have been nice
whoa almost like elbow me in the oh
sorry buddy just trying to shift all my
packages I'm carrying here that's what
we do we take you guys on
adventures we got to put some work into
this for you I mean well can't all be
fun in games no it can be we can use the
Argo and get there man we would get some
looks if we came in here with the Argo
we get in trouble they'd be tripping
they would call somebody they would not
be happy we would definitely be chased
down cool if you could design an
electric one hey you want to check out
The Bard owl path
no you're awesome
dude
nope no I'm not walking up to the top of
that P no this looks inviting down here
it does I know we have to walk back this
nice you know what if you want to go on
your back and just pull your feet up
into the air you'll probably slide all
the way down that's a pretty good idea
ready one see if I can actually ride the
chairs stop drop and
roll stop drop and roll I hear water
hitting this hey this a pretty cool
mushrooms check this out right here man
beautiful little mushies mushrooms we
have right here yeah see them all along
this whole log all along the whole log
here you got certain different types of
mushrooms and I used to know all these
mushes but I
forgot can always relearn Johnny
B all right so Johnny B and myself are
oh I'd say close to the water now
probably 2third of the way I heard that
15 minutes ago Johnny Be is not much of
a hiker you want to go Short Pine or
seven sisters or sberry Meadow well
we're definitely doing the short time
Short Pine it
is such an nice little it's beautiful
actually really appreciating the walk
the big rocks trees the mushrooms yeah
it's beautiful right fall in uh in
British Columbia on the west coast all
these Fallen trees just look pretty
[Applause]
awesome all right look at that little
cubby hole we're heading
into should we go to the
view wasn't that the idea
no I don't want to go to the view
actually hike Wednesdays hang out in the
middle of the forest to left us walk an
hour not to see the view hike Wednesdays
I feel like hike Wednesdays all right
well the view is over here are you sure
well it says view I don't
know all are you sure now back top of
the top of the morning
John
place to pu oh this is definitely a
place to
Puff just this Flat Rock alone is
[Applause]
perfect
well it looks like Johnny Be is a little
bit behind take a
left he caught up
excellent let's go check out this view
that they're talking
about I'm not sure I've been this far
over in the park in a long time this is
where the
there used to be a camp here they have
these cabins and such that they rent out
to the movie
industry oh and there's the lighthouse
right
there thus the lighthouse park that's
what makes it Lighthouse Park so I think
we're going to have to get the Drone out
and fly from right
here what do you think should we set up
the
chairs yeah yeah
I've lived here my whole life I've never
been here before like of course I'm
setting up a chair and doing a dab and
hanging out at the
Lighthouse epicness yeah this is the
lighthouse you know I'm like it's is
like from NOA scoa we have a lighthouse
there yeah it's awesome The Shining
Landmark you can put those chairs down
right here brother then there's all
these cabins I kind of want to put my
chair right on top of up there yeah no
problem you get it up there and I'll
film the whole thing you film the whole
thing me falling everything dude the
helicopter all of it all the new surgery
oh dude everything I'll be visiting you
in this PR much surreal [ __ ] right no
not if I already saying it's going to
happen okay I'm done put my chair put
the chairs down safe so here's how it
goes he's a little concerned we have
some
wind if you don't know what's already
going on we got this happening little
bit of wind he's checking he's checking
his sensors we got that going on right
there it's getting ready to launch right
beside it of course is the denail the
chairs are set up for what for us to dab
why cuz it's puff Wednesday and we're
going to bring you the shots that you
guys want to
see and don't don't forget we hiked in
here for 40 minutes there it
goes that's it right
[Music]
there going right in to it he's going
right for it right away out he goes into
the
wind
up there you guys
go getting you the footage that you want
to see taking an Overlook at what that
Lighthouse that's what's going on you
can see the trees moving back and forth
there and you can see how it's kind of
busting into the wind like that there
really some truly Drone footage here
going on guys you're going to be
watching this as I'm actually zooming
out because now now we're going over the
lighthouse testing it out seeing if I
get back
[Music]
okay that's the guy behind the
controllers right there
oh
yeah okay so now we're going to get a
little daring we got that black cloud
over there it's raining it's heavy wind
we're taking it to to the no extreme we
had a little bit of uh un Zoom there
guys but you're watching that footage
right
[Applause]
now
[Music]
the Drone coming back from that epic
view they were just watching right there
oh yeah wow did that thing fly hard that
thing flew hard
there you guys
[Music]
go boom just like that you got her in
the hand that's what happens there guys
that's that footage you just saw that
was nice that was tight you like that
little bit wetness on the Drone not too
bad all right well we are deep in the
bush here heading up to another Lookout
here in Lighthouse Park we just showed
you the lighthouse up close and personal
with the Drone little bit worried kind
of windy that's why we didn't give you
the what I would call the greatest Drone
footage ever it was a little bit weak
sauce but uh hopefully we'll get some
better stuff up
here as I drop my
tripod something I'll pick up I'm right
behind you my friend Johnny B for the
win this is a crazy little man crazy
little path it seems to almost not be a
path oh wow John you're going to like
this I think you're going to like this
spot Johnny
B oh my
gosh oh I think we found the coast
then so yeah this is what this is like
you know you can walk down a couple of
drops and there's a spot down there
another spot up here more killer spots
over
here look at the rain across the
way oh feel the heat here you
can warm well it's trippy that there's
no wind and it seems like where did the
lighthouse
go around the corner this is effort
we're puffing right here right now we
over there at one point we that mountain
over there let's uh drop these uh chairs
here in the warm
spot this where we're popping right now
got the Drone
out
yep these both in a good spot so they're
both
safe get a little
boat oh it's awesome I could be flying
the derone over him right
now this is
cool lighthous Park is a trip that way
how you just go the slightest little bit
did you see how much it
changed do
[Music]
with
the
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
so the Drone you can see the footage
you'll be seeing it there
but
just pulling some [ __ ] on I'm coming
home right
now
[Music]
see i' say a couple of bong reps with
the Drone is going to be
[Music]
essential
nice
job it's so much fun it is fun that was
some epic stuff that we just witnessed
it was good right so let's uh have some
dabs let's do that yeah there
check that [ __ ] up behind us whoa I was
just talking about
that I was talking about um this chair
and behind this is roughly about a 30ft
drop and and we're not but beyond that
it's probably 60 more feet to the water
to the water yes so I was a little
nervous there cuz it was just a little
bit I have to say and did I not make the
offer I will take that very dangerous
right there I'm always accepting of
keeping Johnny be we keep it real for
you guys as safe as we can keep so
anyway we've done some really fun drone
flying flying I'm kind of was a little
nervous I'm not going to lie that was
pretty was windy as [ __ ] we've shown you
guys a couple of clips and uh I think we
might have a few more sessions in the
forest because we don't feel as quite as
rushed but I figured we'd at least have
this epic Ocean View Vancouver Island
behind us with the rain and the sun uh
sun shining through the clouds I think
it's perfect time for us to sit right
here Johnny B pull out the six-star West
Coast concentr
pull out some Blue River tpin I'm
thinking I'm just thinking you know what
um the TPS look at that I got a whole
bottle of OG
Kush really yeah oh here let me sh let
me try this just for super random but
let's hit
that okay I'm on let's hit
that I like the 10-second heating up the
nail that's just a new like awesome
awesome awesome thing for us did you see
that di did you did you see that that
was like cuz when you go into a bottle
was a DI TPS like that it's more than
one dip and you're going to realize that
so when you get your TPS some people
they go through them really bad and they
cuz you follow our lead and you dip in
there I would actually use the dropper
put a drip in and drop it onto your
product I've been doing that lately have
you even to like a couple of grams like
just a single drop I whip it all around
I add a little rosin to the bub Buble
hash and then the TPS and it it's quite
a lovely product see the the thing is is
is the turps they're essential that you
use them properly because they will last
and I I hear some discouragement like oh
yeah I like dipped in there like four
times was all gone yeah when you soak
your rosin into turpins it's more than
one dip oh yeah it's like a soak you can
count it one drop two drop three drop
you know you got no drops
left got to hit this one a little extra
to make sure I clean off the residues we
won't go the full like hardcore no
hardcore so that was just my TP little
talk your turp little talk my T I like
your turp little talk I'm glad you
didn't fall off this chair to your death
that was awesome um it would we were
talking about the helicopter landing and
then you guys see me get my new surgery
Mar coming in with different turine to
see what helps my pain we're not going
there instead we're going to do like go
out on your
um what is that the Argo Argo and go
have fun on that level not like anyone
dying I can't wait because the steel
truck's going to take us to the most
carb
cap cap a friend cap a friend in need
it's all it takes a little bit of
capping a lot of people don't understand
the carb cap and why a carb cap cuz if
you don't you're just not really going
to get anywhere that extra little leeway
giving us like puffing on a bowl you
give a little hand tap to keep the bowl
going if you have it you should try that
just saying just give it a little
taparoo give a little taparoo little tap
tap tap tap
tap that was delicious and perfect and
amazing I can
smell super low temp perfect L temp and
really like quite surprising on it's
like the sun just went down did you see
the and then all Rain Drops Keep
Falling delicious it's been one of those
days where every kind of three or 4
seconds you get a little bit of a a
might rain kind of drop it's true it has
been just like that I'm sure you saw it
in the Drone little STS while you're
flying old there over the epicness
behind us pretty cool o Kush happy OG
kush look at me Johnny be happy I'm
always happy I'm actually quite
fantastic I have to say instead of
giving you T dip what I did there was
called a turp water board
what's so you got quite a bit of TPS in
this rip coming I'm taking the glass off
for that what was that a the TP water
that was TP water
boarding it's like you can actually see
that this house used to be really nice
but now it's being soaked has completely
changed
color
epic I think that's I have to get one
made like this that just says Johnny B
or JB JB I have to talk to um I have to
talk to the
girlfriend well that is one of the
bonuses of dating a glass blower like
Johnny B does he can talk to the
girlfriend get something blown I didn't
mean that in a negative way in any a
great way we talking about glass
[Music]
that's
the
[Music]
that's all that's going on
here good job Johnny oh keep pushing
that in there you got more hit there you
go there you
go you I'll take that we got this down
pat puffing Bulls in nature it's kind of
fun tasty as hell take the fun out of
that D tasty as
hell all we can go right out on the
rocks down by the water if we walk a
little bit more to the left which is
where I usually go where those people
are right there that's also a nice
little spot you saw it fly with a drone
they did yep I could have taken them
down even closer I like that for sure
it's great that you guys get us out on
these puff Wednesdays we missed a couple
there when the camera was broken but we
got it happening now we got the dual
cameras with time lapses we got the
Drone footage I'll take some macro
videos and photos throw them into this
video and puff Wednesday should be a
substantial Improvement mement from the
regular videos that I post on my channel
you know what I just think that every
video you post on your channel has
substantially a little bit more than the
last one well it's a learning experience
and I'm definitely by no means a
professional I'm uh I'm I just came at
this as a total Amur we have fun we have
fun and as long as there's bows to be
puffed oh let me clean that for you
buddy you know what I was busy talking
no it's such a low temp DB that's I'm
say like I'm really learning because me
myself I've ruined all my my quartz
Bowls because I'm always hitting it
because for me I'm always hitting it
hard and hot I think it's still a good
idea every once in a while to go in and
just give it that that cleanup thatan
which is what I'll do right now just the
cleanup RIP just from those little bits
that are smoking each time you know you
don't quite see the little bit of
residue that's on the side but it's not
enough that it's going to oxidize the
nail up all bad but it's definitely the
beginning that if you don't clean it up
and burn it off it's done it ends up
being done like mine
but you can always buy another one too
they're pretty nonexpensive well it
depends on the company you go with I
think they're a couple hundred or 150
for a quave banger I got a quave these
are the DC glass I think he's around 100
150 as well I got that PUK and be quartz
the quartz one in the beginning PUK and
Beagle were awesome I think we paid 300
for those I that one got disintegrated
after hitting it with heavy torches oh
no that was Sapphire Sapphire Sapphire
Sapphire yeah I remember you said saying
that happened to you I had the one where
they put the Dil on the bottom and
somehow I
uh I did a inin yeah that's nice and
clean the wind it's just it's such a
it's warm it's it's kind of trippy cuz
it wasn't like that at all today over
there anywhere we've been but when we
came around here I first felt it on that
down lower spot and it was it was very
light but when I got up to here and
walked through here right as you were
saying oh my God it's so warm I don't
know if it's this rock that's been
baking in the sun all day or what it is
feels good it's definitely a warm and
the wind's hitting that rock and it's
warming up the wind and it's blowing
it's it's beautiful it's like vacation
time it is like vacation time with you
guys I love it I like
it well what do you say Johnny B what's
next on our adventure here I think we
we're going to um take you
guys that into the park maybe or out to
the coast hey we might not even take
anyim we might just say hey we're making
no promises it's not there's no we're
going to smoke some more hash probably
off camera no let's do it on camera okay
let's do that all
right just the way the Smashing on the
the wind and the weather for the last
like f 80 100 years or however long
these trees been here for long time it's
pretty
cool
straight
[Music]
ahead
a
[Music]
well we found ourselves in the middle of
the
forest we had some communication there
with a little bit of wildlife little
Wildlife communication beautiful
beautiful in the middle of nowhere on
the side of a trail people walk by here
sometimes uh I wouldn't be surprised if
they
did but I'm not concerned either way so
what's the turp this uh pick right now I
mean I'm not going to lie I'm going and
looking for the oh what de I'll hit the
Cherry AK-47 I was looking for the sour
diesel I'm not going to lie I was
looking for that Jamaican Sour Diesel
Cherry
AK-47
yeah little bit in there anyway it's
old I can get a couple of squishes out
of there for us I think we got like
is there 420 on a puff Wednesday 420 on
a puff
Wednesday it's always nice to spend it
with you
guys enjoying the scenery the wildlife
the enjoyment of the of the West Coast
showing you epic views of the coast me
some of those those shots were just like
it's it's stuff you only see in the
movies or of course on oh it's pretty
pretty nice stuff for sure there's a lot
of people out there filming with drones
nowadays a lot of famous YouTube
vloggers that're p putting out some
pretty quality content I'm just cleaning
the dish if you haven't already sort of
figured that out it's got it looked like
it wasn't cleaned very well after the
last dab so we might as well just fire
it off and get it nice and clean there
you go it's a good way of getting it
clean just kind of keep it up and
running and you know blowing keep it up
and running keep it up and around Johnny
Be
you're [ __ ] awesome you got to keep
that [ __ ] up and running man you got got
to keep it going oh dude okay I'm ready
for a dab I think so yeah oh you got one
on there everything you even dipped oh
I'm dipped dabbed ready to go like
everything loving being in the forest I
mean I love this [ __ ] I really do being
surrounded by huge trees some big ones
in here I mean huge for the city anyway
we're not out near the ancient Cedar
Forest where the trees are you know 20
plus feet in diameter these are still
pretty big should go see R he is going
to maybe come to Jamaica wow yeah for
the Cannabis Cup there in December so
I'm kind of hoping on working on getting
Ron to do that and if he does man I'll
tell you I'll be so
excited so excited this is going to be
more like a minute wait I really have
been liking those 10-second weights I I
noticed that the t's like I like so you
know as we count down five
four three two yeah it's getting close
actually one I was counting dabs yeah
give it a shot well you know we are
outside in the world we now we don't
have that warmth off The Rock in that
corner where we just that a little bit
more chillier inside of here actually
you know got a great dab with there I'm
going to hook him up with a Q-tip
because that's just the way of being
able to keep that thing good and
golden
not golden I should say getting the gold
yumy it's
gold apparently it's quite tasty look at
this it's like I'm I'm I'm an apprentice
I'm working on this stuff see thank you
it's things that you do you know you got
to learn this you learn this in work you
learn how to make sure you have the
right tools for the
job lot of times we forget water or
torch there's always something a batter
did pretty good today a charger we we we
kind of figured this you a remote
control didn't that was fun forgetting
the remote control yeah that one was
that was a good one that was the one we
did the well that was going Sitting on
the Dock and that was another beautiful
shot when we take a look at the way the
the whole Coastline looks and how it is
just so close that's 10 minutes away
it's pretty damn cool it's pretty cool
get yourself a
dab get yourself a
dip and uh there's cush cleaner that's
the OG this is like white widow or
something or no
ACDC I have white cookies I got there's
all sorts of [ __ ] Jamaica Sour Diesel is
so tasty I mean hit whatever you want
but that that's the one I was looking
for when I found what I
found puff Wednesday I love these
getting into different zones having a
little puff having a little conversation
enjoying the environment and enjoying
the moment I hope that you guys get out
as well if you don't uh you know maybe
have the most epic Coastal rain forest
to walk through that's okay because even
in the center of Canada the Prairies
there are some beautiful forests the uh
Forest Trails that you can walk through
and do mushroom collecting and just have
an all-around blast and these forests
are all over the world they're all
different and uh they're all to be
enjoyed really I've i' I love them all
was it this one yep that corner one is
the sour diesel let me get you ready of
here I like this
one
little bit of
uh
Jamaica this is the swoosh the swoosh
swoosh the swoosh the
swoosh I I love hearing all those birds
they're all wishing me a happy
420 yep still a really nice low temp dab
that is the way to do it I don't know
why it took me so long to figure this
out but uh I guess that's how it goes
sometimes too impatient to wait one last
one oh that was
tasty that was
great well I think um next down the line
next down the line what are you
thinking I mean I've been enjoying every
stop that we've made every little
conversation we've had every dab we've
done every flown drone we've flown nice
job you're picking up on that that that
kind of I've enjoyed it all man I've
enjoyed it all and I mean even right now
listening to the
birds and potentially
insects chirping all around us I know
it's really nice Prett nice it's random
too because we are literally on the
trail head right on the trail head the
main trail head that takes you in and
out of this park I saw dozens of
vehicles when I went in we bumped into
probably 15 plus people and for whatever
reason there's nobody around right now
which is
amazing what
happens yeah dude let's keep uh let's
just keep sitting here for a little bit
and uh we'll H we'll hook up with these
guys when we hit our next Zone on the
way out of here I like that all right so
as always Johnny B has pointed out that
it is 420 just after I put the pipe away
of course so we have pulled out the
Omicron pen from uptech and uh I've got
it packed full of some rosin and some
bubble has and some
TPS and that's our
420 happy
420 happy 420 Johnny
B I never like want to miss a 420
especially on a puff Wednesday with you
guys so it's like it's 420 and we're
getting a little puff in and yeah we're
you know we're Trucking weather says
rain we say you know what we're getting
out of
here a 420 dab you know a little 420
mini rip so not bad let's head down the
TRU let's head her down let's do it all
right the Woodpecker or whatever that is
up
there probably just one of the branch is
breaking off
yeah as we're standing underneath it
don't
look I anything to hit me on the head
that you can easily spend hours in this
park walking this Matrix of trails that
go from east to west and north to south
it's quite a nice size acreage of park
right mostly all Coastal and uh wouldn't
you say after today John it's uh it's
one worth exploring here in BC oh th%
this is one of a beautiful beautiful
spots that I've never been to in BC and
I've lived here basically my whole life
so um pretty close to the city too I
know it's really nice yeah you know
people are kind of missing out but I
guarantee you guys are going to come by
here and you know and you're can tell us
more about your little trip here here in
the area that's it it's pretty pretty
nice place to take a girl or somebody
should head down the
[Music]
trail