[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world we never went anywhere it's still
puff Wednesday Johnny and I felt
terrible about the last one it just
wasn't enough you know what this is
awesome so now we're downtown in
Vancouver we wanted to get something to
squish we were both running low on
nuggets I squished all the bud Darren
gave me the other day into a beautiful
pad uh uh blob of of rosin this is
important but now we're down at the
Sunrise uh uh uh Wellness Foundation
here with uh Max and Dong we've got the
development application on the wall here
that shows that they're looking to uh
change of use from retail store to
medical marijuana related use so this is
one of the things our city of Vancouver
is doing they're trying to give these
licenses out for people to be able to do
business in this industry I think it's
fantastic what's happening so pretty
cool they they actually have about six
license in Vancouver now that have been
approved right and and what we're having
is legal weed let's go buy some not
really in a sense it's not a federal law
it doesn't really make it legal in a
sense but it makes it so the city isn't
going to come down and and send the
police now the federal government still
considers this completely illegal and
they could potentially send the federal
police but at this point in time it
hasn't happened and we're pretty stoked
with this step as it is why don't we
head in and check out what they've got
the sunrise Wellness Foundation I'll
tell you one of the things about this
place is the quality is on point I I
think I think in Vancouver this is going
to be that that place that has the
quality that we look for yeah 100% let's
head
let's go friend some
[Applause]
thugs thank
you all right walk right in and Johnny B
is already behind the counter well if
you're going to get a new job got have a
trainer in in tender in training I'm in
training nice I I like it so the best
part of all this is is cuz I'm I'm being
I'm in training yeah I have to step back
and watch what happens here so I put my
hands behind my back all right and smell
Beautiful hey I'm in the mirror too
what's up everybody Dom thanks for
having us good to see you mark yeah good
to see you as well I'm going to step
outside I shouldn't be behind here this
is where the staff is I'm not staff I'd
love to be a bud tender but instead I'm
going to consume your guys' bud so I'm
going to step outside all right yeah
here stand beside you in the mirror hey
yeah so Johnny and I came by today
thinking we would look at some of the
kind nuggets that you guys are often
known for something in uh regards to a
nice flavor a really uplifting or heavy
both of the effects are good for us but
something that squishes really nice cuz
we know Johnny B is going to be
squishing that going to be getting busy
on that sasquash oh you know what I I
squish I squish pretty much if I if it's
if it's a nug I squish it if it doesn't
return I don't squish it anymore there
you go let's go through some of the
flavors here just in the uh
got some Hindu
[Applause]
cush
mamore cookies some Hindu star all got
cookies
in some Diamond
OG and some Bruce
Banner oh
yeah wow
blueberry
diesel all right what do you got going
on here Dom we got a few exclusive
strains as well um these are pretty much
you can only find them here at Sunrise
wellness and uh they come from the ogk
labs these three and then this is one
that we've done the uh the feno
selection ourselves on um they've all
got 09 cookies crossed into them which
is the burners cut uh so they're really
nice we've got a gorlic glue 4 crossed
with 09 cookies uh which is you know
known as gorilla cooks or glue Cooks few
different names it goes by really nice
bud structure really Frosty we'll show
you some of the nugs there in a second
the next one up is Teflon which is
Cherry Pie cross with Wi-Fi Alien OG
cross with o09 cookies that cherry pie
really comes through with it it's got
nice kind of purpley nugs to it uh
beautiful little bud structure little
nlets um the third from the ogk labs
which are grown by Sunrise Gardens is
the o9 cookies squared and so that's
basically on cookies back crossed into
itself with the Wi-Fi alien
beautiful through the jar looks very
kind and then the fourth is the Platinum
girl scco cookies that's the dark heart
Nursery cut crossed with WiFi 43 uh both
pretty legendary strains um we did the
feno selection on this one uh and we
think it's definitely a winner got a few
more rounds to go to perfect it but so
far the response has been pretty great
um looks beautiful I wanted to show you
just a few buds here let me just grab my
gloves before I touch these excellent
this is the o9
cookies how does it smell does it smell
loud
no that's loud it's got some loudness to
it it had a scream down
it looks
beautiful oh
yeah o well I'm definitely going to have
to take
um take some of that the9 is nice it's
got a real nice uh thin waxy cuticle on
it too so I think it would be it' make a
really nice hash string I'm sure it
would sift well but I'm sure if you're
just squishing it for rosin you're going
to be quite happy with that one
especially the Teflon as well if you're
looking for turps if you're looking for
something really heavy though I'd
probably recommend the glue cookies just
cuz it's got that yield it's got that
flavor Gilla is common down in the
States but it's something kind of new up
here in Canada M you know everyone up
here wants to go for the glues the
cookies and everything while I hear from
all the Americans they always looking at
pink kushes which is a very common
strain to us right yeah exactly so so
this is the gorilla that's the
cookies this one's the
cooks this so let me a little bit closer
I think
right my the
cooks this one's the gorilla Cooks uh
the one you had before that was the
gorilla Cooks that's the 09 oh this is
the 09 yeah that's the tough one all
right
beautiful so just by looking at the
first three I'm going to see the tlon
Cherry High cross it's a definite winner
if you're looking for chps as well as
yield um I only pressed it on a hard
press which doesn't have the same
pressure as a sasquat unfortunately and
we were still getting you know 15% and
that was you know just with with a lot
getting stuck in our bags cuz it just
doesn't have the same pressure that I
didn't use any bags yesterday when I
pressed that seven G out I just made it
like long like a hot dog and just went
smash sometimes that's the best right
another technique that I've heard people
do is squishing it with a bag and then
collecting it and then putting it in a
bag so they can squish at a lower
temperature once they do
so all
right okay so I'm going with tlon so far
turn anything with that cherry pie in it
right i' say I'd say the best two for
you guys to squish would be the gorilla
cooks and the Teflon I've already kiss
well all righty then I'll take a quarter
of each sounds good let's get those
going for you guys good on you Johnny Be
I don't eveny I can't believe I I don't
even buy it's puff Wednesday and that's
what makes it so just so awesome and you
know what I mean I be locking on the gr
this year and and I don't have the
quality that I us to this is getting
close might even be right on par well we
try and definitely always raise the
standards we're all about quality we
don't want to compromise at any any
level of you know our products even our
$5 grams like this Tex to time War Burns
clean tastes good it's got turps It's a
greenhouse strein but you know you don't
have to worry about spending $5 a gram
on a on a stream here that's going to
get you sick ta time war is also known
for me is also a haly common exactly cuz
it when you grow it indoors it tends to
change into that doesn't it
yeah very lovely defitely some Superior
strange you guys got going on here so
you said a quarter of each but I'm just
going to split the two quarters between
these three because I think all three of
these are going to be really nice
squishers all very different in flavor
as well cuz you'll have the te up you
hear that he just UPS he's like I think
you need all three still getting the
same am same amount I'm just going to
split between these three cuz I don't
want you to miss out on the 09 cookies I
think that's pretty awesome John's like
give me a quarter of each pretty
much split it up you're awesome
John ah yes the bet that that stock
could be a little bit you know over look
at that they even take the stock out for
me want to give you too much stick here
I'm just squishing it it's one of the
best nugs for squishing
squishy
nugs oh John you'll you'll roll some
joints I pretty much like you know what
a nice little I I roll it into a nice
little log I I probably smoke a joint uh
but for me it's a Bly extractions and
that's what really helps for me and what
I really enjoy so it's like kind of like
smoking one of these uh big joints you
got to smoke that joint for like 20
minutes before you feel anything where
you do one little dab and you do one
little dab it's like woohoo this rocking
the blue Rivers yes we do we got quite a
selection of
it River
Tes Swiss Swiss tsunami Cavell s Diesel
black lime
Reserve well I get people asking me all
the time where to get tpin in the city
and I tell them this is pretty much the
one shop that I I have sold tpin to if
you don't want to wait for the shipping
come into the sunrise you can pick them
up the same day yeah exactly love the
packaging too yeah so these are all uh
BPA free craft paper um recycled craft
paper so you know they're pretty smelly
proof what of our
signatures it's actually pretty similar
to packaging actually smelly proof I see
you got meder sitting over there too
with your logo on it fantastic meders
which is awesome which are great for
people who've got sore sore wrist
because it's much easier to hold on to
than one of those small little Grinders
mhm I like that Blue River meds you got
everything unfor you have some hash
bubble hash right behind you well we've
got a few different ones in here Rock
cream we had some nice rosins in there
from concentrated x uh some strawberry
banana flour rosin but that flew off the
shelf within the first day of getting it
oh yeah still have some of his dry sift
rosin um we've got some nice uh Heavenly
days live resins there if you're into
all of those types of extractions but we
covering all the gamuts yeah we try to
cover everything that's a good thing
that's what we like to hear we like to
see access cannabis is a quiver there's
no reason to put only one shot in your
quiver when you can fill that quiver
right
up with all the cultivars and all the
extractions
and I'm pretty excited right now well
it's nice to be able to come to a shop
that actually has some dank nug you do
take um take credit cards right we take
debit we can't take credit yet but we're
we're trying to stay ahead of the curve
of just the deit machine here well
pretty much you know what the the whole
thing is is is being able to take
cannabis and level where I can be able
to start purchasing it on that scale I
think with the application being on the
wall and how the thing is here happening
in Vancouver I'm really looking forward
to being able to able to come into these
establishments Pur purchase legally
wreck and medical and be able to use
whatever it takes means and it'd be a
wonder if we could actually get our
insurance to cover it for us too and I
think we're slowly slowly that's the
next level right there yeah if they
start ensuring our cannabis you know um
um we're laughing
we're laughing if that happens that's
that's super amazing especially for
medical patients you know like if
they're going to introduce a
recreational we can't forget and leave
the medical patients on Dust for sure
not well it comes down to access and it
comes down to patients rights and a lot
of people have their prescriptions paid
for they don't have to purchase their
their pharmaceutical drugs for their
conditions and someone like myself and a
lot of others use canvas for their
conditions so why do we have to purchase
our medication when it's needed every
day to for General wellbeing for for for
homeostasis what I say so I feel better
every day I
use a lovely
plants this guy's got it down he even
knows to color he's like that's the one
no no that doesn't
workon definitely got a very nice cakey
nose to it you know I I really really
I'm a coniss of kushes I think that's
why I
mean I don't I don't I don't have this
in in my garden I don't I don't have
these flavors available to me right now
I'm sure I'll be able to access them
sooner than later well actually I am
accessing them right now here that's the
best part and I didn't spend 3 months
growing and caring it and I know the
quality is definitely exactly what I
would actually be accustomed to and
we're excited to have them on our
shelves cuz it's been a project that
we've been working on for better part of
a year now well I know the Str because
these are some of the strains that I
have popped at the beginning of the year
which was the what you guys are call the
te on the Cherry Pie CR of the on9
cookies was a strain that I I started
working with and um due to the fact that
I went for some surgeries and stuff like
that I had to kind of wait a little bit
so being able to try it right now when I
was getting ready to grow it is just for
me it's fantastic mhm yeah there's only
a couple of people like you know maybe
less than five people that are growing
these strains so it's nice to see to see
the differences mean like the few
Growers that have them because they're
all doing slightly different methods
these ones are done aeroponically and
under gavitas whereas uh I know you know
another mutual friend of ours has them
in a small little tent and he creates
some very very high quality fully
organic and just like gorgeous looking
almost like diamonds on the bud yeah you
definitely see the difference when using
Organics compared to when you're doing
like like you say a current culture
system or a water system or using
synthetics um but with any kind of
proper flesh any knows what they're
doing it's really that hard to figure
out so so I split it up like that that's
[Music]
okay does that work
beautiful I'm going to grab some too all
right well do you know what you want to
try do you want to try some other ones
or the same ones that Johnny got
or I know you want some more that
gorilla Cooks cuz you enjoyed that last
time yeah let me see here I guess I'll
probably get like uh so far you don't
have the Platinum so maybe maybe a
little bit of the Platinum the Sun the
sunrise cut we didn't do the Platinum we
got Teflon 09 and gorilla Cooks sure man
whatever you think definitely want some
Teflon I definitely want to see the
results of these these squishes because
I'm excited yeah film
it probably squish them all in one shot
too like three squishes here's the four
pile squish the best that' be the best
way of doing it that's
it it's been a while since I was able to
just go to a dispensary and buy some
herb I got to say i' I haven't really
done this in a long time I haven't gone
to coffee shops in Amsterdam in a long
time like I got all those things out of
my system in the 9s and I was a part of
you know supplying this uh The
Compassion Club back in uh the early
2000s and late '90s so it's nice as well
for me who doesn't have any plants
growing right now to just be able to
come down and uh pick up close to a zip
of some buds and take them home and
squish them get some nice resin for the
next puff
Wednesday for
me all right just going to pay my bill
here my delicious delicious
flavors how much uh 55 so 55 65 and
85 how much is
complex you can find that color anywhere
in any glass knows that that even Mark
knows that is a sick color yeah know so
one last thing we wanted to mention was
that you guys have a Christmas giveaway
coming up yeah we're doing a little
holiday giveaway uh in collaboration
with high integrity glass art he's uh
definitely someone to look up to if
you're into high-end glass and uh
collecting so uh we've done this in
collaboration with uh with them and for
the first prize place this first place
you're going to see it on that puff
Wednesday is we've got a Mothership mini
brand new with an XL frosted
ofc and this thing is nice was just
going to say Throw That lighter up next
to it so they can actually get an
idea it is miniature and obviously it
comes with the laser cut Turtle case
with the mothership logo on front
beautiful it's really
cool very nice look the XL medtainer is
even bigger than that than the Mini
crack that open and let's see that I
like the color and laser cut so it's
made specifically for your mini so
whoever's lucky enough to win this oh
yeah we have a pretty awesome case to go
with it that is
beautiful God this is a nice little pipe
it just looks so clean look at this I
don't think it's even ever had water in
it it came pretty much straight from
Mothership to here this is second prize
this is second place prize and it will
come with a fresh swing as well um I
don't know the exact color I believe
it's got a blue Stardust maybe a bit of
cobalt in there maybe even green
Stardust depending on which way you look
at it the light you're getting quite a
few different different shades very cool
and so how do people get entered to uh
win such a thing here so it's open to uh
in store customers or our mail order
customers and basically for every $200
they spend per order they get a raffle
entry so you know this is running for
almost two months you've got lots of
opportunities to come in um we keep a
complete tally of it on our system and
basically uh right around Christmas
someone will be the lucky winner of
either the first or second prize and for
the third prize we' got a bunch of
different different Mothership
accessories A little dab rag a dab mat
like a little non-stick slip pad bunch
of stickers and uh we've got lots and
lots of uh collectible Mothership
calendars which have tons of really cool
of their pieces inside beautiful
photography Mr Gray skull oh yeah
January for the wi I can't wait for my
phone call just before Christmas
beautiful you never know hey I joh you
might win I entered because I of course
could be a puff could be a puff
Wednesday celebration right there but I
got to say part of me really hopes that
someone that doesn't own a mother ship I
don't want it uh I want well no of
course we want it I just mean I I I
would hope that someone who never owned
a mother ship in their life gets a
chance to win it ex yeah exactly
definitely very cool man very cool all
right well let's uh let's wrap it up
we've had a really nice little time here
Johnny B you got some flavors I got some
flavors we both got Flav got some
flavors I want to thank Dom pleas for
walking us through as always yes and uh
there may be more there may not be
either way this was more than you
thought you were going to get this puff
Wednesday Sunrise Wellness Foundation
One on Kingsway one on Broadway that's
correct so that's 258 West Broadway or
2943 Kingsway awesome well very cool and
part two of this will be me squishing
the Nuggets that I bought so that won't
be a puff Wednesday but it'll be kind of
a continued Sunrise Wellness uh nugget
squish video so right on guys thanks for
watching peace we'll see you soon
[Music]