[Music]
look at you that
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with Remo the urban grower
what's up dude thanks for having me over
once again thanks for coming up man
you've got a beautiful platter of
awesome variety here let throw that down
there bring it up here look at that
woohoo six varieties three on top three
on the bottom all killer all killer and
lucky me today I brought my Trippy Stick
herbal unit so I'm actually able to try
out each one of these um herbs which I
believe you grew uh with your new
nutrient line yeah all grown with
rainbow nutrients and we've had some
fantastic results yeah well have to say
it looks great um I'm ready to dip in
for certain I'm quite excited to try the
the two that I passed your way but also
I'm really excited to try that headband
you know what that's my new favorite I
think this stuff could win a cup and
actually that's probably I entry into
any cups I enter this year um if you
look at it it's kind of got a silver
kind of tone to it lots of TRC Combs
unbelievable flavor unbelievable smell
um not the best producer in the world
but potency wise pretty strong oh it it
kicks you in the face all right so
that's saying a lot if Remo is saying
that it kicks you in the face that means
it's a definitely a strong string from a
from an ex broker's perspective it looks
like that herb that you could just you
know that always a pleasure to yeah the
Hollywood
looks looky here a little nugget oh look
at that you got it sometimes I have to
put my hand in the background to get it
to clear out like that all right well
why don't you pick the first one that
we're going to hit oh it's right right
for the favorite yeah I'll only need a
tiny little bit so maybe put a tiny
little bit in the grinder for me too
okay here I'll let you take a hit and
I'll throw the rest in the joint yeah it
fits it I mean it fits a decent amount
but not uh nothing compared to the giant
fat joint that Remo is about to roll I'm
sure I'll take it easy today cuz I got
to do all these six and right probably
in a small amount of time yes you know
there's a it's like a sampling I know
that uh they have it with wine or you
can have uh it's a cannabis tasting or
it's a cannabis tasting there should be
a name for this though a smorgus bud
aorus bud there we go so let me smell
that they should have a sneeze guard out
and a little basket of every kind of
weat you know Buffet I like it lit
gently lit with some fluorescent lights
so you can examine the buds before
smoking oh you got to just stuff it in
there yeah it's going trust me first
nice and
gentle
oh thank you sir yeah not a
problem I haven't really um well many
many people will see this video and say
wow bubble man you're smoking herb You
Never Smoke herb okay no he's baby I do
not smoke herb it's true it doesn't mean
that I don't love herb I love herb
because it brings me the resin and how I
choose most of the time to acquire that
resin is through the mechanical
separation using screens or through the
ice water extraction method now this is
merely a third method of extracting
resin this is the hot air extractor mhm
so we one two three four the
button there we go and then hold it down
for 4
seconds the light goes on and she starts
climbing wow where can you get one of
these things um trippy sticks sells them
at their on their website we're also
starting to carry them at bubble bag.com
and um there's a new Vaporizer Company
that I'm Absolut not a company sorry but
a a there's a company that is selling
vaporizers for many many different
companies and I believe they carried it
as well um I I believe their name is
wizard wizard Bros or wizard puff I'll
let you know in the near future because
they've sent me a couple units that they
want me to do um reviews for so I got
this from amelo down in down in La the
owner of trippy sticks so right on been
supporting these guys for a couple of
years what an awesome gift well you know
what particularly to me because it's not
like when you have a big joint of
something awesome it's not that I don't
want to try it it's just that I don't
smoke that way I don't smoke canand no
that's fine with me it's more for me
more for me of course but at the same
time I really want to try all these
different flavors and so you know now
you can now I can on the go you know so
I guess here we go
cheers
wow that is some trippy stuff very nice
like immediate strong Kush flavors but
something else and it just hangs on the
lips The
Vapor very interesting guaranteed both
of us are getting slightly different
experiences from him smoking The Joint
the turpine profile cannabinoid profile
is going to be different for him than it
is for me through the vaporizer yet
we're both hitting the same strain oh
this stuff kind of takes my breath away
believeing it's just a unbelievable
okay well um while we're smoking this
and while you're vaping uh which one do
you want to try next I mean let's go
right over to the kosher kosher good
give my boys Don an air and a
shot right
on well that's where these seeds
originated from DNA
genetics and I think it was just a
standard pack of seeds I you know really
you'd have to smoke this weed to see how
good it is it is amazing but I can't
believe how produces it's one of my top
producing strains so that's up yeah that
was uh I I I sent a message to Aaron
today from DNA when uh Remo was telling
me a little bit about his Harvest from
the the kosher and Aaron was uh Aaron
was stoked of course he he was sorry
that he missed uh Remo while he was here
in BC Remo was over at uh Sun Peaks in C
well next year if we do it again we'll
make sure we all go to the same place
yeah we'll rip up some
slopes rip it up I say yeah we had a
good time lots of different uh levels of
skiers Dave had never been skiing ever
in his life you know um Kim was a pretty
good snowboarder Aaron was a pretty good
skier both uh Matt and Sarah were were
pretty decent it was nice we were all
able to stay in a group and not really
like separate too
badly those are sounding fun times
dude such good times I love hitting the
mountain fresh air and you know what my
favorite thing about going ski is the
chair left every time I go up the chair
left I smoke a joint I think skiing and
snowboarding are definitely Stoners SC
designed for you almost when you really
think of it well designed for our people
yeah I mean lit literally the I have to
admit like I am also very guilty in fact
sometimes when it's a more miserable day
and you've got a real storm kind of
happening we'll go down to Mid station
just to get on the Gandhi so we can have
a session
nice the gonola we like to call it yes
the
gonola that is of course the um the
excuse that Ross was able to use Ross
reati when he was stripped of his gold
medal in Nago Japan in 1998 oh it's a
secondhand smoke from the gonola that's
what he that's what he blamed absolutely
you to smell this this has got some
unique terpenoids a very um almost I
don't
know it's a sweet sharp smell let's
throw some of that in there oh yeah how'
you like the first one I liked it a lot
it had uh very very strong surprisingly
for Vapor I mean keep in mind for me
Vapor sure after I sit here and and
chain Vapor for an hour with Remo
through six to 10 varieties I'll have
the kind of high that I'm I'm looking
for throughout the day but I often get
that in just a couple of rips of dry
sift or wet wash so I consider you know
vaporizing especially out of a smaller
unit like this more for flavor for the
enjoyment of the herb uh but I literally
after one session on that feel pretty
damn good oh yeah no that's that is
medicine yeah that is medicine in the
sense that you could tell that that is a
pain reliever oh yeah it works for me
all right so here we go on the
kosher give her man Take It Out for a
Rip
eh absolutely
so the kosher has a more earthy taste if
I could explain the two Kush tastes uh
differently th this first one when I
tasted it for whatever reason when I was
tasting it the word platinum came to
mind Platinum I like I was just like oh
this is like Platinum kush or something
this is just so such a nice silvery this
one here is is is deeper in in its Earth
Tones through The Vapor at least I don't
know what the difference would be
through smoking it well it's got a sweet
uh taste to it when you smoke it but
it's uh it's very complex at the same
time it's got other flavors in there
yeah yeah the vapor changed a little bit
as well as of course what you'll notice
with the vaporizer like this
particularly when you're using herb like
this now Remo has not dried this herb
out to bone dry because that would be
very unenjoyable to smoke bone dry herb
makes it harsh harsh and terrible falls
apart you lose resin glands so I don't
know what the moisture content is but
it's it's nice and marshmallowy and and
well cured for for smoking a joint well
she snapping look oh yeah exactly for
sure she's Snapp I'll put this by the
mic okay 3 two 1
sh you hear that yep I heard that
totally yeah no I I don't mean that it's
wet in any way I just mean generally
when you're when you're um oh you don't
want it crispy crispy crispy that would
be bad for for smoking whereas for for
dry uh dry sifting and for vaporiz
making hash would be good though yeah
having it pretty dry is not not such a
bad
thing I guess the tries would fall off a
lot easier when it's absolutely crispy
oh I guess better turn up the heat now
she just turned down on me there we go
back up you go back up you go lot how
lot does that thing get well I'm not
sure I've never set it up past just 400°
right THC seems to vaporize around 387
or 390 or something so
406 I have it set at Fahrenheit right
now I think at 454 it actually ignites
and lights on
Fires exactly so when you when you see
me dump this it won't even be um very
discolored cuz I keep the temperature a
little a bit lower than just a little
bit yellow that looks like that Mexican
weed we used to get in the uh the 80s
there that color there except there'd be
a [ __ ] seeds in it sun uh sun dried yep
sun
dried still a little bit more when it
doesn't fall out good then there's still
more to
hit this is
unreal but I going to light up the the
next joint otherwise I'm not going to be
able to keep up with you
here I doubt that will ever be a reality
Remo no that thing consumes uh faster
than this thing well because you're
consuming much more for sure you you
each joint for you is probably four or
five of these I'm putting in like a
peners worth okay so after this youve
smoked like two
G since we sat down that's insane I'll
be ready for lunch after we're done here
yeah you are going to be ready for lunch
what is it going to be is it going to be
uh Black Sheep Pub whatever they got I
thought it was the cheese uh cheese
steak sandwiches oh American cheese
steak that's
tonight we're going to Steel Panther
little little 80s medal for you in the
year 2015 oh yeah seen them six times
before they kick ass good fun hey oh
yeah you should go yeah you know I
haven't been to a concert in a while I
uh I need to get out more often oh yeah
I like going to the commodor and this is
the number one reason like going to
commodor any show you usually blaze in
there and they leave you alone yeah the
commodor is pretty cool I had an amazing
situation there for a long time um my
friend worked for Sirius an X xxm radio
mhm and so the the front booth at the
commodor next to the stage right in
front of the backstage door yeah was
their
Booth they sponsored it so it was their
booth for every show of every day of the
year perfect yeah it had like a little
thing around it and so my friend who
basically was in charge of getting those
tickets she got six tickets which was
one seat at at each seat in the booth
yeah for every show so every month she
got like hundreds of of tickets to The
Commodore and she just showed me the
list and i' be like a Lee Scratch Perry
I'll go to that Michael Francy I'll go
to that like it was unbelievable for the
longest time the Commodore and of course
if you know this about the Commodore you
know that showing up really late unless
you've got a group of friends and you
know where they are is a bit of a pain
in the ass at the Commodore you it's one
of those places that you show up early
you roll in with a crew you sit down you
get your table and you claim your space
you claim your space you can move around
at that point but you have your home
base the home base the home base at the
commodor man the place gets packed and I
can roll in at 11:30 at night walk up to
that Booth it would be empty right and
just say to the security guard like hey
can you open that it was like a bank
thing you know a little Red Velvet Rope
right right and and we'd go with a pile
of people free tickets you know like 50
60 and even sometimes $80 concert
tickets You' give me six of them wow so
yeah that it felt like the Commodore was
my living room for about two 2 and 1/2
years it felt like that that it was
amazing yeah man those kushes were nice
I got the most beautiful flavor of both
of them right now yeah in the in the um
back of my throat well both those I
consider to be completely top shelf
cannabis and actually this whole plate
those might be my two favorite flavors
on this plate I I would believe that you
know even if I if someone were to ask me
what do you think Remo would like out of
these three I would literally right off
the bat go these three right here you
you pick them those are my three
favorites out of there and know these
are all these are still good don't get
me wrong but this medicates me all of
these have a little bit well I don't
know about this one cuz it's an unknown
to me but these two in general are a
much more euphoric and almost AE high in
the in the sativa sense you've got the
sweet skunk here and you've got the um
c99 the Cinderella 99 which produces
that racy effect of the Astro Boy right
more of a kind of get your mind spinning
than a get your back uh at ease which
these I felt it with both of these well
you know what it's interesting you're
talking about these two these two are a
lot more Floral in Aroma than these
three here these are very cush likee
they have that very dank cush smell this
is like especially this s Sweet gun it
stinks that is stinky stuff well you
know you just said it right there and
we'll learn in the future and I
guarantee you if it's not this exact
thing it'll be very close to it that
that smell that Remo's describing that
musky cushy dankness that that we get
that is literally the smell of pain
relief that is whatever tpine profile
that is or cannaboid tpine profile that
is the smell of pain relief and it seems
as though these more florally more like
exotic sativa ones um they have a whole
other uh variety of of benefits that
they offer I love that they get my mind
racing they really oh they're yeah they
definitely
Speedy oo I love that smell of the Astro
that was growing with an LED light too
oh you were saying that which led light
did you use for that well um originally
the LED light was called uh sunlight led
oh I think I have one of those is it a
big crazy thing with thing and then the
company changed their name to uh was it
a lawsuit or something I'm not sure if
there's a lawsuit but they changed the
name of the company I have to check out
I have the same the veg beautiful oh
yeah the vegging was great and what I
tried to do is grow a big plant mhm I
grew a big plant and the guy warned me
don't get this light closer than two
feet well because the plant kept growing
I kind of had to push the plant off the
that big black one that goes out like
this did it touch the light and get
burned no it didn't but it got um I
don't know at the end maybe 8 8 10
inches away and still wasn't burning or
that's what I'm saying cuz that light to
me feels very cool yeah like comparably
and you know compared to the other LEDs
in the market uh it it's got a great
color it was white light which is good
but we're doing another test with one
that came from Lush lighting I have that
one as well the XL Dominator yeah and
you know what I um last year I went to
Seattle to the um Seattle Cannabis Cup
and I met this guy from christon farms
and he smoked some weed that was grown
with Lush light and it was phenomenal so
you can definitely grow Good Buds with
it I've seen it with my own eyes so um
we got one of these lights and we're
putting to the test rate now and we did
a veg with them beautiful vegging and
now we're making buds so uh this video
will be coming excellent yeah you can
check out Remo's channel for that one I
would not miss that I've tried to do the
same thing with my um Lush light I
wanted to do Lush on one side HPS on the
other have three plants the same three
plants under each light and then have
the same three plants in between both
lights capturing both lights I thought
that would be a really neat way to
capture sort of what the LED light did
what the HPS light did what the
combination of them did cuz constantly
in all of these uh reviews and comp
comparatives there people are always
saying oh I'd rather do this than that
I'm getting to a point in my life where
I prefer to quiver over a single Arrow
you know the best greatest way to do it
the best light bulb the best this the
best that it's like who doesn't want a
quiver a variety of oh I couldn't agree
more yeah you know what the way I look
at it's like being a mechanic and you
have to have all the tools and all the
latest stuff a variety of tools is
definitely essential you know to to get
a beautiful variety such as this yeah
which uh which one you want to try next
well I guess we'll just go right along
the way to the Girl Scout
cookies okay and then uh I guess we'll
you know what I'm going to hit this one
last cuz it's the one I'm most anxious
forless it's the stinkiest I know it's
this is a real uh favorite of a lot of
people that I
know that lemony
smell thought it was the Congo but uh
I'd say it's sweet skunk yeah was a
[Music]
mislabel I wasn't disappointed though
sweet skunk is great weed look at the
density of the buds like if you put
those two side by side I'd say the sweet
skunk might even have that bud you
definitely not in density though uh
sweet skunk um they were a little bit of
an Airy fairy bud but I had um I had
stuff like but as long as my arm of the
sweet skunk was just
crazy yeah it definitely doesn't grow
like this and you seen those G13 buds
they at week six y we're getting some uh
what we call them marijuana swords yeah
your swords yeah exactly the swords we
do battle with they're definitely club
like the Cannabis
swords so that is the Girl Scout cookies
it is excellent and you know what when
you grind it up it's kind of got a an
interesting smell to it it's got a
little bit of sour in there mixed with a
bit of sweet yeah kind of reminds me of
uh weed from Europe for some reason
interesting the
European well I find lot the European
strains has white color has that tone to
it no that's like the the lime green
broken up like that oh you get just
giant big Frosty buds out of it I
couldn't believe like the size of buds
you get kind of reminds me of that
Jamaican string that was around uh a
number years Sugar Shack the the
Jamaican Jamaican spice
bear how many names did it have tons but
you know what tons I call it Fool's go
cuz it used to grow these giant buds but
you know you get immune to this weed
almost right away it was like had lots
of triom on it but it just was not
strong weed I feel that as well but you
can grow buds the size of your head but
man that's why I prefer this the cush
cush doesn't make big butts but it kicks
your ass and you know I need to get
medicated I'm not really interested in
what produces the most I'm what I'm
interested in what works the best for
myself anyway yeah well that's the key
difference for yourself cuz like a lot
of people that are just trying to grow
big buds if they don't have that head
space of like requiring real strength to
ease their pain or for that whatever it
is for them that they get out of using
cannabis whether it's a recreational or
a preventative or a
medicinal
um if you're not getting the potency
like this generally most people that
look to find these big giant plants that
you can grow throughout my history
anyway tons of them are just not potent
you sort of break the mold on that
because you're not just looking to grow
big buds to ship them off into the
marketplace oh you're growing exactly
you're growing for yourself and it's not
like you're just like you don't you
don't want just like a nice recreational
buzz you require a heavy narcotic pain
relief yeah and that's what those kushes
really
offer girl go cookies but you know what
it is
impressive that's
interesting definitely not as strong as
I would say um the headband or the
kosher kush or even that OG Kush but I'd
say it's uh you know if I had to give it
a a mark about maybe a 68 maybe not
quite a seven you know these are nines
and 10 I'd say right
well it's got a nice uh hit to the vapor
a good amount came out right away too
which always tells me a little bit about
the resin that's on the
plant you know what it' be interesting
is actually to test all these strains
and uh see how much THC they actually
have and what the canid profile is is
like how much CBDs cbn's Etc well you
know what I bet you the two of us
between testing the resin and you
testing the plant matter and resin that
we we could pretty much nail it down
pretty pretty well at least where the
strongest lay and where the the sort of
weakest lay and where the smelliest and
the you know there simple things that we
can do through the through our
bioassay well these two right here these
are the strongest actually these three
that's your
Powerhouse they
Ripper that's nice it's enjoyable
it's different weed you know what it's
it's very full smoke when you you know
have it combusted like this it's um it's
got a complete flavor to it
mhm yeah I've smelled quite a few whiffs
from from your smoke as opposed to the
taste of the vapor and it's an
interesting way to uh to add to the
palette it tastes better than it smells
you know what I mean I'm not saying that
in a bad way I know what you mean
totally I've had strains that smell
better than they taste
yeah in the air you know had this
amazing crazy beautiful like exotic
spicy flavor and it's like I can't taste
that flavor I want to taste that flavor
not just smell it in the
air and and this stuff here actually
Burns pry nice so I was going to say the
flame or not the flame the color of the
smoke with the light behind you is three
dark yeah it's dark but it's it's got
that blue which I always sort of look
for in a a cannabis smoke you know as
opposed to that grayish
[Music]
smoke well I hope you guys are puffing
tough with us right now it's not that
often that I get to come over to Remos
and literally just have a puff tough
video no so while he's smoking that
joint I'm going to clear my palette with
a little bit of the full melt dry sift
that we made earlier I hope you guys
went over to his channel to check that
out cuz uh that stuff's insane worth oh
that [ __ ] blows my mind
yeah it's great well that's the [ __ ]
that is that you're that you're that
you're literally using right now you
know
that's what what better easier way for
you to acquire your medicine than
spliffs that are easy to take with you
they're not connected to anything you
can walk around and have them anywhere
you go very easy to use exactly I'll
tell you you don't see me with my denail
up on the chair lift up in Whistler you
know what soon there will be a way I
hope
yeah just give some Stoner a little bit
of time and they'll figure it out some
Stoner out there is working on right now
battery pack you carrying your back it's
like those Vietnam soldiers remember
that for their communication devices
their 2A radio was a big backpack
straight up yeah holy Christ now you got
these little cell phones that are this
big that are computers like get GPS that
weigh like 6 o
yeah well that was a nice clear of my
palette yeah that was I love hitting
dryp that is like so many different
things
mhm it's always a good
thing almost had a bit of a fruity
flavor in there too you should hit that
stuff again because it don't give me a
chance to catch up on this joint yeah
you're smoking uh big joints now Remo
I'm taking little Vapor hits um you know
like a a quarter of a gram to a half a
gram he's smoking like a gram and a half
plus oh no I'm I going complete these
joints I'm going to you know what I'm
going to do I'm going to have the best
half which is the first half and uh
I think that's a great idea it's like
wine tasting you I'll be spitting into
the bucket right the you don't have to
smoke those down to nothing we'll spark
those up later there you go yeah
otherwise we'll be here forever which
you know this audience loves Yeah the
more I do got to go to my office today
yeah well I'd love to take the take them
along and uh give a little lookie at
whatever we can look at it you give you
a at the new Warehouse yeah so this
pretty exciting times in the industry
guys like Remo or making moves they're
starting uh you know he started his own
uh nutrient company and I have a feeling
it's going to be even more than just a
nutrient company no we we actually uh
we're going to expand hopefully into
medibles and uh maybe even paraphernalia
pipes bongs awesome leave it open right
yeah exactly anything yeah no that's
awesome I'm really excited to go check
that out it's always nice to see uh
local people in our community doing well
and uh when Remo does well then many
many many people in the community do
well because of course you know Remo
hires local people yeah well hopefully
one day we'll be able to you know employ
maybe 100 or more people here from Maple
Ridge to work at or waros that's awesome
dude I'm dreaming big but uh well you
got to think big right dude absolutely
no reason not to uh no reason to dream
small I think it was Dane Cook who said
dream it you [ __ ] dreamer it's your
dream yeah this classic Dane Cook comedy
that's awesome that's not comedy that's
reality it is but the way he says it in
the in the comedy skd he's like if I'm
Dreaming I'm going to create a house and
it's going to have Moes and it's going
to have like lakes that go through like
he's just going off on it basically and
why not right well that's what that's
basically the metaphor is if you're
going to dream something up for
yourself then uh why not dream it as big
and as as good as you possibly can
especially double especially when it's
something like what you just said to
hire a 100 people that's not for
yourself all right so let's see we've
hit the headband cush y the kosher cush
y the Girl Scout cookies mhm and now
let's go back into some
potency for the OG cush I just want to
point this up I put this down yeah went
and talk on the phone came back and look
it's still yeah burning beautifully
that's I didn't have to relight it oh
that's definitely
impressive uh when you have Camy
schwaggy food in your herb that
definitely right there does not happen
that's when you're doing this all the
time every puff you're taking you're
lighting your your joint that's uh that
takes me back to high school so that's
the feel how hard that is dude I already
squeezed the tip of this nugget it's
ridiculous like you could smash a window
with that you could smash this with a
hammer and it wouldn't flatten the bud
and you know what that that was never um
that was hung dry too so usually when
you hang dry a plant it dries a little
bit looser but I don't know it just
produces such rock hard indicia buds
it's classic that's why I think G cush
it just like one of those old school
favorites old Gardener I tell you yep
the old
Gardener nice I'm always excited to hit
a little
OG and then we're going to get into the
Astro Boy and the sweet skunk so man
probably have a couple of rips of this
dry sift in between and just be like
super thankful to be able to chill here
with
Remo Blaze through his varieties smoke
his dry sift uh photograph his garden
and you guys knowell this get to share
his company what a bonus woohoo thanks
for coming yeah this this has the
bite oh yeah well that is old school
that's great I guess I better take some
of that Vape it up I better take some of
that these ogs man I'll tell you they
really were game changers you know first
it was the
Diesels I remember when s came up that
New York City Diesel and it was just
like what oh I grew that that made
beautiful big buds oh yeah it can grow
short plants with super giant colas on
it yep it was a good one for sure it was
I guess there's been so many game
changers over the years
yeah I mean really the original game
changer would probably be uh skunkman
Sam's skunk number one you know what
skunk number one is the reason I started
growing cannabis
indoors I remember that basically
changed everything here on the West
Coast not just on the west coast changed
everything in Amsterdam I think it's
really responsible for a lot that
happened in Amsterdam and why I don't
think it's a coincidence that the fact
that he was there with his strain that
that Amsterdam blew up in the coffee
shop so much of the coffee shops in the
late 80s and the early 9s were that
skunk number one yeah it was very very
very pronounced strain in every and and
if it wasn't and they were calling it
something else yeah it would you'd smell
it and be like oh there's some something
in there yeah well you know what I
remember our choices back then you can
go get some uh Brown Mexican weed that
they called Cambodian or Tai weed but
you know you knew was Mexican it was
full of seeds you talking late ' 80s
early '90s we're talking mid 80s right
mid 80s okay and then they had the stuff
they called BC red hair which was a
bunch of outdoor [ __ ] and they just
didn't have any names for it so they
called it red hairs cuz they had lots of
um stigma hairs yeah exactly and
uh then came the skunky the skunk weed
they I remember it came around and
they're charging $40 e and it was wet
sticky weed but it smelled like a skunk
and you'd smoke it and get you way
higher than any of that stuff put
together and uh well you know I couldn't
really justify paying $40 for an a like
you know that's kind of what made me
consider growing yeah that was the
roadkill skunk now the roadkill skunk is
different from skunk number one and I'm
not exactly sure maybe one day I'll I'll
do a show on it or something because I
also remember the the road kill SC I got
my herbal unit steak that's a habit
sorry never be sorry for handing me a
joint my
brother oh yeah there's some weed I'm
falling behind again I to get this OG I
was just enjoying that cookies though
you smoked it down almost down to a
roach I know the OG is nice it's got
that I mean that's OG without a shadow
of a doubt
OG but it's I I don't know all that it's
got very the terpenoids are very floral
yeah you can sure taste them you sure
can taste them after when you hit the
vapor on your lips it's amazing you
should try a little tiny hit of that
okay I won't see enough
cheers holy [ __ ] this thing works great
that's what I'm saying dude I've been
loving all your
flavors The Taste on the lips that's
nice oh yeah
just to be able to like for me to be
able to taste all these varieties and
get a nice head space on them and
experience the profiles wirelessly
without like I don't know I'm really
just stoked on technology I'm stoked on
all these companies right now that are
producing all these great little units
yeah I've uh I got a touch with volcano
recently and they've got new little
Wireless um units oh no way so I have
one of those coming I think it's called
The
Mighty and uh I'll I'll be doing a
review on that soon to see uh I mean
basically what I'm looking for in a unit
is obviously many many pulls an easy
charge that it's you know easy to to
handle and hold and doesn't break easy
but also that there's no plastic or
rubber or any type of that taste in the
herb cuz to me that's like a game Ender
I just can't do that if it's got a weird
taste where it's like oh they used a
strange component or the rubber wasn't
the highest end rubber I'm done even
containers I don't like you know the
little rubber containers that uh a lot
of people were using for a while they're
going to affect the taste and smell yuck
they gasing some sort of weird toxin
into your body as well well that's what
I'm saying cuz that nice tasty herb you
know what I like how portable this unit
is and I like how portable you know
they're letting medicating becomes cuz
you can be on the go we could be out
dirt biking and doing this right now
100% ring this would be a situation
where I could see this working for Remo
in a situation where you know he's at a
concert or something he's smoking a
joint and for whatever reason the guy
the the security guard says hey you
can't do that or whatever and he's like
oh that's weird and so he just puts the
joint down and pulls this out of his
pocket it's just like I'll just oh I
don't want to do that I want to keep
blazing my joint of course you do but it
would be a nice backup wouldn't it I
guess for backup yeah in an Investor's
meeting maybe that would be the
application yeah they're not down with
you whipping out big bags of weed and
rolling up joints in the middle of those
meetings been a few they should be
because that's really what it's all
about well you know I've been to Bay
Street now and uh well the whole they're
very excited about the whole weed
industry and what we're doing like all
of it like you know what and I think
having Bay Street and legitimate
investors get involved in cannabis will
help legalize and legit make it
legitimate for for all of us well I'll
tell you something if one of the things
when your company really has this
exponential growth that I'm sure it's
going to have and you guys have your lab
and your scientists working for
different you know to tweak the
nutrients in different ways I hope that
one of the things that you guys do is
figuring out a way to I don't want to
say manipulate but say increase or make
more available whatever it is that the
plant requires to produce um the vacs
and the plastids that are produced
inside the triome head that produce the
phenols and the tpin that produce all
the cannabinoids that we use now if we
could figure out a way to tune nutrients
to resin growth and phenol and turpine
production inside the gland head before
canabo are even cooked into existence I
think the advantage there will be
enormous tremendous and I really see
that I I I I get excited about it
thinking that you know someone like you
be done it's just we have to you know do
research SP a lot of learning right
exactly it's just a matter of learning
but I think so as well I don't think
that focusing on the vegetative
structure of the plant is going to
produce the best medicine in the end I
think we'll have to focus our our focus
on or change our Focus onto the resin
the resin well you know what that's what
I'm focused on is uh resin and
definitely uh lots of tricomes on the
planet this is important to me well
that's CU you're an end user and that's
the best thing that that's the thing
that no matter what like companies like
yours and mine and many other it's like
I always sort of saw that respect in a
guy like uh breeder Steve who he was a
real smoker he he knew what potency was
he was he loved all the extracts and the
hashes joints and Bong rips and you know
what I mean like the guy covered the
whole gamut I always respected that he
was a breeder because I thought well he
really knows what strong is
sorry that's okay man you have just
smoked about five five five or six grams
of cannabis now since we've been sitting
here oh yeah I'm definitely High good
day for Remo good day for bubble man
yeah the room we're in is super Smoky
too and it's a big room yeah we let the
air out already wants to you're right
both doors yeah that's
hilarious we're hot boxing here today
well I think I'm almost done on this OG
okay I'm halfway done so the next one's
Astro Boy Astro Boy from TGA
genetics oh you know what let me one sec
I got to find out the name of this LED
light ah yes the LED
light well I'll maybe grind up a little
uh
my little Astro Boy
perfect she empty she's empty Remo
doesn't leave Herb in his grinder after
rolling a joint I would highly doubt
such a
thing man you'd be the ultimate person
to test a grinder wouldn't you yeah oh
no I'll put it through the test I grow a
lot of um all right burn a lot of dues
during the day so uh
okay the new name the company is
Spectrum
King Spectrum King
led.com you can check them out guys
that's the light that Remo and I were
both talking about that we uh I haven't
bloomed with but he has yeah and in fact
heom that's got that nice Astro Boy
smell wow Fruity Fruity
yeah all right so let me put a little of
this in here
excited to hit the Astro Boy grown by
Remo y that's sweet dude oh you've been
growing a long time haven't you um yeah
how long have you been growing uh under
the mm program since the beginning like
2001 or something or oh I think um I was
like patient number 70 something wow
yeah actually I had this thing even
before the mm had the thing called the
yeah yeah I think they still have them
actually yeah I think it's the more
potent of the of the licenses actually
yeah section 56 I believe allows for
research and
development well I'm into developing
that's for sure and definitely
researching we're doing research right
here right now I'm loving this research
I'm loving that my Trippy Stick pen is
still uh the herbal unit here is just
going strong um I've blazed through four
different kinds so far I'm ready to hit
my fifth the unit's not too hot it's a
little bit warm in the center here but
otherwise pretty pretty good and just
excited to hit that as boy so excited in
fact what I like to do is hit it as it's
just heating up oh yeah so you get that
low temperature Vape exactly those
really really volatile turpins is that a
nice ring in the smoke that was it was
almost like a Galaxy oh yeah I'm not
stoned at all you know what I find those
low temperature uh Vape be very
sweet very tasty actually really tasty
well you can just taste that the the
turpine has literally been like gently
evaporated rather than like almost semi
combusted or
sublimated yummy jeez we've done a lot
we photograph your plants with the macro
lens we've done done a couple videos
inside the the room yeah we've done a uh
a great video on these six Buds which
really I'm I hope that you guys watch
his video
first I'll say it in the comments and
I'll even leave a link to go watch the
video of him showing with the camera
Remo showing all the different Buds and
explaining them that'll be the video you
watch first then you can come back and
watch this one so we've got a variety of
videos today that you'll have to watch
in a hopscotch kind of order and I'll
have links the other way too to your
channel absolutely and so Urban grower
Urban grower is uh the Youtube channel
no it's actually an urban rmo urban rmo
that's right see urban urban rmo channel
is now way bigger than the urban G
Channel problem that Urban G channel
it's got a lot of copyright
infringements and I got a lot of trouble
on that channel that's just pretty you
knew at it yeah so um I just started
another Channel I did the same thing and
holy crap I think I'm almost up to
90,000 K I saw recently you were very
close to 90,000 K so congratulations on
that check out Urban Ramo on YouTube for
the videos oh yeah we'll see you there
some killer videos actually thanks man
mhm and see bubble man and some of the
videos as well REO was actually one of
my big Inspirations on doing my channel
he showed me what camera to get um just
showed me a little bit of tips and just
from watching his videos I was able to
sort of be like all right I can probably
do a channel here and cool well you know
what your Channel's awesome it's uh got
a lot of good information and if you
know if you're a real hash
connoisseur you got to be checking out
bald man's world for sure or be part of
it yeah even better be a part of it M
I'll tell you that Astro Boy has a real
nice taste so here we go Astro Boy here
we go totally different high it's up
here in the
head it's the first one that I felt
really strong in my
head you know what this is really smooth
too it's almost got a you know when you
inhale first it's almost a cherry flavor
I was going to say that could be your
dessert joint yeah you know when you're
sitting down for your three course meal
you might have a a serving of a head
band and a serving of OG with a side
order of kosher kush but then for
dessert you're going to order up that
that Astro Boy and I think it really is
that c99 cuz here the the Apollo 13 and
the Ortega are both very like strong
very much like these three right but the
c99 is that sativa dominant racy kind of
fruity flavor that you get really nice
so what would be the salad course though
well the salad course of course the
sweet skunk the sweet skunk the sweet
skunk is
so light and enjoyable that people that
don't even smoke pot can enjoy the sweet
skunk it's almost like if you dislike
fish but someone says oh here try this
um Indian candy which is the maple gra
oh yeah make even people that don't like
salmon yeah they'll eat that stuff
they'll eat that stuff and be like this
isn't fish it's like no it is trust me
so I think of the sweet skunk as that
very one it's the uh it's the Indian
candy of uh of cannabis it's even if you
don't enjoy pot I've never seen it
produce an anxiet as high in anyone you
know women like the stream women love
this string my wife who barely ever well
she doesn't smoke at all anymore but she
barely um uses cannabis um she does use
essential amino acids and she produces
her own endocannabinoids but she doesn't
use cannabis in a smoking or
recreational manner very often but when
she wants to relax that skunk this is
the sweet skunk that she I'm I'm
actually going to I was I was going to
say if I could grab one little bud not a
big bud like this but a little bud for
the wife oh yeah for sure you'll
appreciate that remember when Steve
cubby was around this was one of his
favorites too back back in the day yep
and I understand that because if he was
able to smoke it Steve smoked an an
unruly amount of cannabis just an
impressive amount much like yourself I
don't know what it was but it was at
least an ounce a day and I remember at
one point it was ridiculous big long
joints even like 2 plus ounces a day and
I was kind of like man that's like
that's that's too much smoke and then he
went and got his lungs tested at this
big facility down in California yeah and
they they said his lungs were that of
like a young um athlete mhm so and this
was when he was 48 years old so I was
pretty impressed that uh sort of proof
is in the pudding that like even in my
own mind thinking that that much smoke
couldn't be bad it still wasn't bad for
Steve cubby keep in mind Steve cubby has
a very rare form of adrenal gland cancer
he has tumors that are growing on his
adrenaline gland and they pump
adrenaline into his bloodstream uh
constantly 24/7 and many people that
have this disease like a huge percentage
most they pass away at an early age from
either a heart attack or a stroke
because imagine having that that acid
running through your veins it would just
it would just erode your or um your um
what's the word I'm looking for arteries
it would erode your arteries and so
that's what ends up happening strokes
and heart attacks but Steve is one of
the oldest surviving victims of that
disease I think he's even on some
medical books did you ever get the
chance to go skiing with him I never did
no way I wish I did yeah I know I went
skiing with him a few times he was crazy
very fast had these really super long
skis and he started a ski magazine in
the US and maybe West yeah in the 80s or
something so I don't doubt that Steve um
was a is a great skier actually Steve um
got me into skiing again um I I didn't
ski for a decade cuz after my accident I
figured I was done and he was like oh no
there's people out there with no legs
you know skiing and they crippled people
with one legs and you know you just go
out there and you do what you can senior
citizens do it and then he got me a set
of skis solid scramblers for Christmas
and made me do
it he just take it easy and uh well you
know before long you know cuz I seeed a
lot when I was young yeah uh me and
steeve were ripping it up and uh thanks
for that because because of that I
actually started skiing with my son
every year where was he living back then
uh Sun Peaks Resort he was living at Sun
peeks yeah
cool and now you're ripping it up with
your boy yeah he's been skiing for 10
years now and uh it's very cool he's got
really good actually there's a video of
them on 710 Riders I went skiing
recently with them and uh we went down
the mountain together I put the my
helmet on and I don't like skiing the
helmet it totally sucks yeah but I I got
a great video of my son doing it so
check it out 710 Riders on YouTube hell
yeah I personally always ride with a
helmet I'm totally paranoid one good
smack on the ice and it's like you have
to learn how to walk and I was just like
Sunny Bono he died from that yeah he
smoked a tree pretty good if you have a
helmet and you hit a tree you could
still die very easily but um you uh yeah
here we go how's it going Swan it's all
right all right right on right on we
only have one flavor left in our six
flavor platter here we're running the
gauntlets today you're about halfway
done your Astro Boy jointed I might just
break off a little snap of this okay
here's a
grinder oh yeah that's that's that's got
that Airy Airy sort of wonderful sweet
skunk smell I I am a huge fan personally
it's one it's one of my favorite sativas
I have to say so that's our dessert for
the today that's the dessert yes so I
better put in enough so you can roll
yourself The Joint you know what as your
grinding that up I should show off this
chunk of hash we're looking at earlier
this was a Christmas
present this was actually one
piece there we go ball of hash for
Christmas Christmas hash we'll call it
is that your Christmas hash yeah and
look at this we'll break it open
Christmas
Dash and maybe at the end we'll try this
non-stop trying non-stop Rock here
bubble man's world oh God smell that
one whoa you know you can smell the the
lemonade on that tiny and I would say
that I've I've learned recently that
there's a fair amount of tpin that have
that orangey sort of smell yeah uh
lemony even
citrusy there's mercine and there's
mercine not as much it's the one that's
in mangoes um there's Valencia or
valencene Sor which is found in
valencene oranges right and then of
course delemon which is uh very not I
wouldn't say popular but the one that
you find a larger amount of often most
common yeah definitely the most common
one in uh in standard
oranges I think that's what um Horatio
is using in his in his extract in his
extract he extracts lemoning delemon
from Orange Rines and separates it out
and then uses that tpine as a solvent to
strip resin off of cannabis plants
brilliant yeah it's I think I tried some
of that I think I had some of that I
think I had some of that yesterday in
back no I wouldn't be surprised at all
he makes uh he's M makes his way around
he's also doing dry sifting now he's
learned uh a couple of Tricks oh John B
came over oh right there it is Johnny B
that would be it yep he's always got
some of her ratios he was the first
person to in introduced me to her ratio
in
fact makes a really good extract that
guy yeah shelf all good gu really uh
conscious of what he's doing and aware
and wants to make sure things are done
to the utmost of safety so his lemine
extract was really a reply to the butane
culture that was the BHO uh guys that
were all making a lot of butane oil he
felt that it was fairly dangerous on a
multitude of levels both for the contam
that were potentially oil soluble being
trapped in the resin from the solvents
and then put into the body but then of
course the more simpler completely
unarguable um explosions like it was
just like kids blowing themselves up
been some fires yeah you know burn
themselves up terrible stuff so uh this
was his sort of reply maybe I can
produce something that still allows them
to dab that's still in oil that's still
potent but just doesn't use this sort of
hydrocarbon to do the extraction mhm so
I thought it was really
cool uh of him to come up with that and
do that I don't think he was the
originator by any means but he
definitely was one of the uh one of the
first people here in British Columbia
doing it on a conscious level right on
I'm sure you'll Inspire others to do the
same mhm oh you got to learn that's the
thing it's not like a BHO thing where
you just like go online and are like oh
I can do this now like what he's doing
with d lemoning is serious chemistry
that you would really require even just
having a conversation with him about it
if you don't understand in chemistry is
can be somewhat over over your
head I have found anyway cuz I'm no
chemist myself
yeah sweet skunk ripping I've almost got
the sweet skunk joint roll excellent
well cheers dude this has been an
absolute pleasure hitting this platter
with you it's been Ripper man absolutely
Ripper yeah it really has been one more
joint to go foro as he sits here and I
don't know
smokes six joints six joints yeah six
six big joints too like I'm sure that's
a 2 G joint or a 1 and2 G joint yeah
there's some cannabis in there for
sure well good Ana if you're going to
smoke cannabis you may as well smoke big
joints of cannabis yes absolutely the
the song is smoke two joints not one
joint right mhm I think if if it was
your song it might be like smoke six no
it might even be more ridiculous like
smoke 112 joints in the morning oh yeah
I wouldn't be able to get out of the
house though that be a lot of dedication
and rolling joints and be be stuck home
dude I saw your asay for today don't
don't try to fool me oh no that was
yesterday's
ashay just this I'll show a picture of
it there right now that this is Remo's
as that I think Swan's going to bring it
over here I have a picture picture of it
yeah I'll like uh I'll uh embedd it into
the video so it shows the nice backyard
with the this is post
noon post noon post noon roach
collection yeah look at that
yummy you could have interns surviving
up oh there we go yeah that was about my
fourth or fifth rip and I just got the
strong sweet skunk flavor come out now
there it is I'm going to do some
catching up here
how's the
salad good toss good I'm enjoying
it good vegetable matter
here yeah I love that flavor really nice
one to finish it off with having all
these heavy heavy heavy kushes and then
going into the fruity AST boy and then
the really light exotic sort of lemony
sativa yeah no complaints
there well that's been quite the
session you know next time allow
somebody to help smoke these joints dude
I think it was awesome I think I have a
feeling that people will be very
inspired to sit down and and watch you
smoke uh six joints like it was nothing
U my most popular video is and and this
is once again you like oh just my
supercharged joints people love that so
one day I did the pure hash joint video
yeah I've seen that one video has almost
half a million views on it wow yeah just
from smoking one gram of hash but you
just smoked like maybe about the same
amount 1 to 1 and a 12 grams of hash in
like six fat joints that's probably
probably you know 8 to 12 gram of herb
you just consumed and on that 8 to 12 G
of herb there's probably like 1 to 2 G
of
speaking of Ash can we finish this thing
off maybe with one of those dabs with
that really crazy [ __ ] right there I
don't know if the camera can you see
that oh yeah I've got pictures of that
as well I'll show that to them and we
will get a nice dab prepped for Remo yay
I love that you have this Grand Finale
brand new little brush that you just
happened to have was just perfect you
know you're a stoner when I mean
honestly
dude you just have everything I'm like
do you have any
parchment you're like yeah
of course I have
everything let's see you might have
to on this one okay well this is the
grand finale here here we go okay
actually I'll get
this six joints and a rip of full m dry
sift
cheers
beautiful yeah
out of this
world that was incredible yeah dude
awesome awesome puffing with you as
always yeah likewise man I guess we're
going to wind it down maybe go have a
tea or a little drink of water we got
some water right here actually and some
right some food we just puffed tough we
need food more cookies hope you guys
enjoyed it's always a pleasure coming to
visit Remo the urban grower and stay
tuned for the bonus the warehouse visit
oh yeah see you guys soon see you there
[Music]