[Music]
the sun's going to be right in my eyes
it is I should probably have my shades
on
all right Johnny be anytime you're
ready
just I sitting my 420 alarm actually
awesome just in case you never know what
happens we it will be 420 did you get it
set yeah no I said 420 okay let's start
it off here okay
hi hey guys welcome to Bubble man's
world Johnny B is in the house it's a
little bright in here it's a little
bright in here it's the Future's So
Bright we got to wear shades where's
your Shades John they're in the car
they're in the car that's a couple
stories
away yeah I'm not going downst forget it
well welcome to Puff Wednesday guys I
just uh myself got back from Jamaica and
John you've been hard at
work yeah well cfty Sunday's being every
day this week nice yes every day was
cfty Sundays every day so you had a crop
come down yes we had uh we had some uh
we had some nice resin this uh this is
not the LED resin this is all the other
resin okay still very nice resin I'm
sure yeah so you know what
um the best thing about this whole line
right here is this one right here my
friends because I know I think it was
about 19 years ago at least 1995 it was
20 years now 20 years you brought back a
seed it was in November of
1995 I heard they tape somewhere
too interesting
yeah but anyways
um we did try the bun on the vaporizer
on the sub we tried that in the very
beginning and and this morning I put
together this nice little
package that is the full melt the
Jamaican full melt first
bounce oh wow that's really beautiful
I'll give you guys a little bit of an up
close and personal so while we're
looking at it of course as always you'll
be able to see it uh really nice color
and Purity on that I think the the best
part of all we get macro photos too yes
got to get the macro photos so you can
really see the level of Purity that
we're dealing with here we're not
playing around I I I actually puffed one
of these on boby's birthday while you
were in Jamaica celebrating the bash
there I was puffing on the Jamaican nice
nice brother respect you know what so
and then of course I made the dry sift
and out of respect I haven't even tried
it yet first I brought the whole
container and that is for you all right
well that give thanks Johnny B that's
like the nicest anyone could ever you I
I it's it's it's something that you
brought back for us for everyone who's
been able to actually uh I'll let you
know that it's creamy well let's let you
get let's get you try it your first hit
oh come on your first hit your first
first H dude I've got to give it back to
you I got to give it up to Johnny
B all right here we go let's see what
Johnny B has to
say
uh that's what I
forgot the carb
cap oh that seemed to work pretty well
actually take that from you
sir different kind of head space on that
Jamaican
huh yes got you
bopping I started hearing a little bit
of Bob H yes a little bit of Bob well I
sure heard a lot of Bob in Jamaica this
year obviously being his 70th
birthday Lamb's bread Jamaican 1995
orange Hill Jamaica thank you random
American who gave me the bud as a
wedding gift as I had just been married
to my wife on the beach the night
before and um that's a little bit of a
well maybe it's going back to Jamaica
where it came
from that sure would be the dream I'll
tell you you know a full circle like
that would be pretty
amazing I think it was talked about when
you po that that seed when he popped was
there five of
them eight eight one and one popped one
popped I remember putting the few in the
little planter to see if they might
actually
grow oh that's nice real
nice very subtle taste not sharp like
these new hybrids of today I I almost
got this
light background thing going on but as
as the hit dissipates you can taste it
deeper and deeper in your throat I feel
it in the back of my eyes and very
relaxing and and just like cerebral in a
sense there's definitely relief in
hitting it almost immediately yes in the
head like a loosening of the eard drums
I like say I'm feeling it right here
like for the first time like how you're
saying it just behind the eyes and stuff
very nice superb Johnny B give thanks
for that a oh you know like I I got some
of the herb to Puff on but uh that I
will guarantee be getting some more
probably um in aable three months
beautiful hopefully I have some in well
there you go but I I have enough to make
some hash with bubble hash I can finish
it off that's just a that epic first
bounce that I always talk about so first
bounce is always was very nice
Congo uh Congo let's leave the Congo for
second last because that is one of my
favorites like literally one of my
favorites and let's go with I mean your
medic Kush that go second last or third
last after the Congo this is this is
something that's very unique this is you
said last though right this is the
Haley's comment and this is that's last
for sure and that's all I got that's the
anti- THC just just a tiny bit be
completely straight once we hit that one
well this here is the is the number four
number two mix number four number two
mix and what about this one here well
this is actually the first bounce of the
of the med of the med okay this this was
just down on the
screen then I trimmed
up and I got more of what are you
feeling
nice so this would be number four number
two number four number two number four
number
two Romulan OG and Larry OG I was I was
told it was a Larry OG crossed with a
ramlin so I had said LR Kush kind of
made sense mhm that's it kind of made
sense that's the name of it yeah so all
right well I'm excited this looks very
buttery very tasty but this is actually
a lot of a lot of seeds that were popped
to find these oxy FAL that I liked I've
number a few few but I know some of them
didn't come back that nice some of them
were hard didn't didn't uh grow that
well but uh these particular ones
were were the tasty
ones I think it's gone up to a few
people's Gardens now
so that was lovely it's one of my
favorites real nice I really enjoy that
one yeah it's it's it's uh smooth as
butter too
my goodness Flor I mean I can't believe
it 34 pretty decent size RI 34 day
flush yeah I'm not sure that the flush
has much to do with the smoothness of a
resin compared to the smoothness of an
herb I think that there's something
going on in the Cure of the of the plant
matter and you know sometimes it's even
just maybe the luck of the draw of the
Tarpin that are present and that you get
a profile of Tarpin that even at a young
age are peeling and smooth and then you
get a variety of strains that require
more of a cure so the harsher more
volatile sharper tpin that hurt the
throat are able to dissipate evaporate
whatever and then eventually unveil the
the subtes or cesin or monotes the ones
below that are kind of waiting to
shine but can't until those other things
have been cured out very nice nice so
that was first the Jamaican beautiful
beautiful resin really nice color on
that a lamb's bread hybrid and then we
hit the number two number four so the
number four was um uh an old world py uh
sand strain is what I'm told hit with
the Larry
OG so these are Pani land R cross with
the lemon OG or yeah was the L OG
yeah whatever it's an OG and it was you
know one of those of those strains we
don't need to get so particular it was
can of everybody always asked and I
always called number two number four and
these were just particular beans that is
this the one we just didit yes all right
well lovely one are we just doing the
whole
on well yeah I think it's h it's
important I sat here just recently with
d420 K and we slammed back 11 rips of
his full melt dry sift I think we should
be able to hammer back six of yours oh
well that's we might even get into maybe
some of his yeah we've got four of his
right here so if we feel we want to do
the 10 uh the 10 rip Gauntlet we can go
ahead but who knows you know you've got
some Congo there and I got to say Congo
is a game changer when it comes to
gauntlets we're we going to do the Congo
roughly in about 3 minutes for 420 oh
nice is that how close we are yeah yeah
4 minutes till till 4:20 I hope you guys
are getting ready to join us if you
haven't already if you haven't already
you know what um I'm I'm going to grab
the first bounce of the medy but then be
the Congo 420 nice might come back with
a medy again because the sun is shining
it is getting a little hot well kind of
warm yeah ready to ready to get puffing
here and kind of wanted to show this
cool shirt that the cool people from era
420 sent me in Brazil that is really
cool I like that yeah medicinal
solution thanks bro thanks for the for
the for the send
for the tea much
appreciated so very nice very nice
flavor on the four and two is that now a
cross of the four and two or just two
plants one one number four one number
two and you mix their
dry five five five
plants wow that one's got to
bite it's good to have a
bite and so this
was
medy first bounce medy first bounce all
right medy first bounce here we go myy
first
bounce
lovely
yeah that's real nice you could Rock
yourself if you took a real big fat dab
of that one I just did and as you can
see I'm coughing trying not to I'm
easing off now thro's getting better
yeah I took just a mediumsized rip and
it was actually quite smooth got me a
little bit of a head ringer where I'm
kind of right
yeah it's nice isn't it mhm three big
rips three nice rips can't go wrong with
that right there
and I'll have to of course photograph
each one so we can get in on that macro
level and see the subtle differences of
each
one because there are differences now
we're getting into
Congo yeah oh that's
exciting Congo is just good for a head
rip to hit medy Kush and then just back
it up with a Congo rip is insane it's
going to pretty much
o that was nice and smooth once you
warmed it up a little bit yeah I found
that one I I went to clean my tool off
it heated up and I stuck in my resin
don't do
that yeah
look getting it ready one minute warning
for our 4:20 on a puff Wednesday guys
cooling it down man cooling it down we
don't need no hot dabbers here no hot
dabbers we don't need no hot dabbers in
this house hot dabbers cool that thing
down you don't be putting your hot metal
Dabber into your friend's perfect dry
sift and just melt the whole lot of
it is it
420 are we feing out it is 420 look at
that all right brother happy 420 man
respect respect was a little bit of a
off bump off bump it wasn't off bump I
was looking at that it was like falling
apart there we kind of white guy out
there
all right cono Bango get in there get in
there Johnny B says all right
then passing it over it's a puff puff
pass still
420 oh that's a nice taste right
there I mean come
on that is that is
real you want to finish
it real nice taste on that Congo it's
unreal exotic lemony with some other
just different spicy flavors in there
that I are hard to explain I'd love to
see the tarine profile on it so I could
understand it
better that's a strong resin too oh it's
um trimming it up was
so just reeks it just rre even bumping
into it in the room crazy makes it reek
even when it was on my deck and we would
walk by and just tap it it was wreaking
no it's it's definitely got a very very
very unique smell and everybody that
smells it in the
jars right away they're like oh my God
what's that yeah like right away it's
and then the sift like I didn't do that
yet cuz I just had a couple buds but the
sift this
morning Wicked Strong man oh man I mean
we did just hit three other full melt
rips but that one that one makes me
really want to like relax and just
really
enjoy how
how medicated I
am not that I have a lot of pain or
anything a little bit that I did have
from traveling the last few
days disappeared with the
Congo such a nice uh
profile we even going to leave the lid
off of
that I can't wait to photograph each one
and sort of see in a close you know
version of what the resin looks like got
my macro lens right here guys so I'll be
uh yes we'll be
going from one I will from
1 to
21 to
31 to
41 and finally
51 now that gets in there that's when
you really are getting close that's when
you're getting so close it's insane
yeah the phones are great with their
cameras but they just can't quite
replicate the level of that m
when I was seeing when he had the shots
and he actually had images in the back
and stuff like that it's quite quite
cool that you can actually yeah that's
that's just a flavor that I know how to
describe it
Beau
cush yeah very
cushy supremely cush so we can go this
is this is like all there there just
that the rest is um definitely going to
be uh be making
medicine W so we better uh photograph
this before we rip it yeah I think so
cuz that's all there is is this the last
one yeah that's all there was very very
minimal of the haly from from I mean of
the flavors have we hit that one
yet we not this no not this one then I
guess we better hit that one and then
we'll do this one but I'll photograph it
first because you guys want to see this
I'm sure I know I do I'm curious too
really am I was really disappointed I
only got this amount off it but I really
didn't want to I just let it hit the
screen I didn't want to agitate it or
anything because I don't want to Rob
anything from it so I mean except all
the
resin what's some all the resin it's
like the medy there was so much it was
so coated like when it hit the screen it
was like poof oh yeah it was really and
it's it
it yeah it's marshmallow
well shall we medy down Med it down
shall we you
shall heat her up cool it
down get we should have a rag
sometimes yeah I just kind of do this
thing here where I roll off the resin
pretty clean then put it on the uh I
have to say that the the new mother ship
is uh quite uh quite a nice quite nice
head I like it a
lot yeah the Fab egg sure is
beautiful it did a great job on
them amazing that that's a production
piece like that blows my mind
okay you
know all right dabbers cooled down
fingers are
clean I'm going in Johnny
B I have to say that this was uh
I I just this is one I always say this
is one I always say is my M it's one I
like the most
mhm have you had mad sessions on the
Congo yet though no I only did one
exactly I did one just wait and I'm
telling you look at it I
know I can't wait and and really in
reality I I'm still like it's all and I
mean I'm sure what everyone's waiting
for is the medic Congo the medic Congo
coming soon from fellow seats the medic
cono no medic cono why not people would
love it dude think of those two strains
together oh would be insane come on both
ways female male male
female yeah it would be probably pretty
insane out of everything you gave me I
was pretty much the most stoked on medic
Kush
It produced I made real nice uh bubble
from it it makes really nice I I love
the flavor I love it effects strong I
mean it's it's it's strong it's really
nice
flavor it's a nice nice tasting strain
I'm going come on now and uh the Congo
is just I don't know maybe because it
was the Forbidden for so long but really
I think there's something to it it is it
is an unbelievably
it's one of the most well it's by far
the most uh like the strongest tasting
rip that we've had today the flavor on
that is very very strong sharp strong
this just like uh it's interesting that
it's over at this end compared to the
Jamaican which was very subtle you know
the
flavors and I wonder if that's because
it was grown here and it's used to a sun
grown you know I wonder if the profile
if we if we're able to to bring it back
to
Jamaica if that profile will increase
through the Tropical Sun and and give us
flavors that we were missing out here
that would be an interesting
experiment I have to go under the LED
next mhm yeah absolutely it sure has it
sure has the strength I'll tell you and
and uh that would be interesting because
that's one thing I did see
actually now just thinking about it when
I I looked at what what I should would
call is like there's money Zone on
there's this Zone there's three
different zones and with the Jamaican It
produced the resin all the way down very
similar the bud structure was very
decreased when we got down to the bottom
and with the LEDs it was just a bigger
bud structure at the bottom than there
was compared that was the only real
comparison MH but the resin production
with with well I I am enjoying it nice
dude yeah I'm sure glad I have one or
two I guess I have two LEDs right now
that I've got
going I'm blooming on under uh x2x L
Dominator right now I've got an Astro
Boy and oh what are all the strains that
Tim gave me K
Berry atomical Haze
maybe Congo nice Barb
Afghani yeah blooming
away that was nice
e yeah only did half of it that's okay
you took a big one not a big one is
still a pretty big
one I was a little excited in the
beginning hit them hard coughing a
little bit have to slow down excellent
you know well it were really nice
flavors man stoked that you have such a
nice stash that you're rolling with and
you're harvesting plants as always and
bouncing and making water hash too I'm
sure yeah I actually um have to get on
that me too working on the room first I
really need to get on that
I know I need to basically run a 20
gallon
batch that's what I need to
do yeah you doing a 20-gon batch yeah I
think I'll do a 20-gallon batch and just
uh you know stop doing all these
independent plants that I have all
separated in in in bags I think I'm just
going to like put all of them into one
20-gon batch and I'll do like bubble
man's you know Lucky Day profile it's
like one of my full harvests just P put
into bubble hash that's called laziness
catching up with you right there when
you get too busy and you don't have the
time to put into the water hash that you
spent all this time segregating all your
plants into different containers yeah I
have that right now yeah me too yeah I
know I'm ready to just like do a
20-gallon batch though that's a pretty
good idea or two or three or two or
three yeah well you know what that was
one thing about Amsterdam with the types
of hashes in that so so there there's
people REM mixing a lot of different
that's one thing that was uh
sure to make big batches just do it a
mix tastes good it does look how baked
we are isn't this great well actually
quite enjoying it you know it's been a
while just sitting here getting I feel
like I was just here a week ago with
d420 K doing this very same thing I
think you are actually I like it yeah
it's kind of relaxed it's nice this
could be an intro for all I know you
know you never know with John and I this
right here could be puff Wednesday and
it could be the and that would be fine
you know we went through six different
varieties of full melt dry sifts we
still have a d420 K's dry sift and one
of mine that I cleaned here well it's
yours there you can see the difference
between a a long cure and a fresher cure
you see the difference in the colors how
this has a reddish brown to it this is
more blonde
today yep definitely have to get picture
of that for sure yeah could have picture
all of these yeah no that was you can
subtle differences just how you said the
three subtle differences is where that
one's probably a couple weeks old that's
really here this is fresh and the colors
are just like pretty white though
surprisingly
yeah is a diesel oh we got to hit that
thank go buddy let's do it you start it
off this Diesel's like really tasty
flavor savior it's good yeah New York
City it's damn fine D 420k thank you
buddy yeah Johnny B d420 K myself always
representing I should have Horatio cuz I
have a little his Pineapple Express that
would should be here at the table as
well and then uh feel like uh that's
pretty darn good to have all my friends
uh inspired into learning
the the trade of sift
[Music]
cleaning all
right guess I better hit that too
huh
wow
that's well I'm becoming speechless
because my throat's just like ah and I'm
definitely um well you could just
say I've
smoked this lucifa blocks got to F it
goad got you got to take a photo of it
first the real test PTO right
here I'll get a quick shot of it or or a
few quick shots of it really curious
like this is something you know what
what's
what's the difference is I don't see a
difference in Glad if it's if it's THC
or CBD or you know if there's any
difference in anything at all I don't
know if it's how clean it is or anything
so just get a couple of
shots so the theory is behind CBD blocks
the fork effects of TC so if this being
high CBD and htio says he just does a
heavy hit of something that's high CBD
could bring you
down I'm curious because this is
actually just
a I don't know yeah we were noticing it
with Matt's CBD Renee yeah see curious
we smoked it for 10 days in Amsterdam
this
year and uh it was definitely
still pretty
contaminated not as clean as the Congo
or that Jamaican or any of those other
ones yeah I think yeah I think I only
looked at the Jamaican and the
Congo but I'll make sure I go over them
and get some nice fresh
pictures
well I definitely have the ringing of
the ears and
everything the ringing of the
ears well that's a few shots to give you
guys an idea of what the quality is
there I definitely say it's of a lower
quality compared to what else he's got
here but you want to start it off with a
rip there Johnny
B A little Ripper a little
Ripper
kind of sacrilegious after hanging out
with skunkman Sam and Rob Clark in
Amsterdam this past last year at the
Canabis cup and they're just
uh definitely not down with uh puffing
on
CBD go
figure but all for science
right
I want had a sharp sharp feeling in the
throat probably because of the little
bit of plant matter in there yeah the
other ones it's amazing how as you clean
it how creamy and smooth it com 100% see
the difference in
that you have to that but there's very
got a fruity
taste I find katonic has a fruity taste
as
well mhm so what was that one two three
four five six seven seven rips eh should
probably try D's uh OG Kush well we
probably add that one let's go right to
the bud bud
batch Bud batch that's always the nice
batch
how'd you feel on that stuff
there I don't think it took away my high
too much no I don't think it took away
my heart too much kind of went like this
I feel pretty I felt like I was
surprised by the flavor of it yeah after
I blew out the sharpness I felt like it
was very very flavorful on my lips much
like CBD Renee I don't know you know
what I'm like this
ABD I don't mind it
actually yeah I mean I just feel feel
like I'm still baked on all these other
ribs
yes I feel slightly baked uh from
theight that we've tried so this is just
a test so what do we got here we got uh
this is D we have a warning on on on
testing videos a warning yeah do you not
try this at home no unless you have a
license in which case puff away yeah
make some dry sift grow some well grow
some herb make some dry
sift I did this one at uh 55%
humidity and uh 55 degrees actually 58
61 always fluctuated in there kept my
temperatures down very low for a couple
weeks hung dry and did very very well
with it
excellent
yeah well it's all beautiful it's all
great I'm really quite enjoying
it
yeah yeah they're OG
strong strong
o give be a nice clean rip of that shall
we yeah a small one a huge one small
huge it is bring it
down Johnny wants a big one big don't
even touch that
thing give you a baby I know look at
this thing that's what most people don't
think that that's big at all but oh no
not at all I see guys they like harsh
but I don't see them puffing on full
melt dry sift 10 rips at a
time there is to each their own it's the
beauty of cannabis have such a wide
variety of choice
well there it
is it is 2015 will be a big year so uh
hug Year I hope you guys uh puffed a
bowl with us each time that we puffed a
bowl and I'm not sure if at the end of
me and John talking and signing out if
you're going to hear the bubble man
music and then it's going to say thanks
for watching or if suddenly we'll just
be in some other random Place doing what
we do so we should eat we'll see we'll
see you when we see you guys thanks for
watching hey guys welcome back to Bubble
man's world and I guess welcome back to
Puff Wednesdays looks like Horatio
what's up in the house Johnny be's out
Horatio's in just like that um we had a
great time Johnny B and I he had some
incredible sifts that we went through I
think about six or seven different rips
oh you guys got to that point yeah we
did we did a good amount and then uh I
thought it was the end of puff
Wednesdays I ended up hearing from
Horatio that he was was on his way into
the City and for him what an hour and a
half to get to the city well it's pretty
much if I don't come now I've got a pack
up and Portage to come again tomorrow
right so yeah little nice yeah it's not
that late right now so we're going to
tune in what we're doing here with
Horatio which we're going to end up
tasting some of his dry sift and your I
guess your tur mouth in a sense yeah I
mean I'm looking at it from uh it could
we're looking at whether or not this is
the new seven star star can't be
six-star is the bar that is the de's
ultimate melt so is a sevenstar the
reintroduction of the lost tpin to in
the drying process added back to the dry
sift basically the impossible right
creating a new product because it's no
longer dry like tur melt pretty much
that's what Tony was calling it in
Amsterdam when he mostly he was doing it
with water hash adding the tpin to the
hash and doing the iron trick and
getting it into this opaque shatter
likee substance uh but we did do it a
few times with the sweet skunk dry sift
and that was a whole we were calling it
TP
sift TP sift so yeah there's I superp SI
Shiva serum Shiva there's some nectar
but I think I do like seven star
whatever seven star is nice yeah just
because it's pretty much a denotation
it's like live resin or anything else
but this in the case of dry sift it's
very specific cuz you can get six-star
melt in bubble sure um any day the weak
but dry sift you better have your own
TPS and they better come from the bud
you derived for true enough especially
we're not down with that clear where
you're taking Turpin out of other things
I mean maybe one day they'll find out
it's cool but to me it sets my Spider
Sense off I like I want to use just the
plant I'm not it's not even that it's
the fact oh you think you're playing God
now well that's what I'm saying I you
understand this is a strain from a
concoction blend mhm we don't even we'll
get to the science of it maybe in 50
years and then there'll just be another
machine we go again the profile changed
from just us adding a small pretty much
it's like it's going to always be the
Kool-Aid of strains and it's always and
unfortunately we don't know what the
effects of Kool-Aid are when we came for
medicine so that mixup is it's a
different type of science that's not
really science at all I should also add
that um You probably noticed that
Horatio and I both have a unit in front
of us he's got the uh denil 2.0 with the
mothership fabri egg and the puking B uh
20 mm quartz bowl and whip uh I over
here have the straight Fab with a 14 to
14 male adapter that goes into a female
quartz bowl from Germany with a 16mm
whip that goes down into um a brand new
unit I just got today from Germany
called the dabinator so dabinator was
kind enough to send this custom box uh
it's got my logo burnt into the top of
it and on the side uh it says dabinator
not sure if you guys can read that but I
can show that in a picture later really
nice looking unit uh pretty solid uh
right away both Horatio and I were
pretty much assuming that it would be a
pretty efficient unit being from Germany
the components wouldn't be Chinese came
out set set at 710 right off the bat
it's got one more degree to go but
that's it pretty nice little unit so
we've got the Dil 2 .0 my standard
obviously I love my denail uh but we've
got the dabinator out as well so we're
going to both uh interchange and do a
few rips of Horatio's tur melt and then
I have a variety of uh sifts here of
course I want to give Horatio a rip of
Johnny be's first bounce of my
20-year-old Jamaican lamb spread hybrid
creamy really different like one thing
guaranteed when you hit it you'll just
be like that's different it's not
overwhelming it's not sharp I'm
wondering if the tur
that I remember are lost from The
Tropical Sun not being that factor that
factor that production Factor you can
almost smell certain things and know
there's a note that wasn't played
sometimes yeah that's what I'm saying
it's like a but yet when you hit it it's
really strong and different well I I got
to try the bud on a herb hit and it was
definitely I was like what kind of high
is this I'm like not couch locked I'm
not pumped I'm like kind of mellow I'm
like how can mellow be strong I was like
oh I'm being like mellowed man what the
heck right so strong so that's I noticed
you have your carb cap do we need I
don't know about the titanium with no
it's fun
okay lineing up lineing up doing under
the table and in
fact if you're nervous about it we've
got the ceramic one right there that
you're welcome to use as well I'm going
to use my um Titanium one on this pretty
gentle giant hopefully so oh I also
should add that
um dabinator sent me a quartz Banger as
well really nice Twist on the neck there
really just once again you can just tell
it's it's got that German Perfection to
it so I'll look forward to hitting that
in uh both the straight Fab and the
fabra egg in the near future I guess uh
if you want to start with the Jamaican
or if you yeah cuz I I did bring some I
did bring some uh what's it called God's
green crack as along with the death
Bubba but just because there's only one
Jamaican we've all had a green crack in
our life one time or another true 19 and
a half 20 years old actually this year
so yeah let's get you
uh let's get you a
rip here you go sir you can take this
one if you like it's a kind of a I'd say
this one's kind of the better of the
two there you go
nice and clean for
Horatio have a little water while we're
waiting check this
out you want some water Horatio there's
no water in the pipe no water in your
just in your mouth like you can have
this it hasn't been sure I was more
worried about the dry rip oh no that's
taken care of you will have water in the
pipe nice
nice ready for this well I'm kind of
looking forward to hitting this
sure hits different than the Fab bag
I'll tell you that
much the straight Fab and the Fab I
guess I'll go for a little Jamaican
too first rip out of the dabinator
it's soft but it's kind of call it
creamy yeah it's a cuz when I tried it
on the herbal head I was I was like wow
that is
pretty creamy with this I'm like wo
that's smooth but I know my chest is
full so it's kind of I like how I feel
the effects uh in my head fairly strong
I'm feeling it it's it's a different
type of that's what I meant by what a
strong low mellow I'm not getting beat
up up top but I'm feeling John mentioned
it before too behind the eyes and I have
to admit when I think about him saying
that right away feel it as well like
it's I would put money on this strain
being effective in
glaucoma just the way it seems to
relieve tension in the forehead in the
eyes not that I had a lot of tension
going I'm feeling for it now cuz yeah it
was here and heading
outwards
I'm and I'm it's definite it's here so
it's definitely it came from my head
slow and after because I was feeling in
my chest but now I see what you're
saying yeah about the eyes it's a pretty
interesting uh little little thing like
I said it's by far not the the strongest
I mean John had the congales here
earlier which was just I mean that
strain is a special strain for Taste and
potency as well even this New York City
Diesel is probably at the table right
now one of the strongest yeah no I mean
that's I think that's the strongest I SM
out of Dar rank it's rank for sure you
know when Daren showed up I was like
okay that even for the Citrus cuz I'm
not a big fan of citrus I'm like okay
that I see why I see why you breed that
I see why you grow that sure I see why
you wanted to look at the uh let's take
a peek I close them up and I never know
how they which one is this transition
that's the God's green crack God's green
crack looks good looks good what's that
smell like I can't ever smell at my home
it's a crowded turpy
disaster it's hard to tell
cushy cuz I wondered about that and then
that's the death Bubba the death
Bubba the death Bubba and what happened
here that is what seven star looks like
that's the Seven Star well that's what
I'm about to find out so what did it
turn into over time kind of looks like
a buttery kind of creamy it it does
oh it's tped out that's mad
tppy all right so we got some Gods Green
Crack is that right that's that I just
because I it froze it and I never I
never opened it that is well got the
macro lens out too so we'll be able to
shoot both um your powder bubble and
your turp sift or you would the thing is
you would you you might mistake it for
some of that live resin if you didn't
know that the you can see the
contaminant that tells you it's not
B yeah let's do
this that's awesome dude do you want to
photograph it first no you know because
go so close what I think that we should
be careful of is this you see how it's
here all buttery don't dig in all right
there I'll tell you a secret about this
island that was the only thing that was
left that was untouched Keef when I
closed it interesting I had a t i was so
it just gran
well I literally tried to do I tried to
do a half and half I thought I could do
a half moon and then it just traveled
I'd like to get a photograph of some of
this and I'd also like to get a
photograph of some of this and some of
this so maybe come in from the back here
yeah like just just the portion that the
middle the top middle yeah cuz when I
added it there was this section and I'm
like oh I didn't get the halfway mark
it's growing it's growing right oh I'm
going to use this you've also have that
ability if you want if you want to go
like with a much thinner well this seems
to be the kind of this is more daber
friendly than the uh than the Scoops all
right I'll hold it you pull yours all
right I'm going to go in from the back
here oh my
God just not hey why
who
like you did the same thing I did you
took that first part and was like oh
that's too small I'll just double up I
suspect these are going to be huge
[__]
rips this this is some wet [__]
sift this is this is this is TP sift
right here Seven Star TP sift
[__] I keep smelling it before I go in
oh it reeks on the
Dabber in reaks but a
petitte
there's a lot going on there's a lot
going on there's a lot going on right
off the
bat what changing it's oh it's changing
it's like oh it's changing big time it's
gone into the back my throat and it's
twisted into the full flavor of the herb
but even when it went in it was like
hash but with these like hints of of
cannabis
Vapor it which now has completely
satiated my
throat I wish I could taste it on my
lips stronger wrong kind of
bong what do you think of that
I mean Chang my High completely cuz I
mean that's the thing I wondered about
the full tpine profile I'm like okay now
this is supposed to be a downer high
this is this is death Bubba I know this
guy but then I didn't find a downer at
all but I'm not this isn't a down
zingery and zesty like TP TP rips that
I've had in the past it's that was cuz
that was my first question I'm like I
don't know what the the effect is like
because the strains didn't match it was
always um it was always a cocktail blend
so I'm like yeah but you're putting
those turps on this High I what is the
what if I just stuck to the same plant
how many phases keep in mind most of the
turps are available in most of the
plants they're just different ratios
well that's that's all these strains are
is ratios and clearly ratios are I mean
I suspect if we got in that hnmr the
actual you know the testing that's super
accurate it's it would get us into a
point where we realize that the ones
that seem like there's none of this
particular tur it's just a it's just the
smallest most infal amount absolutely
it's a it's a code and just knowing that
THC vs take so little to do so much you
know every other I mean I'm still
getting I'm still getting a bit dude I'm
trying to getting modulated I'm getting
I really liked the initial exhale of it
like it was
just so tasty it's really it's I don't
know is Seven Star Cup only is it Hy
only is it
good God it's too far this is live resin
sift it is resen
sift wow major taste in there like
vegetables and roots
and so many
different so many different flavors
that's why I'm it's I'm
grabbed me that time good you too we
both had a little cough it's starting to
spread didn't you find that that that
hit was a real nice I'm still almost
about to
cut your water's right there sir oh
cheers well what a great puff Wednesday
um pretty stoked on the Heat and the
whip of the dabinator I'm not a huge fan
of the 16 mil Bowl I know that he said
he was going to try and get me a 20 mil
Bowl which and a whip which will be much
better for me and then I'll also get a
drop down for this so that uh you know
that it can be down here a little more I
think this is a little bit too high for
me right now it's a bit tall I need to
get a drop down for this as well even
though this quartz doesn't get warm it
doesn't warm the joint and this is the
same it's I found since I switched to
the drop down it's just being here
versus playing this game exactly it's
just a this one you know look at this
and then I can't can't see so it's a
very small surface that's where I
started with adapters to get dabbing
really nice uh whip I like the the lack
of the curl in the Whip and uh the box
is really beautiful and uh stoked on the
quartz Banger so I I much appreciate Max
for sending that out and uh you guys can
check out dabinator uh Google dabinator
cuz I'm not even sure if it's dabinator
NL or dode or do or.org but it's
dabinator it's the electric nail and uh
well that was just real Pleasant right
there dude we'll have to get a couple of
photos of that I just want to start
enrolling it into my program just to
playing around well it's not it's it's
not even the playing around it's like
okay is that your strange on is that
your um is that your medicine is that
your medic cush well what about your
medic cush now is it still your strain
right does it do did it take you further
um what's the difference because this is
I'm I'm mainly just trying to discover
it was the message Mage deeper than I
first interpreted because of my
limitations so as soon as I kind of got
a sense of how much turps are lost
because that means the loud pack how
loud is it right well these are CES
turpenoid that talked about earlier the
super super volatiles and what uh Indra
John Davis called them years ago to me
he called them super terpenoids he said
he was one of the only one of only
people in the world capturing them
through his cryogenic process absolutely
and so I have no real way of
understanding that without building a
lab and getting into this game but it
seems as though in the near future
Jamaica will happen and uh potentially
I'll be able to go there and build
myself a really state-of-the-art hash
lab uh have people like Horatio come and
join us and help out with the uh the
science and the the future of the
project doing all these I guess really
just standardizing the medicine well I
mean
somehow even I managed to become
involved where I'm like how how is it
those of us who are interested in
standardizing the medicine somehow find
themselves by their own interest
becoming those people I'm like how did I
get to be a considered for Jamaica I'm
like well I'm just pushing I'm just
pushing just when you why do Growers
grow what gets them in that room every
day well if if they're the only people
that can experience these tpin they're
living them because they're so volatile
they're essentially taking huffing dabs
in that room right it um it must be
something very very at the core of our
human nature why we're attracted to it
and why it sticks in our brain so that's
where I want to focus my research and
here I am now um where normally the
table this is normally where you see it
on YouTube and then one day the sstar
concept is something I'm I'm
participating in so um worlds Chang
perspectives change and um it's
beautiful I I feel real lucky in all of
this in the sense that I mean I still
have ideas and whatnot and I still want
to try Pioneer and help and Inspire but
I'm really stoked on the Inspiration
Point right now where it's like I've
been showing these techniques in regards
to water hash and dry sifting and it's
starting to get to the point where so
many people are picking it up and it's
growing exponentially that it's
really I was talking about it earlier
how I don't really feel the need to go
and like enter contests and try and and
it's a different
statement position in life cuz I looked
at I'm like well when I picked up sip
it's because I wanted control of data
more than anything I'm like I need
control because if I have a theory that
there's an actual isolative split
between the dry Berry Theory the right
Berry Theory and the rotten Berry Theory
the overripe heads yeah the only way to
prove that I isolate it I photograph it
I'm like there it is there's the ice
ball there's the undeveloped there's the
overdevelop it's no longer a theory it's
real yeah exactly and that's how I
learned everything with my macro
photography really it was an incredible
increase in my education not from
Reading any books or Googling anything
or reading scientific papers it was
literally like I'd photograph something
and then be like oh that's interesting
like what I wonder what that is and then
I'd start you know well I'm big on
having multi- tangential knowledge so I
can't you can't just sit and oh I'm a
solving artist I know what I know and
because at a certain point someone who
knows both looks at your whole 20-minute
argument and goes this guy has no clue
dry cfin Auto butter the same way it's
tpin it has nothing to do with this they
don't know if they don't do it I guess
right that's kind of why the first time
you had described I the minute you said
we put the Barb in the freezer before
the competition I'm like why I thought
it was dry the only reason I could think
of is those tpin are eating their way
out that's the only reason those guys
would put in the freezer and then it
turned out to be so over time like okay
the Barb is unique it's alcol we don't
even know if it's those Tans like for me
it's the weirdest resin I've ever worked
with John had some resin today that was
a little bit similar I was going to say
this the reason is if anything we say
tpin we think oils but that's not the
case right and um alcohol is polar all
right where lemoning is non-polar those
are completely two different extractions
and ability to extract toally and I
found that so when I hear anytime you
guys describe these arbl likee strains I
Google them and I start looking up
analytical results and I alcohol soluble
th I look for the I go all right let's I
literally when you said that I Googled
um test of the shishkaberry and I went
down I'm like okay out of these seven
tests from all these random Labs linol
LOL linol all right now let's take that
back information back to the bar now
let's head out to its other parent and
look up that okay this thing is
practically all alcohol there's no
non-polar and that's why it'll behave
differently in water compared to the
ones that actually can reject water
still makes really nice water hash well
no that's the thing about it is it's
Rene style what's the qu now I asked you
this question what's its storage life
versus its I look at that and I'm like
that's the ripest juiciest Berry if I
leave it on the counter it's going to go
bad by tomorrow because it's so volatile
yeah I mean it it doesn't go bad by
tomorrow but and even when I say it does
it go bad it just changes its shape I've
never seen it funk out and like grow
mold no no no that's not kind of what
I'm kind of asking how many times can
the tpine profile change that kind of
speaks to how volatile how if compared
to well me that smells like two weeks
ago when I smelted it off D4 20K with a
little bit of I guess when it's fresh
it's so loud when it's fresh that it can
definitely change to a degree over the
course of the first month to two months
Matt would be a better person to ask
because he's had it in his life for like
a decade plus always the bud the hash
it's always around because I only
experienced it fresh I'm always like
what this is this is insane but I've
never basically it's never kept long
enough that I'm like oh I see it's not
like when I first met it which um tpine
R um buttery things typically they give
up and they lose um they give off so
much that they change so that's kind of
why I had so many questions about the
Barb that yeah you're right only Matt
would know what 6month old Barb is like
what Frozen six-month old Barb is like
but it's definitely alcohol based in my
opinion and in look up linol look up the
other turps you'll find in its parents
and want to H this one yeah I totally
see why um more of a six-star is pretty
much a phenomenon of alcohol Turpin in
my opinion yeah oh yeah it is so I think
like if I anything if I wanted to figure
out full melt genetics I might if there
was only an app that we could search for
testing of C show me some show me all
the strains high in linol low in lemon
show me all the strains high in Mercy
once we get all these tests man it's
going to be so that's different U feel
free to hit anything I have here there's
the diesel there's d420 K's OG there's
some dry siip that I clean there's
John's Jamaican that's uh which dry siip
that you clean that's not a straight uh
this is right here it was some it was
like a hash plant that a friend from uh
be uh Vancouver Island brought you can
see the you see the color difference
hold it next to any of these well I
remember when I first saw I was like
what is you
and this must be be the has
makes oh my God you switched me out now
I've got the tiny quartz couldn't fit
it missed it cuz I couldn't fit it I see
you want me to hit for you it's not that
I got this is when you need to help your
friends Jesus Christ this is tough can
you get it in there you want me to put a
little more in there it's in here where
that's got to go there yeah we'll grab a
little bit more here I think I should be
able to all right I didn't want to use
the words uh tight V but this is a tight
V if I ever tried to put a Dabber in on
yeah Dil had sent me one I literally
just broke my denil um 16 mil that was
bummed to pooking
be yeah this is out of my shaky range
but this stuff presses up real nice oh I
didn't see that into a thick thick like
I'm not giving you this big of oh I was
like you get putting us on Donuts no no
no no I'll just give you a little dob
can take as much or as little as you
like ohow somehow got my Dabber like wet
at the end so the has was just like
no
no that when you have to do the wrap and
the hook all W and the hook all right
here you go
man
bubble on you got
yours of course you
do nice to have a multitude of nails I
like the blue light along with the
greenish yellow light over there might
be a thing you might see me rocking two
nails from now
on want to thank dabinator for the uh
kind gifts the t-shirts I'll wear them
in good health uh the stickers the
containers
the electric nail the quartz
Banger and of
course uh thank D nail as always for the
2.0 custom Bubble Man logo on that one
as well shout out to DNA Army big shout
out to the DNA Army I just did a video
before this video thanking those guys
for some awesome uh t-shirts and work
shirt that they sent me as well as this
hat grow your own and [__] huge shout
out to Horatio for popping up and talk
talking about the Seven Star this is
just the first time you heard about the
Seven Star you can start talking about
it on social media now this is some TP
sift this is some sevenstar it was very
interesting it looks like a live resin
sitting on the table right now zero PPM
for sure zero ppms you could uh get into
some good arguments with that stuff and
I bet you you could get into some
cognitively dissonant people who would
claim they could a smell the butane
coming out of it absolutely I'm pretty
sure I smelled the butane in there Total
Tan run
dude I don't I don't actually sift dry
sift I don't
actually oh my god well maybe we should
finish it off with one more hit of that
live resin yeah cuz you haven't tried in
that way and I this does hit differently
and it is a different uh resistor with
your uh with your your Dabber you'll be
able to fit it in much easier absolutely
this is the this is the way to well this
isn't going to have a problem melting
off the Dabber at all no exactly all
right very good
look at that eh let's work this thing
asleep all right here let me grab a
little let me grab a little bit a little
bit I mean tons let me just grab like a
double great I almost grabbed the double
and then my hand was like no you don't
uh you ain't going for no nice to go
back between the egg and the Fab this is
where we really find out what were you
dabbing on and what was I dabbing on
true all right let's do this off
Wednesday oh yeah that's different on
this right I can feel it over here now
bubbling in my fore in my
gums
and I'm not a fan of Bubba but this
death Bubba cuz they were like it's
different trust us it is each time I hit
it it reminds me of
something this is e it's almost
like what the hell is that it makes you
chase so many memories is it a vegetable
I gave my
carrot is that carrot it's carrot
cartine holy
caropine carotene I don't know it's it's
carrot it's like really like fresh
awesome carrot like you just had carrot
juice from Bubba death wow and you go on
Leafly and it says Pine so what's the
tpine modulation of carrot cuz we don't
have a carrot strain and we find out it
came from Bubba so it's likey carrot
every earthy every strain again in a
whole basically it's like two sides of
coin the dry and the wet um two
different Med medicinal efficacies from
the same plant so I'm sure interested
I'm loving the way things are moving
forward at an accelerated rate we don't
even know what we're doing we get
together we sit we talk we get inspired
someone says something in hash church we
go away we do new things we come up with
new things we get back together this is
exciting man it's great to see uh
another uh new product hit the uh it
just seems like it's a pathway that
well it's nice to see a true product cuz
like we've seen there are there are many
weird things going on in bait pens
basically in the world of inhalation
there's just as many new products that
are negative as there are new products
that are positive um so uh I sure love
the electric nails and the quartz I
really love the quartz although um maybe
the next session we do will go back to
hitting uh the sick carbine which is the
Silicon carbine yeah they've got me one
on order right now that they told me
about that has a ledge that a sapphire
dish sits in double up for mil shots
yeah a sapphire ledge hitting it off the
SIC so who's to know when it'll ever end
I love the fact that we're not only
trying to uh produce a you know what we
call what I call the Holy Grail which is
the ultimate Foundation as anyone in the
extraction game or the resin isolation
or decontamination or if you're trying
to create new products like turp mouth
or TP sift seven star um you're going to
want to have a foundation of knowing a
what the resin is when it's been cleaned
to 99% and from there you can go and
only then we even know oh you know this
wasn't the melts right off the bat there
would everything would be confusing
there would be I don't even
it's all I can say is I'm thankful I
started and I got out the gate well so
that I didn't really go through um the
rough stages because um having the
opportunity to produce high quality Sith
and
then have that as a foundation turn and
go could there be more versus chasing
the main goal I'm like could there be
more could I'm smelling this I smell I
have the wet butt I'm smelling the dry
sip I'm smelling my lho I'm smelling I'm
smelling the raw turps
mhm do you want to sniff the raw turps
in fact you gave me turps before I left
and I haven't even opened those oh those
were pecs yeah cuz yeah I've got some MK
Ultra my wife swears smells like th and
meat nice interesting maybe another
episode totally up to you my friend I'm
uh I'm here with you now if you want or
uh we can uh we could take a pause for
the Cs more pause the C so all right
back with the turps all I'm back with
the turps all right so
unfortunately because I had things to do
today and I came here I haven't
sifted the MK Ultra just the water yep
MK and this is the turbs yep so I
brought
over fraction of that so um this belongs
to the LH this belongs to the
sift
what that a memory
of I mean I can definitely taste the the
cush of the MK Ultra in there yeah
without a shadow of a
doubt but then there's this other thing
above it that it's before you get to it
it's just right at the start and then it
disappears and you're deep into the
cush that I can't call right that got
that's the flash that's the most it's
like 3% you get one chance to experience
it and
then no the alcohol
portion I don't even know what to call
that it's it's so wild the way it turns
turns into Kush cuzz she was like meaty
salty and then she backed up and then
she's like sweet because now check out
the alcohol
side is that
citrusy tastes
citrusy it's still cushy underlining but
almost like like a chocolate orange or
wow tpin are so subtle it's an
incredible game of smelling them because
that's why I'm so excited about I think
it's counterintuitive too I think the
way I'm taking deep smells I need to
take these really light it changes if we
put these all in the freezer and then do
an initial because it bursts uh the
temperature temperature differential
bursts the V this reminds me of one of
those Christmas is your whack and it
open up and it's like an orange
chocolate yeah do you smell a citrus in
that check out the
water
yeah you you almost see brown
orange that's what I'm saying because
it's not fresh but you know it's yeah
it's that damn it's that damn christm
the reason I think it's yeah the reason
I it's like a flavoring of orang
it's not a true Orange it's like the
difference between delemon and orange
oil it's another one of those I you
clearly got some cheap orange turpins
and put them in this I'm like this is uh
yeah I actually like the smell of it I
don't think it smells cheap it's just
clearly not whole yeah like orange yeah
it's like partially something just one
of the components that makes an orange
taken aside and it turns this is
interesting now this is so much more
interesting because it doesn't have the
the sharp validity of the alcohol that's
carrying that smell into your nose this
is truly water so right away if you took
a deep enough smell of it you'd smell
nothing then you take a lighter
smell almost touch it to your
nose and then you feel these these these
strange sharp like portions of cush that
are completely missing the front the
middle and the back end but there's like
a component between the front and the
middle that's there and between the
middle and the end you can you can smell
them but they're not like when you smell
them like that so if you tasted that
what do you expect to taste I think I'm
going to get a little bit of a cushy
kind of taste but more of a I don't know
why I want to say
kerene cuz I'm not really exactly
sure cuz it's not in that portion that
it's it's absolutely drinkable and when
I actually uh interesting I made a uh
tpine soda for uh my friend Mike and um
I didn't add any sugar I just carbonated
it the first time I tried to do a full
bottle and the soda stream exploded so
instead I put in um a fraction of the
alcohol this much to a full Soda Stream
bottle M tasted exactly
it unbelievably strong and delicious I
actually have to do it again in order to
attempt it that's the same MK it's just
a different portion nor I actually
brought that by accident nor I just
travel with the smaller one
oops all the TP guys trip balls when you
play around oh this is like just like
what did you do like what did you do
with the
money the money's in the carpet and I
can't reach for it
anymore is it the same as when you do
the small perfume scale
it's really nice yeah similar I think
the small perfume scale is a more
concentrated way of smelling it that's T
that's what I found I was like there's a
reason for this scale pure chines are a
trick to smell it's like a when they're
in that concentrated form you really
need to create a waft to catch the smell
of it cuz otherwise it's such a great
smell it's too much for your senses yeah
there's a bunch of Senses shutting
down as it's as you're getting the rush
but that one wasn't too much when I held
it under my nose that concentrated I
mean it was the equivalent of taking a
bong rip that's in a big giant neck
compared to one that's real small you
know what the Restriction is like it's
the same with the smelling the
Restriction smell yeah that's a lot of
that Citrus yeah there's some really
citrusy stuff in
there I say we take a hit of the New
York City Diesel let's do that just
because uh this has inspired me to and
it's sitting right here I'll um I'll
load you up so we can guarantee you
it doesn't fall out just give nice
little Little
Rock oh I do have after oh the water and
the alcohol for the death Bubba oh good
let's see uh what fraction comes out of
that gu all right sounds
good here's your
uh oh look at how well that fits on
there all right so death Bubba alcohol
I'm going to go water first this time
cuz the alcohol was just such a great
smell oh
wow are you kidding me what is that like
bubble gum or
something bubble gum but then but then
once that disappears in the first 10 to
20% you're left with this crazy
antiseptic smell that smells like your
grandma that's crazy what is
that you smell that right smell that
smell the end of that that's like a old
folks home or
something smell
that it's got it there's antic it's an
is there's a thing that your grandma
keeps in the corner of the bathtub that
kind of makes the bathroom not her purse
it's not her purse but no it's it's it's
like something she has in her one of her
soaps and you carry
it yeah it doesn't taste that strong it
well the thing is she's wearing perfume
under that cleaning perum is it perfume
plus her dirty clean or cleaning soap or
just now it's pretty I don't
know this is tripping me out right now
dude so what bub people are watching
this and laughing their heads off at our
conversation right now
what well the bubble gum listen the
bubble gum's there right at the start
smell
it y candy you get that candy wrapped
something something there is candy and
to me it just initially was a Bubba and
then see I see colors typically and the
colors tell me where I am well that's
greenish
yellow what color is that see to me cuz
I don't really see colors I'm just like
I went out on a limb and thought that's
kind of Bri it's like I tend to smell I
try to smell the colors and what do I
see like where would it put me I guess
I'm thinking it's it's green and its
smell in the sense that I don't know if
it's a TH or if it's it's it's a variety
of herbs that are changing itself if you
get too close it starts to get more
candy right that's and then because I
was like I'm like I'm going try the
alcohol go for it while you're
continuing on with your water oh Shyer
look at that
one the alcohol ones are such a pleasure
because obviously they're the sharpest
of the bunch obviously taking a drink of
alcohol compared to taking a drink of
water is really the differences between
these smells it's truly alcohol and
water I like it so much cuz it's not we
just focus so much on the oil the oil
the oil I got to get the oil that I
haven't seen anyone who's fractioned
this off and that's the one I'm most
excited about because tinure wise that's
pretty potent stuff yeah I'm not even
sure what to say about that one that
one's uh that one almost made me dizzy
smelling
it yeah
whoa yeah it's strong this is modulating
the that's modulating I'm just from
smelling it it
is I feel like we've been huffing Turpin
here for the last five minutes and I'm a
bit dizzy this one's a this one is dizzy
it's dizzy isn't
it what's the Dizzy what's the Dizzy
alcohol tpine that we've never tested
before I don't know I'll tell you one
thing it cleared my sinuses I felt it
move through my sinuses so you're saying
in Jamaica I'll be able to pour this in
well not pour it in 5 gallon buckets 55
gallon buckets not not even I'm not I'm
not even I'm just interested in the
machine that will tell me really tell us
NH HMR yeah no more buying Wiggy W
nulear HMR cuz everyone's buying
standards and now we have a new standard
and our numbers are jumping I'm
interested in this especially for the
Tarpin because the tpin are the new
numbers we want to know all about
especially how accurately we can get
part of it for sure come on well is this
um is death Bubba nasal cream made out
of this is that what um is that the
message from it um and separate from
this which may be colic
water there is a lot of potential in
just these
non phyto canabo based cannabis
medicines absolutely thus they are
modulators so potentially for all we
know that you could be taking uh one
form of saturating your endoc canabo
system with trans dermals or um the
sublingual drops or even vaporizing or
consuming Edibles and then you could use
a product like this in another form of
perhaps drops or uh transdermal or
whatever and and modula well the thing
is that's the thing is I'm like well I
can without even thinking about
modulating let's just never seen this
ratio of tpin in therapeutic use either
orally Aroma therapeutically
or and cannabis gives us another
potential we just growing it to juice
the alcohol because the alcohol turns
out to be something right that's I get
excited when you can completely step
away from phyto canabo and cannabis
still has so much for mankind that it
just makes you go oh my god well you're
a fraction man yeah I just I just look
at it I'm like the plant people just
we've got so much going on with what
what if we can get this into a machine
in Jamaica that can fraction it into all
of its components well that's and then
you could take each one of those and put
it into the machine and potentially
fraction those down the re only reason
why I'm scared is because there is
already 300 of these if I just have
River Rock strains that's what I'm
saying so if I just put in the machine
and get a feedback and then we find a
therapeutic clinical trial use we're
that's already our lifetime somebody
else will fraction it and then put it
back together I'm like keep feeding this
thing freaking alcohol fractions and
water fractions and the oil fraction and
did I mention the bud still smells like
the loud pack so there's fractions that
we know that are already in there so you
can actually take the bud like Bud and
now go and extract other tpin out of it
that have nothing to do with what I'm
dealing with right now how excited are
you guys right now listening to this
conversation pretty pump clicking some
sweet [__] are we blocking you harshly
with this pipe here no clue let's get
that out of the way man look you've had
this whole pipe right in front of your
face the entire time I'll look back the
video and go oh I'll just wrote I'll
just cut it out and shift it oh where
did his face go just a hole look at me
doing some manover and look I can do
it
yeah ninja
ninja I'm going to smell this one last
time cuz it did make me freaking dizzy
it made me dizzy I don't know if it was
the culmination of smelling the four
before it that's why I'm trying to
figure out if now if it still has that I
just had a hit of this New York City
Diesel from d420 K and it was delicious
I also hit
your I want to say this is the Green
Crack yeah the green crack cuz obviously
the death Bubba death bubb the Ooze so
we hit that a bunch of times let's try
try that one more time and let's wrap up
does it still do
it
CU I feel like I'm feeling it in my
heart it's sharp yeah it's definitely
sharp it's absolutely 100% when I stop
exhaling that
thing I feel like I just exhaled a hit
like an like a expectorant feeling in my
lungs yeah my lungs I'm like dude my
heart fter in my a little in my it does
it's got a bit of a pikme apple I want
to say lemony but it's not lemony it's
sharper
like
grapefruit grapefruit thyme or something
like grapefruit herb some type of that's
why my wife says season meat yeah it's
seasoning for sure it's seasoned she's
like this is like I'm smelling cold meat
which is really nothing but seasoning
and I'm like really and I'm like I
wonder if it's thy that she's smelling
there is definitely thyme in there she n
she she named that one she started with
meaty salty and then she's like it's got
thyme cuz when thyme is dried then it's
the subtle tarpine it's not the Roaring
oil the fresh one yeah so fresh one is
strong yeah it seems that's what it is
the dried
th well unbelievable Wicked conversation
as always brother I wish we could go on
forever but uh well it's got to be
another time we got to have another show
we can't we can't do it all in one show
and give you everything at once but that
was quite a bit for what late how late
at night is it now on puff Wednesday so
you've now heard of The Seven Star TP
sift turp
melt awesomeness alcohol induced tpine
modulation the alcohol induced tpine
modulation where we're literally um you
know doing
kind of real cloud like I say CU I bring
back this
music man Roy alongside one
[Music]
SP stly s oh yes oh
againest at
me find up on Sal head people always ask
me say why you so humble I don't smoke
Co that's why I don't
grumble media oh
[Music]
yeah her must be burned like must be
cleaned ra vital for Spiritual hene a
king Salamon certify the tree and he is
the wisest man to we so propa prach her
never s true speech so while the song
called leaders deceive man obligated to
clarify and teach you
[Music]
now smoke marijana MEP just get a B from
a friend name car of the highest and
just get it from the higher
[Music]
[Applause]
m
[Music]
when youing on
T really how come I want
make