[Music]
hey welcome everyone to bubble man's
world and welcome Johnny be in the house
for the first time in forever dude let's
call this a puff Wednesday
it's a puff winds it's a proper word
it's a chill puff Wednesday my
neighbor's ripping out all the trees in
his on his property so that annoying
beeping sound we're gonna hear that
consistently through this video maybe
but that's okay I think it's okay so I
think we're gonna start it off johnny
has not tried the bubble man pan yet I
mean it opened it up I've been hit in
mind like he's hitting they're hitting
that he gave me unwrap the wrapper and
I'm like I can't do this without you
guys put it to open mine I've been to
the rib so this is hard packaging for
broken ribs
it's amazing tell us that really affects
your life but how much resin you need
not to call for coughing
like I just don't know what else to say
that I have not gone and yet yet that
has a little exclamation card good job
to compromise to Gary from up tech
that's all improv Gary props to Gary
props Gary here let's put on your good
cartridge so I got one that started you
fill those yeah we filled you up the
cartridge here Johnny B so that you a
cartridge here it's in the bag yeah
really got pushed in good so this is
cool you know what I like so much about
it is um dude you signed it well in a
sense I did didn't I
well I'm honored to be able to screw
this on we talked so much about it I
know that you were in Jamaica and Tony
was talking more than you guys me back
and forth and it's it one two three turn
on it's a five one
five turns it on ready I am
you take a few seconds to load the
cartridge you'll probably have to slowly
now pull and gentle while you're heating
up the oil which is obviously quite cold
on the outside of the cartridge right
now on the inside the cartridge it's
just starting to milk it'll take a
little bit you want to heat this up good
oh yeah it's going good
it's starting to starting to feel warm
anyway that'll boil that rosin at the
bottom pull it into the cartridge and it
may take a few more bits flavor right
now it's coming that's the one well that
bright whenever you had to break
something in you know you got is things
this is like breaking in your new Ben
got a break stuff in him yeah
it's just that no no no
no it's on ice-melt the Terps it's
boiling at the bottom so now it's
pulling now it's pulling into the
cartridge I'm watching you and pull oil
into the cartridge for the first time oh
yeah oh wow it's bubbling and the
bubbles are getting pulled into the
cartridge so this cartridge is a little
bit tricky the first thing you need to
do oh there you go Johnny PU got took a
little bit but he finally got one so
with this cartridge in particular when I
gave him the cartridge the oil was very
hard like cold so you've got to heat it
up a little bit you've got to boil the
oil on the bottom and once it boils it
goes into these holes that are over the
beam now here's the most important part
guard that smells an incredible pull on
it when you're done so pull on it right
now without pushing the button it's a
very important part without pushing the
button you're gonna pull a few times and
what that does is it pulls the oil back
into the cartridge it cools the oil and
it keeps the oil from dripping and so if
you hit these pens a lot and you don't
do what John's doing right now what's
gonna happen is the oil is gonna drip
down to your battery and this is what
happens with a lot of these tanks we've
found a very simple way to avoid it
happening completely cool the oil down a
little bit before before you finish
using your pen how's that Johnny beat I
count one I'm on the end of mine I've
been smoking mine this one same
cartridge yeah I've been puffing this
since
since Toronto since the karma cup
September 9th so that's like 10 almost
10 days you need a proper pen it sounds
like we got to get you trying to eat my
buddy I'm just starting to get to the
end of my now cool well [ __ ] I'm glad
you got that pan Johnny B I'm stoked
that it's working for you and what we'll
look forward to hearing about your
critiques in the near future of how it
work you know what are you we've lived
taking pants apart we've talked about
pans we talked about on casters we've
gone through you've seen the line of the
Pens that I've destroyed I see that was
still rockin I dropped this out of my
truck from 6 feet in the and like out of
the pocket standing in the back of my
truck and it fell right on the the
driveway and it just put a little dent
and somehow I got another dent right
here I haven't broken a piece of glass
yet and I've dropped it about 15 times
yes interesting how this one could fall
over it actually doesn't affect the
glass that's right you can see part of
the design where all the other ones fall
on the glass and break the glass I mean
can i stuff one of these bags full of
stuff well this is what we're gonna do
right now we're gonna preach Johnny
wanted to well he wanted to take a
little bit of his Metis crush which is
absolutely spectacular here real nice
cushy gassy kind of got that beautiful
jarred flavor nice dense Nuggets so the
real key to this is preparation so
you've got to figure out what you want
to press whether it's 2 grams or 5 grams
or whatnot and then we'll prepare the
bud because Matt from sasquatch was
really showing the importance of
breaking the buds into smaller pieces
and filling the corners getting those
corners and the whole side stopped so
that you don't have any where for oil
and I think 5 grams would be good that's
right about there yeah at Point 2 there
we go I wasn't gonna go for point 2 but
we'll go 5 point to know if it doesn't
end it's I think that'll work really
well so if you just want to gently break
your nugget apart we'll start throwing
it into this bed
little pieces and I can so you know what
I really kind of look at looking at
break it off look at that yeah no no
it's like I hate breaking he's like
there's like it looks like there's a
bunch of sand here right now from just
cracking that bud so it's really
important and that's one thing I'm
learning cuz I don't really use the bags
I write I just press bud yep I pressed
bud for a while when I press like 5 or
10 grams of bud I like having the bag I
know that my pressing is on point enough
that I can escape the oil get the oil
out it's only really when you get
inefficient that you'll leave oil behind
in these bags and so and for me I'm
always using like the hair straightener
right right so that's what I've always
used yeah and that just it kind of kind
of makes sense I don't use a bag I got a
hair straightener or I got a can of
clamp now even with my hair
straighteners I still had little bags
that I used first first press I ever did
was wrapped in a little that was right
to my micron bag that's why I still have
the 25 I have access to screen so it
makes sense that I would use bags a lot
of people when it's easy not to use bags
so when a you don't have a schwack of
them but when you have a schwack of them
it's hard not to use them especially
when you have a microscope like mine and
I go to photograph the resin and I see
these little bits and pieces and I know
in the long run of likes
inhaling vaporizing and it's not really
affecting it but from the photography
standpoint it really affects it a great
deal this has had like a two and a half
month cure you can just smell oh yeah
it's definitely not very nice cure to it
it smells excited to do a little médicos
press here I'm excited I mean I like
that you've been waiting hi I'll be
waiting
nothing to be missed it's good having a
little short puff Wednesday you guys
have been asking for it for the longest
time I had no idea let's get that all in
there I had no idea when it would
possibly happen but today John was able
to make it over well you were in town I
was in town that too he flies I fly
you're somewhere I'm somewhere this is
true this is true there's so many events
so many things happening I mean you got
some great great things happening coming
up in the near future here you go in the
discussion but what the ACCE yeah yeah
those guys are doing good things I'm
definitely excited I think we're doing
that in the next couple of days I'll put
the link up to those to that
organization Cory and Tony doing great
things in Ontario we're gonna be doing
think they're doing education so they're
having gatherings where they have people
over and specialists in their fields to
talk about the different aspects of
whether you're they're doing edibles
whether they're doing hash making and so
I'm gonna do a little trichome seminar
and then I'm gonna run them through the
bubble bags while they actually run it
back so it should be pretty fun what do
you think there John Mitty cush doesn't
that just is that a pillow that you
could sleep with
five grams
all right so I guess the plan is for us
to actually have a rip we had our pan
ribs but let's have a DAB let's do it
then up to offer you a DAB John so
actually I was also going to say this is
69% humidity in this but it definitely
feels like it has a lot of humidity yeah
doesn't feel like it's crunchy in any
way shape or form
it's very formable malleable if you
would I've found that when it was lower
humidity or what they give me in the
wrong
and this is just the humidity I liked
and I was curing my room and then I took
some bugs off the plant was curing yeah
I looked out my humidifier on the wall
it had like it was at 70% no like went
inside next question I was like that's
pretty awesome
all right there's a little dab e4u of
the sauce from blind-eye productions
thanks guys and Johnny betta not too big
because we don't want to hurt his rib
John's got hurt rib right now so we're
just gonna give him you know like a
monster one not like a giant monster one
but it's not monster at all it's just a
nice little guy for you oh I guess we
use this as the carb cap that one I
forgot the carb cap all the W killed yes
I am counting you've got about 20
seconds said 29 seconds so far sorry I
should have put that over a little
closer to you now I haven't had a chance
to dig bangers yet I'm kind of waiting
yeah now DC glass has them they're
available
buy stuff online well that's going right
hard to find probably using I don't have
one
yes drop that in there hold that glass
against the side
there we go proper ripping right there
that's proper ripping Johnny God it
smells just ridiculous ridiculous
ridiculous we'll do a little DC glass
cleaner on the DC banger give that [ __ ]
like a doctor it's got some really good
flavor
yeah oh [ __ ] that's Terp sauce that is
terms herb sauce yeah I think that's
Pink Panther Kush with bubba kush or no
sorry pink kush terpenes at it from a
friend of mine see that's the best thing
now we only take the rosin and then you
buy the Terps that first rip you got off
your pen was monster
but from the label de panamá not
watching told you the same thing
you get formed so reps do it man
that's important especially when you're
dealing with it's what we like whatever
you're dealing with all right so I'm
gonna have a little dab with you there
and then we're gonna take that we're
gonna go into the office and we're gonna
stick that on the m1 I could also bring
the m1 out here it's easy enough I mean
one's so portable it's amazing it's
insane actually I know we'll see
it might just stay on my desk but I'm
gonna have this rip first and Johnny B
will be hitting his 10 because this is a
pup Wednesday not a not tough Wednesday
we puff Wednesday's our special days
special puff day I'm looking forward to
seeing the Maddy cush squished through
the Sasquatch press - so looking forward
to it because that means squishing at
home mm-hmm and I'll be testing all
these different things but I haven't had
a chance to sit down with the Sasquatch
to truly test my resin because we know
that the Sasquatch is giving us exactly
what we need it's getting all over that
resin oh we're like Alex I use a
handheld clamp and it's it's not as
powerful as a sasquatch so I'm dying I
want to know how much resin I'm actually
losing
you know like that's the whole question
when you're not using the proper tools
you actually lose in the squish so let's
find out exactly the amount of pressure
what do you think your return will be
I'm hoping what do you think it'll be
it's gonna be the mid 20 25 or so number
so good that John was putting that on
the scale a multitude of times because
somehow in our stone stupor we filled
this with 6 grams instead of 5 that
really affected those results
all right well do you want to compress
this I did all right all right so we've
got the M once a squash press that we're
gonna be using today with the SPX Power
Team this one's really good it's
substantially better than the original
one the ESC Oh which I have right here
this one you have to pump twice for
every one that you have to pump this one
of us so that like foot pedal in the
background and my Dewald air compressor
right here but that runs the bubble man
world v2 here that I have we're not
gonna be using that one today we're
gonna be using the m1 and Johnny B
usually clicks out at about 230 degrees
when he squishes his bud so today we're
gonna test he's using a you know
handheld unit we're using an actual
product release from sasquatch we'll see
what the difference is in regards to
returns we've got 5 grams of Medi Kush
that we've got in here and yeah I guess
it's time to get it in there what do you
say John Wow super excited
all right so I love the fact that they
can just hand pump this which is so
convenient they first have to put the
air in so now a couple of pumps is just
to like relief really right yeah so now
you'll see it's only a few pumps that it
takes so just kind of like when the
muezzin mind my girlie
what's it well I'm sitting at home and I
had my clamp between my legs I pull up
my hair straight in there I clip
everything together and it's just just
the way the function like I squish for
like to exist I've seen it what's that
exist yeah
you want to lift this out press one
let's go see what we got
oh look at the quality of it though
Johnny B looks incredible smells
incredible
you'll be dabbing it soon enough
we'll be dabbing in service correct
take the second squish squish I already
see it getting a little shiny this is
kind of a pre squish you taught me to
pre squish so it's quite likely you'll
get a another 0.5 out of this instantly
it sees already squishing yeah it's
squishing pretty good see I woulda never
known to press it the second time well
often you can get the whole press and
the first time but it's all about the
sweet spot you know I think for the
humidity that you have in there we could
have made it a little hotter I think
that's why the 220 230 is working for
you because you have so much excessive
humidity in there that you're just
blasting it it's it's evaporating and
then it's carrying the resin out for you
not so it makes a lot more so see how
much nicer now that all that humidity is
gone how it's squishing oh yeah and
that's you could definitely see it
gushing now so you know learning and
humidity is really key to like and like
I said that I didn't really know so I
really wanted to try it on the side
different tools you know devtools
exactly different I wouldn't try to
change it for what you're using cuz it
won't be probably as efficient
you know you figured out a way to get
what you have working efficiently just
so that's good this is what I kind of
want to see the beginning I was a little
disappointed but Lee said the second
squish the second Paul in the bag always
seemed to get more you know I mean yeah
you get that first little really nice
but it's always that second pull so
remember squish once squish twice yeah
or you know eventually you could get to
your point I mean if we squish the
24-percent
I probably would have been like I think
we got it all yes that does happen all
right you see there's a little and they
kind of burst it a tiny bit so they
right at the back here all right way
this the first bit here was that point
focus yes collected that it's already
turning to a shatter lake substance as
well so another point five got you 20%
what six even point six solid its paste
solid absolutely yes
would be as well - I'm quite happy for
us to go out right now and have your
that beautiful view you're not gorgeous
I mean I'm the camera guy right now so I
get to come out here and take a look
about sun's shining but it's definitely
just one of those views that are epic I
get to see this all the time that was
pretty awesome yeah that was good we got
a couple of half gram squishes real nice
done there and once again you teaching
me stuff what we're learning stuff
together stuff together we've got our
pens we've got the dabber let's uh let's
hit some of that first backage be my
goodness look at this many push for the
wind it's hard like hard Safi it's hard
like Cathy big toffee and it does fold
like a taffy like you know that toffee
we can snap it or oppose nicely
well put that somewhere so far away from
me I'm just taking a nice little baby
one Oh baby
we do lots of those so you know what
quite happy to see how that was squish
you know my timer my fault oh well I
figured you might actually things you'd
be all over it it doesn't really work
that well Wow
I don't know anytime I swipe up from the
bottom
even from the clothes that [ __ ] I had no
idea can actually I think your phone
just died
am I wrong or can I just not see there
it is
stop watch boom boom alright so give me
20 seconds you keep this up
20 seconds for the heat up so I always
question the heat up is there a time do
you make it like a red hot you make it
so it's blowing somebody out of glass it
depends on the size of the banger it
depends on the size of the banger so the
double XL banger his isn't going red and
22nd oh no I'm definitely not that's
what I've been doing you can leave it oh
wait another 50 seconds so in a minute
10 seconds I'll hit my dad now I have a
quartz banger at home is that kind of
like it's like degrading it's kind of
weird
so I had questionable that we were
actually talking to well I'd say I was
talking to some other glass boys and and
these cheaper quartz bangers to fix the
crushed quartz and they made in China
and then they kind of fused together so
they knew overtime to be grating start
coming apart like especially if you heat
it up red-hot and then it has the banger
heated up red-hot so as you know mine
are coming apart as you can hear what's
going on here
you've got the hole you've got the
breakdown though you know why it's
happening I put I had to you know you
gonna learn that stuff so that was the
breakdown and I was actually using her
like high-end torches for heating up my
banger so I did take it to that extreme
limit and well I'm learning there's
cheap quartz bangers that I made from
cross courts and then there's real
quartz bangers that cost you hundreds of
dollars and that's the reason why cheap
is cheap it's so true it's hard to get
around to no matter how hard people try
no it's just you're not gonna get around
some people strong [ __ ] I'm learning as
we all are brother especially with how
fast things are changing now in the
scene in the industry it's like anyone
that says there they aren't learning is
going to be left behind
I said we're always scratching the
surface of the supplant that we're
researching it's just marvelous to see
how things are actually the things are
catapulting now into the industry and
people and just like
yeah position yeah they're in full
spread seeing who can make it to the
finish line
we're sitting back like this well we're
doing our things was our life long
before pretty much has me mission it was
nice you want me to eat you up please
all right see I'm gonna lose my iPhone
properly I'm get around for a few months
guys I'll get you on it
we gotta get on the iPhone again the
sound side a finally bottom out we put
one thing and and you got to get going
dude or you're gonna be in traffic for
hours how about that I don't that sucks
you know it's always spend three hours I
Drive three hours it's kind of like my
model so if I'm coming to your place and
you look for us from my house expect I'm
saying for at least eight because that's
an eight-hour drive like going around a
minute 15 a minute 20 115 120 I like you
got it off to the side so you can
actually see it instead of its kind of
yeah then I'll carve you up as well here
I got John the carb I always like burn
the rest this would definitely be you
can see I got the marks see the marks
that's not good yeah that would
definitely be huge mark and see I have
no marks how do I think Shh
only branding yourself right I'll do it
nice
trying to be with the perfect low temp
tab no chazz chazz free rip it's gonna
make clean and oh so easy still gonna
give him a couple of nice little baby
roots too damn near took it all in the
first it's pretty good job pretty good
that was Daisy
that was tasty stuff that was your stuff
man is your medicine
by trying so many different ways you
know it's like
it's interesting
or just the flavors were they using
different presses or different
temperatures because it's definitely a
different flavor from that press the
public amis the president usually but
not by much is just he's more profoundly
I don't know maybe I just really needed
that too I think you did I think it was
great right there you go lay back and
relax on the puffs winds they fall is in
the air John and you know it was a
beautiful summer here in British
Columbia although the fires have been
very intense so we are welcoming the
rain of course has backcountry people
and snowboards ski type people we're
gonna be welcoming the precipitation
because that ends up being snow on the
mountains snow on the mountains but yeah
fall is a unique period it's kind of
there's not a lot that you can do you
can't really go mountain biking it
becomes dangerous downhill dirt biking
becomes something cold and wet although
you can't still do it
fishing fishing yeah fish but yeah it's
just kind of falling you know it's a
like an in-between stage where we're
like okay I'm just looking at the trio's
changing colors they are there's a lot
of leaves already fallen on the ground
as well not necessarily here but when
you go into the city and stuff you see
whole parks that are like it's like you
can't believe how many leaves are on the
ground it's pretty wild
well what do you say Johnny B should we
call it a day and let you get on your
way I think that wraps up for nice chill
puffs Wednesday I'll take a couple macro
shots of the bud and take some close-up
video and we'll
we call it a wrap thanks for watching
everybody see you next time
[Music]
Sony's strike like seen as the margin
break my game is open why this one was
up in my face the wisdom of the way my
gets that straight
[Music]
I love the suit