[Music]
All right.
Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World
and I want to welcome my two guests. We
got uh Golden Bear Hades on Instagram if
you want to check him out and Winds
West. And I was with these guys the
other day for Hashurch. And uh we kind
of had all this epic glass together and
had this feeling like we wanted to have
a session, but really the session was
hash church. The focus was hash church.
So today we've decided that uh 420
session is in session and it's going
down. These guys have come down from
Whistler and uh we're here right on the
beautiful House Sound and we've got what
I would call a pretty damn epic lineup.
Pretty stacked up there by anyone's
standards. Perfect. So, we've got uh on
the far left here, your lookers right,
we've got the Swiss Perk, which is a
gift uh from Nate Dizzle years ago when
I went to Holland with him and we uh
drove down to Germany along with uh
Steve Hops to do some collaborations.
Those guys did some collaborations with
Martin from RU. Uh next to that we've
got a prototype uh Fab Egg from Scott
Deppy's company, The Mothership. And
then uh I'll let you explain your piece.
Third in line there. So this is a Marcel
um Dale Smer's collab. It's
a pretty epic. It's got uh some big
thick flat cane on it. some of Marcel's
readies on the base and in the center
and on the disc mouth. I don't know if
you can see. Yeah, that disc mouth is
ridiculous. And and the slide for it,
too. It's pretty awesome. So beautiful.
Marcel actually explained a little bit
about this piece if you guys want to get
some of the history on the last episode
of Hashurch episode 29. I think he comes
in around 18 or 19 minute mark and he
starts talking about it. So, uh, next in
line after that is another clear proto
from Mothership. Uh, this one being the
Taurus, Scott Deppy's design on the
recycler. Uh, it's got a DC glass
banger. And then, uh, next in line, next
in line is an Aaron Colbert uh, Dutch
pump. Uh, Aaron just started working on
these designs this year and he's been
killing it. Super functional. Uh, and
the color way is uh, lemonrop over
pomegranate. And then the guy after that
is uh, Mothership Elite Ball Rig. Uh the
color is
Equinox. Uh the guy after that is an AK
absolute crunk uh
recruit. And uh then a blue Stardust
little stack low
recycler. And then after that you got a
Dosa part of the mother ship and it's
his little tube. It's a his rainbow
ready over the crushed opal. Um it's
really thick um because of the layering
of the crush and the opal. Um, it's
uranium, so under black light, it glows
like crazy. Yeah, it's beautiful. Yeah,
it's one of those sleepers. You don't
really know what it does until you
actually put that light onto it. And
then after that, you got a slop cup.
It's actually a collab between Zach P
and Slop. Um, it's a nice little ripper.
And then beside that, it's a little
Snick. Uh, it's his new line. It's the
the Trill Jammers is what he's calling
them. It's uh double cup purple with
slime and peach. So, it's a it's a
little pocket right kind of. Yeah.
Beautiful. And then finally to finish it
off, we've got the straight fab. A
pretty big beast of a straight fab. Uh
they're not making these any longer. The
holes, the perk holes are put in really
low, which I really like about this
piece. Really adds to the chug. It's got
a Cory Cottenum uh drop down that was a
gift from Flav. and it has the new
silicon carbide um hybrid titanium nail
plugged into the dabinator. So, we've
got the D nail on this side plugged into
the mother ship with the Pooking B um
quartz bowl. And then also I we didn't
mention that this um Dutch pump is
rocking a double XL banger from DC
Glass. So, we're going to hit that one
today. Super excited. Yeah. Maybe
towards the end we'll just drop some
huge rip that we can all drop a ribbon
in there. I'm not really like a guy to
take a 2 g rip, but I'll definitely
share a big giant double XXL rip with uh
with you guys. No problem. Sounds good
to me. So, yeah, we also put a little
bit of treats out on the table here.
We've obviously got our beautifully
cleaned water with some ice, but we've
also got some organic strawberries and
some uh bread with some oil and vinegar.
I thought it would be a good kind of way
to cleanse our pallet between some of
the rips that were taken. It's awesome.
And then you guys went and did uh outdid
yourselves over here, didn't you? A
bunch of work the last couple days. We
made a fat slab of rosin. A fat slab of
rosin, you don't say. Another fat slab
other than the one we had on Hashurch,
right? Well, that's definitely got to be
qualifiable as a fat slab. Strip it
open. A forearm
even. That's how you guys post the
picture. Oh yeah. Let's
see. Yep. That is quite something. I
just uh have a new
appreciation knowing for 100% sure that
there's no solvent or, you know, parts.
And the flavor profile is unlike any oil
I've ever had in my life. Yeah, it's
literally pretty unique, isn't it? We've
also got some Horatio Delbert. Um his
latest lemonine, I guess, distillation.
He's literally I don't know if it was
like a rosin type process, but basically
he cleaned up his LHO to a new level and
this is very very very new and will
probably take a couple of dabs of that
as well. Really good medicine. This is
decarboxilated fully 100% activated
before you heat it up and take a rip. So
you can rub it on your skin, you can
consume it orally, or you can dab it,
which is to me that's that's that raw
raw. That's the real medicine right
there. Yeah, absolutely. And then of
course I got a little bit of D420K dry
sift. We'll be hitting some
dabs dunks of that. So between the hash,
the rosin, and the oil, I think uh I
think we're good to go. It's just a
matter of uh where do we begin,
gentlemen? Where do what would you pick
if you had your pick? Because you do.
That's tough. You know, it'll be an
interesting thing without any sort of
what piece. Are we start at one end of
the table or do we just start picking
off? You could literally start anywhere
you want. I'm I might start in the
middle and just kind of Hey, I don't
mind starting in the middle because the
middle puts me right around here. Yeah,
it's not a bad spot to start.
Start in the mini section. Yeah,
literally these two are both the six the
the sixth piece. They both meet right in
the middle. So, I guess what I should do
is hit them both simultaneously out of
each nostril. Totally joking. That's not
what you do with elites. What do you
guys What do you What's your take on
people flipping rigs? Uh, it hurts my
heart. Oh my god, does it hurt my heart?
What is that? Did someone just want to
like, hey, we should infuse some massive
stupidity into a really kind of cool
like thing. It's tough to say, right?
Uh, it sounds cool. Like, my ships do
flips. And the idea of like flipping a
piece before you take a rip is cool, but
the idea of losing potentially that
piece that breaks breaks my heart. and
just uh yeah, I must just be too old
because I can't even wrap my head around
it at all. I I haven't seen much of it.
Some guy posted in the Mothership group
today and he had flipped a piece and
then took the rip and I was like, it had
one of these on it and I was literally
like, did he just put that on afterwards
or did he flip it with it? And I watched
the video again. I was like, he flipped
it with that. It's probably nicely
resined in there though, too. Even if it
is, I've seen people put buckets in
after they flip it and then I've seen
people with, you know, flip it with
buckets in and it's crazy. Yeah, it is
crazy. I've seen people flipping their
AKs as well. I think that's just it's
hard to handle for sure. Yeah, I
couldn't imagine flipping that thing.
All right. Well, I'm
thinking I think I'm going to hit this
little guy. Your boy blue. Yeah, the
Equinox. It's right in the middle. I'm
in the
middle. And what better piece to start
off with? That color pull is amazing.
I've never seen another elite with that
color pull. There isn't one. It is very
unique. The human in it is uh what sets
it off any blue as well. It's like an
absolute champ, too, doesn't it? So, now
to figure out, do I want to torch
quartz? Do I want to hit silicon
carbide? So many choices now. You've
narrowed down the rig. Yeah. Well, you
know what I did? I've only ever hit this
rig with the banger. A banger. So, I
think what I'll do, um, you don't mind
quartz going indirect? No, should be all
right. Yeah, quartz is is generally
pretty darn
good. Just bring that over this
way. Hold on to that for a second. I
love the quartz cuz it doesn't get hot.
Yeah. We'll give it a little wipe with
this just for cleaning. Yeah.
Just to make sure nothing goes into
the into the
rig. Yes, I will clean my quartz before
I put it into your
elite. God, that just made a lovely
sound. Oh, you want to go behind? I
think it's a good
idea. All
right. Now, what do I hit? What do I
hit? Do I hit Horatio's oil? Do I hit
the I think I hit the rosin. I mean,
that's a giant [ __ ] tub of rosin. I
would start with some rosin. Definitely
rosin, bro.
Lo, not get too much out of this right
there. There it is. Right there. I'll
give you yours. Want to grab me a little
a little
rosen. Yeah, that's nice. That looks so
sweet with the little nail on it. Yeah,
fits it. What would be incredible is if
you could get a quartz bowl with this
color pull. Could you imagine?
But it's just the perfect distance away
to to not be too close. You know what I
mean? It's it's border, but it's like
just got to watch your hat. Yeah. Thank
you. My pleasure. All right. Well, here
we go. Feel free to pick pick a p piece
as well, guys. I mean, it's uh we can
hit multiples at a time.
Oh, that's cushy. Oh, yeah. Very cushy.
That is really awesome. Now, if one of
you have an interest on hitting this
with a nail on it, I will pass it over.
I was going to ask for that next. Yeah.
Start in the center. Keep it going.
Might as well, cuz that's actually a
real nice
hit with the electric nail on there.
Going for the straight fab.
Yep. Now, the straight fab I have set up
right now. It's sort of in an
experimental phase in the sense that oh
I know what it's doing what we're doing
wrong actually why you're going to get a
super low temp hit although it might not
necessarily be wrong but I'll tell you
this particular head that I have on here
you see how it's big it fits a 20 mm ah
and you got the flat coil on it and I've
got the flat coil on because the other
one I have the silicone carbide is just
the head and it come this middle piece
isn't in it so we could potentially try
that out
here. And that is some strong rosin.
That's very nice. Love that rosin.
Mhm. Oh yeah. Such a treat to be in uh
presence of such beautiful
glass with great
hash, great solvent free oil.
It was uh quite an experience going over
to Horatios the other day and getting to
play around in his lab. Yeah, it really
was uh it was you know it's a lot of
people are hard on him in the sense that
oh he's not sharing his concepts and his
ideas. Well, it's like because he's he
feels very responsible that he doesn't
want to share anything that's generally
going to be dangerous to people.
Absolutely. You know, you share
something the wrong way and then all of
a sudden that can be it can it can have
a bad outcome. So, he's really put his
energy and time into making sure that
everything is 100% safe and efficient
and well, like you said, if you don't
have, you know, any knowledge in
chemistry or a degree in chemistry, the
process might, you know, not be on the
level that you're extracting at or that
you're used to uh you're proficient at,
rather. Yep. Yep. Exactly. What a great
rip. Starting it out strong with the
mini ball rig. My goodness. I need a
strawberry. That's what I
need. Yeah, that's pretty sweet looking
uh little unit you got there. All of
them so unique and so different in their
functionality from It's interesting how
we have the pillars on either side. The
Swiss Perk, which I mean, I don't know
if it had it did, but it must have
inspired.
That's why I said before we started all
this. I was it has to have the
inspiration kind of it has to have it
on. When I first had the Fab Egg and the
Straight Fab described to me without
seeing them, I had them described to me
as a 360 degree Swiss perk, right? Mhm.
And I'd say that's pretty accurate.
Yeah, it really is. Exactly. I uh when I
first saw the Swiss Perk, I have to say
I was somewhat like I was like, "Oo, I
don't know if I can really deal with
that." Like it looked so strange. And
then I was smoking it out of it. This
piece was my daily driver for a long
time. Like to the point where I took it
camping. Oh, cool. That piece has been
punted into the bushes multiple times.
Like in the pitch black, people getting
up by the fire and just being
like Oh, it's so thick. Yeah. Super
thick. Yeah. So, it's a real sort of
wellused piece. I always got to shout
out Nate Dizzle for uh for the gift
because it it blew me away and I
remember it blowing S away. Him being
like, "Why is He's like, "Why do the
hits taste better out of that pipe?" Cuz
I sold S like the Jason Lee double and
triple bubbler marble sllingers back in
01, 02, 03. S's always been on the ball
with the newest, latest, greatest,
right? More for function than art. He's
really more into the just the
functionality, at least from my
perspective. He couldn't believe how
much the Swiss Perk made the hit taste
better.
So interesting. Functionality all the
way. Function over fashion. But if you
can get fashion with your function,
that's what kills it, dude. There you
go. Right.
Make this more
accessible. Drinking out of the bottle.
I brought extra water for when ours gets
low. Yeah. Nice.
Top it up there,
brother. Have a little piece of bread
and I love the idea of um cannabis
tapas. Just having nice things out on
the
table. Definitely makes the session that
much nicer, you know. It sure does.
And often the only thing that
really ends a session for me
is becoming too hungry or too thirsty.
It's true. To want to continue. Very
true. Got to fill the hunger gap. Mhm.
I'm going to torch this guy up. AK. And
what fills the hunger gap better than
bread and strawberries?
That's my favorite of my uh AKs right
there. It's got the nice booty to it.
Nice fat. The shaping of these older
ones is uh definitely one of my
favorites.
Sweet. You
want triple torch threat. The torch
torch works quick though.
I just do a dump of
[Applause]
[Music]
this. Nothing wrong with a little
dump. Proper crowd cap for that. Do we
have a FZ? I didn't see one on the
table. I have one. There's that right
there in front of you. Is that what? Oh,
no. I didn't pull it out. There's one in
my case.
Grab a low temp top from there.
So, what kind of times do you guys like
to leave your quartz for? say in regards
to oil versus hash, rosin being oil, um
the LHO being oil, anything else oil
wise that you hit? I have my timer that
I use at
uh dab.ninja
um hooked up. It's uh
I typically go for He's on his phone.
Yeah, I was just pulling my timer to set
it up for, you know, for those best
flavors. I typically we had a funny
conversation off camera. You had to be
there. I typically hit about 42 to 45
seconds for all my oil. And I tend to
not dab hashes um other than rosin I
guess
um on quartz. Any full melt I dab uh
with an enamel with a screen. Uh that
was so good though. Best flavor. I I was
coughing and exhaling the awesomeness of
that riff while you were I tried not to
hit dab hashes on and I was like I was
like you should
try. That was a really nice little rip.
Maybe I'll give it a whirl.
I mean, it is in a sense from an oil
perspective, you're going to have that
pain in the ass of being like, "Fuck,
that's like a lot of char left over
compared to like the clean oils that
leave nothing." You're always going to
get that leftover with tricom heads.
Whatever that membrane, whatever that is
that you're maintaining in the screen
when you press rosin, that ends up on
the nail. It's there right now. And it's
just a matter of torching it for a few
seconds. Uh few seconds extra. I might
have to try some of that D420K.
Yeah, please do. Dump it up, dab it up,
do whatever you need. You're welcome to
press it. Torch me. Yeah, there you go.
It's a torch.
Well, this is nice. We have uh also the
invitation to go see Flav later on. So,
we may potentially, you know, continue
this uh session for a bit here and
hopefully instill some positive
conversation that can somewhat uh lead
people to learning and whatnot. That's
what Bubble Man's World is all about.
Absolutely. Get that information out
there. Absolutely. But at the same time,
a real appreciation for a part of the
community that comes directly from the
smoking
aspect, which often people, you know,
they'll say, "Oh, your channel would be
more educational if you weren't just
sitting around smoking like teenagers."
Try to remind people that the smoking
aspect of cannabis is how a lot of us
came to learn a lot of what we know
about cannabis. the love for well the
passion and then literally like you
start seeking it out like why did we why
did Jack Herrer compile his book why
what led him to you know what I mean
like there's this fire within people
that seems to be ignited through the
smoking and the intake even orally of
cannabis that creates a love for it
creates this sort of you know and this
is one aspect of that love and what an
incredible aspect it is like Marcelo was
saying But the head is all it's not
really about the piece, but it's about
the story of how the piece came to be
and totally what it's gone through and
where it's um how you can sit down and
talk about different pieces and
different techniques that these artists
do and function and fashion of the
pieces
and the whole business end of it too.
And it's like well even the pieces
themselves are they're unique constructs
of fractioned aspects of learning that
are shared through specific
groups. So this guy learned I mean for
instance Jason Lee learned the double
bubbler can that second can weld. It was
a big deal when he just shared that with
Slinger and a host of other people. all
of a sudden that was at the forefront
and that's what everyone was selling.
Like Jason could have tried to hold on
to that in a way, but he really just put
it out there right away in a way that I
bet you a lot of people don't even know
that he was one of the first people to
really I didn't really know but produce
it. And then not only that, well, I had
a unique relationship with Jason back in
the day that he would send me the odd
time like prototype pieces. Like I
probably got six or seven of them over
the years, kind of clear or sometimes
somewhat worked prototype pieces that
were just
literally ways that he was I guess using
you know the piece was really just an
experiment to come up with whether that
seal works or whether it chugs properly
or here I tried this. Yeah, exactly. And
and because he's Jason, if he was
sending it to me, that it means he liked
it enough that it wasn't for sure, you
know, one that was going. A lot of
people don't understand that guys like
Jason, guys like Sling, Marcel,
uh, and then there's, you know, a host
of other glassers going back way before
them. Uh, you know, guys like Dan K,
Snodgrass, Hugh, all those guys. I had a
Huegh. That was my first piece. Yeah.
Like no one understands that all these
techniques, the shapings, the the seals,
everything evolved from everything those
guys were was crushing or were crushing
out back then. Absolutely. And uh that's
how it goes. Things didn't start at
Mothership. These guys, you know, had to
evolve to this point. The glass had to
evolve to this point. They bounce ideas
off of each other and see how things
went. And sure, everybody evolved into
their own things and kind of took ideas
from people and went their ways and
was killed it on their own levels. I'm
happy the hedges are coming back. Mhm.
Now, they never really went away, but
the appreciation
got lopsided, I think, for sure. It sure
is beautiful to see a a row of
them. Just nice, beautiful pieces.
Absolutely. Couple clear protos in
there, but they got the function to
them. Yeah. Right. They're respectable.
Well, do what say ye, dosa?
I'm passing that banger there, Jack.
Yeah, man. Try a little dab of harashio.
What am I going to dab? Mhm. I don't
know. Oh, yeah. I think I'm going to
take that. What are you going to dab on?
Let's go for three of those, I guess.
Three of those. Well, I'll start the
party.
I'll start the
party. This Dose is such a beautiful
piece. I kind of fell in love with it
the first time you showed it to me in
Whistler at the uh actually if you guys
want to check out the first time I seen
this piece. It's uh it's the Whistler
video with uh with Aaron from DNA and
Matt the Great Gardener and
uh Flav
421. You're there. Who else was there?
That guy might Yeah, Devin might have
been there too. It's hard to remember
but it's worth checking out the video.
We have a good session and there's as
well a beautiful lineup of headies. Just
the ridiculous pipes that Flav had alone
were like he he brought a lineup. We had
a few doses out that Yep. 100%.
Let that go for a little bit longer.
Yeah. It's always nice to get that low
time.
And so a lot of people, you know, this
is a personal thing, but it's pretty
easy to figure out on your own level
what's too hot as opposed to what's too
too low. if that's possible for you. And
uh I noticed it a lot with the CBD
Renee. I was dabbing CBD Renee dry sift
through quartz and I was just finding
that at certain temperatures it was so
candied out and if you went too hot it
just all that candy flavor was gone.
I've only had CBD oil, but I noticed
that as well. higher temperatures, super
cherry-l like flavors, lower
temperatures, super floral
notes, and uh just
that contrast in flavor was
[Music]
incredible. God, that just completes the
piece. That was super low temp and it
was
nice. I know people can't see the baby
dabs of this LH show that we're doing,
but they are absolutely tiny and they
hit like freight trains. I can't It
does. I can't even explain it. Like, it
totally does. Bman gave me a dab a bit
earlier on and I was like, "Okay, well,
I'll take this little dab here." It was
a little bit smaller than I would
normally dab and it just crushed me and
I was like, "Wow." Like, big ups to
Horatio. Stuff is amazing. Yeah. Doing
the good work. Decarved already. We were
saying the highlight. There's something
about that. It definitely feels
medicine-in-y in the way that it goes in
and just feels like a very strong
edible. It Yeah, it feels like right
away it melts your muscles. Any type of
any sort of like discomfort that you
have just gets taken away right away.
That is extremely that is the difference
between making hash in your you know in
your basement as opposed to you know now
going into the lab and producing
literally a neutrautical to
pharmaceutical level medicine. It even
smells very very herbal in the scent to
it. Yeah, it really does. It is pretty
strong. What do you need? Yeah. Thank
you. Caparoo.
Kaparooi. Ah, this is
L. So many nice pieces. What to hit
next? And then go meet up with Vlad. And
I'm sure he's going to be like
more heavy to the heavy. The table could
be so ridiculously heavy, which it kind
of already is.
I'm I mean, I puff out of prototypes or
pro production pieces, uh, you know,
clear glass most of the time.
I love the Elites. I think they're
awesome and amazing. And for whatever
reason, I just haven't focused my
attention in the collecting of them. I,
you know, Flav and Higherend Row, they
have such beautiful pieces that it
almost feels like enough to just be
exposed to them, you know? I think if I
Those collections just inspire people. I
mean, clothes collections inspired me
for sure. different inspired. I love
them. West over here like Yeah. No, I
love the collection, but for whatever
reason, what made me get a Marcel is
definitely Flav's collection for sure.
Oh, yeah. Flav's got some beautiful
Marcel's. Collecting glasses been
something that I've loved for uh a few
years now. It's good fun. It's amazing.
You know what I mean? It's brought me to
uh to meet some incredible people, to
have some uh pretty incredible memories.
Maybe we'll pull out my headies. I've
got like the 99 Marcels. Oh, please.
Let's do it. I would love to see I would
love to see those are in my office. But
those are the true hedies. We go into
the city. It's true. They are
ridiculous, dude. That's where started
for people that don't really know glass.
It was my first head. It was I mean I
had a Hugh Grass and it was nice and
there I'd seen Snodgrass pieces and I'd
seen all those style of pieces but it
was like and maybe they were even
considered heady and I even met Jason
Lee in 1998 when I picked up Marble
Slinger Hitchhiking and Jason Lee was
the guy that was with him and he showed
me what he called a 420 piece and I was
like what do you mean 420? was like,
"It's $420 bucks." And I was like, "
$420 for a pipe back then?" That must
have been so like mindblowing, right?
And it was like this crazy beautiful
piece that he had like blown this clear
orb of glass around the bowl. The whole
top of the bowl was just clear glass.
And he had put a little hole in it and
filled it with water. Like filled it
right up. I was like, "How did you do
that?" He's like, "Oh, it took a long
time." It's like eventually you get all
the air out. It's all full of water and
the one little drop of air plugs the
hole so it doesn't leak. Crazy. It's
crazy. And anytime you put a nug in the
bowl, it magnifies the bud like a
picture all the way around the pipe. So
I was just like, "Oh my god, dude. That
is [ __ ] maybe the greatest thing I
ever seen." In fact, if we do end up at
my office later looking at some of my
headies, I have a chillum and it says
bubble man and it's made by Jason Lee
and the whole top of it is a clear glass
piece that you fill with water. So mag
the reason he did that for me was cuz
when I met him he had that piece and I
was just like what? But then in 99 when
Marcel came out with the stacked
sculpture piece, I don't pretend to say
that he was the first person to ever do
that, but it was definitely the first
time me or any of the people I knew
around everywhere I took it had had ever
seen. And I'd pull that thing out of a
box and people would just be like, "Are
you kidding me?" I can imagine. They'd
be like, "How much was that? How much
was that piece?" be like, "Oh, like 4G's
$4,000 pipe in 1999." It was really
insanity. Insanity, dude. Yeah. And I
dropped that. I was like, "Dude, I'm
like I remember meeting Marcel." I was
like, "How?" Like I'm like, "How can you
expect someone to pay that? That's just
so ridiculous." An hour and a half
later, I was I was offering him to break
it in cuz I I I bought it.
That's how it is. That's how it is with
that. Like you see it and you're like,
"Oh, that's awesome." But that I don't
know if I can afford it, but you can't
sleep and then all of a sudden, yeah,
you can't sleep on it and it just keeps
you up at night. Makes your palms sweat,
affects how you eat the collectors, to
me anyways. Like, wow, that's heavy
duty. It's a real thing and we're
talking about it here on Bubble Man's
World. You know, the glass addiction.
Yeah. just that that collecting is an
addiction. Collecting is an addiction
and I and people like literally to the
point where it could could bankrupt you
the way like uh you know going to the
casino. Absolutely. Because I've seen it
on a certain level. Absolutely. you
know, within within range. The
particularly what I like about
collecting is it teaches you
responsibility.
And at the same time, when I when I try
to have the discussion with people that
are outside of the community or the
scene and they're just like, "Well,
that's just ridiculous." And I'm, you
know, like, "You could buy a car with
that." And I'm like, "Well, yeah, or you
could buy that piece and sell it in two
years and make profit. That could buy
you two cars." It's very true. So, but
it's it's like playing the stock market.
It is. Sometimes you get lucky and
sometimes you don't. Uh, but the thing
about collecting the piece, the thing
about collecting that I want to say is
don't buy a piece for its resell value.
Sure. Buy the piece because you love the
piece. Collect it for you. Y, that's why
I've collected what I have. That's
generally why you would want to collect.
I mean, there's always people that are
going to buy it. How long have you had
your AK for? I've had my AK since 2009,
2010. Um, people don't know about AK
until like what, maybe two years ago.
Like a lot of the people, it's tough to
say. It's tough to say when, you know,
the hype started, but you know, I've had
my mother ship the So, this has gone up
in price like 18,000%. A ridiculous
amount compared to what I paid for it.
That's awesome. Um, but you know, like
you buy for love, you don't buy for you
don't buy for resale value. And then,
you know, well, you don't usually
someone does. A lot of people do. And I
I made a post about this on my Instagram
lately, and it wasn't, you know, a bunch
of collectors received it very well. And
a bunch of people who flipped didn't who
flipped glass, you know, didn't receive
it very well because they thought they
were getting called out. And, you know,
I'm not trying to hurt any feelings. I
just there's a lot of art that gets
flipped and that's part of the reason
why glass is so expensive these days.
Yeah, that's the art world though in
general. People always anything that can
can fetch a price in those ranges is
going to have a group of people that
hone in on it. Especially because what
they're feeding on is feeding off of is
that energy of you like wanting that
peace and you know what I mean? want to
grab like people desiring these pieces
so much that of course someone's going
to try to step in
and profit off of it. And then with
regards to what you just said about
people desiring the glass like glass thy
has gone up in the last which is just
terrible. It's the most gut-wrenching
thing. I mean I I have way more like
that that's something that really to me
I would call out. You know what a lot of
pieces have come back through the help
of the community though a lot. What did
you even What do you do with it? A piece
like that once you've, you know, like
you've stolen a piece. Great. What are
you going to do with it? I heard about a
mother ship getting stolen and the
person who stole it was rolling into a
into a lounge and dabbing out of it for
the same day they stole it. That's
crazy.
Yeah, that's insane. Like mothership
groups on Facebook, they it got shared
super quick. Somebody noticed it was
gone and it's wicked. It got brought
back. This thing's pretty sick, eh?
Super mini cup.
I just know for me certain things get
into my collection and they don't
leave. And that's what collecting is.
You know what I mean? It's not holding
on to something for 5 months and then
being like, oh, in order to afford
something else, I need to sell this. You
know, that's one way to do it. I'm not
I've done that. I'm not Yeah. Like I'm
not I'm not smiting anyone. I'm just
saying like that's there's collecting
and that's the base that I come from and
I must come from that base too cuz I
have glass from 9798 99 and we're now in
2015. So yeah 17 18 year. That's
incredible. Even that orb I showed you
earlier was from ' 06. Oh this thing
mind
thing is pretty crazy. So I yeah I've
been offered so much money over the
years for that Marcel number one and
I've always just been like oh you know
like Marcel actually always made sure
that I don't know if he feels this way
anymore but back in the day he
definitely said if you ever consider
selling it I would appreciate it if you
contacted me before
uh you know anyone else. I think for
certain pieces that's especially like
meaningful pieces I think that's cool.
Mhm. I've made some trades and some some
sales with close friends and that's been
one of the conditions. It's like listen,
if this ever gets sold, I'm the person
that you talk to about selling it. Uh it
has to come back to me if it goes
anywhere. And I think that's especially
between friends, between uh people that
have respect each other. I think that's
definitely something that's uh good to
do. Well, Marcel's the blower of the
piece. It was a historic piece and his
steps of blowing glass. Absolutely.
Makes total sense that if you were going
to,
you know, you know, want to move it that
you would just approach him and goes
back into his vault if anything. Yeah.
And just be like, work out the, you
know, hey, I would like to um I would
like to have a piece of or pieces of
this stature. Cuz I'll tell you, that
piece was expensive back then, but now
it's priceless. But now it's Yeah.
Like if there was a Heavy Glass Museum,
that would be a cornerstone piece, dude.
You know, Yep.
I do know. Absolutely. And I smoked it
with so many people. That's another
piece of history. Incredible. The big
shot. The big shot. Big shot coming
up. Sloth is real nice. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
I can't remember
this. It doesn't
matter. No, it has to be in
order. All right. Well, someone's got to
hit the XL. Double
XL. Yeah. Get the Duchy
roll. That thing is ridiculously huge.
We don't even have anything to carve
this thing. It's uncarvable, man. Oh,
wait a minute. Oh, that kind of guy.
Fits. Maybe that'll fit. That's a big
one. It's a little bit better than that.
That's for the silicone carbide. So,
even though it doesn't look that big,
it's pretty big. It's massive. Yeah,
it's massive.
It's massive. I'm not going to be taking
a monster massive rip right off the bat,
but I am going to hit this giant double
XL bowl just to see how she hits. I
won't be putting two grams of anything
in it.
Just yet.
There is still daylight. So, a little
bit early for that. There is still day
daylight. Yeah. I hope we really do make
it into the city and bump into Flav
because it would
sure just step it up. You know, this is
a good fun chunk of video looking at all
this glass, all this glass, talking
about the different
uh aspects of their functions and the
glass blowers and the
community even from the collecting
standpoint because obviously these two
guys are collectors and in a sense I've
never really thought of myself as a
collector but as winds here was talking
I thought geez I am a collector. Yeah,
you got a pretty good collection
stashed. It all started kind of uniquely
for me. They were my friends. Mhm. I met
them and they were kind of young upand
cominging glass blowers and I just loved
what they were doing. I felt like it was
like a form of
activism that they chose to, you know,
because they could have done any aspect
of glass blowing, but they chose to do
the form of glass blowing that produced
pipes for smoking,
hash and consequence, cannabis. The
stories of how you met them was or are
rather incredible. You know what I mean?
Right.
Good old fish tours and stuff. It's over
the top. Pulling Yui just because some
guy looks like he needs a ride. Yeah. On
the wrong side of the street, bro.
Pulling a Yui.
Hey, I think I want to pick that guy up.
Whatever.
Turns out it's Jay Lee. Holy [ __ ] Yeah,
it was Slinger, but then he was with Jay
Lee.
male version of this.
Uh, we can only hope.
Yeah. 20 mil coil might Jesus Christ. Is
it
raging? There. Is it raging? Uh, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. It's pretty hot. Can I have
a hobo fire? Like if I put this in there
right now, I think it would burst into
flames. My buddy did that with the dabs
ball toss. He got it on the first try.
Have a hobo. whole thing went like one
of
these. I'm totally not doing it. Not
going to do
it. All right. Where are we going
here? Little dry sip from D420K through
the Dutch pump.
Shout out to
[Music]
Aaron. Oh, that was really nice.
Super smooth kind of hit that thing,
huh? Tell you that hit like a like a
freight train, too.
size dab and uh he doesn't even look
like it touched a quarter of that
bucket. Yeah, not even close. I still do
feel the need to want to like scrape
away the leftovers.
This thing's still raging, by the way.
You can probably take like eight low
temp temp. That's probably one thing
where this thing will come in really or
Yeah, you just light it up once and then
just pass it around. It's like, no, no,
dude. It'll be good for everyone's in a
corner. It's good for like an hour, bro.
It's good for an
hour. I'll blow that out and clean it
out
later. That was super nice. What was
this guy over
here? Like a
spaceship. Park these beasts with
precision and
accuracy. We won't be flipping ships
here today. No, it's the ship flip free
zone.
Flip flip free. I like it. Pretty
stoned. I had to think about that for a
second. Kind
of feel like I'm good talking. Then LH
just kind of taps you on the shoulder.
It's like, "No, you're going to trip
over the next three words." Yeah.
Right. Decarbed medicine. Yeah.
What hasn't gotten? It says for oral use
only syringe here.
I don't know about that. Did a Swiss
perk get ripped? I don't think the Swiss
perk's been ripped. No, I don't in front
of me, but I might switch it up. Could
hit the Swiss perk. Dizzle
up. Um, what have I hit? I've hit the
Dutch pump. I've hit the Equinox and
ship. I've hit the zop. I hit the dosa.
I hit the stack low.
Huh. I've been doing pretty good. Hit it
pretty far down the line. Not too bad at
all. Might have to hit the
monkey. The slop cut banger fits on
that. Hey, what's up, buddy? That's
pretty wicked, actually.
Like, it's bizarre yet awesome. And it's
got some good function to it. Oh, I can
tell right off the bat just by the size
of it and
stuff. Pretty tight,
too. I often find these little rigs to
be the ones that will often give you
that look kind of like I almost fell off
my chair. So, which one are we doing on
this guy?
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh yeah, look at that.
This is just like your little pocket
rig. Yeah, perfect little sits sits by
my bed. Dude, it's so sick. Now, who did
this? Tell me about this piece of it
again. Uh Snick. Snick. Snick did this.
Yeah. Wow. This is a new thing. He's
been kind of doing okay. Well, that's it
was uh from age this year. Right on.
A couple nice little opals in it. What
is a piece like this move for on the
open market?
15 I think. 1500.
Just
1500o. Got to be real careful with Yeah,
he sits in this case. Yeah, I guess so.
Gets pulled out, used put back away.
Yeah. He comes through and sits by my
bed for a while and he was back in his
case. I see.
Excellent. I'm I'm excited to hit
it cuz I have a little
Yeah. Just got that low temp. Nothing
like that Swiss function.
Can you park that for me? Yep. Thank
you. I can park that for you.
That's
perfect. Need to be
uh Oh, maybe I do. We'll see what
happens. I like this. Hey, careful
now. Trying to pull on. Oh, it did drop.
I thought I felt it on my hand.
Uhhuh. Fixed.
Well, I got to say I like this little
snake so far in my hand. The way it's
just super trippy monkey face looking at
you with the smirk on his
face. The eyes are pretty uh pretty
cool. Yeah, the marbles are dope.
I think it's ridiculous. That giant
[ __ ] thing.
It is crazy. So funny to put it in small
rings, too. Yeah. Stick your thumb right
down. Yeah, might as well. There we go.
Yeah, that's People watching can see.
Awesome.
You know, when you the madness, when you
need a a banger that
uh that will go three, four dabs before
it's cooled down. If you want to dab
your whole stash at once, that's the way
to do it.
You dab me up again. Addicted to
[Music]
that pushed out.
Pardon
me. RIP. Little rips
always hit with
ferocity. Cool monkey. Have you seen my
mink? Anyone else want to hit the
monkey? Yeah. Pass up this way. I'll
take Yeah. Come on. Give me another dab
before you do.
Give me another dab before you do,
please. Of what? LHO. No. Rosin. Rossin
them up.
Can't stop dabbing
that. I shouldn't purpos.
Why should you stop? Damn it. Feel like
when I first started dabbing oil way
back, it's like that same kind of like I
just want that taste in my
mouth constantly.
So much cleaner. Never thought I'd say
that.
Well, you know what? We're probably just
going to continue on doing this for
quite some time. So, we'll wrap it up
with the last rip here that Winds is
about to take. And uh hopefully we pick
right back up with a simple transition
into hanging out with Flav downtown
Vancouver. It's going to be fun. Yeah,
absolutely. And you know what? This has
just got me all inspired to go like
order some Goldies pizza or something.
Goldies before? I've never had Goldies.
So, before we go, I just want to say a
few things about Golden Bear Hades has
never had Goldies. Yes, please do. Um,
so Aaron is a new up andcoming Well,
he's not new. He's been on the tour
since 2012, but he's uh this is kind of
like his breakout year. He's really
hitting it hard. Uh, he's a good friend
of mine, local to Colona.
And
uh yeah, these Dutch pumps are the
[ __ ] Now you get on the boat. 40
seconds now. Yeah, about 40
seconds. So Puff Canada just had two of
these and sold
them instantly basically. Uh I'll have a
few for sale and then uh Hetty Shops
around North America. hit Aaron Colbert
up uh or me up and uh we'll take care of
you. So that's Aaron Colbert, Dutch
disc, Dutch
punk. It's cool. It's definitely cool.
They're all [ __ ] cool. Swiss Perk
into Fab Egg into Marcel Old School into
Taurus into Ball
Rigg AK Zlop Dosa
Stacklo and that little guy the Snick
and of course the Straight
Fab. So many different cool
functions. Instagram's really cool that
you can get in touch with so many of
these different artists directly. It's
one of the great things about it. I
think I I know most artists aren't able
to deal with all of that aspect of the
business and they just pass it on to
different people and businesses that
they do business with. Y, but it's neat
for the collector to be able to have
that chance to get in touch with the
artist and acquire glass direct. It
surely is very cool. All right, guys.
We're going to see you soon. Thanks for
watching Bubble Man's World.
Yeah,
I put all the tall pipes and he's just
gone. Yeah, he's washed out. It's just
like my Marcel's wearing a hat. Hey,
what's up? How's it going guys? Hey man,
you guys want to hit some dabs? He's
just that uh off camera voice. It's the
off camera voice for sure.
Hey guys, welcome back. Uh we of course
are not downtown Vancouver, but we did
go outside and get some pretty sick
pictures of the glass lined up outside
on the top of the banister. Probably
enough to give, you know, a normal
person a heart attack probably. Yeah,
they were hanging out there a little
bit. Stacking G's on the uh and we even
went off and ate while they just sat
over there. We did. We did indeed. We
had a little uh barbecue action there.
So, we are well famished and we thought,
you know what? Rather than leave you
hanging and just end the video, we
thought, let's go back and have another
mad session and hit a bunch of that
rosin and that dry sift and that LHO.
So, what do you say, gentlemen? Let's do
it. Shall we do this? Let's do it. I
say, oh boy.
And let's start with this little guy. He
was quite fun. Put this on there.
Yep. Perfect.
See the difference? Put it on upside
down. Pretty funny how this has been
sitting out here and Yep. It's nice
kindness that gloss over to it. Let's
smoke that. Head it up. No, I mean all
of it in the double XXL. All right. I'm
just joking. Just drop as much
as Oh, that cuts out nice. It really
does, dude. Miss melled straight. Whoa.
Look at that. E. Holy
mol. That's insane, dude. It's so tacky.
Like, that's insane.
We did vary temperatures a little bit.
So, one side is slightly tackier and one
side is slightly more like shatter
almost, but it's all tasty as hell. You
definitely have to rip it. Yeah, mine my
reach. Mind my reach, man. But I really
need this effing dab.
Come on now. Throw me that tool in your
hand. Tripping. Someone really had that.
Look at you guys going for the uh right
as I'm about to light the torch
up. Good old hand. The three uh
stooges. Luckily, we're not the three
stooges. I haven't hit this guy yet,
too. Oh, well, you better hit that. Have
I hit that yet?
Hit once. Oh, well, that's not enough.
No, no, no. I'm about to hit I mean, I'm
mostly hitting the pieces I don't have
access to, and I definitely want to hit
that Marcel, but I'm going to hit all of
these again real quick here.
Shoop torch. Yeah. Thank you. Oh, nice.
You're going
car for you guys.
Oh, this
guy. Love this little
guy. Look at the size of the dab he's
taking.
I'm taking like a little tiny baby. Just
really wanted to rip this. Mhm.
[Music]
Booyah. Teamwork makes the dream work.
That was really nice. It was very small,
but it was very
nice.
Snake
respect. All right, Stacklo, come here.
Come here
you. Uh, what are we going to drop in
the stack? Let's do a tiny little bit of
LH. Just enough
to get the dabber
[Music]
sticky. Do a little bit of a dipping. I
love that sift.
A small dip
in. That'll
do. All right. Torch. Beautiful. Thank
you. Stack those are really nice. You
did well with uh with getting this
guy. You're like, "Yeah, give me a
dozen." You order 10 of them. Oh, yeah.
I got
10. Bet you wished you got a dozen, huh?
Oh, I wish I got like 30 of them. I had
people lined up for them.
I kept them all local, though, which was
nice. Yeah. And yeah, I pretty much
tried keeping them all. Uh, most of them
are all in Vancouver. Um, a couple of
them went out to the east coast. They're
great. I wish I Canada. I missed the
boat on it, but I would have grabbed
one. I remember when I first saw it, I
was like, "Dude, I grabbed one of
those." Dude, shaping, function, size,
color, everything is really nice about
them.
You want to throw me the
Marcel and a banger. We don't flip
ships, but we definitely flip Marcel's.
You flip it to me and I'll flip it to
him. Uh, no.
Such a nice piece. Hey. Oh, gorgeous.
That's a solid piece of glass right
there. It's a nice tabletop piece. Look
at the ribbons of
Dro made the base. That's just insane.
Readies are off the wall.
So
wicked. And this air trapping is
to magnify all the ready. Yeah. And this
is part of the ridiculousness, of
course. Yeah, that slide is awesome.
It's pretty epic. It's huge.
Totally epic. It's like Rosame.
That was nice. The uh LHO dry sift combo
was maybe the strongest hit I've hit
since we here. I might have to uh do a
rosin LHO dry sift rip. I think that's a
good idea.
I think that's a really good
idea. Why not? I mean, this is a
session, right? Started out as a 420
session. Well, it is now potentially 7
puff hard Wednesday session. It is a
puff hard Wednesday session. I guess
that's the reality of it. People have
been asking for a puff Wednesday and in
reality this was a puff Wednesday. Puff
tough. Yep. Indeed. All right. And in
the torch, brother. Thank you,
sir. I like it.
So
sweet. He
says this
is the pick. One of Nate Dizzle's last
handspun
perks. Really? Yeah. He got a lathe
after Germany.
kind of ship change the game plan for.
Yeah. So, I guess these guys does do
Mothership also have some pretty
incredible high precision tools that are
kind of like that's what I've heard. A
few people have mentioned that they have
access to these really high precision
tools which right off the bat shows why
they would, you know, it's kind of why
ROR stood out back in the day just
because it was
100,000 100,000 euro lathe torch very
expensive lathe. There's almost like a a
level of precision that is not going to
be exhibited in most tubes that are
blown, but RER definitely is still
here. Yeah. Martin from RER will be
coming out here in the next few days.
We're looking forward to having a visit
with him. Been waiting to see him out
here for oh 15 plus years, maybe almost
20 years. been friends a long time.
Always had a relationship with Roar, of
course. It was one of my first I used to
hit their pieces a lot. I mean, I still
do have my Roar collection. I just uh I
used to hit them a lot before Glass
turned into what it turned into. And now
there's so many aspects of it I find
that it's uh it's hard to keep up. Thank
god I know a lot of
people. Wow.
That was a crazy figure. I punched to
the face. Right. Triple triple the
whammy. Right.
That's so sick with the banger on it.
I normally hit it with a bucket. This
This piece could could also hold the
double XXL banger. Well, I think very
well. It would look more appropriate.
Yeah, this one looks a little kind of
like shrunken head style. It looks a
little Oh, no. That's not even it.
That's awesome. You're like, "Hey." Oh,
I don't even have to try. That's like
way bigger.
That one's hot. Probably just torched it
up pretty good from all
angles and quartz
well, which does tend to hold that heat.
But yeah, that'll be
uh that's exactly how that's going to
look. It's a monster. It is. whole thumb
in there. Oh, yeah. And you can fit like
a big person can fit their whole thumb
in
here. It's pretty
sweet. Don't need that amount of uh
surface area. It kind of is nice. And
I'm sure that there could be some
There's still so many unknown factors
really. People know what they like and
they're convinced of what they like
through different discoveries of
temperature and low temp and higher temp
and this that and the other thing, but
they're all being experiencing them
through different variables. So it's at
this point it hasn't really been like in
my opinion properly documented. Not at
all. to the point where, you know,
wouldn't it be cool to just have a list
like, oh yeah, like for chords, these
are the temperatures and these are the,
you know, like a a proper explanation
like, well, I noticed the taste change
from candy to more of a spicy. That's
where the email comes in though, right?
Oh, absolutely. You can dial it down.
But also the names of the turppins and
knowing when those turppins, like which
ones are the most volatile, meaning
which ones do you taste first? I saw
someone put up a list on Instagram a
couple weeks ago and I had a list of the
turppines and their temperatures. It's
just like, hey, just so everyone can
understand. Yeah, there's good
information out there on that. You can
find it for sure. It just doesn't seem
to be available enough. I would sure
like to see it more. I would agree. Like
even right now, I'm sure people will go
and search for that picture that you saw
on Instagram and they'll be like the
toast sandwich. No, not the toast
sandwich.
Where is your ha?
Golden's all beared out.
Very good. What did I just hit last? I
hit the stack.
No. Did you hit the the troll jar? This
one? Yeah. Yeah, I did. I thought I hit
another one right after that though.
Stack one. Yeah, it was a stack. Stack
one. Yeah. No, I took the banger out of
the stack. That's right. Nice.
Yes. Put it in the Marcel. The last hit.
really was quite [ __ ] rocked after
that last hit. Wonderful. Yeah,
everyone should try a triple threat. Y
All right, triple threat number one.
This is your triple threat.
I don't want to put too much of this
stuff on there. You might want to. It's
definitely the one that uh Well, they
all the combination, the synergy of the
three. Like, it's so heavy. That's
serious uh canabonoid profile stacking
right
there. We don't flip ships, but we do
stack profiles.
It's the truth. How's that for a
t-shirt? Oh, it's delicious. Tastes
good.
Yep.
Damn. What did I do? Bring my water
outside? Yeah, I think when we were
eating. You want to fill up? Yeah, cuz
then I'm drinking the rest out of there.
Nothing like a nice glass of water while
puffing dabs. Sir, man, that first rosin
dab I did just grip me too hard.
That's awesome. This one takes a hold of
you, too. Trust me. All right. When am I
going to hit it? Oh, did you dip it in
dry sift? Yeah. Oh, yeah. He says,
"Yeah, absolutely." What are you going
to hit it out of? Well, I mean it's
Marcel sitting right here. Yeah, there
we go. Go very nicely.
I know cuz I'm hitting it as well. My
triple of that as well. So,
it's always nice to hit nice glass. It's
even nicer to hit a bunch of nice glass
in a row. Yeah. Go back to my one weekly
piece. So, you just visiting out here?
Yep. Nice. Yeah, I'm living in Colona.
Very nice.
That's how I came to know uh Aaron
Colbert. Oh, okay. Yeah. Living in
Colona. Just moved out here from
Ontario. He was one of the first dudes
that was uh super welcoming. Very cool.
Yeah. Very cool. Well, I'm in Colona
every once in a while. Hit you guys up.
Yeah. Let us know. Come to the studio.
Got my friend that owns a a winery just
in West Bank. Oh, cool. Yeah. Pretty
close to the bridge. Beautiful area.
Yeah. It's good. It's right behind the
gas station. Actually, on the way down
to the bridge, there's that little gas
station off to the right. It's just
right above there. Oh, cool. It's he
used to breed cannabis, so he's doing
playing around with grapes. Nice. Yeah,
it's pretty cool. For sure. K Town has
ever thought about coming back now just
becoming so much money. You know, he
just came back out on Instagram. You can
follow him at breeder
Steve. One word. Why does it sound
familiar?
Oh, he's well involved. tastes, you
know, grapefruit and sweet skunk.
Yeah. Like he's spice of life.
Ah, spice of life seeds.
Oh, where Yeah.
Yeah. Triple thread. Yeah. Yeah. Yep.
Yeah. And that LH.
Yeah. And that comes through. Kind of
ridiculous, isn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah. I was kind of spaced out for about
a minute or two after I took that dub.
All the viewers are going to be like,
"Wow, he's just spaced out." I I am
spaced out to a degree.
Yeah. That's
awesome. All
right. Dric sift.
We got the whole thing all lined
up, dabbed out. That is I don't know. I
love what I own, but like that's my
favorite piece maybe in the table. Huh?
I said I love what I
own. All
right. Yeah, it's hard not to love a
Marcel. I mean, come on.
He's really like not only like pioneered
a big chunk of the game into this new
millennia of glass blowers, but he's
also like stayed up.
Yeah, it's hard to
do it. That's what I mean, man. It's
incredible. Very much.
So, this is a mix hit. How long did you
wait? Uh, I waited about 354 seconds.
Well, that long, eh? Yeah. All right.
Cool. I felt that it retained good
amount of heat off this big shot blazer.
Perfect torch, especially for a banger.
All right, here we go. Finishing it off.
[Music]