[Music]
here we go
again I get to sit in the middle this
time these [ __ ] had me on the side
last
I was their side
[ __ ] all
right what we got we got that which is
good to have nearby we got uh this is
the D lemoning we can pull that out
later as a start
of there okay perfect this is Horatio
though correct I thought so just put it
on the
side and yeah hey guys welcome to Bubble
man's world it is uh lovely Sunday
afternoon we just filmed a almost 4H
hour hash church and we're here with the
uh the good guys over at Van City
extracts I just met Matthew uh not too
many days
ago a couple of weeks he was the
gentleman that came up to d420 K and I
and sort of blew us away with this
really beautiful Quality Dry sift and uh
today we've also met Ally who's doing
some of the dry sifting uh with Matt and
man hats off to both of you guys dude
cuz this is quality product you guys are
obviously taking care of growing proper
plants or accessing proper gear because
uh decontaminating is only one part and
I'm sure Ramone uh you can attest for
sure yeah cleaning is one part but you
don't always get that yeah you can clean
to 99 but you don't always get that full
milk so yeah exactly I mean the hardest
part really is whether you're going
through a grower yourself is really to
either find the person that knows the
plant that well or either know the plant
that well yourself and it's really hard
to do with different strains right so if
you can really find a strain that you're
able to train and work with and produce
those resonance heads you can keep doing
it over and over that is the key for
sure a lot of people haven't quite
figured that out that they need this the
super important factor is having a great
grower but also in choosing great
genetics and so all of these you should
walk us through a little bit of what you
got going on and feel free to hold it up
and show the camera whenever that's a
beautiful piece of right here we have
the flow flower
rosin yeah yeah and what strain is that
what strain was it again I believe it
was an Obi-Wan crossed with something
else ah yeah you guys showed me a BT of
that Skywalker I believe ob- one
Skywalker yeah that was really kushed
out and super nuggety and chunky chunk
then for the dry sip we have some
headband
cush dry siip that looks like flower
rosin Clarity counts yeah it does we
have some morte that won the first place
solvit list at g&amp; Great Northern
extraction cup yep beautiful and also my
favorite so far candy cush the one that
started this meeting up really it was uh
this was the the dry sift that Matt came
up to D and I at the cchq and offered
you know when he came up I swear it was
this reminiscent thing where I was like
oh my God this guy is for sure going to
give me an a an oil slab right now cuz
it happens to me a lot which is weird
cuz you people would know that I'm not
really like a big oil guy oh so but when
he came over and I was like oh my God
this guy's Mak give me oil he was like
he's like he's like I want you to have
this dry sift and I was like did he just
say dry sift you know like the smell and
the quality I was like all right sit
down let's try this out so we've
literally been setting this up for the
last half an hour we came in we haven't
had any Puffs since hash church and I
think it's time to hit some of these
flavors definely which one you guys want
to try I mean we're going to open it up
with the best the starter the the the
one that smells like a half pound of
wheat
on start C candy yeah you know I love I
love when I'm decontaminated to 99%
gland heads I love when the gland heads
have been grown to Perfection but then
at that point I love a strong turpine
profile and I find that this particular
candy cush dry sift has all three of
those things the one thing I've realized
with this candy cush dry sift is with
other strains when we were sifting it
throughout the whole process your your
nose kind of gets uh used to the smell
used to the Turing profile and I kind of
stopped smelling it after about a couple
hours in there right but with this candy
cush it didn't matter how long you were
in the room with it how close you were
to it you could smell it the exact same
the whole time just saturated just
saturated my nose saturated my taste
butts even every time I hit it it was
amazing well it's got great texture I
mean even the way it's picking up off
the parchment the way he's just cut the
dab it's just really really nice uh nice
and we're happy that what's the first
give it to Rick we're happy that van
City extracts is deciding that a quiver
beats uh you know a single you know one
trick pony oh yeah definitely it's all
about you got to expand your Horizon and
you know the whole the whole reason why
we're into cannabis in the first place
is because of its medical quality
exactly right and if you're really
passionate about it you'll take the time
to study it you'll take the time to
learn the plant how the plant can
benefit you and uh what it can do for
you how it can help your every single
day life mhm yep no totally 100% the
gear up for that hit a little hit
through the sick maybe you got that all
on yeah oh yeah 723 and 749 for those of
you wondering at what temperatures our d
nails are at um the sick is a unique
head uh on a nail in the sense that
serious you can turn this thing up to
800 and it's still going to hit more
like a low temp dab off of titanium and
quartz now silicon carbide is a a
highend and ceramic so it's it's just a
little bit different from
that let's see if we can't get this in
here nice big old silicon carbide rip
very nice top quality so happy to see
the youth picking up the torch thank
you we're happy to see the Pioneers
enjoy what we're making yeah definitely
it blows us away definitely if it wasn't
for you guys in the first place we
wouldn't even be able to get close to
where we are there's not that much
information out there readily available
to the public that you can know while
watching that it's 100% accurate true
right everything that you get on the
internet is pretty much just you know
half and half well it's like looking
looking for a needle in a hay stack
sometimes yep exactly there's good
information out there but it's uh it's
literally floating in a Cess poool of
disinformation of disinformation and
David Suzuki had a brilliant quote years
ago when he talked about his show the
nature of things it was a PBS uh show
really incredible nature show and he
really thought he was going to change
the world with this show and he he I
seen him speak one time and he said you
know it was I quickly realized when you
jump into a Cess pool that you take on
the appearance of everything in the cess
pool even if you are yourself a gem no
so the internet has a little bit of that
problem in the sense that there's a lot
of sess there's a lot of [ __ ] and a
lot of crap to sort of filter through
and a lot of people who maybe aren't as
passionate about this um particular
topic as ourselves they might have an
even harder
time you know distinguishing the real
from the false that's why uh we love
hash church and we we really respect the
people on there because we know
everyone's speaking out of the kindness
of their hearts to help better the
community to help better all the
processes we have going on yeah well I'm
glad to hear you say that Cu uh that's
really what hash church is all about
it's just about creating a dialogue uh
sharing uh information with people so
that just getting rid of this fear
scarcity that there's not enough for you
and there's not enough for me and sort
of putting more of a love and abundance
Vibe into the air where it's like hey
guess what like if there's not enough
pie on the table we can go bake another
pie exactly you know what I mean there's
we can make enough John made enough for
everyone Rastafarian friends say all the
time and I'm that resonates with me I do
believe that job made enough for
everyone I'm not necessarily a religious
person but I like the aspect the
spirituality aspect of cannabis and uh
the helping aspect I mean you know like
I said some of the stories in hash
church today were really powerful Colton
and his mother Wendy coming in and
sharing their story that's uh that's
real true value and I always bring that
value back to this because people like
to distinguish the two and they say well
okay yeah that's legitimate a child who
needs medicine but you guys are just a
bunch of Stoners sitting around smoking
hash how can you call okay well guess
what people like Colton learned about
this plant from People Like Us and how
we learned about this plant was not from
going to university courses or reading
about um different aspects of this in
textbooks but we learned about it from
from inhaling phyto canono from
consuming cannabis that's how we learned
about it that's how we better understand
and and learn about this plant by the
relationship that we have not only with
growing it and processing it but then
taking what we process putting it inside
our bodies people may look at us like a
bunch of Stoners but me personally kind
of just saved me I I had to take
multiple oxycottons every day because of
my herniated disc in my back after my
car accident brutal this guy right here
showed me the beauty of extracts he's
the reason I got off opiates that's a
big deal for sure and it is a very big
deal I was a zombie at that point and
it's they're doing this to the youth
these pharmaceutical companies are doing
this to young kids like getting them
hooked on to 19 years old at the time
Oxy Cotton are [ __ ] hardcore you know
what I'm talking about like what more of
a hardcore pill could he have said that
he was taking what 20-year-old man needs
to take 80 migam oxyc that's straight
hillbilly piece like heroin and to be
honest like in the world we live in like
with with the experiences you go through
and everything usually Somebody by the
time they're like even that age that
drug will do more than just relieve that
pain it will do some other thing in
their brain and relieve other pains that
they need to be the person they are and
it's just it's some weird [ __ ] those
those pharmaceutical pills man they
that's the thing you know those pills
kind of take you away from who you are
and make you a zombie and Bob Marley
even said you know when you smoke the
herb it reveals good to yourself it does
true you know it's the complete opposite
and that's why the pharmac super copia
doesn't want weed to be available
readily to the public the way I take it
to the next level and even say that it
not only reveals you to yourself but it
reveals it as well it really
unveils the the potential offerings that
can Canabis truly has not only from um
an industrial standpoint and the many
thousands of commercial products that
could be made from hemp uh from a health
standpoint of crushing the seed oil and
acquiring all 11 essential amino acids
that the body needs but can't produce
including the three that children need
so that's 11 nine for adults three more
for children and then it also produces
these phyto canabo that are like the
essential life fuel or Essence for every
cell in our body to communicate at
healthily back and forth to one another
in able to put our central nervous
system and our immune system into
homeostasis the endoc canabo system
requires canab and that right there is
an incredible quality I don't think it's
a coincidence that the level of the bar
that we set as connoisseurs as some as
people that love to inhale this plant
both recreationally and medically and
even Al be it um preventatively
that it somehow coincides with us having
the most valid information to help
people that need this plant for a uh for
medicinal purposes you know the
pharmaceutical companies they're like we
don't really know we'll test it in a lab
we're testing it on our on ourselves
through bio acid we are taking it and
it's so instantaneous you know it's hard
to deny someone with glaucoma with an
intense ocular pressure having a quick
puff out of a pipe or off of a spliff
and releasing that ocular pressure in an
instant it doesn't matter how much you
think you know or if you have a medical
degree you're going to have a hard time
convincing that person that what they're
doing isn't isn't good and isn't right
for for them so it's interesting
discussion you know it's uh it excites
me and uh so does puffing more of that
try telling Colton that's not good for
him I mean yeah I mean man crazy my 67y
old father man he gave him one dab of
dry sift he didn't take his pills for an
entire day yeah that's how it goes
that's over 20 pills he has to take a
day absolutely all 20 of those pills are
slowly trying to uh what they're doing
is a bad job of trying to do the job of
what canabo the natural um signalers are
canabo these are AR qu imitation
basically low quality imitation that
produces all sorts of adverse side
effects costs uh untold amounts of pain
and suffering and costs enormous amount
of money taxes people's paychecks well
it doesn't cost a lot of money that the
government and tical company but it cost
a lot of money to us that's right right
herb herb shouldn't really cost as much
as it is you know one thing that I
really was hoping when the dab era came
around was that the price of flowers
would go down a little bit and the price
of extracts wouldn't be priced as
outrageously as they are these days to
some people are charging 150 to 200
bucks a gram and they're preaching it
for like medical patients like I really
personally don't know many medical
patient I could afford that no it's
insane and it's unfortunate that the
prohibition dollar went from prohibition
went from well you could serve your life
in prison that was what the value was
put upon cannabis if you can go to jail
for a long time well then you can get a
lot of money for pounds in that
particular place MH and so that
prohibition dollar as it slowly turned
into the medical dollar it just never
changed it just didn't change and in
fact it did for a short period of time
what happened was herb dropped through
the floor both here in Canada
California the West Coast even in
Florida you were able to buy pounds for
thousands of dollars cheaper than ever
before because so many pounds were
starting to gather in California they
were able to send them all over the US
Surplus yes Surplus and Canada stopped
sending pounds down to the us cuz they
started growing so much and having such
a surplus it really changed everything
and it wasn't until people started how
people really accessed the prohibition
dollar that that was slowly getting lost
was through oil they were able to blast
pounds and get that dollar back and all
of a sudden it's like oh I'm getting
like this many thousands of dollars for
a pound well how I make
shatter 100 they were throwing it away
before so it's this whole new like it's
one of the things that I I I stayed away
from the oil scene I mean really patio
brought me back to even considering um
um an oil product and then so did rosin
you know this this is the rosin Headband
Kush Headband Kush so yeah right here in
front of me just coincidentally enough
is you know beautiful flower rosin that
is an oil as well as a deliming extract
from perao uh which is an oil as well
they don't scare me I I know that even
if a mistake was made there's not going
to be something left in here that can
cause me adverse you know there's no
footprint from an outside source of the
can particularly a chemical hydrocarbon
I'm just afraid of them I'm not to I'm
not to say that chemists couldn't learn
the process and do an exceptional job in
a laboratory with lab grade materials I
guarantee that can and should exist I
just say that um more people like your
guys' self should be focused on things
like this that are that give you a
greater room for mistake for error yeah
because hydrocarbon is a cruel [ __ ] for
it's a dangerous gas you know the way
the way that we really like to look at
the whole um um you know hydrocarbon
extract era if you will is there's a lot
of misinformation out there first of all
absolutely and second of all a lot of
patients are smoking garbage stuff
they're smoking poison 100% so we really
feel as because I mean a lot of people
obviously believe that their own extract
is I don't want to necessarily say the
best but the safest you know they're
like oh I know my stuff is safe I know
my stuff is good the way that we really
started our company we we made extracts
for ourselves we never really wanted to
go into this and go to dispensaries but
a lot of people around us were saying
we've never tried extract like this you
know it's actually different than the
stuff we tried it's like I've tried oil
for my first time brought it to Eden
medicinal society and they just they
went crazy they had never really seen
anything like it before really and so
like we almost I don't really want to
say we feel as if it's our duty to
supply the city with good medicine but I
just feel a little bit more oblig better
yeah obliged to do so right because I
see the garbage that's out there and
there's nothing I can really do except
for produce my own safe hydrocarbon
extract and let the patients be able to
get their hands on it for the best price
right I try running all sorts of
material so that anybody with any price
budget will be able to afford extract
not everybody wants to pay 80 90 100
bucks a g for Shatter or butter yeah
that's do not many patients can yeah if
you have a very debilitating physical
disability and you can't work 8 hours a
day you are really a physical like
you're a patient how are you going to
afford $200 a gram $200 a gr when your
disability check is $900 day and that's
you know not everyone is is um smoking
it some people really need to consume
this
orally you know totally and for those
people to consume something now
comparing it to pharmaceutical drugs
they're still more expensive there are
pills that cost $80 a pill there are
pills that cost $150 a pill and it's uh
just it's just not really doesn't seem
to be the Cannabis way I don't think
cannabis is just for millionaires that
can afford hundreds of dollars a gram I
think in India cannabis is known as the
poor man's drug and it's available to
everyone it doesn't matter who you are
what class you're from how high up you
are how low you are you should be able
to access cannabis because it grows in
the ditches it grows in the mountains
and it's available and it's like that's
always how I've seen cannabis and I
think that's why the agenda is so
threatened by it and why they're like no
nobody can have it because in reality
the this is what they don't want you
guys to know so pay attention
here H you can have it it's for everyone
and it's everywhere on all four corners
of the planet which is pretty incredible
it can't really be said for that's the
beauty of it for too many other uh
plants it grows everywhere so no matter
where you're watching from in all the
different 208 countries because that's
currently how many different people how
many different countries watch Bubble
man's world 208 countries so there's
people tuning in from all these
different countries and depending on
your laws you know I I don't urge you to
go out and get yourself arrested or in
trouble but I definitely urge you if
cannabis is not allowed where you live
and you want to be a part of and have
cannabis in your life then you either
need to a make things happen in the
safest most efficient way for you or you
need to move those are the two options
well that's the thing that always blows
me away is the fact that we're sitting
right here smoking comfortably in peace
M and there's people on this same Planet
somewhere getting beaten for smoking by
police they're getting thrown in jail
for smoking like it just really bothers
me that we're all living on the same
Planet yet everywhere has a different
you know I understand there's different
cultures there's different ways about
going for things but we're all like
we're human beings we got to be logical
about things it seems like there should
be almost the way physics has laws there
should be common sense laws that it's
like okay we respect your belief system
cuz one of the things I appreciated
about traveling in India is that India
respects all the belief system systems
like you can hang out with a shite and
you can hang out with a Krishna and you
can hang out there's so many different
belief systems in India they're all
tolerant one another well they all
believe deep down that no matter what
you believe it's what they believe it's
just through a different perspective so
you won't see it the same way but it's
just kind of a known thing that it's
like listen it's it is what it is it's
this energy we come from here we go to
there they all have these sort of
standards and there should be sort of
Common Sense standards like physic
physical laws that uh no matter what
your belief system or culture is you
shouldn't be allowed to execute people
for a plant you shouldn't be allowed to
put people in a cage for 30 years of
their life for a plant and uh you just
really shouldn't even I I can't even
believe that people are like it's a
ticketable it's a ticketable offense yay
it's like we fought for a ticket it's
like what we fought to get ticket a
ticket no how they
doing how was it working out like that
yeah that that's pretty much what the
point I was trying to bring up at cchq
is that you guys the pioneers made that
possible for us that's why we're sitting
here as a younger generation saying holy
crap we only getting a ticket for weed
while you guys are actually fought for
the whole thing that's not what you
wanted you wanted more than that but we
didn't really see the fight we were
growing up as you guys were fighting and
when that all came along and where we're
at now it's completely different than
what you guys wanted well but that's the
plan right you always want the youth to
not have to go through what you went
through uh particularly in this
particular
fight I mean I I just keep always going
back to Rick's dad like sitting in
prison for 27 years I just can't really
wrap my head around that dude like you
were my son's age when that [ __ ]
happened to you that's devastating that
is like criminal criminal that's
kidnapping and even worse than
kidnapping it's like it's like it's like
murder yeah it's insane a father away
from his child for a plant and his wife
and
his right now it is yeah it's 420 the
let's have a puff in honor of your
father let's do
that this is a good time to tell him bro
you haven't even been mention and [ __ ]
about about the you know let let them
know what they can do well what you can
do is go to frey.com and sign the
petition uh if you support just read the
site you'll see what happened um my
father's been locked up in prison since
1989 actually he's been in prison since
88 but was sentenced in '
89 um strictly a cannabis smuggling
charge which they then turn into a RICO
charge and turned into a 98-year
charge so he's been in ever since and um
yeah the only thing we can really do is
at this point right now is sign a
petition and raise raise awareness I do
have
some attorney things going on at the
moment so I'll let I'll let everybody
know more once that's solidified you
know but um I'll be going to see my Pops
in three
weeks and then I'll even know more so
it's just a trip you know I mean live in
this world where it's bugged out just to
to be cuz I just went from
Frisco and there it's kind of it is
pretty much tolerated and legal to some
perspective medically and then go to
Colorado where there's where
there's and then in Seattle and then
here you know so you see all these
different that it's actually possible
and then think like yeah Poss and I live
in Amsterdam where it's like you can go
downstairs and buy a [ __ ] you know what
I'm saying that's the thing the
government they like to make an example
out of people that's the problem you
know like they they go out of their way
to do so and they even break the law to
do so now it's beyond an example cuz I
mean
now it's like [ __ ] now it's [ __ ]
like my dad doesn't need to die in
PR Out The Window Man Common Sense isn't
so common anymore anyways well that's
what you guys can do now you know you
can do keep you updated and spread the
word go Instagram follow
Frey and go frey.com excuse
me I was just trying to mute my mic
while I was coughing there in my head
I'm still stuck in Ash we filmed hash
church just a few hours ago before that
probably 7 hours before hash church we
filmed a two hour and a half uh little
video with Horatio with all the tpine
modulations and the pure
thca and the the D lemoning and the D
lemoning distill it and wow it's just
been a great kind of last 20 or so hours
it has been good what a time to be alive
indeed and with you guys like quality
guys inviting us over to like lay out
superb dry sift and ra and with the
motherships andw thank you thank you
guys for coming absolutely definitely
thanks for having us it's nice to be in
this neighborhood I don't come to the
this side too often but uh it's nice in
here I like the trees and it's just a
real nice kind of quiet raise your
family kind of neighborhood yeah
definitely definitely real nice
indeed wow
very what's that it's a very mellow
area and so is is this some of the
nicest DPS you guys have seen since
you've been in Canada or what um
honestly can oh yeah yeah really
represent see you saving the day here
guys we haven't had the best dcep to
show these guys well honestly since
smoked mine like a fiend since we really
started making dry sip we've never
really smoked anyone else's but our own
right so I always thought it melts it's
good it SMS it's good right but when I
saw bubble man's reaction and Darren's
reaction I was like shocked and then you
know a couple days later on high sech
the way that you guys just you know
reacted to it I would really blown away
well the way it is is it's it's like
this and and remone was in the same boat
and there's like more and more people
stepping up to this plate and I think
they think that it's like it should it's
like a rare position but really it's not
you guys are just the first ones out of
many to come to realize they're simple
techniques if you pay attention to the
resin somehow it just ends up being
better than if you don't pay attention
to the resin if you growing for
vegetative yields and flowering periods
and how much can I get and how fast can
I get it it just is never going to turn
out for the same is like no man like
we're going to dry sift all this [ __ ]
and like when we do that like it has to
be grown this particular way we've
learned from mistakes and it's just a
different focus when you have that Focus
you end up with this it's that simple
and there's more and more people every
year since we started Legends more and
more people come to the plate and when
you make the best it's all the best is
the best yeah you just have to take the
proper steps and it's that's it and the
proper steps start with growing yeah
exactly you know what I mean the people
who can control their resin are the
people who can grow their resin and
that's what I've noticed in this
industry in this community the people
who seemingly have the best sort of
quality resins are people who have a say
in how that you know what's required in
order to do your job so that's the thing
though what it it's almost as like a
spiritual journey in itself you know
understanding the it's not like you can
just go to school read books and find
out about it you'll know the basics of
it but until you really put your heart
and soul into it interact it won't speak
back to you exactly there's a lot of
interaction going on in it so it's
exciting we geek out on this [ __ ] as you
can see
here when when he came home that day
after he saw you at cchq and he said you
looked at the dryp the way you did yeah
I I almost fell out of my chair cuz I
was like I couldn't believe that
something we produced yeah man just us
two look at how nice it is would make
you that impressed yeah I know we we had
never even thought because the best is
the best no matter where you are or who
made it it's like ego aside it's like no
that's the best like and oh you have the
best too that's amazing oh look he's got
some too I won't be happy until everyone
has it all different flavors these are
what he says to me every day he says
everybody deserves to have that's why I
I'm more more than a hash maker I I am
now cultivating
hash you becoming a philanthropist for
the Cannabis Community cultivating hash
makers yeah well whatever it takes man I
I love the industry
so it's good to see the industry showing
support back right I mean like when I
talked to a lot of older people like
just last month I had a meeting with
some guy he's like in his 40s 50s and he
was telling me he's like you know just a
couple weeks ago I threw away my second
phone like what do you mean he's like I
used to have a business phone and a
personal phone my entire life he's like
we used to have to worry all the time
check over our shoulder but he's like
now the industry has been so supportive
that it's taking heat off of a lot of
people cuz they're watching Everybody
not just certain people absolutely right
and when we stand together they really
can't take us down well and when you
realize that most people in the Cannabis
industry aren't actual criminals yeah
they've just been criminalized sure
there's some interaction with when you
make something completely illicit
there's going to be an interaction with
the non and the actual like elements of
of crime that's what they do for a
living you know what I mean you make you
you give them you fund them by
prohibiting certain drugs when you make
certain things illegal that funds
organized crime they would have a lot
less money if those drugs that they were
but then again you know maybe they're
just business man that were like oh well
if the drugs were legal we would be able
to just do a sort of business model with
that like I I'm not one to pretend to
know uh that aspect but uh it it's
interesting to see how far we've come
compared to the heat that once was yeah
it's nice to hear that buddy got to
throw a second phone yeah exactly he was
he was Prett about extra Pocket spish
yeah that's just too much especially now
that everybody's you know a little too
anal about radiation and everything
comes off your phone and your laptop you
know you don't need to be carrying 10 of
them in your bag exactly one of my
phones is
ringing ah the good old
days just a bag of phones I had a design
that it was going to be a briefcase in
the back you you'd crack it open and it
could be like five phones on this side
and five phones on this side and then
when you close it there would be like a
plug for you to put your headphone
mouthpiece into and then a a little
light to let you know which one was
ringing
that's pretty smart yeah you back in the
days back in the day that's proprietary
information that was some 96 [ __ ] right
there and do you have the whole belt
full of beepers you uh I didn't wear
them on a belt but I definitely had a
little bag of some in
it yeah we've come a long way but
there's still a long way to go so that's
definitely why we continue on this
mission of creating these dialogues and
sharing information with people and
letting people know where they can find
Van City extracts for people that want
to like follow you on Facebook or uh
Instagram yeah we have we don't have our
Facebook set up yet but we have
Instagram you can follow us at Van City
extract on Instagram and the only
dispensary that we're currently at right
now is eating medicinal Society every
now and then we might have a drop of
like a special flavor or a variety at
different dispensaries but for the most
part we're just eating exclusive nice
and I guess the dry sift isn't leaving
the head stash eh yeah well I mean I'm
trying to get enough I'm talking to the
grower he wasn't really into dry SI till
I showed it to him I shouldn't have
really showed it to him but uh he didn't
really know his flowers were actually
producing those resins that were really
good so when I came back to him he
actually wanted some himself yeah of
course but I'm trying to you know get
him on the same level as I am with the
whole patient lead this medicine take it
off the top before you do anything else
exactly exactly so what we would love to
do is to be able to give patients access
to dry sift at an affordable cost would
at the Quality that you would like where
can I say like that's what we're trying
to get going yeah I for the longest time
have just been trying to grow enough
resin for myself to have a gram of it a
day so I can consume half of it orally
and half of it through uh you know
inhalation and it's hard even just to
grow that small amount of while you're
running a business and being a father
and doing all the other things in life
it's not that easy to just grow
365 G of resin but it would be a lot
harder without the sift right it sure
would be for sure I'll tell you
definitely glad to have my screens yeah
which I never ever promote my own [ __ ]
but you can check these screens out that
we're all talking about at uh fresh.com
it's uh get your B bag all that sort of
resin extraction tools we definitely
have you covered and uh what I like to
think of is pretty good support in the
sense that even people for years have
been asking me how to do stuff with
other people's products and I've been
answering them and basically doing
customer service for like every other
Bag company and most people who sell
like a dry sip box or any of those
people call me they're like how do I
what do I I'm like okay well you need
more than one scream like at CH asking
me if I on hash church if I only had one
screen damn did you see the mean that
got created it's like me smelling a bud
in Jamaica a sativa plant and it says
one screen eh do you have any panty
hoes cuz panty H could be used as a
screen y yeah right a single farmer grid
screen so if you only were able to have
one screen I think i' grab the 70 and
then just some panty hose defit so etm
was
like yeah I definitely use the screens
myself I mean it's all I've ever used
and I don't think I'm going to switch to
anything else because the results have
just been spectacular yeah well that's
the that's the hard part right now
there's a few other people asking me to
promote their dry sift methods and I'm
having a hard time doing it because a I
haven't been able to be find it
efficient uh or really even work in the
same way at all like especially for the
decontamination no one's coming out with
a better
decontamination um method anytime soon
that is like a a game Cher being able to
do that and even carding was a game
changer for the patient no the patient
person who was patient enough to push
all the contaminant through the card you
could get it you could get 99% heads and
then with you know M uh online on
YouTube he wrapped parchment around the
card and he found when he was doing it
that it was sticking to the parchment
well then d420 K wrapped it around a
thicker thing a DVD case and that was
really the game changer right there so
everyone had their place in that and
those uh guys should deserve their shout
out for helping everyone along the way
you know get to what I like to call the
unadulterated canabo profile yeah and
that's what uh that's what dry sift is
it's it's the purest of the pure it's
the Holy Grail it's like if you can
master that one that's a a good Arrow to
have in the quiver and all the other
arrows in my opinion line up definitely
I mean personally I couldn't really see
any other way to be able to get those
glandular heads without using any
solvent you know purely unadulterated
like intact yeah completely intact with
no water solubles taken like water hash
like literally
really profile that's so I think on that
note we should um thank these guys from
Van City extracts for having us come by
and showing us such good Hospitality
thanks guys showing us the superb sift
and rosin and uh yeah it won't be the
last time you guys see these guys and
uh thanks for watching Bubble man's
world see you
soon
peace awesome that good yeah we can just
push that button on the back of that
camera
forgot and invite our friends into the
some flower
[Music]
rosin everybody knows you never go full
human yeah over the Canadian
[Music]