[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world I
have been a little m.i.a since the my
Orca filming I have to admit I've been a
little bit nerve-racked about some of
the well-established cannabis-based
channels that have been deleted recently
off of YouTube making me very nervous
terrible news about Raynald the urban
grower the pot TV lost theirs and some
others so I've just been really kind of
holding back but today I figured we
would do a little unboxing I've got a
little treat in the mail here and I
thought this would be a good video to
get up on the channel and let everyone
know what's going on so I have got this
from putco puffs Co sent me a little
something-something so I figured we will
use the happy daddy dabber here to get
into the box
and we'll see what's going on in here
we'll see what's going on what
wonderfulness they sent me today I think
I know I think at this point you guys
even probably know but you never know
nothing better than just opening the box
to actually find out let's see what we
got off to say this about these guys
this came in like three days from the
time it was ordered to the time it was
sent to the time it arrived was three
days literally ordered on this day sent
on this day received on this day so very
cool and we're I'm in Canada and this
came from Valencia California so that
was pretty cool to be able to get it
that quickly real quick and easy
shipping a box within a box a little bit
of bubble wrap my receipt here on the
price of the unit he's go for 399 us and
indeed it is the PUF Co Peak
so I've been quite excited about
grabbing one of these I'm not gonna lie
I had tried just a couple of times I got
to try the unit and I was quite
impressed with it but I've mentioned it
before you know today is really just
gonna be the unboxing video obviously I
can take a DAB from it but for me to
really try a unit I need to be able to
take it around this is a very portable
unit I'm often carrying you know my mini
the carb cap the container the dabber
the terpenes the hash you know all of
these different things the q-tips and so
I like the compact thickness of this
obviously it's still going to be a pipe
it's still going to be a dabbler that
needs to fill and I'm still going to
need q-tips and I'm still gonna need the
carb cap but I really like the
portability of it I really like the
cleanliness the lines I think it's very
much like receiving an Apple product
almost so far so you get out what you
put in I like that as well so let's see
what we've got here nice very very nice
easy intuitive opening box there and
what does it say here it says intuitive
very interesting the first word that I
read on the inside of the lid at the top
there intuitive so we've got intuitive
powerful precise portable welcome to the
Pete share the view take a video of
yourself using the product with puffs go
peek and we'll share it with our global
audience all right well I'm gonna do one
better than that I'm actually gonna take
this bad boy to 420 another beautiful
just full box that comes right out it's
got a couple of things in here what do
we got here we've got the most awarded
vaporizer ever so that's their little
puff Co pen unit that they've got their
peak technology and a discreet size I've
used one of the puff Co pens and I have
to admit I really liked it my friend
Alex gave it to me years ago in Jamaica
probably one of their first units but I
still have that one alright so let's see
what we got here it says nice little
booklet that comes
it always nice to get a little booklet
with an explanation of what's going on
so we go you're almost to the top we
know it's a drag please read through all
the directions this device is the first
of its kind and we'd like you to learn
the easy way by reading this booklet
you'll learn some secret tips and tricks
as well so it's got what's inside page
three it's got a QuickStart page four to
eight temperature settings on page nine
battery on page nine cleaning your
device on page ten advanced features on
page eleven a warning on page eleven and
finally peak protection on page twelve
so why don't we go through the entire
little booklet here so there we go there
we go breaking it down and showing each
unit so we've got the loading tool the
cotton swabs the USB cable the AC
adapter the glass attachment the carb
cap each glass pieces hand-blown and
Mary may vary slightly in size good to
know
the atomizer cover the ceramic bowl the
atomizer and the base and that's
basically what you see on this page
right here all of those little units are
right there QuickStart so step one fully
charge device before first use so we're
going to do that right away we're gonna
fully charge this device before first
use oh it's very clean very very clean
look at this little unit isn't that a
nice little unit right there gotta say
if they've had a real hype with this
unit and I can kind of see why so
there's your base right there got our
atomizer in there we've got our nice
little glass top
oh yeah they've got they've got a little
uh a little cover on this a little
plastic cover I guess that's unique
holes Zorro there's the hole right there
on the back so there's a nice little
hole right on the back of the glass and
then it also explains if I can get that
to you how to line up the holes to fit
this base this is a very nice little
base feels like it's well made it feels
thick if you want to
there we go it feels very thick and it
feels just well made it does not feel
cheap whatsoever so does this this feels
heavy heavy heavy very nice I like that
I'm gonna read it before I start trying
to play around with it empty water
before storing glass that makes sense
just fits in so tightly as well I'm
really a fan of things that fit into
their cases well there's the little
dabber that it comes with they've got
their own unique dabber that comes with
the unit nice little scoop there and
we've also got our carb cap very very
tiny little carb cap it's definitely not
a big carb cap which is great probably
just fits the unit to perfection and
I'll show all that here in a little bit
let's just read the booklet shall we so
we're gonna fully charge the device
before first use device pulses white
while charging and turns off
automatically when complete so we're
going to do that
I guess the yep look at that right here
so I'll make sure that I've got all
these components back in here properly
so I can turn it sideways again so this
is the base this is the glass this is
the carb cap this is the dabber and then
right in here you've got your cables so
we're gonna pull those cables out
nice little charger okay take that
plastic off right away nice and clean
seems like a nice quality charger there
feels good in the hand and what else we
haven't got a couple of cotton swabs
that they've given us just a small
amount there four of them and then we've
got also a ceramic dish I guess if you
use probably an extra one I'm guessing
as
yuuna did have one inside of it I'll
just check that out again
yeah it's got one inside of it there
guess that just unscrews although I'm
not going to attempt to do anything
without reading it first you know it's
such a natural thing to start playing
with things and moving them and pulling
them and twisting them but you know what
this is a unit that I've never seen
before I've never seen anything like it
it's very unique so why not just follow
the instructions to the tee nice short
little cable you know another thing that
people tend to do is you know they'll
see this universal plug and although you
might have many plugs like this what I
suggest and I do this based on my own
pan is use the one that you got with the
unit you know my pen for instance if you
use a super fast charging from Samsung
which is the same plug it actually will
blow out the battery it's not going to
blow it up but it'll burn out the
battery it just won't work properly and
so I'm always letting people know that
chargers right on the front the chart
tools right on the front of the unit
there and as you can see so I'm gonna
charge this little bad boy I think I'll
just plug it in right here into the wall
I've got a nice little charger and lip
open the box is upside down make a
perfect table for the charger alright so
and it is indeed flashing light it's
going real slow pulsating white and then
off white and then off so let's read the
rest of the book step 2 after fully
charging is fill glass with water just
above the air holes do not fill glass
while attached to the base do not allow
water in lower sections so this is a
pretty important factor here here's the
unit right here I guess I can pull off
the plastic that says align air hole
with atomizer
so that comes off real nice and like I
said I'll show you that again
there's your hole right there and so
we're gonna line that up properly when
we when we put this in and obviously we
don't want to get water inside this
lower chamber because it could come
right out this whole drip into your
atomizer or drip into your battery base
and probably cause some problems so
we'll follow those instructions really
well you can see how we're supposed to
fill it up with water right there all
right there we go
hope I'm not going too fast for anyone
all right carefully push glass into the
base align inlet holes on the front of
the glass with atomizer step four to
lock and unlock the device hold down the
button for three seconds all right so
that's cool once you click this glass
piece into the base I guess you can push
the button and it'll push a little piece
out that keeps it locked in step five
single click to toggle here I'll show
you the pictures of those as well there
we are putting it into the base here we
are holding the button down to get it to
lock into place then we're going to
single click to toggle through the heat
settings so blue is a small load it's
about 450 degrees Fahrenheit the green
light is a medium load it's gonna be
about five hundred degrees the red is a
large load and that's 550 degrees that's
actually what I hit my hotbox d-mail
davon ater at and then white XL load is
a 600 degree and so you can see those
right here these are the settings right
here for the puff co peak and then six
step six use loading tool to place
contents on the bottom surface of the
bowl well that's pretty self-explanatory
take your dab and drop it into your
little atomizer base there and then we
go step seven this is where it kind of
is unique in the sense place the carb
cap on top of the atomizer often people
will put their
they'll start hitting it while they're
putting the dab in and then they'll put
the carb cap on this is load it put the
carb cap on and then start hitting it
but not right away because we're gonna
get the heat to initialize and that's
step eight and so what we do is we
double click to initiate the heat up
that's about a 20-second average heat up
time press and hold the button every any
time to exit pulsing light indicates
heat up mode is active so depending on
the color that you chose in step five
which are the single click to toggle
through heat settings one is blue two is
green three is red four is white then
you go back and then you engage it once
you've loaded your hit so when we choose
our heat settings it's not actually
engaging the heat we don't engage the
heat until we put the hit in so this is
very different from dabbing where we
heat the quartz up and then we drop it
in and I've heard some people complain
about oh well I don't want my my rip
heating up in the bowl while it's you
know like while I don't want it in there
while it's heating up well trust me I've
hit this thing before it's not gonna
make a difference especially with turf
dipping especially with high grade
materials plus you've got your carb cap
on top and it's not gonna be releasing
anything so anything that may have
apparate into the air and start
vaporizing is still trapped in that bowl
you're still gonna get that flavor in
that taste so don't worry about that
step 9
device will vibrate and lights will
flash when ready inhale repeatedly until
devices finished producing vapor see see
page 11 for sesh mode sesh mode
obviously is a mode where you're not
gonna have to heat it up every time I
believe we're gonna get there soon we're
already on page 8 page number 10 once
you you're done use a cotton swab to
clean the chamber after use so that's
all pretty self-explanatory I think you
guys all know how to clean a unit this
is gonna be different because your units
not going to vibrate and flash lights
when it's ready so that's pretty cool
here's a nice little page on your
temperature settings as well as your
battery cycling through the four
temperature setting
click the button once lo is a small load
450 twenty-second heat up medium is a
medium load 500 degrees 20-second heat
up high is a large load 550 degrees
that's a 25 second heat up in the peak
the excel load the one that a lot of
people are probably going to be using is
a 600 degree and that's 25 seconds to
heat up as well and you can see that up
in the top corner there and then you've
got your battery percentages there from
a hundred to sixty percent from 60 to 30
and from 15 to zero so click the button
three times to check battery life color
will indicate remaining battery life so
you click it three times if it's green
you've got between sixty and a hundred
percent if it's yellow you've got
between thirty and sixty percent and if
it's red obviously that's time to get a
charge in and yeah cleaning it's
breaking it down right here on how
simple the unit from the carb cap to the
cover to the little ceramic dish to the
atomizer all unscrewed from the unit as
well as the glass being removed
preparation remove glass before
unscrewing and reinserting atomizer
don't over tighten the atomizer clean
your carpet glass and atomizer by smoke
stow soaking in isopropanol alcohol I'm
guessing I could also probably use my DC
glass cleaner I'm gonna check with them
I know I can for the carb cap and the
glass but we'll find out about the
atomizer it says it can be cleaned fully
assembled or disassembled number two be
sure to clean gold connector on base and
bottom of atomizer with an alcohol
soaked cotton swab I'm gonna find out as
well a fake if I can use the DC glass
cleaner for that number three is a
warning after cleaning rinse and allow
all parts to dry before use this is
going to be pretty important obviously
different liquids are not safe to use
when electrical currents are flowing
through when batteries are being used so
you want to make sure things are really
dry once you start getting going again
and yeah before removing the atomizer
make sure bowl has cooled do not get the
base wet it's electric it will break
third
clean device after every 20 uses and
then we've got advanced features I want
to cover the advanced features really
quickly sesh mode this is something that
I think we're gonna be using here at
Bubble man's world sesh mode haven't
reached your peak we got you covered
we created a sessom Oh a session mode
that increases heat and extends your
session by 15 seconds use it to boost
heat or to share with your friends if
vapor production is low double-click to
initiate sesh mode still not hot not
enough damn your hardcore sesh again you
can double click as many times as you
want to keep the session going and then
it's got a whole variety of warnings
might as well go through them multi
click colored light flash when there is
poor or no connection between the base
and the atomizer you'll see a rainbow
lights 5 red light flashes indicates a
short-circuit red light holds means the
device has overheated I think we're
probably going to end up seeing that at
one point in time here and then basic
things do not allow water in the bottom
chamber of glass do not let water seep
into the atomizer do not overfill glass
do not store device with water in the
glass remove glass before unscrewing and
inserting atomizer attached detached
glass carefully do not force wait one
minute between uses do not fire atomizer
four times consecutively several short
inhales produce more vapor do not place
contents on the sidewalls of the bowl
do not overfill chamber if you
experience a bug
turn the device on and off should the
issue persist contact support keep away
from extreme hot and cold temperatures
and keep away from moisture and high
humidity now you know if more people
read those simple warnings so simple
that simple list I bet you nine out of
ten times this unit [ __ ] up pardon my
french
people have not listened to these simple
very very simple rules and they'll be
like well I didn't know I shouldn't fire
the atomizer four times consecutively
well if you read the instruction booklet
it would actually tell you that that's
what you're not supposed to do so it's
yeah they want to make sure we have a
consistently perfect experience should
something go wrong visit puff cocom to
view the fa Q's your questions might be
covered
if not you can live chat with a
specialist on our site or contact
customer care at support at puffs code
comm pretty sweet little unit I'm gonna
let it heat up
sorry not heat up but charge up and once
it's fully charged we're gonna come back
and we're gonna do a little session and
we're gonna see how how well this thing
back here guys you'll probably notice
that my head and shoulders are missing
but I kind of took a little page out of
sneaky pete vaporizer reviews i really
liked the way his was tied up and closed
and that's how we're gonna do it so I've
got my little unit all charged up here
and I guess we'll just follow the
booklet real quick we've got it on I'm
gonna hold the button to lock alright I
held that down for three seconds it did
a little vibration so I'm guessing it's
locked down now single clicks to toggle
through the settings so one that's green
- we're on red already let's go for
large we'll set it at large so it's got
a red light that goes all the way across
the sides here you'll see it very very
sweet it just turned off actually but
the way the light lit up was very nice
well load the surface to place the tool
so we're gonna grab our tool I'm gonna
do a little turf dip I believe got some
nice material here that we're gonna load
up not too too much but at least a
decent amount all right so let's get
that in there boom well I get my second
tool here so I can get it off nice and
clean cuz it said not to just leave it
on the sides boom fell in perfect
alright so place the carve cap on top
steps lose using loading tool to place
contents on the bottom surface of the
bowl not the side
we will place our carb cap on the top
there and then double-click to initiate
heat up so we'll go one two alright so
that's going to initiate on our heat up
wait about 20 seconds pulsating light
indicates heat up mode is active alright
pretty excited about this little guy
all right let's give it a shot
I have not turned it on yet so let's try
that again
please carp get double click to initiate
heat so we'll go one two all right let's
give that another shot it's starting to
pulsate now the light has turned on this
time my bad
alright let's see what we got here it's
very different way of dabbing
yes I'll probably get quite used to it
once I've got the time line down and
understand how the unit heats up looking
for that pulsating light to let me know
it's good it's definitely not heating up
so I'm gonna try and figure this out
all right so that was a little bit
different it's always about the learning
curve on these units I was pushing it
and then pushing it and this time I went
click click so a little bit different
and pulsating so here we go
[Music]
Wow
third time's the charm on that I'll tell
you
really really nice flavor on that
obviously I Terp dipped it but that was
tasty
three good-sized rips so far from
something that would normally just give
me a single dab off my nail give you a
little see inside the unit there so that
was a little bit at first difficult they
like to be honest though I'm not gonna
do one I'm not going to edit that out it
was hey it took me a couple of times to
get it right and it was the simpleness
I'm gonna just give them out a nice
little clean it's got the straight the
the pointy ones as well which is great
to get into those corners and she is as
clean as a whistle
great little unit right there HuffPo
peak medicated I'm gonna take one more
dab this time with the camera a little
further back so you guys can see and how
that was really really nice
all right we're going to give one more
shot here grab another little dab this
time I'm going to dip that time I dipped
it into the ACDC and this time I'm going
to dip it into the gills lemons so let's
see if we can't get that happen and real
nice and fast a little bit of Gil's
lemons in there a quick little drop into
the chamber definitely having two divers
I think is helpful getting it in a
proper all right so we'll hit that in
there much quicker on the double and I
can see the light on the back I can see
it all the way around and I guess what
happens is once it reaches temperature
it's going to the lights going to
pulsate a little bit it only takes about
20 seconds and you're ready to go
looking forward to hitting the gills
lemons and the CBD isolate on this one
here we go
sounds like my dog wants a little rip
right now so anyway that was great
little review of the puff coke peak
really wonderful little unit I'm gonna
take it to 420 in a couple of days I'm
gonna hit it with a bunch of my friends
and we'll see how it goes so far with
the first few rips I have to say I'm
very impressed with this little unit
fits right in the palm of your hand
easy to clean fairly easy to use you saw
there was a little bit of a learning
curve there as I tapped it slow the
first few times but definitely impressed
with that unit so thanks a lot
puff Co we'll see you next time on
bubble man's world
[Music]
you