[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world and welcome to Puff Wednesday a
special Johnny B Edition a Johnny B
Edition a special Johnny B Edition you
know what this it's it's
it's we got to Puff first we got to Puff
first got puff first then we got to talk
about you know the what we're talking
about well what led us to talk about
what we're talking about um I think it
came down to um weren't you looking for
your license I thought it was more along
the lines of you getting harassed both
at a a traffic stop and then a couple of
weeks later at the Edmonton airport
where they detained you took your
cannabis charged you with cannabis this
and so to me that's really what all of
this led to from you know okay I'm just
kidding yeah no this led from this and
this is uh so Johnny's done his research
he's figured out exactly what everyone
wants to know all of us that are sitting
what is it the Allard trial that the all
trial is the injunction for us so I have
my license over on my wall there and if
it says expired March 31st which does
happen to be my birthday I know it's a
great day 2014 yeah the the expiration
date of the but then the creation of the
injunction and our license has been
valid since however if you don't have
your license at a traffic stop there's
some information they need to know so
let me get Johnny B there's some
information know but and this is this is
really it's injunction related to the
medical marijuana access regulations mm
and I got this little letter from Health
can I going to tell you how you can get
this little information here and for Law
enforcements and for municipalities
after note after a derp I got to do it
people be like why did you cut Johnny
off I'm like I cut him off to give him a
DB I'm allowed to do that
medication I mean come on it's legit
right there got a little bit of Darkness
on
the there you go Johnny there you
go so yeah very good information today
we're going to be sharing in regards to
Canadian citizens who want to learn how
to to uh further protect themselves if
they are protected by the Allard
injunction uh if they're not yet a part
of the acmpr and if you have no idea
what you're supposed to be doing in
regards to either of them if you are
already attached to
those so like Mark said would have come
down to was me being pulled over first
on February 26th um last month and uh I
was asked if
uh basically my car smelled like
marijuana that's what he said it's a
brown new impressor so it didn't I got
pulled over because in my opinion the
round plate number but we won't get into
those things um so right away the
officer asked me do I have my paperwork
and at that point I had nothing on me I
was in my car so he asked me if I had
any marijuana on me and I hand them a
container like I always do of course I
do you know that's my medicine we should
explain to them too how difficult it is
to carry it's not a card in Canada show
them the
paper okay it's not a card in Canada
here here's the piece of paper and the
piece of paper in question and what
we're looking at has to have this expiry
but unfold it you don't have to show
them dates show them the back of it show
them the length of this piece of paper
this document supposed to car this
letterhead piece of paper it's
ridiculous in something the size of a
wallet and you're not supposed to lose
it and if you fold it up too much and it
becomes destroyed and you can't read
part particular addresses mean this fold
across well that's what I'm saying now
imagine you folded that to fit it in a
wallet and it's how many years old now
three four um this is four years old cuz
I got in 2013 14 15 16 4 years old so
this this was a photoc copy of the
original copy that I actually have so I
did photocopy that so so you you have to
as an mm patient in Canada medical
marijana access regulations and you had
a license before March 31st of
2014 you have to carry around a piece of
paper not a card they make it as
difficult as possible and I'm sure
someone at one point said let's let's
make it so they have to carry the whole
document not just an easy card that fits
in your wallet so this is part of the
problem with many people the m and the
acmpr and the
mmpr they don't have the ability to
carry around this large document it
becomes unrealistic and I'm telling you
to try and keep the one on my wall as in
good condition as this is what I handed
the officers I handed them my card cuz I
still do have a card but it did expire
that's be 10 years old or something oh
this is seven years old so this is the
cards he used to be able to get from
from Health Canada he had a card on had
a beautiful little picture on there for
it so I'm covering up my address and
then they made it more difficult so I
actually had about half a dozen of these
particular cards and I still carry it on
me and when I get questioned like the
officer that pulled me over an a I
handed him my card and I instructed him
to call Health Canada 24-hour hline to
find out more information in regards to
my license and did he do that um the
officer in aiser did yes he did
wonderful so is this something
you know walk us through not only what
happened to you but walk us through what
these people need to know and do for
future references before they get pulled
over so here's my notes calling from
Health Canada so I'm really I put them
down on some other paper here so we can
actually go through it what proper links
we have to go through and stuff like
that thank you my friends you're welcome
I like that stuff you just put a little
thing there I can sit back so the the
first thing is is is really in reality
when I got arrested and charged in
Edmonton at the Edmonton airport
we both failed to do two things a for
one I failed to present an expired copy
of my license that is of course we saw
how long it
was and then they failed to do the one
thing that I told them to do right away
and it says in here IND different
additional information for Law
enforcements and I love this health
candle provides a
24-hour 7day a week service line for law
enforcement agents to answer any
questions providing through the MMA
amcpr and what's that number um right
here I I have it actually written down
here so I'll give you all those numbers
interesting that it's not written on the
document that they tell that they print
off yeah yeah so is that the one this is
the this is the document that you have
to get to I'm going to go through the
steps that you had to do to get to this
particular little piece of Buri document
this is an important document that you
need to actually to refer to because it
talks about the regulations it talks
about the laws in Canada and drugs and
Health Products that under the amcp and
under the mm and we're going to put link
up for you guys John going to tell the
story on how much research he had to do
to actually dig it up okay so so this
was this is something that I told the
officer to do in Edmonton so you call
Health Canada mhm well that 24-hour
hotline is like when I called Health
Canada I was on hold for 2 hours and 41
minutes then they hung up because it was
the end of the day oh then the next day
I was on hold for 2 hours and 8 minutes
and I finally got
through that's where these notes come
from I talked to a really nice lady sh
CH I talked to her back in 2007 and 2008
when I first got my license so each
province had an individual person
dealing in representation of that
Province so it's kind of interesting so
when I talked to her she said first
thing she said to me I said in regards M
mm they said they have no grounds to
talk about it the first thing she said
we have no grounds to talk about it John
like who has no grounds Health Canada
because the program to them is done okay
right they have no GRS they're not
sharing or providing any information at
all on the mm you can see I've written
this down exclamation mark like they've
actually said this but because I had
such a good relationship with Cheryl she
told me some steps that I can tell you
because I she I told her what happened
she goes yeah I said I need to educate
people she goes yeah we know all right
like so you know she kind of went into
some detail so here's the first thing
you've now I I kind of wrote theis here
already this is I've having fun
information you should know about your
mm license and in regards to maybe being
arrested so you need to hold a copy of
your expired license dated March 31st
2014 so Mark's going to kind of talk a
little bit more inform the party there
is a 24-hour access line to confirm your
paperwork and they already know this
they don't give you the number by the
way that's why it's not on there she put
they do not give you the number that the
law enforcements can call help that
sense that so they have a number so
that's the reason why it wasn't there I
just it just clicked tell the party
there's a website to look up the
information information go to
www.health
canada.gc.ca
MMA put it across the screen for you
guys so we put it across the screen no I
mean I'll do it in editing okay this is
going to so it's a nice I like that yeah
okay so here's what it gets tricky it's
pretty cool all right okay so and even
if you type you see this okay first do
we read these first two things these are
the they have step one step two step
three okay I'm going to go through these
other steps to tell the officer who now
questioning you about your legal right
to carry cannabis and just say for
instance your piece of paper is in
transit coming back to you because it
was destroyed you watch this video you
got some information how to obtain your
license that you don't have anymore so
you're going to tell him that he needs
to do these specific things so you say
you can go to the website and they all
got smartphones I'll take you there I'll
take you these steps I want you to click
on licensed producer because you're
going to have two different sections on
this page right and you go license you
want to click on licensed producers this
will take you to a purple page yeah and
I talk to Jason Wilcox about he goes
purple page I'm go purple page he goes I
never knew about a purple page I like I
never knew about a purple page either
and Jason's really involved with the mm
Coalition against of course everybody
knows Jason wi so you have to scroll
down to the bottom of the page and click
on the link and it's kind of additional
information for licens producers it's
kind of hidden yeah you're going to see
this and this is the website it'll take
you to this other website so I'll put it
up he's going to put it up there and
it's uh uh hccg
c.ca marijuana for information uh for
this was next page is also purple now
look to the gray menu on the right it's
going to be this little gray menu right
information for medical practitioners
and law enforcements will say in this
thing have a couple other things now you
have to click on law enforcement to tell
them to read the section injunction
related to the medical marijuana and
what we'll actually do is we'll just
give you the final link so you don't
have to follow five links we'll just
give up the first the final link that
will take you right to this uh law
enforcement and then save it on your
phone or save it in your browser and one
another thing just say this does happen
and you can't remember say well you can
go to Bubble man's world and you can
click on how to you know and we'll have
this link there so actually the officer
can find out some more information law
enforcements municipalities everybody
needs to know this information to stop
harassing patients I mean come on but
you're going to get this page when you
click to this here right you get to this
page that's the page the but it's purple
and now that's not purple anymore right
okay all right and I said I printed this
out I was told you can you know so print
that page and have it with your license
if you want yeah but I got I got a
better you notice the one I printed to
with my license there yes it's when we
were starting to be allowed to make
derivatives I remember that you're like
I can have I printed that page and I
swear off the website like a day later
like they didn't have it on their
website anymore so with this PR page is
going to have access under the amcpr
tell them to scroll down to the last
page and that's going to have what I
have here highlighted in yellow and it's
going to be that specific information
and it's going to be injunction related
to medical marijuana access regulations
in it purly states please note that
certain individuals who were previously
authorized to possess and produce
marijuana under the medical marijuana
access regulations mm remain authorized
to do so by virtue of a federal court
injunction order done that's a big deal
that's a huge
deal am and want to know more they can
click on law enforcement and then
they're going to be able to know that
they can call in and hopefully at this
point you're not arresting somebody or
you're not being arrested for carrying
your medication oh that's great
information okay so so that's that's
that so they just get pulled over so now
like yourself or some other people they
might have misplaced it they don't know
exactly where it is how do we get it
back how do you get it back so this is
more information that Cheryl kind of
went on about and of course thanks
Cheryl Cheryl's awesome you know what
she really knows the program if you're
calling H Canada and you're talking to
Cheryl try to be nice have a little
extra patience with her I know people
phone Health Canada often pretty pissed
off great she's she's helped me out so
much over the years you know these
people do they have a job that's it like
like the officer in question that was
arresting me he looked at me and I was
telling about the anoc cannaboid system
how we teach each other and stuff like
that showed him my cocom Fusion he's
like this guy's medical What charges you
charges me for having cream little medic
clear disl in a little V he it was the
other officer shame on J Tau yeah but
actually they didn't they didn't pay
close enough attention telling me to
they didn't want to call help the police
have D they have the ability to just
ignore things though they do it on a
daily basis with certain things and if
they want to start harassing you there's
always you know there's always the
ability to not do that to read the
situation and be like you know I think
I'm going to put it together that this
guy actually is do you want to explain
how now I'm going to get into this next
how we can get our licenses back for
those of us that have destroyed or lost
them okay so of course I took notes as
you can see very nice notes all from
Cheryl like she was telling me exactly
what I need to do and the first thing
you're going to need to do these are
some good steps you're going to have to
request the
copy from Health Canada that you need a
copy of your original license and both
by email and mail no
email and then oh no okay yeah we're
gonna get oh I'm sorry yeah it's your
own notes I was reading sorry but that's
fine okay what I was getting in here uh
do not fact that's what I was going to
mean it's email and first you're going
to email and then you're going to
directly mail but do not facts she said
do not facts do both of those mail both
those but the first thing you do is
going to I have to request a copy of my
mm license includes your full name date
of birth address on where the license
was issued so not not your address or
and and here's the whole thing so I had
there's another thing I'll talk about
quickly just say you've moved and you're
no longer have that address you're still
licensed to carry your medicine so that
means you're not licensed to grow at
that specific location why to say
anything that's not the truth it's well
you can still get well because if you
want to continue to grow then you have
to reapply through the amcpr but say you
don't want to continue to grow you've
moved you have access to cannabis you
just want I you just want to possess it
but I don't have my or you could say
that you haven't lost your license to
grow and you've just lost your license
to
possess seems like okay so we're going
to include the following information
guys you're going to include a uh the
address of where the license was issued
your phone number date and sign you have
to date and sign this need you got to
date and sign it and take a valid copy
it has to be a valid copy of a piece of
govern government issue ID so it's going
to be a passport or your driver's
license there isn't really anything else
uh you're going to scan all this
information a nice little letter I I'm
requesting a copy of my original mm
license um you don't have to tell them
that I lost it or this or that you just
you want a copy you can request up to
two copies because someone like myself
loses things it's a piece of paper it
could get destroyed you can't laminate
it I don't know that's what I thought
but actually there's steps that you can
do okay you can actually even take a
picture of it mhm right so there's ways
you can have that so you're going to put
an information in there who you are
where the address where it was issued
your date of birth your phone number
your email contact you can put this all
into a little package scan it make sure
copy of valid ID and you're going to
email this to OMC
dbcm hc- sccg c.ca I'll put that link up
as well that email up on the screen for
you guys great stuff right so basically
I'm going to be doing myself I'll let
you guys reest a cop license you can
request up to two copies just do it of
course right you get one time you might
get two copies U copy of valid
government information uh put into volum
below oh okay so yeah and then put this
into Vol and send it for individuals
seeking information about Canabis for
medical purposes contact Health Canada
tollfree I got only information right
here Mark's going to put this all up for
you guys you can see that boom there you
go so here's all the information you can
contact Health C for General inquiries I
have the information here
by mail where you're going to mail it to
health Canada address locator 0900 C2
AWA Ontario uh well it's kilo1 alpha0
kilo 9 post the code information email
and everything will be of course
scrolling by like you said scrolling up
on the screen um makes it easy it just
kind of makes life easy I got it all
sitting on written out here it's exactly
what health Canada told me to do so it
wasn't like a lawyer or anything I did
this all myself Laura would have charged
a few bucks for this information a lot
of information and then probably would
have sold it afterwards for more well
here's another step so say say say you
didn't have a copy of your license like
myself the officer in question did not
call Health Canada why do you want to go
home and catch your plane and you want
to see it for a couple hours and be on
hold I wanted to go home they delayed
the plane for me I got on the plane and
I I took one I taking one for the they
took your hash well I'm going to get
that hash back [ __ ] rights that hash
did I do first thing it is I called
Health Canada didn't call a lawyer
nothing called Health Canada told him my
situation told him what was going on
then I got all the information I have a
copy of my license March 31st I've
attached the letter in question of had
to contact law enforcements and what the
law enforcement needs to do I then got
to hold the crown
prosecutor in Edmonton hi the red de
nice Got a Hold Up same name too did you
explain to him the situation no I didn't
get an extent to talk to John oh okay
okay so I'm like joh like perfect so I
was told by the secretary cuz he
probably hasn't even received the
charges yet he may not even get them
until the day of court right right he
might he might not see him but I'm going
to speed up that process so why waste
taxpayers money why waste people's time
why send the lawyers and stuff like that
so of course what I did is I went into
regards my case number I attached him
information regarding I I I faxed him a
copy of what happened and I actually
contacted the lady in question called
that she gave me the direct fact numbers
to the crown prosecutor so say say
you've been charged in any other
Province or anywhere else there it's a
federal offense so you're not dealing
with preven you're dealing with Federal
always with cannabis always with
cannabis so then what I did is I I've
contacted I've got the proper
information to fax this in and phone
numbers I scanned everything a copy of
my license a copy of the information
from Health Canada M and a copy of the
charges in question and sent it all in
and cross my fingers and hopefully it's
not hopefully it's well no they have to
draw the charges it's 100% they're going
to drop the charges listen I've known I
we had our friend get busted with what
400 plants in his house and he didn't
have his license yet and he had a very
good reason to have a license he just
never got around to it so when he got
charged he immediately went and got his
license not because he was charged but
because it was time to a protect himself
properly because what he was doing
wasn't what they think he was doing
which was selling to the black market
versus growing for himself yes and so uh
he got a he got a license with the help
from uh Johnny B and I guess myself in a
sense cuz I hooked him up with Johnny B
of course I mean he would never known
right yeah yeah but really Johnny B
hooked him up and uh he got all of his
charges dropped like soon after and it
was a mandatory 2 and a half year prison
was facing kids you know everything what
went on but so it was kind of a
nightmare but it ended up being a real
dream in the end and you know it's
important that people who are medical
have the protection of medical and it's
also important that we pass or
decriminalize or legalize because
everyone deserves to be protected uh
from Cannabis prohibition and we're
looking at legalization coming next year
July 1st 2018 appar 2018 is what they've
said the liberal caucus has announced
that they're going to uh have
legalization in motion I've seen a lot
of the uh points they didn't seem to be
too great no
hashes um how about just Li hous four
plants per household limit on the plant
like 100 cm or something or something
yeah so it's there there's it's a foot
in the door it's better than nothing in
the sense that everybody can grow
cannabis and you got to think not
everybody every household but if
everyone was growing or a lot of people
were growing three or four plants you
got to think that the smell is going to
be in the air that that whole foot in
the door that made it easy for people to
be discovered will disappear when it's
so normalized that people all around are
smell like we yeah it's just like just
like you smell skunk cabbage when you
smell skunk cabbage like skunk skunk
cabbage smells very very much like weed
and I'll tell you nobody has plans to
eradicate it or to get it out of the
ditches no one complains about how
horrible it smells really what happens
is if you smell it you go that smells
like like really good weed or a skunk or
something and that's you know that's
because it has that same sort of tarpine
profile in the air but um oh I was going
to make mention please and I and I'm
just thinking about I'm looking over
there's another really important factor
reason why you want to request a copy of
your license even if you have the only
original pull that out way request a
copy and the reason why Cheryl said this
is because you get a really nice cover
letter to law enforcement standing
exactly what to do and I haven't she
didn't tell me what it is but she said
request a copy and you get a cover
letter so I really I can't wait to see
your cover letter yeah yeah no doubt I
can't wait to show you my cover letter
well let's do it up let's get that rip
Mother
Lover all right well this is great stuff
Johnny B I'm not going to lie it's h we
wanted to really give you a good puff
Wednesday and uh although it might not
have been quite the adventure that John
and I often go on or uh have as much
squishing and and hash making but uh
good information is good information so
hopefully the people in Canada can uh be
helped by this information and uh for
those of you that have mm ARs and need
to
request youve got the information
necessary to do so now here's here's
another thing that was quite interesting
is the officer said do you have a
doctor's
note and my girlfriend said I bet you if
you had a doctor's note and a card that
said aurar in your back pocket they
would let you go so it's interesting on
how this new system cuz I did have a
fully expired card it sounds like Health
Canada's Got a li little bit more work
to do in regards to maybe not holding um
a stubborn like childlike perspective on
the mm because it's over but instead
recognizing the federal judges court
order to uphold it and not ignore it but
actually maybe focus on it head on maybe
even spend a little bit of money to do
as much research as they can to find the
holes in this system and where it's been
let down I think a lot of the holes come
from the lack of communication from
Health Canada how small Health Canada
really is for this particular job versus
how many people are joining every day
and the absolute failure to um properly
communicate with law
enforcement uh to protect Canadian
patients it's it's insane the the
officer in question failed to do his
deal to fail to do his duty Call due
diligence and call Health Canada to
verify like here's another thing
educates all police stations and all law
enforcements across Canada with this
information I mean it's everybody like
it's a stretch it's a stretch but you
could literally be helping people you
know from great crimes because when
we're not wasting the police's time with
victimless crimes that aren't actually
crimes that are actually just a complete
and total waste of time money and uh
more importantly the duty of protecting
citizens that are In Harm's Way because
you know somewhere there are citizens In
Harm's Way and if the police weren't
wasting their time with patients like
John they would have the ability to
maybe spend more time trying to find
those crimes and those criminals so it's
a stretch I get it but it's one that
could be made that makes uh proper sense
if you look at it from the right
perspective don't waste our time don't
waste your time you know what it three
people lose the taxpayer lose the cop
loses and then the person who he could
be protecting also loses I know I know I
just I just I just saw this sitting
there and this is some trim bin sift
trim bin sift should we run it through
the squashy I think I think should we
run it through the SAU he's got a trim
bin or if you don't you should get one
uh because if you're trimming your own
and with this new legalization coming
forward everybody's going to be able to
have a little bit of their own sift yeah
and you're going to be able to do all
these things you able to get
screens but I
mean and then we can squish it y but I
mean there's just ways of this this
little thing like these little little
epicness and stuff like that you able to
do get and it was it's I kind of like
you know came this little tube it's kind
of cool but uh and then you got the bags
look at this it's like so this is all
taped
up get it in there this is the best part
guys is with legalization coming on and
what's happening here in Canada and and
just with everybody able to not every
household being able to grow up to four
plants in the near future in the near
future that means you guys are all going
to be able to in Canada be able to
harvest your own resin you going be able
to get that first little trim that comes
off of the off the pl those bins or if
you're using SCS or anything like that
and you get this little epic oh smell
that smells very nice it's uh definitely
needs to be like and it's definitely
like in position in position is right we
can squish it though can you squish it a
bit I think we can squish it oh yeah
it's kind of gooey I know it's it's it's
pretty good stuff man it's kind ofo it
kind of like it didn't break up like
poopy powder like I thought it was going
to honest no this this actually
melty it's got some meltin to it already
all right all right let's see I was
going to put it in in in the in the
freezer potential gets got a little bit
of excitement going on here oh I always
bring exciting things look at always
time you got he's like wow okay wait a
one time one time you brought me like
hemp I know that was fun clean this I'm
sorry I was just like was like what is
this [ __ ] is this
CBD there's no glant in here I'm like
sure there is something in there oh I
got another little piece look at this oh
good you need that last little hole
there so I mean like I said come from a
simple trim bin it's a little system
where there's two bins put together and
there's like 12is I don't sell them on
my site to be honest it's crazy I know I
know because we're all about that stuff
but these things work really well um and
that's just when you're trimming these
are these guys got something larger me
myself we got these screens above us
right now and then we're going to grab
them down there and show you and there
just a great little two little small
screens that you guys can all pick up
are you going to squish the [ __ ] out of
this and we're going to squish the [ __ ]
[ __ ] out of that dude he's got excited
look if you can see the smile and he's
like it's pretty hard I'm Li see this
squishing it's not too it's even kind of
like all already squishing out squishing
out kind of he's like wa this is
actually hey you know what we're going
to have to like do a pre this is an
organic little garden of course um well
it's a it's a medy one girl everybody I
kind of de's use organ let's turn it
around and go to the
press all right so we're over here now
and uh I guess we're going to do a
little press here what do you say give
mean a little press well I don't I I
think I'll just
uh do a little lean on I actually
completely Swit that the lean over so
this is just a little of a prepress the
prepress
I no the last time you did it it was it
popped they got the arm they do got the
arm it's true but I'm telling you last
time the last time you did it I'm
experienced
now all right I'm going to trust you
John let's see
if let's see if John blows it out
Jesus it won't damage it I would crack
it open here soon do
[Music]
it
woo some cake batter there look at how
thick that is on the
edge cake batter that's that smells
[ __ ] amazing it really does like that
smells really really
good you can see the old cake batter
there you can definitely tell that was
probably about least 60 70% Canam you
can feel how much is in there too they
really want to horse you might able to
do a sish but might be S there I'd say
it definitely didn't leave much oil on
that unit the way like only a bit on
this edge here that's that was that one
not bad hey it's really
good that's kind of like my first squish
guys yeah with SAS no blowout congrat I
kind I kind of sat and watched the
saswat guys in Jamaica I learned some
things oh yeah that's right we had the
booth there on
that
want to grab the
uh da over there
oh Okie
toie pretty cool
here we
go not bad
hey we're losing
our so there's the
butter and there is the
shatter type pull and snap pull and snap
rosin
versus
LA Z cake
all righty hey you're you're being
recorded now hey hey all right d420 K is
with us
live by satellite mother lovers live by
satellite right there d420 there he is
let's just make you full screen let's
just go [ __ ] full screen
[ __ ] [ __ ] Mother Lover
let's not hold that mother hey thanks
for joining us on a puff Wednesday we
just uh John just shared with his uh the
audience his knowledge on how to
reacquire copies of our licenses for
those uh still under the mm injunction
of Allard and uh yeah it's all good
information we're going to put the links
in this video so let me put the camera
down on me and John and we'll all have a
puff right excent
now Bo hell yeah dude well dude it's PFF
Wednesday here look what we just
squished actually in one squish we
produced two types of
rosin and what's the types butter and
and like a shatter consistency one's
really buttery and one's like shatter
they came off the same Squish and The
Buttery one from a low temperature press
well they're both from the exact same
press it was one press we opened it up
and it was like half of it was butter
and half of it was uh like shaty
consistency I want to hit that butter
first what do you think Johnny I bet you
if would have blown it
out more to it or
like I don't really know what I think
about it to be honest I'll let you know
after I hit it both of them I'll have a
better idea than uh than uh well let's
hit this here we go
D4 b r bong ripping on both sides here
so now the whole thing is with the
butter what I would say and how this
whole thing kind of played out is as I
was squishing it before I squished it
really flat I think by not squishing in
the flat leaving that little Gap the
other with squished out was more getting
hotter and then the lower temp is
because it was so thick it def didn't
heat up as much and that's probably if I
would have kept going it probably would
have all came out like the shatter
that's just my
hypothesis I think that the reason I
didn't say what I thought was almost
exactly what he
said if that makes any sense yeah just
kind of makes sense you know what's
going on with that and stuff like
God thinking about it here and that kind
of oh was that that was hot yeah son of
a [ __ ] you see that it was like always
a ninja it's like
ninja let me clean this for you here
there's one you can use so you don't
burn
yourself that's the worst burning
yourself on that you sometimes there is
a little bit
of that's what happens that's that's
this is the danger of dabbing say this
is the
MSNBC you burned yourself dabbers are
burning themselves All Over America
little finger dabs yeah big [ __ ] hey man
hey in 1986 we all had the little H
knife lip Mark remember 85 84 Y in 1985
Back to the Future came
out here let's hit this Johnny joined it
Johnny ready here I go long R Dar it was
very tasty I'm not going to Li it was
quite quite tasty that little bit of
uh
let's get that on there and let's not
leave it on there to the point where it
burns one of our fingers I'll be on that
for you very nice taste very nice H Buzz
not going to lie good
Buzz good sh
yeah how do you feel about that
John remember when they used to ask the
horse what how he felt about it on Ren
and
Stimpy no good and he'd say well sir I
don't like
it it was real
trippy good old Randon Stimpy for those
of you that don't know Google that [ __ ]
bit torrent it stream it figure it out
it's pretty funny it's pretty acidy it's
pretty psychedelic it's pretty way out
there um like when they're going door
too selling rubber nipples and the guy
answers the door by holding out his
Walrus and The Walrus is like call the
police never what oh [ __ ] it's out there
you going have to Google that stuff
because
go it's way way way more warp than Tom
and Jerry though come on okay so I'm
getting right back into the testing of
the dabing of the squish please do
please do ouch
ouch ow all right going into the shatter
going into the shatter that pull and
snap texture that's oh my God it's just
like it's like a camera it's not even
snapping it's like stretching it's just
it's like it's like a caramel
you yeah it was a dry sift out of the
trim bin yeah MK Ultra dry sift out of
the trim
bin yeah it's pretty darn
nice did you think we were talking about
this
yeah see that's I got a whole bunch of
real pretty clean
stuff all clean her up real nice I'll
give you
a I'm get broken this deal so Johnny is
brokering the
deal [ __ ] off it's done I've already
brokered the deal so just so you know
I'll be taking 20% of that you're taking
hey he just said 60 at the start so he's
already down 40% from his initial grasp
he's going to be
down giving me
you going to try that oh you
did I didn't even see you hit that how
was the uh snappy snappy as opposed to
The Buttery
buttery um taste wise yeah I'm going to
want The Buttery butter I mean the
snappy snapy really you prefer
it is this going to burn me when you
pass it to me no I didn't do that to you
I didn't hand him a hot one like this
one like ow it's pretty hot it's okay
and you handed it to me in a way that I
almost had to grab it by the hot
I was trying to put the resin stamp on
trying to get me man there R stamp here
it's like you get stamped you get a
resin stamp all right you got a round
little stamp this is going to be my last
puff Wednesday puff and then we're going
to put the camera on D and he's going to
take us out with a giant giant like four
G dab I'm just
joking oh my God he's got the ball rig
going yeah get your dab ready you're
going to be on camera after this one
he's
next
so you know what uh it's going to be a
little bit of some controversy here
talking about the different flavors
different textures and uh you know just
the different
um what happened
here one or
two wow they both taste grap but
different grape I know the butter is
more fruity yeah and the shatter one is
just it's more like I don't even know
what it is see how sits on the tongue
though it's Morey it's just interesting
it's interesting and how and I think
Darren might have hit that it's
definitely not the strain or the
cultivar that he said it was no it's not
and I said that I think it might be a
mixed bag something got in there yeah I
smelt a little bit of the haze in there
that is you know often associated with
an MK Ultra but I mean have you done any
squishes like this where we're getting
two different type of for the same
squish it's kind of not quite to that
extent of even amounts no it was so
pronounced it was so pronounced on the
well you guys saw we showed it with the
uh camera but um it was definitely
pronounced would it be nice to know the
thickness and all that whole thing will
Happ hey damn you hate it when only
happens once to hey
what like hey we want he wants to do the
bong r d420 k is going to take us out
with the bong rep puff Wednesday thanks
for watching guys d420 K taking us out
take pretty sure it's s hey isn't that
guy in shooter that Mark wallberg movie
I think so man I think I think he was
killed shot in the dome was he
[Music]
back peace out
D peace boys
PE