[Music]
all right guys so we're down here at
John's truck and John has brought the
goods once again I like to transport
stuff for growing tell us what you got
Johnny well first off the Hop is of
course we need some bulbs and covering
both spectrums these are the bulbs that
you have uh picked up uh they're pretty
cool I like them yeah I mean I've uh
grown one batch with the um the digilux
so far and it was full melt super
resinous no one that I smoked it with
asked me if I used any weird light bulbs
or anything so I got to give these guys
a thumbs up so far um I use both the
metal highight and the HPS and and that
was along with the nanox ballast which
I'm sure we showed you this guys before
but just like this thing is so
ridiculous well this nice angle too in
it
size that same plug again that leave
that there's that size of that little
look at that bad boy so sweet pretty
stoked on that stoked on the
Nano all right so that look all right so
we'll put that aside we've
got some cocoa fiber cocoa fiber dude
stoked on the Coco fiber I've been using
this like
Matt good for uh proper drainage really
gets a good uh in fact even uh one of
the places recently I was at they use
stray cocoa yeah a lot of people do use
straight cocoa when they're doing in the
bigger bigger plants yeah and they get
in the 10 20 G this go straight cocoa
it's good for draining get great great
root structure I did the that whole root
test with COC stuff excellent have more
with it you brought your hard pots here
you got your hard pots two gallons and
three gallons there so we're going to do
a transplant on both the sick hash
plants today they're going to go into a
5 gallon with some very very dry promix
cocoa fiber uh combination uh the three
gallons right sorry and um I guess we
got two more things
here losing the pots the pots I'm going
to walk them up here
right brother awesome I'll come with you
drop off the cocoa okay so two things
left in the truck I'm going to have to
jump in to get them
out so this is the one that we're
excited about indeed check this out guys
you know what one more way of jumping
onto the new school easy cloner power
cloner do-it-yourself cloner whatever
you want to call it these are the
classic 10g Reservoir 45 plant sights
got the neoprene pads for holding the
clones the misters underneath I think
we're going to have fun with this one
John you know what i' I've actually had
these running at the store there and
we've had them there they work great um
people who have picked them up love them
um I'm stoked that um there's one
actually um in the house now yeah well
this way when we need clones of any five
you know like swed Congos Afghani Barb
My Little Pony Betty Kush Astro Boy the
Jamaican and hash plant wow we're doing
pretty good there that just lined up
plants five of each one eight different
eight rows awesome so let's put that
aside
awesome and last but not least of course
that tent ah the secret Jordan Dr
240w my tent I have the same
one so yes this is the exact same one we
did last time um we won't probably go
into the full detail like we did last
time but we want to show you at least
the simple
framing of the tent so we'll have a nice
uh camera view for you of that and we
want to do the uh Power cloner as well
so we're going to take that up to my
office and set that up so what do you
want to set up first John um I think the
power cloner power cloner yeah we'll see
you guys up at the
office all right so we're going to rock
out the power cloner
Botanicare let's open her up
John got a 45
site oh I like how that opens very easy
[ __ ] never opens nice like that you know
what I think these guys
did I want to show you what it was here
now we're going to set her down looks
like I can just dump it right off ready
Bo clean we done yep we're done that's
[Music]
it Johnny going for the rip going for
the easy
[Music]
peel more to go when she's all
done I'm going to go for the basketball
are you ready two minutes left in the
game no two seconds I think I pass it
over we lost we lost the game Bubble
man's a failure all right so
that Reservoir this is going to be the
goods right here this is our
Dome
I saw basically how um this fits into
here like this it kind of drops in here
and all the Jets are fit in and it
basically this is the the
cords nice and that just sits right on
top and then the Dome so well let's
check it out I got the trusty old Dodge
key on they sent us uh prices for all
the different reservoirs sizes we've got
white and black 10 gon 20 20 gallon and
40 gallon if you can imagine big old 40
gallers what is that like 125 sights or
something this a little
mepr thing these are the pucks yeah
these are little bit cicare stuff in
here to inspire root though all right
well I'm thinking I might listen to my
buddy Kingston who's got the uh recipe
down on lock so this is risos spere root
inoculant for seedling and transplants
and then the aqua shield and power clone
both from Botanicare Solutions
all right so we get the pump ging book
of course general purpose utility pump
perfect hoses the hoses and these will
probably be the air pucks and maybe the
other pump these would be the little
power cord for the pump there we go oh
you got the emitters the little Jets
there you go okay
[Music]
so here's the
instructions and we're just going to
follow the instructions cuz what a great
idea to follow the instructions what a
concept power cable for the uh power
cord for the yeah no it's just a little
pump oh yeah for the airstones
for the airstones yeah I saw it had
airstones as well as this pump that uh
you know Jets out the uh so we'll leave
those in
there let's see what we got going here
so we've got the reservoir and clone
tray the hum the humidome uh the
manifold which is this little guy right
here the clear tubing which is right
here we've got our food right here we've
got the mag pump the mag Drive pump the
single air pump that you just had in
your hand there we've got 13 yellow
sprayers 15 yellow sprayers and 35
yellow sprayers so I'm not sure which
one we got I think the 13 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 14 so it's probably 13 with an extra
one it's always nice if they want an
extra one 45 neoprene inserts I'm not
going to count those and then the
airstones are the only thing I didn't
see that must be in here yes there they
are right there 47 oh you count it
excellent Johnny is a since he smacked
his head he's real good with numbers
like real good with numbers hey what are
the lottery uh winning numbers going to
be for next uh 911 21 23 36 41 power
bowl that's $200 million win we only
expect about a 2% return on that if you
wouldn't mind sending that to Cara
bubble man's world Johnny pimp lappa B
for fellow and uh Bubble Man Marcus G
williger anyway let's get into this here
John okay run water through the manifold
rinse power cloner Parts make sure
you're cloner is clean and debris free
before using this can be done by rinsing
all conon prior to use no problem we
have a hose right over there we'll do
that once we've rinsed this out which
I'll go do right now we're going to
insert the sprayers
Johnny insert the
sprayers oh
wow that was
awesome well it fell pretty good
distance but I it was still kind of
protected so
yeah so he's rinting things off there
right now and you know what I'm going to
take a better look at this just want to
take a quick look they said he watched
the video on it so I haven't actually we
set one up at work was quite easy oxy
was uh
down all right so it looks as though all
the Jets are clear and free there we
go spin these all over there that looks
like yeah nice and nice job yeah you
know got the hose right
there all right so a little bit of water
in that which is okay that's of the
sweets down
here
so now it's literally about putting all
of those little guys into there so if
you want to pass me a
handful we can both just
uh what did I do with the directions
there they are so here we go gently
thread a sprayer into each side on the
manifold they are all the way in in the
pictures they said gently so they said
gently but yet in the pictures they're
all the way in so what do you think
there do we we keep
going I'm going to go wait until the
arrow
is it gets pretty tough on the hands
doesn't it yeah see that way can't do it
so oh this one's good I guess it depends
on if you've come in at a strange
angle if you did your fingers are going
to
hurt try to close them
out all right
so we've rinsed our manifold we've
installed our sprayers use the yellow
hole punch wrench the yellow hole punch
wrench to
tighten the sprayers until snug make
sure your arrows are pointed away from
the reservoir wall do not overtighten as
this inst strip thread so this is the
tool this makes and total sense this is
wonderful reading the instructions all
of us you know what John I love doing
this stuff with you because I'm kind of
the same way I don't really you know
always pay full attention to what's
going on
with's yeah we're just like how could I
not be able to do this yeah it's quite
easy oh wait but once again we just put
it in very Loosely it's quite easy oh I
did it completely wrong you know we did
fine usually I do it completely wrong
and then so I'm going to screw in these
little bottoms on the on this pump here
so it sticks into the bottom of the r CU
of course this is going to pump the
water through the
MS oh this is a great little
tool really tightens these little guys
up nicely and the fingers was not I
wasn't feeling that I stopped I stopped
I just stopped I was like I'm
done well it wasn't super enjoyable was
it
um hard little plastic piece so I'm
pretty excited about this guy I got to
say I've heard these little do it
yourself and easy cloners and power
cloners are all really quite nice not
that I had a huge problem with uh the
cloning but I need something a little
more no-brainer with my setup and this
seems like it could potentially be it so
I mean really like all the products I
use this is really like a review Now
power cloner never sent this to me I
just went and bought one and uh
just realize there's this nice beautiful
coach behind me yeah take a load off
Johnny this is kind of the uh slow
arduous work you're getting that done
taken care of oh yeah yeah a
man this is great soon will have the
ability to rock 45 clones in the blank
of an eye the best part about is going
to be um they're just basically Roots
just water there'll be no pucks no dirt
so they can go into several different
systems actually all systems you can
transplant them into anything yeah
exactly that's what I like so it gives
us a chance to actually experiment a
little bit more too and have a little
bit more fun at the same time um really
learn
uh I haven't I haven't had the
opportunity of actually getting into one
of these and just uh felt like it wasn't
too much didn't need it don't don't need
to have that many yeah totally now it's
really for me it's about sharing no no I
find it's just more more convenience
well in the sharing you know here with
the commercial uh not commercial but the
mmpr or the mm how we are able to make
things work for us is that we are able
to you know John's able to bring me a
medic Kush and I'm able to say here
legal to Congo and Doc is able to show
up and say Here's a Harmony and a and a
Northern Lights these this is key that
we aren't uh supposed to mother out
every single strain that we want to have
access to because we need access to more
than one strain you know for me I I
think I'm a around the 30 strain you
know I like to have 20 to 30 strains
that's just what I like to have that's a
nice thing and
so and I'm sure there's people out there
that could literally use
more I mean when you think of the
incredible benef turns into this yeah I
know isn't that great yeah this is fun
John so I just put this little filter on
the end here so nothing else gets in
there if any Roots come off the bottom
they don't get stuck in the pump so it's
very important that you put the filter
on the pump too yes and they've already
wrapped it which is quite nice with um
sopan tape so it's actually already got
the water seal attached to it all right
I just did all of these perfectly
perfect there we go they're all pointing
in the arrows are all pointing in spin
this into
here oops don't need it anymore dropping
the tool dropping the
tool so is this supposed to point a
certain way when we're done here
actually hold up I was going to say I'm
going to go through the directions I'm
sure that's the next thing to do um
connect the pump to M make sure there's
a Teflon tape on the pump threads it's
there um slowly thread the pump into the
manifold hand tight and gently turn
clockwise until the pump is snug and
lines up with the short end of the
manifold you hold that there yep I'll
spin this perfectly give it a spin looks
like a microphone it does doesn't
mm so that is they said hand tight so
okay so what's gonna happen is it's
going to be like the cord's going to go
into here and this piece is going to go
right here okay so right now I guess
what it'll have to do is it'll have to
line up something like this the other
way we tting it up still so we can still
place the air pump on a stable surface
outside the reservoir all the air pump
yeah no problem there stones this is
simple simple this is great
p is going to be in here like this so
this will point the other way the other
way the other way the cord needs to go
on the other way yeah or you probably go
around one full more it's got quite a
bit of threading left so with watery
objects you always go more than less how
we doing is that doable right to there
perfect and that's probably how they
designed it cuz that's just
slick okay so there's your cord fits in
there perfectly we should actually just
show you how that just went in there yep
perfect there you go they got it all
lined up pretty good these guys are
pretty smart on their design a no
brainer here and then you've got your
cord basically goes into this little
guard and I guess that's next up is
going to be these
airs that's tight go down with all of it
I'll be able to pull it up if we need it
out perfect so there's that next
up next up install the manifold we've
done that this is sitting in here
perfect make sure the filter faces away
from the cord guide push down firmly to
seal seat the manifold into the
reservoir so sck that like really get it
stuck install the air pumps and
airstones so this is super easy crack
those bad boys
up look at this ni nice little sho got a
little this a nice single one power
Corner seven Great there you go thank
you sir
so this should be one long cord perfect
so we're only going to use one of the
stones I don't believe we need two the
other filter that uses two has a double
here there's two holes so this one only
has the one
and so attach one AirStone to end of
tube and the air pump is to the other
end so you just attach one of those to
there and I'll attach this to here and
that's literally
done that's
it that's
it how exciting this is just coming
together quite nicely it's almost things
worth when we put things together oh
yeah we make a little mistake here there
but that's I think we're do going to
have to put this up put this into here
so the water doesn't Splash up yeah oh
yeah exactly that's why you go right to
the
bottom yeah the AirStone in there too
exactly I knew there was
two great these are quite nice little
Neo HS now I'm wondering if you just I
guess you would plant them each time or
you just take them out separately that's
wonderful you take them out you open it
up you P it out and then you rinse this
off and you put it
back and if you only want to have this
many you only have to have this many but
you have have all the holes filled or
the water sprays up of course that's
what I'm I'm now we learned that the
hard way at work and uh we came in the
next day and all the water was out of it
and it was all over the floor it sprays
like a mother doesn't it yeah yeah no no
it just starts leaking everywhere and
that was just because of leaving the the
few of these and it's why I'm using mine
in my office and so I'm going to put
this on top of a table and that table is
going to sit in top inside of a 4ot by
4ot basically a reservoir that way if it
does leak but you know what even if it
drops the whole thing I mean this is a
10 gon rest for us a lot of water it was
just us starting it out and since we did
that put all these in we had never had a
problem again yeah that's you it it was
just that one little if you read the
directions funny enough I bet you it's
in there ah you know what you know it's
probably literally right in there and
says make sure you put all the Pucks in
I think maybe they all out and then
someone took a couple out or something
happened where if you take these pucks
out they get water every well that's a
good tip to give people yeah so make
sure you always was there two extra uh
three oh I said 47 there was 48 I yeah I
was
close you were darn close that's quality
closeness so boom shab
boom and our little Dome
and the one we have at work is
completely C2 it's pretty cool so I've
never actually seen this type of model
yet boom there it is the power cloner 45
plant unit from bot
Botanicare um potentially might have
these up on the site I'm not sure if I'm
going to do it I have to first check the
product and see how much I like it I
like the quality of the plastic Dome
it's pretty thick and this is really
nice too hey yeah not bad well we'll let
you know how it goes guys thanks for
watching um we've done let's see we've
done a meeting with Doc Atomic yeah we
got to do the T we've done a meeting
with Doc Atomic a meeting with Matt the
great Gardener you came over we talked
we exchanged uh you gave me the the
gifts of medy kush and My Little Pony
doc Atomic brought the Harmony and the
Northern Lights Let's uh maybe go have a
session and then get that done okay I'm
down
cool all right so Deja Vu we're here
again we're always here there's your
there's our old work I like that I like
it as well next one wonderful job right
here let's do it
up so this is another secret jarden 8X
4T tent you guys watched this last time
and saw it set us up if not uh then
stick around cuz we're about to do it
right now and it will
be
easy here I can just cut
this there we go once again nice just
comes in a perfect little bag box so
I'll lift this up can slide on some
hardboard oh hey how's it
going very good all right
so all right so we got a nice little bag
that this comes in just like last time
let us open it up hey
John all right so here's some components
we might as well this
out couple for
you
really most of the work right here these
poles are really yeah just lining them
up and getting them
all that
it s for the
bottom all right I would have loved to
have swept the garage but I think it'll
be
okay we kind of know what we're doing
this time around kind of know what we're
doing nothing another a little bit out
of the way here this thing is completely
like
already did the other one come like this
oh yes it's
awesome oh yeah
right the bottom it's got the H so we
just have to open it up which I believe
we opened up the
bottom last time the bottom the bottom
yeah which goes all the way up to here
which is the here down there follow
right there open it
up yeah you got
zipper
okay zipper on that this one it goes
down to here perfect there we
go all right here we
go open this bad boy up all the way
around
around and this is what we did last time
just socks in all right no socks just no
shoes sh to cover the plumber
TR these
ones these were our top these our M
that'll be horrible sound one two for
camera ending four all right one two
what do we got for Corners
here already laid them up so we have the
ones that go the top the back here our
eyes and now put those hes across the
back directly across here right here
like going like this yeah okay so one
that's what it says here I I I I
perfect and and the A's are 1 2 3 four
exactly perfect so I guess best first
things to do is to connect the eye to a
corner
slot then we have
two well that's it so this is probably a
good idea a skirt that goes inside I use
this on my other one and it's best if
you put the frame in the bottom of the
skirt rather than try to put the skirt
in afterwards frame there you go yeah
want to put the skirt in there that's
just what I noticed last time so you get
the skirt laid down
get all this stuff lifted up so we're
not hiding crucial
components um it goes the other way
actually yeah it does from the velcro I
almost always do things the opposite way
as what they go the first time but I
guess as long as you get it right in the
end it's really all that
matters right see the velro on the
inside of the pieces and the corners
that the PS will go
[Music]
around
right all right so pull that into place
kind of makes it a little bit easier
even doesn't
it
um I need one more Corner how many
corners you got there
four one two three four yeah I have one
two three four isn't one on your end one
two and I have here's the two middles
okay cuz there's two for the middle for
the middle I have one one here extra one
here but I need a fourth one for the top
Corner here's one right here but I need
this
one I need to keep you looking there it
is right there awesome perfect then I'll
leave that one with that one this one
with this
one all right lad
position got your a A can I have a
couple of
A's the a
another thank
you it that is your
a be grabbing your friend's
a whatever you
do and this is the middle piece so we
just go like
this it's in here just like a glove it's
snug that's why I would make sure you're
you're going to have a bit of a harder
time I guess that's not connected yet
make sure that piece is in before we
push these guys
together okay this will be a bit of
a a bit of a tough nut it's going to be
really tough seemingly is impossible
unless you can pull on that as hard as
you
can something CU we're kind
of bottom piece I need those this piece
is sitting to the top okay on every hole
all the way around all right brother
here how about you pass me
[Music]
them and that one to the
Top This is a lot this side not being
able to sort
of all right for that this is going to
make this
[Music]
tight a quick and easy tent up yeah it's
actually quite
straightforward we're only hanging a
single light today because we've got the
LED from Lush on um
order and so once
that arrives we'll be able to step that
up to the
next into the tent take the tent to the
next level for now it's just going to be
the one uh high pressure
sodium and you got to put your Tops on
here yes the tops the tops do one at a
time cuz I remember doing this last time
then we got to put the poles in the
middle again which is going to be our
eyes then we're going to have three one
for the top and the
middle here there's a eye can give you
that one
for those one is perfect thank you
good okay okay take that
yeah then is this going to be going
between these two those two there there
you
go should be one
more oh he's on he's already on using my
L on
he's already on
okay good stuff excellent okay next up
I'm I'm going to pretty sure it's just
these ones cuz that's all that's left
and we just go one two 3 4 1 2 3 four
all
[Music]
right
actually hear it push together and then
just snap there we go see how easy that
was guys pretty quick and easy like I
think we did that during 420 oh my
goodness well that was good we got the
tent up should we pull it up I think
we're um at this
stage where we start with one side and
it zips there so I think this was the
top we did last
time this be the top right there
it's so tight here like impossibly
tight wow must
Zipp this one's right to the end that up
okay right trying to get this light up
now oh wow
oh my goodness that's have a Dy oh I
broke it out of the thing here no
problems here we go that went in that
one
didn't okay there we go there's that 6
in we needed
Johnny so make sure all the Z are
under
now it's just a matter of Zipp you're
off all
right you got the zipper on your you're
going to have to get in there I'm going
to hold it on the inside right here and
I'm get you go
the see if you don't have a friend
helping you with this oh my goodness
I've actually did this by myself and uh
I'll never do that again super no
F booya coming outside here super no fun
right we did it bro thank you again for
all your help John you're always such a
pleasure to work
with uh yeah so you've seen the power
cloner you've seen the 8x4 jardan we're
probably going to do a small setup with
the ballast not sure we'll film it if we
do you'll be seeing it otherwise uh time
to hit some the tent set up and and go
hit some fresh frozen fresh frozen so
that's what we're going to do peace for
now well here we go so we're going to
mount that ballast we love this little
great stuff and you actually pulled this
out of your freezer yeah out of my
fridge yeah out of my freezer it's uh I
didn't need it so it's a so it's perfect
so we're going to be able to mount it
and mount it like that and even have a
little ledge it's kind of cool I like it
man maybe you can put the little uh de I
mean little a time and temperature gauge
on there you can put your little stuff
in there which is kind of
cool so have friends help each other I
know it worked very
well all
right that guy and then we'll Mount this
guy other
side just uh like that people see how
the little Zippy straps work well and
how straps yeah zippies I like them got
to have
them it's uh turned into
um now we got to uh maybe take this in
here all right yeah let's do
that so what I'm going to do what we Yi
just talked about is just melting this
sucker right here just like that yep
that looks great let me just get the
camera organized sorry okay yeah
actually we're not going to use this
whole we could almost flip this up and
around yeah and it would be mounted
already
John what do you think well we're done
what do you think Buddy there you guys
go hey like that friends for hey that's
awesome guys that's sweet dude so uh you
know just to reinforce it I feel pretty
secure zip it up zip it I got one of
these in here guys
so do a couple of those or one of those
it doesn't hurt that is awesome though
uh that was um I'm pretty happy with
that I I love it when a when a a plan
comes together oh yeah that easy too and
it was that easy guys like come on it
was ridiculous so really I guess what's
left to do um unfortunately I don't have
the proper shade and I don't have my LED
light here but I do have um a simple
mobile socket here here porcelain Mogul
socket and we're going to hang that
right in the middle here and we're just
going to hang that for a day or two
until I get my proper LED light and my
ballast so is that perfect how that just
worked in there yeah well that's the
whole purpose right excellent there she
goes and she's on she's hear the intake
and the outtake on that little nanolux
pretty sweet lights on we're going to
lose our power right away so let's move
on to this I'll go change my battery
nice okay so we're time to stick that
light in there Johnny that shelf worked
built so good you see that yeah I saw
that you pulling it off there sweet so
we're gonna use the digilux Met metal Hy
dig Did you like
myal yes yes it's are ker ker nice this
how this thing opens here I like that so
all right I'll take that box for me you
going to take the box
[Music]
yep going in all right so let's light
that up and see what we
got what it'll look like I suspect is
another metal
Hy lighting
up give it a
second is this where it doesn't
work oh it's where it works why wouldn't
it fre it was freaking you out though
John just like freaking a little bit you
know what give it a minute this was like
a a great way of doing things in here
we've gone through this one before
everything always works for us but so
listen this isn't finished the way it's
going to be we're going to put in the
adjusta so I can move it up we're going
to get a shade on here the HPS is going
to this is metal highight but the HPS is
going in it's going to go over on this
side over on this side here I'm going to
have a two times XL Dominator and so
this whole side of the tent will be
Dominator that side will be HPS and
right in the middle we'll get a little
combination of the two so we mounting
our fans in the corners yeah let's mount
a fan or two into the corner and
yeah let's Mount one right into that
corner and then let's um let's fill this
tent with plants let's get some plants I
think there's two right there there is a
couple right there uh congales and Barb
so we'll get to
that all right guys so we were just
about to throw the 10 plants that are
going into the tent that we just built
and we decided you know it's best um to
put these in in a 3 gallon pot rather
than a two I'm not looking to stretch
them out Beyond stretch out but I really
believe in the power of the roots having
somewhere to go right before you put
them into bloom it really gives that
plant a happy beginning so yeah just
pull off the Barb tag there buddy there
you go oh you know what I'm not sure I'm
going to throw that barb in
here don't yeah I'm not sure I'm going
to throw Barb in here right now but you
know what we'll transplant it anyway
okay we'll transplant it just the first
one I grabbed off the L here it's
perfect there you go here we go I'll get
some uh nice cocoa fiber and PR
mix that John had me doing when he first
came here I think that'll be enough
right
there look at those beautiful white
Roots they're gorgeous Barb's healthy
buddy yeah nice drop it in oh perfect I
like the way the sides fell apart and
filled in the bottom
hole I think he looks like we were
professionals he almost looks like we
know what we're doing here it almost
looks like we know what we're doing here
all right so yeah usually with the sides
you got to do this whole finger thing
but these are pretty much packed already
that's
great next up is the
congales yes the congales see this next
uh tent for me is going to be all saos
that's why I chose um not to do the Barb
this how do I take that barb
home I've got a Barb uh blooming in the
other tent right now so I'm quite
excited to uh to have that start going
I'm Afghani as well bloming in there
with some many hazes and some My Little
Ponies and some Astro boys and here we
go again all right k did we put the
sticker on yet or no yeah it's already
on there perfect first things first once
again beautiful Lous roots oh beautiful
Lous root
beautious all
righto really excited about flowering
out the Congo uh maybe more so than any
strain that I have right now I'm I'm
excited to just learn the accuracies of
it I haven't really tasted it grown with
Med One organically done yet you know
really nicely so medy medy uh Kush
mail that's probably going to happen
yeah that'll be fun that'll be a real
fun uh experiment all right so here's
the Congo
Congo what's up next uh we have another
con woohoo love
that I love
that sure doesn't take a lot of mud or
dirt soiless to put in the bottom here
we don't want them over stuck so all
right tongo it up there Johnny we're
doing the uncomfortable kneeling and uh
labels on there right yeah you put it on
there sure you the
man love those roots they're nice and
fat Roots aren't they oh jeez P that one
that's okay try to get it in somewhat
straight there so it's not growing at a
crazy funky
angle
next up the congales another
congales all right this way we're able
to get enough full melt beautiful resin
you might this one this time yeah you
know it's really about me having a place
to dry the actual plant that's my my
sort of problem so fresh
frozen we're already used the let me
flip that one over there we go do that
one
time and look at
that all
right all right so let's dump in a
little
side side
action
[Applause]
super stoked on the sativa tent in
general even though I do have sativas in
my other tank I have John's My Little
Pony and I have his medy Haze they're
both more sativ they're both going in
there so
uh it's not a sativ attemp by any means
there's a bunch of AST Boys in there
there's h a Hos we have some sweet skunk
coming up next yeah sweet skunk is is
next up on the on the list I got to fill
up my five bucket again that's why I'm
kind of stepping out of the way right
now and I'm going to just label these
pots my sweet skunk has now rooted just
nicely at my house awesome yeah same
with the Afghan and the Barb they're
going to be going down pretty quick
smile on your
face
yeah it's nice to be able to take a bit
of
a w it's so nice to have the big bin
full of perfectly mixed you like that
soil well yeah you got it it's like
having a reservoir it's a an earth
Reservoir all right so that's a Congo
get that out of the way we got a couple
of sweet skunks coming up
next two sweet
skunks one for
[Music]
you for
me drop them in
okay like wow look at that should still
roots on that or just
heal that's
healthy all
right feel free to grab a big old can
full of dirt if you want or
two plants are always so happy to get
transplanted from I really like starting
in one gallons going to twos there you
go going to threes it sort of gives the
roots like hope you know like they've
hit this wall they're like oh no and
then you kind of come along and you say
hey prob we give you a little bit more
room there
bud and that's what we just did for all
these guys how was that for
perfect
beautiful
nice job very good man so once again
transplanting quick and easy getting
your resin
ready doing the quick clean up on the
soil that we
spilled I got my little trusty piece of
cardboard for my uh sore knees yes I
think that was a great idea Jamaica
style Johnny ah some place I'm going to
be real soon yes some place we're both
going to be real soon and you guys are
going to be there with us so why don't
we toss these plants inside the tent and
uh yeah hey watch you here bring that
around
here now the Barb we're thinking about
maybe leaving out right now yeah that's
right talking about so first thing is
the sweet skunk and if I remember you
saying correctly you want the sweet
skunk on this side of the LED right well
they're both going to be on both sides I
have three sweet skunks and I have
three here we go we'll just keep that
right like that I'll pass
you uh Congo Cong go next to that sweet
skunk like right here and then you can
put a sweet skunk over on the other side
nice in the other Corner side action go
and there's another congales for that
area and then we're going to have
another congales go in the middle middle
Cong and a sweet skunk middle and a
sweet skunk middle and this sweet skunk
is going to be rocking it guys yeah oh
yeah now what do we have down over there
we have that's the Barb and then we have
an East Coast Sour Diesel I might have a
second one of these I can bring in and
that way I can do right there I can do
East Coast Sour Diesel here and I can do
East Coast Sour Diesel here so that look
at this room dude I love this little
concept what you going to do here I
think for now fabulous for now we'll
throw Barb in with these ladies right in
the middle there just cuz there's room
and we'll exchange Barb with an East
Coast Sour Diesel when we get a
chance
um as always I got the biggest smile on
my face because look what I'm around
guys yeah it's nice man it's just nice
it's nice to be able to grow your own
medicine so here we go oh God the XL
Dominator is going to go right here
it'll cover a good chunk of this tent
this light will be over on that side and
uh once again buddy I want to thank you
so much big thanks for the help and uh
we'll get medic cushion here next time
too oh yeah awesome
beautiful all right guys I think that
was a really good puff Wednesday it was
Non-Stop and it was long and I want to
thank you guys for watching and spending
all this time with me and John and all
the other interesting characters that
come along and and visit us um this is
going to be the last real big show I
would think before we bug her off to
Toronto for the next gen conference
there and then Jamaica after that for
the pilot project that we're working on
so just keep watching Bubble man's world
[Music]
peace my Fan's kicking it in there let's
just shut that out I love that
[Music]
hyper to the wind all right so we had a
few more uh plants that I forgot about
which were the two that John brought
brought the medic Kush and the My Little
Pony number one My Little Pony pheno
number and then from Dr Atomic we got
the harmony which was via reer man and
we got the Northern Lights one of his
favorite lemony fruity citrusy Northern
Light strings so my little ponies down
there medy Kush Northern Lights and so
I'm going to give you a couple thank you
and I'm going to take a couple we'll get
these guys down on the
old all right
sobly don't have to put too too much in
here with these little guys suspect they
sit oh yeah that'll be about good right
there for that guy let's see what we got
with Harmony same
same so one two SS yeah you could
probably use even a little bit more
you'll see that they're a little bit
lower than
anticipated all right so this one is the
harmony oh I always got paper in there
that's interesting in huh I'm going to
take it off think the roots kind of
they're not really grown into it very
well that's for sure little bit of Chunk
right there it's organic matter it's
okay yeah just I'm going to do the my
little I want I don't want to worry
about any rot these roots are a little
bit uh a little bit Brown they look like
they could use a lot of
Loven so mine are nice and wet yeah this
one's very wet as
well oh I got a really high
concentration of cocoa this time around
if you've noticed on my material there
yeah I really loaded it up I think it's
maybe even like 40 to 50% there you go
yeah got to experiment and play yeah
well I like the idea of having better
drainage there's nothing wrong with that
in my opinion the best part about it you
got to be able to get everything in and
out all right
so one of the things I'll do right away
for this as well as um for the My Little
Pony there is I'll be printing off
labels right now and we'll be getting
them on there so right now we've got uh
the harmony so I'll just put his I got
my little staks that I'll just stick in
there for you excellent yes that's
perfect you know even when I don't have
a name I'm happy to have a name so I'll
just put Harmony on there for now until
I get my little printed up piece so
there's there's the
harmony Mi up
the
NL the
NL medic cush what's that medic cush
medic
cush we like the medic cush nice and
little root B there we got white roots
in the bottom this one brown too though
eh yeah jeez we really got to get these
roots healthier well you know what this
has been in this one gon pot for like 3
months Oreo that's what so high should
been transplanted here and you can see
the purple stock it was a little
stressed because all those roots were
all bound up in the bottom yep yep so
maybe that's why the paper's in there
maybe that's why might be a trick we
should ask him about that yeah I mean I
don't know about it myself so that's why
I'm releasing it I just try to keep it
real simple I know what I know and it's
kind of a simple sort of method which is
just I'm curious I've never seen that
and there must be a reason to it that
this Dr Atomic so yeah well you know
when you do something for 30 or 40 years
sometimes that's the
reason that just might be the reason you
know it seems like it worked and I've
been doing it for 20 or 30 years we'll
ask the doc we'll get him on camera and
we'll find out what his what his
reasoning is with paper secret of the
paper yes I mean it's hard to say if
this plant was healthier looking I would
maybe believe that it was doing
something good but the plant is a little
bit sickly it's stressed beyond belief
it's producing only three levers if
you've
noticed there's not actually many five
or seven levers on the plant but we'll
get it back to health we're going to
bring it back real nice I'm super
excited to have it in this
stable so there's the NL there we go
there's the Harmony and there's the medy
and the My Little Pony there we go guys
so just like that a couple of more
plants have been transplanted and the
stable grows even bigger thanks
Johnny all right so one more thing I
just forgot about um Dr Tomic brought me
Harmony and Northern Lights John brought
me medy Kush and My Little Pony and so I
don't want to send uh well dromic I sent
home with everything uh John's taken
most everything but not everything's
rooted on him I think the Congo didn't
root for you con R okay well
dude
conges for are you for are you small
Amigos I want you to take this Barb home
too no sorry that's not the Barb that
I'm talking about that is an East Coast
Sour Diesel I do have a barb want to
give you I have a Barb right now that
I'm going to be flipping and you know
what what's great about that is uh right
there bar ra so you can flip that pretty
much right away I'm going to say when I
flip my next one this a little bit when
I come back from Jamaica that's what I'm
going to my next okay well when you come
back from Jamaica these are going to be
big these are going in these are going
to be big I'd say they're as big as
these well it's 3 weeks weeks yeah we're
gone for two and then on them for we're
going to be gone and we're going to be
gone anyway you got the Barbara you got
the um congales and this is what we do
we share things out of our garden I had
no idea I was going to pull these out of
the garden for John today but it just
made sense he's my good buddy I'm
surrounded in genetics okay they're
everywhere um let's share them that's
the the I'm just going to keep saying it
share your genetics it's right on John
enjoy that
[Music]
awesome