[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble manan's World
I am over with Nate a buddy that I just
met really online in the last month or
so sure so kind of a funny story how
Nate and I met he purchased some Blue
River tpin from me and he was having
some credit card nightmares and so we
ended up just being like I'm canceling
that one and I guess he forgot that he
had done this order with me and so it
came back and also when he did the order
there was also a little bit of it was a
different address and a different
shipping address with a different
country in fact and uh it was kind of
funny you know I was a little worried
that it was a scam and I contacted him
and he assured me no dude trust me it's
all good but things kept taking a little
bit longer like a week and I started
getting more nervous and was a little
bit aggressive and he was like oh bro
I'm so sorry I'm so sorry and then like
a week later he's like hey do you want
to come over and hit this pipe that I
just purchased which was um is even a
stranger trippier story CU of course if
you guys uh are recognizing this piece
right now this was a beautiful
Mothership that uh high integrity glass
art sold gez it's got to be over a year
ago now yeah for sure yeah a gentleman
from Montreal out east had purchased it
and he actually came to my hotel room on
a few occasions and I was lucky enough
to smoke out of it while he had it and
now you know now Nate's got it and he
invited me over so I thought well let's
go film a fun video over at Nate's place
in Vancouver and uh I brought the rosin
that we pressed out the other day with
dom and Max which you also know for sure
yeah so it's a small world Nate also is
friends with dom and Max so we got some
Blue River Tarpin we've got some
beautiful flavors here basically two
flavors pressed at different
temperatures and different times I
brought um the Teflon and the 09 cookies
so got a couple of teflons couple of 09
cookies and yeah if you want to fire up
the Beast and take the opening dab I'll
get you one off
here going to jump up
here let's open up a tur good I'm saying
cookies good interesting because when I
did meet up with the gentleman that had
purchased this pipe from row it was the
cookies that he bought from me like in
multiple packs that day so here we
are just a delicate little TP dip there
oops nice bounce and catch ehy some
basketball action right there finess
finessing that
[ __ ] all right so I'll just ask for the
carb cap of choice thank you very much
nice with the seed of life for the
single with the MEAP is so ridiculous
dude when I got it it had one that had a
slit in it still oh wow wow so you just
grabbed yourself a mega pot for sure
down in the states good call good call
12 seconds on that so you want to tell
us a little bit about this pipe you must
have learned all the fancy names and
everything about it by now I heard 3D
Purple Rain exosphere and that's about
it thing that's different that I heard
is that second little exosphere kind of
inside of
it sick though it hits so well when you
hold it in your hands like that you can
feel the rumble like crazy compared to
if it's just on the surface even
[Music]
agreed got a little uh Q Tip action for
sure what a beautiful piece what a
wonderful Rumble he's it's true it's um
it's actually one of the reasons why
this particular piece a lot of the
really heady pieces I won't pick up I'll
leave it there and I'll hit it like that
but with a piece like this you really
want to feel it rumbling in your hand
and Rumble it does that was a perfect
low temp dab by the way this timer is
the best it does how long you heat it
how long you cool it it works
perfect 100 dabs and this thing's barely
even dirty well let's get you one of
those cuz it was just so darn nice it
wasn't a huge dab by any means I usually
take slightly smaller dabs when I'm TP
dipping for sure I'm not sure if you're
on the same boat with that but
I also find that it really potentiates
it so much
that L seems to work
fine that was number nine what are the
differences in well I'm about to go into
my little phone here I got to go to the
picture and I'll tell you while you're
taking your dab what the difference is
so number
nine number nine is a second press it
was um
six of a gram that came out it's the
Teflon and it was the second press so
yeah well it was delicious I dipped it
in cookies too so it's not going to be
an accurate uh feedback of the the
cultivar itself but
uh stoked to be hit in this
3D
Mothership try to get some nice camera
up close for you guys to see the actual
uh bubbling that occur C here in the uh
rumbling I should
say can't believe the perfect perfect
temp that you're getting every time on
that I prefer personally a larger Banger
or XL honey pot like I just for sure
even for small dabs even that's it yeah
exactly it's all about that surface area
and especially the way quartz dissipates
its heat someone was asking me if the
etchings like in the actual bucket like
for the seat of life if that increases
the surface area and actually makes a
difference difference I have no idea if
it does or not interesting well I'll
definitely tell you that when I put the
sherbet pencil in and just moved it
around gently I right away noticed those
ridges there like okay so I'll be a
little more gentle maybe just hold this
here sure I always use the glass ones
instead of the titanium ones or anything
yeah yeah of course that makes total
sense
actually especially with ridges like
that with the titanium one I generally
will put it in a quartz and just do this
yeah just right on the side I just hold
it up against the wall and then uh yeah
I don't need to be uh there's lots of
people that like try so hard to get it
off there though you're like it'll just
smell give it a second I'll tell you
I'll tell you I think we should hit
another one just because a this piece is
amazing B we're just kind of meeting
each other and having our first sesh and
uh well there's all sorts of other
flavors here so what was number one that
I did was it this one was the first one
we just puffed right that's how I did
yeah I think so I kind of want to go on
this real super butter yeah for sure I
going say both of these look so light
and mess
butter Tor you the problem with it is
like smell so yeah little jar of Heaven
which two did you order when you ordered
I got the Crown Royal Jamaican one and
the I think Sour Diesel but I might
something El s diesel my favorite one
out of those Jamaican ones that was one
of my
favorit
beautiful excited to hit this again for
sure God I always look at a pipe like
this you probably noticed right away I
took my keys off from around my neck def
pendants or anything pendants Keys
anything I'm really one of the first
people even though it's not my pipe but
because I photograph them often and and
make videos with them and stuff I feel
still extreme responsibility of being
around them for sure that I have no
problem sharing that information with
people and being like Oh no you know
just really take the thing off it's not
even like the sunglasses on here that
can fall off just just all right here we
go
the carb cap is so deep in the crown
isn't it it's
crazy never even bother
trying it's like a full knuckle in
it's pretty cool though for sure it's my
favorite ofc well no
[ __ ] beautiful low temp dab on that and
did you notice the lighter color rosin
made a clearly lighter color oil in the
dish as well it's a great laugh sure and
if it's
50/50 absolutely there you go
Nate well what a pure joy I had no idea
today I was going to be a hanging out
with a new friend B smoking out of an
elite Mothership and see making a video
for all of you guys to enjoy I've been
pumping out videos lately like the last
four or five have been real consistent
and and good but uh today I had no ideas
I was just like ah we'll take a day off
no days off for you no rest you will
smoke
Elites Mothership sure has changed the
game you know it really have have taken
this whole thing to a new level which it
helps other glass blowers I'm sure
because it takes collecting to the next
level when you have a piece like this
that's you know literally five to six
figures it's uh it's a special piece of
art it's not uh it no longer is just a
thing anymore it's now an
actual piece of functional art I think
of all these people that spend millions
of dollars on Art and don't get to use
it they don't get to use the art I mean
sure hanging up on your wall and it
looks beautiful but this you can pull it
down take some Dabs out of it put it
right back up get completely
lit and then yeah put it right back up
that was a nice dab you got there that
was a really nice one and that was tur
free for sure don't get me wrong it
wasn't tur free it was just free of
added excess added
turbs so what are we thinking here now
maybe number eight eight looks pretty
like tacky for sure it's only just going
on of numbers yeah well that's I knew we
weren't going to be able to rewrite it
all you know yeah for sure I was like we
can't rewrite this all I know these
stickier ones that are less I mean it's
still pretty buttery but the more
tackier ones uh are are second runs
second presses and still completely
delicious so let's see what number was
that number eight you just got yet yeah
so number eight where are you number
eight five six
you are a second
press of the Teflon looks super nice and
golden there for the crappy picture that
it is it's like Golden
Tears all right so I guess we got to
heat this bad boy up want to take it
you're doing so good on the torch know
telling you it's all about that this
timer I like your timer I might have to
grab that what is it an
app it is called Interval Timer Interval
Timer who would have guessed well after
this dab is this my third and have you
had two or three two so okay so after
not this dab but the next dab that Nate
is about to take perhaps we will find
ourselves out in the city at a beach or
at a park or in nature we kind of wanted
to get out start the show here and then
take the piece somewhere really
beautiful and get a couple of nice
nature shots also brought the Drone so
that could potentially have happen as
well anyway I'm getting ready in the 10c
range
here 10c
range also a good pipe not to be
grabbing if you have rings around your
fingers you know grabbing with the Rings
that's a sort of faux paw in my mind
God it's just
so it's such a lovely
experience to ride in the
Bentley you
know that's really the truth of it right
there so well it's such a pipe that is
worthwhile of producing in Elite Form in
my opinion you know I've I've hit a few
head pieces over the
years that hit like utter incomplete
[ __ ] which is just like almost a crime I
remember really meeting with uh Jason
Lee and him talking about how you know
he just wouldn't sell a pipe like that
he would always put water in it he
always trouble trouble it you know make
sure you wanted to hit it and it was
good feel that it was hit in the way you
at least were you know felt like was a
good representation of your work but uh
you know with these ships that's the one
thing that is pretty consistent that uh
they hit great
have you ever hit the one that's the I
don't know exactly what it would be but
I guess kind of a Taurus then it has a
3DX sere in it and it doesn't have like
any Clin Parts at all here a picture of
it I might have it sounds like something
it's a weird one I had it for a bit but
it was horrible just the only one I've
ever hit that wasn't good
interesting I don't think uh I've hid it
before just let me oh no I've never even
seen that thing before that's tripped
out right it's one I got it took all
your breath to even get a little pull on
it or anything oh my God we'll show that
to you I'll insert it into the video so
you guys can see what we're looking at
right now so this one is
you after a torch
up yes
yes there you gok those TPS drip
downward
so yeah we should get out I don't know
where but somewhere it' be cool we've
got the Drone it would be cool to get
that thing in action as well we're
definitely limited to our time right now
it's 2:48 and it gets dark out like fast
so try to get some fat footage for you
if it works out it works out if not hey
we had a great session out of an elite
Mothership
piece yep yep it's finally Sunny too
yeah that's another thing it's been
rainy for about 60 days days here so
getting a little bit of sun is kind of a
big deal this is another reason I
suggest you learn how to ski or
snowboard and like the mountain because
if it rains the way it's probably going
to this winow there'll be a ton of snow
and the snow is super fun and it's like
a good vibe and the rain is kind of a
bummer and not a good vibe I mean it is
with people who don't mind it but the
people man if you have a problem with
rain and you move to like Washington
State or the west coast of British
Columbia don't do it cuz it rain here
it's like a temperate rainforest need a
lot of
water comes in pretty consistently nice
rip yeah that was so tasty those cookies
are so good dude I'm telling you cooks
all right well we are going to put this
thing in its case and head out into the
city of Vancouver so who knows where
we'll see you next but uh it's going to
be in about a split second transition
and there we will
be all right so Nate and I have made it
down to what is this English Bay it is
English Bay we're just kind of at the
far end of it oh yeah there's the boat
house over there that's all sort of
Denman Street and Vancouver part of
Vancouver in the background and then of
course the endowment lands are behind us
and we're right here on the Pacific
Ocean and I guess uh we brought the
beautiful piece we took some lovely
photos on the side of the the sand and
on the rocks and as you can see cuz
you're looking at them right now aren't
they lovely so I managed to grab some
Q-tips to maintain the
Integrity of that xile Banger and uh I
guess really it's a matter of passing me
over that Dabber I'll let you do the
torching I'll hold the ofz if you like
you don't have to worry about such
things got an extra hand it's one of
those things when you say you're going
to hold that you don't put down you
actually
hold especially that one especially that
one yeah all right so we're only going
to do a dab each here as we've been uh
very graciously awarded a free mu music
Zone by our neighbors who were enjoying
their music but I told them I wasn't
able to record if music was on so they
were pretty cool Vancouver dudes just uh
offered to turn it off so I do thank
them and yes I think this is going blow
oh yeah it's already done it like once
so I wouldn't be overly
surprised nature dabs
with the mothership Elite I love it dude
I love the sound of the water here you
go
sir you're most
welcome and I'm GL to osz you when
you're
ready cuz that's what friends are for
coming out into nature so yeah the the
sun's going down as you can see it's
kind of behind us here you can't really
see but it's not too far from going down
we might get to one other spot after
this if we can rip into Stanley Park
real quick and pull over on another
little Zone and have another little
session I would love to at least get
three zones for you guys uh with this
beautiful piece and of course it's just
such a joy to shoot the thing every time
pH photography wise I mean my goodness
pictures they come out very
nice 8 seconds this timer is the timer
for sure it's definitely the
timer all right so here he goes 8
seconds in and it is his time for the
dab
below out of the mothership Elite
we
go how cold is out here even the rig
freezing cold everything for sure
although it still bubbled up and gave
you a RI look how cold it is even
though no yeah yeah no it's very cold
actually which is insane cuz it seems
like it's much warmer out now when we
first got out I felt like it was cool
but now I could sit here until the sun
sets for
sure all right pass me that little
sherbet pencil there get a little DB for
moah or a big one whatever the whole
piece breaks off when I said that no
joke it did got to do it all got to do
it all those are the rules you know so
yeah just a beautiful day people walking
down the path here all different walks
of life enjoying life here in Vancouver
you know the beautiful thing about
Vancouver is it really is a
multicultural City people from all over
the place come and live here and it's uh
I mean you yourself came from the US
it's pretty
cool pretty
cool forch it
up so yeah for those of you that aren't
aware of English Bay we're basically
right at the entrance to Stanley Park
one of the you know it's kind of our
version of Central Park here in uh in
Vancouver it's as large as the city of
downtown Vancouver so it's uh it's a big
chunk and it's definitely a bonus to
have it to be able to go walk through
ride the bikes the seaw wall all the way
around it's pretty killer I'll let you
do the uh ofz
honors thank you sir the Bottom's cold
isn't it the Bottom's pretty
cold I love this piece though
man sweet nature dabs while the dash on
are walking by see this
little like what's up you guys do GBS
down there is that a mother sh
yeah it is yeah we
are be beautiful so we scored a couple
of nature Dabs at the beach
we're not going to waste any more time
I'm going to cut to the next scene so
these gentlemen next door to us can
listen to their music and uh yeah let's
head deeper into the
park he's just doing his thing all right
little session on the side of the you
had nerv how's it going
guys that thing is so ridiculous I
wonder like what what do you even see
when you look at that but you don't know
what it is like what I want to interview
that guy right now she said she thought
it was beautiful yeah but did she even
know what it was was she like that's a
pipe or no I told her afterwards that's
what I'm saying it doesn't really look
like
all right all
right well we're here right on the side
of the lake that is
literally right next to the entrance to
Stanley Park through the city so there's
Stanley Park through or the sorry
Vancouver buildings through the trees
there it's even recording already
all right we wanted to record with the
beautiful sunset and the you know but
we'd rather just sit here and I think
have a nice we've got the view and we'll
show you the view uh afterwards so
that'll work out fine so all right we're
going to heat this bad boy
up you have a torch too all right where
they can see some of it because it's too
nice not to
share want me to grab
that to hold it to make it look good
look it needs to be in the sun I think
it looks yeah like this there we go just
allow it to
cool this is how you have to hold this
piece always just just in the end yeah
and it's good if you have angels singing
in the
background or not doesn't matter how we
doing for the timer good 10 seconds 10
seconds oh yes fny every time you open
the Pelican case there Little Angels
Sing yeah you could maybe that's a
product for Elites only of course all
[Music]
right that so tasty
I'll tell you there sure is like more
attention paid to hitting on these
Elites really pay attention in every
aspect of what you're doing you just
there's
a deeper amount yes I put them in my
pocket so they would be nice and quick
for access all right so let me quickly
get you maybe do some camera work for
this particular dab cuz they're missing
it over here
[Applause]
25 seconds left on the
timer just enough time to to give you
guys a beautiful pan out of that lovely
sun
setting yep Stanley Park for the
win glad we managed to hit three spots
Nate sure good enjoy your dab brother
[Music]
booah well I don't know how it could get
any better than that three fat
spots and uh I'm happy I had a good day
Nate's coughing in the background you
know that was a good
rep I guess uh thank Nate for coming
through with the super peace found it
out brother and uh yeah thank you guys
for watching Bubble man's world we will
see you next time peace
[Music]
[Applause]
out
original indigenous
[Music]
food planting irriation where watering
give me full weeks of flowering full St
with the
raining with full
still respect the Muslim the Christian
where you go through
the
original
[Music]
indigen
orig indigenous
[Music]
from the beginning