[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
what a day today it's been filming
videos since early this morning I hooked
up with Remo the urban grower went down
to his place photographed with my macro
lens his incredible garden he's got all
these Dino FEM seeds in there right now
as well as his own UVC chemo Kush which
I actually acquired today that was a
real bonus Thank You Remo thanking the
urban grower came home got the led lush
light did that video plugged it in
downstairs it's growing right now an
exit eh PS super excited about that I
want to thank the guys from lush once
again lush lighting if you want to check
those guys out don't make assumptions
they're the new and improved LED light
I'm gonna give it a shot
everyone's got an attitude and an
opinion about these things but for me
personally what I'm going to do is I'm
gonna let the light do the talking I'm
gonna grow glandular resin head so I'm
gonna isolate them I'm gonna have h PS
and LED right next to one another so I
should have a h PS and an LED resin
content I've got the same plants from
the same cutting same phenotype on both
sides which is east coast Sour Diesel
sweet skunk and Condoleeza so it should
be pretty exciting I then came upstairs
to find out that I got something really
exciting
so this is a product that a friend of
mine has been making for some time and
it's a product that I have always
supported I think it's just a really
cool product every time I post a picture
of it or even mention it people trip so
I figured it was time to share to cut
that kind of thing this is you it just
wasn't happening look at this open here
so as you know being a bubble Man I
don't smoke joints another joint smoker
is very nice very nice packaging not
sure if any of you guys have seen this
this is a good type of packaging they
use on the toxic waste
you just seal it on either side and you
go over it with a iron I believe and it
seals it right up so right fin 13 years
since I smoke joints a stool of joints I
kind of missed them and so when I hooked
into Matt in Toronto and he said oh here
I have one of these from so-and-so and I
said whoa where's he been I haven't seen
him in years
well he was here apparently well okay I
didn't get to see him but I do have his
number so I contacted him and I saw hey
can we get something going on for the
bubble man and can we try some of your
wonderful products and he said
absolutely and he sent me a little
package so really nice packaging that
you've done there my friend will mention
your name because I don't know that you
want your name mentioned but I'll tell
you you know these are one of the most
impressive little products that you can
make in the cannabis industry in my
opinion and there we go so it looks like
a bunch of straws what could that be the
balloon
well let's check this out ooh here we go
so these ones are dry cept these are a
hundred percent dry cept and you really
just have to see these to believe it so
it puts them in straws okay I'm so
excited to show you guys this this is
like this is what I'm talking about
I could probably use a little dab or to
push it out there's one we use the
quartz oh I see they just cracked right
open the straws open up
so that straws cut in half and just
peels off the other one and then you can
do the same thing down at the bottom see
if you guys can see that there we go
so
you see that that right there is a
hundred percent hash no paper no glue
just good old hashish so here's
something you don't see every day
bubbleman smoking a joint now it's not
your everyday joint I will admit so he's
managed to come up with the real proper
amount of contaminant versus glandular
trichomes heads and when I say
contaminant it's probably capitate
stalks the system of hair is more so
than actual plant matter you just get
that lit up real nice and take a hit
so when your pup in a pure hashed went
like this the one thing I would say to
be careful about because it does have a
fair amount of air space in the center
if you want to put the joint in front of
your teeth when you're taking rips just
because you could pull back potentially
a little coal a little hash bomber a
little you know red-hot so you don't
want to do that also another thing when
you're smoking these don't try to fix
them if you see the ash leave with me
bare we go
leave it be don't try to fix the ash
don't try to knock the ash off it [ __ ]
up the charity to raise a house join
this joint will burn right through and
in fact this joy weighs a gram
real nice taste on this it's apparently
the Bob of Kush been a while since I
smoked one of these peer house joints
[ __ ] love it mmm should probably take
a Facebook update picture right
Wow super nice you can see that ash hold
and hold and strong there hasn't dropped
off real thick the beautiful smoke on
this too
not sure if you can notice in the camera
but it's a real blue smoke always a good
sign as a hash smoker when I see that
blue color and the smoke I'm much
happier than if I see a gray color
what is that according to I wouldn't
suspect the ratio of terpenes and
cannabinoids versus plant matter waxes
and lipids whatever it just seems to be
a nice good sign when you get that blue
smoke above halfway through the hash
droit here god it's nice to just be hit
and hit after hit after hit after hit
and feel it completely in the top of my
head here I mean most people would put
this joint down right around now of
course I've got those people I've been
puffing pretty chronic for about twenty
plus years hash for 13 plus years
chronically every day
I like these line in the hip hop song
hip hop - reggae where he says you can
say it's habitual but every day it's a
ritual I like that
Wow I wish it would have brought these
two repos today I've been real nice to
smoke a joint with Remo those guys
passed me joints a hundred times today
and a hundred times I went No thank you
no thank you no thank you I don't smoke
paper and I don't smoke glue and that's
just the bottom line it's not anything
against the the you know and I don't
smoke herb as well so really those three
things that's a pretty major pretty bad
you're full pump for me I just spoke
cash so what better way to sort out me
them to let me smoke a pure hash joint
so you can see there we got that ash
looking okay nice and long this is right
around the time where people who try to
fix the ash don't [ __ ] do it
leave the ash alone
the ash might even involve cooling the
cherry down a bit I don't know but it
seems to like you break the ash off what
seems to happen is at the bottom there
where you see the black ring it seems to
let loose right there and it starts to
crumble and fall away
if you break off the ash so don't do
that
a little piece of - gave apart there at
my boat but I mean what a nice trip tree
that is right that is just a beautiful
thing right there
pure hash joint a grin good lovin life
now this is dry cept he does make bubble
hash ones as well I think these ones
might be bubble hash yeah yeah these are
the bubble hash ones right here so these
ones are 70% chocolate chunk and 30%
ak47 bubble hash and then these other
ones too bubba kush are 100% dry scent
so Maddie's done a nice job on this and
then he sent me some of his new ones
which are 50 percent of it is hemp star
bud ground into powder and then remixed
into 50 percent dry set so probably
going to share those with Remo once
again I have no interest in smoking herb
but my good friend Reba loves it and I
love that we have such different
perspectives such different full
appreciation for the plant but coming
from a different perspective Rima loves
the bud he loves the joints he loves
looking at buds and thinking man I'm
gonna roll that up and smoke it
I love the resin I still love the buds
and I love photographing them and I love
looking at them and smelling them but
I'm really most inspired when I'm
extracting and isolating the resin heads
off of the body that's that's where I
get my kicks using the mothership bowl
that I guess could be kind of like as an
ashtray that's how we do that's the
entire ash of this joint is still on
here even though it's shorter than it
was it's sort of shrunk in its there
hasn't been any ash drop so and the ash
is quite a nice grayish white color it's
certainly not overly dark
oh yeah now we're getting down to it
real real nice this is the last little
bit of this joint and this is really
where you make the decision if you're
going to smoke this nice and clean and
finish it right to the end or if
someone's going to get impatient knock
off the ash and the cherry and [ __ ] it
all up so I'm going to go for the first
one which is puff it right down to the
end
- bummer and that's awesome like that
bad boy out now puffing down clean the
building joints that I need to smoke
these days you know pure unadulterated
hash joints free people that asked me on
the regular what should I do with my non
melty bubble you should roll that [ __ ]
into hash joints how do I do this bubble
man how do I do this okay this is my
friends method I have no idea exactly
what he's doing but I can tell you what
I would try to do this very same thing I
would laminate out squares of hash in
grams and I would get them to a certain
thickness and to a certain size I would
roll them up just like he's doing I
suspect he puts a toothpick or something
on the inside freezes them in the fridge
of the freezer cools them and then
removes the toothpick from the center
this is what I suspect he's doing I
don't think it's a huge secret I think
other people have done it I'm seeing
them sold as Pixy Stix down in
California ten plus years ago
and I think they've been for sale for
you know 12 plus years here in British
Columbia so a really cool little thing
though man I'm telling you that's one
happy bubble man puffing on that [ __ ]
Kootenay baba cush
well they didn't count how many rips I
got but there's any really gum the
[ __ ] out there that want to go back in
the video and count how many rips I got
I've gotta think I got fifty did I get
fifty I'm not
well that is just about ready to fall
beautiful
so we peeled it off nicely there's the
ash and there's the the roach that was a
one ish ash going right there
oh yeah so I made a little brooch like
this you know if it was just paper and a
little bit of herb even if you have your
supercharged thing going on in there it
would certainly not be the equivalent of
what's here right now this is still
three big dabs or at least one really
big dab let me smoke down nice and slow
just cuz I wanted to show you the
absolute perfection that my friend has
developed
what's with this particular method I
don't know how he does it so perfect but
it burns to near perfection every time
I've ever smoked one of these it's only
when someone messes with it that it
falls apart and I'm not sure why when
you're smoking a roach but it makes it
more efficient by just sort of squinting
one eye I'm not even sure I could hit
this without squinting that eye
what's up with a hot I mean you guys
ever notice that that's weird
look I got hot on my finger I'm getting
close dropped her there she is everyone
the end of the joint tiny little cherry
and I didn't even actually burn the will
get it right in here with the ashtray
well there you have it smoked down too
darn near nothing of course you could
always throw this in a pipe I think I
have one right here
careful Pedro lamp I mean I guess we
might as well finish it right finish
what we started
okay just got to too darn small for its
own good looks okay time to finish you
off
[Laughter]
a little bit harsh in a bomb grip a
little bit but that's again because I
just smoked the whole gram a bit who
without what was tasty whew that was a
tasty rib that's er that's her
need to be smoking the last of the ash
beautiful well there you have it Stace
stay tuned for a potential address
website where you to yourself can order
up some of these pure hash joints I'll
tell you it's not gonna be the last time
you see them for me that was super
enjoyable just puffed a gram of dry sift
in about five minutes I'm gonna go be
vaping it go hang out with my plants but
thanks for watching oh man it's world
see you later
[Music]