[Music]
hey guys what would a bubble man's world
today we're gonna be doing something
that I've said I was gonna do quite a
while ago now we're gonna get the peer
pressure the lungs the long peaks press
going and what we're gonna be doing is
we're going to be squishing a half pound
I'm player it's my bike so if I take you
through a little bit of the workflow
although you have seen a little bit of
it Oh beautiful beautiful half pound of
where is my bike on point as always try
to do a little bit more video but for
you the buttons are quite big
they're definitely larger than what I
like to press some people don't prepare
the herb at all they just you know press
it the way the way it is I like to make
sure when the bags are full and I'll be
using 115 micron bags today these are at
the 2.5 inch by 9 inch which fits
perfectly in this press right here in
this template a little pre-press unit
from pure pressure got my nitrile gloves
here powder free and latex free I've got
my little tool for both flipping the
bags inside out which I can show you
real quick as leaving the seam on the
outside we know that we're gonna collect
a lot of resin there and that's not
really ideal so we just flip the bag
over that way and it's real quick to
flip the bag inside out so we'll be
doing probably about seven of these as I
can fit about 30 to 35 grams in each one
so I'll probably do seven of those at
one point in time and I'll be
putting on my gloves so we can get the
buds broken up I've got a couple of
trays here I'll probably weigh out 30
grams at a time throw it in here get it
into the bag and pre-press the bag put
it over here and repeat until the whole
1/2 pound is taken care of
it's I'm guessing it's 224 200 put in
grams in here
so that's gonna be like 6 and a bit bags
really quite lovely bud though there we
go
yep me a beer beer beer beer beer all
right put that great turpino lean smell
and yeah we're looking forward I've got
the press you might hear the air
compressor go on every once in a while
as I've got it up to 140 psi anytime it
drops below that it turns on and that
goes up the press is also on the plates
are heated I'm heating today we're gonna
be doing 220 some say it's too hot I can
assure you the resin is actually
absolutely Terp rich when it comes out
it's gonna be a beautiful yellow golden
color and it's gonna be very glossy and
it's gonna be very chirpy I've got the
little funnel here which I love for
placing inside the screen and then I
usually just sort of collect the herb
and I use the little stick to pound it
through the hole and pack it down into
the bag nicely any little spaces that
you leave generally in the screen
particularly in the corners or on the
sides are going to collect and pool
rosin and every little bit counts you
end up losing more than you need to lose
so those are just simple things to keep
in mind
and rather than video record this entire
preparation of all this bud I thought
what I would do is do a time lapse for
you so I am going to change the camera
put it on time lapse for you guys go
through this entire half pound and then
we'll video some of the presses or all
of the presses it's going to be real
nice
do 35 gram raw bags each time and I
suspect with the where's my bike that
will get anywhere from 25 to 30 percent
returned 28 to 29 would put a big smile
on my face so yeah why don't we get
started
[Music]
the old blood medicine
that was fun that took me about a half
an hour although on the time-lapse I'm
sure it's only gonna be a minute or two
and yeah we got five six thirty five
gram bags pre pressed and loaded and
ready to go got a few extra buds that I
kept out here for photography um and do
some macro photography so you guys can
see the glandular trike trichome heads
excuse me and I'll also do a few photos
just of the buds themselves and some
video of them up close so you can see
the quality of the bud that I'm working
with and I guess next up is let's go do
the pressing I'm gonna probably do one
full press where I take you through
creating the recipe I take you through
the whole process of what will change
our gloves as well because we've
fingered up these ones pretty good and
yeah I think I like the time-lapse so
what we'll probably do is I'll take you
through one squish on regular time we
can watch it nice and close-up dripping
and then I think I'm gonna do the
time-lapse for the pressing as well just
to kind of make the video not two hours
long note that it would be that long I
usually press for a couple of minutes
per bag and there's only six bags here
so even if I did a full three-minute
press still be under 20 minutes although
I do like to go back and do a second
press as well so I'll record that for
you guys so why don't we head into the
rosin office and get this job done the
compressor just loaded up to 150 psi so
we've got a little bit of give I've got
my set six sheets of pre-cut parchment
paper from pure pressure that are
sitting right here I've got one of the
plates for pressing the
plates to hold it down so it doesn't
slide out and that way I have it
accessible right here I've got my six
filled screens pre pressed right here
and then I've got some older parchment
pieces that I've already pressed once
this is what they look like and that way
press
I thought sheets that are ready and I
don't what I can do is I can do my first
press and while I'm collecting the first
press I can actually go and collect the
second press so what we're gonna do
right now is I'm going to do a full
press and show you what we get and then
we're going to do the time lapse showing
all the rest of the five getting pressed
really quickly and then I'll do a
collection I'll do that on time lapse as
well I'll collect one maybe off of time
lapse and collect the rest off time
lapse do a pre press through the detail
press of getting it all into a nice big
orb and that'll be it we'll do the
second press and you guys will see how
easy it is to work with the long peaks
peer pressure and let's get started
shall we
okay so here we have the settings right
here there's all set up if we go to our
recipes and we go where is my bike so
I've got this set up we're gonna change
this a little bit the weight is actually
35 35 grams so we'll get that up there
the bags are actually two point five by
nine it is 115 we'll go for a medium
speed the humidity is way closer to 60
than it is to 16 and then we'll do three
stages
Stage one we're gonna do sixty seconds
and the pressure we're gonna go at is a
hundred and forty psi and we'll repeat
that as well and the reason I do this
and not just one full stage is at any
point in time I like to just I can shut
her down obviously you can do it however
you like you can do it all in one stage
your third stage second stage at a much
higher psi 140 psi is a little bit too
high for half
but it works great for flour and these
are all things that you learn over time
when you okay let's just make sure that
saved the way I wanted it to yep it just
missed my third one so we'll go 60 will
go pressure 140 it'll save and then
we'll save and run
yep there it is perfect all right so
here we go with our our where is my bike
and if you're wondering where the e is
there's not enough letters so I'm gonna
pull the camera back so you guys can see
the press and we'll get going here nice
and long cut perfectly for the unit just
fold them over and there's no crinkles
in it
magnets here that I've got that I use I
use it so much as I like the back the
parchment to hang a little bit lower
than that is set up but it is there for
you if you want to use it we'll get our
bag in what I generally like to do
because I really like the placement of
this to be up top which we've talked
about before is so you can pull the bag
out once you've opened the pressed rosin
but what I do like to do is I like to
make sure like I don't generally put it
in like that before I pre lower the the
place so what we're gonna do is we're
going to hold these two buttons down
which are going to go for five seconds
three two one and we're ready we're
gonna lower these plates just a tiny bit
[Music]
just a tiny bit and that gives us a
tighter space to press down on the on
the bag with so I'm gonna get kind of
out of the way here I'm gonna lower this
down in that toggle dropper
generally after about 10 to 30 seconds
you'll start getting the rosin coming
out and that is where is my bike never a
disappointment with where is my bike so
we've got a couple of drips happening
now and we'll hold this up so it doesn't
go all the way down it's a nice squish
for sure and that's generally what it
looks like when you squish flower that
has proper resin content on it I'm sure
if we went around to the back of the
unit right now we'd see a little bit
squishing out the back as well and you
can see it right in there
boom all right so this is just a quick
minute so far a minute and 30 seconds
and you can see they're still really
nice flow the drips are collecting at
the bottom here it's starting to fatten
up and we've still got flow generally
when you still have flow like this and
you're almost done your two minute press
it's not a bad idea to just continue on
otherwise you're gonna have to go back
and do a second press and you're gonna
expose it to more heat in the second
press than you will if you just do a
full two to three minutes first press
quite lovely look at that
all right we're in our last 60 seconds
of pressing here and she is bubbling you
know there's always people that are
gonna say oh if you don't want to get
the bubbles you got to press a lot
lighter it's this is a subjective thing
you can press however you like anywhere
between 180 and 220 Fahrenheit is
seemingly pretty good you might end up
with a little bit more of a buttery
consistency versus a shadowy consistency
depending on the resin but you can play
around with your times and your pressure
I like to 24 flower between 200 and 220
but with the moisture content when it's
high 220 is perfect for me and the PSI I
like to go up to 140 so we are pressing
at 137 psi right now we've got six
seconds left and this is gonna crack
open I'll have to put the camera down
yeah I'm gonna put the camera down real
quickly here all right so I didn't have
the record button on when it popped open
but that is our squish right there very
reasonable by flower standards I'm
definitely feeling above a 25% return
and we're going to collect this one
right away so let's go do that
[Music]
as you can see a pretty king pretty
clean pickup you know what I consider
near-perfect as it's grown to perfection
beautiful cultivar that's able to
express itself in the first place you
just end up with a real nice easy resin
to squish and collect everything about
it is pleasant
[Music]
indigenous here kinda
oh here you go without touching any
resin that she pretty
[Music]
tear it a little piece of parchment
I'd like to twist the tool to get the
rosin off of it usually works pretty
good and that's a nine grammar nine
grammars that's pretty darn good that's
a little under 30% I'd say we're at
about twenty seven twenty eight percent
but there's gonna be another squish in
the second one so very very nice results
for a first squish beautiful color and
yeah I'm quite happy with that there
that Golden Delicious that's right there
so why don't we leave that one there
we'll come back and do some pressing in
a bit and let's go press the rest
[Applause]
[Music]
nice spot
pressing let's get this going up so I
push the two buttons for five seconds I
use the toggle switch to bring the plate
down just a little bit my way it creates
a tighter area and I can just kind of
squeeze the bat again and control where
that little bit of make sure your screen
doesn't pop out you can lower it really
nice and slowly so we've got 138 psi so
we're good I turned off the loud air
compressor cuz nobody needs to hear that
but this should be a good press right
here this should be a good press the
quality of the where's my bike is just
second to none is absolutely gorgeous to
squish I always like to count my streams
I like when I get 10 or 11 oh we've got
seven but they're long just a beautiful
press got some good motion on this one
over here
she's a drippin big clear dome window on
the inside there and like I said when we
go to the back you can also generally
see in there that you
a nice little squish happening as well
beautiful so as you can see the long
Peaks is quite a lovely little press to
press on
it's very controllable I love the the
dual buttons I love the dual toggle I
love the emergency stop not that I've
needed to use it as of yet but it is a
nice option and of course there's our
recipe going to town right there
showing us our maximum psi reached the
amount of time that we pressed for and
generally I've weighed the first one I
got almost 10 grams it was nine point
something I'm sure with the second
presses that I will do on these that we
will see another gram come out of rosin
out of each one of those so we'll get
those done next beautiful so 5 seconds
left I usually get the magnets off pull
it out put my fingers underneath to hold
the bag blade to the top of the bag like
that grab that little piece so you can
get it out without spreading any of your
resin around and that looks like a real
nice squish so let's go do some
collecting and my life it's my life it's
my life and it's your life your life
it's your life but every come together
for one life we've come from
[Music]
to get a button extra ground
thirty percent
around 40
maybe I'll get more than a gram gram and
a half
we'll see 73 our night in my run
[Music]
her body's a parasite Charlie's on our
values the cannabis
right
[Music]
all right well the compressor finally
shut off that's why the music was
playing there and yeah we're getting
some decent returns here it looks like
at least a half gram do a gram and a bit
per bag so you know when there's six
bags that's another quarter plus you
know quarter to 10 grams of rosin that
you would other have otherwise not
gotten I don't think we're gonna get 70
grams off a half pound but I certainly
think we'll get above 60 in total I've
already got fifty five point six in the
other bag so this is gonna crack open in
about 15 seconds all right a little bit
there anyway this one that had a mild I
had one that I kind of pushed out a
little bit there's gonna be some decent
resin in that little guy right there it
is always be prepare for as you're
removing you know lowering the toggle
down if you've got your fingers in and
around in and around that area you
really really really I don't think I
have to say this but you want to avoid
pressing your fingers that is gonna be
no bueno all right let's see the rosin
starting to come out already
what a lovely cultivar shout out to
maple butter boys for growing some
incredible herb shout out to karma
genetics for breeding some incredible
herb for those of you that don't know
where is my bike it is from karma
genetics it is the amnesia haze I
believe pre 98 cut if I've got that
right or 98 cut and it is crossed with
the biker Kush so a real producer
crossed with this real beautiful sativa
you know euphoric effects almost amnesia
like effects to be honest and yeah look
we left a little bit of rosin behind on
this one it's dripping on a second so
you know that there's a decent
in there if it's gonna get the drip
going terpene alene rich very very
sativa very euphoric uplifting some
people love it some people don't love it
it can cause a little bit of anxiety and
those that aren't heavy smokers but
heavy smokers generally really like this
cultivar great quick you know I think
I've been working maybe an hour and a
half total and I've squished a half
pound I've got close to 60 grams of
rosin that I've produced top-quality
rosin I'm gonna keep it myself because
it's beautiful and it's my medicine and
it'll probably keep me in rosin for the
next 3-4 months probably all the way
through the summer but I know the maple
butter boys have this cultivar available
so I'm not sure if they're still
retailing or what they're doing but I
know another group recently that I've
been promoting and helping which is see
this guy extracts and dabs to go you can
check them out on Instagram if you
wouldn't mind going and given those two
accounts follow they also have where as
my bike and a lot of the varieties that
I've been pressing lately because I got
some of the flour from them so the
chocolate the god but where is my bike
they've got some decent varieties
available as well and I consulted and
trained their guys so they're using the
long peaks press as well and alright not
a ton there but
Shuler kind of real cloud like I say
[Music]
all right I collected the other three
then I squished so far and got 2.5 grams
I suspect in total I'll probably get
maybe four see what happens
all right the compressors off again and
so thus is the music we've got a little
bit coming out on this one not quite as
much my battery's about to die so I'm
gonna switch that out right away
all right second last one here oops
I'm gonna slip slide but not too bad
still got the majority of the resin
there got a tiny bit on my glove at the
bottom but we survived it let's get
right to the last one and then down she
goes
[Music]
[Laughter]
all right so this is the last squish of
all the squishes I've done I've done six
bags twice so this is the twelfth squish
and it's actually giving us a little
drip we're gonna get a substantial
amount I have gotten four grams so far
out of the second press I got over 55
grams for the first press so I'm looking
at about a hundred or surahs 6262 grams
of rosin per half pounds so that's like
a hundred and twenty to 124 grams I have
seen as high as 130 130 plus from this
upwards of 30% but I certainly won't be
upset with a 27 to 28 percent return
all right
I've already pretty much removed all the
other ones but why don't we come and
we'll do this last one together and
we'll show you what we ended up getting
and yeah we'll finish off this video all
right
the way make sure we get all little
particulates of herb usually I would
have swept this all up but I've been a
little bit preoccupied also be careful
when you're collecting on an oil slick
or a silicone mat like this and
generally why that is because it's soft
and if you do the collection the way I
do the collection you can tear through
the screen I learned that with Johnny B
the other day when we did his cush and
so I'm just a little bit more careful on
this I do have to say I like collecting
on a larger surface area with this small
dab or that being said these guys have
sent me a really nice collection tool
that I have not yet used yet I have a
hard time collecting with a tool that
has such a flat large surface area it
just feels like it's gonna make it more
difficult to get the rosin off that
being said that is an assumption that
I'm having and I could potentially just
give it a shot and see see how easy it
actually is so far these guys haven't
let me down they have engineered the
Machine quite beautifully and as well as
the tools very simple tools but wow your
life sure becomes more difficult when
you don't have those simple little tools
to prepare your bud with you guys saw
how easy it was to break the buds up and
then jam them through the little funnel
with a little stick as well as flipping
the bags inside out all that stuff just
makes life easier so we'll put that on
our second batch and there's you know
I'd say there's 4.5 grams of seconds
here you'll get this out of the way I'm
gonna scale out this is just a beautiful
cookie
almost 60 grams of where is my bike in
yo face it's got some weight to it I
won't lie that is some serious weight
right there so let's tear this other
section of the sheet then goes the air
compressor in the background so yeah
this is just over 55 grams actually 50
5.06 not quite as high as I thought and
this is about 4.3 a little bit different
on the tare so you've got just under 60
grams here we go quickly here to my
little calculator my percentage
calculator you can zip that up right
away let's see what we got here 60 grams
now I didn't actually weigh the herb I'm
guessing it was an accurate 1/2 pound it
could have been a little bit less well I
know it was a little bit less because I
kept out 9 grams right here so it's
probably more accurately
[Music]
let's just make that a little bit more
accurate 15 grams 28.0 3% is what we
have gotten here with that press pretty
solid return I'm not gonna lie and I'm
not sure what I'm gonna do with this big
paddy I guess I could get a big piece of
parchment and press it out into a big
disc why don't I do that I'll be right
back
all right so I ended up pressing that up
into a nice disc as you guys can see
here it's very thick it's a thick piece
55 plus grams and just yeah looks great
let me see if I can't get the camera off
the tripod here
beautiful beautiful beautiful you can
already see within it there's a little
bit of buttering going on and this will
butter eventually all right why don't we
do a quick dab all right let's pull the
tiniest little section of this out I'm
gonna probably squish another another
little bit today so I still got a little
bit of work ahead of me but let's get a
little quick gab out of the mothership
Minnie shall we
my time twenty seconds heated and I
usually leave it for between 50 and a
minutes of cooldown that also depends on
how high you have the torch so the torch
isn't super high right now almost twenty
second heat up there we go and I'm gonna
have to run and get q-tips in between
this because my Buster's there's one
right there perfect all right we've got
a 45 second 50 that sounds about right
got some DC glass cleaner for those
times that you hit it a little bit hot
not that that was too hot it cleaned out
quite beautifully with the DC there it
is nice and clean as a whistle we got a
beautiful Pattie I think that that was a
successful little run and long Peaks
pure pressure you guys can go check them
out of peer pressure comm might be gold
peer pressure comm I know their
Instagram is gold peer pressure I'll put
it on the video so it's correct no
matter what and I'll also have it in the
comment section and yeah thanks for
watching bubble man bubble man's world
we will see you next time
[Music]
you