you guys know how to
talk we be Pros Cu
uh every news agency on the planet's
been through this building everybody
loves marijuana there was a story that I
saw on the internet one time this Museum
in American Midwest some dinky little
town they had this saate in their Museum
it hadn't been open for a very long time
so they gathered all the local
dignitaries in the news and brought them
all out and open up the safe and turned
out the safe was full
marijuana and that's exactly what they
did all the people in the room cheered
and
clocked now I don't know who was in the
room but as far as I can tell in just
about every scenario that you get into
anybody speaking about something and
they sell you marijuana everybody cheers
nobody not one person ever goes boo
[Music]
I'm not sure why it's
illegal but um over the years you
certainly in this media they all talk
about uh what a genius businessman the
marks
are now I see how you guys did
that they talk about how much of a
genius Mark is with business but uh let
me tell you a little story about some
business that we did one time
now not very often and I don't think
other than this one occasion did we ever
sell drugs but on this occasion we
did Mark ranged a young couple from the
United States came up here and they
needed a pound of
wheat so we got him a pound of
wheat this is up on the Sunshine Coast
we met these people in a motel room
it could not have been sketchier or
crazier thing for us to be doing it was
just we didn't know who these people
were at T but uh on faith we were doing
it anyway but uh from
Louis woman was
cute that's why we did from St
[Applause]
Louis but at any rate when we finally
make the deal with these people we did
get them a pound a week sell it to them
in a motel room got out of there walked
away lost $200 on the
deal we didn't make any money we lost
money market quoted them a price
whatever it was and that's what they
paid but we had to pay
more that was the only time we ever
dealt any drugs we lost
money so it was never for the money
[Music]
well let's see who else who we get up
here well maybe uh this