[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and I have here an absolute stunning
piece of artwork that uh thanks to high
integrity glass art uh we're allowed to
uh have a nice ni little rip of this
little this little beauty and this is a
Klein recycler by quave and it's the
Sienna Brown is the color it's got just
beautiful artwork done on it I've taken
a few pictures so I can inlay them over
the video it's got a Mothership honey
bucket on it and uh I've got some East
Coast Sour Diesel potentially 90 Micron
I'm not sure maybe
73 find out later for
now let's rip fat
glass love these little Honey Buckets or
buckets whatever you call them I uh I
find them to work the best with your top
quality melt most of the people out
there are using oils uh chemical
extractions solvent extracts but uh you
can use them as well with uh with a good
full melt water hash or
a full melt dry
sift nice quartz just heats up so
nice close that up drop that rip
in
well that was definitely the nicest
recycler I've ever hitten it felt like
it was hitting
back yep yep it feels like it's hitting
back I like
that thanks high integrity glass art
check them out and thanks quave you're
definitely putting out high quality
glass Mothership of course shout out to
you guys as well and thanks everyone for
watching Bubble Man's World
[Music]
Peace