[Music]
hey guys bubble man here just wanted to
open up a package I got today in the
mail maybe take a few dabs with you so
this k came today
from the rare dankness
crew pretty stoked as I've been speaking
with Scott and I'm pretty darn sure I
know what it
is and I'm
stoked Skillet tools not just for taking
dabs but also for opening
packages all right we'll put that
down oh
oh
yeah look at
that it's what I'm
saying rare dankness thank you so much
guys seriously that is really really a
nice looking hoodie nice and thick XL I
was worried it was going to be a large
this is the full
size nice looking
hoodie way to get down and
represent yes feels like just yesterday
I was looking at one of my friends
wearing one of these sick hoodies on the
Facebook page there
and I will be proud to wear the rare
dankness definitely was stoked on
puffing your strains def definitely was
stoked on puffing uh that moonshine Haze
and I guess recently you did a new cross
didn't you you did another cross I was
reading about it there and it was what
was it the c99 crossed with the the
Moonshine Haze I can't remember either
way I'm always looking forward to trying
more of your genetics thank you guys so
much thanks Scott thank his wife the
whole rare dankness family and yeah
check out rare dankness for some serious
genetics some serious resin producing
full melt certified
strains and uh yeah maybe we better take
a dab can't just end it with just me
yapping got a little full Mount dry
shift here denail in the Mothership
[Music]
all
right thanks again guys peace
[Music]