[Music]
it's nice and empty right now which is
great because it's usually just super
[ __ ] full we've got the wheat maps
guys representing vex cannabis Endora
can appear
the vegan hot dog stand we got to give
them a shout out because I was so happy
that they had this stand right here
representing
[Music]
the whole Canadian group right here yeah
pound it out what's in the box what do
you think you're fond of course
yeah the ships in the house it's a
little bit dirty a little bit dirty the
whole team representing right now guys
excellent so how's the show going dude
every time I look at you you're
surrounded by 50 people this is the
smallest crowd you've had around you and
it's your family
[Music]
like see people everywhere he looked
around every booth was just stacked
that's sweet so the nutrients are
crushing it
frost you get everyone's loving the Remo
nutrients
please let's see it best nutrients up
good oh yeah beautiful
I can get in there first prize for Remo
that's how he does it all the time he
doesn't bother with their second and
third awesome very cool we're gonna
leave these guys at Remo little sound
bite and keep watch bubbleman for
more.we video peace out guys