hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am on my way to Remo's place this
morning quite excited always excited to
go see Remo obviously uh he's just at
the end of another great run and today
we're mostly excited to go see this
incredible Congo that he's got uh for us
to photograph today I'm basically going
down with my macro
gear I'm going to go and shoot uh
whatever strains he's got left mostly
I'm really going to shoot this congales
it's really the one that we're excited
to uh to see today it's apparently you
know 7 to 10 ft tall as many of Remo's
plants are in this last run if you saw
the teaser video that I showed you
recently so it's uh 6:30 in the morning
pretty bright for 6:30 in the morning I
got my method 7 HPS is on because I'll
tell you I Get Wicked headaches
photographing under those HPS lights um
doesn't take long about an hour an hour
and a half in and I've got a pretty good
size headache so these will eliminate
that opportunity and you know today
actually we're not just filming a video
over Remos but I got some other special
stuff planned for us as well so I won't
ruin the surprise now but uh you'll see
more about that later today so I'll see
you when we get to
Remos hi mountains of the
world deep
valleys flat surface of the
world people
living they're living
[Music]
just stuck where you
are as life goes
by as life goes by
goes
by turn your start
around and get your engine in
gear and leave the stagnant Waters
waterers
behind just leave the
stagnant stagnant Waters
behind Rocka music
rockers
music she New
Horizon New
Horizons see New
Horizon hey guys man here I am over at
rmo the urban Growers and I'm about to
start doing some macro photography but I
figured before I did I'd walk you
through the room real
[Music]
quick all right Rao's just coming
to do some watering
so this is that girl scout cookies
from Hemp Depot it it's looks nothing
like any Girl Scout cookies I've ever
seen but wow is it
dank this is unbelievably dank bro have
stinky in
here oh yeah got
stink absolutely beautiful while you
guys have heard me going on and on and
on every time I come into this room it's
uh it's slightly exciting to say the
least this is another Girl Scout cookies
you can see quite a bit of a difference
on the two sizes between this one and
that
one stuff full of budle goodness
though there we go now we got the right
color it's a little bit hard sometimes
to get the right color
dude it is completely insane what's the
date
today the date is uh oh I I can do this
it is the 14th 14th and I know that
because it was my daughter's birthday
yesterday wow what is this a rock star
ro oh yeah this is the
chemo such a
beautiful wow I can't wait to photograph
this
raino you I really busy haven't be able
to there any leing or
anything normally like take some those
jell Leaf out so ligh the rockar is just
white that is Tricom farming that's some
of the strongest [ __ ] oh you can tell
the resin just
looks completely insane Rockstar chemos
look at this one right here this UNC Cho
this is insane right here look at
purple yeah this is
pretty that's Tricom
City Tricom
City rainow brand nutrients holy
Christ and I'll tell you I never ever
ever get sick of coming into this room
it's just like
basically heaven for a person that is uh
passionate and in love with cannabis um
the way I I absolutely have a passion
for cannabis I'm I've been involved in
the industry for 25 years and uh I'm
telling you in all the 25 years that
I've been doing
this a handful of runs have impressed me
this
much blue cheese I thought that was blue
cheese oh
yeah my God so where where did this one
come from that one there that came from
Jerry
blue cheese real nice color on
that yeah it's the smell you can see the
blue it's just starting kind of Bluey
purple look at this tip see how it's
like
yep just beautiful
and greener
[Music]
[Applause]
pastures seek New
Horizons New
Horizons SE New
Horizons for new just new new and green
up
pastures rockers music will change your
mood rocker music lift you
high rocker music change your
mood rock music Lift You Higher
[Music]
refresh yourself
now and cleaner cleaner
[Music]
cleaner
Waters
Waters listening to the music of
Life you've got to
listen to the
messaging the
music rockers music rockers music
Let It Rock
You music rockers
[Music]
mus big old rock star right
there it's about 7 foot another rock
star over here what's
Tranquility just a nice word L of words
like
that dude it's right on well look at the
plant so how often do you hand water
these bad boys every day every day hand
watered and uh all the water is coming
out of your it's all Rec my fires and my
AC you hear that reclaimed water from
his dehumidifier in his AC he's got a 55
gallon drum in the corner there huge
what how many tons is that system per
how many tons is your air conditioning
uh we got a 5 T and A 4 T we're full 9 t
in here 5 ton and a 4 ton you hear that
a total of nine tons of cooling in this
room and this is
uh this is what you need when you want
to uh you know step your game up to the
next
level this is a great room to grow uh
it's easy to your
results you get great results wow you're
not joking man this really looks
great this is an unbelievably crystally
plant this girl scout cookies I'm I'm
really surprised that the quality of the
resins growing all the way down the fans
oh yeah
it's another big fat girl scout cookies
Bush and then of
course these ridiculous
monsters now what what were these two
again which one that's a girl scout
that's a girl scout as well so this is a
very different feno from the one over
there yeah it's Fox tailing out a little
bit or just bigger buds these ones just
seem to have like buds a size of your
your
forearm look at that yep that's that's
basic
as big as your forearm holy [ __ ] the
lower ones oh yeah this one is
yeah I think they're at the life what
are we at 7 and 1/2 Weeks here 7 weeks 7
weeks my God but with a veg of what
six uh yeah these ones were a little bit
shorter I usually like go two months but
here as you can see all the MS are a
little bit smaller nice so he says he
usually likes to go for 2 months
normally but these plants are a little
bit smaller I guess in a sense they are
but my goodness they're a real nice
smaller oh yeah they're tight and
[Music]
compa well one of the things that I've
always been impressed with uh about rmo
and his ability to grow is that he he he
always constantly takes in strains and
genetics from many different companies
he's not one to shy away from cracking
some seeds and finding a feno and uh
he'll usually do a version of it that is
at least as good as the best version
that you've ever seen if if it's got the
ability with that being said are sure
the con easier your oh there we go so
yeah uh of course Ramo received the
congales a while ago I know that he
likes the strong heavy-hitting uh action
of an indicia for his pain relief but I
just felt like the Congo could use a
place in his garden uh that he would
appreciate the uniqueness of the Exotic
smoke that it had to offer and uh he's
apparently got a monster downstairs so
it's going to be the biggest Congo like
seriously the biggest Congo you've ever
seen in your life it's going to be nuts
you will be impressed I not going to fix
that I just
did I need to do some staking and
pulling in here dude so you you guys
didn't even see that but I basically
just picked up this Bud that is like I
don't know an ounce or something that's
side and it was just hanging down like
this
side we call that Holy Christ
raino oh man that
is going to be all over my camera now so
that's fun what else can we show you
guys here this want to see this water
reclaim system that he's pulling his
water out of perhaps we going to be
careful in here there are plants
everywhere what we got here at UBC no a
rockar what about this guy oh the white
OG there's a little white OG for you
guys white
OG next to a absolutely stunning rock
star now I am just picking any top to
show you guys to give you an idea every
single top is damn near
Perfection no bugs
no mil I mean really it's it is beyond
impressive when you have a grow of this
stature of this quality and it's just
like a machine he just he he rolls it
out much the way like he rolls it up he
rolls it out as almost as fast as he
rolls it out I know that every once in a
while rmo even himself potentially runs
out of herb so this is the importance of
allowing Canadian citizens is to be able
to grow our own medicine can you imagine
the cost to Remo if he had to buy this
much medicine for his head he smokes an
enormous amount of cannabis for pain
relief and to be a to have to buy this
cannabis for $10 to2 a gram would be
completely astronomical I can't even
imagine how much it would
[Music]
cost we got happen here he got all his
names written down on the bottoms of the
uh of the um cans garbage cans and give
give you an idea of the size of the
stocks that he grows Ramos's lower buds
on the bottom of his stocks are bigger
than some
people's bigger buds
well I think I'm going to get to it guys
I'm going to pull out the macro lens and
take a bunch of pictures for the next
couple of hours because I know you guys
love to check out the macro photographs
hopefully we'll have a nice long
slideshow for you guys and judging by
what I can see just with my naked eye
I'm pretty excited about the prospects
of uh photographing this room here so
catch up with you in a bit kind of Cl
like I say is I bring about this music
[Music]
man Royal alongside one
spot stly s oh
yes
again on our bur highest the
highest looking at me eyes so red
because head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke Co
that's why I don't
Grumble
stly yeah oh
[Music]
must be burn like your teeth must be
cleaned rather vital for Spiritual hene
a king Salomon certify the tree and he
is the wisest to we so prop preach her
never Sound True speech so meanwhile the
sound leaders deceive man obligated to
clarify and teach you know
[Music]
from a
friend the
highest just it from the high
[Music]
[Applause]
Earth
[Music]
when you sing on you down you see
me stre my people still paid by Gun Man
and say you are with resources and in
turn showing off your yearly
budget hers
you know
me
[Applause]
[Music]
Ro on the
hers oh yes my
medicine some call it
campy some call call it
weed some call it marijuana marijuana
some call it
herbs some I call it
[Music]
fence
with
Earth strictly
[Music]
right alone
my my life it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
life
we're coming from behind
[Music]
behind you and
warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors tring from
behind dting forward at this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and I come to turn the
table turn the Paradigm around yes
deprogram and
[Music]
reprogram free
mankind spiritual un
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world of
[Music]
spiritual un Warriers dring from
behind ding forward at this
[Music]
time read the mindset of the people
children
true children seeking for the vi the way
to go through I and I come to freedom
freedom with the light in the
[Music]
K Spirit you are
warriors are on a
mission showing the world of
a spirit you un Warriors tring from
behind tring forward at this time
spiritual and
warriors are on a
mission showing the world of
a spirit you un Warriers trotting from
behind trotting forward at this time
[Music]