[Music]
hey guys just about to head into Remo's
room here thought I'd bring you with me
for a little tour got the green light on
I've got the camera set for the right
white balance so the orange should come
through nice and green for you guys I
should warn you
guys this is
incredible
so let me just get these doors all
closed so here we go Remo
style okay so I get to come into a lot
of Grow rooms but I got to tell you
coming into Remo's grow room is unlike
going into any grow room it is so
spectacular I mean look what he's got
right in in the front door here he's got
this incredible shrub like plant
holy really nice smell on that
CT not too sure it's got a lot of the DM
seeds in here um Dino Cham is one I
believe he's got uh
Rockstar potentially a UVC chemo cush an
Amnesia yeah the back rose chemo over
here so let's start out with what we
know which is some purple plants I've
been right in this very spot shooting
with the macro lens
before I'm actually about to get in here
and shoot with my with my macro lens
that's what I'm here to do
today film a couple of small videos with
Remo really spectacular quality on that
as always
Remo just brings the
fire what do we got happening here so
here's the chemo another chemo right
here you can see how big this plant is
pretty decent
size um what do we got over
here got to check
out original Amnesia so this is the
original
Amnesia also from Dinan lot of these
seats came from uh
I believe will pick them up in
Barcelona let's give you a little tour
here here's a rock star from
seed this uh plant is about 7 ft
tall there's a
chemo let's go back and show you that
rock star again I didn't really give you
the closeup on on that
one and then uh is this the Amnesia here
no this is a Dina chem this is the Dina
chem so let's uh let's give that a
little all
right over to the chemo
white OG so these are white ogs right
here the white OG
give you idea on some of the stocks on
these
things that is a big old
stock give you an idea how big these
monsters are they're just
spectacular I can hang out in here
forever so we got a chemo on the left
and a rockar on the right another rockar
from
seed oh that is one big nugget of dank
well I got to tell you guys it is Happy
Happy Times hanging out here in Remo's
room the guy is so good at what he does
he's an inspiration to the Cannabis
community and uh growing out people's
genetics on the regular he doesn't stick
to what he knows he literally will give
what is if something is supposed to be
decent he'll give it a try he'll put it
he'll put his efforts into it and uh
more often than not he'll produce
something uh I mean if I personally was
a breeder I would absolutely want Remo
the urban grower to grow some of my
strengths wow
all right well I can do this all day I'm
going to get to shooting now I think
I've got an hour and a half left I'm
going to be very busy shooting the
macros so why don't you guys puff some
bowls and we'll catch up with the end a
bit look at that stock Dino cam
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with Remo the urban grower and
Swan one of his many cameramen I guess
the main cameraman you seem to be the
he's the guy he's the guy he's the guy
behind the camera and and I just did
wanted to do a short video today on
bringing Remo some gifts so I cut these
out of my garden this morning and we've
got cones sweet skunk and Astro boy wow
so they're all special you know the
sweet skunk I don't have to tell you
anything about that well thank you the
congales is a special strain from Africa
that is very uh wanted and loved by many
um the Astro Boy is a TGA genetic
subcool strain and that is the Apollo 13
male pollen hit a plant which was an
Ortega cross with a c99 wow so it's yeah
it Stacks it's fruity I think you're
really going to like that one
crazy well you know what I've I've grown
this sweet conun before cuz Steve cubby
gave me a cutting of this and it was
unbelievable people used to come up to
me and go what is that it smells
unbelievable it's special and uh I
smoked the congales with Al The
Alchemist and it was outstanding and
yeah all the Alchemist has the congales
so he's uh now you've got the congales
well many many thanks like I will course
the good use I will flower these plants
out and yeah you've got your monster
joint lit I I'm going to hit a little
bit of hash folks sweet some nice clean
clones bug free mold
free just
healthy I use some of my clothing gel on
now yes fruits I use Rainbow's roots on
uh on all my clothes right on I'll have
to give you some
more here
camera well I just spent about two hours
in the garden and it was awesome those
are some big plants eh you got some
Beauties in there thanks I mean my God I
think six varieties we went through six
different kinds of canas you got UBC
chemo yeah Med man's rock star mhm uh
um the white OG from Karma
yeah the dinam dam it's Dam's version of
chem dog the original Amnesia yeah D
them again and didn't they have a third
one that you critical plus critical plus
yeah I get from Dam thank you dam for
the seeds yeah they sure looked great
the resin was stinky and smelly and uh
it was just nice to see a mix of the BC
strains with uh with even some Dutch
Flowers and then you know some of those
Spanish
varieties she make some great medicine
yeah it sure will it sure made some
beautiful photos I'll tell you
ooh double
timing what Sol the stab it's probably
vegan man oh yeah hello totally it's
made with water and ice okay I'll do it
I will volunteer for the dab for the dab
okay all right it's go time people on
the quartz through the Dil with the
Mother
Ship Exodus
[Music]
the urban gr wow man that really takes
your breath away let me tell you props
to the great Gardener that is his half
gy tastes so good that was the stuff you
had in Toronto right absolutely remember
he had special ice packs to keep it cool
yes I lent him some of those ice packs
you're going to need a joint to settle
that tote down I rip my face off
my God I was sweating you just got all
sorts of buds on the table too here
what's what do you got going on here
just stashes of your regular well that's
actually some white OG and then we got
some DM feno number one some critical
plus uh Toronto weed another critical
plus uh Critical Jack oh man you pretty
much have them all right here on display
see what else we got
someo this D cam staffed pretty nicely
and some goo goodness oil check that out
it's made with ISO not butane this is
the hard as The Rock right
yeah like shattered that's some hard as
a rock show that to the camera
absolutely look at this it's golden and
clear look you can see right through it
look at this that's awesome see right
through that
stuff so which one was one of your
favorites out of all these that you grew
I mean I know you love yours but besides
yours did the white G uh the white I've
always liked it it it's unbelievable
weed you can smoke this stuff and it
does not burn you out and it's got a
great flavor it smells like it's strong
it's very strong um from the DM
collection um I really enjoyed din chem
I had this one pheno actually that one
feno that we looked at that's kind of
purple in that room yeah I grew that one
before and it's got a great flavor to it
I photographed that it's real pretty
it's very heavy weed it's right across
the one that's green correct yeah that's
the one that stuff is unbelievable
there's the other feno in there that
makes the bigger Buds and I think uh I
might have some of that left here it's
pretty good but the other one the chunky
one yeah yeah that's that's the one let
me tell you people that's the one
awesome dude well man I'm glad to have
uh been invited over here again get to
uh film in your uh beautiful garden get
to photograph and get to bring you some
uh some gifts thanks for the gifts come
by and photograph anytime you want or if
you just want to come buy a Medicaid
always welcome my my door is always open
to you thanks Remo much appreciated yeah
man thanks for watching Bubble man's
world and uh we'll see you guys later
peace peace out all right so you got the
UBC chemo cush there there it is one of
your favorites correct yeah I went a
cuff last year in Toronto treating
yourself with this one and it took first
place took first place um I got it from
a cutting there's a a legend around this
that it was uh created at UBC for uh
people that are fighting cancer on
chemotherapy and this was supposed to
relieve their symptoms uh whether that's
true or not I have no idea but it has
become one of my favorite medicines for
sure nice packs of punch doesn't it it's
very strong um we've tested it it's
about 24% THC that's definitely up there
and it's very photogenic as oh yeah yeah
it's one of the most photogenic plants
I've shot with my macro lens it creates
a lot of anthocyan in the purpling in
the capitate stocks really all in all
it's just a a super beautiful little
plant and I'm just super stoked to throw
it in my garden so uh thanks again for
uh sharing your time with us Remo not a
problem and we'll uh we'll talk to you
soon enjoy see you guys
later hey yo
B Timber Ro feel good give me
[Music]
a one man homegrown Man real purpose of
the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let
time VI the
time with is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying have been traveling to kingst 20 M
hours sing on like the clock fresh
vegetation with trees and with flowers
[Music]
off big and if bigger Bigg I me
make pass pass
[Music]
pass now before that
off and pass that pass that pass that
now purpose after the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine on the road there
be some cops
up we
me upon your scene to intervene in my
brain St that and behind your
me and my team have another
25 we smoke it up
[Music]
clean my
now pass
[Music]
pass make pass pass pass and then
Go pass pass
[Music]
pass I make pass pass pass
n
[Music]