[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome to an exciting day
of heading over to Remos yes we are in
the truck we're heading over to Remos we
have an absolutely breathtaking Sunrise
happening on the way over to his place
here as I head east on the Trans Canada
heading over to Remo's place I'm excited
I haven't seen Remo in a little
while he's been doing all sorts of
amazing things he's uh started himself a
new company he has himself a new
Warehouse they're doing all sorts of
different um foods and rooting gels and
basically you know he's he's really
taking himself to The Next Step he's no
longer with Advanced Nutrients but he's
sort of on his own and uh just promoting
uh promoting the rean the Remo Urban
grower brand and uh it's always a
pleasure to go see Remo the guys got one
of the nicest Gardens I've ever had the
pleasure of visiting um I'll tell
you it'll be interesting to see what
happens in the future of Canada and the
future of cannabis because uh you know
this guy Remo is going to have a
position in it somewhere
so I guess we will see him soon all
right guys I am here at Remo's office
just chilling out this is usually where
we're puffing bowls and enjoying um you
know the resin that we love so much
Remo's inside the room right now which
is just through this door and another
door and he is watering his plants we
noticed his 5 ton air conditioner had
about 55 gallons of water um
saved up and that's basically when he
realizes it's time to water the plants
so he's in there watering plants I'm
about to go in with my macro lens and
get you guys those photos that you so
crave always a pleasure to photograph at
Remos because the quality of the resin
the quality of the plants and the
quality of the grow is just so on point
that it's just it's comfortable for me
to be in there thank you method sevens
for the HPS glasses the new coups um um
I'm able to close shut off all the fans
so the plants aren't moving and the
temperature remains quite cool I never
get too hot in Remo's rooms nor to his
plants and he never seems to have any
type of nutrient burn whatsoever so I
believe this is one of the first crops
I'll be photographing that was grown
with his new line of nutrients and I'll
let him tell you about that a little bit
uh after I photograph the plants so why
don't we go see what Remo's up
to
always a good idea to have a door
between the
[Music]
door and get the white balance on point
for you
guys so the plants are nice and normal
looking hey yeah I'm going he's a
hardworking man water in my PL yeah
buddy
we're in week six here we're just uh
giving it some water we're
leeching just giving it just a plain
condensate well everything looks
absolutely spectacular as always uh
these are my own nutrients this time you
know I was just saying that on the other
side of the door that this will be the
first time I've actually photographed
using the macro lens plants that have
used your nutrients so that's pretty
exciting the whole line hey oh yeah and
I'm quite satisfied with it um we we've
doing some tweaking on it and I I think
think we got a a product that the public
will be totally happy with I'm happy
with it if I'm happy I know you're going
to be happy well I can say this much
right off the bat that it's definitely
up to par with what I consider you to
produce oh nice just from opening the
door these look
unbelievable healthy zero root uh n Burn
I can see the resin glistening from
here it looks like standard killer stuff
for
sure yeah and I I guess really the best
uh you know better than any machine that
you could buy the bioassay of of Remo
that seems to work actually the first
nutrients have come off for assembly
line I want you to have take home and
grow your plants with it oh that'd be
really cool I do a little for bubble man
I do a little Remo experiment yeah
that'd be awesome dude I'm going to take
these guys for a little walk through
your amazing garden show them a little
bit about what I'm about to get the
macro lens out and then I guess I'll
start doing photos crazy I'm going to
continue watering yes you keep working
buddy back to work all
right Big Unit
there so always just the most ridiculous
quality when it comes to
Remo I mean it might sound like I'm
blowing smoke up his ass but I'm telling
you I've been in a lot of Grow
rooms and the amount of work that goes
into this
one is very
impressive always good for fall colors
that's what I can always guarantee that
I'm going to get when I hit Remo's room
doesn't matter the time of the year
because he controls most of the
variables in the room from the
temperatures to the humidities to how
often the plants are watered to how wet
they stay it all ends up really showing
in the end
product really excited to photograph
these plants because I've never
photographed anything grown with Remo's
nutrients you know it's not just anyone
that can just produce a nutrient company
I mean I'm sure a lot of people think
it's a very simple thing you you get
your NPK but as I was talking to Remo
earlier there are a lot of variations
and there's a lot of different qualities
in the materials that you can use for
nutrients and some companies will cut
corners while others will not so I have
a pretty strong feeling that Remo's
nutrient company will be on the not cut
Corners
list all right so we got oh look at that
already down to the bottom of the
barrel out holy smokes man it's actually
pretty impressive that was a
55gal labor of love
man so I get my workout this is my
Fitness World in here yes
beautiful show a few other strains here
he's got some kushes he's actually
photograph he's over there right now by
an absolute
monster the Girl Scout
cookies
I believe this is a sour
G yeah that's one of the fenos it's uh I
like this one it kind of GRS like an
Inda yeah it's definitely like not the
really stretched out version that uh
kind selections told me about cuz I also
got one from kind selections just one
feno and he said it was very
stretchy smells amazing though it really
does just standing next to it might as
well give it a
little oo yeah that's that's a nice
taste put those method sevens on so I
don't have to uh squint so
much you guys have the natural method
sevens cuz I'm controlling my white
balance right now with the camera so
you're seeing everything as uh under
regular light however HPS lights are
always going to produce this very orange
light so if you want to avoid that slap
on some method
sevens and you will not have that
worry take you over to see this girl
scout cookies cuz she is absolutely
ridiculous so this thing is just bud bud
bud and more bud it's like a wall of Bud
it's kind of ridiculous
actually love that yeah that's
great it's an unbelievable mass of Bud
on this plant
dude yeah I know I like it
too
wow this one I can barely
reach 7 and 1/2 ft tall I would say
what's your roof nine 8T 8 ft so this is
7t
decent resin production too for such a
thing what a wall of
Bud
unbelievable and then next door we have
a little
chemo a sweet sweet
chemo beautiful fall colors on this one
wow
one of the things you can always be most
impressed about is are the tips of his
leaves you don't see the yellow tips
most people will have burn like you
wouldn't believe
but never seen it in Remo's
grow beautiful resin content on that
plant he definitely knows how to grow
vegetative weight but more importantly
he knows how to grow
tricomes as I am completely surrounded
by tricomes right
now all right I can do this all day I'm
going to get taking pictures so you guys
can go a little bit closer and we can
see what's going on on a macro level in
these plants see you
there all right ready now
[Music]
yeah all
right rooted and
grounded are you rooted and
grounded I'm rooted and grounded I take
the time of meditation just Mother
Nature rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and grounded
rooted and grounded the time of
meditation see children children go to
school when you gradated don't TR know
the
rules people people PL
food and if you don't love the
environment you shall surely
lose water shall be one of
commity so we should protect life
entirely yes rooted and
grounded are you rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and grounded I
take the time of meditation to love
other nature rooted and
grounded are you rooted and
ground rooted and grounded I take the
time of meditation City you
lead us lead us Le
the
right
[Music]
fruit bend the tree before
it so the youth can see their
[Music]
go mother care for your father care for
your son
yeah go
[Music]
so we should learn to protect our own
liberty rooted and
grounded get rooted and
grounded I rooted and grounded I time I
meditation nature rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
Ro and grounded time
[Music]
Med you got to learn in
life it's out to love and how to
organiz
yes so no let no one move you when you
know you're doing the
right oh don't let no one fool you when
you standing and
M rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
grounded I rooted and grounded I take
the time of meditation Mother Nature
rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
grounded rooted and grounded the
[Music]
time