[Music]
hey good morning everyone bubble man
here just uh it's about 6:00 in the
morning right now and I'm heading over
to Remos to do some filming and some
puffing today um just got the mother
ship here filled up with the grunge off
and we're just going to do a
quick pouring it back into its own
bottle I love this product wake up in
the
morning I can wake up in the morning and
simply see I don't want to make a big
mess here but I want to share it with
you so I'll just pour that basically
right back into its
bottle try not to leave all of
it little bit to
spillage this stuff is basically
like a natural
cleaner just basically do a quick rinse
through it's going to be extremely soapy
grung off is is is a soapy substance I
think it's using
um he uses a a an enzyme from a soybean
egg but uh basically what it does is it
strips the resin off of the inside of
the pipe and it makes for very easy
cleaning all I'm doing here is rinsing
it out you'll see you get a very very
nice clean piece of glass so this is
what I do every morning this is how I
keep my whips my daily drivers I should
say this is how I keep my daily drivers
clean and just uh yeah nice quick rinse
with hot water and you've got yourself a
beautiful clean
bong I know Remo has no shortage of nice
glass over this place but we figured we
might as
well show up with a nice piece when you
show up
right all right that a little to do
it all right
so clean glass all right so let's take
this piece over to Remos and see what
he's saying this morning right so we got
that Mothership clean as a whistle just
going to put her away in
her little pelan case here I like to
keep everything nice and clean I got my
controller my dnails in
here the quartz whip quartz bowl and my
remote control and last but not
least my
glass so that right there is pretty much
all you
need for denailing
I also have my license in there just in
case I'm pulled over at any point in
time it's nice to have the federal
exemption to show the RCMP that hey it's
okay I'm allowed to have these pounds of
hash all right let's get on the road and
head over to Remo shall we all right
another 6A ammer for the bubble man just
pack up my BS here in the truck and I'm
going to head down and check out
body alcohol can produce longlasting
changes in the neurochemistry of the
brain so this is really
rather because it
has high THC content which is boosted by
being grown
under how many young smokers actually
use is
another it is expensive and the best
estim suggest that
these account for just 50% of the UK
Market 50% of the UK Market
[Music]
CRC
w
CR
[Music]
alcohol produc longting
changes the new chemistry for green so
this is really rather uning have exped
but
goodness because cross high THC content
which is boosted by being grown under
lights how many young smokers actually
use scum is another matter it is
expensive the best estimate suggests
that scum varities account for just 15%
of the UK Market 15% of the UK
[Music]
Market hey Remo how's it going buddy
dude stoked to be back let me tell
you yeah dude
[Music]
hey
buddy at raino the urban Growers uh he's
just in the house grabbing some things
but we're about to have a little session
here we've got the uh denail getting
ready to fire up um a bunch of different
dry sifts Ramos's got his bags of
wonderful
cush stinks right through the bag quads
right there that is uh what I hope the
mmpr grow can produce but that I am
slightly
doubtful so yeah let's get the session
happen welcome to Bon man's world
hanging out with Remo today super stoked
to be here dude um well thanks for
having me on your show too dude you you
had me on mine last time I was here and
that was really fun we got to make that
bubble with those uh I guess we were
using fresh frozen yeah and that was
what the UBC chemo cush that we got a
killer yield of that too actually it was
kind of surprised how we got you know
and it's interesting because I was
talking with um Matt from the great
Gardener recently and we were talking
about the difference between the oil
yields and the bubble yields and people
are always like why does the oil pull
out so much more yield and so he
actually ran fan Leaf through his Bubble
Bags yeah and he got all this hash uh I
guess they're like um um CLE heads that
don't have capitate stocks they just
grow on the leaves the stock tragon the
stock tricomes yeah they're they're
basically real real small little guys
and um he produced a bunch of it it was
the strangest stuff it was definitely
not like you know the real good stuff in
the 90 and 73 bag but uh the it
definitely had medicinals there 100% and
I and if you were to make oil out of it
I.E remove the oils that are in those
little wax membranes you know rather
than the way with the hash you're
smoking the whole wax membrane it seemed
like a lower grade you know what I mean
to a half guy with the oil that will
just get all of that resin out you know
not only the regular heads but in these
these smaller ones as well so here's a
side note for you um remember Jeff Tech
absolutely he uh took a bunch of stocks
he had L over stocks and he's what the
hell sort of my tumbler he tumbled it
and he got hash out it just stock no bu
totally believe it I was I was telling
these guys to do the same thing with
with water cuz they did the family batch
and I said try a stock batch the only
time I ever did it yeah it was the
whitest hash I've ever made really yeah
hands down it was bizarre it was it had
like no chlorophyll in it whatsoever
that it was just this white so here I
want you to push the top button on this
little remote control okay that's the
top button and what that's going to do
is that's going to turn on our denail oo
okay here we go click so that's on wow
just lit up yeah it'll lit up it'll go
off for 1 second and then it'll hit the
temperature and then we'll climb I've
got it set to about 750° f and uh yeah
just stok to have an electric mail
session with uh with rol this thing
looks pretty [ __ ] this thing is
really cool man these guys have done a
great job so it's it's simply put it's
an element you know the Box runs the
temperature it's they've got all these
wonderful components they're not using
the Chinese components anymore they've
got another British component for the
front piece this is going to heat up to
700° at 750 fhe and then I have a quartz
Bowl it's a little bit dirty right now I
usually keep it a little cleaner but
sweet it's machined to fit that pretty
much
perfectly that eats up the quartz to the
right temperature or 7° yeah or whatever
you want 800 900 600 it depends on sort
of your palette and your your flavor but
it's basically a nail that's always on
we don't have to torch so it's ready to
go one after another go all the time
beautiful yeah it's kind of a NE concept
absolutely we're back okay all right
yeah let's see we've got a little bit of
water actually quite a bit of water but
I'm okay with that the mother ship's
kind of a neat piece you know sometimes
I'll put a third of the water a half the
water today we got a lot in so that's
okay well notice there's re diffusion
get lots of bubbles with this prodct
yeah yeah absolutely they've got this
sort of Swiss perk happening which they
call the Fab and usually they blow it
out into an egg and then there's this
little guy right here it's a little puck
yeah and you can kind of see on top well
there's holes in it everywhere it's
etched it's a flower of life laser
etched symbol and that's where the
[Music]
bubbles come out of right out of the top
of that little p per so it's way for
thin dud yeah Mothership these guys are
definitely uh ahead of the game right
now with sort of uh the glass that
they're that they're producing
definitely a ton of talent coming out of
the mothership crew I guess somewhat
local too CU just over the Border just
right over the Border in Bellingham
which is which is nice so I think we're
going to start it off with this this is
some sweet skunk dry sips SM smells like
sweet dude it's 99% gland heads no
Waters touch this hash it's completely
dry and it's the Purity is still uh like
what we like with uh with bubble hat I
remember Steve cubby um he gave me a
cutting to this way back when using
Canada oh yeah and I grew it out and you
know what it was the only sativa that I
really loved growing consistently and I
remember just lighting it up and people
would come you know even if it was a
smoker room they'd come from across the
room and come up to me and go what is
that true oh yeah it cut any smoke any
smell CU it's got such a distinct sweet
such a distinct smell no it's true like
however that came about what I remember
about like just a shorter flowering
sativa that still has that hazy fluffy
look but yet with this sweet I I just
never really tasted a sweet Haze before
you know hazes are usually just pissy
and almost sour yeah but here Let's uh
let's load you up with this so this is
from uh the great Gardener right on
actually I'm going to grab the one more
thing that I sort of forgot over
here which will come in handy for this
which is um a quartz carb cap and that's
when I put the bowl on here you'll see
that it's a little bit there's a lot of
air coming through and I'll just carve
it up like that you'll be able to use
your finger to uh control how much how
much you go you can give it right away
the minute it
sometimes you don't even have to carve
it just a little bit of reduction that
the cap itself gives is
perfect yeah wow flavor flavor City it's
nice to be doing sativa bowls with raino
at what is it 7:30 in the morning right
it's early I've been up for a couple
hours already though you had to be up to
yeah yeah I had to get up pretty early I
mean I wasn't you know working in the
garden like you probably were but uh
pretty nice hey nice little quick rip
flavor flavor
City all right I'm going to Dr one of
those yeah I just went and saw these
guys uh last week over on the island
that was pretty fun we got a nice little
facility going on there doing good
things remember a few years ago they won
a Canabis Cup in
Amsterdam they yeah yeah that was there
which hash was that that they won with I
wonder was that H or D here that was
Stone at the time we went out for the
victory dinner though that was kind of
cool went to a place called
Nomads it was [ __ ]
awesome had um we had uh vegetarian food
and regular food but it was all Middle
Eastern oh nice yeah nice yeah you were
definitely uh you guys were missed this
year it was weird how many people came
up to my booth and were like is Remo
here where's raino yeah like I had quite
a few
people we had important work to do here
we had to you did take care of the
Coalition and make sure we're going to
get this injunction and that's been a
lot of work itself yeah you guys have
you know I give you props there's
definitely only been a real key a small
key group of players that have really
been pushing this injunction and Ramo is
definitely high up on the list along
with Jason Willcox and John Bell and a
whole list of other wonderful people
that are really putting their energies
into
um not just being worried about their
own license but actually being worried
about everyone's license you see even as
it gets closer there's a lot of people
that are just're freaking out we're
freaking out yeah you know what I mean
it's uh I I don't think it's a hard
thing to dis to even discuss when you
consider how much energy people have put
into building themselves a proper
facility um making it safe doing all the
cameras and all the security that Health
Canada requested oh yeah giving our
addresses through all the hoops and we
jumped through all the Hoops we did
everything that we were needed to do and
you know for me I still have faith cuz
it hasn't happened yet I'm I'm pretty I
think we'll get it I think whatever
whether we get it or not I think we
won't stop growing and I don't think
we're all going to be going to jail
either so it's uh yeah that injunction
is what I've got my money on for sure
and uh you want to give them the website
actually where they can go
that's mm Coalition against ral.com
absolutely if you're a Canadian citizen
or even an American or someone else from
around the world that wants to learn
what's going on with us then you can
check out that website and there's a
bunch of different uh discussions and
sort of information that can give you
the updates on uh on what we're going
through here in Canada yeah you know no
we can't lose this battle it's just
ridiculous and you know what's even more
ridiculous is that uh the feds expect us
you know the night before to take all
our weed that we have accumulated and
sitting around destroy it all and start
purchasing the weed the next day that's
makes no sense at all why would you know
I I can't imagine any patient cuz a lot
of them are on fixed incomes taking
perfectly good Canabis and destroying it
or flushing it down the toilet just to
spend their money at $10 or $14 a gram
the very next day that that makes no
that's throwing money down the drain
absolutely and to do the math real quick
of what Ramo just said let's go to a
lower number than uh 122 to $15 a gr
let's say say 10 cuz it's easy for the
math that puts us about 4 uh
4, uh 4 480 bucks 448 G per pound we're
at about 4500 for a pound and now both
Remo and I know how much resin is
actually on that pound you're looking at
between 20 and 30 g m and for $5,000
that's over $100 a gram for resin and
that's diluted on plant matter and
hasn't even been worked off the plant
you have to buy whole plant medicine
from these people they don't even sell
extracts well and it's not going to be
buds it's going to be this ground
irradiated crap it be like buying a
bunch of shap yeah it's uh it's it's
it's definitely I'm praying that it's
just all a nightmare and they just want
these mm licenses in so bad that they've
made this you know these ridiculous um
assumptions as to how reality can can
exist for us which we don't fit in into
this reality that they're trying to
create yeah but you know what I can't
see you know any reason for there to be
um us existing you know producing our
own cannabis and having these commercial
producers as well because not everybody
can grow their Canabis listen I'm 100%
And I get a lot of flack for this
because I post the links I'm 100% for
licensed production facilities I'm just
100% against
exclusive licensed production facilities
no you should be able to grow your own
absolutely if you have the ability
do it absolutely 100% and none of this
grandfathering into everyone has the
right to do it I mean you can Brew your
own beer and you can make your own wine
I'm pretty sure you could probably grow
your own tobacco people just don't
bother because the products that they
have available to them are are good
enough for those people and the small
percentage of people that those products
aren't good enough for they brew and
make their own wine and you know what I
mean like why can't we do the same thing
let us grow our own medicine
also you know one one more side note um
I I think they got to get real with the
pricing because if they don't what's
going to happen is most of these
patients aren't going to be able to
afford your $10 ground stuff and they're
just going to go right back to the
street right back to the black market to
buy their cidis because it'll be cheaper
for them it's true you know they'll be
able to have a better quality life cuz
they have money left over they can't
blow all their money on taxes and high
pric weed and get a bunch of Swag
they'll go to the street and buy a $20
rid for some killer weed cuz I know it's
out there oh yeah oh it is out there for
sure uh it'll be interesting to see
where it goes nonetheless um yeah OG
Kush full m dry SI all right bless
up holy cow you still that whole thing
yeah
wow you never smok cigarettes before did
you never in my life that's it see that
that's Al smoke cigarettes cuz you'll do
bigger Hoots just like bubble man right
it's true and one thing is for sure that
joints are not going to affect that and
I'll bring this back to once again Steve
cubby now I before I met you Steve cubby
you remember how much that guy used to
smoke yeah like it was unbelievable like
he smoked like a pound every week or two
or something it was just insane how much
weed he was smoking and I kind of was
like dude like it can't be good for your
lungs well he I think I smoke more
though I I believe Sooke well he he went
down and did this big test on his lungs
you know where they blow into the
machine and it was at some heavy duty
Clinic down in the US M well the guy's
lungs tested like that of I'm certain it
was like a late 20s healthy men you know
what that is Cubby was in his late 40s
or something at the time but you know
why that is it's not the same as smoking
tobacco even tobacco what it does when
you smoke it you have silic hairs that
help clean out your lungs and those
hairs get paralyzed paral and when you
smoke cannabis uh those those hairs are
still very much active doesn't and when
you cough it's actually a good thing
it's uh forcing that you know that's an
expector totally I mean the real bottom
line is that they spray tobacco with
radium 226 which is a radioactive
nucleotide and we don't put that on
cannabis no tobacco wouldn't be that bad
if they just didn't spray that chemical
on it cuz I have friends in Jamaica that
smoke like the natural stuff doesn't
give me a headache you know when I when
I smell indian spirit or whatever like
those give me a headache they're
cigarettes they're have a filter and
they just it's not real well they got
other chems in there that actually slow
burning they definitely they make it to
go out and all that stuff and it's not
allowed to burn for a certain time my
friends Harvest their tobacco right out
of the for out of the Jungle that's the
way it should be that's 100% the way it
should be so this is from a good friend
d420 K he's up in Prince George yeah and
he's been mastering the art of of dry
sifting I mean uh he's got it down
pretty good so I'll give you a little
rip here I okay bombs away this little
hoochi really feel that reduction it
makes the hit in my opinion easier to
take that was a nice rip oh I'll clear
it up for you
thanks sweet some leftovers so yeah
we're hoping uh to show you a little bit
about what Remo's got going on today and
uh obviously he's always got some fun
things to show us so we'll probably just
continue to smoke a few more bowls I'll
show you my terpinator experiment oh
yeah I want to I want to hear about
terpinator experiment yeah terpinator is
a new product uh I guess Green Planet is
Distributing up here in Canada and uh
yeah supposed to increase not only tpine
production but Tricom and resin
production so I I I'm not sure how but
it if if it can that isn't
unbelievable um statement to make I
agree so we're putting it to the test
yeah 100% what a great thing to put to
the test too if this works this is a
revolution especially for hash makers
you know without growing any more
Canabis you're going to get 20% more
unbeliev and more so than that even like
for me it's like to increase tpine
content or to be able to have any idea
how to manipulate such a thing M tpin
are the modulators of canabo and THC
they offer and create different
perspectives depending on their ratios
and you know where they are in their
life and it's why cannabis can change so
much when you cure it over a long period
of time MH you know get that creeper
sort of weed thing coming on if you've
ever cured I had some ancient hash it
was 13 or 14 years and it was dry sift
wow um from Amsterdam and um that was a
smoke you know the smoke was
absolutely I mean just to be able to
smoke anything that old was special it
was red powder dust so it looked like
nothing I'd ever seen um unfortunately
taste wise it was very stale I guess it
would be after time it was very St
taste-wise but I will say that it was
the first time since probably I was in
high school that I experienced that
creeper effect I hadn't experienced the
creeper effect and I really started
putting it together with you know the
way the tpin when you get get a real
good hit and it grabs you in the throat
like those are tpin that's those are
those volatile oils just grabbing you
and they're they're actually they can
bring canabo into your bloodstream right
through the back of your throat just
from taking one good rip I mean
obviously they get into your lungs and
it goes even quicker into your into your
bloodstream and whatnot but um the fact
that they weren't present they were
almost
gone you take a hit of this hash and it
would be literally 3 4 5 minutes before
you felt the effects of it crazy yeah it
was definitely interesting so we know
that tpin modulate the effects of canono
and THC so being able to increase or
even manipulate the ratios of tpin in
any strain that's why I had to try it I
got a question uh how did they store
that um that hash that you smoke that
was 13 years old like was it vacuum seal
you know what I think I think for quite
a while and I'd have to confirm cuz I
don't want to be disinform
people um that it was in a nitrogen Rich
environment that the oxygen was removed
and it was replaced with nitrogen so
this will preserved for a long time
however I think that was around maybe 10
years and so when I saw it it was 12 or
13 years old had had 2 years I'd say
just inside a small little uh glass case
probably in a cool dark place but
nothing like a refrigerator right um and
it's still around I think now today it
was was made in
1991 holy so there might be a half a
gram or a gram of it but yeah my good
buddy he used to just give me the
tiniest little bit each year that I go
to Amsterdam from like around 11 or 12
to 16 or 17 years old wow yeah it was a
pretty neat experience sounds like it
you know what maybe we will get our
licenses preserved and we won't have to
worry about it anymore we will doing
things like that yeah no think PA I
think they lied to us straight up oh
yeah and exposed us yeah I mean wow I'm
not sure if you guys know this but they
sent out letters to all 30,000 um exemp
or uh people that hold Federal licenses
whether you're a designated grower or a
a person that's possessing it and
growing it yourself they sent us all
letters in big white envelopes with
clear plastic windows huge huge clear
plastic windows that instead of just
showing you know our address in the
corner it showed their full name which
is basically like a medical marijuana
Access
program basically a lot yeah basically
what they did is they told anyone that
could like every mailman every person in
the mail industry that touched or SE had
seen those envelopes they knew that
every one of those addresses either had
cannabis stored there or first responded
with a grow up even better I
corresponded with a grow up so yeah it
was it took me a few days to actually
realize that that happened I was in
disbelief I really was holy [ __ ] let's
just out everyone that was a big screw
up here we
go smoke it up man
nice yeah that one
was the Shish Berry crossed with the
Afghani the
Barb he calls it the Barb funny
name wow does it have that shis Berry
smell of old though you remember this
shis Berry and that's from cash crop k
no I think this original well I you know
what I'd have to ask again originally
Shish Berry was from breeder Steve M um
cash crop Ken um did did use a lot of
the genetics that Steve used so I'm not
too
sure hey how's it going you have a guess
yeah that's okay we're
loose we're
loose all
right back again we've just been hitting
this non-stop think I'm going to roll a
joint yeah you should be rolling a joint
I'm going to uh give you a little hit of
Barb too nice after
uh oh yeah that's sweet it's almost like
catnip
wo wow but none for kitty kitty gets
none Kitty gets none so tell us Remo why
the beard why the beard yeah well notice
you got a beard you know some people get
playoff beards well this is my beard for
the injunction I'm not shaving until we
get the injunction oh I like it I hope I
don't end up looking like a zzy talker
oh my goodness could you imagine 10
years from
now no we're going to get the
injunction if we don't get the
injunction we're going to get something
like it that appeals to us all well if
we don't get the injunction I'll have a
great place to stash does under here
let's put them under my chin yeah there
you go and my beard there you go all
right so another hit of the
Barb barbs
away Cito
Barb got a roll Dy though
did you supercharge it no this is unlet
unlet it that's cool it's early but you
know you know me I'm going to maintain
smoking joints I don't want it become I
don't want joint rolling to be a lost
art yes you will hold it together
absolutely cuz none of the kids don't
want to roll joints they all dab or they
have bombs it's
true make sure you roll a couple joints
a day I'm not saying don't dab or don't
smoke your B do that but it's balance
you got to do both roll a couple joints
a day yeah I haven't rolled a joint in a
long time but um maybe I'll roll one
today oh well we got lots of cannabis
you can select any cannabis you like
nice any I've got like a half a dozen
different kinds of rolling papers to
select from beautiful we'll hook you up
we'll make sure you roll the nicest
joint ever oh stoked the bubble man
joint watch for that video coming soon
to YouTube I'm stoked to uh get into the
garden and check out what we what do you
have flowering in there right now oh we
got a few different varieties um we have
the UB Kemo Kush we have rockstar got
white OG from Cara genetics okay then we
have uh some Kosher Kush from
DNA and what else am I going in there SS
like a nice selection so far oh um blue
cheese which I'm about to SL right now
oh yeah that one had the real sort of
ranky danky smell yeah it grows giant
buds too Dan I was very surprised at how
dense it was actually some of the
biggest buds uh in my garden are going
to be the blue cheese this one your buds
generally are always pretty dense though
all the different strains you show me
have uh that one sort of thing in common
that they're definitely yeah I find the
Kush doesn't really grow giant butts
just really good quality lots of resin
lots of crystals or tricomes yes
excellent crystals tricomes call them
what you what you will but um actually
jod called them something cool the other
day that i' never heard she called them
cannabis heads she's like she said nice
yeah she was like yeah when you're at
when you're isolating those cannabis
heads I was like yeah the
I'm a count of set exactly you are
indeed I think that I might be one as
well yay here's the Cannabis heads
everywhere I will smoke this joint
absolutely and I'm going to have a
couple more rips with Ramo and then
we're going to uh head into the garden
and see what's going on awesome we'll
see you
soon all right so you ready to go back
in or what hell yeah okay let's do it
here we go put sunglasses on it's going
to be bright
welcome
back been waiting for
you really grow right stunning so here
we are in week six of
flour just started to Lee uh going to be
some yellow here and there the purples
just starting to set in just lowered the
temperature in the air conditioner we're
doing a crazy test we're testing that
terpinator product out supposed to
increase your flavonoids terpenoids and
resin content and give you more triones
up to 20% so I'll try anything that'll
do that so this half the room we tried
terpinator on and this half no
terpinator be able to compare the two
plants we're going to get bubble man to
take some closeup photos so you can see
it because apparently there's a physical
difference you can actually physically
see more triphones like a considerable
amount more so we're going to test it
what do you think oh I'm definitely
stoked I mean it's true anything that
can make a claim like that you got to at
least give it a shot yeah no I'm I'm
giving it a fair try for
sure and this already has a lot of
tricomes on
ITC it's got some great purple color
happening lots of
tricomes yeah I'll be coming in here in
a little bit with the macro lens so uh
any any resin any plant you talk about
I'll show a nice macro photograph of the
of the plant you're pointing to cool we
got five different types show you oh
excellent five different kinds today
folks all right so these ones here are
the UBC chemos this whole row is UBC
chemo
[Music]
beautiful half this row is UVC
K the other half
here this is blue cheese oh the blue
cheese look at the buds on it yeah that
is a nice looking plant
lots of Tri cones probably the smelly is
p up out of this room for sure very
chunky I'm going have to give that a
little sniff oh pass the sniff test man
is that
sticky towards the end it servs Go
purple as
well I find the cushion SE purple first
here's a nice cushion look at that maybe
the terpinator is working that looks
like it's rolled in
Sugar you see that
mhm very nice nice resin production and
this is this is a Kush um yeah this is
UBC
chemo and actually this is a perfect
sample two plants cuz they're ruply the
same size they're the same strain
they're in the center of the room so
maybe we'll get you to do the macro
shots and needs to compare the two to
see if we can visibly see more triom
absolutely cuz this one's non-
terpinator and this is Bator right here
and it does look kind of a little more
crystally I think it's a little early at
do have a lot the product
but I'm going to get the maximum
strength 30 MS
excellent and then moving right
along got rockar right
here right here that's the rockar that
is the rockar just back in I half the RO
about a couple extra weeks ago
everything up the front here is a little
more right uh this is white from carage
[Music]
di there's another
rockster at
this she looks beautiful starting to go
purple as
well oh they're all
beautiful jeez and that's really getting
affected by the cold
air and let this one
here this is Kosher Kush ah the kosher
DNA
I'm looking at the CO2 we down to 464
looks like I got to swap that CO2
tank
okay go and get one of those go get a
new CO2 tank yeah but I guess you can
get your lens on and take some macro
phot yeah that's what I'm going to do
for
sure I'm going to slap the macro lens on
this camera and we're going to start
looking at some of these uh resin lands
up
close we'll see you guys soon yeah
see that how's that this guy is a uh
watch sweet kill two birds with one
stone Remo
sweeping sweeping his room with
CO2 some high dis charge right there
holy Moses know what I find is that all
the
little Le yeah just
Dr up on the floor everywhere
see goes up you going to give it another
shout or
what they love it yeah they
do all
right back to photography I am now on
the blue
cheese hey guys bubble man here just uh
doing a little photography macro
photography here in Remo's room
beautiful UVC chemo Cush
um yeah I'll be sharing these photos in
the near near future the thing is
absolutely covered in resin super
beautiful there actually a whole row of
them here behind me um I'm going to
shoot that and then we're going to head
on over and we're going to
shoot um the blue cheese which is over
here this is the blue cheese here this
guy right here absolutely ridiculous
covered in resin completely we're going
to talk about the Rock star we're going
to photograph the rock star another real
beautiful strain bong Guru and then of
course last but certainly not least
we're going to talk about um the Kosher
Kush from DNA genetics this thing looks
like Girl Scout cookies man it is
absolutely Beau beautiful super nice oh
yeah and I better not forget Karma
genetics the Beast back
here I believe this is the white OG and
this thing is uh pretty ridiculous as
well so yeah we're going to have fun
nonetheless I'm in a room full of
monsters I love it this is where I'm the
happiest and uh yeah I'm going to get
back to macro shooting so I can share
the pictures and we'll see you soon on
Bubble man's world yeah welcome back
guys we're going to try this new pulse
rig I just got yesterday oh that's right
that's what we're going to be hitting
nothing is
beautiful it's got this awesome Dabber
here I like the Dabber here let me uh
press up some of this dry SI so we can
actually use the Dabber and right now I
got a Boral silic it down
in I usually use a fumo pipe on there
but if you want to try dabbing of it and
look at this it's got this ledator you
can actually put concentrates or daer on
there so you just go yeah and then we
got the
dome right there that we're going to put
on last but not least last but not least
all right so let's get some Gable
product here well you know what you're
the guest so I'm going to heat it up but
I'm going to let you go for it okay so
there's a there's this I am going to get
the quartz nail it does hold the heat a
little bit longer oh yeah let's see what
uh this isn't hot now is it no actually
I think your quch Bol might fit on this
thing I know I wonder if it would let's
just check it out real quick might be a
little bit warm well usually I can do it
if I I usually like 750° warm well you
do this little trick where you get
holding the bottom quartz is an
unbelievable product mhm this is not hot
this is a little bit hot this is Wicked
hot oh my God so we'll see this isn't
really meant to fit in there but n not
going to do if we had a piece we would
have been able to do it but that's cool
we'll torch the quartz it's still a
quartz Bowl it's just no no it's just a
or it's a little glass bowl it's a Boral
silicate now well no problem we'll hit
the Boral silicate it just doesn't hold
the heat quite the same but you know
what it's equally as clean and that's
what it's all about having a clean to
exactly and really I just want to hit
the pipe and feel the the filtration of
it whatnot oh no this thing's a
Cadillac you're not going to believe I
really um this is my new favorite pipe
I've got tons of dozens of pipes dozens
of bonds and this is it that's a nice
looking piece so let's get the torch and
dab I'll let you take it for a chest
drive I'm going to take uh Remo's new
pipe for a test
drive Paul glass folks
all right so I got
a A little dab of the
Barb for silicate
ribs all the different ways to inhale
the plant we
love you know this is kind of a an
all-around guy Remo when you think about
it cuz he's smoking joints one minute
and the next minute he's doing pretty
much the most upto-date thing that uh
the young people are doing these days
which is taking dabs torching Nails
electric Nails oh yeah you got to
diversify yeah I would like to stay
current I'm the same way so this the
last as you know cools rather quickly so
when I take the torch off I think it's
go time delay yeah I'll just put this
right over it right away yeah you ready
yeah I'm ready okay it's go
time go bubble man go
[Music]
and he puts the reduce around
there right
off what do you think well that was real
nice really a nice clean looking
piece it's got the chandelier diffuser
in the Bott from our family to your
enjoy yeah I like the double shower head
that's a real nice piece and The Taste
was
phenomenal let's uh let's do it again I
think we should this time with you yay
inhaling I will inhale unlike some
president unlike some
presidents yeah
indeed I didn't inhale wow everyone fell
for that one right yeah well you know
what it kind of goes to show you that
those guys can pretty much say anything
people will just swallow it well you
know what if I was President I would
inhale frequently oh my goodness and I
would be a buzz kill about it I'd
legalize that be my platform well I'd
legalize and then I'd quit it seems as
though it's coming you know I mean
that's the one Saving Grace in our
injunction and in our the mmpr change in
licensing is that look at how it's
changing everywhere else legalized in uh
not legalized but definitely Statewide
allowed in in Washington and in
Colorado California's never been too far
behind more and more States putting it
on putting the initiatives on their
ballots to get for uh I've heard Florida
I've heard Michigan I've heard Boston
I've heard New York the ti are changing
all right go give it a
go oh
nice professional to his own pipe oh
that is so smooth it was very smooth
that's what I felt like the the
filtration was so much less than I'm
used to the mother ship has much more
water in it right now and more of a chug
but it's still filtered beautifully it
does it does yeah nice little piece what
else can we smoke in this thing um well
we could smoke some really nice powdered
dry sift cool I wonder if that stuff
will from our grinder would go there I
think to a degree it won't probably
bubble and melt the way we want it to
that's really the ideal situation to get
something that's like extremely clean
like the these two are are 99% just
gland
hits
crazy beat it up
yeah so hopefully we can
[Music]
uh I me I guess we're going to need that
Dome on there it's just going to become
it's going to be a little bit tricky
here here you go put
we turned this into a whole experience
that last so had so much flavor oh
really nice that was uh that bar the
Shish across with that Cy there's
nothing like smoking out of a a clean
rig off of glass
wow full flavor you ready to rock I
guess I'm kind of ready Rock
[Music]
awesome
too
wow yeah people are always asking can
you dab bubble or can you dab dry SI
we're we're hitting bone dry powder and
it's
um it's dabbing yeah and it's not
leaving much residual on the nail at all
pretty clean add a little bit of dust
and blow that off and let's do it again
let's do it again yeah
[Music]
absolutely got some OG
cush oh Jee from Prince George really
with some Prince George yeah come a long
way D 420k we'll give him a shout out
he's just started his YouTube channel
over at d420 K and peace he's making
killer
[Music]
hash come buy a blade sometime he's
going to for sure cool absolutely he's
supposed to be up here in the next month
or
[Music]
so that looks pretty orange I think it
looks great I
[Music]
do here go the all right and
that's oh more than a
lungful was two lungfuls two and a half
even
maybe smooth
s it's sure a nice little piece it
reminds me of the
Toro the big nice big base on that thing
yeah I love that I'll never trip over
actually you mind if I give the people a
closeup oh yeah know not at all I'd say
about 3 4 ft is about as close as you'll
be able to yeah right there I'll take
some photos as well it's really a nice
piece pulse glass I like the uh the
dab the
dab and a
lightsaber that's
cool that is nice there it is there it
is thanks Paul's Glass for the awesome
rig yeah thanks Paul's Glass for the
awesome rig thanks Mothership for this
awesome rig and thank denail for the
electronic
nail awesome endless thanks yeah you
know thank cannabis how about that I got
to take time and good thanks every day
for sure 100% that's one thing they
teach you in
Jamaica give thanks give thanks they're
constantly saying it they're constantly
doing it so
anyway thanks for watching I'm Bubble
Man uran grower we'll see you next time
peace
[Music]
GRE