yes give thanks for Life give thanks for
the timing give thanks for all great
things on earth it is now
a horizontal move in terms of Jamaica
legalizing cannabis and it's a joy for
us to partner with foreign investors
especially from ukan from the bubble
man working together together for get
this thing properly done in our Island
not only it is a great financial benefit
to individuals involved but it brings
forth great financial benefit for people
of the nation which is very and most
important to these people who are here
with us today and rich is just a joy for
be here with yeah it's a joy being here
right now right in a blue M Blue
Mountain right now drinking a little
Jamaican Blue Mountain Cafe you know me
and Mr here and you know our team from
out of Canada you know representing for
the music and the herbs you know good
herbs so say to the fullest because you
see right now you see you know the herbs
right now and the music together you
know it's a great Venture it's a great
development right now because you know
it can only do good for the people you
know I mean physically mentally
spiritually you know because I mean you
know this vibration right now you know
if if right now we have our herb and you
know we have the best one of the best
her the best hers in the world right now
come from right here in King Jamaica
yeah and I mean right now need to be get
out there man you know so a lot of
people can you know get employed and you
know send them skids skids kids to
school and you
know you know create jobs you know the
music likewise said speed you know the
music and the herbs go together you know
a combination brothers and sisters you
know so just one love Vibe and a good
vibes right now you know for real from
from from you from you say from you say
cannabis and you say herb you say reg
music and and rich is all about that
yeah that's why how combination with
each other being being working together
as partners not even no management you
know we we we not really end that aspect
the too tough we love work together as
together as partners and team
team brother love Vibe you know for real
real for real so you know and and and
just like how we work together that's
how with like we and from Canada work
together from Colorado River Rock love
you you see me you guys are do some
tremendous work outside in the world
which we we see it from afar and we
appreciate it and we love it here in
Jamaica everybody loveed the vibe you
know we been out and hopefully we'll go
back out in some fields and you can say
exactly teaching The Growers that that
is that that that's to doubt importantly
to me when the bubble man was out the
him and John teaching people educating
our local farmers and Growers of of the
herb how it can be done with their
knowledge combined with your all
knowledge you know which get a positive
meditation because as you and I know
Peter TSH Bob Mar all of them man you
name it them been singing about this
Richie has was pioneering this movement
as the younger generation of rians who
who at one point in time they wouldn't
play
Marana mus it was
video video because fight that time
nobody would have video it much less
never want play it with you you know we
have to give thanks to irm who go them
way and say play this song the world
need to hear it you know yeah Richie has
been advocate for the herb
since since since
since time until this time you know we a
going to stop right now because you know
that you it's a good thing and it's a
good plant it's a plant where I really
meditate and wonder at times you know
why is it that this plant get so many
fight you know and people fight against
this plant so much we which mean it's
just a herb just like any other else
tree you know just like we have like you
have a lot of herb tree right now in
Jamaica for different different you have
Oliva you know you have many type of
trees Bush you you know as we would call
it but the herbs now you know we we
really wonder why you know people really
fight the herbs so
much we in which mean give us more time
now to look in it and and check and
realize something must good about it
because only the good things are person
would fight against you know rebel
against you know so we get over
understand that you know it's a it's a
plant that you know the king of the
forest you know yeah it's the king of
the forest and is a plant that have a
lot of meaning and and have a lot of use
you know and the more the more I learn
about this plant I learn to know I get
to learn
that it carry this Farm of medicine
within it where which where in which it
heal a lot of people worldwide you know
so I guess probably if them free it up
and Legalize It And thing you know some
of those like um pharmaceutical and all
these things you know have to take them
off the shelf because you know this
would come and Place everything you know
so when you check back now you really
check the measurement and and check
check the ratio of things and get to
over you know that is the reason why
fight against the three so much you know
and then come for find out say we didn't
want human being structure a Canon
system learning all about these things
it really enhance our knowledge to
understand say certain areas of the
plant the troms the canaban Noid the THC
you know where we as Jamaicans and we as
a people as a people need to know about
so we talk about educational aspect
growing and learning about marijuana
from the universities from case come
right back to UI to ncu you know we like
everybody for take it on on the
scientific level and know say there's
great opportunities and there's great
medicinal value for this plant which we
continue to to to hold back even though
there are some some some federal
governments who say here free up we
still having problems yeah you know how
what is free you know what is free to
you so we want to thank the Jamaican
government for make such a positive step
and we hope we trust within within the
Parliament that it will continue to move
forward to where it ought to be yeah for
sure work hard to be you know herb is
not about just smoking herb no it's not
about smoking and smoking and smoking no
her her way beyond that way beyond that
way beyond that I see cancer as Rich
singing song you know we use the herb
for more than one reason reason and I
want to tell you too it's not you know
the music make a whole lot of things you
know shoes said speed soap you know um
roll on you know a whole lot of things
so it's like it serve a whole of
different purposes you know and you
can't we can just name a few but there's
a whole lot of things out there where
which mean you know it have it can use
far you know and it's it's it's it's a
thing that's a meod that that
um we we right now as Jamaican you know
we we definitely we need it we need it
right now to our economy and all these
things right now we need it because you
know we still have to go back again to
you know providing jobs for people
because right now in Jamaica it's really
rough man really rough because I mean
you know the economy is very low
you know and you find that people suffer
yeah right here right now only herbs
can only cannabis can free the GDP
balance of trade you know you know right
now we in a horrible deficit so only the
herbs can create the export increase you
see and if as I'm saying Rich the man
will grow it him get a a donation for
his work inside of the industry seeing
him now turn a trickle down effect him
turn and him decide next room go the
hardware store the hardware store man
send him kids go school so a trickle
down effect and it's great for know why
the Ministers of Jamaica realized that
and step on it in this format you know
and and if we don't do that now with the
right people which is most
important nobody mus just Fe them can
come Jamaica a singer and come grav aous
this movement yes yes we won allow that
a people anymore it have to be real so
as my partner always say you know we
careful of the suits we are the roots
yeah yeah you feel me give thanks man
love that bubble man you know say yeah
we keep that going you feel me so just
an energy there you know energy there
energy it's a good vibe and it's a good
movement you know to see the
ministers you know yeah make a move
towards it you know and we're just
looking right now forward towards it for
the greater part of it right now and you
know until it just fre up you know just
like that and we're in which
mean you know just free up free up man
yeah free up cuz his majesty take it say
couldn't say it any clear right if a
great if a big nation which is a first
world nation think them can do without a
small nation like Jamaica we going to
have problems inside of the world you
know see so we have to come together as
a people to get race class Creed and
color come together in a one Soul one
Harmony for one objective and the
mission is use cannabis for enhance the
welfare of the entire human race yeah
that's what we say at CD c you know see
that's just basically our view you say
of course live Green live live green
yeah perfect love
[Music]