[Music]
well it didn't take long we got these
guys they're here in
Canada dabbing it up flabs in the
house you always see Flav's glass before
you see
flab nice to be here dude so we had a
little Adventure getting you guys here
but you're here yeah thanks to Cuban B
up [ __ ] what the all love all love it's
all love I love you brother for real was
just weird to sit there I hadn't been in
that situation since I was really
young yeah that's too bad well but we
always got hope
we got you now we're in the truck we're
rolling on a little adventure and we're
going to uh we're actually going to get
the boat we figured it's kind of a nice
day it's like almost 20°
C which is I don't know what in American
American I got a button for
that all right well we're going to have
an adventure you guys are we're taking
you guys along with us so uh you'll be
experiencing The Madness of Rick and
Ramone in Vancouver oh yeah on that on
that World Tour Mark you want to dab or
no I know it's oh it's still recording
oh you canb you can un reccord it we got
enough um yeah I should probably have a
little dab so apparently we've been in
this slow ass traffic like how many
hours because this [ __ ] doesn't
know how to dab and drive [ __ ]
[ __ ] totally [ __ ] up bro totally
[ __ ]
up
there you go hey yep there it is I guess
we're all good now the rubber necks are
done that's all they were doing is
slowing down and watching that [ __ ] [ __ ]
yes sir all right so we we've totally
flailed and didn't film any of our last
session it was a good session too we
sublimated we dened wow heavy heavy
session was a great s we LED we bubble
hased down but uh we ended up now we are
on our way we dropped the boat off just
at the house now we are on our way to
Squamish actually we're in Squamish this
is Squamish British beautiful British
Columbia Squamish we're just about to
head up to Squamish downtown and we are
picking up that dirt bike that I went
and got with John the other day in hope
so we're giving you the update we
probably have a little session and a
nice meal try to remember to bring you
guys along with us and uh yeah we're on
our way to get that dirt bike now so
here we go over and
out well you know back again the D
huh
nice get into some trouble with that
yeah oh yeah look at this garage
find oh
boy
[Music]
that's what I'm talking
about this place looks like a lot of fun
this place looks like fun man sweet
right this [ __ ] is crazy yeah yeah I got
one of these bad boys check out
this now this two
man dop bro we got to go out with that
right that's
dope get on there you got that [ __ ]
right there check it out that's you yeah
I got one of
those The
Outlander
what a [ __ ] beast bro so what we
getting just a half a dozen of these
yeah six of these and we
good six of these should we get two
three in yellow get two God we're
obviously joking but uh man I love me
some
toys love me some toys even this thing
looks hella fun just a little single one
it looks fun as [ __ ] it's cool how they
have two different models
mhm the rad
tab seriously that looks fun too though
right there man real fun oh yeah then
they got the ski
dooo and then the new 5 500 that [ __ ] is
sick the middle of the neck oh yeah yeah
yeah all right but you don't have those
I do have some do you I bet you be the
biggest one for youth
[Music]
hel uh service some oil for the old
chain couple
[Music]
tires good Shady Tree Shady Tree we got
the bikes it's time to eat some
[Music]
food oh do I buy
another ticket I'm like no don't buy any
more
tickets up
[ __ ] dabs 12 dabs each dabs dabs each
oh 12 dabs each yeah all right let's
pull over into the dab Corner 100
calories we just fu
dabs dabs dabs
fors time DS der do
DS
DS [ __ ] went we about to get Derby we
all good we're good we're we're good
let's just get out of this spot all
right bro let's do it so here we are
here we are very close to Whistler very
close to Whistler at the Pub we just had
them
wings and some of them things little one
wings that salmon burger was very very
weed way too much food it was good it
was very good time to smoke Shuffle
smoke Shuffle it's now smoke time and
we're going to smoke some Congo or
Kush
Congo I guess you can pull right in
there
interesting that could be the look
some full milk man some full milk Congo
some
Congo just going to
park your I'm just going to park like a
NC you going to park how close to me to
that car am I like I got my whole back
open and everything um you're pretty
damn close yeah you're getting kind of
close how close uh
like
you're that close yeah you're kind of
close crunch that
close D did I i' say you got a body like
like a really not a body like like like
a dead body like a foot cuz there's a
body in the
lake I'll put it
there Squamish
police oh it's integrated police that's
the integrated Police Services man this
was some [ __ ] tightness this is six
sixo parking this is some Charlie Murphy
[ __ ] right here
this guy's going to be
like all right let's get enough how
about the honeybee honeybee and
rain that isone it's a rumble a
rumblebee for those of you that want to
know what we're talking about that's the
rumblebee that is the rumblebee right
there this is a very yellow truck with
like a wasp type bumblebee on the
back derbs it's it's Derby DS Derby it's
Deron all right der Deron is in the
house yeah mhm yeah got everything going
on back there do you need anything we do
we have parchment what do I got in here
parchment I don't know about parchment
got a bubble bag cart a bubble bag
cart um I'm just going to use the Noto
hot side and just like flatten that
I got like
a like a funky funky funky feel tip I
don't know what I'm nice one is it it
nice I like that one I got a
de got a yeah I got a de is it Funky
Field tips are good yeah they're awesome
Nish makes
those for real shout out to Funky Field
tips I like how it says Cypress Hills
Funky Field tips and not be reals funky
you know yes it's pretty cool he gives
them props he does absolutely those
things are pretty pricey though right oh
what they are I mean you know they
should be given to you if you're pretty
cool little product he gave he gave me
this one too he gave me uh give me
two one came in a little case they're
great this the best place to
SM
100% they make for big differ
Cory's actually the one that taught n
how to make them are we heating up that
torch no I'm Patty out some [ __ ] here
let me heat up that
torch I don't I I'll do some torch
heating Tor we got a dab who's up
first your first dab it up do
it dabby dabby
doodle yes here we are in Squamish
Squamish Squamish also called sampton
having little uh having a little truck
session I mean it's such a beautiful
area we could have easily gone to some
epic nature site and got outside and had
a session there but sometimes you got to
Puff in the truck you know pull over on
the side of the road and just do do it
Chu do it right just chove it
up
yep yeah I think
so
durbs it's derb time der
let me see what I got
[Music]
here go oh the little on the goer well
you know what if we don't want to wait
we could just have the two rigs going a
double Derby and it hits like a little
champ I I know that rig it does hit like
a champ do we have that water
in that
awesome this thing takes the smallest
amount of
water this was my Barcelona well not
this year but last year's Barcelona
special is it the good one blend it is
good I got a little good good a little
high on that water shit's so good so
[ __ ] good
[Music]
man
here
con Le and we are smoking some of the
cono the congal Le is very good we like
the Congo it's pretty good the
Congo F you go d right there yeah nice
got the Dabber
all thank you very much
the adabs
are
[Music]
indeed do the light there you go f
second what's up sir
up Tony
yeah Tony
[Music]
Zamboni the Little Flower mate ever see
this little guy
no not
bad this gu's rolling in his caddy it's
it's hot it's good good should
be it happens it
happens it does there's a body in the
lake
oh now there's unicorn Tears On the
Floor very very tasty oh a unicorn tears
y' the Unicorn tears dropped on the
floor
zah need the DBS H I got one here there
you oh you hop some [ __ ]
up I'm on point bro how you roll
man let me just pull some Seven Star up
from [ __ ] side
here it's time for the
seven put that on the hot nail or
[Music]
no