[Music]
hey what's going on everybody welcome to
ball man's world I'm here with Neil
gallant in Montreal Quebec from the
maple butter crew and we are at his
Regardie facility here where he's doing
a bunch of different sort of experiments
using different nutrients and different
lights and I guess today he's gonna walk
us through a little bit of what he's
been doing what he is doing and we're
gonna do macro photographs we're gonna
do full video and you've got one room in
bloom as well correct we have yeah well
two rooms and ones in the first week of
bloom we're gonna go check out under HPS
and then we have a vetting room under a
ceramic metal hot lights and we have a
led room under flowering right now at
the end of flower excellent well I'm
glad I brought multiple pairs of method
sevens so I got my HPS around my neck I
got my LEDs on my face and I didn't
actually bring metal-halide ones but I'm
sure will be a little figurative you
guys have a good amount of these lights
so yeah for those of you that aren't
aware and I'm sure most of you are aware
maple butter has been producing artisan
rosin they produce incredible quality
flowers I did meet Neil through a mutual
friend of ours
however right away we really clicked it
off because Neil and John his partner
are really all about quality they
produce incredible quality resin really
well grown cannabis and it's just they
don't have to brag about it they don't
have to puff up their chests when I saw
their mug for the first time and I saw
their hash and Roz's and I knew right
away that these guys were on points
which is kind of why I'm here today
thanks a lot mark well yeah well thanks
for the intro we had you come out here
today because we've been doing tests for
an LED company based out of Montreal and
we've really surpassed I think all
expectations with these lights we
room that we usually would have had 12
couple ended using about 12,000 watts in
a room with five times eight of AC and
we basically changed that to a 6,000
watts of LEDs so about half the wattage
and we're using about a third of the AC
capacity that we were using before those
are huge numbers for those of you that
run operate larger facilities it might
not mean as much to a small facility but
when you're getting into a much larger
facility those are very substantial
numbers to be able to cut your wattage
in half and even the lights must be a
little bit more comfortable to be
underneath yeah they're definitely not
as strong you don't get that burn in
your neck from the HPS and things like
that when you're in your rooms for long
also you like the buds don't get any
burned from them you can pretty much
stick the bun directly under the light
you'll see stress light stress because
there is intensity but you won't see any
birds the pistol will still be very
white they won't burn at all right so
it's kind of cool at first I was you
know like everybody else you know I know
LED is definitely going to be something
for the future and that we need to look
into I was just not sure in what
companies to look at some of them are
basically replacing let's say does that
run with or by a table so let's say
2,000 watts under a 4x8 of double-ended
they'll replace it with 3000 watts of
LEDs to basically go and get the same
same key ratios in the room so you don't
have to change
you don't have to change but you're not
efficient you're using way more amperage
more you know you're you were using ten
amps before under two lights now you're
using 1314 mm so you're not it kind of
you know it divides the purpose of being
what we're trying to create here so
we're doing this because we want to go
micro that's been our plan all along we
knew that the regulations we're going to
come out eventually they finally did you
guys have a really clean facility I'm
impressed with the SOP that you guys
have sort of incorporated here I've been
through the entire facility so far and
it's just very clean it's very
professionally done you guys have the
smocks and the the booties and the hair
nets and the gloves and pretty much
everything that just needs to be on
point for for a proper facility when
you're growing cannabis you don't want
to be you know growing microbials and
fungi and pathogens you want to make
sure that those problems and it's things
that we know moving on to the future
we're going to have to continue to
really be on point because the this is
gonna be stricter when we're gonna go
micro so we need to adapt ourselves now
before we get to that stage you know
when we get to that micro stage it's not
going to be something new for us that
those things will already be our
standards and so you've been looking at
the LED lights I suspect for a while now
they've been around for what I've had a
few little ones here and there try a few
little tests without you know much
result you know Mitch he's had some the
same LEDs for about seven years and he's
been doing quite well of his and so it's
what really gave me the you know I
really wanted to try it I know that it's
gonna be you know the most efficient way
of growing eventually but it was
financed if we can increase the resin
production which is for me more
importantly than increasing the veg
yield although one could argue that the
to coincide with one another yeah that
when you do increase vegetative yield
generally you should get the greater
surface area and get more resin but I
find that no I find that sometimes
pumping liquid co2 sure it'll get less
THC at the end like often we've seen
rooms where we had no co2 we get less of
a yield much more resin content on the
plants then sometimes with co2 so that's
why we do very mild views of co2 here we
don't you know they get thousands of
1,200 feet hams
we're not pushed public pumping the
rooms too
that's cuz you guys are tracfone farmers
yeah and trichome farmers are focused a
little bit differently than vegetative
you know that sort of prohibition based
model of and when I say that I'm not I'm
not really calling that down I'm just
saying it's where we were stuck we were
kind of segregated into this mentality
of how much can I get and how fast can I
get it and now as things become a lot
looser a lot more legal a lot more
mainstream and men as it become
mainstream it's very it's an incredible
thing how mainstream cannabis is slowly
becoming amongst all the rest of the
population that you know last two years
it's unbelievable hugs become a lot more
you know I thought that's yeah saying
that in Kobach yeah and it's still very
conservative here that's what I'm saying
but we're still you know we're breaking
the boundaries of the year and it's
getting a little bit easier and I mean
for sure there's still people that are
deniers especially here to come back
sure like even the College of Medicine's
that only see Canada is good for about
four or five different they'll eat all
those words they will eat all those
words I love that the bubble bags are
the bridge between us right now yeah in
the background on the camera you all I
we did take those up because you were
coming in we're gonna make me run it
back for sure so I'm looking forward to
doing some macro photographs I'm
definitely looking forward I guess this
kind of will be in a sense a part one
video because we really want to be able
to show you not just what it looks like
in photographs and in video but also the
actual numbers versus what they would
normally get so we'll be able to give
you the vegetative weight of the room
that we're gonna go photograph and video
and then we'll also be able to give you
the resin content ie red cannabinoid
entering content exactly we're gonna
have
tested so we have all the different
rooms are basically going to have
different mother deterrents with the
different tables all have different
spectrums of lighting underneath them so
we're gonna really see if they have
different turkeying developments under
different lights sheriff so that's what
we're gonna have analyzed to really see
which light is that the keys were still
in testing we're still trying to follow
up the right model to be using I'm going
more towards the hybrid models a little
bit of white sandy Fred's mixed together
I find that it's it's the best mix
because you get stronger plants under
those White's they don't fall over as
much and we get those hollow stems or
I'll give you under those deep browser
HBS's interests oh you know like we're
we're trying to build the right recipe
and I think we've done pretty and you
guys are growing exclusively with Canada
nutrients currently at the moment we are
doing kinda nutrients and uh absolute
about this growth
so that was pro right of course of many
of you might remember soil balance pro
pro from past church when he started
when he came on instead of talking about
the different beneficial bacteria for
the plants very cool interesting concept
of collecting these microbes from all
nights together assembling this real big
recipe bearing in your health your
plants healthy and no it works really
well we like kind of nutrients we the
last two years we've pretty much tried
every single nutrients out there we've
stuck the cannon out just because we're
doing more testing on lighting at the
moment so we kind of want to have the
same base thank you so
changing too many very exactly then it
just becomes too many different
variables like you said you can't really
claim anything at that point so we're
pretty much running on counter right now
very base nowhere we don't beat very
high so you know eight nine hundred ppm
that's pretty much it awesome dude well
I'm looking forward to walking through I
know you have some workers in the
background working I guess trimming down
the canopy ah yeah they're pruning in
the HPS room right now I'm pretty thick
so they're doing a little print today
and we'll just walk in the facility and
I'll show you guys around cool well I
didn't bring the camera lens for the HPS
room but I do have my method sevens so
I'll end up taking off my wide-angle
lens and just putting my method sevens
in front of my camera so they can get
that nice clean light rather than that
orange yeah you that would inevitably
come through on the camera which is
really sort of a very powerful way of
showing just how effective the method
seven glasses are when you're in the
room that orange light can really cause
like headaches and discomfort over long
periods of time and you'll just see when
I come in with the camera I'll keep it
orange and then I'll put the glasses
over top of the grow I'm sure many of
you have seen the Instagram shots on
Memphis Evans account but it's
definitely why you'll see everyone in
the room wearing them they are a game
changer when it comes to the growing
for sure and we really love to work with
a method sentence I mean yeah they're
great guy great they're great guys and
the glasses are great so it's alright
cool man well let's go for a little tour
all right I'll do it all right take us
in all right
[Music]
Oh
Kotex y'all UV obly get wha love it that
says UV protection is essential yeah
Reliance anyways
you have some you extra UV lights that
the flowering session that we're gonna
find let's get Matt there's seven here
we have three rooms of the same size
they're about 300 square feet rooms we
have three four and six four by eight
tables on each they're on rollers
[Music]
beautiful nice and smooth yeah well walk
in here
so this is under these double-ended
lights which everybody seems to be
growing under at the moment
it's my first experience with them I
think they're a little intense for the
type of farming that I usually do you
know you definitely feel the heat on
your neck in here and things like that
but the AC works well I mean there's
plants are doing well it's a pretty
comfortable temperature yeah exactly
and what cultivar do we have here this
is all where's my bike so we're doing a
full run of Pike in here
lovely and this is just a weekend yeah
this is about five days in they're just
starting bike sir papa usually 7 to 8
days but I've noticed under the LED
lights which I was very surprised they
actually started popping at about you
know five to six days so I actually got
heads out a little bit faster and also
the plants were not stressed from
transition I went from the ceramic metal
highlights to LEDs and they didn't get
that that transition shock where you
know these got it a little bit of
meaning of the week they're coming back
at the moment but that's what I really I
can notice the differences between the
double n days or the LEDs and things
like that sir in all our rooms we also
have these little antenna things these
are basically monitoring our light
intensity or co2 levels or humidity
levels temperature levels at different
heights so we have light canopy we have
plant canopy and we also do like bottom
canopy at the table so that we really
get the humidity readings and the
temperature readings inside of the plant
canopy not just on the ambien exterior
temperature and what program are you
using for that we're using a service
called a data can and it's somebody that
Robin friend of ours that that's
programming it and does really well
with a few LPS right now to introduce
this system and I mean I really like it
we've got it all apps off we've got our
co2 emitters hooked onto the laptop so
basically we've got all that program
what lights turn on co2 turns on enough
for our readings in our plant canopies
and then we can have the different
readings from the different tables as
well so we're collecting all your data
but more importantly you're able to look
at it in real time anywhere you are
outside of the girl room exactly I get
an email if ever my co2 tank is that
there's something like that temperature
levels I can put you know different
different alerts for different Peaks so
we're saying no a deviation and things
like that exactly so I get them on my
cell phone
great that's amazing look it's not you
know we still hand water we're not doing
any feeding systems at the moment which
that's something we're gonna look into
eventually but we definitely like
working with with cocoa and all our in
all our rooms so
you know we go in there much every two
days the waters plants are very clean
underneath and we're starting to prune
them very important to keep these plants
clean underneath any type a little break
it just really becomes a vector for
contamination for sure for sure and some
things like we do super cropping here so
you can see like we'll have some elbows
on our plants literally like the stoma
technique so instead of no cutting or
plucking our heads we basically just do
a super drop an elbow on our plants get
a few more heads
[Music]
beautiful so yeah it's a nice
comfortable room to be in I love the
even canopy I love that you guys are
collecting your data points you know not
only for the fact that it becomes
important to be able to you know when
you're not feeling comfortable or you've
got that intuitive feeling that you want
to know what's going on in your grow
room what a great way to be able to go
on the boat you showed it to us
yesterday we'll make a little video of
it later where we can show them exactly
all the different graphs and how well it
works and I mean and now we're seeing
like it's all this the peaks and things
like that so like in a room like this we
have five times a day C twelve thousand
watts of double-ended it works good
together but we're definitely not
efficient
you know we're using five tons to blow
this room whereas in the other room
we're having more spikes at the moment
on our data because we have to have a 5
ton AC there and I've been dropping it
down we've been trying to use it as low
as less possible we can but we're using
maybe two tons out of the five and we're
still getting a lot of spikes in the
room
just too big for the for the room that
we're running at the moment the LED is
burnout about 45 degrees Celsius
we want to filter out as many of those
spikes as possible and really not a nice
even exactly so that's what we're
working on and but the other thing is
also to be careful because that first I
kind of got lost in these data graphs
you know you serve you just start
looking at it and you start tweaking
everything in your room and then
everything starts moving sometimes you
have to get lost to be found yeah
exactly and then we started working a
lot with the BPD as well with this I
mean just say the most valuable lessons
you've ever learned from growing was
making mistakes
oh yeah and we've had our fair share of
mistakes well that's why you're a great
grower because the best growers in my
opinion are the ones that have made the
most mistakes well and that's hard for
some people to wrap their heads around
you know but it works for photography
for instruments for everything like the
more errors you make the more
understanding you have richer I mean we
did you know this is our third crop in
this facility you know our first one was
a bus we didn't do very well we tried
about 12 different genetics we had
tested some there was a few that weren't
tested and then one ended up her meeting
at week three right underneath the the
top colas we didn't see it pollinated
and you know [ __ ] us
but you know we turned around and we
made sure not to make that mistake again
[Music]
like the sides look a little bit better
I find at the moment I still have a
little bit of tweaking to do but
definitely looks good how's it going
down there Mitch everything good
[Music]
so you've hooked a little bit out with
the water filtration system water
we're all good team about the experience
so just why forget
better quality tie counts
better fault
clean
beautiful
what he's doing here is a lot of R&amp;D
learning from your mistakes that's how
class you learn from them
how much you can learn two different
angles
over here
[Music]
the challenges every room is different
you know right now we're throwing room
if you like
constantly adjusting ourselves and you
know learning more and more and you know
I think that's what
it's you know learning about all the
different types of lighting and taking
the right decisions well we're gonna go
micro I mean you know we've held out
we haven't wanted to go out to you
because be quite honest we like being
able to
smokin Joe at our facility maybe not in
the room sure you know we do like a
little bit of a say in my opinion is an
extremely important factor that seems to
be getting lost in the lp system Health
Canada's not really allowing for the
importance of I mean of course gas
chromatograph and all these sort of
tests are important but what's more
important when you're building beer when
you're luckier you're gonna you have to
be able to know it's hugely important to
be able to establish profiles is at the
end of the day the computer can tell you
a bunch of things but why don't all the
vineyards have these some machines
testing for terpenes because it's the
palate it's definitely something to
lobby Health Canada for in the sense
that you know maybe not everyone at the
facility is sitting back and puff and
tough all the time but having a cannabis
sommelier having a professional you know
trains olfactory specialists come in and
I think they're gonna have to because
especially with the fact that they're
gonna be allowed to buy from micros now
you know testing one thing but you know
like you can still have
so the thing is going to be is how are
you gonna determine the price of the
cannabis that you're gonna pay her you
know is it ready to grow products like
want to have a micro God
one to see what it brings you what is
the by what's your bio essay what is it
just like does it make your eyes water
collect that Peter toss and baubles
Rastas 170 they said we will meditate a
meditation master
that's existing in today's can dissolve
how big the but how fast while right
yeah how much you get their life no it's
Jerry properly no storing fury and
timing
all the subtle nuances yeah I'll go
through machines call like kind of an
expert because you're looking at
and those little steps make a big
difference when you ignore them along
the way
compared to when you focus on them along
the way to me it's really the difference
between the people who are growing I
guess with the black market we call
quads versus the people that are growing
you know the doubles the dubs
it's like a bad word yeah and the thing
is there's so much of that going around
that the prices are dropping but people
that are still growing quality are still
getting their prices and and that's what
people need to realize it's
put the effort in and you'll get what
you deserve for your product and
you know when people know what you're
growing know the way you're growing you
know people ask for it by name and I
think that's why the micro industry is
gonna have such an impact
we can bring a lot of those three
friends to the legal market
well it's kind of why I've used my brand
in my name which has kind of been
synonymous with quality over the last 20
years teaching people about quality
where I've always gravitated towards
guys like you that are also on the par
so I kind of can give this sort of you
know full melts certification to certain
groups of people that I know are growing
resin that can actually produce you know
melty hashes yeah we're doing pens well
weep strains we're not doing the regular
eight-week strains we're looking at
trichrome development before we are
visiting we're not you know we're not
just thinking at the next paycheck like
you know I know I need money like
everybody else but at the end of the day
we want you know to do something of a
higher quality in the north we want to
stand out err sign
regarding by the moonlight
[Music]
while by now
further this is talking to us about it
and you know there has been a good
flight response that's always smoke
feels
Gracie's feeling because
[Music]
when you're separating
that feeling polyphonically spoke
somewhere else
Hargreaves both lenders evening brought
a and wank
new trends
the Latvian Warner really develop
trichomes
pet hair of the garden or the golden
stress and we think about money yeah
in pension that's the real wimp answer
that yeah there's definitely something
to be said for that the LPS aren't
really focused on that right now but I
think it's the importance and having
groups like you guys in a sense become
LPS or become micro growers and
processors to sort of I think that'll be
the missing link that will really be
able to show these LPS you know you're
not doing everything wrong growing an
incredibly clean crop is important but
there's there's other little aspects
that if you remove probably the process
you won't end up with the same results
[Music]
my fulfillment
for sure great airflow in here you guys
have and then you've got a nice bit you
said you had a five ton in here yeah
five time filter
Municipality wanted to make
ever the power went out that the whole
neighborhood didn't smell so we all
licensed the buyer municipality to do
yeah yeah well I mean they see that you
know we want to go ahead with this we
want to be part of the micro so and
we're working with your municipalities
that want to work with people that you
know want to bring this new business
that their town so awesome well let's
let's go check out another room this is
great see you
[Music]
all right so here we are in one of your
I guess cloning mother bedrooms
[Music]
CMH ceramic fennel highlights we're
using
it's double freaking beautiful we're
actually just using one at the moment
it's been very intense 1 / 1 / hood it's
the red icy ones turned off next one
we've been instructed with the ceiling
try giving them both but use a lot less
lighting they're really intense those
legs very hot as well we're gonna try to
do flowering with them probably soon
enough
none of our next ones
just done more that are coming in soon
so we're gonna change it up here and a
little bit in here in the bet you would
change supply these probably bring it to
Le
because we really like
the way that the LEDs have done the
vegging at the moment most likely going
to change to that this is basically our
badgering order to keep our mothers take
our cuttings here so right now we have a
bunch of players my bikes and apply a
participant baton here
things like that a few genetics that
works running out in the corner so we
have coffee
[Music]
we did warriors rather than just the
trials still testing
next round of mother's milk that we have
is it Oh milk or there's some bikes to
here they're all they're all a little
differently but there are all Mills it's
bad choice and labels you can't take
them up cause I see I see because I saw
a couple UWM bees there yeah so it's a
hundred milks hundred mils where we'll
take 90 of the best ones
if you transplant two greens for flowers
perfect before they start also on tables
nice and easy to move yeah much larger
tables these are 15 we've got two of
these in here pretty easy to work around
I like the handle little steering wheel
there
I've always just used that my hip
all right great well let's go check out
the final room the LED room do it
alright guys so here we are in the LED
room John Neil's partners here with us
as well and we're just gonna talk a
little bit about the difference between
the HPS and the LED that they've seen so
far oh hey guys so yeah welcome to our
LED room as you can see it's doing quite
well at the moment these are the panels
we have they're 200 watt panels we have
mix spectrum on this line here so we
have a row of whites and then the deep
red and then the white this is
definitely the row that we're preferring
at the moment and then we have a row of
all whites the one that you're seeing at
the moment so those are usually more use
under for vegging but we did a test to
do the flowering under them and we saw
the same type of results as you see
under metal highlights so they don't
stretch as much they're a little bit
sure than the other plants but the bud
structure is a little bit tighter the
test is really going to be on the
different turkeying productions and the
resin so we're gonna be able to do all
the different tests we have basically
six tables here we have three tables of
where's my bike three tables of mother's
milk and they're all growing under
different spectrums of LEDs so we're
gonna have a slightly different result
under each table okay can you tell us a
little bit about the company that you're
working with how you came to put these
LED lights in your room over other ones
and what was really the turning point
because it's a lot of it's a big
investment to do R&amp;D for other companies
yeah it is and we've seen quite a few
companies go around
I basically spoke to the two engineers
that design the lights and put them
together and they were talking and what
what they were telling was made a lot of
sense we were basically gonna try to
replicate what you know a thousand watt
bulb did with half the the the wattage
and they said that they had found they
said that the formula the right formula
to do this and they sound pretty
convincing I gave them a try and right
away you know we saw great results from
the beginning of flowering we saw like I
was saying for the the buds I actually
started developing a little bit quicker
a day or two quicker than I was used to
the light transition from ceramic metal
highlights to the led room was it was
perfect there was no stress whatsoever
the plants were always happy and healthy
under the lights seems like they can
even almost grow into the lights you'll
see light stress but you won't see any
temperature like affecting the trichomes
or the pistils they'll still stay white
so it's really interesting and the other
thing is also that these burn at about
45 degrees Celsius as opposed to 750
from a double-ended wolf exactly which
difference in temperature we're using a
third DAC we would have used you know
usually we use a 510 AC in a room this
size with 12,000 watts of double-ended
and now we're using about a 2 tons max a
ton and a half and the mother's milk you
guys have been growing for not as long
as the bike correct we've had it for
about the same amount of time we just
haven't really developed it that much
we've grown it a little bit
it wasn't as popular as the bike so we
didn't give it as much attention
attention
definitely beautified it's it's really
got a nice profile yeah super unique
compared to a lot of things that are out
on the market right now
it's got subtle nuances whereas most
things are either based off of a cushion
it's got the density it's got really
nice structure and I just wonder I guess
when you're doing RMD for a different
light when you're used to HPS what
you're really looking for is an increase
in either your ideally both your resin
and your vegetative yield production for
sure the bikes look huge yeah man they
do and they you know and but normal huge
I mean this is usually like under the
deep breaths is more what you'd see
under an HPS it has a lot of the same
characteristics where you'll have those
those hollow stems you can see now at
the end of flowering the plants are
having a harder time holding themselves
up they're not as as girthy as the the
whites would be or the metal highlights
would be but the the bud structure is
very big I mean we have some coolers in
the back there that are
and so we're definitely seeing the
different traits from the different
types of Lighting's that are very
similar with what we would find some
lark or greater and what was what was
the name of this led company again this
is Eric group a moment or er a group
they're not out on the market at the
moment they'll be shortly I believe on
the market there's a few LPS that are
also looking at these lights so we're
just basically waiting on the numbers
that are gonna come out of this room to
see the grump the grand-père wattage
that we're gonna we're gonna get grandpa
wattage and I guess the first quarter
ticket or the resin meal after or it's
exactly so a percentage you know the
bike we're used to getting a high 20s
high 20% yields and rosin and things
like that so we're definitely going to
like to see if we can still maintain the
same same numbers yeah a hugely valuable
data not only for the LED companies but
for growers as well I mean if you can
use half the average if you can create
less heat if you can use less
air-conditioning
these are all just sustainable concerts
and it seems like the yeah and also like
all the stress that puts on machinery
like you're you're constantly fighting
you know you're fighting heat all the
time in your double-ended rooms look
we've turned everything off in this room
and we're in here talking I mean it's
not getting lauder we're not getting a
burn on our necks the micro molds are
very low compared to what you'd see on W
on
you know over at 384 hundreds we're very
low but yet you know we're getting great
results the resin production looks on
point - to my naked eye I haven't gotten
my macro lens under there yet but it
definitely looks on point in the sense
that the resin is growing up to the
teeth to the tips of the sugar leaves
some of the fat needs themselves are
covered almost to the edges definitely
the milk is is waved like the stems the
fan leaves are growing like full visible
trichomes you can see the heads with the
naked eye trichome goodness and a
wonderful aromatic got a smell in this
room between these two cultivars really
nice great job guys so once again you've
got how many lights total four how many
watts in this particular one so if we
take one table we run five lights of 200
watts under one one table so we're
running a thousand watts under a 4x8
table and you have six of those we have
six of those so running 6,000 watts in
this room at the moment compared to the
other room that runs it
both those not the water and this is
your first grow with these lights is
okay so yeah you've got I like how
you've got a whole row the Reds yo of
the mix and then weights that's a great
way to do it and so we're also gonna
look so when we go for get they're doing
3rds well we're doing one and two like
six at the same time we're gonna have
six different like tables to test so
we're gonna and everything have to get
tested look at the the trichrome not the
track number the terpene productions on
on each light and we're also testing
another light now it's a little UV that
we're adding only at the last four hours
of the day for the last four weeks
growing we're only trying it in one
little section for now but we're
developing a hybrid model of light that
will have like the UV included inside of
it so I just want to stick my face in
these buttons consist this little
melting water and standing at this level
seeing the size of these coal is really
oh really beautiful I want to get in and
photograph some of those they're not
sure account don't you do it but
definitely figure it out these lower
buds will be no problem yeah this one's
we're not the mix spectrum the good
definition of it the ones hanging on the
end is the red that was there they're
just developed
yeah they've got nice shot nice it's
just yeah so I mean all in all before
you harvest before you make pass just
your sort of intuitive feelings you guys
are both pretty happy with what's going
on here yeah I'm very happy very
impressed yeah with the the switch from
being HBS growers and then going into
this LED market where we're gonna be a
little bit more conscious of the energy
we're using here and you know we want to
go the microwave like we've been saying
and so this is really we really do
believe that in the micro it's all gonna
be about efficiency you know we're gonna
be have a very small footprint so it's
all gonna be about being efficient that
you've saved here it's like you could
literally have panels on the side walls
we'll be using we're looking at adding
things like through the canopy and
things like that so I'm having little
lights that are mounted on tripods that
go in the middle of the canopies and you
know without UVs and things like that
but we're looking at a bunch of
different things definitely have plenty
of ideas yeah well I really can't wait
to get the macro lens
here I thank you guys for walking us
through it and yeah this may be next up
will be a little macro photography and
I'll do some nice close-up footage with
the video camera so people can really
get an idea of what's going on in here
great guys thanks thank you
[Music]
Oh
original indigenous here
[Music]
original indigenous here kinda
[Applause]
[Music]
Hey
Oh
[Music]
dear God
you want to hit some foam melt
[Music]
[Applause]
and we're joking when they said the room
is really comfortable the lights are
giving off very little heat whatsoever
the room has really well conditioned air
it's you know for only using two tons of
a five-ton I don't know they've got
about six to eight fans in 806 it's not
the hugest room but they're definitely
doing a good job in cleanliness they're
growing great looking cannabis so far
obviously once I've helped make some
hash out of it and we've squished a
little bit of it that'll be the true
test but overall I'm quite impressed
with this LED room it's you know the LED
lights looks somewhat dated but to me
looks mean nothing when it comes to the
actual production of the lights and what
they're actually pulling off with
they're focused on the engineering of
the lights and the spectrum that to me
is a lot more important than trying to
make something look fancy for a grow
room and it's a great-looking canopy you
know they've got the lights really
packed in nicely and obviously using a
lot less damage is going to be something
that growers are looking more forward to
being able to lower that heat make the
room more
to work in
and be using you know less wattage seems
like a win-win to me
all right so I'm going to get my macro
lens out and do some photography now and
see if we can't get some great resin
photos of the mother's milk as well as
the where is my bike souring so that's
what we're doing next
[Music]
here off camera I've got Stefan to
panfish top Gardens group who has these
guys have been the engineers behind the
LED lights that the maple butter boys
are growing in this R&amp;D room and we've
also got Neil from maple butter and
thank you for being here today Stefan
thank you
yeah absolutely you know only had the
last 24 hours or so to sort of be in and
around these lights but I have to say
even just from turning off all the fans
and all the a/c about 10 or 15 minutes
ago and kind of getting caught up
talking outside of the room when we came
in it was a real joy to not just be
smacked with that HPS heat and lighting
spectrum that tends to give me migraine
headaches so I guess I'll start with a
quick question
give us a little bit about your
background a little bit about how you go
on into LED lighting and and maybe how
it translated into cannabis growing
absolutely so again thanks for having me
and I want to thank Neil and John for
the opportunity we my team that is have
been in the LED business for better part
about 15 20 years so we started off way
back what we call the white space and
that space has evolved dramatically and
when we see white spaces general
lighting that space has evolved
dramatically over that period of time
and now we fall antenna purposes have
been focusing our time and energy will
last eight years in the order culture
business what we brought to bear was
essentially what I call the
collaboration between experts in the LED
business ourselves universities and also
commercial growers what we wanted to do
is make sure that we did not develop
products sort of in a vacuum and
ultimately take feedback from people in
multiple different industries in order
to develop a product line of agriculture
fixtures that we think will deliver on
the promise and that's what we see here
essentially with the help of Neil and
John who have been growing under our LED
lights we definitely see first and the
results are very happy with that and
I'll certain that Neil talk about this
is feedback or is experience so far
we've been in this for how many weeks
now we're in the ninth week right now
flowering and
yeah I mean from day one you know it was
definitely a little bit of a leap of
faith but if I had the right points you
know we we dropped the wattage in the
room drastically like half what we would
have usually had and we changed a little
bit our ways of growing so like upped
our temperatures a little bit and
started playing a little bit more with
the BPD and then we really started
getting a you know really nice results
from the beginning we have no stress
from transition lighting from vegging to
flowering no overall a really nice great
product
well the bikes look absolutely
phenomenal not to say that the mother
milks don't but just from the
perspective of these giants you know arm
sized buds i years ago would have never
thought that that was possible under LED
lighting and i'm quite certain that you
know not too many years ago you could
have grown these plants taking the LED
lights out put the HP SS underneath and
just told people yeah this is an HP s
garden you know you can't do this with
LED you could literally trick people the
buds are huge and more importantly
obviously vegetative yield is huge to
all sorts of growers but for me it's the
resin content and these things seem to
be on point for how sticky they are how
much the room smells terpene profile
being profile is definitely really nice
because we have they don't see any heat
stress on the plants whatsoever these
burn at 45 degrees Celsius I believe
with no 8 c7
literally there's no real risk of
damaging a crop with these we're using
1/3 the AC capacity and half the wattage
in the room so I mean it's it's it's
really a good great gain of efficiency
in growing under these lights and so
what were some of the key things Stephan
for the development of these particular
lights the shape and the sizes the
strips the lights used like what were
some key things that led you to create
this particular design with the white
and the red so again we've been at this
for about eight years
and one of the thing that we we've been
constantly looking at as you pointed out
is you would have never thought this
possible a few years back and indeed it
was not really possible because the
technology was not there yet it was not
ready for primetime so to speak
there's been a big evolution in the LED
industry especially for the culture in
terms of combining different types of
technologies and different colors from
Ligeti but also for light output and
especially in the work culture business
in terms of micromo production for the
plants that is so what we looked at that
we wanted to take a different approach
because again through our experience in
feedback that we've received typically
under HBS you have that one point source
or one light source that emits a lot of
infrared energy a lot of light
essentially but LEDs it's very different
and we wanted to have a more of a
distributed approach more of a canopy
approach essentially giving the ability
as Neil pointed out that you could
actually take your lights and bring them
down as close to as possible to the
canopy in fact our lights will go as low
as you know no no space whatsoever so
you let the plants go into into the
lights some of the feedback that we've
received and through our own experience
also over time as we understand one
thing if you go back in time with in the
white space moving parts or mechanical
parts was
she looked at a look at or pawn as a
failure mechanism over time so that's
why what you see with these lights the
rug it that was the intent for growers
their waterproof there's no moving parts
there's no fans so as Nell pointed out
is over temperature these lights will
not go very high in temperature and
they've been designed that way to
maintain a certain level of temperature
so in this space you feel very
comfortable very well and working under
the LED lights the other thing too is we
took percussion in terms of our IP in
the distributed fashion so you asked
about the two different products that we
have we have one that's called super
grill which is more of this white
whitish with a very special spectrum
distribution and the other one is more
of a distributed with a little bit more
red or what we call deep red which
facilitates growth from from experiences
and also tests that we ran we're also in
the process of introducing these are 200
watts fixtures and people sometimes a
surprise saying 200 watts yeah well with
combination so to replace a thousand
watt you'll go with 600 watts
essentially so again there's economies
of scale when you do that here we went
500 cut but we're gonna go a little bit
more under the hybrid model that's
correct so let's Neil pointed out we
have a hybrid model that's going to be
released here very shortly it's a
combination of both from a special
distribution but also ant in the the
wattage so we're moving from 200 to 300
watts so the idea is that you combine
two which essentially becomes a four by
four grid essentially to replace a
thousand watts
give or take and then can you tell us a
little bit about the differences between
the plastics that are
shielding these both the white and the
red I know this one is opaque yes and
one is clear so it's very good question
so the one that's clear it's because of
the spectral distribution so because
it's all white of the same color recipe
so to speak you don't have to diffuse
the light because the light that's
emitted is uniform across the board on
the other one if we open it up and see
that we have different LEDs some are
white some are red so in order not to
have what we call shadow on the plan
because of the two LEDs we've designed a
diffuser that diffuses the light
spectrum completely so give you a very
uniform across the entire fixture a
uniform light spectrum distribution it's
holding it pretty solid like I'm not I'm
not completely understanding all the
science behind lighting I've looked into
it a little bit over the years from
metal halide to HPS to LED but obviously
there's a substantial difference between
the red and and the light that's correct
and what you would see again if you go
back to HPS there's different spikes if
you look at the latest distribution our
spectral distribution there are certain
spikes of what we call light-emitting so
essentially the the the frequency at
which you know different colors are
being emitted in this case what we
wanted to do is ensure again that we
have a uniform distribution and a
spectral distribution that provides
either more deep breath in the case of
the fixture what we call the new mega
bloom and a little bit less in this case
at a super go and it all depends on the
grower and we keep on saying that we
would never do this with other growers
obviously the rows know how to grow
their crop pharrell we're here to
facilitate we're here to help in a
process well the these growers know how
to
their crops really absolutely I get to
photograph a lot of different groves and
do videos and a lot of different growers
this one's really really well done I
love the way they've taken you know
almost I mean obviously it's a cm PR
it's legal but it's also I still use the
term where you've kind of you're going
from that black market to that legal
market and these guys have done an
incredible jump in producing like a
really professional room for you to be
able to hang these these LED lights in
and it's amazing I have to say to watch
both of you stand under the lights like
less than six inches and not be sweating
and hot and uncomfortable that's the
point I want to make is definitely again
we definitely want to thank Neil and
John because we've done a number of
these installations so far and we always
typically put them at the top of the
list of what we call attention to
details mm-hmm and and what Neil
mentioned before is there's a little
paradigm shift when you go from HPS to
LEDs and that's critical for people to
understand is that you you need to
monitor obviously the environment and
growers know that what you need to do
differently under LEDs to some extent
increase the temperature manage humidity
a little bit differently and results
there too well especially because when
you have someone like Neil and John able
to show the proof of concept of the
lights then when people fail themselves
and blame the lights you're able to say
well we know that this is is possible so
and most people it's very much a human
trait they do it with my product oh I
you know I made some bubble and I put it
in the bags and it just didn't come out
it's like well that's not the bags
falling it's actually Broward who did
that wrong so having the proof of
concept to be able to show you know the
quality and it's really I mean these are
some serious nuggets you know the bikes
look to me like an old-school late 80s
Early 90s cannabis cultivar just the
formation of the buds this big and then
you've got over here the sort of newer
sort of calyx stacked fox tail Mother's
Milk which is just I mean they both look
except the resin is super resin is ya
know and they're gonna have weight you
know they're dense that's the other
thing with with LEDs you know is you'll
get you know this it looks like it's big
with them when you dry them you don't
get that dense weight where these
definitely look dense at the stake
everything falling it's a nice it's a
nice growth and so what's the future for
er a lighting are you guys looking to
fill up some LPS are you looking to do
like additional lighting and greenhouses
like what all of the above I would say
at this point in time we have a number
of installations underway the idea was
all along to prove a point which is as
you pointed out this works there's been
a lot of bad press in the industry about
LEDs and that the market is very open
right now so there's multiple different
entrance which is fine I think that's
going to allow the industry to evolve
what we wanted to do is very we're very
close and we want to continue that we're
very closely with growers because they
know how to grow their plants best but
then again like I said we're here to
facilitate so the next steps really are
working with LPS there's a big push for
micro RPS in Canada so we have a
presence both in Canada in the US and
we have big plans awesome very cool it's
a yeah it's absolutely impressive what
you guys have done here all together
thank you the lights look great I love
the way they really create a full canopy
there's no real breaks or spaces and
lights just likes where the efficiency
also comes in right like every square
and just full is really filled out so
that's where you get your efficiency you
know having a small high-powered unit
you know has to dissipate as good a job
as well you know what it's just as
important for the small-time grower as
it is for the large time grower
obviously for the fallen small-time
grower who doesn't have a lot of room
and a lot of space and air air
circulation is always a problem being
able to bring the temperature down this
much is very substantial but also on a
large scale I mean using half the
wattage using half the AC reducing your
footprint by such a large amount is is
it's a game changer really yeah and I'm
really looking like I'm gonna have a you
know equal equal crop as I would have
under HBS's well I'm glad you said that
because this will definitely be a
two-part video I'm not sure how we'll do
the second part but I definitely want to
get the numbers from you in respect to
the vegetative yields versus the normal
vegetative yields grown under HBS and
then of course from the bubble man's
perspective most importantly the resin
content the cannabinoid and terpene
profile it's great that it's two
cultivars that you've been growing for
some time the bite is tried and true
when done properly you know the bike can
produce 28 percent plus returns on on
rosin and
oil so we headed up to 32.7 on the first
restaurant eh oh so excellent well it'll
be great to see that we'll do you know a
second part video even if I have to get
you guys filming some squishes and maybe
some water hash making we definitely
want to show the the resin content and
of course I'll be photographing the grow
still with my macro lens so during this
video you guys will also be seen what
the resin looks like growing under these
LED lights it is just a pleasure to be
in here awesome guys well thanks Stefan
for sharing your time with us I
definitely think that in the future it
would be great to do a hash Church
episode on maybe the future of growing
where we get the tissue culture guys
where we get the LED light guys have you
guys come in have John and Neil come in
the growers have some extractors come in
and just talk about this from all the
different perspectives of growing
cannabis because I think I think it's
it's a big game-changer and I'm
obviously we've all been hearing about
LED lights for a long time and people
have been you know just as excited as I
am now five years ago but it wasn't
there the results weren't there and this
to me
looks like there was
they're here awesome thanks guys thank
you
[Music]
the old blood medicine
Oh