going on YouTube bubbleman here just one
of my last days in Amsterdam and I
thought I would go live yes I am live
look at that just riding my bike through
Amsterdam here having a very nice time
it's a beautiful beautiful day and just
on my way to go see a friend figured I
would tell you guys a little bit about
my new online course for those of you
that haven't seen I'm doing a solvent
las' extraction course in conjunction
with ganja talks the free four-part
series is already up actually and we're
gonna be doing a more in-depth version
of the course here soon where we are
it's going to be an actual pay course
and so oh no - the next one the new
market alright following my friend right
now is a little bit chaotic as I'm
driving a bike to your Amsterdam and
there's cars and people everywhere can
you talk about the misconception of
cannabis psychosis well um that's a
difficult one you know I used to have a
roommate who you know truly was probably
cannabis wasn't for him and I think it
really opened a little bit of that
misconception up in him I had never seen
it before but I think cannabis is an
amazing substance but you have to
understand there's so many people in the
world but there's always gonna be
someone who it affects in a way that is
not so positive quick little change of
hands are kind of sketchy I got 20
people watching live but really what I
want to talk to you today is the course
so my bio on Instagram has to go to go
follow me on instagram at bc bubbleman
in my bio there's a link into the
cannabis ganja talks University your
ganja tux solvent list extraction course
and basically the first four videos were
oh the next chat past church I'm hoping
on Sunday but the first four videos that
I did were basically free I did four
modules I talked about the different
types of glandular trichomes I spoke
about water extraction and freezing the
wax membrane and isolating glandular
trichomes to a 99.9% purity I spoke
about dry sifting the mechanical screen
separation of using different sized
screens carding a little bit about the
DVD static tech and then I talked about
rosin as well and I went in depth to
moisture content flour versus hash
played speed to temp different units
that can be used to process and you know
it was free course so I didn't go as
deep as I could have but the reception
was so good to the course that we
decided to do a much more in-depth
course and I guess that's going to take
a lot more of my time up so we decided
to make a pay course the team I'm
working with has been incredibly
professional they put together a really
great course and I'm gonna be the
professor for that course it's gonna be
an online course there's gonna be three
modules bubble hash dry sift and rosin
is it clean that's great to hear
we are just riding you can see where I
am right now that's kind of crazy
because they're seeing everything that's
going by but you're not really catching
oh good Joel good I hope that I hope
that it's wow look for the price that it
is for 249 bucks you're absolutely going
to get your money's worth there's going
to be a certificate in the end so you'd
be certified as the bubble man solvent
list extraction courses is completed and
I'm also going to have coupons for some
of the different tools that we'll be
using from the bubble bags the bubble
now is the mechanical screens the rosin
presses either sasquatch or peer
pressure I don't want to be able to give
you guys discounts on some of these
units so when you pick up this
information and you learn it you want to
apply it and this will be variable
pliable information you'll be able to
start a company based on the information
I'm going to share for you for a measly
249 bucks I think it'll be well worth it
and well priced
and I'm looking really forward to it so
you guys have any questions at all about
it or anything else for that matter feel
free to ask because here we are this is
great we have to go way over what bridge
it's closed oh we're doing a Yui the
bridge was just closed and now it's open
I just about got squashed by an
ambulance
I'd be careful OOP
got to be careful
Yeah right so I'm going over this cool
little bridge right now that was really
[ __ ] cool
keep up got to keep up super stoked
gonna see the skunk man today let me see
Rob Clark today and I'll be seen soma
I've seen Rick delici I just love coming
to Amsterdam it's been a long time since
I actually spent some time here and it's
just a beautiful city you know and it
helps obviously when you have friends
and you know the city really well I've
been coming here of course for 23 years
so I've gotten to know it pretty well
over the last few years
funny to see such a small group of
people that it must be three or four in
the morning back home in Canada right
now cuz it's I don't know 11 10:30 a.m.
here in Amsterdam we've got a bit of a
hill here not a bit of a hill pump those
legs in pump it I got my buddy in front
of me Ian Davidson from Segre a pretty
awesome organic farmer and a great guy
all in all been working with him with
with the segre team for the last six to
eight months and it's just been a
wonderful journey they're all great
people and they have a really really
solid business plan to bring tissue
culture to the cannabis industry and a
very precise professional method of
manner that will it'll probably change
the game alright Norwegian frog hey I'm
gonna change hands again whoo spikes are
not that easy to drive without hands oh
it's just 1:18 in California that's why
I do need my KTM mmhmm Vondelpark
BlueTEC centrum all right so we're
probably gonna be crossing over this is
a big old Street right here Centrum
here we go oh we're going right through
where's my bike yes exactly
found it let's just hope it I'll smack
him but well that's because I wanted you
guys to come with me I wanted to talk
about this course that I'm doing and
share with you a little bit of the
beauty of Amsterdam as we bike through
mind your step mind your step there's
some houseboats over there 2:20 a.m. in
Edmonton well thanks for joining me
everyone we got 52 live viewers right
now and that's really cool does anyone
have any questions about the course or
anything else that you want to ask me
the course so I'll tell you something if
you don't of course I've consumed today
are you kidding me the course is going
to not only have three modules bubble
hash dry sift and rosin but it's going
to have four videos in each module and
then it's also going to have a live
demonstration video where I'll be doing
the process for the particular
particular module and you'll be able to
watch live and ask questions and have
your questions answered I have been to
the green house coffee shop took my
friend there on day one we didn't
actually purchase anything I'm pretty
connected here in Amsterdam and don't
really purchase from coffee shops but I
had to go show them it's a lovely little
lovely little shop no unfortunately I'm
not able to share tech that's not my
tech but see if I can break here and
actually stop Oh what do you think of
them apples Ian this place is amazing
it's pretty good right I don't want to
leave we're just cruising I thought
already way I thought Aurora was already
leaving the tissue culture method well I
don't think that they're leaving the
tissue culture method I think they're
going to be doing it through their new
partnership with the nandi labs and one
of the things that Andy offers is
cleaning up genetics but Sega is a
little bit different in the sense that
they have an incredible multiplication
rate and they have a molecular biology
lab that's been standardized through the
use of hops a plant that has had tens of
millions of dollars spent on it for the
genome so they're doing things they're
really specializing on tissue culture
and not doing a lot of else what's going
on wrong crush
love it it's fun having you guys here
with me what's that big u-turn all right
we're doing a u-turn I'm letting a and
navigate and he's never been to
Amsterdam before so this is awesome
and we're on the bike path going the
wrong way so here we go here we go nice
and tight
you must welcome I'm really excited to
be working with the ganja tox team
they're very professional you guys are
gonna get a certificate when you take
the bubble and course the solvent
extraction course when we finish you get
a nice certificate for that and you'll
have a lot of knowledge like I said
earlier you'll really be able to apply
this knowledge potentially start your
own extraction company and of course as
always I'll be answering questions on
every aspect of all of the processes
we're tight here we're tight here
whoo-hoo-hoo that was tight that was
tight very good 73 in the room where can
we get on the course okay I should know
the website off by heart
it's like solvent list extraction course
calm or something but if you go to my bc
bubbleman Instagram account and you look
in the bio in the bio he's the website
address sorry I ate mushrooms but how
much I don't know how much up mushrooms
you ate get on the right side there
buddy
how did you take the course oh you go
sign up on the website so go to I'll put
it in the comments of this video but if
you want to right now go to BC bubbleman
on Instagram look in my bio on my front
page and you'll see the website for the
course I should know the website for the
course but I'm focused on different
things
all right we're going left here let's do
it
man whoo stat okay this is not where I
thought we were going but that's okay oh
we've gotten here only brought 74 people
with us so what is it 176 or something
yeah but I don't see one it's back this
way oh yeah we are I think we are here
yeah yeah this is this is I know where
we are I know where we are
everyone knows vision grows the best
herb we love visions are absolutely love
visions are yeah I know where I'm going
this is my friend's house all right well
we are going to let you go now as we
just got here but have a great day
everybody and thanks for coming on this
beautiful bike ride throw down sit down
it was a blast find a nice little spot
to lock up our bike there we go I'm
gonna lock it to mine all right
there we go boom awesome guys thanks for
coming on and I'll do my best to do
another little video and I will put the
direct link in the chat jewel right away
oh oh I'll do it what is the direct link
just tell me you can't do it with spaces
the wake and cycling exactly random
Dutch Dean in the background with smoke
I got the button shirt [ __ ]
everywhere you go the [ __ ] is under
construction Aloha reg 4:20 good to see
you
endeavours [ __ ] the world free the weed
whatever you want to whatever you
whatever FTW stands for for you oh ok
we'll need this you sure you don't want
to do mine up against the thing there I
think so awesome for the win
well I guess we should yeah I was just
gonna say time for ok solvent list
extraction course.com perfect thanks so
much Joel that's very helpful of you
selfless extraction course.com and I got
my little vaporizer here
yummy
oh so good there you go have a rip with
the youtubers you guys can check these
guys out at segments err national int L
calm you can learn a little bit about
tissue culture see where the cannabis
industry is headed catching up to the
rest of the plants that are out there
considering every other seemingly
clonally produced plant on a mass scale
uses tissue culture
why wouldn't cannabis futures here
futures here peace out everybody