[Music]
so John where are we bud we're we're in
the back of a rick shop you need a
lighter for that I'm I'm thinking I
might have one yeah I don't have one
anyway yes we are in the back of the
Rickshaw we're in Amsterdam we're in Dam
square right now and we are just heading
over to
SAS so this is sometimes a nice way to
travel when you're in Amsterdam you
don't always have to take a cab you
don't always have to get your own bike
sometimes it's nice to uh yeah you can
puff tough John's puffing it up in here
great birthday day I'm enjoying myself
can't get any better than this yes
enrio enri our good friend enrio the
sublimator we're at Square yes hey woo
we got bubble man back there right on
enrio way all right enrio is making his
own YouTube video so we just caught a
little bit of
that SI is this
huh I just I feel that this is better
than a c oh I'm I'm loving
it I'm puffing I'm
[Music]
going all right so yeah this what I
wanted to do on my stuff like this stuff
like this exactly stuff like this I
don't want to yeah this is what I want
to
do old Amsterdam heading over to
SAS all right so we'll be at s soon
sweet we're going to uh smoke some
bubbles maybe get sublimating on some
Amnesia Haze and we'll uh we'll catch a
clip when we're
[Music]
there
here's
bubble having a great
time what's up you
keep it's great to hear enrio in the
background doing his
video Yeah sub
culture right on awesome good
fun this is a nice
uh the hotel
europ nice fancy
place coming around into
the flower
market
nice GE again
yep
damn we got to come back next time and
get a bong in here John we need a bong
we need a bong so our neck Rickshaw our
next Rickshaw will involve a bong some
beeline and a lighter some full Mount of
course all right running red light yeah
got to love it okay SS good and we're
here pretty much here
oh they're working right across the to
of what's
[Music]
that look whoa just opened up
good okay it's coming up
here eight I think it's 10 this one
right here right here right here stop st
stop he it's there no no but we're not
going there we're going to the apartment
behind you on this side right here right
here yeah yeah
awesome high five that was awesome dude
yeah
on