hey how's it going guys welcome back to
Bubble man's world flab just stopped by
and brought this little beauty probably
have seen it on his Instagram feed this
is a new little bubbler from Marcel I
guess him and flab have been talking and
coming up with cool Concepts and ideas
and basically from those conversations
Marcel created this beautiful little
piece um yeah it's got the little 10 mil
Bowl on
it nice little
Dome and I've got my dab all ready just
a matter of heating up the nail real
quick which is always quick with the 10
mil it doesn't take very long to heat
this little guy
up and uh yeah we do a little
dab Sweet Love hitting new Marcels uh
whether it's a giant crazy you know
Singularity or the buck angler or any of
the ridiculous Marcel pieces or even
just a tiny little you know beautiful
simple art piece like this I personally
love the small
pieces
small
piece big
hit thanks for watching Bubble man's
world