[Music]
how's it going guys bubble man here with
Andrew from sample automation he flew
out from uh Massachusetts New Hampshire
Massachusetts New Hampshire
Massachusetts it's New England he came
from New England get in the car get in
the car right anyway um we've been
talking uh myself and Corey his partner
who's responsible for a lot of the
Cannabis based information uh Andrew
you're more focused on the software the
sensors all the actual Hardware so
Andrew's going to walk us through the
Rosen reactor today we've got uh well
we've got uh about 1,800 G of apricot
Kush rosin kind of looks like peanut
brittle right now
and we're going to get this into the
Rosen
reactor which is right over here and I'm
going to have Andrew walk us through
what this is how it works break down all
the components the software the brain
and the vessel uh and then you guys will
have a great understanding of why it's
important to have a piece of Machinery
like this this is so you can avoid
watching Bubbles as you decarbox and
stabilize your resin for Vapor carts so
I'll put it over to you Andrew all right
well our rosin reactor system comprises
of three main components one is a laptop
which is going to hold your software and
our calculator you've got a control box
which can control two individual vessels
and the third is our vessel SL manle
assembly with our manifold on top um the
way this system works it's able to track
both the Ambient Air Temperature and the
pressure of the vessel you have the
internal product temperature as well as
you can then control the ventilation and
burping of gas as well as the inner
charge of nitrogen gas inside of it we
then fully control the mantle and we are
able to monitor the internal temperature
of the heating element to dial in an
exact temperature and track everything
both on screen as well as control all
the components of the system um inside
of this control box is our brain as well
as a temperature controller that will
communicate both the brain but also al
control the individual temperature of
this manifold sorry mantle apologies um
we have different vessel sizes this is a
one L vessel this would be a half lit
vessel we have 2 L 3 l and 5 L
respectively and they all simply attach
with a 3/8 um compression fitting um and
so you've got the one vessel right now
it's plugged into over here this
manifold is all plugged into here and
then there's also another one on the
other side that you're not seeing and
that's what he was meaning in regards so
you can run two of these Systems off of
one brain the software itself will
actually run four brains it'll run up to
four brains so you can have up to eight
vessels all of varying sizes we just
simply spec it out depending on what
your process requires as a facility mhm
okay beautiful excellent so explain to
people why this is better than I mean
this is a very simple question and I I I
know the answer myself but why are
people going to be more interested in
instead of using V ovens and watching
the bubbles uh finally stop in their
material to figure out their decarb time
what is this going to offer us that is
going to sort of take it to the next
level preserve volatile organic
compounds and ensure that the thca has
been converted to THC so that you don't
have uh crystallization in your carts so
what we found is the the usual process
of decar oxil obviously creates CO2
which generates a pressure from that the
typical Tech has always been to watch
the bubble
and what happens when you get towards
the end of that process is there is a
saturation of Delta 9 and Turpin that
occurs that starts to hide any of that
reaction and you don't see it on screen
here but I'll briefly show you on one of
our brochur is you can see there is a
taper off to the green line of the
reaction that taper off could take two
to three times longer than what you
initially expect meaning the last 15
maybe 10 10% of thca that you believe is
no longer inside of that material is
still remaining in it and it won't show
until 5 to 10 days later after youve
filled all of that product into
cartridges which can occur in either
crystallization or cloudy cartridges
where you lose the perfect clarity that
you should have to create the most
optimal product and preserve the most
amount of Turin while doing so and
that's like microscopic crystallization
of thca they're not creating Giant
Crystals uh but they're just these
microscopic ones and they do create a
very sort of Cloudy not ideal for shelf
look
corre okay you additionally have some
more controls where everything in terms
of this software is all built in as one
you have a logging function that you can
start and stop you can disengage and
engage the tanks individually you can
charge them as well as discharge from
buttons on
screen the system is designed to work
away from a laptop where if you have a
TV connected you can actually pull out
the graphs and you can move these to
different screens if you want to you can
also if we had multiple tanks you can
turn this graph into a multi- graph
setup so if you had four tanks you can
show all four graphs all at once or you
can show all four graphs on a TV the
whole system is Network connected so you
don't actually need this laptop to stay
with the system you can place this
laptop wherever you'd like in a facility
simply plug it into your network connect
the soft software and everything can be
controlled and you can simply leave up
and display everything that is going on
but none of your users will have control
of what's going on only a specific
individual in your facility needs to be
able to get access to that computer the
workaround we found is we use a program
called nides to give you remote control
and you can simply place that on an iPad
and walk around your facility and
Connect into the computer wherever it is
in your facility and remote control it
right in front of it beautiful so the
software itself comes as a license we
also have a calculator that works in
combination with this that allows you to
input the initial product amount the
volume of Your Vessel your target
temperature your target amount or
whether it's known or unknown your
amount of THC that's inside of the
material and it will help you calculate
a quantity of vet that it believes will
be the complete process you then use
that in combination of our venting which
we consider consider a frequency to
create an estimated time Target that
will allow a user to be able to I guess
accomplish a full production with no
issues of Cloudy carts that you can rely
on and repeat over and over and over
again at scale and discharge the button
discharge that's for venting yeah so
right now we have everything set up in a
manual mode in automatic mode but if I
go into my controller settings and turn
it to our manual
function our discharge button will now
IND individually work I see and our
charge button will work at any period of
time but we control that this play
button up here this is the controls to
your temperature controller right now
it's only set on a single profile line
so you can set this into multiple
profiles if you want to this has just
got one but you can add up to 10 they
will work their way down it and you have
days hours and minutes which they could
work through beautiful when you simply
hit play all that will happen it will
come up and advise you that your set
point is that it will tell you your
heater set point and it has now changed
everything for the temperature
controller to start heating that mantle
exactly to the temperature you want when
you press stop it simply kills that
temperature and it will send it back
down to the value of zero heat is off
beautiful so today we're going to be
using the one lit
vessel um Cory was talking about um
leaving about a half a liter of head
space for the material so we've figured
out that'll probably be around 700 to
750 G of rosin that's uh we have also
marked the vessel so that when it goes
into here um we'll see that the tape the
top of the tape line is right where it
goes to and so we don't want the rosin
going above this tape line that'll
ensure us that we have enough head space
uh with the lid of the unit plus the
little bit of extra space here uh that
should be about
uh that's 500 M of head space that's 1
lit so we know no matter what as as you
go with it we spec vessels based on a
body size and then our head always has a
known amount of air space for that head
space so we're always calculating the
fact that it doesn't the part that Cory
has found the most unique out of this is
the relative temperature change between
inside of this mantle and the top of
this glass vessel creates a condensation
of tpin and you get a reflux and you
will actually Reco because that
temperature shift is so drastic it may
be 150 to to 175° in here it is about
80° on top of that class M okay
excellent so I guess uh we can start
with throwing our rosin into the reactor
uh and then we'll see what kind of
program we're going to run it through
and start this uh this
decarb all right
so put a little bit of rosin in
here
it's actually coming out a little easier
than I thought it
might um oh we're going to have to get
the vessel teared and onto the screen
onto the scale I should say I did I oh I
did get the weight of that on its own if
you need it you did tear it already y it
should be
1,115 85
1,16
1,116 M all right and go so so yeah just
a little bit of it's kind of got the
round
bottom
uh
2016 just go
o three fix that quickly
enough all right
so see if we can't get this
rosin into that that
vessel it's nice when you're in a cold
room cuz you can actually get away with
touching that's where these silly gloves
will come in handy that I'm got on the
way
here this is something else this is
going to be a big
challenge
it's like I want to grab it from the
bottom but I I can't it's going to make
it worse your hand just going to be
stuck to it oh
yeah oh there it goes that's
okay let get it figured out here this is
just going to be a nightmare
basically
okay
[Music]
that
okay A little bit of
product okay so 1116 to
1,400 so we got a little bit less than
half
on there going to take this glove off
and throw on a new
one calculator out as
well just under
it and we managed to get some
out that was
impressive
yeah so work like this could be done in
the cold
room it's amazing how stuck it wants to
be before it actually releases you
really kind of have to cut it from the
from the
bottom
I just don't want it to be too thick cuz
I don't want it to yeah hit the sides to
hit the sides at
all if I can avoid it I
will oh this one has way less
material
there you
go let that fall down
naturally
okay,
1817 g 14 15 16 17 that's
700 say that's probably more than enough
I think so too
so tear weight gross
weight is well it's minus the 11 so it's
about 700
right yeah what was the total weight I
got calculator the gross weight is
18817 minus
no
116 701 18 177 base
42 now weight is 7:01 yep
Point did you do the oh no I didn't know
the I'll do I'll do
them
1817 go we've got our rosin we got about
700 g in here into the vessel and then
into the reactor it goes so you simply
place it in and then you've placed a a
small
little o-ring yep there's an O-ring that
comes with every vessel that simply gets
placed into the groove that's literally
listed on the head that's going to
create your seal and your vacuum that's
it you're going to slide your mantel
underneath we use a little stainless
tray to make sure everything nicely fits
underneath and stays balanced for us
okay that's that little guy right there
we have much better stands that we
provide with the product it's just it's
the demo [ __ ] easy one yeah yeah well
we're doing line up your probe
centrally and then you're simply going
to hold your your head and loosen your
two clamps to allow everything to slide
down
okay as that slides the probe will just
press straight into the material yeah I
can see that in there too probe is in
and then all we're going to do is use
the clamp which has a freet
not
attachment it has a wing
clamp simply going to do just press it
in and remember these things are tight
cuz it's a seal that you're holding yeah
yeah of
course and that's that what was that
that came off there I think it was just
probably a little piece of that little
thing there oh yeah just piece the clamp
perfect
perfect excellent that's it so then
that's now sealed in place the Rosen
reactor is almost ready to go that's it
and then we don't have any nitrogen so
so we're going to just do we're going to
assume I did a pressure test to the
vessel before it came here so I know
it's going to be sealed M but
effectively we're going to make sure
we've got all of our settings correct so
you're going through the settings here
go through the settings so we're in Ros
we got a Fahrenheit temperature we're in
a temperature control setup our logging
file yep we want our pathway for our
folder we're going to prompt for a file
name perfect we then have our logging
time interval so this will log on a 30
second interval there's also on the
right hand side mhm for all your
settings beautiful we're then going to
go to our tank settings and
switch to go into our Auto high low
mode oh come on gloves don't like no
they don't that's fun the
screen enable our discharge mode so
we've now lost control of our manual
discharge button y we've set our trigger
value so our high trigger value is 5 PSI
our low trigger value is one
PSI close our
screen and when we hit start it's going
to erase the
background we are then going to leave
this as our file name unless you want to
change it to what you had for
your to that yeah rp23 do2 and then I
guess we could add the D cuz when it
comes out when it's finished it'll be
decarbox
elated we'll save that as our file name
so this is going to save and log as a
CSV file and two things have happened
both the logging has started your graph
is eras to restart it started tracking
the release rate for PSI per second and
it has started the
heater so that's the release rate you've
got discharge mode you've got ambient
temp product temp heater set point
heater
temp as well as pressure low pressure
high and pressure effectively the five
on top cuz this release rate will only
exist when logging it will disappear
when not logging but everything from the
midpoint up is pressure everything from
the midpoint down is temperature
temperature and so we've got it set at
180 we're going to let it sit and let it
increase in temperature this is starting
to autotune to get to the exact
temperature of 180° and set as a fixed
temperature mhm and we're going to
Simply sit back and wait
beautiful excellent
let's do some
waiting so I just asked Andrew uh you
know what we're actually waiting for and
he gave a good explanation so we'll go
through that real quick so we've now
started the process we're waiting for an
initial build of temperature right now
our product temperature is only at 55°
which means we most likely aren't having
any kind of reaction take place so we
want to wait until our product
temperature stabilizes once that
stabilizes you will then start to
generate a frequency of venting and that
frequency of venting allows you to
determine a time scale if you have a
known count of total burps that you're
aiming for and you have a frequency of
those burps our calculator then helps
you determine an estimated time scale
for that entire process which helps for
that very last 10%
% usually pull that's the part that's
the biggest catch cuz you've gotten 90%
of the way there and you've just hurt
yourself by pulling it early all right
so we'll wait till it gets up to
temperature we'll wait till it starts
creating that pattern for us and then
what do we do at that point we're then
going to Simply use that temperature and
that ventilation frequency to determine
what works for our time scale if it's
going too long we're going to increase
that temperature which should then
reduce the frequency and reduce the time
okay the time in between therefore
you're having faster reaction and we're
going to Target the right temperature to
time process that works for both your
facility as well as for the highest
retention of these volatiles all right
beautiful thank you one last thing I was
asking Andrew so what do we got to do we
got to sit around and we got to watch
this thing now and wait for it to get up
to temperature he's like no man we're
going to go to lunch because everything
is controllable on your phone so we use
a program that every single laptop is
provided with um it has a name and a
password to the PC and you'll be able to
see it but right now I can control
everything that is taking place on that
tank and computer from my phone from our
lunch so we can simply just go out to
lunch monitor the entire process go from
there and it was why we would say to
people if you want to connect it into a
network and have a main PC like you see
here but that PC is actually located in
the manager's office but then somebody
who's that manager if they have an iPad
they can very easily still still be in
this room and control it they're the
only person that can control it so will
there be a subscription that you guys
offer down the line where you kind of
can like help monitor for people that
don't know what they're doing maybe as
well and you can kind of give them a
little bit of hand holding where you
know they're like we're do we're about
to do a batch little light comes on or
you get an email now you guys are
monitoring for them and kind of maybe
doing some of the math and organizing
they can tell you what they want you
tell them how to get it that's correct
Corey um who's my colleague he will sit
down and we have a package that includes
this he will give you I think it's about
6 hours of time remotely for dialing in
your process working on calculations and
determining everything you want to do
with the system so it both works as a
cons consultation Aid as well as a I
guess the best way explain is a specific
model that works for your facility I
would call it white glove service thank
you for real just came in to do a quick
check and uh Andrew is just going to
point out a couple of safety features
that he got put in uh based on a friend
who worked at OSHA having a conversation
with him he just told me this so he's
going to be repeating it for the second
time but I thought it was important for
you guys as well so go ahead Andrew the
importance of so we have a glass vessel
that is pressure rated to 100 35 PSI at
100° C the man the manifolds all have a
adjustable prv which can be uh a plunger
can be added for an emergency relief if
you need to we then have an analog
pressure gauge and a manual ball valve
and they're all on it for worst case
scenario situations where the vessel
needs to be relieved immediately of
pressure if it was ever to go over a
certain amount of pressure or if you
don't have any kind of connection to
this for any reason you still know
what's going on in this entire process
so you definitely in the Sops want to
always make sure that you're checking
this making sure that it's closed cuz if
it's open I guess we're never going to
be gaining any pressure there you go all
right thank you all right so one of the
things I wanted to cover with you Andrew
was you know there's a few different
things that can fail on the unit how
hard is it to troubleshoot if something
fails walk us through what that kind of
looks like so basic troubleshooting you
can use by the software where there are
two buttons onto it for discharge and
charge that control both of your two
solenoids for discharge and charging by
clicking them you can simply easily
check there's an LED on top of each
solenoid that will flash we're not going
to do it now cuz it's currently running
live yeah um in regards to the internals
you have two temperature controllers
that can easily be taken out by bolts
and our main brain which is effectively
an embedded PCB board and it's held on
by four screws and you simply switch the
board out and that's the main component
change after that that's actually it
okay so you have your two solenoids you
have this little plunger piece inside
that's it you can get to the inside of
that valve if you need to by taking off
that nut you can get to the physical
shaft which can be unscrewed off the
valve body you can clean all the seals
you can get fully inside to it and then
screw it all about together again
underneath it you have a a seven Micron
particulate filter that once again same
thing you can easily take out the filter
put it into an alcohol bath clean it and
simply place it right back in
again Additionally you can always adjust
your automatic prv if you want to go
higher or lower everything is set to 35
PSI and after that everything is a basic
component switch out is the sensor for
your temperature and your pressure is
held on by a standard compression
fitting as well as your temperature
probe is held on by standard compression
fitting all of your sensors and
solenoids are attached by m M12 um
four-way automation cables and all of
that goes down to a single 12-way cable
going into your board so fairly easy to
troubleshoot and find a problem if you
have one correct and fixing and
replacing pieces are incredibly easy to
do the concept is is you need 1 all key
set to fix everything okay beautiful
thanks
man hey guys so yeah now you've seen the
Rosen reactor in action unfortunately I
was unable to get footage I wasn't there
for the finishing up um I I think it
took us around 14 hours per 700 g that
we ran um we did end up doing about 2700
or just over 2 and 1/2 kilos uh we got
it into carts which I can show you the
picture of the cart very nice color the
color in the labs when you're doing
video the rosin looked much darker than
it actually was it looked kind of like a
peanut butter but it was quite yellow
amberh color in the uh Vape carts The
Taste was absolutely phenomenal we are
wai waiting for the final COA in regards
to showing that we got a tpine increase
uh Cory did hit me up the other day and
let me know that he was getting um a
substantial increase in Tarpin uh from a
couple of batches that he did recently
in
Florida um we're quite excited with the
unit we got to admit taste Wise decarbox
Wise we had the COA come in and it was
like 100% decarbed to Perfection so this
really allows you to get that 100%
decarb and get it accurate so you're not
watching bubbles you're able to monitor
through your phone which is great and um
yeah we're going to be using the Rosen
reactor here for a little bit if anyone
has any interest or questions about the
Rosen reactor please feel free to reach
out to me at bcbl man.com or sorry BC
bubbleman
icloud.com uh send me an email I can
send you some information I can uh hook
you guys up with the company I am going
to be uh helping them move some units
here in Canada and hopefully in the US
all in all we're quite happy with the
white glove service um we're quite happy
with the fact that Corey was monitoring
the decarb each and every time and uh
yeah we're just uh you know more tools
to be created for the industry that
we're in that are designed specifically
for these jobs rather than Jerry rigging
and doing things sort of half asked so
if you guys have any questions um I will
try to do a follow-up video eventually
uh showing the final process of Us
opening the unit if you allow the unit
to heat up the rosin can be quite
viscous and that way you can take that
and pour it right into your filling
machines if you're doing Vape carts or
get it back into whatever vessel you
want to have it in before you get it
into um you know Edibles so thanks for
watching as always please subscribe and
uh we'll talk to you later peace
out
[Music]
w