[Music]
hey guys welcome back to part two of the
Rosen Tech I have of course made a
little bit of it here I can uh got a
little dab here hanging from the from
the Dabber and just put that right there
for
now don't get that
lost guess that's the way she's going to
go so yeah I've got the Dabber here
filled with h a nice little rip of rosin
I've got the little bit on the piece
here that I made in the last video a
little bit of uh dry sift rosin that was
pressed out of here little no melts for
you made Ros and you guys saw the video
how great it worked how easy it was with
the 25 micron screen the 25 micron
screen is reusable um Jeff church was
saying that he he um cleans his with
either like a pure alcohol a grain
alcohol or even an isopropanol um I
would prefer a grain alcohol personally
the cleaner the cleaner the better and
that's what I'll do to reuse mine I'm
also going to try and make some smaller
pieces that are more fitting almost
circular pieces that I can start uh uh
selling on the site so that people have
access to this screen you can heat it up
and it's not going to release any type
of uh chemicals so that's important and
then of course what you guys all were
missing was the rip so without further
Ado I've got the um the special nail
here see if we can get this unhooked yep
beautiful
beautiful very nice it's a little bit
different from working with uh with hash
that I'm so used to but the rosin still
pretty pretty dealable so I've got the
silicon carbide nail with the
um Sapphire insert if you can see that
let me see if I can get it a little
closer for you
guys yep sappire insert you can see I've
taken one rip already and that's the rip
that you guys are going to get to watch
on the nail as I take this rip now one
thing I noticed was the boiling and the
bubbling and the melting doesn't so much
occur when you've gotten rid of the
membrane um I always thought it was the
Tarpin boiling out but you'll see in the
video that it's mostly just oil on the
sapphire slowly um smoking off so here
we go Rosen dry sift rips through the
Taurus
now it has a very similar taste to the
dry sip keep in mind this was dry sip
that wasn't that good it has the flavor
of that dry sift minus whatever that I
mean it's increased the potency and the
and the quality guaranteed even in the
taste now I'll admit I probably used
more heat than was
necessary but really what I can taste is
a purified version of the dry sip that I
wasn't as fond of now it's a tough gig
to try and make a rosin taste as good as
a a six-star full
melt because you've already grown that
six-star full melt so properly the tpin
are already present and of course Jeff
talked a little bit about how his tpine
content went up in hash Church on when
he tested his material which makes sense
if you get rid of the majority of the
hash and squeeze out just a smaller
amount of the oil you would think that
your tarpine ratio would go up just from
the removal of the wax
membranes however lets not us get
confused at the fact that those tpin are
going to be altered due to the fact that
heat was present U Mark mentioned uh one
of the sesquiterpenoids uh
caropine uh it starts evaporating at
107° and there's other ones present as
well at at those low temperatures so
obviously the the 200° temperature of
the rosin uh is going to heat that up
but that's why we're figuring out ways
to do it uh quicker get it off uh faster
and this is not by any means a
replacement for learning how to dry sift
or learning how to um wet wash what this
is is another thing for you to put in
your quiver another great way to test a
bud if you don't smoke bud and don't
have a vaporizer PR this is just another
option for you guys so uh don't think
too deeply into it don't start bashing
it just yet you know give it a shot it's
kind of fun I will tell you that the the
resin potency wise goes up more in my
opinion than three stars the the high
that I have from that hit of what was
considered a three star dry sift that I
wasn't even hitting to bump that up to
the Quality that this is right now I
can't say enough about it um I probably
will do a video with the pressing of the
buds when I finally get a little t-shirt
press because the hair iron just uh
isn't releasing any resin from the buds
so uh yeah stay tuned for that and of
course stay tuned for Barcelona I'll be
leaving uh in the next couple of days to
fly down for spannabis and we'll be
doing a large uh a huge variety of
videos down there I hope and most
importantly the one I'm really excited
about is Hash Church Todd McCormack set
up with Ben droners the owner of the
Sensei seed Museum in Amsterdam as well
as down in Barcelona that we are going
to be able to film in his 15th century
building uh that is approximately you
know 10,000 ft of just epicness uh Ben
does not cut any Corners he's a real
quality guy and it'll be interesting to
see uh you know hash Church filmed at
the at the Hemp Museum so please come by
and check that out next Sunday live it
will be at 9:00 a.m. West Coast uh time
BC time uh which will be about 6:00 p.m.
in Barcelona so we look forward to
seeing you there
and uh yeah
props keep watching Bubble Man's World
[Music]
Peace