[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh it is still Sunday at about almost
4:20 10 minutes till 4:20 I'll make sure
that we have a hit and in fact I'll make
sure we have a hit with what we're about
to do which is process a little bit of
rosin um in hash church today we had
soil grown from Instagram come in and
talk a little bit about his Bud Tech of
pressing buds in the um T-shirt press
which he does for less than a few
seconds at a certain temperature I think
it was around 300 or 280 uh ideally the
hair straightener guys I think they were
talking about 200 to
230° um the tool that I actually have
today is one of these small hair
straighteners could have had that
plugged in and ready real nice easy
switch on the inside to turn on and off
and we'll get to that in a little bit so
basically this is the process of milking
the resin glands from the plant matter
or from the hash um I have not done it
with plant matter yet but I did do one
little batch using some lower Quality
Dry sift so I figured because I know
that works for sure um I'm going to
start with that so I've got my pressing
screen from a25 Micron pressing screen
from a bubble bag kit uh I've got a
little bit of um parchment paper left
over from when D 420k gave me a bunch of
dry
sift and I've got the straightener and
then I've also actually got some slick
sheet I thought we would do a little bit
through the parchment paper and a little
bit through the slick sheet and then we
could kind of see which one we liked
more right now most people are using the
parchment paper uh without even the 25
micron screen
I think you find when you use the uh the
hash method uh when you're using hash
instead of Bud that it is actually quite
convenient to use it like that so yeah
just cut off a little a little
square all
right so this is some sort of
like much hotter temperatures can be um
can be used on this particular stuff so
we'll see how that goes we'll do the
experiment I managed to get just the
tiniest little bit of rosin on my finger
and now I can feel it literally on
everything got to be careful with that
stuff all right so what we're going to
do is we're going to take a little bit
of this no melt
sift got a little bit there you can kind
of see the quality I purified it but
it's not uh it's just not melty it's
just not happening on the Melt Factor so
think I Chang Chang the color of
the video we went a little blue there
well I'm okay with it if you guys are
okay with it anyway so what we're going
to do is we're going to get this hash
rolled into a little sort of section of
the pressing
screen this is what Jeff was showing us
today on hash church he twisted it up
kind of got it all twisted up like
that all right and then he merely took
it and he placed it
between the pressing
screen between the parchment paper I
should
say so now it's just a matter of turning
this
on uh Jeff had a digital readout on his
he said the lowest temperature he could
turn this on to was about 230° so that's
what he was doing um I'm with Tony I
just kind of test test it with my finger
and you can kind of see right off the
bat as you start pressing it
you can kind of start seeing
resin want to leak leak out of
it I can see it already
starting then of course a little bit
more little bit more pressure a little
bit more
heat and now you can really see
it kind of greasing up in
there all right so turn that little guy
off you saw that took a few seconds you
can open that
up this is uh your press hash inside the
pressing screen which of course still
has some Goods on there and then most
importantly you've got the dabs that you
just got out of
that how impressive is
that actually let me pick that up
because you guys need to see a little
bit better than that
all right so I just pressed that right
out
of right out of that hash you saw it
right here on Bubble man's
world and I'm sure before you saw it on
Bubble man's world if you're out there
at all you saw soil grown you saw Jeff
church and you saw these couple other
characters that are out there doing
these um processes I by no means am
claiming that I am the first
I just find it very interesting I think
it's pretty cool that we can get this
quality of resin out of a lower grade
lower quality of hash I can open that up
and you can see on the
inside what we're left with is that
lower
grade of hash that we've melted
so that was step one now why don't we
try doing that
again with that same little bit of
hash and we'll wrap it in
the the other paper this time
around and we'll see what we can get off
of that we'll see if maybe there's more
of an attractant to this particular type
of of of parchment I mean it's not
parchment it's a Teflon type of
thing and I can see it already the oils
just from one little mild press I could
see the uh the oil is wanting to come
out oh yeah I can see them dripping
actually can you guys see
that all right
so okay second
grade milked off on that paper I think I
like the way it looks on this paper even
better it looks as though even though
the same amount of heat was applied I
didn't get the same amount of bubbles on
it and keep in mind this is an older
hash and I think the reason we're a
seeing this this darkness is because a
I'm new at this and I'm probably using
more heat than I need to but
also that this material is a little bit
older it's it's been dried for an
extremely long time and I think that has
a lot to do with it so I'm going to
photograph both the parchment as well as
the oh let's get the name right here the
oil slick sheet I'm going to call it the
slick sheet cuz that's what they call it
so the slick sheet also has some nice
material here I will photograph that for
you guys as well so we'll put that off
to the side and yeah that is pretty darn
cool right there a little bit of rosin
for you guys now if you guys have
anything you want to add to the comments
please do so at the end of the video
here and of course if you haven't
subscribed already please subscribe and
of course share these videos we're
trying to get them out to as many people
as POS possible and uh having an
audience as as big as the one I have
right now is a huge blessing and I want
to thank all of you guys for uh spending
your time watching these shows and
spending your time commenting and uh you
know trying to make the channel a better
channel so uh Rosen Tech from the bubble
man we'll talk soon peace
[Music]