foreign
[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
literally we're sitting on my deck here
in beautiful Lions Bay BC and I'm here
with Kevin from Royal Harvest and uh
first of all good to see you dude as
always brother he drove up from the
Okanagan so it was a good four or five
hour drive for you that's about a five
hour drive this morning but a beautiful
drive and worth it every time so Kevin
and I linked up through book club he had
an event at book club where he brought a
bunch of his flavors will you tell them
about it yeah I ended up getting
introduced to aldolfo there at book club
and we started talking about bringing
some flour in as I got involved with the
book book club chat I noticed that uh
Marcus had reached out with some
interest of uh looking in to see what my
flower could do so we ended up uh
coordinating a Time came down here uh
had a lot of fun he taught me
um I've always been about the flower I
started this at a very young age 12. um
in a necessity to help family and I've
been focused on really trying to
generate and create the best flower I
can so it was very interesting when
Marcus reached out to me in regards to
making some half so I was more than
excited to come down bring him some of
my flour and he uh showed me the process
a little bit of making some hash and I
think we actually came up with some
absolutely uh nice product would you
think well we have many many jars
sitting over here I'd say about 30 or 28
yeah at least 25 to 30 jars of product
we ran three different varieties 100
grams of each so
well below the threshold of the five
gallon bubble now and five gallon bubble
bag kit we ran it through the eight bags
through the labs we did it here at my
house and unfortunately we didn't film
that video there was a lot of work to be
done I'm just noticing as well I didn't
wipe the table but you know what that's
okay the table isn't the focus today the
hashish is the focus so this hash is the
first time we're going to be smoking
this we're going to check melt tests
we've got our puffco and our Focus car
to two
uh you are on and I am on so it's just a
matter of lighting them up oh one thing
I will go get which will be very
important and shout out to Bowie from
glob mops is
um
some Q-tips I'm learning I'm new to the
extracts and doing it this way but
they're necessity to clean every time
yeah you don't want to be not cleaning
and then shove it to Apex ancillary as
well they sent me uh this cool little
kit I will be using this one today for
you amazing and shout out to Mystic
timber for the little scoop for me we'll
be using that one for me and I'm gonna
go get the Q-tips I will be right back
all right got the XL glob mops I find
these ones with the wood
so look at that this Perfection shout
out to buoy for that and uh I guess if
you want to pull in some flavors here we
can start loading up some
doubles iron where is it I've been
eyeing that 90 Micron I have shout out
to calyx too for hooking me up with the
jars
go to some great jars there we go you
can do this this is the 90 Micron red
velvet runs oh my God oh my God I know
absolutely insane dude it looks like
diamonds yeah it's insane
very very nice all right well
I'll load up a little
oh my God it's melting in the Sand Dude
I guess what I'm gonna do is just
to dab out on oh man look how sticky
yeah that is insane yeah you definitely
uh look at that I can't even get it off
my stick yeah that's a good uh size dab
too I didn't have to take it off very
good sized step
we have not allowed these to grease out
at all they've been in the freezer since
production well they wait they dried at
a cold ambient temperature out of the
Sun out of the light and then right into
jars right into the freezer at you know
minus 21 degrees Celsius so
um I guess what we do is you'll hit this
top button twice
and then you can just look and we'll
watch for the Melt Factor we'll share
this with you on a different video we'll
so you guys can see the Melt factor of
it oh look at that go excuse mountain
look at that thing boil up oh yeah oh
yeah oh yeah that's that's full melt
that's full Mountain
yeah mine's boiling up too very nicely
wow
what a flavor
oh my God
[Laughter]
holy [ __ ]
got a little sweat but beating on my
forehead there
I only had mine on the second heat seat
setting as well it was Green
all right now a little check on the Chas
always going to be something left I
don't know why someone turned it into
full melt is when it leaves nothing on
the nail that really wasn't a part of
the definition of full mouth in the
beginning but certainly if it leaves
nothing on the nail that is the highest
caliber of full mount
it says a tiny little bit of Chas
probably in the like one to two percent
range of what got put in
so not too bad at all
that was nice that was the 90 Micron red
velvet runs
dude the first one we tried now we did
go with the 90 too though
upping our our potential possibility
I couldn't help it though it looked so
nice in the jar that it was calling my
name it really did look nice in the jar
it looked great in the pipe too yeah
absolutely
uh we both hit very different size uh
rips you hit quite a big one I hit a
much smaller one probably half size but
still got the full melt effect sometimes
with melt the more you put in the more
it will appear to melt whereas if you
put a smaller amount in you won't see
quite a violent Mount I had a still a
very nice Violet Mountain we'll uh make
some videos for you guys to see that uh
here in a little bit you want me to
clean you out oh you did it yeah I did
it you got it already
I'm learning I'm learning it's all
processed the only thing is is I try to
do these holes at the top they have the
tricks oh yeah so I've watched you slain
your bubble bag so I know how adamant
you are to make sure things are done
properly you learn that when you use
your bubble bags make sure in between
you're taking the time to clean those
bags perfectly every time otherwise it
reduce it reduces the the
the effectiveness of
the banks you know they'll start
plugging with resin as you leave that
resin behind and don't clean it and it
just ends up being a bummer uh
that's unnecessary an unnecessary bummer
there you go
uh wow that was really nice beautiful I
mean my goodness tell us a little bit
about your red velvet runs uh red velvet
runs it's um I got the cut actually from
a buddy of mine
um I don't know too much about it I just
started running and playing with it
we're getting great yields and very good
returns off it nice nice looking flowers
yeah it's absolutely a stunner it's just
completely caked it doesn't miss every
time beautiful smoke beautiful flavor
and you know it brings that Quality
Clean Smoke every time is it one of the
pictures that you had sent and shared
with me
um
because I remember like one in
particular that was very like light it
was a lavender-ish color almost the
entire Bud it may have oh no that is the
Fritter mints oh the Fritter mints yes
interesting yes I haven't seen that one
yet not yet not yet actually it's just
getting ready to head to processing
right now very cool yeah well right
before we sat down for this we got a
shot we got a message from Adolfo saying
that he's having a special hash night on
the 28th of this month absolutely
couldn't be a better time for that now
that uh we have some hash to bring no
but think about the timeline of making
like you know it's probably take a
couple weeks or a week to plan such an
event but imagine you had to grow an
entire crop yep we had to turn it into
hash yeah we had to dry the hash
properly then jar it up and only after
all of that we'll be prepared to get
that message and when did we get that
message about like 20 seconds after we
sat down and I put these jars in French
you were scraping pretty much the last
Slimer hash off the box and you got that
message right like how does it work yeah
crazy I want to put my macro camera out
I did
um microplane these so the heads are
going to be pretty shredded in that
sense they won't be the same beautiful
round heads that you usually see but
I'll try to do some macro photography on
these to show a that you can dry bubble
on a pizza box and not get fibers in the
hash I mean you did not see a single
fiber with the naked eye clean as can be
wouldn't you sort of see that if you
think you would you would notice those
Little Fibers but if not I'll go in with
my extremely extremely powerful macro
lens and show you guys one more time
that if done properly there's no reason
you should be pulling any fibers off of
the cardboard this is also specifically
for people in tropical countries or in
the Pacific Northwest in Washington
Oregon British Columbia we have very
high humidities not now I'll admit no
not now no no but it is extremely hot
out right now
um we have very high humidity for about
eight months of the year nine months of
the year so to try and dry hash without
a freeze dryer in an air drying method
it becomes very very very difficult to
do so we learned this over the years
when I was telling people you need to
use a desiccant you need to use
something to pull the moisture out of a
hash and nicotine was being like you
don't need to do that at all you just
put it on parchment and it'll it'll work
fine which it you know to me I was like
he doesn't know what he's talking about
to him he was like he doesn't know what
I'm talking about and then eventually we
put it together that you know our
terroirs we're affecting our ability to
dry hash and remember when you're making
hash as long as you follow the
directions quite simply
this is all very simple when you get to
the hard part is when you have the wet
bubble and now it's the part that
involves removing as much moisture or
water content from that hash as possible
and then getting it broken up into a way
where you can actually properly dry it
and not everyone has freeze dryers so
this video isn't particularly right now
talking to those of you who are home
hashmakers home Growers who don't have
freeze dryers who don't have a budget
for a three to five thousand dollar
freeze dryer there are ways to safely
dry your hash depending on where you're
at and how long does it take them to dry
their house that way compared to
well you can always test it and I
suggest that you do test it by putting
it in the environment that you feel is
the correct environment to do the
drawing and then accessing it after a
couple days or three days or four days
or five days
um because it's really like an intuition
to know and if you take the hash and you
put it away with any moisture in it that
moisture is going to cause problems down
the line especially or really only if
you're not putting it in a freezer
absolutely
absolutely if you're going to expose it
to uh you know
room temperatures
especially in the hot summer
if there's any moisture in there it's
and and you'll learn it very quickly
it's a funky smell you know I have
people sometimes are convinced no that's
just the smell of my genetics and I'm
like it's not it's the same with the
same Funk smell right in all hash that's
been
um not dried you get the same thing with
flour when it's you know they're almost
there but they go to cure before you get
that smell that it's like it was just
too much was left there's a fine line
yes there's a fine line and it's almost
an instinct that you develop over time
to know where that fine line is right to
really get that difference of that high
quality product yeah no totally
well I guess uh we're gonna have another
sip of water and uh try another
absolutely another flavor this one's
your pet 73. okay that's what I just had
her hand on perfect
all right by now you've probably noticed
things have shifted I pushed pause on
the video that was a phenomenal dab we
just enjoyed a really nice off-camera
conversation pretty big too yeah
absolutely absolutely uh but we're ready
for another variety which is the Slimer
so what can you tell us about the Slimer
the uh the Slimer is uh said tiva
dominant hybrid
um definitely can smell the turpinoline
in there you betcha it's about a 60 40.
very nice buzz it has that very nice as
you said that terpa just hit you when we
were making it you could just smell it
coming out of the washer yeah it really
was it was uh I hate that though as well
as love it I love it because it smells
amazing I hate it because I want it to
stay in the resin I don't uh it's funny
how you know sometimes I had something
in Germany some honey bananas really
nice rosin and it was amazing it was so
loud but it was so loud that I just kept
opening the jar and letting everyone
smell it like a hundred times more than
I would do to any normal jar of anything
and
it it started to dissipate a little and
I remember a friend opening it and going
oh my God and closing it and opening it
and going and then doing it three or
four times in a row and feeling like
stop doing that
you're taking my turps out of there I
mean I didn't because there was another
side of me that I would was more focused
on which was like enjoying what he was
enjoying exactly through him I was like
and that's a great feeling to be loving
it yeah it's about the experience it's
the same with my flower
what I do it for is the experience that
the person gets on the other end when
they open that bag and they smell it and
then they want to smell it again you
squish it and smell it you know it's all
about the experience and you know you
take that with flour with hash and it's
it's an amazing when you get to this
kind of caliber of your hash you get
that caliber of experience right true
yeah
true
that looks like a nice hash
I gotta hit this thing again on top
twice um yeah every time but not yet not
until you put the hash in okay
it's kind of a
funky mess
a little bit less sticky let me see how
she does
I think I hit it right did you hit it
twice look on the screen it'll show you
is it is the is the temperature rising
oh it's turned off so you got to hit it
five times
there you go
all right then twice and then twice
yeah all right now she blows
I'm smelting a little bit
late
my lid hit it
it smells and tastes so good way less
melty but really tasty I'm terpenaline
like um that's one of my favorites so
the Slimer
I think the Slimer would be better as a
pressed hash
I think if this was pressed into hash
and let cure for a while that it would
be we should do it actually with a bit
absolutely we could also press rosin out
of it to gain a melt Factor
which we also have the ability to do
so much you can do with ashay oh yeah
it's interesting there's a small
percentage of it that is just meant for
melt
and make some shade for that hash
yeah so also a very nice flavor like
beautiful completely different from the
first one much lighter because I didn't
put as much in mine as I put in yours
and it didn't have quite the Melt effect
I think it would still be probably a 50
to 60 percent return on rosin yep which
isn't terrible I think that full melt
that we hit would probably be like a 85
Plus amazing amazing which at that point
once you're getting into the 85 Plus 90
it's kind of like
is there any necessity to that yeah when
it's melting like the way it was in your
bowl so yeah really nice flavors I
suspect we're going to end up doing a
lot more
um myself and uh Kevin yeah
collaborations so we'll end up running
some more of his genetics he has so many
genetics it's ridiculous and like he
mentioned earlier he never came from
this from a hash perspective it's always
been a grower perspective yeah which is
awesome yeah so I mean it's great to
learn that what I'm putting into my
program and what I do reflects into the
hash
um you know another person that
approached and you and everybody seems
to be getting great results so that
means a lot to me because not just my
flower I wanted to be able to resonate
through the whole industry through every
aspect so you know what like I said
better flower better product on a deal
right yeah that's exactly how it works
for sure and uh yeah I look forward to
running some other cultivars he had some
really nice uh jars today here that
we'll show you in a bit uh what was it
it was Frost and fruitcake and sure and
sure bow yeah both beautiful both very
different in looks and structure and
profiles entering into the Unicorn cup
yes yes yes they are so I wanted to
bring two completely different flowers
again this is what was ready but
out of my rooms I'm trying to bring a
completely different look to the
consumer so when they go into a store
they have varieties of multiple you know
great flavors you offer that for certain
in fact
as much as I want to show you those
flowers we're going to show those
flowers we'll we'll we'll make a part
two to this video with those flowers all
nice and close up in the sun which I'll
do the video for today because they're
so very specific looking buds
and the Unicorn cup is an anonymous
entry correct uh they don't know who you
are as yeah when you enter yeah oh yeah
we are Anonymous or not no no not not
okay well then we can show the flowers
yes if it was Anonymous I wouldn't feel
good about it no Royal Harvesters
when but okay you're entering but when
he gives out the samples oh I don't know
there so we'll find that out yes and I'm
pretty sure it's going to be what I
thought initially and if that's the case
we'll show the flowers in part two of
this video as well as announce the
winners
the Unicorn yeah it's pretty exciting
just to be part of it um this is a
special year for it first time they're
really making it a boat wreck
um as you know I've come from pretty
much a lifetime of Legacy market and
it's great and almost exciting for the
first year of the Cup being part of a
wreck is my first year being able to be
part of this amazing industry so it's
kind of everything's a blessing you know
it's all exciting stuff coming down the
pike
excited too I can't wait to go to the
Unicorn cup and I'll definitely film at
least two or three videos at the Unicorn
cup maybe some a chat Fireside Chats
that we did last year with the group
which was really good and maybe some
paddle boarding with my bro
on the um out on the lake absolutely
Spud Lake Tyler Ty shout out to Ty
um all right well listen
um that was really nice both those ribs
got me completely elevated I'm not good
at sitting
so we're gonna go do something more fun
than this but we're happy to share some
time with you and definitely props to
Kevin and you as well sure yes awesome
thank you everybody
[Music]