Quick question in regard to that Sam. In
regards to when did you guys come across
tarpen as a modulator to can to the
canabonoid profile?
Uh well about
2000 Rob and I well I obtained some pure
THC 100% pure and uh what we did was we
vaporized 25 THCA.
Yeah, it was THCA. But thank you. We we
vaporized
uh 25 uh milligrams each in a volcano on
one of those little uh they're like a
little stainless steel brillo pad. Those
little pads that they have. Okay. So, we
were blown away because I mean, if you
smoke 25 milligrams of hash or 25
milligrams
of you you you get stoned and you it's
pretty good. But with this, it the most
describable thing about it was that it
had no individuality whatsoever like
cannabis products do. It was really
flat, one-dimensional, kind of boring.
Uh Rob, I think at the time actually
said, "If this is all there is to
cannabis, I wouldn't be a smoker." Yeah.
If this is what you got turned on to in
uh high school or
whatever, instead of the real thing, you
I don't think any of us would have
really been interested. It's sort of
like
uh being a fan of Everclear, you know,
the
the 180 something app proof um liquor
you can get in Nevada. It's not even
legal in the state of California. But
it's ethanol essentially and nobody
drinks it straight. I mean, you nobody
just dilutes it with water and drinks it
because they like it. It's uh it's a
novelty. THC was the same thing. It's it
had no color at all. So later that day,
what we did was we uh mixed it with a
little bit of uh 50% dry sip skunk
resin. And what that allowed was uh to
create a material that was 75% THC, so
less than 100%. But it was also tarpin
rich from the resin from the dry sip.
When we smoked that, the effects were
twice as strong as a pure THC. And uh a
light went in in our heads because from
the early 70s, both Robert and I, even
before we met, had felt that
tarpen might well contribute to the
synergistic effects found in cannabis.
I think one of the primary reasons was
because haze when it was tested for its
THC level was to be, you know, in the
high end of cannabis, but when you
smoked it, it was in the outer space of
cannabis. I mean, it was really really
active and uh I think that was because
of the tarpen. I I think that's how you
felt. Well, the the other amazing thing
in the
early 70s was that people started
growing cannabis. You know, they started
growing senia and that's when you really
noticed what the difference was between
fresh homegrown and what imported weed
of whatever kind you ever got
before. What that was, you know, it was
it that was a profound difference, you
know, just to see something fresh, you
know, the way mother nature gives it to
you. the essence of most of the weed
that you smoked back in the 70s, a
moldy, musty essence, you know? I mean,
I remember my first bag of weed, 1974,
it was it was moldy. Now that I I think
about it, it it certainly was mold. I
think most mo most of what I think most
of what Robert and I got, even though it
was imported, it was not moldy. Or if it
was, it was very very very very
slightly. Yeah. But a lot of trying to
make a lot of ways though a general
statement that most of commercial weed
at the time essentially which came from
Mexico was probably uh fouled with with
mold and all kinds of different
microbes. If you look very hard, you
would have found things for sure. And
some of it, of course, is unsmokable as
you know. Just plain it was just plain
ry. Yeah. But uh young kid on dead tour
in the mid70s by 1980 I was hooked up.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, meanwhile, back to
tarpine. So, we we smoked the pure THC.
We rise. This ain't it. We smoked THC
mixed with resin 50/50, which made 75%
THC by dry weight. And wow, that that
was very interesting. So then what we
did a year or two later, we obtained all
the canabonoids. So all the top 10
canabonoids THC,
CBD, CBG, THCV etc etc. And we also
obtained the top 10
turppins. And then we were able to try
the different canabonoids. And we found
out that a couple of interesting things
like number one if you smoke pure CBD in
a fairly large amount, a tenth of a
gram, 100 milligrams.
Then what happens is it blocks the
activity of even the strongest dry sit
for about 8 to 12
hours. So that was interesting. The
other interesting thing was that THCB is
not psychoactive at all. The because a
lot of people at that time believed it
was. Then we tried all the different
tarpen with
THC. Uh so we tried 25 milligrams of THC
all double blinded with one tarpine you
know as tiny amount as we could put it
with it and what we found out was that
meine boline
uh tinine and a few other definitely
potentiated THC and most of the others
or a lot of the others also modulated
THC to different uh levels. So, some
made you couch locked, some made you uh
speedy, and it was like a revelation. I
mean, we had suspected it, but we never
never really dreamed it would be that
clear because we did it with 12
different double blinded test subjects
with a 100 question survey before and
after, and we all agreed on the same
things.
different people preferred the couch
lock or the uh uh the uplifting but they
all agreed that that particular compound
with THC had that effect. So yeah it so
this was all you know maybe 12 years ago
or 13 years ago although we started it
practically 15 years ago and it's uh
yeah it's it's not at first I was afraid
to release the information because I
thought people would start coming out
with
uh Skunky Sam's improve your weed spray,
turn mold to gold. And they have to a
certain degree, but what the better side
of it is when people are extracting
tarpen from the natural cannabis sources
and then adding them back to the same.
That's that's pretty benign as long as
no chemicals and solvents are being left
or Yeah. I I don't know what to say, but
the truth of it is it's changed cannabis
and our understanding will continue to
learn, but it's a really big step
forward. What I'd really like to see
done is is
uh something much more sophisticated
than we were able to do, you know, and
and see see science put to bear on this
situation and see what we can learn
about different tarpine combinations
with different canabonoids. Oops.
There's 140 of them. Seems the most
interesting uh avenue for me at the
moment.
That's 140 known, right? That's just
what we know so far. Yeah. And some of
them are really in trace amounts and
that doesn't mean they're not important.
That but uh yeah, about 20 of them make
up most of the turppines in in uh
cannabis we smoke today. But there's a
smattering of other other compounds and
they could be key also. So yeah, there
could be a couple hundred tarpen. We
just haven't IDed them yet. Yeah. But
the smaller the amounts, the less
significant they are likely to be just
by odds.
There's probably also heavy selective
uh pressures involved recently, you
know, in the way of people breeding. I
mean, there's there's aromomas people
like and
there's effects they expect based on
that aroma. It's this feedback loop
thing that makes it all kind of hard to
study in a more detailed way. And and
it's and it's it's
[Music]
uh it's important and those things are
somehow related, but they're not as rel
related in the way I would have thought
in a biochemical sort of way. They're
more related in in what we individually
make of each variety and our
relationship with it. It's gets I know
I'm sounding a bit cosmic for the
scientist guy,
but it's impossible to separate one from
the other. I'm not even sure exactly how
you would do a a statistically rigorous
test of the tarpine and and can and
canabonoid data. It'd be interesting for
somebody to set it up. There's a lot
more powerful tools now that we uh have
had They are biochemically related.
There's no question about it. Of course,
but of course, but that's not the only
relationship is what I'd say, right? I
mean, I've always wondered if they're
competing pathways. I mean, they use the
same precursors. So, what exactly is
going on? Hard to say, but we've
certainly jacked up both pathways and
modern varieties. I mean, these these
hybrids are uh big producers of all of
the above. Yeah. It's not like there's a
shortage of one thing or another. they
the turppines seem to have become sort
of a mishmash and uh it's more now what
what plants don't have rather than what
they have in my mind that's sort of that
uh what makes a a variety and that's
characteristic in the way it smells to
me is a key tarpine it has or a couple
of them but also all the turppins that
it's lacking so that it doesn't smell
like everything else.
It's pretty uh inbred at this