You know, I was going on a couple of
weeks ago about being of service to
other people. It's one of the real gifts
that we get to have in this industry.
Um, is to make other people's lives
better.
years ago, I was up at the Gronigan Drug
Center for research and uh I went to the
hospital
there because my wife was getting a
liver transplant at the time and I ran
into
a well, she wasn't a young lady, but a
middle-aged lady who
uh she saw me and understood that I was
there working with cannabis And uh she
says, "Can you get me some cannabis?"
Because uh she was uh she was dying of
uh pancreatic cancer, which is uh not
only really really difficult to beat,
but it's one of the most painful uh
deaths that uh can you you can go
through. And uh
so I mean my
company, we're breeding all these unique
varieties of cannabis and everything.
And what I did was I I found her some
cannabis the next day or two. I brought
it to her and uh you know a few days
later I saw she just says, "Oh, I want
to thank you." I says and I says, "Well,
you know, it's not going to be a cure."
and she goes, "Yes, but what it does is
it lifts my pain me above the pain." So,
I don't have the the pain uh you know,
just driving me down and uh so she was
able to uh you know uh lift her spirits
above the pain.
And we as a company, we never dealt with
patients that much. We were a re medical
research and development company. But
what our end goal was was to because
this was uh uh in the early 90s was to
bring cannabis back into western
medicine because it was not there at
that time. And uh I I think we were very
successful at that which helped a lot of
patients further down the line.