hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world I had a great time in h church
today and I figured I'd take you guys
along for a little motorcycle ride to a
special Park here in British Columbia
Vancouver West Vancouver that I
absolutely love I want you to check it
out it's
called what is it called soon we'll be
around the corner and we'll
tell one of my favorite Parks I come
here all the time right along Marine
Drive really good spot not to be
confused with ly
Canyon all right guys so I just got to
the entrance of this park I guess this
park is called Sandy Cove just had a
little bit of an experience on the
motorcycle there I pulled up and I went
to park the bike and I I put my foot
down and there was a bunch of mud there
I didn't realize how thick it was and
when I put my foot down my foot slid
just enough to pull the bike
over woo it pulled all my momentum all
my weight luckily there was a young guy
by the name of Ryan waiting on the at
the top of the road for a ride and he
was able to run over and help me uh I'm
under the highway right now for those of
you that are wondering I was up there
and now I am down here cool little trail
that leads in here show you guys Sandy
Cove Beach and it's a Prett pretty short
little entrance that gets you in
here I've very rarely seen many people
in
here and
uh yeah check it
out hello
hello you guys enjoying the day oh yeah
excellent excellent beautiful park for
doing such
things you taking a video yeah I'm
making a little video for my YouTube
channel
all right a couple of happy
folks let see where we come out
here pretty sweet
[Music]
very
cool so we made it out here to the
Pacific Ocean figured this would be a
nice little dab spot to bring uh the
bubble man's world
audience I know you guys enjoy coming on
the trips or so I heard today in hash
Church which once again I just like to
say guys was an absolute wonderful
experience it was nice to have so many
of you show up really share
your your experiences with us and it was
touching some of the stories and some of
the people that came in really were were
sharing very personal things and we we
appreciate
that so guess I'll try and balance this
thing on here
somehow get my my dab tools ready it's
not the best for for visibility but wow
what a beautiful day out here guys can
check it out kind of wish I had water
I'm pretty darn
thirsty W how's that for an impressive
spider web you guys catching that see
that big guy there another one down
here pretty
cool
so we're going to want
this sitting in a
way propped up in a way so that it
actually lights us up now probably it
won't be the best
idea to put it on top of the bag until
I've pulled out all the important tools
that we're going to
require for this quick dab sesh that we
are about
to that we're about to do
here all right kind of show you a bit of
that view don't want to cut it all
off got a little bit and I got the the
boat and
the all right keep it
going trying my best here people I think
that's pretty good we got a fisherman
over here pulling the Nets it's pretty
cool looks like they just pulled up with
their
boat all right nail hash
Dabber nail hash Dabber all right I'll
go put some water in the little hit man
as always
all
right got the Hitman all sorted
out with saltwater it's going to be a
salt watery
rip
um I'm not even sure where I put the
nail I know I pulled it out oh there it
is the nail always comes in handy with
the
Hitman so we'll pop that on
there all right all right so try to
stand at a reasonable distance so I'm
not right up on the camera with my head
chopped out of it but uh I don't really
have a table here so it's going to be a
little
bit of a of a
workout especially for the dabs going to
have to be Steady Hand Steady Hand
Richardson is what they call me out here
dabbing on the Pacific Ocean and if you
guys want to learn where this particular
place is um when you're heading uh South
uh North nor West Northwest on Marine
Drive which is Marine Drive North which
when you come off of uh the Lion's Gate
Bridge if you go left or right you're
going into North Vancouver or West
Vancouver you want to take the West
Vancouver left which wraps around and
takes you uh towards Whistler the lower
It's The Old Highway basically before
the big Highway got put in and as you
pass the gas station about 6 km from the
bridge um you'll come up to a bridge and
I I showed it a little bit it's got uh
it's basically and I'll show it right at
the end of the video so you guys get an
idea where it is there's just a
staircase right next to the end of this
little Bridge there's uh rails on each
side that are kind of silver and white
and at the at the end you just pull in
I'll name I'll give you guys the street
name as well when we get up there and um
yeah there's just the staircase you come
down here and there's literally this
epic beautiful almost private beach I'm
not sure if you guys can see there's
some people right there look I'm
squashing their heads squashing their
heads any new K Kids in the Hall fans
out there remember the squashing your
heads video that was classic classic
hilarity all right so we're doing a
brave move here we've got the
dab on the Dabber and we're now going to
heat up our
nail outside dabbing is always a little
bit tricky just because you can't really
see the heat of the nail I go by the
sound as long as the torch is making the
right sound I know that I'm uh I'm
heating it up
good and uh luckily it's not windy at
all so there's literally no wind easily
get a good dab
here all
right dabs up guys
well that was enjoyable that was nice I
feel
elevated I'm probably going to relax sit
on the beach see if I can't catch some
seals dolphins or whales of course if if
we do I'll definitely share with you
guys the wonderful audience in bubble
man's world can't thank you guys enough
for subscribing for sharing the videos
uh for talking about it for being a part
of it cuz really bubble man's world is
nothing without the world of people
which make which makes up uh all of you
guys and I thank you for it and I hope
you enjoyed the dab and uh yeah I think
we'll call it a day on this one but uh
if I see anything cool I'll definitely
share it with you and I'll I'll I'll
make sure that I write in the comments
the name of that street that you can
turn right on uh uh to park to get down
to this beach so thanks for watching
Bubble man's world and we will talk to
you guys soon peace PE