[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and I guess it's pre puff Wednesday it's
not Wednesday is it it's BC day it's BC
day Monday Sund and we've got Sarah
Sunday visiting out from the East Coast
well not really the East Coast but East
fromal Central more I guess Ontario
Ontario I always thought Manitoba is
Central really Ontario we're in we're
our own
onario and then Johnny B who hasn't uh
oh jeez I guess I really haven't made
many shows so it's not like you haven't
been on them they just haven't been made
no actually I've been um doing some
Drive shifting videos myself excellent
excellent and that's going well for you
teaching the the wills the ways of what
I do the ways of the sift well speaking
of sift I'm about to light a pure look
at that hash spliff we love hash look at
that yeah that is a beauty that's all
just dry SI roll to damn near Perfection
that is you should really get in there
at the camera and show the camera what
it looks like wow look at actually here
bring the camera a little closer so you
guys can see what we're talking about
here
it grabbing it get it on the end so they
can see the little
spiral yeah yeah getting up and looking
at that well it is beautiful it's a work
of a master work you know what you know
there a lot of art that goes into making
a pure H joint that's for sure
definitely care and attention I think
you've talked about it yeah a little bit
you know my friend that makes them does
a wonderful job he's been making them
for like 12 years at this point in time
and I say we smoke it I think that's
probably a really good idea a nice
little on the end of The Joint look at
that nice blue smoke coming off of it
instantly very
blue nice and dense looking I love how
when you blew on that the smoke went
through the other end like nor when you
blow on the end of a joint and it just
kind of go you blew on that just blew
right the other end like yeah it's
like well there you go Sarah welcome to
BC thank you very much I will smoke this
with care look at that that is beautiful
thank you so much for this lovely
welcome awesome chilling out it's a
beautiful day once again I have to say
we've had a pretty epic summer this year
nicer than uh usual oh beautiful summer
you've definitely gotten Ontario's
weather basically and we've gotten your
weather it's been shitty and cold and
cold at night such a burn cu the winter
was so harsh too know right [ __ ] that
barely got to
30° they let me past yeah I just got
back back from Jamaica and I have to say
it is you know as hot right now right
here as it was when I left really really
oh when you left yes it hasn't changed I
was going to say cuz Jamaica what was it
like it looked like it rained a little
bit there for you uh we got a little bit
of rain it was nice it hadn't rained in
like over 13 weeks in some of the
parishes so they were very very happy to
have uh that rainfall there while we
were there and of course we were joking
that we brought the
rain who brought the rain man come on
there you go rain maker and he ended
giddy actually told me that he he done
some turtle thing that he drew in the
sand or something I don't know what it
was about some rain look at the ash on
that by the way you should probably show
the camera how lovely the ash is nice
color I don't want to put it too close
cuz then we lose the Sun but it's a nice
white ash there you go this looks very
fine and mhm like like it would be just
like the lightest dust you don't really
get a chance really I think it's um
maybe we can um learn how we can all
make our own house strengths at home oh
wouldn't that be great I'd love to know
how I'd love to know all your tricks cuz
I'm sure you're very I did a post on
Facebook that definitely inspired a lot
of people to do it and quite a few
people have posted pictures and whatnot
but I I could probably do a video easy
enough I was kind of waiting to talk to
my friend cuz I was really hoping on
getting him to do it cuz he's the master
you know I could do it but he's the
master he knows the ratios of the
quality of resin that are required he
knows the temperature to meld them
together in the shapes and sizes that
are needed the thickness how to roll it
how to the whole nine yards right it's
lovely it's beautiful when the ash you
just hit it it just it's just so soft
it's like soft powder but
um you should do that yeah I I I will
one day it'll it'll it's a matter of
it's a matter of going back to uh the
cies and visiting my friend Ron and when
I'm visiting him uh I'm going to go
visit my other friend who uh
is
nearby two for one trip sounds like yeah
two birds one stuff it's a two for one
trip nowadays it's usually a four or
five for one trip it's good to be busy
yeah there's always a few dang that's
quite lovely yeah I'm really liking
these uh these pure hash joints it's a
nice thing to get back to that yes this
is perfect for me because I don't like
bugs really I'm not so much for I mean I
can deal I be enjoying the dabs of this
morning because they haven't killed me
nice but but this is up my alley okay
you're inspiring me man yeah right on
yeah first time I ever saw those things
I just thought that's a great concept
come
on yeah it's definitely um you got to be
very careful end super tasty yep 100%
wow that's so nice it's way taster than
um in any other format it's insane it's
because there's so much it's a gr of
hash we right now well sounds reasonable
let's do it I want to do that every day
multiple times you can do it okay I know
I can I uh I did a video of just smoking
one of these to my own head and it's
almost my most popular video there you
go and it's only a month
old pure I'm telling people are into
this yeah they
are how big can you make these things
can you make a giant one oh I'm sure
that's the video that talking about
earlier that's what you need do that
pure giant house make let's see how big
we can get it we do them in steps figure
out what's important to make a big one
make it burn really well look at all
these ideas coming back from Ontario AB
I love it I love ideas you should bring
that up there it's all
about it's all about hooking up puffing
bowls and puffing puffing dubes
surrounded by beautiful strings and
talking about medicine that's it man
absolutely that's how the ideas flow I
want to try something I got this little
bug bite the other day it's really itchy
so I'm definitely going to I put some um
bomb on it last night and
then today I was going to grab some
cream give me a shot and see how it
works I brought some CBC cream back well
I'm definitely going to grab some CBD
CBC
CBC from Mark I'm going to put it on
this little itchy thing and I'll tell
you about it on puff Wednesday in two
days we go is that two days from now
yeah is two days wow craziness how time
flies it's f when you're
flying and I was thinking we should go
put the boat in the water yes great idea
I was lured with hash and boat ideas so
hash and boat ideas yeah I heard of that
the boat might happen the smoking on the
water I believe was the the O this is
cracking
uhoh
uhoh I do the two two finger like put
your other finger on it hold it yeah so
it's more like if you use one finger
it'll just collapse I understand it
requires a technique it it
does it's uh the trick is really to try
and leave the ash on the Cherry it seems
to cool the Cherry down I actually have
this phone
call while we're on the video
seriously I thought he was I thought he
was serious there for a second I was
like I'm going to take this phone call
what's cuz of The Joint got pass you
well I just did it as soon as you said
that I'm like well obviously you don't
have time for The Joint
either you know what the best thing
about the house joint is when it comes
apart we can still throw that in the
bong and smoke it boom and it's even
better no no good for the environment
there's no waste actually pretty good
for it's funny I've posted me smoking a
few of these and people like Oh I
thought you didn't smoke paper bubble
man I'm like I I don't I don't a pure
house it's just funny when people are so
convinced in their what they think is a
reality there
no think before you speak it's always
good well it's quite nice to be able to
smoke up your house joint um now I think
last time we tried it on the water
didn't we um dump in the water we should
now try do no last time I jumped in the
water with the whole thing in my pocket
and then we smoked it at uh the seven
sales in Vancouver that's right wow by
the Cactus Club there that's right in
front of the planes yeah anyway we're
going to go do the boat we'll catch up
with you when we get to the boat
all right guys we have jumped in the
boat John and Sarah behind me here kind
of trying to get them between my head
they're both sort of too close to no
John that way Sarah that way there you
go now you're fitting so we just jumped
in the water here we're about to head
out to Horseshoe Bay out yonder you can
see it's damn near a perfect day out
there on the house sound sure feels like
a perfect day it is beautiful there's
the lkti island shrimping vessel
so yeah we're going to go for a little
boat ride here we'll share a little bit
of it with you while we're doing it and
otherwise we'll see you when we get to
Horseshoe Bay
that
good is this the local area here this is
this is the office man this is the lion
office off
off wow it's
um
417 4117 eh yeah good timing but I guess
I think I'm going to have to grab that
it's time it's time to do a little 420
Ripper on this Monday afternoon with
Sarah Sunday and John Bell Bubble Man
the house
sound why don't we H put on some music
let's do that let uh I got the pong
ready all right you ge her up I'm going
to go put some tunes on all right guys 1
minute warning to 4:20 we're sitting out
here on the house
sound I couldn't find my tripod so I am
the
tripod you are happy 420 so okay 420
Sarah
okay thank you
purp and we all use the herb to maintain
my
[Music]
focus oh that was
tasty tasty is
[Music]
good I guess it's my turn
jeez all these beautiful things to
choose from I think I'm going to take
this giant ball he went right for the
[Music]
watermelon for more than one reason GL I
see
I seriously no
beine oh yeah there you go he's got to
have be
[Music]
line of course's got beine that lighter
just won't be
[Music]
here we go I always use beine when I can
if you do ever see me sucking on a
lighter it happens the odd
time it's cuz the only thing available
cuz you had to maintain his Focus yeah
it's good to have standards and
everybody has their standards I think it
works better than the
lighter oh yes it's definitely cleaner
we got organic matter
yeah the song just said it all for
us it did I'm going to have to get back
in there do your research and
see and long life and long life and long
life some local kids just out having a
good day this is a good life
yeah
seriously I think I'm almost ready to
have a swim here oh
yeah I cannot come here without actually
getting into the ocean that has to
happen well we got to go eat some food
in hes Bay too should we do that first
and then come
swim swim and
eat eat and
swim you don't want to swim on a full
stomach I don't mind okay
all right we'll catch
[Music]
up Johnny be jumped the gun he's in the
water I missed it I missed it
interesting okay why not oh there goes
Sarah you guys aren't messing
around how is it it's um refreshing I
would have to say that Jamaica's water
was a lot warmer refreshing this yeah
but this water is pretty nice I haven't
been in the Pacific
Ocean and I don't even know I can't even
think before my accident was being at
least 8 or 10 years wow you sure picked
a good day I just jumped in it was I
know the cold water is H it's
okay I love it wow I think I'm going to
jump in with these guys backward
flip the backward flip 420 rips and
backward flips don't not hit your
head care like 420 rips and backward
flips oh backward
flips uhoh oh no woo woo backward right
there oh my God so much fun imagine if
my camera rolled into the ocean there oh
God no we would have been like
[ __ ] oh it's so nice by the way come on
this isn't even this is barely
refreshing so this is me hesitating do I
want to get in the water listen if you
want to feel refreshing yeah pin drop
about 6 ft you know like hold your arms
and pin drop you go down four or 5T
you'll feel it on your feet yeah I bet
it's like 20°
different you feel it scuba diving fast
feel that was it
sual now I'm going to go down 20 ft go
what's up guys swimming in the Pacific
Ocean you got to do it sometimes BC
fabulous hey happy BC happy BC day yes
is called BC living BC life BC life BC
life I like it I wish I was living here
so I'm going to go that way Ontario it's
not quite as not quite this this is
awesome and then you look over there and
Buddy's just like surfing behind his
boat how [ __ ] I mean this is a
lifestyle this is a very good lifestyle
yep very nice my children were born over
there on the water oh no way in that
neighborhood with the White House
yeah both of
them that kid looks like he's having a
blast
I have all the equipment to do
that like being in the can't hear
anything just float you're close well I
got to say that was pretty damn nice
little back flip into the ocean I don't
know if you guys saw that that was off
camera but I landed quite nicely on my
face it was quite quite beautiful
anyway I think I'm going to get these
guys rounded up and head into Horseshoe
Bay there is a little bit of a chop out
there so we're going to need a little
bit more time than I
thought D see when we get there oh my
God I know I'm sorry I didn't mean to
eat like
that oh we're casual like that oh it's
warm here yeah it is for some reason
it's warm right there uhoh it's warm in
this spot right here I wonder why
oh I uh took a big piss there that is
that why it's foamy look oh stepping off
the boat onto the dock here at horese
Bay with Sarah and John so we head up
for some fish and
chips fish and chips is what did you
think of that BC fery as we pulled up it
was pretty cool thing looked like the
bloody Love Boat yeah it was uh we
waving and puffing and yeah yeah lots of
people were waving hey I was waving joh
was waving like waving everybody yeah
and they were waving back know they
enjoyed the tunes sure I didn't even
have the top speaker so they probably
didn't really hear them very well that's
okay we heard them we did we enjoyed it
they were for us it was really for us oh
left it was a boat so there's the boat
house pretty fancy restaurant if you
want to eat really nice food we can go
there I say we do go there the boat
house yeah let's go to the boat house so
much nicer than fish and chips cool plus
you can get fish and chips there I'm
down totally down CS is a bit fast
foodish
I haven't been to the boat house in so
long and that deck just called my name
excellent yeah excellent I'm down I want
the full experience we'll head to the
boat house yay recheck it out so
exciting it's exciting yes well you do
this all the time not really okay cool
I'm glad that we're both on the same
level of
excitement I see bubbles oh look at all
all the time I like I see people
swimming with disgusting water
you've never been in the water before
maybe go over there though look how
clean it is yeah that looks okay that
looks
murky it's
murky all right so we just got to the
boat house here guys this awesome menu
see some of the things on the menu here
what did we get we got some coconut
shrimp and some AI tuna tacos I'm sure
we'll get some comments on the
radioactivity of the ocean um if the
ocean is radioactive I hate to tell you
but the rest of the world is too
probably uh it's not going to stay out
of the ocean and just stay in the ocean
goes in the air goes into everything
dring it right now Cheers Cheers here
cheers this restaurant's right on the
water you can see the ferry that we just
passed and a little island with some
Arbutus trees out
front and uh yeah real nice spot one of
these classic BC spots if you've ever
come to BC and you've stayed at horese
Bay for a short period of time through
the ferry transfers this is where we're
at so we'll be eating soon guys all
right the food just got here guys how
does it look oh three piece Hitt and
Fries y three piece Hitt and Fries
called I went for the uh salmon burger
and fries we're going to eat so bone
[Music]
Appetit well we're just finishing up
dinner here and uh we figured um hey how
about a little bit of dessert huh
little bit of Barb a little bit of Barb
checking out the new pen I'll tell you
it's uh it's very easy to stuff and
fill that was tasty guys was that tasty
sound she like it was really good I
think I'm going to have this going for
the AO tuna Taco it was really tasty too
it was very nice so we're just kind of
sitting here
chilling um definitely a nice little
toy but I mean you know
Bey fair in the background taking off oh
that was a big uh rip yeah we are
sitting on the outside here so it's
quite nice we're in the '90s smoke in
the '90s Rip's just rolling behind you
it's actually um some dryp nice that I
got from uh the great Gardener but I
cleaned for the great
Gardener we always like the great
Gardener yes I know I saw just the other
day Wonder appearance as usual you were
hanging out with man I was Matt and
Sarah saw them both at Jacob's wedding
awesome times very good good times good
folks well there we are guess it's time
for me to get some
dessert that was a big rip that was nice
s just released a big rip I blow it
straight up cuz that's a lot of smoke
right now sitting there that's awesome
look at how much smoke that
is oh Johnny
chimney Johnny
chimney I'm profal Johnny chimney no we
Chim we at
um
cchq
cchq here comes another fairy they just
never stop do they it it is a long
weekend but you see there man fairy
lineups must be
brutal heading back over to the boats
too because it's called L like
you know when you get a random
friend sounds good see you later
of
the empty making too much nice so Inc
small to cuz I'm by the way they car
arms in arms stepping out with the arms
relinquishing the power of the P when I
know to compromise much less the so tell
them still don't get them how K
and but I with smoke so get don't stop
half with your throat rain drops falling
from the sky will be multiplied
no drops and paralyze all with them in a
disguise great drops falling from the
[Music]
sky getting a call yep Bird's calling me
how awesome is that we're hting this uh
bird yo
bird I am on the Pacific Ocean floating
in a boat hitting an apex
pen painting the Apex y right on woo woo
what kind of coil is in that what we
asking uh yeah what's the resistance on
the coil what's the resistance on the
coil that's awesome dude well you're on
my video right now I'm filming a video
right now and you're on it bird is on
the phone with me here let's we got you
on uh
speaker you're on speaker
bird hey how's it going everybody I wish
I was there I'm actually flying out the
Down Road Ste
miss my friend bub man let's do this
again Jama baby hell yeah dude you sent
a care
package oh yeah took the care pack to
Jamaica and we'll be getting there on
the 11th so Jamaica will be having Apex
pass Apex pass Apex we got the whole
crew lined up oh beautiful man you're
taking care of them as I knew you
would crew care people hell yeah dude
they show enough that you know
i i i SP just so I can never rep just
welcome let go by fully
fully all right well enjoy the the rest
of your day and just want you know your
package will be there on Friday thanks
bird say hi to Giddy say hi to Tony and
we'll talk real soon brother definitely
enjoy the rest of the evening say hi to
the family you bet man
bless all right that was a nice little
call to get from bird while we're
filming here on the Pacific Ocean you
can see it's just a perfect freaking day
out here right
now how you guys feeling back there
fabulous Apex and out yeah about 15 now
reach for the Apex yeah it
works all
right welcome back guys hi guys we're uh
we're back here on my deck we had a bit
of a boat
experience exp speaker fell in fell in
the ocean that was a little it's like a
35b speaker that fell off my tower just
missed Sarah bounced off the side of the
boat I'll never forget saying what was
that and then you guys going your
speaker
speaker like a helmet or something black
thing rushing at me and you see this
thing that thing was Heavy too made
contact with my head it would have like
tell we be hospital right now yes we
absolutely would have been reconstructed
hospital with the camera John are here
ward in Squamish BC we're going to
finish off the day helicop Sarah was
having she was having such a good day be
you have my Dabber or I I actually have
mine your Dabber yeah so what I was
going to offer you was medy My Little
Pony or I will take anything in all the
above all right let's start over here
it's the it's the
start full right in there this is uh
first bounce this morning which um of
course I did a video on the other day
for my Sifty
Sundays and I love giving away that hash
because as Sarah knows and as he's about
ready to explain that taste of the first
bounce woohoo to I love my dry SI
screens they're useful they're extremely
useful I really like that ceramic
insert that was a little bit different
from the one that sat on the top where
before that one's actually inside now I
like that yeah well you know what
happened was the other one sat on the
top because do you notice how this is a
little taller right here yeah okay
because I was going to put a screen on
top of mine I asked them to shave this
down so it was even with this when they
shaved this down it made this fatter oh
and so this no longer went inside so
this won't fit in my other tie nail top
but it fits in the one that has not been
shaved down that's
hilarious well Sarah um we're all going
to do a hit of medy here and then we're
going to do all hit of uh each one so
I'm allow Mark to dump that on there for
thank you thank you all right there is a
bit of a trick to it in the sense that
uh if you don't get it off if you put if
you hold it over the tie nail for any
amount of time it melts to the skillet
to I'm going to say it melts and then
you've got to scoop it off the titanium
and the whole trip is is that we're
hitting it off the ceramic and it is a
different tasting hit subtly but it's
still
different one for you Jo super tasty in
here for that and going down the line I
clean the skillet tool as well thank you
very much I saw that we always talk
about scle clean your Skillet tool
before you pass you have seen in Jamaica
Tony opened up all these beautiful
hashes and I looked inside it was like
flow OG it was just all like like a
dirty Skillet tool got put in there like
four or five times to perfect hash it's
it hurt my
soul we puffed it nonetheless of course
it it's just an OC it's an OCD thing you
know the thing that I kind of laughed
about um is when you're like where's the
Bruce Banner it's all gone well this
same thing happened in Barcelona the
Bruce Banner when the Bruce Banner the
full Mountain I got one little hit that
Tony saved me and then I I pressed it
out and I put it on top of my denail and
it was there for days when I put it
pulled it off of the denail and put it
on like a the top of a a little
container Giddy Up came and and puffed
like 80 to 90% of it which was like
totally legit that his nose found the
sweet piece and that he was but it was
one I I just kept forgetting that like
when you're puffing with a big group of
people and everything's game they're
going to want the same thing that you
want so it's like and but the funny
thing was and I share all my stuff
evenly that was just something that Tony
said I saved this for you yes this I've
been saving this for a year for you it's
one little hit I want you to have it and
then I turn around and it's almost it's
almost all gone and when he said
it was funny I I remember when we were
um no it was actually
amdam and and uh the Bruce Banner
someone actually took it all and put it
into a joint remember yeah that's why I
laugh so hard because this had already
happened previously almost almost a year
ago with tobacco yeah and they mixed it
with tobacco too yeah that was even the
worst part about it oh my God the
kill all of it the [ __ ] no it was it was
like that's why when he said this I'm
not saying you can't say it but listen
but funny thing was was Tony was was
upset he was like but then he was like
oh I rolled it he's like where's that
hash and he's like I rolled it into a
joint you rolled it into a joint well
let's puff it so then Tony took a hit of
it and it was full of tobacco so then he
was
like the hell else smokes with tobac on
there sure oh it was funny it it was um
one of those things that uh for me when
you said it on your last trip in Jamaica
I personally I called G I was like what
are you doing man I laughed out loud so
hard watching that video yesterday
because I know a story yeah it was the
second yeah I was just like o again
second time oo so that would be the
Astra boy that was um I that one got a
kick I grew this this actually
particular resin I grew at between the
temperatures of 65 and 70° Fahrenheit
and I kept my humidities around 30% the
whole time so it was kind of like m
talked about growing at a lower
temperature to try after David Allen
told us that growing at a lower
temperature would it was 100% David
Allen mentioned it and I said I'll do it
and and well even before that I said I
was very interested in it I never did
anything in the regards to it cuz I
don't have uh the air conditioning units
or anything I run a very simple system
and summertime is not an option for me
but I'd love the idea of a cold room
grow so um this is the cold room grow
experiment um what we're smoking yeah
nice it's an idea do it with the My
Little Pony dessert hash oh some dessert
hash that Astro Boy too will give you
almost an anxiet is high like that c99
sort of some people hit it and they're
just like okay so do you want to enjoy
that asra boy high and then hit them for
a couple minutes you know the longest
time sit back we're in the shade now we
uh had if you noticed we Jerry rigged
the um the towel the towel on top of the
umbrella it's giving us it's giving us
shade certain level of it we could give
uh give joh a little bit more shade
seems like he's coming no I don't think
I'm going to get the sun's pass that
point it's not too hot anyway yet this
at this point in time I just lean back I
get down here mhm chill oh we've got our
ice water we've definitely had a nice
hashy day today is BC day and we did it
up I would first swim in the Pacific
Ocean yes before yourent first time
before your acent first time in years
and the best part about it EXC about two
weeks ago I was swimming in the ocean in
Jamaica you I was there with you I know
it's like twice in almost 30 days that's
like Wicked aw I don't know it's um Good
Vibes I've always had the urge to swim
in the ocean when it was near and it was
one of the reasons why I wanted to live
near the ocean absolutely I people don't
think about it too much but when you
look at the ocean it's a freedom to get
you can go in that ocean on a boat and
literally go anywhere in the world if
you have the proper vessel that's
basically that's what that why do we Ser
Road don't even do that why because it's
Freedom you can go anywhere that is a
great way looking at
terrifying sa out into the world well
considering what you said it was a good
day that we only had the speaker come
down didn't get towed there was
no you know wasn't too much money ripped
all the way to Horseshoe Bay oh my God
that was so fast that was great but
great great great so much fun yeah like
I'm all like super paying attention
making sure there's no it's the ocean
you know you guys out there that have
boats on lakes
it's not the same no it's not the same
there's killer whales in
there well I didn't we didn't see any no
but they jumped saw eag though remember
we see a bag and I saw a seal oh you did
I did yes oh ex I did see that seal too
I was I felt bad actually cuz when we
were on Boer I probably could have just
gone around the island and showed you
guys uh baby seals out on the Rocks dang
well next time they're out
there I found I like nature
it's like that's why I'm here so is that
why you're here I well I like you came
for a beautiful wedding for some friends
well I didn't I'm here for a multitude
of reasons but one of which is the
natural beauty of uh British
Columbia I don't have mountains I don't
have that Vista so you were at um Jacob
and Nicole's wedding yes yes and lots of
cannabis activists were there I'm
certain um there was yes there was a
select group of cannabis activists
including men
Sarah and excellent uh Adam very cool
well I've known them a long time and
it's great to see that tied it up yeah
yeah amazing amazing after all these
years I look forward to one day being
able official to re I eloped with my
wife yes that' be nice yeah we eloped in
Jamaica in 95 so you're going to do it
up get married well I wanted to do it
right before my father passed away and
that sort of put the kibos on that we
were going to do a 10 year anniversary
but maybe we could do a 20- year
anniversary or something like
that I've been with my wife for 25 years
we've been married now whatever it is 19
oh my God I know I was a monster too big
mine was pretty big too but forgetting
that I'm a baby whenever he gives me big
works like that I'll just give him one
back and then my next one's a more
reasonable size I'm not loading up
anything don't be sorry I I was I was
trying to be nice dude I always I always
like to remember I said it see that's
the little got me ripped this is this
was the My Little Pony spit it at you
though hey if you do it'll be for the
show MLP it's being renamed to MLP MLP
MLP it's just the way it is MLP is that
like sounds like a political person I
don't care is it an MLP I'm past the
point that's pretty close to MLB this is
good res Major League Baseball Major
League oh MLB right W I wasn't even
thinking that
Ripper that pure dry sift to Will Rock
You with the full tur content right yeah
I know it's still
makes but it's a good cough like got
like kind of like dho like I feel like
I'm being suffocated cough yeah that's
scary yeah this is more just like very
expectorant it is for sure and I find
the more you cough you know I I'm not
really a big fan of that if you don't
cough you don't get off saying I don't
think that's true but I'll tell you the
more you cough sometimes wow the more
you do get off it is true was because um
you're choking yourself with oxygen you
can't breathe so of course you're going
to get a little to the brain you're
going to get a little bit of a buzz from
it just
saying yeah that's just my theory but
you know what Ian what's up Pooch oh
this one cat and dog so much fun my dog
got shaved he got he go little de now
he's like a little deer hello Oreo Mr C
Mr C is in the house here Mr C
scratching me up oh oh
nice why you hurt me like that so I was
thinking I got I got I got um I got like
280 gram of fresh Frozen asra boy in the
freezer yeah nice I got another like 70
gram of uh nice dry popcorn nice I got
another like qu pound of nice solid big
buds awesome and then I got another
about 70 80 grams of some smaller other
popcorn so I want to run a test I want
to take 70 gram crush it crust get all
this get let's clean it run the 70 grams
of fresh Frozen clean it or run it like
a a single bounce we'll do uh clean it
crush it down completely see how much
resin we get from 70 gr of dry and then
two how much grams we get from 280 gam
of fresh okay there you go cuz then it
gives us a ratio the ratio should be
accurate if you dry yeah you can also do
it this way dry the material that you
use fresh afterwards and you'll get the
dry weight of that herb so we'll do that
so it'll tell you the cuz this people
are always so confused like they like
dry yields way better well it's like
well dude of course it does it's a
higher ratio of plant matter that's just
common sense dry yields way better
course it would be it doesn't yield any
different it yields the same yield the
Yi's not going to change it course
obviously yeah oh my go for me I'm not
looking at the actually the I'm not
looking at the yield that I'm curious
about I'm more I'm more curious I'm more
Curious on get no no not the ratio
either curious on
the let's let's just take this whole a
lack of Tes in the dry obviously I mean
that you won't have to be curious about
it it's a fact of science dry material
or have less Tarin than fresh material
100% however dry um triome membranes are
easier to dry with water hash and in a
sense in my opinion give like a nicer
fresh Frozen's awesome for a short
period yeah but then it Butters out hard
and it's like it's just so hard to dry
that stuff properly it can be done but
here in the Northwest Pacific Northwest
we should mention really that's where we
are thanks for the kick there yeah I was
like he's doing a little freak Now give
me a kick um the humidity is high here
it's like really high so you maybe even
getting room that's more controlled so
high it Butters out Matt's dryp I know
like come on all the time look this is
it right here let's smoke some of that
there Matt's dryp look at it's buttered
it should be just powdered out stuff
nice he even said that he's like check
this out so it takes the argument out of
the white out sort of all water hash is
wet yeah it's hard you know Jen do on
Facebook she's mentioning her theory is
is that it's natural plant acids I don't
know if it's natural plant acids if it's
tpin there's all sorts of different
solvents in the resin itself thanks Matt
it could be breaking down the wax
membrane but it seems to have something
to do with
moisture I believe what do I know though
so I'm well baked here and I'm actually
you know I just did a rip of that
um was that the Barb or the
off Barb uh Barb or blue blue uh
blue blue Blue's Barb too I have no idea
what's going on zoning out well we're
going to give you one
more because I just I just I just had
this one Barb you must have been puffing
Barb with uh Matt and um I believe there
was some Barb I believe there was some
Barb and some CBD Renee and some there
were it was all good it was all good
we're all happy I know you said smaller
so I got to go see those guys soon I I
need to go film an episode I have I'm
sure she said another epic adventure it
always is I love going and visiting
those guys okay they're people to enjoy
talking about you know Matt's just so
passionate about growing and about
getting uh the proper medicine it's
really nice talking with him about
growing techniques and stuff like that
because when you sit down there and talk
with he with someone like [ __ ]
um all any anybody who's breeding and
growing at any kind of level is doing it
because they passion like talking with
you sir about how you love growing and
talking about the different times and
temperatures and humidities and it's
kind of it's kind of nice to be able to
sit down and talk to somebody who's
spent years doing exactly what we love
doing yeah how many years have you been
growing
for seven or eight maybe nice maybe I
guess it's maybe about eight now that's
fun yeah and what you're actually
getting like a vacation right now did
you shut your garden down for the summer
no I'm lucky that um I have a partner
boyfriend that's able to take care of it
w that's great and uh and uh yeah so I'm
lucky enough thank you to be able to
come out here and enjoy BC and see all
my friends and go to wedding and uh
hopefully I'll come back again soon yeah
I always used to come back like until I
moved here I came back once and then I
came back like twice and then I came
back like three time like it just you
know what I mean it's just like coming
here quite often I came here when I was
three I never went back well your
parents brought you here it's a little
harder when you just go by yourself I
thought I came when I was three man like
you know what I hitchhiked into BC when
I was about 17 that's awesome i' had
gone before with my grandma when I was
nine seven you were with your wife uh no
the first time I came here I hitchhiked
by myself with my
snowboard really yeah you determined
sounds like an adventure it was quite
something I did Jasper and I did Lake
Louise cruise through b got all the way
to vanc couver it was very fun my last
ride dropped me off and I thought they
were pretty cool people but I left my
backpack in there with all my like these
clothes I bought in Central America and
like a CD player with like a you know
like a a bunch of good CDs and I never
they never came back they were the ones
that dropped me off they knew the house
damn yeah it was a bummer it was what it
was you know it happens I got pulled
over in that same van in the interior in
B and we're like way up in this mountain
town and his whole dashboard is full of
what did he have he had like sugar cubes
wrapped in tin foil or something and
each one had two hits of LSD in them
then he had a giant ashtray on the
dogghouse just full of roaches and we
got pulled over me driving by the RCMP
oh and and it wasn't insured the vehicle
wasn't God so think of this how is this
possible in any way shape of that you
could get away
from that situation could you imagine
how impossible that would be it be
pretty hard so this is what happened
okay he doesn't see the LSD he seemingly
ignores the joints yeah he doesn't ask
to search the van who he tells us that
if we make a promise to just pull up the
street a bit here he'll take us to a
park and just sleep in the van overnight
and then walk down the hill and right at
the bottom of the hill there's an
insurance place and buy insurance for
the van that if we did that he he'd be
good with it what a nice guy I'm telling
you it was ridiculous so [ __ ] small
towns RCMP though
Federal it go either way man listen all
I know is not all cops are dicks no
there're certainly not cuz this guy
certainly was not a dick and he was just
like wow okay drove us up he's like all
right guys I'm trusting you guys
tomorrow morning walk down and get the
insurance and you know being the dumbest
that we were we drove the van down the
next day inste of walking yeah
it was fine he wasn't there no of course
not still still idiots disrespectful
kind of of the situation well you know
you can wanted to say okay I'll take
your deal and I'll go with it to the
letter you want to allow him to be a
nice guy and then not ruin that for
everyone else by putting egg on his face
and saying why do I why did I trust
youly no I agree I I agree with you in
the meantime we could have spent the
night in
jail um I can't remember what else oh
dude listen for sure overnight in jail
in
holding that yeah well you were
certainly Super Lucky and he was a hit
here maybe all
right John's just feeding us hits I'm
super high
already F just little micro
dabs of
killer first
mouths it's good they're tasty as [ __ ]
it's like like good [ __ ] it's it's just
first bounce it's not even I'm first
bouncer more than anything I love it you
don't really clean your hash much well I
don't have to I bring it to you now I
haven't cleaned any of your hash in a
while it's going to be making bubble
hash with the fresh rolls and you will
me another another so much I get my
first bounce and then I wash it oh okay
I'm
I'm I'm in hash Heaven are you using the
250 and the 180 yes I do use those quite
a bit you should I do because cuz that's
a first bounce every time
all the all the time and what's good
with that was is The Leftovers that just
kind of like I got the little B don't
get me wrong I love my 70 I I'm I'm I'm
pretty much always out of 90 runs by 73
and then lately I've been mixing the 90
and the 73 only on the second run
because that's tasty nice and then I
just the first run is like the first
bounce of the fresh frozen right and
then there's the second run which is I
got to get more you know so it's like I
got stages and and now with my new
fridge that I just picked up I got three
times the ice Half Moon and I have that
separate drawer so I can actually you
know I have that freezer full of weed I
got dude I have a freezer full of weed
right now I have um three My Little
Ponies that F them that filled two half
PB bags I have three or four Astro boys
that filled a couple of half PB bags no
I just took one okay so I just took five
actually okay but I literally just took
big no no nothing big nothing big
reasonable or huge whatever just just
reasonable let's go with
reasonable I've had a I've had a lovely
day oh um well the boat ride for me and
jumping in and yes you might see me
going hard and stuff like that but
actually I I can say I told Mark how
stiff my neck was it's lightening up now
that I'm getting some little medicine
yeah bubbling it up fabulous on the
Mother Ship indeed yeah so I also have a
whack load of fresh frozen and I'll have
to I I'm not in a huge rush to get it
done cuz I have resin right now but I'll
definitely be doing it in the next week
we could do one for puff Wednesday I
have
enough maybe I'll even go get a 20
gallon machine and some 20 gallon bags
and we'll do a 20- gallon batch I'll
just literally like do everything do all
of my [ __ ] at once do do like a just's
do a lucky day profile all these like
awesome strains that I grew [ __ ]
everything that's grown it's all organic
I have no worries that I know that all
of it will be full melt yeah of course I
don't know why that is I don't consider
myself an expert grower although I will
tell you the guy that showed me and
taught me how to grow Ron hickey that
guy was a very good
teacher it was OCD to the T that helps
and so focused and like P interested in
the perspective of the plant and spend
so much time amongst the plants and in
the plant that it was a good uh he's he
was a good Mentor to have for learning
how to grow cannabis good teacher is
very valuable hey remember our videos in
the Jamaican field the blueberry I know
skunk so this is the orange Hill
blueberry skunk from the field that John
and I were in I saved one seed actually
this wasn't from the field we were in
this one was
from um the nicest Bud we saw at inad
yard while we were in Kingston and
remember we got showed that really nice
Bud that you and Tony smoked yes and it
was pretty much the nicest BD we saw
while we were there the whole time so
this is that nice so I'm definitely
going to get a cutting of
this I don't know I think this is the
one you said didn't have much of a smell
yeah it doesn't have much G it's kind of
like
tomatoey average Stander smell the the
other Jamaican that I have has a really
nice stock smell I it's deep it's piny
yeah really piny as well the uh sweet
skunk and the congales which is right
behind you
and I don't know you just moved away
from that and after you put that plant
over there and rubbing it it smells
really nice
right M what about that one what's that
barb or Afghan I think that's
Afghan from the great Gardener it's
always good to be surrounded by
interesting genetics I uh I'll be
interested to see what comes of this
particular strain that lived its life in
Jamaica and is now here it's an
experiment it's aour dedication effort
exactly learning and listening to the
plant yes the plants tell us a lot oh
that is the key yeah my uh son was
moving one of my plants uh while I was
away and he snapped one of the branches
and he just like tied it up with a rope
and it's it's doesn't even need the Rope
anymore that thing is solid F itself
yeah totally awesome I was like how'd
you know that got pepp intive you just
got it right away okay so next
Generation gner oh yeah fabulous hand
down those skills he's growing all the
peppers here as well so we have a whole
row of uh sweet peppers that we're
growing and we planted the sunflowers
together by in seed we have habiscus
cell going we have an
avocado yeah just a potato that needs
watering desperately up in the
bucket wow yeah it's desperately need
some water it needs some water it's a
potato though it'll have water to feed
those leaves for so much longer than
most of these those leaves are all
coming out of the potato yes they're
good solid greens yes quite nice but I
imagine that would impact your potato
production uh it big
time well I guess uh we're ranting we're
just going to stay here and be stoned we
uh I'm actually quite quite high and I
have no idea hey you know what we may
see I did some dry sifting and that's
what I said I'm bring over great BC day
yes love this vacation we we may see
Sarah again but if not we uh thank you
for coming out and we'll maybe see you
next time in yes absolutely and you'll
see uh Johnny and me on puff Wednesday
in a couple of days we'll try and film
it and I'll try to get it edited the
same day and uploaded so we'll make it
short and sweet we'll make it short and
sweet peace out guys peace well we uh D
and I were driving through Vancouver on
our motorcycles and we bumped into Sarah
and John so that was pretty funny it was
cool it was pretty trippy actually uh
I'm like we should be eating at Joy's
right now where's Darren and I'm like
there's mark
so I CAU the UI in the middle of
Hastings right in Vancouver dinner after
a good session put her in reverse and
backed it up on a street as they were
stuck in traffic it was
great so we figured we' come into
Stanley Park have a little sesh um this
is generally a pretty popular spot
however it's so [ __ ] windy that dabs
aren't going to happen here but we got
the Apex and so I figured you want to
light that up S yeah sure sounds good
Apex down with some of d420 K's uh full
melt dry sift so full melt dry full melt
dry sift in the house there he goes he
knows about the full melt dry
sift she said dab his head
to you're like dab and he's like whoa
guys come
che's just bumped into some dudes
they're going to come down and hit some
bowls with
this they know about bub I don't know
they know da that's
enough oh we're filming this okay
right no you won't be on TV you're not
looking to be on YouTube Can't brisk oh
come on don't be coward risk it that's
okay they're here on vacation behind the
scenes supporting you guys okay we like
the support from behind the scenes we
like our house it's critical well be
well peace guys cheers guys on guys
cheers guys all right so yeah let's just
hit a few more Apex bowls and we'll bug
her off to a part of the Park where we
can well I I used to come here for the
9:00 bang and at 9:00 every night a
cannon goes up makes me cl bang that was
back in the
days yeah this is a classic spot that
you can come here at almost any time and
catch people smoking herb here a lot of
people come and smoke herb at the
Lighthouse so that's North Vancouver and
behind us and West Vancouver and then
we've got uh the rest of Stanley Park
goes into the lion's Gate Bridge which
is one of two ways to get into the the
north the north side of Vancouver
there's the other one over there
beautiful ride through the park second
nrows this thing is hitting like a champ
wow dude this thing hits like a champ
hits like a
[Music]
champ wow I didn't even know that lower
level it's called the seaw wall it goes
around the entire park actually the seaw
wall is the most popular thing at van in
in Stanley Park it goes the entire round
the whole park I think it's 11 km long
sticker bikes down there dude I would
love to that would be amazing ride it
ride it I've I've done it on a bicycle
you can do it on skateboard and those
whatever those shoes wheels are roller
blades roller blades yeah if you want to
wear
those I'm not a rollerblader can you
tell good time I remember last time we
were uh on the other side of the bridge
in West
every we watched that crew that big ship
and it was like doesn't clear by very
much either it's a couple feet you're
surprised well it's about 20 or 30 but
it's still like it looked like 2T from
here yeah it's pretty pretty big
wow what are you saying D where do you
want to go do dabs to dry
sift wherever we can get away with it
nicely and easily anywhere we want you
want to do in the park somewhere that's
like low wind over by a tree or
something maybe we can find a Big Hollow
Tree or something anyway we're going to
go figure out a spot to dab up finish
off on the Apex all right so we're at
Prospect Point going to go check out the
view here from Stanley Park across the
water to uh West
Vancouver and uh I guess the guys are
going to grab some ice cream or some
food
here we'll see what
happens let's go check out the
view get me one you want an ice cream
vanilla helicopter it's quite a Canadian
flag right there there's the Stanley
Park Lion's gate
view you can go here
nice boat
all right well I think we're going to uh
wait for the ice cream delivery from
Darren Sarah and John I'm going to head
down to one of the lower areas and have
a dab session it seems a lot less windy
over on this side of the island so we'll
catch up with you in a bit all right
West Coast ice cream
session with John and Sarah and uh soon
to be d420 k
want some ice cream yes please I see one
with your name on it right
there chocolate so um I'm thinking we
head up towards the view go down a few
levels and just pull one of those spots
as our own spot and dab it up sure let's
do it do it all right we're doing
it good she's got the fatty going
already the Dennis Hopper
fatty so we are at Stanley Park um we've
got the Lionsgate bridge right next to
us you can actually see um Mount Baker
background pretty beautiful great View
today and then we've got west north and
west Vancouver this is all West
Vancouver and behind us that we SE here
and the Pacific Ocean so it's quite an
entry Port all the all the ships that
come from around the world to bring
things to Vancouver basically come right
in through here all the cruise ships
come in and go out through here it's
definitely a bottleneck you can't really
get out the other end it's Indian Arm so
it seals up in in deep
cold what hit it up
Sir bad about that pass D's joint I'm
hitting D's joint uh full uh dry D's
joint de joint yeah so tell us tell us a
little bit about de joint hit almost
fell down it's power well de joints we
had a shop going 7 eight years shut her
down in 2008 due to a landlord and my
own I wanted to go in the bush and make
money make money Up in PG yeah so now
we're going to open up another shop here
getting married at the end of the month
and then it's full Ste ahead opening up
a shop and getting it going again seat
company there going to be a tattoo
studio in it there's going to be a
piercing studio in it there's going to
be clothing lines that you've never seen
before that's going to be new and put
out there so the whole n yards there's
going to be everything a little bit
everything I want to talk to a lot of
personal glass blowers that do it
themselves and uh buy buy stuff from
them going to talk to some of the
Distributors nice just going to do my
thing like I like I like it's a real
good social aspect of stuff that brings
people together I want to do seminars on
how to teach people how to make the dry
SI how to make the drawing public you
should make it proper not not just just
making it and figuring they're making it
right show them the right way they will
just go you do know the right way that's
the key it's uh yeah I look forward to
seeing what you produce up there what
you what you build up there with D's
joint you got a it's many hats that you
could wear up there in regards to uh
that store like you said tattooing and
distribution potentially seeds and maybe
even eventually in the beautiful world
of BC maybe one day you'll be able to
sell legal Canabis up there well that
would be optimal yes that's exactly what
i' like to be doing so uh you know once
it does become recreational legally and
all that sort of stuff it's going to be
good I'd like to awesome look at pain m
it's
amaz I love it we were doing it we were
filming up at uh with the planes behind
us that time and remember we'd be like
no no go ahead go ahead we're telling
people no no you can go cuz quite a few
people there were actually clued in yeah
they weren't wanting to cross the camera
yeah these people didn't even have any
idea they were on camera they're on
Bubble man's world hey they're
welcome I'm down with a with a dab here
is what I speak you got to get yeah put
me a dab on one of the uh on the Dabber
and I'll heat up my pipe so all you have
to do is would you like pick this Dabber
up put some hash in it I'll heat this up
I don't care I don't care at all I'm
happy to go with whatever uh is
available I like all John's flavors any
dabble D any dabble
dud want is just the fire we don't have
any nonf fire in this I have fire is
what's so great about this something
that have you seen this before isn't
that nice
yeah you put the year on probably uh
November November of 2013 nice so you
already know that this has got probably
almost close there that's all good so
almost it's got 9 months curing 9 month
cure I'll take
it I know I just dumped it on there big
dker that was like a rock
she that was
good you know what's best as he's
hitting that you're hitting this I'm
going to hit this here I'm really loving
this
Apex we can load it up for you too thank
you yeah
think mind my
reach and the torch as well so we've got
about three glass pipes here we've got
uh Patrick uh Redbeard's uh Swiss perk
pipe we've got a a piece from The Hitman
and then you've got the little piece
that uh flab 421 gave you yeah it's a
Peter size crft love and it's got some
air traffic was playing last night
awesome which one yeah what song was
playing last night said
I it was awesome talking about it we
were hitting this little pipe hard last
night on my place was quite
nice just
Bak Beyond B Fu that's how we do eat a
few all over the city drink a little bit
can I give you some 120 um anyone will
take 120 I'll put it maybe the we're all
about it we're all about it we all about
the flavors com with Vine it's very
important very key actually you know
like if you're going to pull away from
the torch and the nail to not have the
beine for me is like these little
Skillet um oil slick little
uh container look like
f Prince of Whales that boat that just
went by uh
me
yeah
woohoo I'm
ready
thanks being a BC that 120 as I'm I'm
definitely going to hook you up
definitely going to hook you up yes I
need to be hooked up at that 12 need
that [ __ ] that brain melt brain melt
it's a nice good good joint Denis Hopper
it's just not the fire that uh that I'm
looking
for both those hits were great the dab
was obviously a little lighter and a
little cooler with more taste but the uh
beine rip my God it hits you to the head
it's it's the
120 well I got my 990u shirt on today
but I love my 120 I got my 73 and when
he showed up last night he was wearing a
120 nice hey man
we're all about we're all about one
thing and that is that epic house that
we love to smoke
indeed pretty sure you guys like to
smoke and that's why you're watching I
bet you most of the people watching
right now are smoking something of some
sort while we're puffing cuz it would be
weird just to watch us puff you got to
puff with us yeah if they're not they
should be if you don't have anything to
Puff then it's not weird you can just be
like inspired and realize that you two
can puff the best that there is by
simply making different choices yes like
I'm going to grow this and I'm going to
extract this with care and attention
with care and attention then again if
you don't decide to do those things I
have a funny feeling that enough people
are going to in invest their time in the
near future to get it done so that
people on all levels have access to it
whether you grow and and isolate and
extract cash or
not oh there it is one is that good oh
did you get that one that was a nice is
it it it's rocker this was the fresh
frozen of the um the mku that I took
down before we uh went for our first
trip to Jamaica nice yeah then you went
back again and now we're finishing it
off I like that
powerful it was a fun trip I met some
good folks you'll meet them next time
you'll definitely be in get good good
folks EXC
I was hoping it was
for I'm next that just all hardcore push
Sarah down and take the rip it's my rip
she gets up roundhouses me on the ground
oh just jiu-jitsu's right on on oh my
God that was
A's trying to K whoa I got in trouble
for that
one cut C just give it really cuz
there's no water in the pipe there's no
water
[ __ ] he didn't go up and get the
water I forg [ __ ] we
doing we we'll be right back with uh all
taking care of Sarah we're taking care
of Sarah she's um
she's doing good she's starting to
recover now already I'll take one for
the team take one for the team I'll be
sitting next to her with my eyes water
I'm going to do it I'm like crying last
you got the one you got the one we're
all looking for yeah you got the ti Tim
Horton's up yeah it's crucial for the
Timmy's oh my
God okay we're covered covered I think I
know I might spontaneously start
coughing again sometimes that
happens thank you thank
you now I'm going to
getem
high extremely high wow yeah exem m
nice fresh frozen goodness right there
we have about 800 people taking pictures
of us right now yeah I know it's pretty
hilarious they're like they were like at
first they were taking pictures of the
view but now they're like those people
down there are smoking bers there's a
whole bunch of children watching like
kids the kids are busy looking at the
flag all of all of their well that's why
we came all the way down here this gu
like what's up how's going we're always
good now we bubble
mou it's good not drive after you puff
that's a good point it's a very good
point where you guys from right here
I've been here 20 years and never in my
life come to this spot I think John's
been here 40 years I've been here for 40
years and youve never come never been
here 40 years living in Vancouver you
know what where you the where you from
California oh nice call yeah to Seattle
Seattle and then drove
up enjoy beautiful PC
go check out
Whistler yeah we're not going to have
time drive it's an
hour it's hour was this is definitely a
wh no listen if you cross this bridge
and you literally take a 15minute ride
around that mountain right there from
that point on it's 1
hour it's epic is it it's epic just VI
it's unbelievable you can take the
gondola up to the top of the mountain
and literally walk around the peak and
I'm telling you it's like nothing else
you do here will move you that that much
even people that aren't into Mountains
go up there and they got like a tear in
their eye you know what I mean so how
cross Mountain cross Mountain's
beautiful you'll have an amazing
experience up there it's right where the
big Wind Tower is the one with the wind
uh turbine just to the left of the
windmill you can see a building in the
trees it's sort that's a big beautiful
it's nice going up there yeah that's
good that's a beautiful view there and
then obviously the SK go down this way
so that's
got lights up at night and do you have a
car yeah so then you should look at
driving up into uh I mean not maybe
Horseshoe Bay but well White Cliff Park
is at Horseshoe bayk yeah and then uh
Lighthouse park is in west Vancouver
it's just it's actually close to where
those ships are it's unbelievable man
the trails through that Park and how
they all come out at the ocean you could
be standing there and watch a pot of
dolphin swim by light park that's the
one Lighthouse Park is the one I always
went to it's got the Epic huge giant
trees in the park that are very old you
don't see them
everywhere and uh it's got nice yeah
nice
hike it's cap suspension bridge good I
would pref I would say go to uh Lin
Canyon yeah we were Lin Canyon is the
smaller less touristy one yeah and it's
I I think it's the better one really
yeah just because of just because
everything location the the suspension
bridge the view of the suspension bridge
from Lin Canyon is more beautiful it's
less built up and less people go there
it's a lot more narrow yeah yeah it's a
lot more narrow too so it's really clear
to I love
that it's got a local opinion it's cool
that you know most of what's going on
yeah I've been here 20 years I feel like
I missed all of this stuff talking about
like damn I didn't see all of that and
I'm leaving well you'll come back yeah I
next time I want to go see some of that
stuff that's it absolutely hey you're on
bubble man we're filming this right now
yeah oh really yeah we're all like the
most cannabis based people you could
possibly imagine all of us have like we
all work exclusively in cannabis she
grows cannabis I teach people how to
make hash for the last 15 years um these
guys have shops and products and also
promote growing in hash and we're all
medical um Fally medic workers patients
yeah he's helped tons of seriously
inured workers of people like that help
better education on pharmaceutical drugs
be dude I hope call speeds up it seems
like Colorado left California in the
dust and California forever was the most
Progressive the most on point the most
like I I don't know get the vote they
didn't get the vote gone through at
least once maybe tce just seemed insane
like how did California not get the
vote too Stone to go in and vote they
forgot yeah there you go
all the
people [ __ ] smoking oring out
true well enjoy your trip Ness
right yeah it is on a different level
too though they all have different state
rules so I think it needs to be flipped
to Federal cuz you have right now
families with epileptic children who are
like I live in Utah I can't get the
medicine that will stop my child from
having seizures every day which is like
canis cids the from the Cannabis and so
they move they drive to states where
they're allowed to have it and it's like
that's insane what kind of country is
that making [ __ ] people move over to
another state the whole I mean the
recreational use I mean I can see people
debating it yeah no problem debate it
all day long here here's the thing the
minute you let medicinal in the door and
you realize just how medicinal it is and
everyone's like it's the most medicinal
thing it's so medicinal you can actually
take it just for its euphoric After
Effects and so now now Rec what it is an
makes you feel good postraumatic stress
disorder it is one of the most
effective drugs that people that they
know of and of course it's not even
recognized by doctors they don't
describe it to soldiers that come back
from have the most trtic stress [ __ ]
they on it's all just crazy it's like
man like from up from up here I think
like it's the land of the free it's
America it's like we're fighting for the
so it's like how do you do that to your
people how long has Vancouver has beenal
here like forever um it's not you know
it's just decriminalized in a way that
we have Federal licensing so you can get
a license here federally but it's like
it's a special license that you go and
get from your doctor it's not just legal
it's not legal regation
here accepted totally accepted vapor
bars
dispensaries so so if you go into those
those stores or place you have to have a
card yeah they be but they'll give you a
card pretty darn fast $ see a
they
gots oh yeah it's not too much different
from the California model I think it's a
model that is okay for beginners and
eventually once we get into something
more established you know maybe let that
small amount be the grandfather din or
something cuz you always need like We'll
always need dispensaries and Vapor
Lounge type bars regardless if cannabis
goes to a more pharmaceutical 10 years
will be eating material store in every
corner it's about end canabo system and
feeding the bodies of
TAC that's pretty heavy it sounds insane
but if you learn that you have an endoc
canabo system and that every cell in
your body has receptors for these
particular type of canono which are
produced androgynously in your body are
called endoc canabo and how they're
produced they they use the building
blocks of Omega-3s and Omega 6s
essential fatty acids right essential
amino acids your doctor
says now we can get into talking it's
to I got my mom up there I got to get I
actually I ran out of [ __ ] gas here
at a rent car yeah this is the space
spot all the way just call them up and
get them to bring some Triple A's coming
nice but it's going to be all right well
it was good chatting with you man check
it on my mom she's probably freak out
you can check out bubble Man's World on
YouTube bub okay cool thanks guys yeah
man right good meeting you manp s sash
s you're going to come back here that I
take it
right here's what I membership to
business C here I got one going
on always ready but I mean that's the
best part of what we do is as we're
sitting here and we're talking and
someone drives interest we just educated
him who's now going to talk about it
with more people go to your channel and
he's just going to start edging and
that's the best part about sharing is
caring this sharing is caring puff puff
puff I'll leave it on that note hey
Sarah it was super awesome hanging with
you puffing with you and uh thank you so
much should we'll see you back in
Toronto if not back in BC soon than
later yes Johnny B tomorrow puff
Wednesday and d420 hopefully you're in
the house we're doing we're doing puff
Wednesday we did a
show we did a show on his channel too
today so that will be on uh d420 K on
YouTube so keep that out too all right
peace guys
[Music]