[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here with dom and Max from the
sunrise Wellness Foundation welcome guys
good to see both of you see
as you can remember from the last puff
Wednesday part two the sunrise Wellness
Foundation episode um Johnny and I went
and we purchased uh a bunch of different
flow flavors to squish for our personal
head and these guys were like hey we
have some stuff that we would also like
squished so they gave me a jar of uh the
Teflon and they gave me about 36 gram of
the o09 cookies uh and because I was
playing around with um the materials
that I had purchased from them which was
um Platinum girl cookies crossed with
WiFi 43 and Teflon those were the two I
had then Johnny B had the o09 cookies
and gorilla Cooks that's right so we
pressed all of that had a great time
learned a lot about the different
temperatures cuz I don't put press a lot
of flour I press mostly hash bubble hash
dry sift finger rub for that matter but
not a lot of flour little bit of a
learning curve came out uh pretty high
temperature 240° was pressing for about
15 to 20 seconds and getting a really
really stable shaty uh rosin that still
had a wonderful taste didn't have any
burnt popcorn flavor to it a lot of
people were like stressing on me and
saying I was pressing too hot people
throwing around numbers like
180° 200° 210 so I started experimenting
with those with a little bit of flour
that I had and immediately came to the
conclusion obviously that I'm sure a lot
of you have already come to that a low
temperature longer press is going to
produce a buttery rosin compared to a
shorter press with a much warmer
temperature you get this more consistent
sort of pull and snap or even a shatter
uh type end product so I didn't want to
press the material without them because
it's really kind of a personal choice
that you need to make how you want your
rosin to come out both of them were
producing the same yields I was getting
20 plus% from the rosin whether it was
butter or whether it was shatter so I
think we're going to do a variety of
things today um Dom and Max have uh
already processed and gotten the the
plant matter uh you know broken up
properly which we we contacted Phil soil
grown uh and I asked him hey what's the
best way to process flour he told us you
know fill the pouches about half fill um
leave the nugs in full you know leave
them basically as nugs but break them up
for the first few that you put in so
that the corners of the screen are
filled up which I thought you guys both
knew that tip when I mentioned it to you
I think that's a really great tip and if
you want to know a really great tip that
is one because the oil will pull into
those corners and you'll lose a
substantial amount in the screen and I
think it's why people don't like to use
screens and why they say hey I'm losing
oil so we're going to do a variety of
things today we've already done a little
press we pressed my last butt of the
Teflon and actually can I offer you guys
a dab I love a dab a Teflon right do you
want to maybe prepare a few there and
I'll get the pipe over here and I'm
actually uh going to put a little bit of
water in the
bubbler I think I think so I will be
right
back oh yeah that's proper yeah this
stuff looks really
good right and yeah we pressed this
stuff um what was the temperature 220 or
230 220 220 so this uh Teflon Bud was
processed or processed pressed extracted
at
220° I'd say it was under a minute like
yeah so we didn't time it we were just
kind of doing it Loose we wanted to have
some nice dabs for the uh for the rosin
vide so why don't we pull yourself off
one get it ready on the Dabber there Max
and uh oh yeah let's use the little root
Sciences root Sciences hooked me up with
a little dab mat the other day and it's
funny I have so many different oil
slick of dab mats different kinds that
just seeing another different one like a
c circular one that's just fits the pipe
so perfect is uh appealing to
me let me make sure you have uh one more
exactly can't leave you hanging and give
you a carb cap less rip it's just not
the
same friends don't let friends dab
without carb caps unless well unless you
absolutely don't have one but then we
mver that [ __ ] there you go Bud find way
so pretty excited to get squishing on
this flower I'm not going to lie we've
uh we're going to film it of a nice you
know we're going to show you the full
preparation of you know putting it in
squishing it out opening it and
collecting all of the rosin and uh after
that because we have so many packs here
there's about 10 here um or 11 even uh
we're going to just really show you the
Quick Clip of each one getting pressed
and the squish that we got out of each
one did we weigh each one yeah we did
they're all weighed to 6.9 to 7.1 G okay
so uh this was another thing that we
talked to Phil about soil grown cell uh
he mentioned to us that you know
starting at about 240 degrees doing a
15-second press finding out your
stability finding out your quality
finding out your yields that lets you
know from there that you can move down
uh in temperature and you know notice
the differences that you get it's
obviously people don't want to waste
they want to get as much as they can but
they don't want to get especially us we
are not coming at this from the the
point where we want to get so much at
the expense of any of the quality or
flavor that's right you know so I I can
tell people out there already are saying
well then you got to press it all at
180 you know there's definitely a higher
concentration of flavor in the lower
temperature
um uh presses but at the same time God
it's still such quality when it's
pressed a little warmer and that snap in
and there's still tons of flavor in that
that's delicious absolutely this one is
kind of an in between um butter and
shatter texture thank you sir just
lovely nice to have you guys over for a
little dab session yeah it's yours
Mark
booah jeez it's a house
fire not bad at all all right here we
go like it it's a nice strong buzz off
that
Teflon yeah
a hashy kind of creamy taste it really
does great tasting oil for uh with you
know flour
rosin it's nice for me I got to admit
because for water hash for dry
sift I really need to have a decent
amount to be able to play with
rosin you can have a very small amount
of Bud and still get in the game yeah
and I think it's one one of the things
why it's going to be such a popular why
it is such a popular uh method and
growing every day because it's so easy
to get in the game I mean even this
machine for 2300 us is pretty amazing
considering what you would spend on a a
butane closed loop extractor CO2 machine
any other machine that makes oil is
going to be a fairly high cost this is
one of the higher end units on the
marketplace right now for commercial
production and it's you know a couple of
grand us three grand Canadian so I say
uh we're dabbed up let's get squish
let's uh let's get squishing I'm going
to head over to the other side of the
table and we're going to kind of operate
the press as a as a team here so let's
do that now all right so we're over here
on the other side of the press and uh
basically real nice uh presentation we
packed the the all screen mesh bags
exactly how Phil has requested uh
leaving a nice open sort of half well a
third of of the lip of screen which you
can just it's nice and packed in there
and we're going to slap that into our
parchment unbleached crack that open for
me there d a little bit more that's
perfect try to get this kind of into
the some nice
flow that's even tight like that's
pretty good A little bit more yeah
Perfect all
right all right gentlemen shall
we give that a little press or what go
[Music]
ahead nice keep going a little
yep got a timer going
for all right pop it
open then you want to close that back
down so we can the plates
up
yeah got a nice little collection there
it's nice and creamy just you want to
hold this guy by the I think God we
could have squish that more oh we're
going to squish it more for sure but
just to give these guys an idea of what
came out we were looking for about a
gram and a half of rosin and I would
definitely say we probably got about a
half to a gram so we probably got a
little bit more to go um do you want to
gra run that out and put it gently on
that metal piece out back
there close that up y
I needed more pressure too like go down
a couple more times me
too cuz it
really really just started right at the
end I could start hearing it going but
the color on that oh the da we'll need
the Dabber look at that oh yeah oh yeah
we got most of it on one side from
closing it which is always a nice
maneuver yeah all right so
the color is incredible it's like the
creamiest lightest
blondest God does that feel right
between creamy and porn
sap God it just feels like ice cream I'm
serious holy
Mo all right so we'll find out how
efficient we
were by merely um getting this first
Wade so was a good
plan it'll be interesting to see how
much more squishes out of that on our
second Squish and it'll let us know what
we need to do for for time wise for
allowing it to squish out so yeah that
was about a half a gram so we definitely
have a good solid
like8 to another gram of of rosin that
should come out of uh out of the next
squish all right so we're just going to
do a quick little secondary press on
this
guy we weren't using all the pressure
I've also folded it in half just to let
you know there it's not pressing up as a
whole flat piece I like to flatten it up
for my second one here we go
it
click you can always go
back that's what I thought it was going
to be like there you go blasted it out a
tiny little bit we blasted out the bud
just the tiniest little
bit
but one little guy right there was
pretty good
but as you can
see we got that missing
gram so that gram we were looking for
here it is right here I would definitely
say that's probably about a gram
compared to what that was and that's a
half gram you want to just go drop her
on there for uh what I was saying is
when you're pressing such great quality
material and it's unfortunate that the
majority of the dispensaries this isn't
the easiest thing to find there's just
not a lot of supply of it there's not a
lot of supply of it lot of people want
to grow things that you know don't take
long to flower and yield a lot M and
these things the truth is they're harder
to grow you know where some things are
just easy to do it right as well yeah
well God bless those that are doing it
right how we doing on that
good wo jeez look at that just giant
pile of buty
and there we go right there guess and
that's about a
gram one one G so 1.5 G from s g yeah
there we go that's what we're looking
for pretty killer for sure uh we'll
press this out as well it's going to
look a little bit darker there with the
uh how thick it is but I guarantee you
when we press out that uh thicker piece
it's not going to have a very different
color maybe a tiny tiny little bit
darker but we'll do that later as well
so that is but is that is the second
press too that is the second press yeah
so but a unique second press in the
sense of not the if we had gotten most
of that out and there was only a little
bit it almost protects itself when
there's a lot of it if there's less of
it you get this much darker color that
comes out of your rosin second presses
aren't usually very exciting in
particular if you've gotten 80 to 90%
out in the first press but when you've
left
66% it still comes out pretty damn nice
we've got the pressure down we've got
the temperature down I think this next
squish we're going to go for like a 1.3
1.4 return on one squish so I think we
can do it see what we can get I think we
have it in us do
it all
right 219
open a little
more you want to open that up for me
nice little squish right there I'd say
we probably got about a gram on this one
maybe a tiny little bit less like 0.9 so
we' still got another point4 to get out
of our second Squish and we'll get a
little more efficient I think if we
would have left that for a little bit
longer I think we would have seen our
close to full return uh
return God she's pretty
though yeah it's a nice color
got
going all right so more
collection 1.4
1.3 so we just pulled like 21
22% off of in a square so that's the
success we're looking for that's what we
want to do right there and you can see
it's got a real turpy sort of almost wet
look to it little bit of pulling pulling
uh snap texture to it but this is going
to be butter in a in a day or two and
man about 19 and a half% all right so
that was a great return 1.4 from
seven and as you can see an absolute
beautiful
quality you know pretty cool that you
can just go buy flowers and produce a
quality of of rosin like this
Max is going to collect this
up yeah
buddy all right okay so we just uh
pressed out a little bit of our first
batch there you can hold that up to the
camera real nice and close it'll if you
put it Clos enough it'll snap to it
perfect so I'm about to take a dab of
that nice little slice of pie I like how
Dom made it into a pie that's a very
nice uh very nice
touch wow that foamed up really nice
that almost looked like bubble has when
it was it stopped pretty quick in about
a second or two in it turned to just oil
that's why I kind of went to show you
but it was like done and it foamed up
nice lovely
strong
satiating let's get uh a piece of pie
for you I find actually that's not the
right
one that's not the right one there's the
pie that one's mine
actually my last nugget the
[Music]
Teflon that's so
delicious we should have a Cherry Pie
pizza
party many pieces of good things oh yeah
that just Foams up it looks totally like
foam out and then it dissipates within 2
seconds it dissipates
little help we're friends for
cheers all right it's very good going to
get in here for a piece of uh cherry pie
there Don I just did that ninja dab oh
you did the ninja dab first awesome okay
the uh the Dabber let's get back to
pressing all right so we are grabbing
the
third third bag third bag of Teflon that
we're about to press uh the last third
uh pouch that we pressed was actually 09
cookies and that uh that is this one
here and Dom's written all the
information out quite quite lovely the
09 top left corner 1.3 out of seven top
right corner third pouch First Press 60
seconds 220° Fahrenheit so uh We've
lowered the temperature it's dropping
right now it's 2113 as I speak and we're
going to get it down to about
210 and 210 we're going to probably
press what do you guys think for a
minute a minute 15 yeah I can think
about a minute minute 15 see how see how
it sounds see how it smells maybe even I
mean I pressed uh 200 or 210 I pressed
210 at at 2 minutes and got my yield so
we'll check it out we'll see what's
going on of course uh it's always nice
to figure out your ratios without
sacrificing that second round you want
to get as much as uh you can out of that
first round and get that really lovely
color but uh I mean hey if you've left
some behind and it's more than a point
it's definitely worth going for so why
don't we put this one in
Teflon the Teflon
[Laughter]
Dawn there's a little bit of the uh that
kind of buttery rosin that came out
really beautiful
quality Dom said right away what did you
say I said I don't care about the yield
it's the best best press We Done Yet
boom Going
lower we're just collecting this rosin
and laughing at the sliver that's uh
good good looking out Max that's uh
that's proper right there so we
collected some lovely raw in here but
this big sliver just came off in one
piece and I thought that was pretty
uh pretty sweet all right so we'll just
drop that in there Max is about to load
is this our fifth pouch now this will be
the four right this will be our fifth
squish yeah yeah so this is our fifth
squish we've uh we're still at 210°
we're actually down a little lower
26° so uh never never a bad thing to go
a little bit
lower going in for the straight I like
it I like
[Music]
it look at the color of that it's like
brown sugar lots of it on here still so
we'll get that off in the okay I mean
not lots of it but enough that it's
we'll be collecting it this is so
nice that
buttery sappy it's like cake it is like
cake we just baked a cake a cherry pie
cake it's like cake batter rosin good
Lord there you are 4K
4K of absolute buttery
goodness very
clean see what kind of you guys tighten
the paper
woo so that's what we just
uh produced I really got to get the
macro lens out there's all sorts of good
stuff going on
here would have been a great thing for
me to shoot each one on the Dabber but o
just so much more
work all right so we're going in with
our fifth pouch correct gentlemen yes
yes we brought the temperature up to 211
de5 is that where you wanted it it's
exactly where we want it okay great so
we've got
uh we've got it right where we want it
200 two 212 now it's up
to that's okay give her a
shot all right so we're opening it up
here
215° pressed for about a minute and 45
seconds let's see the squish oh it looks
buttery and delicious you want to pull
that out for
me oh my gosh that looks real nice very
nice so we'll get that collected and do
the next squish uh all right we've got
press number seven here ready we've got
the 215 to 216° temperature in goes the
pouch Dom's working the
compressor all
right how much I like a cultivar
you know we can look at these all we
want but the way you'd really tell what
are the best is by having them all and
which we will all have and we'll have to
let each other know which ones we smoked
first because that to me is the ultimate
test 50 more
seconds
okay definitely more about
better rugs and okay so this is a second
press we're not too sure why we got an
incredible quality off the last hit but
it was only point4 and we've been
getting pretty pretty consistently like
1.1 1.2 return you know 6.7 on a lower
end but quite a few that hit over 1
point0 uh yeah go ahead
Max yeah all right here we go one minute
press nice little
squish we were wondering where the rest
of it
went tiny little blowout but we'll
collect only the
bottoms a little dark darker color like
what happens with a second
press yeah very nice you know looks
nicer out here than it did in there
that's for
sure so a little bit of contaminant over
on the edges here we'll avoid uh picking
that up but uh we'll
definitely very nice to have a big um
you know one of those lenses over top of
it that elderly people use to read it
would be nice to have that for rosin
collection because you could really with
Precision avoid the contamination that's
in there all right so we're doing our
second uh pouch of the cookies we had
five cou pouches of cookies there's four
left this is number four and we've got
it at
212° and we're probably going to do
about a minute to a minute and 45
seconds yeah and we're going for the
butter so bring her
down 1 minute 45 seconds is this a
second or a first this is a first press
oh right right hold on couldn't remember
o that's nice
that is
[Music]
nice you can leave it right there even
it's uh I'll just zoom in on Wow almost
a mixture if you look at it here right
in here in particular you get this sort
of
buttery um live resin duel thing going
on it's like caking right
out you want to take it out and give it
a quick uh
all right so we're throwing in another
batch of 09 cookies we've got the
temperature at 2113 you want to hold up
that last little batch that we got the 1
point was it 1.2 top top right top right
next to the other Cooks way up right up
there yeah
yep so there we go that's what we got
out of that one 1.2 out of out of seven
first bet pouch 1 minute 45 seconds at
21 and uh I took some really lovely
macro shots of this that I will of
course be sharing
we'll get it up nice and close so you
can also see that is some very nice
quality it's been interesting hasn't it
guys seeing all of the different kinds
come up and see which ones make you
drool and make you like oh I want to hit
that
one it's just like a 10° difference
yeah
incredible so a 10 degree difference
this was an accidental uh squish on our
third pouch when I was pressing uh uh
squishing the Teflon and I accidentally
grabed an 09 cooks and then this is the
one we just pressed out so quite a
different texture quite a different
color I'm sure there's some different
wow does that look
amazing all
right in she goes 215° we're going for a
minute and 45 seconds gentlemen yes once
again all
[Applause]
right and this up that was a minute and
45 seconds
translucent
fake oh my gosh yeah that looks real
nice huge surprise press that one again
it came out beautiful again I just can't
believe
it all right take it outside and cool
it all right we're going to do a second
press that last one for whatever reason
at a minute and 45 seconds at
211° we came out with Just5 of a gram
from a quarter so that's around like 10
% a little below less yeah eight8 and a
half 9% so we're going to squeeze out
another uh well I would say probably 10%
right
now a minute and 14 seconds minute and
15 seconds it was second one oh okay I
just wasn't sure what you guys were
going for okay so we're opening up at a
minute and 15
seconds pull that out see what kind of
what kind of Squish we
got beautiful definitely sell some nice
color let's take a picture of these
Bubbles and show them what that looks
like under the macro
lens all right our second last one going
in now this is
uh 21
212° uh what a minute and 45 seconds
guys
[Applause]
talking about oh it looks
great some cake
batter Okay so we've got our last pouch
of the 09 cookies we've done well boys
nice little collection of rosin squished
out here we'll go over the numbers in a
bit for now uh we're back up uh well
we're a little below
210° so we'll probably leave leave this
for a solid minute and 45 seconds to 2
minutes wouldn't you guys say yeah just
to get as much of that first yield out
as we
can oh yeah you can hear it
bubbling P it open soon yeah it's there
taper
off just a second press on that one
right there yep here you go fold it in
half and get that pressed up all right
this is the second press we got a fairly
low yield on that last pouch uh 3 came
out um you know still a minute and 45
seconds 212 de so it's really trippy I
don't know where the consistency is
being lost we're not seeing it super
often so it is an anomaly but uh we are
seeing
it oh yeah look at that that's there it
is
there's the
uh there's that yield oh you want to
grab that piece there no problem it's
nothing it's nothing worth nothing worth
saving there we
go so there's that
yield
beautiful all right so that was our last
press um where's the three right here so
we got we got A3 uh very low first year
uh return and then we hit it again uh
for a little longer it looks quite dark
actually in this video right now but
it's
actually not as dark as it looks but a
little bit darker for certain and a real
nice smell to
it nice bouquet so we got our 20% yield
anyway and we managed to uh still get
that3 separated so a nice lighter
color and I guess uh yeah we'll just get
these all lined up on the
all right boys what do you have to say
about what we got here so we did some
squishing today a couple different
flavors uh top side over here we got the
09 cookies squared and then at the
bottom we got the Teflon all right and
so what is the top row that is three
versus the top the second row in the top
that is five are those all seconds these
are all our first presses so this was
the first poach second poach third
fourth fifth poach so the first and
second we really were so efficient that
there was really no need for a second
squish yeah we were content with the
with the yield on those ones these ones
we uh we figured there was definitely
more more left in the pouches so that's
why there's uh second presses and those
are the the top three here all right so
just to give them a little bit of a
better idea all the numbers written here
these are the second presses these top
three yeah and then these are all first
presses this was The Accidental press
that we did during the Teflon um this
was one of the first buttery ones that
came out that we were really impressed
with and of course some uh inet on both
of these and even this third one little
surprising when we only got the uh3 but
we squished out uh although dark still a
damn near gram of uh of nice rosin and
then down here we've got the Cherry Pie
Teflon yep Cherry Cherry Pie cross with
Wi-Fi Alien OG and 09 cookies the pie
gave it
away all right and these are all the
first presses on top or no yes exactly
and what is this uh so that's a that's a
second press second press damn yeah that
looks really good for a second press so
this is a first press this is the first
this first this one came out and we were
just so happy I mean look at the color
on that it's just
ridiculous another 1.6 on that one but a
second press of 6 much darker color no
doubt about it uh Phil soil grown s
absolutely told us that we would notice
that very lovely peaches color on this
one that one's nice 0.9 no second press
on that one one and then our point4 also
came out very nice color even lighter
than the one the peachy orange one but
more lemony and yellow esque
so I would say that is a success what do
you guys say that we each pick one to
dab on and finish this video with a nice
dab think we can do that
excellent all right so this is the one
that Max is choosing as you can see a
finely buttered with mild shatter
consistency to it a first bag a second
bag First Press minute and 45 seconds
2111 fhe
1.2 out of seven so there's no second
press on that one and uh that's the one
Max is going to be hitting all right Max
is going to take his rip we'll check
this
out definitely a lovely foam to
it and this is the on Cooks 9
cookies 09 cookies
how does how does that sound it's it's
it tastes really nice consistent with
the flower taste that you're used to and
the and the the color of it was really
nice too when it was actually foaming it
was very light it foamed up light brown
for sure we'll try and show you that as
well the on cookies is strong too got
quite a lot of quite a lot of horsepower
to
it all right Dom which one are you
picking I'm going to go with the Teflon
and I'm going to go with the third pouch
going base purely off looks we got a
really nice buttery batch out of there
nice you g to squeeze off a piece of
that bar or what I think that's what I'm
going to go for right there I like that
I think that's a good idea boom it's on
secured all right so we're going to
catch the foam on this
one much darker color but it's lighting
lightening up now there at the end boom
[Music]
rip I like Max coughing for Dom's hit
that was bros I'm still feeling that
09 all right so now it is my choice
tough choice that it is I just want to
kind of puff on all of them but uh you
know I think I am going to go
for the point
for
teflon wow
crazy good
choice that one's one of the brightest
actually she came off
nice she's definitely active
yeah all right here we go Dabber
nearby salute
wow taste was on point powerful strong
for for certain really tasted
that cherry
pie I do appreciate the way that mildly
shatter in between butter Ros and r rips
seems to grab you a little differently
than the TP Rich butter which also I
can't say which one is better but it's
just personal preference I went for that
one because of its shininess and its
color yeah anyway super big shout out to
soil grown s uh for the sasqua Rosen
press and his whole team over there
absolutely top-notch tool gentleman
really looking forward to the V2 which
is out really right away we're all
stoked about that and of course thanks
to Max and Dom from Sunrise Wellness
Foundation and uh the wonderful Growers
that uh produced the bud that we grew uh
that we processed today through the
through the the Rosen press and uh yeah
thank you guys for watching Bubble man's
world always a pleasure to have these
guys over we will see you next time
peace out everybody
[Music]