all right guys so we got a little cut
short the other day uh I had to go pick
up my kid and I apologize for that but
be done Kids First kids first when
you're a good dad and now we're back at
Chris's shop it's a day later actually
it's a few days later and uh well where
where we going to go today we're going
to go around the seaw wall Vancouver
Stanley Park seaw wall man Che that out
I'm excited about this so we've got the
boosted boards again as you can tell
we're not just wearing these helmets
because we fall down often but we're on
the boards and we're going to go cruise
around the seaw wall and we'll probably
finish it off uh either at this lounge
or at another Lounge this Lounge
probably have a Char boards up exactly
perfect another Cruise exactly and go
for another Cruise so we're going to do
GoPro footage as well as cam footage and
uh let's get the show started bro sounds
good do it
[Music]
hey Chris wow I'll tell you really nice
takeoff on this level
four a lot more uh just receptive lot
more receptive
hey you really got to
take take care St kind of real cloud
like I say I bring about this
mus man Roy alongside one spot
[Music]
stly s oh
yes
again look at
me head people always ask me say why you
so humble I don't smoke the co that's
why I don't
me
[Music]
yeah her must be burned like te must be
cleaned ra vital for Spiritual hene a
king Salomon certify the tree and he is
the the wisest man to we so sh
propaganda the preach her never not
sound true speech so meanwhile the song
called leaders deceive man obligated to
clarify and teach you now
[Music]
marij
friend the
highest from the high
[Music]
[Applause]
when you sing on you T
[Music]
down
really come
streets my people still P by Gun Man and
tee say you with resources and in turn
showing up your yearly
[Music]
[Applause]
the
Earth yes my
medicine some call it
Cy some call it
weed some call it marijuana marijuana
some call it
herbs some I call it push
[Music]
pants make me
with that
s
Earth
strictly
arms
right alone my
heyo
B Timber Ro feel good
[Music]
me man home man
real
going the purple after the weed to the
mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I've been to King M hours
sleeping on like the fresh vegetation
with trees and
[Music]
flowers
Ander
[Music]
pass I make
pass
[Music]
pass pause that
now after the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
dying well I imagine down the road there
be some cops setting
UPS
man we
me upon your scene to intervene in my
bra St that and behind your scene me and
my team have another
25 smoke it
[Music]
clean man
now pass
[Music]
pass
make pass pass and
then pass pass
pass po
I make pass pass
pass it's my life it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
[Music]
life we're coming from
behind
[Music]
behind Spirit you un
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world of
a spiritual and warriors trotting from
behind
ding forward at this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and I come to turn the
tables turn the Paradigm around
yes deprogram and
[Music]
reprogram free
mankind spiritual un
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world of a
spiritual and Warriers tring from
behind tring forward at this
[Music]
time the mindset of the people chaa
children true true children seeking for
the via the way to go through I and I
come to freedom freedom with a light in
the
[Music]
K spiritual and
warriors are on a mission
showing the world
of spiritual Warriors dring from
behind dring forward at this time
spiritual and
warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spirit you un Warriers trotting from
behind dting forward at this time
[Music]
they say there will be
salvation I said there won't be
[Music]
cuz there will be no salvation here
in until the PO there cries are
[Music]
heard so come now my brothers
all to the
call for
one
[Music]
one one
rich men cries are heard my Hiding cries
are heard then why then why why can't
the
poor hey hey now for the poor they've
been crying out for these many thousand
years there vibrations are traveling
throughout this world oh yeah so come
now Brothers all and rally to the
call
one one un the world one
word you and I crying out for Unity
that's what God he
said that's what marus
said and now those of
you read the books of Prophecy that's
what the prophet said he that's what
they
all and better got to come now better
got you but it's only going to come
starting with you and you and you and
you yes better got I come now yes better
has got to come but it's only going to
come starting with you and you and you
and
[Music]
you oh yeah
doing doing it doing it
well what what what what you going to do
now with the Judgment so near at hand
what what you going to do tell me now
what you going to do hey hey you see the
blood blood blood of the Oh My Heart and
souls it's crying out oh yes it's crying
out
out pretty soon there be lightning and
thunder earthquake World drin and fire
be are crashing in yes in on you you you
you you you you the wicked ones the
unjust ones and all of those who use
people
rights oh yes for their own
game what what can I do now with a
judgment so near at hand what what you
going to do tell me
[Music]
now blood blood
Don't You Worry hry About a Thing take
you easing believeing and never give
don't do
worry about a thing they keep he's
believe me and never
give life is not hard as lions which are
in the background and if you go over the
top of the Lions you end up in my my
area the Lion's Bay so look at the size
of this thing
hey I've been on the bridge when they
when this thing went by before and it
was uh with me and Tosh here I'll get a
good shot of you right there
Chris that's sick one more pie sign it
up yeah there we go hang loose even
better hang loose even better get the
boosted in there yes
exactly always better with there we go
you got double
boosted uh yeah let's have a
[Music]
session think sure doesn't clear the
bridge by much hey like holy [ __ ]
[Music]
well that is a big boat considering
there's a smaller boat in front of it
really giving you the size uh difference
barely fits into my wide angle lens
camera look at that barely fit the whole
boat
in you're doing
great knocking boards
over all right so Chris called it time
for a for a little puff session we got a
couple of options I brought the little
saram saram pen little uh vape pen but I
think we're going to
go
full if you brought it we should use it
ooh wait a minute now we might have to
go see we'll see what we got I think we
can do this I think we can do
this make sure we got all the pieces all
the components that are necessary such a
nice day each nice day gets
consecutively nicer I would agree with
that actually supposed to be like
cooking this summer too
so beautiful we deserve it yeah for sure
so is there any like uh really nice like
new pavement out in Lions Bay if like
you know up in the up in the mountains
there or anything like that I think the
best place in Lions Bay would probably
be
um this is where some of the upper upper
streets are pretty good but it's mostly
longboarders who are going at extreme
speeds down and sliding with hand like
when they have those World competitions
down in Washington there's usually about
five or six of those guys that drive up
over the border and then they hit a few
spots in the British properties and they
usually get as far as lion's Bay these
boards I think they would be really
amazing for Squamish cuz now Squamish
has a seaw wall type of thing that goes
throughout it um any yeah Whistler and
even pton has quite a bit of it so yeah
I think that this could become really
popular along those lines sure so let me
see here we got
get a little dab this will be the
easiest I think for us we'll do a little
LH from
htio dab a
doodia dude I can't tell you how stoked
I am on this whole experience I knew you
would be as soon as I was riding I like
I know who's going to think this [ __ ]
bubble man yeah you called it dude it's
like ick people message you and said you
got to check this [ __ ] out
bro I'm going to just lower this down
where it's a little less a lot of my old
surfing buddies too I've been telling on
them one of them came out from the
island there a week or so ago and
checked it out he was totally stoved
it's hard not to
[Music]
be I'm just like stoked at you know just
coming up on 53 to be able to rip these
things oh dude you're ripping them hard
too you know so it's great man thought
all that stuff was like a thing of my
past you know all the surfing and
skating and stuff had been so long this
kind of what I needed to reinvigorate my
life a little bit was that kind of
adrenaline rush Stoke you get off the
board Sports you know yep totally we're
hitting this egg uh saw water again I uh
I brought lemonade but I just didn't
feel like putting lemonade in the Fab
egg you know I guess I could have but I
think I'd rather just
uh tiny torch and uh wind is definitely
not your friend with these
things nice I guess that's what Matt
will be flying in on tomorrow
yeah yeah Matt Baron the GRE Gardener
coming in for a ride tomorrow so all
right let's see if I can get this
[Music]
work very good all right so that was
actually really nice uh nice rip I'm
going to get you one real quick so we
can head out on our way like I have to
say when I'm doing stuff like this I
don't want to sit around and puff for
like an hour I really just want to have
a get hit and then on the road exactly
for sure man I think you know all board
Sports it's like you know you go to any
snowboard scene and there's going to be
the hardcore guys that are hitting the
hitting the herb and hitting the hill
hard you go to a surf break there's
going to be the hardcore Surfers that
are hitting hit the session on the beach
before they paddle out skateboard park
same thing and I don't know like I think
that uh in regards to board Sports those
type of sports cannabis can really throw
you in that Zen head space that where
you just kind of get in the zone with
what you're doing and stuff like that I
don't know if totally if performance
enhancement is right but performance
Focus yeah performance Focus for sure
you know he's literally claiming now
that cannabis is a performance
enhancement uh drug for him so I think
have to take him out for escape you know
what he'd be really down to this
actually yeah yeah for sure we could
definitely get Ross to come and and
cruise around with us on these things I
think uh maybe when we go up to Whistler
we'll make sure that he's around and
we'll uh bring the extra board with us
and yeah for sure man you know we could
do that I think that bubble man's world
is going to become electric skateboard
man's world it's so fun absolutely man
it's the best uh transport for the city
you know what I mean you just get get it
to where you I I have to go for
groceries just like oh good I got to get
some groceries man grab the pack pack
and get the skateboard I know you get
all excited about it all right so here
we'll hit you on this side right here
boom
yeah that's the same for me you
fake good old Vancouver people aren't
even surprised they look over and they
just don't even shake their heads cuz
it's Vancouver what's the shake your
head about just a couple of guys hitting
a Fab egg under the Lion's Gate Bridge
let's get back to skateboarding dude
another
one take it one day at a time and
fulfill your dreams
remember no one is an island no one
stands
alone in your doing always remember your
them all when things get hard and
lean hold on to your faith and fulfill
your
beam and
don't
[Music]
worry about the thing
take
easy me never give in
[Music]
don't take it
easy me never
give test of time test of
patience just like in the days of
patient
[Music]
remember the man called job he Tred the
rocky
road he know where he was going so he
know where he was coming
from believe in yourself my
friend as you
pursue just you go
to and don't you
[Music]
wor about the thing
take you he said believe me and never
give
don't
about there you
he's me
never and my people keep the positive
that to
doing hey kids F your back time to go to
school
if stop the got the
rolling you you why on the street side
Lo rising at the Winds Don't
you about the thing
take he's believe man and never give
don't you
worry about the
take he
said
man don't
[Music]
you hi mountains of the
world deep
valleys flat surface of the
world people
living they're living
[Music]
just stop where you
are as life goes
by as life goes by
goes
by turn your start
around and get your engine in
gear and leave the stagnant waterers
waterers
behind just leave the
stagnant stagnant Waters
behind Rocka music
mus rockers
music see New
Horizons New
Horizons seek New
[Music]
Horizons for new just new new and
Greener postures
SE New
Horizons New
Horizons SE New
Horizons for new just new new and
greener
pastures rockers music will change your
mood
rocker music lift you
high rocker music change
your rock music LIF you
[Music]
high blinking let's see
refresh yourself
now and cleaner cleaner
clean the
waters
clean the water
listening to the music of
Life you've got to listen to the
messaging the
music rockers music rockers
music Let It Rock
You music rocker
You rocker music will change your
mood rocker music will lift you
high rocker music will change your
mood rockers music will lift you higher
seek New
[Applause]
Horizons New Horizons
she knew her