I don't think they can come up with a
cat evidence on cannabis that sort of
turns it into something so dangerous
that you can sustain treating it in this
in this restricted way and we really
need to acknowledge that all of these
years we lied about it most people get
their information from a five-second
trip on television or a couple of
paragraphs in the newspapers
that's one of the major benefits of
legalization there's a lot more people
are gonna consume and we've seen what a
hundred years give or take of stigma
have done to just change everyone's
perceptions is this plan to the point
where they bear so little resemblance to
the actual properties of the plan and
it's terrifying to see how them and this
information can lead to so much software
but that's still it's don't matter not
from happen you don't I mean in the way
that legalized reason is rolling out
there's there's still gonna be another
fight thank God I think that you know
there's there's different functions in
society I think activism is an important
function I think having enforcement is
an important function you know and then
I think you have education politicians
who who catering to death emotional
reactions in terms of votes you know
they don't stop to talk rationally
reasonably most of the time about things
and there's people suffering there's
people you know countless people though
you see somebody who's you know going
for attentive to withdrawal and you can
do something to alleviate some of that
pain you know you know there's so many
good things that happen we are expected
to come up with innovative solutions
until that opioid crisis we find
ourselves after the transitions are
always you know it's like giving birth
then you're like you know it's you know
what intense process that's why I say
move things forward it's not just about
the things that we're very actively
trying to move forward here but like
what could we do now well why do you
need to protect kids from cannabis last
time I checked kids have
endocannabinoids systems - yeah what the
doctor yeah he looked at me you said
you're a desperate mother reaching
you're grasping at straws I told him I
was like yeah I am he said what are you
gonna do if I don't give you this
prescription I said I'm gonna go home
and I'm gonna do it anyways you can't
deny me that your chance to save my
child cannabinoids regulate all
biological functions through the
endocannabinoid system so what's the
problem
legalization I mean it's coming for
everybody and then cannabis work so
legalization kicking in especially at
this time it really is important to be
talking about these other things I also
have faith in the activists and the next
generation to just continue this
movement I just see this is a point in
time I don't see this is the destination
and I think if we all keep that in mind
there have been some pretty big
victories but the ones I respond to the
most and the quickest are the parents
because I know I've been there it's
scary and when you try to take on a
medical system that's really scary I
think if there was a regulatory market
in place it might be a real good
transition but there isn't anything in
place and so you know nobody big not
just a gray area but a great timeline of
when that's gonna be and when those
shops can open up that's what all those
guys are baby but at the end of the day
I mean the plan is gonna be a legal
entity in Canada and we can do anything
we want with it
I mean we win just change their mind
about one little thing you know and then
come back and then one more thing you
know and then one more well I think we
need all the stories I mean they're all
stories right a clinical trial to type a
story there's also a piece of that story
where it's so expensive to be able to
tell that story that it limits who gets
to speak so I think what's so great
about something like move the movement
is it's inviting other people who have
wisdom and you have important
information and important stories to
share to share those stories as well so
it's not just this one story where the
entrance of the storytelling Club is is
incredibly high that was awesome