[Music]
okay hello welcome everybody to Bubble
man's world I am back today again with
Sabo and we are going to sit down and do
a little bit of a sort of organ
conversation while we enjoy a couple of
vapex hailes mine turned down
substantially the way I like it his
turned up a little bit more Yep about
the 1:00 setting here 1:00 setting and
I'm down at what you would say
maybe 7:00 7 o' yes maybe 7 o' little
bit of a lighter lighter hit that takes
a bit longer to give that Smoky Rip but
uh yeah we've got eight quartz tubes
here that are nice and clean and ready
for for dipping three varieties of rosin
so we've got a hash plant we've got a
sweet skunk and we've got a congal oo
and then we also have seven varieties of
tpin two in the closed packages here the
Blue River we got Swiss sonami and the
ACDC both High CBD CS actually not that
there's any cannaboids in there but
still they are the profiles that come
from a high CBD cultivar and I'm of the
firm belief that
those r ratios of Tarpin synergize and
modulate CBD a particular way I think
probably in a better way than just
extracting out CBD by itself interesting
oh I will be uh Curious to try and you
know I love the taste of CBD strains in
general so I'm sure I will yeah they
always have they always have a bit of a
cherry esque sort of nice turpine flavor
to it that I that I found that's a great
description also excited to show you
guys this new little piece here a step
in the right direction for me now don't
get me wrong I loved the pipe that came
with the vapexhale it was thick and
strong it didn't feel like you know
inexpensive glass that you didn't get
your money's worth I felt that it was a
nice heavy thick piece and the way it
fit on the unit I loved as well but
coming from the perspective of someone
that collects uh you know even though
they're clear fairly expensive glass
pipes uh I think it's a great idea to
offer an option that doesn't involve um
the tube which is fine I've hit it four
out of the sublimator and I've used the
one for the vapexhale I just love the
idea of preserving it in glass uh me too
as well you know uh the the silicone
hose was designed more for usability and
utilitarian purposes but I I am like you
you know I love collecting really nice
glass and many times when you have a
silicone hose in between a high-end
vaporizer and a top-notch Mothership
like this one uh you know it's almost
like a one of these things doesn't
belong with with the other so we decided
to create this all glass uh connector
here and you know um this is just the
version one of it you know we think that
uh based on the time I spent with you
and D yesterday you know there's some
improvements that we can make but at
least it's a step in the right direction
and you know really excited to to show
everyone uh how it works as well as to
taste all of this awesomeness in front
of us and by no means am I saying that
this is the better there it's a quiver
Sabo and I are quiver guys we like to
have more than one option because we
know there are more than one type of
person out there and what's great for
you may not be great for the next person
so the Silicon Co tube is actually going
to is is is absolutely going to find its
place with certain people and the the
glass on glass accessories are going to
find their PL people have different
preferences and for
me the taste of the vapix hail the way
the heat heats up the quartz in the
little tube of glass that sort of
convection style of heating
um it offers me such a beautifully
preserved hit that I want to take it
through glass I want it to go right
through glass right to Glass and and for
me I do obviously notice a difference in
in in the hint so I'm quite excited to
get this uh get this little Gauntlet
going here yeah absolutely me too and to
your point you know uh I never been want
to say one is better than the other I I
like to have options as well when people
ask me you know what's my favorite piece
of glass or what's my favor favorite
Hydra tube that goes on top you know
typically my response is anything I
didn't use yesterday you know like I get
used to the different pull and feelings
of certain pieces of glass and you know
for me just having that variety really
keeps things new and fresh for me I
think it's an incredibly important
perspective for us to have that although
you know when you find something that's
great and you want to share it with your
friends and you're inspired it's
important that you don't let your ego
get too involved and where you want to
enforce that this is the best Better Way
by all means show your friends things
and Inspire them to do things
differently but understand that there
are a lot of different people out there
and for me who comes to mind right away
is Irv Rosenfield one of the two or
three legal federally exempt cannabis
users in the US along with Elvie Musa he
gets the big cans of joints 300 of them
every month from the Mississippi
facility and we had on hash church and
we were talking about the quality of
this bot and of course it's Swag and
they're grinding up all the stock and
this that and the other thing and all of
these connoisseurs in the rumor saying
we got to get you better product ir and
that's just ridiculous and and then Irv
just came up with this most beautiful
perspective that none of us had and he
said guys this works for me this is
working for me and in that moment I
realized then he should have access to
that we can never make access only what
we think is best or what we want as best
but we need to open our minds and hearts
up to the opportunities of the quiver
all of the options that we can bring to
the table and we have a few good options
here on the table today what are you
thinking you want to start with you know
um had the congales yesterday so maybe
the was this the super skunk or uh we
got the sweet skunk and then we got a
little bit of hash plant here as well
that's this one's nice because it has
not as strong of a presence as the other
ones it's almost closer to a distillate
even though it's not it has a turpine
profile but a lower uh profile uh from
I'm used to in these other uh more
narrow Leaf drug cultivars this is a
wide Leaf drug cultivar and I find that
when you dip it into the turpine you
really experience that particular tpine
that you're uh that you're dipping into
so this is more like a blank canvas it's
it's closer to a blank canvas absolutely
yeah that's the reason I brought that
one I thought these ones are amazing to
mix because their profiles are so unique
even without adding Turpin but this one
is really one that is more closer to you
know pure canabo with uh a tpine profile
added yeah and this parchment paper is
really top notches well I don't know if
anyone could see this well let's give a
shout out to Snick and the 710 parchment
crew this is a great concept and idea
and I'm glad that you mentioned it they
come out with these little squares
they're wonderful for um for companies
even like vapix hail or any company that
wants their logo it's almost done in
like a braille so it's raised so you put
the rosin in and you peel it open you
see the imprinted in the rosin too the
that is very cool yeah I like that
myself so let's do uh let's start off
with a little hit of this and what do
you think I I'm thinking maybe grape
ghost hey that's the first one that was
staring at me back so I think that's a
good one all right let's give it a
little whiff now I will say a neat thing
about the vapix Hal as we're about to
hit some Tarpin mixed with um some some
rosin is that this is one of the first
units I used that actually allowed me to
hit pure Tarpin in a way that I felt
that they were preserved enough that I
would actually do that cuz before I was
dabbing pure drops on a nail I found it
to be a little bit harsh it just the the
direct Grill style of heat that
conduction was just too much compared to
the the light preservation of this
convection style unit and uh well Brett
and I from West Coast concentrate I
think we did like 10 or 15 tpin a
gauntlet right at this table yeah watch
that all the gauntlets have been done
right at this table the first D40 yes
the first d420 K Gauntlet that we did 18
flavors
uh was here and then Brett and I did the
10 or the 12 whatever that was and now
you and I are going to do just a mini
one just a mini one just a little mini
one four four four each uh because we
have four clean uh tubes but uh that
leaves at least three tpin that we're
not going to experience but that's okay
yes we've always got off camera yeah we
could do those off camera excellent
so can do I usually get a
little I usually Heat this up a tiny bit
but I we should be fine so what I liked
about what you said earlier about having
the multiple Quivers is um you know
there are certain concentrates and
certain you know forms that I feel like
you know might be better for dabbing and
then there's other things like
concentrates and what we're doing today
that I think you know really work well
with our convection based methodology
But ultimately you know I feel like if
you can find a safe easy effective
consistent healthy way to consume your
concentrates you you know whether it's a
low temp nail or through a device like
this you know these are all uh uh
Positive Directions to go in and
removing you know the smoke and
carcinogens from your from your lungs
just a small little dab to give you guys
an idea I'm not sure how well you can
see that but it's it's nothing major
that we're putting in here we're going
to do a little Gauntlet so we're not
going to be packing these in but uh by
all means you uh are welcome to all
right have the first go cool thank you
so much so I'll try to do it at an angle
where people can see what's going on
yeah and got your carb
perfect so we could already see the
first bits of vapor coming out I'm going
to lock this in right
here and here we
go this stuff is just
shatter
wow that was really tasty that was the
the ghost that was the
ghost all sorts of interesting things
going on in that flavor
profile
beautiful got me excited
[Music]
here jeez
wow wow yeah it's an impressive little
unit you've built here I'm not going to
lie when I first saw it I was like oh
okay okay it's like it reminds me of a
few other units that I've seen and I
wasn't you know as excited and then Tony
said that he had tried it and he was
like no you have to try this I'm always
Blown
Away by any unit that can taste as good
as like a big dab off of a nail through
my through my mother's [ __ ] and uh the
vapex hail definitely has that hands
down and that's why I so wanted to be
able to hit it through my mother's this
this is a treat this is a treat thank
you and I don't know if we're filming in
high enough definition but anytime I
take these TPS I get crazy goosebumps
you do that is wonderful I mean there's
no denying that reaction it was almost
like when I went to the hospital with
d420 K and we visited Johnny B after he
had his neck surgery his spinal column
was being flattened and so they released
this one of his vertebrates off of it
and they were worried that it was going
to blow up like a balloon and just pop
cuz your spinal cord is very much like a
a little little balloon and his was
flattened well when the pressure
relieved it it worked out in his favor
and he was extremely you know the the
pain that he was out of was incredible
but he was still obviously sore in the
hospital bed having just had spinal
surgery and we go there and it was the
purple punch that I pulled out and I put
under his name under his nose and
literally in a second he was
like he felt a shift in his
Consciousness and the way the pain was
being experienced and it was a very
short shift he said it just went away
and he he was he was blown away at how
powerful just inhaling smelling a tpine
not not vaporizing just the tur huh yeah
so mine's at a lower temperature that's
why I talked a little bit uh and let it
kind of get going we spoke about this
yesterday at the cchq right so as the uh
glass tube is in the heating chamber
longer it does continue to build up heat
so bubble man here is at the lowest
temperature which is roughly
225° and it's sitting there baking in
the hot air oven uh he'll get probably 4
to six inhalations I got 2 to three at
the 1:00 position which is closer to
375° but you know the great thing is
whether you're a high temp low temp you
know somewhere in between type of Dabber
you'll be able to have the control to
get these hot air dabs oh my God is that
delicious and it immediately felt under
my eyes like inside my head right under
my brain I can literally feel that's
those tpin getting it right to me it's
amazing that we have all these different
compounds that we can now use but it's
as important to have mechanisms that
allow us to vaporize them unadulterated
and unchanged yeah that's the important
factor that we're dealing with now I
believe so I mean I think a good analogy
is you know it's like um if you have a a
coob beef you know you get a steak of it
um it's it's taken so much time to to
create something like that and if you
were to let's just say make ground beef
out of it and make hamburgers well it
could be you know almost uh you know a
bad use of it so uh when I saw what you
and Tony were doing with these
tpin and I I I just knew that this would
be a device that would really kind of
you know help people enjoy it at a
higher level and really I mean all the
the amount of plant that is required to
create just this amount of Tarin I mean
you know it really is like liquid gold
or or liquid Platinum because um the
therapeutic utility that I get from this
it's it's on another level with the
concentrates and I I'll be very curious
as to hear what you know what the
research and science has to say as to
why we feel this way when we add more
tpes to the plants but um there's going
to be a lot of people focused on this in
the upcoming years and I think it's
going to be important for us not to
react in this sort of like who are you
who do you think it's like no let's
embrace all of these people that are
coming into this part of the industry
the people that are going to get phds
and they're going to learn chemistry so
that they can study these molecules and
and explain maybe the pathways or the
relationships that are occurring
underlining that we don't yet understand
especially in regards to how the
interaction occurs in our own endoc
canabo systems which is it's an
incredible amount of science even if we
were just to pick you and one cultivar
that's an incredible amount of science
once we break it into the world and all
of the cultivars that are available
including the ones we can produce
through
breeding it makes the hair on my arm
stand up you know yeah well what's
interesting is I'm going to be very
curious about the CBD chirps and how
they affect the body and if uh that's a
good way for people to you know get that
into their system I mean one of the
biggest things that we've seen
especially with the professional
athletes like Eugene Monroe bu Williams
Taran Jones is uh when they are able to
consume larger amounts of CBD per
inhalation you know they feel a
substantially different effect and why
you know we've been uh really promoting
CBD use with our device uh we're getting
one over to Nate Diaz as well who had
been using the pen but um for whatever
reason you know um when the CBD is
combined with some of these TPS you know
we're noticing a much higher level of
pain relief for these athletes and you
know it's essentially why I've been
getting goosebumps every time I've been
you know fortunate enough to experience
them myself there you go sir that is the
same rosin with now the kovo or Coello
I'm not sure how you pronounce that
Valley in California I don't want to do
it Injustice but this is the sour diesel
tpin oh Sour Diesel give you a nice
little dip there and a nice reasonable
size rip the the efficiency of this unit
is also uh you put in big monster dabs
and you're definitely not going to be
getting through five or 10 of them in a
row cuz one one big monster dab will be
like 15 plus hits I got three light one
really good one and a couple of light
ones after that out of the one I put in
but I put in a really small dab like
substantially small I gave him a little
bit bigger one uh this time around and
I'll take a bigger one as well so nice
to see there's something really quite um
rewarding about seeing a clear piece
fill up with vapor and I also like
watching it travel down this pathway
I do never get tired of watching it
that's for sure and obviously this is
the beginning right now I I picture
maybe a little stand that's custom built
for your pipe or whatever that your pipe
is in place the unit is in place and
it's all one unit so we're not having to
hold it up but truly it's it might it's
not as awkward as it looks I wouldn't
trust just anyone with it that being
said this would definitely not be the
good idea to go down to the cchq lounge
and just blaze everyone down and go here
you go yeah you just fit it right in
into there definitely someone along the
line is going to do something that you
don't want them to do but uh it it's
working great for us well I think the
idea of a stand like this that could go
up and down right into this that's it
like this is locked in we didn't really
do this properly but this is a really
beautiful stand that Sable brought as a
gift it fits all of these little uh
these little units I think we're going
to get ones with holes drilled that fit
the tping jars I can picture that in the
future for sure uh at least Blue River
versions and uh then also the the little
mechanism here that maybe attaches
through holes so you can use different
size ones that fits the pipe right into
the unit yeah you know then then when
you move the whole unit um it would uh I
would also maybe put like a nice felt
you know so you can move it across the
table Yeah we we have rubber feet but we
have felt feet too that we can put on
the bottom but I like the way this locks
in so it doesn't get knocked over did
you get your rip already I did get my
rip thank you so much than dude I wasn't
like paying attention it's funny when
you're just loading you know thank you
I'm using the the dab tender so I I feel
blessed to have someone uh uh do it for
me for once I hope I'm doing it justice
you are you know you never you never
want to use someone's unit in a way that
is uh just not the way the unit was
designed to be used so if you were using
it incorrectly I would let you know you
are a pro I would appreciate that always
for sure so that was cavello and I'm GNA
hit that as well so you know yesterday I
heard you uh telling people about you
know kind of the methodology you guys
were using to create these Tarpin versus
you know how some other people create
tpin so not all people are using you
know uh uh same technology well right
off the bat for sure you know not it's
it's a pretty you have to have a a
commitment in your procedure and Tony
absolutely has commitment in his
procedure he's developed it himself you
know over the last year and a half to
two years and he's gotten to the point
where I can tell from just hitting the
different tpin and smelling them I've
only really tasted a few out there where
I was like this well it's whatever he's
doing is he's doing it right and and a
lot of them have just like off color off
taste little things that when you first
smell with your nose it's you learn to
decipher the difference between a real
gassy sort of like woo to something
that's not supposed to be there to
something that's not was not on the
plant when you smelled it right you know
and so this can be tpin that are
exchanging and changing into new tpin
based on heat so depending on how much
of that steam is being in contact with
the actual resin so there are tricks to
inverting and there are tricks to using
vacuums and there are tricks to using CH
chambers that cool things down Tony's
obviously come up with an incredible IP
and his tpin you know and I say his tpin
because I I don't make the tpin I do
represent Blue River here in Canada but
really the making of the tpin is Tony
and uh he's he's he's nailed it he's
done a great job and and that's not to
say that someone else isn't going to
nail it tomorrow but at this point in
time I don't promote Blue River because
I sell them I sell Blue River because I
promote them yeah I know I I get it
because uh when I became familiar with
tpin was with Blue River so unbeknown to
me I was experiencing it at the highest
level then
as the idea became more pervasive and
more and more people were doing it I got
to you know see other people's t or
whatever they wanted to call it and it
was different so when I heard you
explaining it to someone else I was like
oh that's why it's different well and
people are calling everything tpin we
should be specific when we call these
tpin that they're cannabis derived tpin
that they they were ratios derived from
Cannabis ratios they're they're accurate
ratios they're not mixes that we created
do you know what I mean right we're not
purchasing food grade tpin and then
making um mixtures in them and that
that's something that worries me because
cannabis has been producing tpine
profiles for us to inhale safely for
thousands of years but we don't
generally inhale pure tpin extracted
from lemons or pure Turpin extracted
from mangoes or or any of those things
so yeah it is really interesting that
the tarpine science you know where it's
derived from and what ratio and it's
really amazing that your body you know
has these such
pronounced um effects from you know
these different smells it really makes
you think about you know what you what
you eat as well and how all these things
synergistically work together well
exactly we've been talking about that in
um hash Church lately Dr Natasha uh rise
has been coming in and sharing some
beautiful information with us in regards
to how to activate the endoc canabo
system something will have a great
interest in of course through exercise
and through activity uh there are
different diets there are different
activities and diets that we can use to
actually activate our endoc canabo
system and these things will have a
great greater uh return as to say for
the experience that you have from that
amount in that particular time meaning
it's not just a runner's high that
you're getting when you're exercising
and you're using cannabis you can
actually somehow get that cannabis
seemingly communicating all over your
body and really feel the effects much
more intensely once once you're active
and it's why for me I've never been an
inactive cannabis user I'm not really a
couch and video game kind of guy not
saying that that's a bad thing you need
to do your enjoyment and relaxation but
I see some people getting sucked into
that and I think it would be great for
them to get out and go hiking get your
blood moving get oxygenated and it's it
to me for nothing else just to be able
to enjoy your cannabis Vibe on a whole
other level and then obviously realize
that's livity the importance of that is
incredible and it's just one more thing
cannabis is trying to tell you yeah you
know uh for me that man thank you for
saying that I mean I obviously an active
cannabis user as well U maybe not
obvious but that's what we try to proot
to me it's obvious and you know this
device is kind of like the first step of
you know how do we deliver the canono in
like the safest healthiest way but you
know let's be honest like cannabis is
also like enjoyable thing so how do we
make it fun for the user to use so you
know I really loved dabbing but there
were a few things that you know
especially I'm 39 I have you know
friends that are in their late 20s I
mean sorry late 20s in their late 40s um
and for them like the torch and nail was
just something visually that was hard
for them to get over there's no denying
that the torch and nail is is hard to
get over it's it's
hardcore it is hard it just is and way
before dabbing occurred like in the '90s
before it was named and I'm sure there's
people that are watching this laughing
we were doing that in the 70s of course
you were you were taking oil and putting
it on a hot metal substance and inhaling
it of course that's been around for 40
plus years I'm not denying maybe
thousands maybe thousands you know off
the coal cuz I remember traveling in
Guatemala nothing else but some oil and
being like dropping a a drop on a coal
that was just burning red hot and clean
and it was like man I'm dabbing in
Guatemala that was
1998 but uh yeah back then we would hit
the man a this crazy contraption that my
friends made and uh yeah it was
definitely uh some Next Level [ __ ] we'd
bring that stuff to a party and it was a
blowtorch that had a spoon bent over top
of the to the torch and they would heat
up the spoon and then there was a glass
Bell that went up into a buong it was
super ghetto and really hardcore and it
scared people yeah when you showed up at
a party and and not people in their late
40s young people were freaked out by it
they were like what the it didn't pass
the mom test did not pass the mom test
so it's kind of a neat thing that you've
done here because you know did did this
ever exist before you came up with this
concept of like sliding the I I've never
seen it before uh you know it's it's one
of those things where um it was actually
designed for flowers and um as we were
designing this device uh concentrates
became very popular so uh during the R&amp;D
process uh we wanted to make it a hybrid
device but we also didn't want it to be
like really good at flour and just
average at concentrates so uh luckily
the design that we came up with for
flowers was able to be transferred over
to the oil side and apply you know not
all but most of the technology um you
know we were able to create a device
that I think is is really good at both
and um ultimately I think for especially
a lot of uh uh uh cannabis users that
are athletes or are very active um being
able to get the canabo without any of
the fats waxes lipids or plant matter
you know um it is more congruent with
that type of diet and uh you know I
believe allows you to be a much more
active cannabis user as well awesome I'm
just like at getting the the dab here
and thinking of all the haters on
YouTube going Bubble Man didn't dip he
didn't clean his Dabber and he was
dipping it into different cpin I'll have
you know that I'm only dipping the tip
of the hash into the tpin and not the
titanium portion of the Dabber it's
crazy when you start editing and doing
so many of these videos that you become
so aware of the things that PE you're
just trying to you're trying to share
these great messages that you feel are
important and it's just you know what I
said it the other day when I was talk we
were talking to Jeremiah and jod I said
you know we don't really get to create
reality exactly how we want it we get to
we get to manifest but often it does not
man EST the way you think it will for
instance he just said this thing was
designed for flowers and to me it is a
100% concentration unit to to me you
know like I'm not saying you can't use
flowers I've put them in the basket and
it's great but I just would rather
concentrate the resin off the flowers
and use that to me that makes so much
more sense and it's uh yeah you can't uh
we fight for things and we fought for
cannabis to be you know allowed and and
more normalized here in Canada and and
uh to me we've won quite a bit down in
California you guys have won quite a bit
is it perfect no are people going to
jail still and being arrested yes but
the fact that we have these places that
we can go and buy cannabis and
concentrates and that these machines
exist that you can inhale them with damn
near per through Perfection is a is a
pretty big win and I think that we
should start congratulating ourselves a
little bit and sort of maybe even
throwing a little celebration and saying
hey we got we got some substantial [ __ ]
done in the last 25 years you know I
mean uh there's still more work to be
done but I feel like you I mean uh we
have made so much progress I mean I'm
wearing this shirt today power plant
Fitness you know this is the gym that
Ricky Williams and Jim McAlpine are a
part of that is going to open in the San
Francisco Bay area that um oops uh
allows you to
consume cannabis before you work out and
the machines that you will be consuming
cannabis with will be these nice baby
dude that's amazing that is really cool
yeah I mean you know just uh I mean even
a year ago this idea if I spoke about it
to people I think they would just kind
of scoff and say it was a you know a
pipe dream no pun intended but dude I'm
now the wheels are in motion so for so
many years since doing back country
Photography in like 2010 and 2011 and
being in the back country with skiers
and snowboarders that were just super
inspirational and that I saw were using
cannabis as their inspiration more so
than anything else but because of
sponsorships and whatnot the lack of
normalization it was like it had to be
hidden and it's it's it takes a lot for
these football players to come out and
talk about this I'll tell you because
there are multi-million dollar careers
at stake and when you see someone like
Ricky Williams choose to promote
cannabis over um his multi-million
dollar career it's really hard to argue
with the Integrity of such a cat yeah I
mean you know know like okay so what
could his agenda possibly be if he gave
up millions of dollars to do this right
I would think his agenda is to educate
and help I mean uh even more recently
Eugene Monroe who's been very vocal
about this I mean he was an active
player and he was you know telling the
league to look at CBD and cannaboids as
a way to help the players recover from
these intense exercises and you know I
told him the first time I met him like
to me he had so much to lose that you
know just having him come out like he
had all the respect in the world for me
because of what he had on you know on
the line for saying what he was saying
and um you know I think he brought a lot
of attention to uh not Justa uh can uh
cannabis but CBD uh uh in particular and
you know I'm having people from all
walks of life ask me about it that I
never would have imagined you you know
would even consider cannabis as a a way
for them to heal and um it it's cool to
be part of you know just a small part of
this movement no it really is man it's h
it's coming a long way and of course
it's speeding up you know if you ever
read I think it was Art Bell that wrote
a book called The quickening and it was
uh it was crazy David Ike actually but
uh showed a beautiful metaphor of how
the way we share information is
exponentially growing and the metaphor
that he used was a giant dinner plate
and he takes a dinner plate and he
wobbles it on a table so it's doing this
sort of thing and it's going W woo W woo
W woo and he's like okay that was like a
thousand years ago and then it starts
going W woo W woo W woo W woo and he's
like that was like a couple hundred
years ago and then it starts
going and he's like that's now and then
right before it stops it's just
like and then it stops which is also
gets into Terrence McKenna's time wave
zero it's pretty interesting stuff uh to
look into there's definitely the amount
of information that is passing every day
every hour is like more than what passed
a 100 years ago in maybe a week yeah so
that's a concentration that can only
every system reaches Q in engineering
right Q is like the maximum that any
system can can take before it basically
either stops or disintegrates so it's an
interesting time that we're living
living in of of massive amounts of
incredible energy and people like Eugene
Monroe and yourself and Ricky and all
these great people that are just uh
they're standing up to normalize
cannabis use in everyday life in
professional sports in um you know
pallative and homeopathic care canabo
pathic whatever that word that Lester
grinspoon came up with canab canaba
pathic they're so hard to say it's a
great term whatever it is I wish I
didn't train re I apologize uh Lester
but uh yeah I think I'm going to hit
this beautiful rip that I smell that's
how I feel when I try to pronounce
certain Tarpin um I I read about them
all the time and then when I have a
conversation with someone and I actually
have to say the name of it it always
comes out like really jumbled and
disjointed yeah I hear you well it
couldn't be anything worse than what I
just did to be
cibopath uh word so um what what was
that last tpine that we just experienced
push cleaner oh yes dude and uh was that
still the hash plant rosin or a
different rosin no that was a different
rosin okay that was the sweet skunk and
the reason I put the sweet skunk in
there is because that cleaner from the
jack is really sort of sativa and exotic
and of course the sweet skunk has um
sweet skunk is not skunk at all so
there's uh there's some there's some
nice uh cultivar in there but it it is
not skunk oh I assumed it was skunk
because of its name um PR Steve told me
that uh Mark had run out of all his
skunk seeds on the menu and so he was
like we need something skunk and he was
like I got these and I can't remember
what the name was but he was just like
Mark just named them sweet skunk which
is incredible might have annoyed me back
then I probably would have been like you
can't do that but after so many years of
it being a favorite cultivar that the
name is is a part of it to me and it's
uh I kind of yeah I just went with it
yeah well the name is just to describe
something so exactly and Chimera
mentioned it in hash church one day
hopefully we'll be able to the names of
these cultivars will be you know below
that will be what makes that up what is
in it what are the cannabinoid profiles
and what are the Turpin and the
terpenoids because that's uh that's what
it actually is you know orange
creamsicle okay what it's orangey and
creamic actually it is we should
probably hit that one next yes well
isn't that aren't people doing that
already uh today where they are starting
to you know come up with you know the
the profiles oh yeah slowly but surely
but I mean like the full profile you
know like there's there's a potential
150 tpin that we could be testing for
and most places test for I mean most
cannabis cultivars nowadays only have
the same 10 to 12 right and that's a lot
to do with prohibition based growing
where you grow for the greedy purpose of
how much can you get and how fast can
you get it because if you were to train
only a specific way you would learn
quickly that the blind spots that you
left behind would be would be vast you
know they they got rid of a lot of
profiles by cutting down flowering
periods people that would only grow 6
weeks seven weeks drains well that means
all the 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18
19 20 21 22 week drains are all going to
be more rare because no one's taking the
time to produce them and those cultivars
grown in different countries produced
different cannaboids that we also don't
see in everyday strains we don't see
thcv and we don't see a lot of CBG or
CBC and there's cannaboids quite a few
of them that we don't see because and I
this is my theory that cannabis uh
prohibition based growing sort of you
know cut a lot of that out is
unfortunate really yeah it makes sense I
mean people were just growing high THC
strains right yep yeah yeah
it's fascinating reading all the
research on the various avonoids and how
they help the body I I had a chance to
sit down with one of the uh Chief
scientists from steep hill and uh he was
explaining how CBG has been helping his
father recover from a stroke and uh his
father is an oncologist and a few years
ago or maybe two years ago um suffered a
stroke where uh uh he was a essentially
um from the neck down you know paralyzed
jeez and uh for 6 months they went
through all the standard um therapies
and medications that one would go
through when they suffered the stroke
and then not too much progress and as
you can imagine
um uh uh was getting desperate so they
started administering CBG she pushing
out on you look at that well I'll finish
the story later that's a good rip I've
never seen it push out of the tube like
that I seen it come out just gently from
here before but she was climbing all the
way up yeah that was orange creamsicle
with congales rosin so that's going to
be yeah that's going to be a wow for
that's what I was assuming it would be
right there better have one of
those and please do finish that store
because I certainly didn't mean to cut
you off I just
uh well just to get cut to the point um
after 6 months uh he was able
to uh go back to practicing medicine so
they have been documenting this and uh
you know hopefully in time we'll be able
to to share this story incredible yeah
but to
me you know when people are talking
about whether this
is a medicine or just you know something
that people like to you know recreate
with you know I like it it's such a
silly argument
because if you believe in any type of
science yeah that's what I say just let
us have it please all of
us so I think that congales dreamsicle
was my favorite thus far it had the most
like uh complexity and depth to the
flavor
um I don't think I could even articulate
the flavor except that it was um
very very enjoyable um there's like a
nuttiness I don't know that I always get
whoa it was almost coconuty on the
exhale it was almost and but like creamy
coconutty like almost like suntan lotion
but not like or a p
colada not bad like not the way you
would expect like I hate this taste of P
Cola but that was amazing
Jesus I think that congales rosin is a
really good base to be uh dipping into
the cuz we had the congales with the
cleaner yesterday and uh that one had me
goosebumps for a good five
minutes this is so
good I just want to see this available
to more people you know like I just
think that it would be a cool thing
for people to have access to Great
tasting you know having the conversation
with Jeremiah and jod emry the other day
um where where it was like you know like
what's the most important relationship
that you have with
cannabis other than the way it makes you
feel and the smell of course of course
it absolutely has to be the smell it's
the flavor profile and The Taste and the
smell and that's you know that's what
the Tony he's done with these Blue River
turpins he's just pulled them out in the
most beautiful of manners and uh I'm
happy to share it with people I'm happy
to share it with you uh I'm very stoked
that you came up with the vapexhale and
I look forward to some uh potential
future collaborations with the bubble
man and the vapix halil team you built
an incredible team and I'm definitely
excited to see where the future leads
vapix hail and Sabo yeah well I believe
this
this and this it at this point that is
like the tippity top of how you could
experience cannabis absolutely you can't
fake the Goosebumps that I get you know
it it it's no sales pitch here I mean
that's what I'm saying and I've even
made a point on and I'm sure you've
probably done it with your unit as well
where you're just like for the turps I
just thought I have to step back for
like a week or two and just like cuz I
got so deep in and I was like I just
love these things people like oh it's
hype it's hype people that clearly had
never done it every single person I've
ever given a dab to has been like wow
that's what they always say and so I
just felt like uh I needed to pull back
make sure that there was no hype or
anything confusing me or any sort of and
I didn't have TPS for probably more than
a week actually and getting this these
seven vials was just
like thank you yes yes absolutely it's
like your favorite sauce on your
favorite meal Pizza without sauce is Noy
I know well when I was little I used to
really like reading those books where
you could you know choose um you know
either option A or option b me too yeah
I feel like go to page 74 if if you want
to jump off the cliff I was going to say
look over the cliff that's so funny oh
my gosh so I believe you know these
Tarpin um especially with that first one
the uh the Kush or the hash plant yeah
it was has um you know I felt like
because that was more of like a blank
palet it really kind of took on the
flavor of exactly how that smelled
whereas when we had the congales as the
base um especially with something so
different like orange yeah it just uh
the synergies of it was undenied it was
next level Next Level I usually hit the
Kush cleaner with the Congo because of
that cleaner and that sort of sativa
flavor or sweet skunk but uh I thought
you know what he wants orange creamsicle
it's our last rip and we haven't hit the
Congo yet you also notice the vibe from
the Congo is it's that's one that I
would be working out with you will
people will learn at that gym that there
are cultivars that are congruent to
getting them to working out yeah so um
down in California one strain that seems
to be very popular is the red congales I
don't know how similar it is to this one
right here right but um I
do uh we have this other company can of
athlete that is making this recovery
serum and whenever we can get uh uh our
uh distillate made with this type of
trim um we believe it is congruent with
the feelings that you would need to
perform at a high level after you
consume cannabis where you get like the
focus with the relaxation I guess uh you
know more closer to Flow State and um
yeah I mean I think this is a strain
like you said is really congruent if you
want to um you know do some sort of
activity that requires like dexterity
like maybe wakeboarding or yep
snowboarding so absolutely yeah well
it'll be interesting to see where it all
goes in the next upcoming years I'm
definitely uh I'm in it for the long
haul this industry has had me for 20
plus years and I don't see it letting go
anytime soon so going to keep on
enjoying incredible technology and
learning as much as I can about that
technology and these processes and the
growing and all of these different
things so I can share it with you the
bubble man audience and uh I want to
thank Sabo vapex halil for coming right
to my house to film this video and I
remember you even said yeah I'm going
come there we should film and I was like
yeah okay you're going to come here like
you're down in California man but I do
appreciate that you came up and uh
shared this uh beautiful technology with
everyone and I can't wait to see it
showing up in the vapor bars here in
Vancouver thank you thank you and you
know um I appreciate you inviting me
over to your house um you know I know a
lot of people say yeah I'll go visit and
never do so I'm very appreciative of
that and also I mean being able to be a
part of this journey with you um you
know I've known about you for a very
long time and for me you know I also
like I don't get tired of being in this
industry because of all the people that
I know that we are helping whether
directly or indirectly you know whether
it's showing them new technology like
the tpin or new Delivery Systems like
this device you know being able to
educate people and let them know what's
out there so that they can make their
own choices and do it safer or better
you know it always feels good and be
being able to feed your family while
helping people I mean how could you ever
get tired of that can't beat that Sabo
thanks for coming up dude thank you
brother really appreciate it thanks for
watching Bubble man's world we'll see
you guys next time peace peace