All
[Music]
right, here we go. We're
on. All right, so we've got our resin
here. Our 25 micron still sitting out in
the bag, which is fine. It's uh out in
the cold weather. We've got the towel
underneath and we've got the towel over
top. We've got our strainers, a little
one and a big one, and a variety of
spoons that we'll be able to use inside
the strainer to allow it to to fall
properly. So, I've also got um this is
helpful cardboard with all the numbers
written on it already. 160, 120, 90, 73,
and 45. And I have uh some other
cardboards here as well with more
numbers on them. So, it's pretty
important, even though you might think
you know what's going on, to mark down
the resins. Like I was saying to Ron
earlier, when he put the the 220 right
in the middle, if we had all of these,
you know, sure, an expert hashmaker
should pretty much be able I could tell
you which one the 45 is, the 73 and the
90 would be pretty easy to hone in. It
wouldn't be impossible, but let's just
be organized and and do this the proper
way. So, we're going to do straining
today. We're not going to do
microplaning. Microplaning is a process
where I freeze these after removing a
lot of the moisture, either letting it
wick just like this. Freeze them and
then microplane them over the cardboard.
We're going to do stainless uh strainer
today. And I'm going to just clean this
out a tiny bit cuz it's still dirty from
the last time I used it. Giving it a
little whack like that will literally
clean 95% of the resin out of it. That's
why I like the strainers. It's nice like
that. So, this is pretty high quality
resin. You kind of have to know with
straining how what quality of the resin
you're working with. If you're working
with an extremely high quality resin and
you press down really hard, it's bonded.
You're never going to push it through a
strainer. You might as well throw that
stuff in the uh in the freezer and
microplane it. So, I'm going to be um
pretty gentle. You can see there's these
patties here have now dried out a tiny
bit. Pretty much for straining, I don't
want them to be much drier than that. I
know the quality of this watermelon. I
know the quality of Subcool and his
strains, the TGA crew. They don't mess
around. Um, those guys produce Fullmelt
genetics, you know, certified by me, the
Bubbleman. Um, yeah. So, let's let's do
this. We've got our strains here. I can
kind of lift it up a little bit for you.
220, 190, 160, 120, 90, 73, and 45. So,
we're going to take these for starters.
Now, the 220, it's it's nothing. It's
not even a product. So, I mean,
literally, I'll just put it up here in
the corner of the 160. I I won't push
that through the strainer. I don't want
that on the strainer contaminating my uh
my final product. And nor do I want uh
the 190. Uh they'll both be cooked into
metamals most likely. So, those can just
sit right there on top of the screen or
on top of the cardboard. This is the
first one I'll actually do. And I
suggest when you do this that you use a
separate strainer for your lower grades
as opposed to your higher
grades. So take that out. We're going to
take our 160. Now, place it in our
stainless strain strainer and literally
just grind it through. You know, not
grinding it harsh, but just nice and
gently. And you can can see it just
falls as powder. And uh I'll get Ron to
do a few of these later and I'll
actually film it closer so you can see
what I'm talking about of allowing it to
spread thin. And so as you get to the
end when you think that you just have
all this hash stuck in your strainer,
you just come over to the other side and
kind of give it a little shave and give
it a little
[Music]
whack and everything comes off of your
strainer. So there's our 160 done. Our
220 and our 190 are sitting there
undone. I'm going to take this strainer
and this spoon and put it over here
because it has a lower quality resin.
And because we want to be obsessive
about this, let's think about it. We use
cannabis for 3 months. We made variables
of choosing phenotypes, growing it under
extreme conditions from controlling
everything indoors to trying to control
bugs and powdery mildews. Maybe you're
in a greenhouse and you need to add
extra light because it's not sunny
enough and you need to There's so many
variables that happen along the lines
and then you get to the point where you
trim it and that's a variable and how
you maintain the trim and what you do
with the trim and taking the trim and
finally washing it, not leaving it in
the water too long, doing all the steps
properly. Getting to this point, this to
me in my opinion is the only thing that
the water hash maker is doing right. The
ice mixing is popcorn and anyone can do
it. It's it's it's water and ice is
doing the whole job for you. So, please
don't take credit for that. The grower
has grown great resin for you. So,
please don't take credit for that. What
you can take credit for is doing this
properly. Doing this process properly is
extremely important and uh you'll be
rewarded when you do. So, this 120 that
we have is huge. So, I think I'm going
to put it on the 120 and the 45. It's a
very big piece of of uh of 120. So,
we'll get that right into the into the
strainer. We can just put it all at
once. Nice little pile there. And then
we'll want to move this out of the way a
little bit cuz actually I think yeah,
I'm going to go 120. I might even do
120, 45, and 73. This is so big. I might
do the whole. And you can see how it
comes out. You want it to spread thin.
You don't want it to be getting all
thick. And that's why you need a lot of
space for the cardboard. A lot of people
do this wrong. They clump it all up.
This hash needs surface area. Once it
has the proper surface area, the
cardboard is going to do its job, which
is to wick the moisture out of the
hash. Very important process. That's why
so many people that are that turned off
a water hash because a it was never
dried properly or b it was, you know,
made
incorrectly. Little things, little
variables like um not leaving it in the
water for an
hour.
Awesome. All right, so the card filled
up there. I'm not sure where I got
caught up. I was tapping the 120 micron.
We've now moved into the um 90 micron.
Beautiful. Beautiful. Nice fatty little
patty of just absolute blonde goodness.
We're going to get that out on the 90
here. Strainer just works so good. I got
to say, like I prefer this over uh the
microplaning every every time. It's just
so easy. You've watched the videos of
the microplaning and the grinding of it.
It's just I mean I I don't do it a ton
so I'm not pretending to be the the you
know the expert microplaner but I
definitely definitely prefer
this. That's just clean and easy. I
don't have a drop of resin on my
fingers. I get all the resin off of the
um off the strainer. Even though you can
see the there is a little bit of a
buildup there from someone not cleaning
it. You can get it all off if you
require it. Okay. So, get over to this
70 micron
here. 70 can go right into that same
one. And we'll see what we got for
70. All right. I managed to save some
room on that.
Okay. So, we'll be able to do our
45 and still make room for it because
I'm not sure if you guys remember at the
video there, I actually put the
120 on the 45. And that's important that
I mark that down. Like, these two are
120s now. And as well that I mark this
down that uh I don't know if there's a
pen around, but I'll make sure that I do
that because I don't want my resins all
mixed up. Once again, 45. I could
guarantee tell. I can always tell when
it's the 45. It has a very particular
taste almost regardless of the strain.
It's always very
oily. All right. So, there we have
it. You can see that it's really not as
difficult as some people might make it
out to be. You've got
your cardboard resin, 160, 120, 90, 73,
and 45. All beautifully spread out. This
is um easy to move in my opinion.
Cardboard's light. I can go now and put
it in the room where it's going to be
drying, and it's just going to stay away
from dust, debris, hair, everything. Um
we'll probably take one of the 100
micron screens, the four the framed 2x4
foot frames I have, and we'll flip it
over top of this so nothing can fall on
top of it. So, um I think that's pretty
much it. We'll catch up with you guys
later when this is all dried. I'll end
up getting macro photographs of it and
melt shots. But for now, I just want to
give a huge thanks to Ron for having us
out here. I want to get a picture just
to say this, you guys. If Mark was seems
at all fast what he's doing, he's on a
plane in the next 10 minutes. We got to
get him on icy roads and to an airport
and on a plane. So, he did that rock and
roll.
Cool. We'll see you guys later on
Bubbleman's