use of cannabis and uh Mark Richardson
and kig love they can also attest to
this in a moment and so what we've done
is we've I've I've adapted a very simple
Ritual from the 19th century by this guy
Chandra Ananda Khali and he in 1867 came
up with a a three chilling ritual it's
dedicated to the three phase Shiva we've
got a three-face Shiva right here uh um
smoking a Chillum drinking this holy
bong and preparing B right here right
and uh um he would have been us they
would have been using Chums much like
this antique Chillum from India and uh
um what what what uh Ananda Chandra
Khali's view was uh as he wanted to come
up with a form of Shiva worship that
included all the different casts of of
India so that they weren't separated uh
uh um through these racial divisions you
know the color of their skin and things
like that and so he came up with the the
three CH the three CHS for the
three-phase Shiva and the three-phase
Shiva in his time was Brahma Vishnu and
Shiva which were the three main deities
which kind of broke up uh uh the cast
system but the three-phase Shiva he goes
way back in history that goes way back
to the kusam period when the cians uh uh
were dominating Northern India uh the
three-face Sheba was worshiped as well
then so it's a very very old God and
very cannabis connected as well and so
uh um what we're going to do first is
I'm going to um invite everybody to like
load a pipe or a Chillum you know the
beauty of the three Chillum ritual is
the Simplicity of the ritual that was
the basis of it something that didn't
take a lot of preparation something that
uh everybody could partake of in
together and that's that's kind of what
we're going for here it's something very
simple and basic and we're gonna in have
a kind of a overview of Shiva in between
the three children we've got different
speakers coming up throughout the next
couple of hours and uh we're g to then
we're going to do a simple uh um um bong
pouring on the Lingham ritual as well at
partway and so let's start it all off by
uh loading up a Chillum or a pipe or a
joint you can use whatever you want but
the idea is the three things and uh I'm
gonna let Marcus Gary Richardson hey why
don't you pipe in you know you've been
to India and you've been to the big
celebration of the
Kumba uh which is like the the the the
huge hugest celebration in the world
longest Contin continual celebration I
believe as well as probably the largest
human gathering on Earth and you've
partaken of the Holy ganja with sadus
worshippers of Shiva right there in
India why don't you tell us a little bit
about
that yeah well what an amazing
experience it was to be able to uh to be
able to have that experience in the
first place and I kind of
remember you know I think it was the
year that Tre you know I was really into
fish and I was traveling and cruising
around and checking out fish I kind of
missed the Grateful Dead scene just by a
little bit Jerry passed away in 95 I
ended up on this fish Road and around
1998 the guitarist from fish was like
you know what guys like I love that
you're here every night and in so many
words he basically said go do something
else like honestly stop following us
around stop doing this go do something
else and I was like you're right I need
to do something else and I was like what
would be a cool like thing for me to go
like travel like for tour like I'm going
to see fish but it's not fish it's like
a multi year old ancient ritual you know
taken place by millions and millions of
people over the course of our lifetimes
and certainly even over the course of
just my visit there was over three
million people in the town that I went
to so I did go to the Kumba MAA I was
lucky enough to go for those of you that
know a little bit about the Kumba it is
a festival that happens uh every three
years in four different holy cities so I
believe it's Jaipur alabad uh varasi and
haridwar I could be wrong I may have
gotten that wrong but I ended up in
harir where it re does every 12 years
you end up for what is called the Maha
Maha Kumba now they also have a a Maha
Maha Maha Kumba which is the 144 year
cycle so when you get into a rituals
like this with a group of people that
have had history like this I mean for me
it was the most incredible thing and to
compare it to fish and the Grateful Dead
lot was very cool because when I got
there and I was you know overwhelmed by
all of these incredible people you know
we started you know we started oh let's
go smoke some Charis with these guys
let's go smoke and we were smoking with
all of these different sects the brahmas
and the bishnu and the you know the the
the eventually the shites but before I
met the shites I met the nagas and that
was probably some of my most intense
experience because that was there was
some massive cultural differences I mean
I don't even think people in like not
everyone in India hangs out with the
nagas you know because there's even
cultural differences in that culture but
from for me I found that it was just
they were just really the most out there
from anything that I understood or knew
and I really thrived on hanging out with
them I mean it was archaic hanging out
with a bunch of kind of new dudes that
were you know that we they knew we
didn't speak their language so they were
kind of grunting and using body
languages and we were just in these
little almost like cave like huts and
they've got their bodies covered in
ashes and they don't own anything and
we're smoking this napali Charis that
you know me and my buddy brought to the
Kumba MAA and it was just incredible I
remember leaving there I remember
leaving the Naga tent if you will and
there was uh a Hari Krishna who was
outside and he was quite educated and uh
you know he looked I I could tell he'd
been to like University but he was also
very you know he was following his his
spiritual path but I was really kind of
offended by what he said because he said
oh what were you doing in there and I
said oh we were just you know meeting
and interacting and sharing energy and
he said did you eat any food and I said
yeah of course they offered us some food
and we ate it oh you will surely be
poisoned he he says to me and I was just
like I was like all right so even here
at the Kumba MAA there's this same Petty
energy that you find on fish tour you
know like this is this is something
we're just recreating these rituals in
our own rights through because we lack
the culture in North America so we
recreate these gatherings and I really
found my people when I met pasupati the
shivi Baba that I connected with in
harir the one that I continue to smoke
with every day on the banks of the ganes
one more chillim we are making yes Baba
G one more Chillum we are making and man
did we smoke incredible hash he had the
nose he found us like you Chris would
find the Dank on dead tour you know
amongst three million people and on a
side note this guy spoke over 50
languages he would pull people off the
ganes he'd just be like that guy there
go go get him go get him and then he
would just speak their language didn't
matter where they were from North Korea
South Korea Thailand China Vietnam he
just spoke like I didn't even know that
one person could know that many
languages and in the meantime his story
was that he was caught stealing uh as a
young boy nine years old he had a choice
to go to prison or to become the helper
of the Babas and so he started helping
Babas and traveling with Babas he he was
from rajastan so he ended up meeting
some really colored colorful character
shite Bubbas and they took him under
their wing and he would you know create
and and the the clay cups in the morning
so that they were all ready for the chai
throughout the day and he would keep the
fire stoked and he would sweep the area
on the banks of the river and so doing
that for many years he that's how he got
onto the spiritual path of the shite
Bubba and uh just really connected with
the shites while I was in hardar I never
snubbed my nose at hanging out with
anyone CU I was so interested in
learning from all these different
cultures but it took me two days to
realize who my people were at the maaha
Kumba he was the motorcycle Baba too I
think he was known as as well wasn't he
that is a different Baba that's Shiva
that's Shiva jiri and Mark Rose can
speak of Shiva jiri later and that was
Doc Atomic who actually
introduced Mark Rose to Shiva jiri and
I'm sure he has incredible stories
because you know he that was a heavy
Bubba that he was hanging out with and
he hung out with him for a lot more than
a month here and a month there he was he
was invited into caves that like no
white person has been invited into maybe
ever you know like for sure at least for
a thousand or 2,000 years caves that
cows were allowed in but uh just not
foreigners and so I I hope he tells
those stories later yeah yeah I wish I'd
invited doct at Tom like I didn't really
think of it I I I actually now that you
mentioned it I should have he had taken
when my son was born he'd taken a
picture to Shiva Jerry and had it had it
pictured you gave me the picture so uh
yeah dude I said that all we I was like
man like let's get a picture of I
actually asked Mark Rose to do that and
he was like oh I'm too afraid to ask
Shiva jiri so then I asked Dr Atomic and
he was kind of like oh man like I don't
know and I'm like dude what are you
talking about like of course like this
guy's full of love like just tell him
the story and you know two days later
there's there's Shiva jiri in the cave
holding the picture of your son yeah was
so incredible dude yeah incredible and
his son is called Shiva too
sha it was so cool trust me I went out
of my way to make that one happen and so
did Doc Atomic and so did Mark Rose they
were both just afraid to ask him and I
thought well come on I get it that you
rever and look up to this man but you
know listen if he's emanating the love
that you're saying he's emanating then
it's not going to be a question he's
gonna say of course Mark Rose was
surprised when he just said of course
yeah give me the picture let's take you
know it's surprising like these these
guys would they're basically Street
people a lot of times but then they're
great figures of respect in India as
well you know and and with full of full
of mojo as well so it's like a real
dichotomy it was uh it was really hard
for for the British to understand when
they first went in to India that these
naked Beggars were were commanding the
respect of the town's people more so
than they could with their weapons and
horses and chariots and all that type of
stuff they must have missed those
chapters in the Bible that said Jesus
doesn't come back as a CEO of a Fortune
500 uh company yeah he's generally gonna
be barefoot he's might look like a
beggar what you're saying Trump isn't
the new
Messiah no comment no comment well uh
first Speaker We Got Is Here kig la love
and he's gonna give us uh you know if
you don't know about Shiva now you know
because uh our brother here is going to
be giving us a a good Spiel on the
background of shba in Kashmir well thank
you guys very much I'm very grateful to
be invited to talk
um I don't have to say what I'm about to
say but I want to say it because I have
a lot of gratitude and so traditionally
we think our gurus but because I
normally EMB break with tradition I'm
going to do it anyway because out of
gratitude right and so the first person
I want to thank is Chris because growing
up Chris was a major figure for me like
I grew up uh in Christianity and I broke
away from Christianity like my heart was
broken and a major reunification with my
theolog my theology with Christianity
was Chris's work Chris kind of like gave
me back the romance that I lost with
Christianity because he he made me
realize that this plant and what Christ
was saying and the and the Jewish
Mysteries were this continuous message
from ancient times that I eventually
connected to Kashmir because in Kashmir
we have a mixing of the Jewish Mysteries
and the shite Mysteries it it was there
where I found this big Melting Pot
ancient ancient times where you could
see the Jews and the leites sharing
cabala and shavis side by side mixing
their Theology and so the modern cabala
and the modern shabis that we have today
came from that mixing came from that
that inner mixing of ideas from shavis
so everything Chris has been doing from
the start has been leading up to this in
the same way and it's been like a
Confluence of rivers just like the
yamuna the sarasvati and the ganji meet
at the at this this triple point um one
of the main figures that connects all of
our traditions
is uh it's called trium bakana which is
dianis dianis is know as thos the the
Thrice great one right the winning one
the triumphant one so TR Baka connects
us to that River TR bakan is also the
the God who is married to the triple
Rivers the three over and over again the
triple the triple Rivers the triple
Powers the triple PR prongs the triple
goddesses he's also the God who is
married to the triple goddesses so the
this special meaning of triak also is
not only three eyes it's three rivers
and three wives it's three meanings in
one this idea that three meanings exist
in one repeats itself over and over
again even in like a Jewish Jewish text
where you're supposed to interpret it
there's a a three-fold meaning in one so
in the same way these shite texts is
three meanings in one there's the Shambo
interpretation there's the shaki
interpretation and there's the
individual interpretation we're dealing
with the highest level in Kashmir with
the monistic with the first one with
Shiva himself where we identify directly
and simply with Shiva so when we talk
about Simplicity and bringing back
Simplicity this particular time right
now Shiva ratri is the union of the of
the future and of the past together
where the Sun and the Moon come together
where the in and out breath come
together where we realize now at this
moment that everything's opening up and
we get that understanding of the true
potential of the future where it was the
same potential that came from the past
that shiva's that that consciousness of
potentiality that has infinite Evolution
infinite potentiality here at this
moment now we're experiencing a radical
revolution of Consciousness this
psychedelic research has been like at
the Forefront of this this is why I
thank you and I consider you part of
that lineage of gurus I see you just as
much as somebody that I honor as I I do
Swami G thank you very much for your
work and in the same way uh Swami lakman
jeu he opened up the tradition in this
age he opened up tradition so everybody
gets initiation anybody can can open
open up these texts anybody can listen
to what we're saying and be initiated
right now that that everything has
changed the future is open to us all of
us are going to become Shiva if we want
to if we so desire and it's that simple
in the 18th uh in 9th century was it was
one of the Masters uh utala DEA he is
the master of the master of the master
he he's one of the the starting masters
of this tradition he opened this
tradition up to everybody he said no
doesn't matter who you are women all
casts all creats all race anybody if you
can understand these words that's how
simple it can be it can be as simple as
understanding because it is as simple as
recognition this is the school of
recognition it is the highest and the
easiest path and when we say easy we
mean we laugh because it's like it's
deceptively easy because it requires a
level of mental fortitude that can only
be facilitated by something like
cannabis so back again cannabis is
important because cannabis facilitates
the forgetting of the world and the
focusing on Consciousness on meditation
on the higher elevation of the mind so
cannabis once again brings us into the
moment into the focus into the
one-pointed awareness so when Swami G
taught me how to pray he was quoting the
Gita he was quoting a vava text but he
was like it doesn't matter if it's a
vishna text we we'll use the vnaa text
and we'll say you know in it's a chapter
three of the Gita verse 14 where he
talks about rain food sacrifice in the
beginning God created the world through
sacrif
we sacrifice to the Lord the Lord Reigns
blessings unto us well whenever we light
up that same fire is the same fire of
sacrifice that fire in the joint is the
yagna that same AG is the same Agy in
the in the vitic fire rituals we're
performing thetic fire rituals when we
light up and we say to ourselves this is
Shiva this the fire is Shiva we are
Shiva I offer Shiva to Shiva who is Lord
Shiva Lord Shiva is consuming Lord Shiva
and you don't have to say it a lot you
could just recognize it as your smoking
your joint as you're inhaling and
exhaling both of these movements it it
represents that that constant throbbing
that constant awareness that Shiva is in
everything and and that direct
recognition is what what I keep trying
to bring up with this uh with this
school he's saying paa says the direct
constant recognition of the Lord is the
highest form of devotion no nothing else
is necessary just constantly remember
that Lord Shiva is shining in everything
all the time and that becomes like this
constant understanding that that that
you do in everything so you our yoga is
focused on going outside and working
doing help helping the
world
e
e e
this missing piece of Kashmir of Christ
cannabis the Jewish Myster is like this
is a continuation of our heritage my
Heritage my what I was raised in what
I've been researching what you've been
researching like this is a continuation
of of the dichotomy and what I feel is
the the resolution of the dichotomy of
this world in which most of the world
keeps fighting this fight where it seems
like it's the Scholars versus the
Warriors right but in ancient times they
were friends and so like why it seems
like we've degenerated into this fight
between like um the Jewish Mysteries and
the Aryan Mysteries but what if they
were one in the same at one point if
they just all degenerated into this
stupid fight this ignorance of the kuga
has made us forget that the the scholars
existed to facilitate the Warriors and
then we have we have to come together
and realize that we're brothers and
share in that Unity understand that
we're specialized in different ways but
not restricted from the
knowledge see I'm I'm not trying to push
cast I'm just saying that we have to
realize that the vas talk about how well
what what's good for you isn't good for
me because I was built to do this and
you were built to do that so we
shouldn't criticize each other if you're
in the mode of this like like you were
talking about the nagas right the nagas
are a completely different mentality a
different way of thinking right well the
Kashmir shavis comes from nagas it comes
from thinking Swami lakshman jeu he
doesn't identify with Rama he identifies
he identifies with lakshman and lakshman
is considered um aaga he's considered
the The Reincarnation of patanjali who
was a Naga he's considered the the
Incarnation of shesha Naga he's in he's
uh considered the the direct incarnation
of the tamas Guna so this whole Naga
teaching is very dark it's very Sinister
it's intense it's Primal it was here
before humans was here it was here when
the reptiles were here it is an
extension of this primordial and that's
why in the myid we always see um the
Naga and the human Krishna and brother
balarama Rama and his lakshman you know
there's always the human teaching and
the Naga teaching and so here here we
are realized that Shiva is is friends
with the nagas friends with the Naga
teaches that's why Shiva is bowling off
because he'll be friends with anybody
he'll be friends with the with the with
the nagas with the ghosts with the
demons and and he's e easy to please
anybody can come offer anything to Shiva
and he will give them bounds he will
accept it that's why we can come with
not only cannabis but any herb any any
plant that we offer with love to Lord
Shiva is a means and an access to Lord
Shiva that's why I love the word eny
because truly it is that Theos that
Shiva that we're trying to generate
whether we do it through yoga or whether
we do it through a preparation or an
Elixir a
plant whether we do it through Mantra or
japa or Kundalini Awakening like all are
means to achieve Lord Shiva my my master
his favorite his favorite uh book was
the shivas scra Al it is a a celebration
a song that was that was written when
when uhal was on the on on the boat and
he was just singing it he was just in
ecstasy singing on the boat and his
devote was writing it down and he's just
praising Lord Shiva praising Lord Shiva
and he describes all of the sex he he
describes the Kula sex the Agora sex ex
he describes the right hand path the
left hand path noen path he says that
all paths are a mean to to CH Chiva
whether you want to do nothing or do
everything whether you and he says the
highest form of of of attainment is
devotion devotion will carry you no
matter what you do if you put devotion
in it it will always carry you to the
end devotion will carry you to all the
yogic powers to to to to achievement of
whatever it is that you want Devotion to
Lord Shiva in everything that you do is
the means to attain whatever it is that
you desire and that's why it is so
simple bolanath is always my favorite
because he is so simple I strive for
that Simplicity that's why going forward
I want to make things as simple as
possible for everybody I feel that I
feel that let's let's open everything up
let's make it simple it should be simple
that's the promise of Technology right
like people take for granted clean power
clean energy right but that's something
if you go to India that's not something
people have that's something that that
that's been there a huge leap sanitation
all these things we should be as shites
coming back like the gods introducing
all this beauty just in the same way
they gave us Beauty we give Beauty back
to everybody why not we have such beauty
what we have here is such a gift like
you've literally discovered the omit and
now it's time to share it with
everybody thank you Chris once again for
your work thank you kiga brother that
was beautiful man and yeah there's
there's no escape from Shiva man we all
return to Shiva that you know alls we
can do is uh struggle a little bit
against it inevitably you know the big
the INB breath and out breath of the
universe is the big bang and the return
of the big bang and the the recycling
and there's no Escape man the best thing
to do is just fall into syn with it man
find your place in that Cosmic scheme
your will man and be one with Shiva and
our next uh friend that's up speaking I
see Doug's there he made the
technological leap and uh joined us on
zoom and Doug as well like Marcus has
spent a lot of time in India spent many
years in India and uh I think he has
some uh probably some stories to to
share with us uh Shiva related ganja
related uh uh whatever whatever you can
bring to the table brother Doug it's all
yours oh you got to turn your unmute
your mic there's a little spot there see
it
unmute yeah it'll be on the bottom left
bottom left am I on now yeah we can okay
uh nice to see you again Chris uh I
spent seven years in India I originally
went there because I
uh I was in the pop business in the
early 70s and uh everything became
commercial so I decided I'd go look for
the hash Fields so I had I went to India
and uh when I was there I met some
incredible people and had some
incredible experiences I rode a
motorcycle from one end of India to the
other and uh I lived up in a place
called uh Kulu uh in Himachal Pradesh
mostly was my base even though I was all
over India and in Himachal Pradesh I
lived in a valley called the Kulu Manali
Valley Parvati Valley and it's very
famous for Quality hashish and and in
one Valley Parvati Valley who is the
consort of Lord Shiva in a little town
called a village actually called
manikaran uh is a home of Lord Shiva and
there's a Mander there as well as the
Kara and uh I lived in this area for
years and years and I I became friends
with this nagab Baba who is a nagab
Babas are priests of Lord Shiva they
were they don't have much they only have
a blanket and Lungi and they have a fire
and they don't touch material things
money or anything like that you know but
this one nagab was the most powerful man
in a 500 mile radius his name was gopal
G Maharaj and uh which is funny because
he has a v naava name but he was a nagab
baba Shiva Baba and he lived next to
this little temple in in a place called
out Au T it's it's spelled and uh he
lived in a little Shack beside the
temple and he was like he was like the
counselor the merry counselor the the he
he was the doctor the he was the ruler
even though he owned no possessions at
all he was the most powerful man
everyone respected this
man m to the max like the pope or
something and uh he lived next to this
little Shiva Temple which I found really
interesting because it had two altars
and the first alar was a buwan and buwan
is a Yoni and Lingham or translated in
English a Vina with a penis in the
center and and on Shiva roty everybody
bathes the lingum and the Yoni with
yogurt or or
or uh milk uh usually with a combination
of cannabis like a a bang lassi kind of
thing and uh flowers and garlands and
they have a feast and and it's the one
day in India where cannabis is legal
being a
Sacrament and the nice thing was this
little Temple next to him the first
altar was a bakwan and then the second
altar was a lifesized deity of Lord
Shiva and Parvati and Lord Shiva is
standing there and he has a meter long
penis and Parvati has her arms wrapped
around the penis smiling so
sweet I used to love to take Christians
there because they would they would uh
they would go oh that's perverted and
I'd say oh but what's perverted you you
worship a monkey on a stick come on
isn't that
perverted just to make them realize that
the different concept is not bad it's
just different and it's a very sweet
concept because the buck one goes back
to the union of the male and female
which begins life and and in India it's
uh the oldest temples are buan temples
actually and uh but I used to love to
take people there just to just to show
them to make their mind see a different
light a different view you know you know
also this ngab buub and I we got really
lucky I uh when I went to India I went
back and forth a few times I lived in
Boston at the time in the states and uh
my doctor gave me a big bag of
tetracyclin eye cream and other
medicines like uh there was some
penicillin also right and anyway
I took her with me to India I didn't
know you know why I had it all this
medicine but to show you that Shiva has
a plan I when I got to India there was I
was living in this little village on the
side of a mountain and uh there was a ey
flu then this eye flu took over all of
India and it made people they couldn't
see they couldn't function in the light
for for like two weeks right and this
nagab babba and I we went from Village
to Village to Village
and we treated people with this
tetracyclin eye cream which reduced the
sickness to like two days and we were so
lucky to do this to be able to help all
these people and I realized the doctor
gave me this without knowing but it it's
it it's the God's plan and uh as a
result I would wake up every morning in
my little village I lived in and there
would be potatoes and carrots and all
these cauliflower all these veggies on
my doorstep and this is the way the
people repaid me they're a very very
sweet place to live it was around 3,000
meters up in the Himalayas and uh it was
a great experience I I have many many
stories but I don't want to take up all
your time I thought just to share one
story would be nice give that to them
pardon was that just an intuition to
give that to them or like something told
you that that would be a good medicine
for them or how did you come up with the
idea I didn't I just wanted to take
anything that was valuable back to India
that I could take I took seeds I took
grain I took wheat I took all different
things with me right but the because my
doctor gave it to me I thought well I'm
going to the third world maybe this will
come in handy and it was it was ey drops
Tetra cycl ey drops of all things and
when the nagab bab babba told me this
flu was taking over The Villages I was
happy to go with him and we went out all
for the next few days Village to Village
to Village treating people with
tetracyclin eye cream and curing them of
this horrible I flu you made some pretty
good oil in India as well didn't you
blew a lot of uh sados Minds with the
potent oil you were making yeah I was
actually turning hashish into honey oil
using a petrolium ether as an extract
and uh activated charcoal to clean it up
and I had a great big leeching pot that
held four kilos of hashish and
uh and I was making oils and living very
comfortably in India and and and the
nagab Baba who was my friend he loved my
oil
he I was feeding with my oil and and uh
he told the police not to not to bother
me that if they did bother me they would
have to deal with him and of course
everyone was very much even the police
very much afraid of this man because he
was the most powerful man and he had all
the people behind him so the police
never ever bothered me and I was sitting
up in this Village it was illegal to
make alcohol in this Village but I was
sitting there making oil because oil is
a
Sacrament W almost like you were just
protected you had some kind of yeah you
had some protection force and maybe that
was you know Shiva protecting you to do
your good work yeah you know a funny
thing was when I was living there a
bunch of people came down from Manali
with like about 10 kilos of Hashi and
the police busted them and my and my
nagab Baba friend went into the police
station he took the hashish and says
this belongs to Shankar and walked
out and the police couldn't touch him of
course right and then he gave it back to
the to the people that the police took
it
from that was funny there's a great book
called cannabis Madness and colonialism
and it's about um trouble the British
Raj faced with those type of individuals
the naked Babas and the naked fers and
the Islamic tradition and uh the British
were you know going in there taking over
this is like during the British Raj but
they would like be cruising down the
streets in their in their wagons and
things like that and uh a naked Bob
would walk right out in the middle of
the street and stand in their way and if
they would try to get physical with them
it was a real line cross for the people
you can push people so much but you
start AR like messing with their
religious world and they will Rebel in a
heartbeat right you know what I mean so
it was this tenuous situation where they
were able to main control with a certain
amount of respect but if they cross that
line then the people would uprise you
know and so they were trying to figure
out what to do with these sadus and
stuff like that and this is where this
scientific explanation of oh well
cannabis you know quasy scientific
explanation of uh cannabis makes you mad
uh uh first originated and so they
started saying well these guys are
insane and once they put a medical term
on it was less of an offense to the to
the locals and stuff like that and they
just started grabbing up all these sadu
and stuff all over the place it's a and
it changed it changed the Indian
relationship with this hoi herb and the
Resonance of that British Raj
prejudism against ganja is really still
there now in bread into the people of
India and India should be leading the
world in medical marijuana and in
cannabis science and they would be
leading if it wasn't for that earlier
influence of the British Raj demonizing
shiva's holy plant that's right you're
correct there they demonized the plant
but the thing is in India the Naga Babas
are very powerful and they had the
backing of the people so if the police
don't have any control of nagas because
the people believe the nagas are are are
saintly
people you know
absolutely H uh Mark I think your friend
uh mark from Nepal is up next is he here
or uh I don't see him did you send him
the link oh I didn't I guess I did I I
didn't know him I just thought you'd
send him that maybe maybe he didn't know
I don't I don't think he's on my friends
list wasn't on the email no sorry man I
should have mentioned I thought I'd
mentioned that to you maybe I
didn't well I've got enough numbers uh I
can send uh does he know about it though
like yeah I I never mentioned anything
to him I I didn't if we can pull him in
I wasn't really sure about that I don't
know if
he's I'll uh I'll just type for a few
seconds let me yeah no for sure man
we'll talk a little bit about the lingum
you know um you you know uh uh uh um
Doug mentioned the lingum there and this
is a classic example of the lingum uh uh
inside the Basin of of the Yoni you know
and uh um is also and this is a cobra I
don't know if you can see that yeah
representative like Kundalini energy
which is like the power of sex Instinct
you know um and this is a uh a
three-phase Sheba and it actually has
over his uh uh phus area an aat Cobra
serving as a lingam you you know and uh
um I like this particular Shiva a lot
because I just ended up with it my shop
I don't even know where it came from you
know when I have my shop I had a lot of
uh different things come through but
he's got like a Chillum right here on
his belt ready to go and then he's got
right here you know
erected with the Cobra and he's also the
the three-face Shiva which goes with the
the three-phase Shiva Chillum ritual um
but uh the lingum is like you know
although it represents a phus it's like
the Primal Force the driving force of
the universe you know and that's uh uh
um really like you know like just the
the the drive for Life man you know like
the the the the Primal force of it all
and um there's an interesting story in
in the Piranhas I think it is and you
know one of the things I like about
Shiva is it's kind of almost like a folk
tradition as well and you're not stuck
with the dogmatic kind of uh uh view of
some of the other aspects you know some
of the more like fundamental aspects of
Hinduism you know what I mean and so
there's all sorts of folk tales and folk
songs and and and that that type of
stuff around Shiva and I'm this is kind
of an adaption of of a panic myth as it
was told to me but uh the story is that
uh Shiva was wandering through the
jungle and uh there was Brahman women
and they were at a a pond washing their
clothes and stuff like that and Shiva
comes out of the Jungle naked as he
often you know generally was with his
erect phus and the wom like oh my God
what's this you know and uh um so they
uh go running off to their husbands
brahin and they they say oh we were
washing clothes and this naked man
showed up a wild man with an wck Palace
you know I'm like oh this is terrible oh
what the heck you know and they go down
to where this guy they see him and they
call a curse down on him in the name of
Brahma and his Fus falls off and it
starts ripping through the forest
burning everything in his path and
destroying and they're like what the
heck you know and they go running the
Brahma and they go Brahma Brahma and
they tell him the story of the the their
wives washing clothes and the Naked
Jungle Man with the erect fallace and he
goes oh no that was Shiva man and that
is the procreative force of the universe
you should built a baby in the shape of
a vagina and bathed it and worshiped it
you know and this is like kind of true I
think in a lot of ways of the unbalanced
phallic age that we're in this
patriarchal age that we're in and the
unbalanced nature of of of the drive of
the patriarchy whether it being swords
for piercing and penetrating or bullets
or Torpedoes or rockets for penetrating
it's all about dominating and
penetrating other cultures and uh that
is why this sacred herb energy you know
the the the the Yoni energy which is
present in cannabis we grow ganja for
its its female qualities you know and
this is what the symbolism of the
pouring of the bong on the linga is
about is is restoring that balance is
cooling it Shiva was introduced to ganja
by pvar to Cal him down to stop his
wanderings to chill him out when they
were having a fight you know those are
what the folkus say about it and so it's
a really potent relationship this this
relationship between ganja and and the
male God because the ganja balances the
male god with the female energy you know
yeah you're very right there in India
uh Parvati before she was Parvati her
name was sat
and she was embarrassed by her father
Daka and Shiva tends to get very angry
and this is why Parvati introduced him
to ganja because he got so angry he
chopped off daa's head her father's head
because she burned herself up because
she was
so disrespected by her father her father
disrespecting Lord Shiva so she burnt
her body up and took another body later
as perati but she tend to get very angry
and he replaced her father's head with a
head of a
goat as he did with his own son
Ganesh so yeah ganja was is
really it's the balance it's saved my
life and I think many many
more nice I see another brother is here
Satan Raja Satan always a pleasure uh
another uh Pilgrim to to his homeland
India uh um taking in a few Kumba melas
as well and and we've invited saan to
talk a little bit about his experience
with the chillim in India and Kumba Mela
and to to share some of his wisdom with
us welcome saan thanks so much for have
me Christina Chris brothers sisters in
the world ganja lovers Shiva lovers we
all unite tonight oh you let me know
when you're ready for me to Pipe in go
ahead man we're we're a little bit uh we
had a a missing speaker so we'll we'll
get you in a bit early and very good my
joy well everyone let's pull out the
sacred plant the sacred herb another
round for those of you who've already
gone through a few
rounds may all beings know peace may all
beings know truth may all beings know
love may all beings be Sanctified in the
ritual fire of Truth and beingness Oho
the all smoked to the great one
so friends family
lovers so wonderful to be
here you know I have Indian Roots I was
born in Uganda Africa raised mostly in
Canada but I've been many times to India
and I had a wonderful sharing years back
with Chris Chris and I go back I've been
totally enthralled by work but more
valuable is who he is as a being as a
person who cares about the illumination
of society not just his scholarly
capacity which is brilliant but the root
of where that comes from and I believe
that's the root of Shiva itself now
there's a term we have all heard of in
the Western World Shiva as portrayed as
the
Destroyer but I would like to give you
another offering of the translation of
the term shiv and that is not as the
destroyer in the har sense but a more
accurate Artful translation would be
taking into account the sound the energy
the language is the kind k i n d the
kind
disolver so first of all if I can invite
us to rescript our way of thinking slash
burn kill destroy and look at it as what
within our personal existence and
reality what is within our personal
existence and reality that we fear in
this time of Letting
Go this is a huge time the whole world
on multiple Dimensions is being
rescripted up leveled uh corruption
craziness ego all these factions are all
up yes it I also feel and I invite us to
feel a profound unifying sacred energy
that is allow owing the impurities to
rise to the top the churning the
churning to rise all the [__] to the
top which we see which Chris is a great
advocate of sharing the [__] on the
planet right so but underneath it we
must recognize that Shiva this energy
within us is not an external
God this is the God within and this is
the aspect of the Triune aspect of God
there's the arising from the void into
Consciousness the Brahma this creation
we looking at each other moment to
moment being recreated moment to [__]
moment from nothing and our bodies are
sticking together we have some [__]
continuity which is unbelievable if you
look at it as subatomic level how the
hell do we even have continuity that is
Vishnu the continuity of existence
matter energy time and space is the
Vishnu quality the arising out of the
Void into existence into temporal
dimensionality is considered Brahma now
what is Vishnu or shiv shiv represents
that which in our being which is
returning back into the void returning
back to the source of creation so the
traditional yogic Warrior approach in
the Kumba the yogis taught me the nagab
Baba has taught me says don't be scared
of Shiva don't be scared of dissolving
how can you be scared of the ultimate
benevolent love on the
planet love also shows up in a way which
allows things to dissolve and return
back into the primordial elements of
being so I ask you on a pragmatic level
not just esoteric all of us friends
watching listening what in our life is
Shiva yanking us with right
now how is Shiva putting his Trident in
US shaking us up pinching us pointing us
it's three points the heart the mind and
the belly the soul the sex those are the
three Trident when Shiva is active is
poking the [__] out of us what four he's
looking for us to look for where are we
holding on to something that deserves to
dissolve is it a business we're holding
on to is it a relationship we're trying
to resurrect resurrect resurrect
resurrect but it's much better off to
let go and let go into the kind
dissolving is it um uh uh um an ambition
that you've been working on and you know
what it's just going flat flat flat
you're putting so much energy into it
but you're not getting the return from
the universe that's Shiva is saying this
is not your path many of us have chosen
and walking down paths that our parents
have chosen our society has imprinted
into us that we should walk we should
take this is a sacred time my friends
that I've experienced more than any
other time in my life where the
willingness if we can find that
willingness to what's the fear what do
I'm holding on is it my home my
location you know I know my brother
Chris has gone through this of letting
go of his home base for years and moving
into a whole new dimension but I'm sure
there was Shiva involved he had to face
within himself all the attack M ments
for years of a home base that means
something brings you brings you calm
confidence brings you a sense of
home where in ourselves are we [__]
holding on to fear what's the biggest
thing that Shiva is saying it's time for
this to
dissolve is it a bad
habit is it a limited thought I'm not
good enough I have no value in the world
let Shiva burn it
maybe you think you're too big oh I need
to be this and grandis myself be this
and this we see this in the world Shiva
will burn that down anyways Shiva comes
for those who self angiz and tears them
down and what is that that is the force
of the kind the benevolent dissolving
might not look like it in the moment but
it is the other form rather than
self-aggrandisement that Shiva comes to
purify within our being to return back
to the void is self-depreciation
where are we holding ourselves small
where are we holding ourselves less than
who we are are you a smarter than are
you a smart in a way that needs to come
out are you radiant and beautiful in a
way that needs to be expressed what
needs to be expressed that fear is
holding you back with this to me is the
heart of Shiva so let's take a few deep
breaths and I'd like you to feel into
your
being like to feel into your being what
you know right now you need to let go of
that you haven't built up enough courage
confidence time contemplation but in
your soul you know it's time it's time
to let go it's time not to be ruled by
the fear of
smallness what's the one thing you can
let go
of when you have that let that percolate
Feel the fear within feel the what would
it mean if you let go of that husband
that wife that dog that business that
that uh coworker that boss that employee
that
relationship and then rather than trying
to do this on our own through our own
personal will let's connect with the
grand will of Shiva in side be in
communion with that energy of the kind
dissolving and rather than Valiant
ourselves become push ourselves into the
relinquishment of the fear how about if
we just offer the
fear to Shiva in a sacred flame a sacred
smoke breathing in the Life
Force knowing that with the deepest
ation the drawing in of Life the drawing
of Brahma the sustaining of Vishnu and
now in the
exhalation the sacred offering even your
fear Shiva will
take even your attachment Shiva wants
and yearns
to absolve from
you will you give it to that that great
disorganizing power of existence will
you offer it without Holding Back Being
Greedy with your limitations holding
your [__] smallness my smallness to
ourselves prompting ourselves up to be
the Valiant nerds that we think we are
when we're really embodied gods
embodiments of Consciousness where are
we anything less than the embodiment of
total Consciousness total
love let's have a smoke
let's smoke to that let's smoke to Shiva
come Rock us with the greatest
gentleness Pocus with his Divine
Trident take that which is already
denaturing that we're holding on to to
keep its current
form and allow the
form to be given its rightful completion
package
in
path om
om om shy Shanty Shanti Om Shanty Shanty
Shanti you see beloveds family World
family I believe that we are all
incarnations of shiv and Shakti here we
have these beautiful couple in front of
us
the Divine manifestation in their own
unique form never to be found again you
and this one you and this one and yet in
our
uniqueness the union of what is already
the exact same also resides
undifferentiated
Consciousness Consciousness that's not
limited by the frames and the walls and
the boxes we put around it let us be
wider than all those frames right now my
friends let us manifest Shiva Right Here
Right Now by becoming wider and wider
and wider than our minds wider than our
bodies expanding our presence beyond the
room that we're in filling the room
Beyond filling the greater room of our
town our city our Province our state
wherever we are filling the wider room
of the country we're in filling the
wider room of the planet we are in
filling the wider room of the great vast
expanse filling the widest room of the
great infinite universe and universes
all
Locas and as we expand out into the
Infinity of
being we sit here with a beautiful smile
we inhale a smoke and remember in the
midst of our
humanness the sacred already resides in
the midst of all the [__] calamities
that can come at us we look at death in
the face and smile with joy come and get
me
Shiva come and get me to the great one
thank you so much sanay always a
pleasure brother you're very special man
and brother thanks for coming here and
sharing your
wisdom blessings much
love and uh for viewers at home who have
prepared their bong for the link ritual
uh time to get your lingum where's that
brass
lingum now um the pouring of bong on the
lingum you know to uh cure the heat you
know put out the fire of the male energy
that's burning so much on our planet
these days it's a very very agent ritual
you know and one of the big reasons that
uh the the bong on the on the lingan
ritual was for was for malaria in in
um in India in the 19th century that was
was a big problem malaria and and one of
the ways that they would would would
would try to beg Shiva to release it was
by pouring bong on the Ling to put out
the fire of that you know and we're kind
of suffering under a fever these days in
the world you know the covid has been
pretty brutal man for for Humanity and
Sur surprising how interesting how much
uh medicinal cannabis has been affected
for that for a lot of people and the
scientific studies going on around
shiva's plant in in relation to covid uh
um there's all sorts of different angles
that is being looked at for Co you know
and it was probably good for malaria
back in the day as well but I think that
you know on this Shiva ratry that we
should really all say a prayer for Shiva
to release Humanity from the bonds of
this cruel covid which has taken loved
ones from some of us which we've seen
spread around the planet and change
things you know maybe it's given
Humanity a pause for reflection in a lot
of ways you know maybe it's shiv's will
that this has
happened but I think that it's time to
move past this you know and I think that
we can all join together in a prayer
pouring bong on the linga
let's all focus and think of the
suffering that this Co has caused around
the
world the half a million people dead you
know in America
alone millions of people dead around the
globe from this cruel cruel disease
unable to visit with our grandparents
and our and our older people in
isolation in their last years because of
the cruelness of this disease
let's all ask Lord
Shiva uh um to to to release US release
Humanity from this
fever and uh pour some bong on the
lingam and uh my Shi is going to take
the honors here and pour bong on this
Ling so I'm just gonna actually show
what the bong looks like because people
might not have seen it before I'm just
going to show yeah if you're joining it
you don't have no idea what's going on
bong is a traditional drink prepared
with cannabis in India it's shiva's
favorite drink and people have been
preparing bong for for thousands of
years the the the vtic Soma may have
been a drink very similar to Bong
certainly evidence indicating that and
so this is sh Sha's sacred drink since
time Memorial the way he sought relief
and we're going to pour some bong on
Shiva Lingham as people have done for
centuries
bomo
Mahadev boom
balling releases from this fever
well we can kind of chitchat for a
little while uh um Richard's not up for
for a few minutes yet did you ever get a
hold of Mark Rose Marcus no I sent him
like three messages to three different
numbers and Skype you know saying what
happened and that what we're doing and
that he's invited but uh I don't even
know where he is in the world right now
well there you go it's a whole other
it's a whole other country over there in
Nepal where he is so we'll just think of
him here and say a prayer for him has
anybody got anything they want to add in
here or prayer or anything like
that I wanted to talk a little bit about
um what R shockd plays in the Kashmir
sha tradition and I just want to say as
quickly as I can because there's a lot
of information but in reality we're
we're actually shaki worshippers um we
worship svati or sharat Devi which is
one in the same sharata is the the
goddess of knowledge and of language
sharat is actually the three main
phenomes the three mother phenomes put
together
Shara so when we have sharada when we
say we have faith Shada we actually have
sharada which is we possess knowledge
knowledge gives us Faith because when we
have knowledge we have certainty and
that certain certainty of will that
willpower is shaki so in our tradition
shaki is willpower but it is Lord
shiva's willpower to do whatever he
wants so in this way we understand that
there's no such thing as Maya there's
only the Free Will of Lord Shiva
everything is Lord shiva's free will all
the time including your free will in
fact in chapter two of the Shiva strali
it says Lord shiva's infinite power is
found in every bit of Lord Shiva so
shaki which is Lord shiva's power is so
infinite that she can reproduce herself
infinitely even in the tiniest Speck of
shaki can produce the most infinite
potential of shaki so even the tiniest
graen of sand has Infinity in it has
Shak the infinite in it right well our
own willpower is like that grain of sand
that can expand into the grandness of
shaki herself the the Lord is so Grand
that each of us can become a Shiva
himself this is a secret teaching of
shivas s this is means that we become
ontologically distinct shivas ourselves
I you me all of us can become our own
shivas because Shiva is so Grand that he
can infinitely reproduce to infinite
shivas if you desire if you will and
that willpower is shaki that willpower
is Maya they're one and the same so this
this bondage is not bondage it is
willpower when you realize that is that
it's all your will power you're never
going to be bound it is infinitely your
freedom to create anything but you got
to put that willpower into it and that's
that in our in our tradition Shiva is
that Vira he is that fire that he puts
into the Shak but then shaki turns it
into everything good she is the sacred
cow if if it is the proper worship of
shaki that produces all the beautiful
things in this world so it's like we
must learn how to turn that fire into
love I think that's why more than
anything cannabis teaches us how to turn
that Viva into something beautiful that
blossoms into something that's that's
like a something that allows us to see
beauty I I more than anything want us to
understand that shaki is Beauty and she
shines in everything and she is power
and she is so infinite that all of us
have access to that
infinity and then she is everywhere if
we allow her to enter our life in every
space beautiful man you know there's
some one of the guys I really like that
writes about Shiva is this guy elain
downo and this book here is dionisius
and Shiva about the connections uh uh
between Shiva and dionisius and I'll
maybe go into bit that a bit later and
uh um here's another one of his books
Shiva and the primordial tradition and
uh the the well the gods play the Shiva
oracles which are all about Shiva in
this time predictions about Shiva in the
C stuff is particularly different
because he gives a different time
timeline he says that he went along with
actual yogis into the mountains to
actual Naga yogis right and he writes
that he talked to them about the real
time cycles of the kuga and he says no
we are at the end of the kuga this 43
this 400 year thousand stuff that's just
vava misinterpretation [__] the
shites have the real dates and we're at
the end and Swami G says the reason why
we opened up the tradition is because
we're at the end we're at paralia we're
at the [__] end right now the world
is [__] reciting it's time to open
open everything up because people are
going to need these teachings this is
like this is literally the armor this is
like the the Lifesaver we got to come
out and be like hey guys this is simple
we C we can give everybody what they
need right now in the moment where they
most desperately need it oh you brother
you said something so [__] powerful
they just landed like like everything
for me and that is there is no
Maya that what was determined or or
called Maya in some ways of perception
is actually the the the embodiment of
the will of Shiva this is our
opportunity and this is Shu the
expressing itself not some illusion to
overcome or to kill or destroy or to
robe or to heal you know and that to me
is the essence it's so beautiful what
you said and so needed now with a world
where most religions many uh systems
have an idea that ah there's the
illusion we must move Beyond and
transcend and the problem is is that we
need to enter whatever the thing we want
to move away from that we think is
illusion and find the freaking truth of
the willpower of who we are how we are
generating this we are generating this
so I join you in recognizing this whole
existence as the Forum of
shui our next our next speaker let me
just introduce yeah we we'll cut pick
this up again our next speaker is an
important speaker in this thing you know
one of the things I mentioned about the
three chillim ritual was that uh uh
Chandra Baba Chandra Kali there he
invented it to be inclusive you know and
I think that's a really important
important message you know and Shiva
represents everything between the two
poles of the masculine and feminine you
know everything in between that every
everybody and a lot of religions in this
cuga age have
rejected people that stand between those
two poles of the masculine and
feminine they persecuted them they burnt
them at the stake they've made them
illegal shiva's always embraced them
it's always been part of Shiva energy
and our next speaker Richard they're
gonna talk to us about this dual aspect
of
Shiva Richard thanks Chris thanks for
having me I appreciate being here I
really enjoyed the conversation so far
um so one thing to kind of disclose
about myself is I identify as androgine
I identify as both masculine and
feminine myself and in my spiritual
practice Chris knows I'm athelite I have
a lot of involvement with Otto the
Gnostic mass and particularly the the
teachings of Alistar Crowley and you
know I live in Baltimore and I work in
Washington DC and um I actually went to
an exhibit on uh on Tantra and things
like that over at the Smithsonian they
they acknowledge croley's role in kind
of bringing a lot of these ideas into
Western culture in that time you know
he's one of those figures who really
made it more accessible and it it really
shows in a lot of his work and the
things that I study so um I wanted to
bring that up the the two um things I
wanted to talk about with my time today
was um of course Arana rishar the the
androgine aspect of Shiva and Parvati
the combined aspect of that and another
um deity you know I'm I'm honestly still
learning a lot within the Hindu um
Hinduism but uh it came to my attention
um bahuchara mat who is the Patronus of
um the the hedra the of the transgender
community in Indiana Fact one of the
like oldest extending cultural um
transgender cultures in the world um so
I don't know if I'm able to share my
screen but I wanted to bring up an image
of that real quick just for a con uh
post disabled screen sharing ah okay I
can't you put the uh screen sharing on
for
Richard let me see if I can do it oh
there we go okay your entire screen is
it working yes yeah yeah I just gotta
hit it can you see my screen yet I don't
see anything on it just your
name Oh weird Okay
um I'll go into the settings I got it I
got it I see there we go now can you see
my screen
there yes is okay so that's um bahuchara
mat and she's the Hindu goddess of
Chasity fertility and her maiden aspect
and of incarnation of the mother aspect
of Shakti and she's as I mentioned the
um considered the Patronus of the hedra
community and I have some images of the
hedra it's a really interesting I I just
recently started to study about it um so
in the Indian subcontinent uh the hedra
are Unix intersex people and transgender
people um and the hedri community in IND
India prefer to call themselves kinar
kiner referring to the mythological
beings that excel at song and dance and
um one of the other things that's
interesting about them culturally is
they're officially recognized is a third
gender in India um being considered
neither completely male or female and
they have a recorded history in the
Indian subcontinent um since Antiquity
um suggested by the Kamas Sutra so I
bring them up as um a contrast these are
some images of some of the the hedra um
Community there and these are some more
images that I bring this up as a a a
contrast to what I'll talk
about um with the androgine aspect as
for comparison so I was interested to
learn about these two with
ardhanarishvara so I'll move over to the
images um of the androgine
next and so these are some of the images
of Shiva Parvati together in the arar
Arana rishar form um where the male and
female is split equally in
half and some of the other things that
correspond in in Western occultism I
have some images in here um of for
instance the devil card we were talking
about you were talking about the
patriarchal phallic energy that kind of
is permeating the world and Shiva in the
masculine sense is considered the the
ultimate masculine entity but in this
androgine form it's an equally balanced
masculine and feminine so one of the
other things you see in Western
occultism of course the imagery of bamat
the androgine um of Arcane Perfection so
the breast of the female the phus of the
male again kind of um bringing these
contrasts in unison and in alchemy the
alchemical Rebus is um symbolic of the
magn Opus the great work the idea of
blending the male and the female in one
and so I wanted to talk about um what
that means conceptually so we talked
about um let me see if I can stop
sharing my screen for a minute um the
idea of becoming one with Shiva and so
but who does Shiva become one with Shiva
becomes one with Parvati in that sense
and so like how do we emulate that how
do we incorporate that masculine and
feminine energy in ourselves and you
were talking about the influence it has
on our world today Chris and also how
Shiva is some who is a caretaker of
those people but those people are all
people because every human being whether
you identify as male or female have
those components of that masculine
feminine energy within them and this um
this um form of of Shiva is
Arash is uh kind of uh symbolizes that
and one of the things that's happening
um you know Alistar Curley talked about
the ages of the eons the Eon of Isis the
matriarchal age the Eon of Osiris the
patriarchal Age and what we're in now he
would call the Eon of Horus the Eon of
the child and the child was interesting
Isis is very obviously feminine
matriarchal Osiris was symbolic of um
very masculine patriarchal and we're
still we're still moving out of that age
of of Osiris and that that kind of
speaks to that masculine influence you
were talking about and in in some ways
manifesting in intense toxic masculinity
and and the solution to that isn't
necessarily to erase masculinity or to
to get rid of it it's actually to that
blending and balancing with the feminine
and what Horus represents and when
Crowley wrote about Horus he actually
said um the defining feature of the Eon
of Horus is this idea of both sexes in
one person and a child is considered
epicene they're not fully they haven't
hit puberty so they're not fully male or
female and that's this eon of the child
and that kind of imagery and I think a
lot of that I think Croley was
influenced by a lot of these ideas on
what what it means to blend the
masculine and feminine and what that
creates in a person's Consciousness
their view of the universe and
understanding of self and others so I
wanted to um there's a description of
arish that I wanted to uh read off real
fast it says talking about how the two
Shiva Parvati combine each other you
understand he has to accommodate her in
his own body he has to shed half of
himself so he shed half of himself and
included her this is the story of hard
Aran Shara this is basically trying to
manifest that the masculine and The
Feminine are equally divided within
yourself when he included her he became
ecstatic what is being said is that the
inter masculine and feminine meet you
are in a Perpetual state of ecstasy you
do it to try to do it on the outside and
it never lasts and all troubles that
come are that are an ongoing drama
essentially it is not two people longing
to meet it is two dimensions of Life
longing to meet outside as well as
inside if you achieve it inside the
outside will happen 100% by his choice
if you do not achieve it inside the out
will be a terrible compulsion this is
the way of life this is the reality
which is being expressed in a beautiful
dialectical form Shiva included her as a
part of himself and became half woman
half man this is a symbolism to show
that if you evolve in your ultimate
context you will be half a man and half
a woman not a neuter a full-fledged man
and a full-fledged woman that is when
you are a full-blown human being you are
not skewed development you are not just
masculine or feminine you have allowed
both these things to grow masculine and
feminine does not mean male and female
the feminine and masculine are certain
qualities only these two qualities
happen in Balance within can a human
being live life of fulfillment so I
thought that was an interesting um kind
of perception of it I'm gonna move back
to share my screen one more time for a
few more Imes I think I got a few
minutes right yep a few okay let me see
if I can share this again real
fast um just to kind of talk about some
of the Theology and that kind of
think so I I pulled up a few charts um
that kind of talk about this idea
of I can zoom
in peria and pro uh prti so perusia is
the unmanifested formless passive Beyond
attributes Beyond cause and effect space
and time and so perusa is is is Shiva
the pure existence and prui is um
Parvati the you know his his Goddess
that he combines with pakui is the
creative force of action the source of
form manifestation attributes in nature
and mahad is the cosmic intelligence or
budy aamar is ego the sense of I am and
then satva rajas and Thomas um come into
manifestation and then Thomas breaks
down into the topas of um you know earth
air fire water and ether as well and
it's this idea that everything forms
from the interaction of these two and
these two are symbolized by that
androgine concept of Shiva but I think
what's interesting is we are meant to
incorporate that into ourselves um it's
kind of like a model you know like
looking at that form and reflecting on
it meditating upon it synchronizing
yourself with it how do you balance the
masculine and feminine in yourself what
does that even mean to you what is
masculinity to you what is femininity to
you how do these parts exist within you
and how do you temper yourself to
balance them and and radiate them and
exude them and and live them so I wanted
to also kind of draw your attention to
something interesting uh to me at least
um the manifesto of of cley's Gnostic
Catholic Church the whole point of the
Gnostic masses you know I've had some
history of politics over this because I
used to be able to be a priestess and
Gnostic masses because when I read
Crowley's works I said oh that's what
I'm supposed to do you know I should be
able to do any of these roles and they
put a bunch of really silly gender
restrictions on it they don't want me
doing public masses as a priestess so of
course I don't but anyway here's their
Manifesto that um cley authorized in
1944 kind of relates to this idea of the
ages the masculine feminine so the world
has entered March 1904 the new Eon the
age of the crowned and conquering child
the predominance of the mother Eon ofis
and the father Ian of Osiris are of the
past many people have not fully
completed those formula and they are
still valid in their limited spheres but
the Masters have decided that the time
has come for the administration of the
sacraments of the Eon of Horus to those
capable of comprehension the Sexes are
equal and complimentary every man and
every woman is a star the Priestess must
Now function as well as the priest the
expression of the above thesis in public
ritual is to begin by the establishment
of the Gnostic Mass which while adhering
to the vital elements of the most
ancient and true tradition fixes his
attention on and aims most firmly in the
future and lastly I just wanted to read
a quick quote if I can find it these are
some things Crowley wrote In Magic Libra
ABA book four God is above sex and
therefore neither man nor woman as such
can be said fully to understand much
less represent present God it is
therefore incumbent on the male magician
to cultivate those female virtues
virtues in which he is deficient and
this task he must of course accomplish
without in any way impairing his
virility it will then be lawful for a
magician to invoke Isis and identify
himself with her if he fail to do this
his apprehension of the universe when he
attains samadi will lack the conception
of maternity and last quote before I
just talk a bit about um discussion this
constitutes a profound riddle of
Holiness this is a comment on um
one of the Holy books of the
Lima those only understand it who
combine in themselves the extremes of
moral idea identifying them through
transcendental overcoming of the antomy
they must have gone further yet beyond
the fundamental opposition of the Sexes
the male must have completed himself and
become androgine the female and become
Gander this incompleteness imprisons the
soul to think I am not woman but man or
vice versa is to limit oneself to set a
bar to one's motion it is the root of
the shutting up which culminates in
becoming a maryan violet or a black
brother so let me HP off my screen
sharing I just wanted to say um
connecting this to the real world what's
happening in the real world around lgbtq
issues right now in the United States
there are tons of bills in the states
right now um on transgender athletes in
high schools and things like that saying
we don't want transgender girls
competing in sports you know um we also
you know it's not even that longer that
the united states legalized same-sex
marriage like 2015 it hasn't even been
like what six years or something like
that but this progress is happening and
to me that's kind of that current of the
Eon of Horus that progress that's
happening that Spirit that's guiding the
evolution and the acceptance of people
and as we do that I think in order to
have that acceptance where we're moving
away from where we were historically you
were talking about people it's true Joan
of Arc why was she burned at the stake
because she broke gender Norms you know
what I mean people if you break a
[__] gender Norm society's going to
come get your ass so for me breaking the
Priestess uh taboo over in in Crowley's
Church they came after me I just got off
bad report you know what I mean they
they they were so pissed at me uh and
why just because I said no I'm not g I
said you guys this is how I understand
my spirituality I know that you some
some people understand me over there of
course but the people that write the
rule book said no you know we don't
accept you sorry do what we say or get
out um I think that what we're seeing
the Eon of Horus that the idea of the
child and the and both sexes of one it's
incumbent on every person kind of how
ear it's incumbent on every man to
invoke Isis identify with her we're
talking you could we're talking about
the same idea of balancing Shiva Parvati
in that form that you can reflect on
with that andrine aspect um how do we
bring that into ourselves because that's
sort of that 93 current to me that that
theic energy has a very androgynous
bomatic Vibe the Gnostic mass is
numbered Libra 15 and tarot card 15 is
the devil card it's baffet who crowy
called the androgine who is the
hieroglyph of Arcane Perfection so to me
I think it's incumbent on us to reflect
upon what androgyny means what the
balance of the male female forces mean
and and what what we can do with that
power in our lives to help change the
world but anyway um I'll wrap up thank
you for the opportunity to talk
hopefully it was uh was
interesting absolutely thank you so much
Richard you know and it's interesting
you know you talked about Crowley saying
we had to bring into balance the
masculine and The Feminine to achieve
some and what's interesting about that
is is the very first time that aliser
Crowley achieved
samade he was on
hashish uh in 1904 It Was Written in his
Diaries this wasn't known until after
his death when his Diaries were revealed
because Crowley feared that people would
reject is a demon of somati if they
realized it came through drugs this is a
very special drug it's very special drug
that's full of female energy it's a very
special drug that was recognized as the
goddess the Tree of Life in the ancient
world and it's here
now to balance the out of control
masculine energy it's here now to pour
the bong on the Eternal lingum of us all
all male energy you know and that's
what Sacrament as well this is why this
herb was so special to crley you know
was because it you know his his
psychology of hashish is all about the
attainment of samade with God and
practice you know what I mean it takes
more than just ganja was that easy we'd
all be doing it there's got to be some
intention in that as well you know and
uh um you know it's I was going to talk
a little bit about uh I recently wrote
an article you can find online it's uh
the cannabis infused wine of
dionisius when I was going over that one
of the things I was really looking you
know come across is I I've known about
this connection between dius and sh
because of other books but I never
realized just how
intense the connection between dius and
shba was you know this like is a
historical fact like it at 4 or 500 BC
when Alexander went into India he saw
people there worshippers of Shiva
pressing the grape and making
wine and he thought that he you know the
Legends were that that dius had come
from this place Nisa which was one of
the places they thought it was wasn't
Indian and in Alexander's mind when he
came into India he stumbled on to the
birthplace of Nisa and it's no lie that
the devotees of
Shiva and the devotees of
dionisius
recognized this was the same deity this
deity of ecstatic celebration this deity
that you know accepted women power man
you know that was a big part of the
dionan revolutes right uh um and uh this
is like not some fancy of of new authors
like the 20th century like a down alow
agent authors wrote about this
Roman
historians of that time period wrote
about this connection of dionisius you
know and and there's connections between
dionisius and Yahweh as well ad donus
this is like there's coins
minted with Yahweh and is becoming the
same God basically right and it used to
be quite an ecstatic religion at one
time it's much much like Shiva religion
you know in in that sense of that that
ecstasy that that was based around you
know and uh um yeah it's it's really
really really really powerful stuff man
and uh um has Swami joined us yet is he
on board here
or that oh I don't know it looks like a
couple of people maybe have not made the
technological leap to uh to get on here
I was expecting a few other other
speakers but we can all talk has anybody
got anything they want to say here
or in the in the Kashmir shavam
tradition um the goal the goal is uh
Sadi like yoga is somati right and so
when we when we uh think of the the
culmination of yoga as being samadi and
then samadi stabilizing we call it sesa
we call it the absorption of Shiva so we
become Shiva himself always and but we
can't get to that point unless we go
first through shaki so it's like at the
beginning we're Anu we're just an
individual not connected to the
universal life force and then we go
through Shak and she initiates us she
connects us to the life force we have to
let her in she is like the grand teacher
and she and she runs us through tests
she she like gives milk and we go from
being a little kid to then growing up
and then we integrate her and then when
when we once we integrate her then we go
into the Shambo mode not Shambo is like
the the full culmination of accepting
everything in totality see when you go
into the highest mode you're just
blissfully accepting everything because
everything is shui everything is just
pulsating with her and so there's
nothing to do everything's already being
done Shambo just enjoys his shaki always
making love to his shaki his shaki is
making love back to him I'm just just
making love to her all the time and it's
just Blissful it's like pulsating
wetness everywhere just the nosis is
persistent it's like all the time and
that is that is what we seek for is that
to is to always be sucking on that omrit
to always have that wine being poured
into the skull the skull Bowl to always
be having him drinking the wine of the
senses we should she is the senses she
is the wine she is the Bliss she's all
of it and so when we let her into us and
she allows us to become it we realiz
shaki is the very self-reflective
awareness we say in kism that the mind
is shaki the awareness is shaki but
Shiva is the the core of awareness so
when we go I that's Shiva and we go M
that's shaki I am and Shiva shaki
together it's that constant
self-awareness but the totality of all
being everywhere everywhere is happening
that same time that shivaki shivaki
shivaki
beautiful we have another I have to go
all my love and we see all my love I
need to leave but blessings on this uh
wonderful occasion and prosperous
occasion for all of us bless you all
thank you thank you thank you thank you
brother now we have another H presenter
with us uh we have Rachel uh um I'll let
her maybe introduce herself and tell us
a bit about her and she's going to take
us through a little bit of meditation
and maybe while that's going on Swami
will show up and uh uh we can tie it up
with Swami thank you so much for joining
us Rachel we're so pleased to have some
more shocky energy uh it turned out to
be a bit of a a lingam lingam
presentation lingam energy here a little
bit too much but uh we're trying to
balance things out here as best we can
and we're really glad to have you here
sister oh you're muted unmute
yourself can you hear me yeah yay I'm so
glad you're here Hi Selena it's great to
see you and an honor to bring some uh
shaky energy to the Shiva lunch here
I've been I've been listening the whole
time so uh just just joined now on
figured out how to do that so happy to
be here with you all and wow what a
wealth of information what Amazing
Stories everybody has shared uh just so
great to hear the enthusiasm and really
this Renaissance the Revival of
celebrating uh mahash shivar Tre so I'm
I'm really honored to be here uh I'm a a
regenerative cannabis farmer and I also
like to honor the plant medicine through
ceremony and so what I'd love to share
with everybody tonight is a little bit
of pranayama breathing techniques that
we can use to really embody everything
that we've talked about of understanding
Shiva and honoring Shiva tonight um and
also honoring our plant medicine the the
cannabis plant medicine and um
really finding that Divine balance with
the Shiva and the shaki energy through
also uh chanting and they say uh even in
the Bible they say in the beginning was
the word and so some say that word was
oh which is really a vibration and so I
like to keep a foot personally in each
world of uh sort of being the bridge
between the scientific world and the
spiritual world and so when you think
about vibration uh if you look at it
from one angle it kind is like a cosine
graph right and so if you turn that
towards you it it becomes something
physical uh in time and space if you're
familiar with Organic Chemistry you
might call this a confirmation the way
that molecules arrange themselves in
time and space and so the vibration of
sound when you look at it from a
different perspective it becomes matter
it becomes light something we can see
and obtain and so M was really all the
vibration of the creation of the
universe so a lot of um you were
speaking tonight about the sense of
creation sustenance and disillusion and
so when we sound oh it comes from our
own self and our body so the o sound
really emanates from our belly and so if
you think about your belly your belly
button your Naval that was everybody's
original life force right our umbilical
cord is where we all began uh our sust
sustenance our creation and so um the M
every inhalation and every exhalation
should in theory begin and end with our
Naval Center so what I'd like to invite
all of us to do in this moment is just
practice feeling in to that space to our
space of creation and if you're familiar
with the chakras or the uh Spinning
Wheel of energy our Naval Center would
be also called called our solar plexus
or manora and so that represents who you
are who yourself is and so um I forget
his name as he just had to leave but he
was saying you know what is it that you
want on this planet and what is it that
you literally need to get rid of and
remove so you can make this space but
tonight is such an auspicious night to
get so clear about that that why why are
we on this planet and it really comes
from the breath from the vou from The
Prana that life force so if you um I'm
going to sit over here so everybody can
see me you can take your middle fingers
and bring them right to your Naval
Center and have them touch just sitting
naturally and as you find your
inhalation let it begin at the belly and
breathe in deeply fill your whole belly
fill your pelvic bowl and breathe into
your wholeness into your
fullness as we previous prly practice
breathe into the whole entire room let
your body take up the space around
you hold at the top of the
inhalation and then with your lips
closed again the navl initiates the
exhalation the out breath slowly let the
breath Escape as you draw your belly
button back behind your rib cage toward
your
spine slowly letting the air come out
through the nostrils
and once you feel like you can't breathe
out any further try to Exhale a
millimeter deeper it's like you're doing
a deep clean into all the crevasses of
your body like we're uh dusting the
corners of our soul with our breath so
let's try that again when you're ready
take a big inhalation through the nose
slowly breathe into your wholeness into
your fullness
and exhale completely releasing it out
and as you breathe out you might start
to feel your fingers cross and pass over
one another so really letting your hands
feel this embodied space that you are
creating you can let your eyes close if
that feels comfortable to you and start
to tap into and feel your own Rhythm
through your very breath
simply breathing
in and peacefully breathing
out and now I'm going
to offer a little prayer for us if you
have your ganja with you um I have a
little chilling pipe I'm going to be
using tonight and I've also made some
bong I've been following going along
with everybody and I'll show you here
the bong I made I don't know if you
could see has uh rose petals and
cardamom and fresh ganja I use the
flowers so it's nice and strong
definitely feeling
it and when we breathe when we work with
the cannabis plant medicine we're
inviting in all of the elements here so
the Earth being the plants itself the
element of Fire we're creating
transformation and change so when you
bring the fire to the flower we create
that transformation and change that
creates the smoke or the ethers so we're
sending our prayers up to the heavens up
to the gods and giving great thanks to
Lord Shiva so a mantra that I invite to
share with you all tonight is om
shivaya and so we will after we work
with our herb uh we can practice our
Mantra 108 times so let's take a moment
if you're joining along with us using a
little hempwick to give a tribute to uh
smoking as clean as possible as we
always can eliminating the butane from
the lighter and I'm going to take a
moment to say a
prayer light the fire upon your flower
breathe in deeply
and exhale it out to the
gods om
shank so now I invite everybody to join
me for 108 rounds of
omaya so if you're wondering why 108
there's many different reasons why this
number is so
auspicious that one of which is the
Sanskrit alphabet has 54 letters and
each letter is seen as having a
masculine and a feminine or a Shiva and
a shaki aspect um and so if you do 54
time 2 that equals
108 so giving homage to each of those uh
letters within the Sanskrit alphabet
also if you look at the number the
number one may represent God or the
creat creation or the wholeness uh the
number zero is uh the the sustenance and
then the number eight looks like an
infinity sign that sense of infiniteness
and so together we have the creation the
sustenance and the disillusion um
there's many other aspects of 108 from
the astrological perspective of the
vetas when we look at AOA uh in the in
the sky and seeing the way that we have
10 uh different houses and nine
different plants planets uh sorry 12
different houses times nine planets is
108 and so when We Can chant you can
even do a th8 as well but I thought we'
just offer 108 for today and some other
interesting things so on a Mala if you
see people wearing these beads uh today
they often have a lot of aesthetic
quality but they're really have a deep
purpose the japamala is to uh first of
all keep track of count um when we count
the uh mantras in a mantra man means
mind and TR is across so we're going
across the Mind our minds are always
speaking to oursel or having this sense
of chitt what we call in Sanskrit is a
chatter sort of that selft talk that we
hear and quite often the selft talk can
be very um negative towards oursel they
say how we speak to oursel is worse than
we might speak to anybody else so in
this moment I am inviting everybody to
just release that and see if you can use
that Mantra to bring in a sense of
loving kindness and the way that your
mind can speak to yourself from here on
out um and so when we go across our Mala
beads the japamala we'll use and if you
have the beads you're welcome to go
along if you don't have them that's
absolutely fine you can join in the
Chant at any time and we'll use our
thumb and our middle finger to press on
each bead this Center bead here is
called the guru bead and and this bead
we give great thanks and can bring to
our third eye or ajna Shakra to give
homage to our Guru to Lord Shiva tonight
and uh Guru is the one who removes the
darkness so that we may see the light so
in doing this chant it's really a
discipline right it takes discipline to
say something 108 times it takes a
commitment to something and when you
think about commitment think about two
molecules bonding together so we just
inhal the ganja and now we're committing
to her to working with her as our plant
Ally and we're committing to Lord Shiva
to the lord of the ganja the lord of the
bong we're giving great thanks to the
plants to the universe for our very
existence so give your whole self over
this is a service that we're giving and
the more we put into it the more you'll
get out of it it's just the Law of
Attraction whatever energy that you're
creating whatever it is that you're
voicing and I know for myself I just
want to mention the first time I ever
tried chanting I'm not a singer I was
very quiet you'll probably hear tonight
but think about it as your heart's song
doesn't matter what you say sound like
it's not about being in a right tune um
but it's more just about letting your
voice be heard let the gods all of the
Divine your ancestors know that you are
here the theer the more from our heart
the Baki is from that heart center the
more we can sing there that the more our
prayers will be heard and answered so um
we'll begin together let's take a deep
breath in through the nose and out
through the no mouth just clean in the
channel
inhale and
exhale we'll be chanting
Omama
shiv so we'll begin on our first
exhalation
om
om om
Nam
om
om om om
Nam om
namash om Nam keep going with your heart
om
om om
Nam om
Nam om Nam
om
om let your prayers be heard
om om
namash om
namash om namash
om
om stay committed
om om
om
omash
omash give your whole self over to it
om
om om
namash om
om
om omash
[Music]
om
om om
om stay present
omash
omash om
[Music]
boom
M thank you so much Rachel that was
beautiful and helps us get Centered for
our last presenter the great holy man
Swami chat I don't know if I pronounced
your last the last part right Swami
you'll have to uh correct me on that uh
the pronunciation of that
term you're muted
it's on the bottom left bottom left
there we go not alone and Miss
pronouncing the name that's why I just
usually just go by Swami there you
go chai like te chai and Tanya like a
ballerina or an ice skater figure skater
chai Tanya right and uh it uh it it
means uh Consciousness and uh Rachel was
talking about cheat and as
saand Works into cha so uh they are sort
of one and the same at a certain level
so well thank you uh for inviting me on
to shivaratri is quite an honor to be a
guest here and uh yeah and the OM namash
chant of course is H one that we always
chant there's other ones too
harash one of my favorite ones for uh
doing a Chillum or smoking ganja is uh
you take the joy and you
say and behold the wonders of the world
revealed through the Cannabis and so
it's a way of seeing the world as a
magical illusion uh and taking it to the
to the higher level that way so um
anyway it's uh what to say about
shivaratri the idea that this energy is
thou uh walking the Earth and being
amongst us uh that is you know
celebrated uh she was different uh
incarnations or manifestations of Shiva
where um Shiva will just show up to you
at a certain place sometimes you'll look
up and you'll see that little sickle
Moon up in the sky that little sickle
Moon you say oh that's a sign from shua
right or something else will grab your
attention you realize that oh that's
that's a message from Shiva maybe you
see a beggar on the street or something
like that and there's like all of a
sudden there's a little zap in between
you say oh oh that that was like that
was a little shaki from from Sha and
that's the way that sha operates in the
world in his form as being in the
present now he has a form of Shiva as
the aora Shiva who is on the burning
gods and infecting and being involved in
that sort of transformation where you
cross over to the other side as the Lord
Of Destruction there but the liberation
of the Soul through that right then he
has this manifestation as a lingum and
normally on shivaratri we're pouring
over honey and milk and melted butter
and ghee and all these things over the
shivaling uh that is then uh our worship
ceremony where you know we can go on for
hours and hours pouring these Libations
over uh and then uh there's the form of
sha that is beyond the expansion of the
universe that just the very conception
of it doesn't even put borders on on the
on the universe and all its multi-
universes uh through the time of
creation and dissolution and the
maintaining uh so that's sha and then
Shiva does have a a wrathful form uh
that you know is breathing fire and so
on that's sometimes called rudra and
then of course uh
Nikki just reminded me my favorite form
of Shiva is shaj where he's
dancing and in the dancing uh he is then
creating the universe through the uh EXO
Tanda which is the thou the 108 dances
uh that Shiva positions that he does in
order to create the universe and that
you know we celebrate that same with the
108 repetitions of of the uh uh punch
Dasa this five syllable Mantra of Shiva
and so Shiva is the the center and then
um when we think about the
chakras right in the muladar chakra at
the base of the spine in that little
triangle uh there is a sh lingum there
and that is then you know how we focus
the energy in the lower chakras and
bring them up and transform them uh
there's another Lig in the heart chakra
and uh another lium in the third eye
chakra and that's how the energy Supreme
and the third eye chakra is like that J
lingum the lingum of light uh that is
that is absorbing all the energy of the
universe and radiating it back out to be
shared uh with anyone who uh it tunes
into that and even actually those who
don't tune into it share in the energy
so that's all the forms of Shiva as a
beggar and as a yogi uh and then one of
the great forms of Shiva is with Shiva
Parvati as the and just as I say Shiva
Parvati who comes in but my
poty is her is her Sanskrit name H and
she is my consort and beloved and Shea
parti and uh there's a certain place
where Shiva Parvati joined in a space
above the third eye uh the Shiva Shakti
kolini rising and joins there so you go
beyond the The Duality of male and
female in that this is called the kakala
chakra and in another triangle uh there
is the Sia and parti there United in the
Bliss uh Beyond any time or space and so
uh we we use this the lingum as a way to
symbolize the essence of the energy
without a physical form the lingum is
actually a representation of a
non-physical thing with a physical thing
and the lingum is the simplest physical
thing as a source of energy and then we
must always remember that the lingum is
embedded in a Yoni all right and lingan
is embedded in a Yoni and that is part
of the Sha
Shakti and that sha without shaki yes
there you are thank you Chris sha
without shaki has no power and so um
just okay occurred to me that we did
omash but there's a variation that my
teacher in India andiri gave me of the
Sha Mantra and it includes the feminine
the Shakti and I think one of the great
things about this day and age is that so
much of the religion has been masculine
dominated to worship the goddess and to
worship the goddess equal with with the
God is one of those things that our
modern day wants to wants to bring
forward so there's a form of uh this was
given to me by Chand
om so we put the
syllable after OM and is the there the
syllable of the Bea Mantra of all the
goddesses taken together but
particularly it's the be Mantra of
banwari the goddess of the earth and
also the goddess who is the the all
embodiment of all the threeness of the
universe so when we
say is like om for the manifested world
the manifested universe om includes all
the unmanifest and the Manifest and is
where we bring it down through the
creativity of the feminine so we just do
a few uh of these omash since we we
start I came on when you were doing om
namash so we we then incorporate the the
divine feminine into this and so we'll
just do that for just a few minutes and
we'll go so om
om
[Music]
om so you can carry that on as
108 and there's a way also to do uh
japa as it's called there's there's
three forms of japa the one is the out
loud the viatti form of japa and that is
great to do in a group and then there's
a whispered form of the japa which is
Mia form of japa and then there's a
silent form of japa and the silent form
of japa is one that you can carry on
continuously that you it's sort of this
base like a tamburri base note
underneath whatever else you're doing
and so it just
becomes and you speed up the Rhythm so
it's
[Music]
like so you're creating this Rhythm and
this and this kind of torque within
yourself with the Mantra and what
happens is as through the Mantra your
bones start to vibrate with that tone
and eventually all the molecules in your
body vibrate with that tone and that
tone
that
sound is the Divine you are invoking the
Mantra is the Divine the yantra is the
place for it to manifest and that's
Tantra so uh anyway can I just say a
couple things I'd like to add which is
um and I know this from personal
experience because and it does work if
you say om namash Shaya with full pure
intention a 100,000 times
times expect big changes in your life it
absolutely it's because Shiva is the god
of transformation so when you recite
that Mantra 100 thousand times and it
doesn't have to be all on the same day
you know it's just when you've done it a
100,000 times with pure intention you
will have transformation and the other
thing I wanted to say is that right now
as some of you probably know the um
Kumba is happening in hardar in utan
state of India up on the Ganga
and tonight there'll be well probably
was 12 hours ago but there's huge
celebrations happening there's the big
um the jalo the parade when all of the
Babas go out and parade to the river
that probably happened this morning and
tonight will be a very special time in
India as literally millions and millions
of people will be celebrating
this fire ceremony I mean all over the
country I mean they'll be drinking bong
and they'll be very high so um coming
from that direction on our globe tonight
is some lots of higher Consciousness
yeah and whenever we chant home and do
those mantras our psyche our mind mental
patterns join those of all those people
doing that not only in India but all
around the world that's the great thing
about chanting M just by itself is when
you chant home you join the chorus of
the syllable Bea Mantra of the universe
which has been chanted since time in
Memorial will chant in time into the
future and we become part of that wave
every time you use
the Mantra of M so uh it's just a
blessing to be here and thank you so
much yes thank you so much thank you so
much Swami and and your partner as well
it was beautiful um you know this has
been a wonderful event I've been doing
these like small little home Shiva rotes
the last couple of years and because of
covid you know we which seemed like a
terrible thing you know and it is a
terrible thing but there's also this
massive change happening in humanity
right now because of it and here we are
all alone together you know and we
wouldn't have been doing this if it
hadn't been for Co you know here we are
all celebrating this and this is gonna
this is going to grow in the west Shiva
rry is going to become a celebration of
ganja people I feel that and this is
just and I thank you all so much part of
this I say one more thing
about there's like Nikki mentioned the
Kumba and that's when millions and
millions of people go try and be and be
in the same place on the edges of the of
the ganis right the ganga but shiv rri
is completely different everyone goes to
their local Shiva Temple and so what
we're doing here is your local little
Shiva Temple and that's what it is all
around every Shiva Temple tonight and
over the night every single one of them
has a celebration it's not like
everybody goes one place it's every one
goes to their place and that's why it
has that extra energy that it's your
neighbors and your friends and people
who been worshiping at that Temple for
such a long time and there's a whole
myth about how sheiva you know all these
millions of temples happened all over
it's part of this the Hindu mythology so
yeah we're doing the thing in the right
way I like to think that in the caluga
that you know the Iron Age the age of
you know materiality and physicalness
that an aspect of spirituality has taken
on the physical form of ganja and a
medicine that we take body born of Shiva
from shiva's own body and I think that's
a really powerful way to take the
medicine you know all of its intent the
difference between a sadu and India who
sits down with his chilling before he
sits down to do his a Sonic Sonic
practices and some kid that's you know
about to smoke a blunt and play uh um
some video game is an
intention and it's all in how you see
this herb and how you visualize it and
what you put into that and take back in
with it you know and I think on this the
final third shellum you know of of the
three chilling ritual of today's Shiva
ratri uh 2021 I just want to thank you
all as aspects of Shiva that have come
here today to share your wisdom and if
you have any closing words you know
we'll just open up the floor and uh go
from there thank you so much man thanks
for coming means so much thank you
um I want to share something really
quick um that's okay but um uh I love um
actually what what's his partner swam
and Nikki Nikki yeah um thanks for um
adding uh thanks for adding that in
about how powerful the mantras are um I
actually had a really powerful
experience a couple years back with
Mantra beads and um I had no
idea um what that would open up I was
actually had such a deep experience that
my whole yoga mat was completely
drenched in tears like I'm talking like
a puddle that of just like an explosion
of tears that came running out of my
eyes and it really blasted me open and
it actually like was really scary
looking back at it was it really shook
me up and I didn't know if I was having
a mental breakdown or what what was
going to be happening and it was it was
very intense so um um you're right like
they are very powerful and I think it's
very important that we have tools to
work with because the times are really
intense and um the times are really
intense and we need tools right now and
uh just like Rachel was talking about
with the chitter chatter and Rachel
thank you so much for um sharing with us
it was really beautiful to hear um you
and guide us through that so thank you
so much Rachel for coming and um yeah
what you talked about with M yeah that's
um something as well too I think um and
the breathing um these are really
important things that we have that are
free that we can use and access at any
time and um we just need to create the
space for it and as the feminine I think
you know um setting up that space and
that time and the right setting and um
using these plants these medicines um
with uh a way of you know for self self
awareness and the more that we become
more self-aware we can become uh things
around us become better you know it's
like walking in our truth and walking in
our um leading of especially I think for
the feminine the beauty that comes out
that's kind of been lost in our world
it's been very masculinized and um
remembering that beauty I think is going
to be another important aspect to us um
going forward because I think our
society's forgotten the beauty so and
when I say beauty I'm talking like
it's everywhere it's just we've
forgotten to look for it so those are my
words thank you
everybody special thanks to Mark
Richardson too you know for hosting the
event here on a zoom platform and
YouTube and stuff like that and uh
taking care of the the control board and
stuff like that thanks so much Bubble
Man boom boom yeah man boom Shankar
Shankar mahv it was a wonderful
beautiful experience
um I listened to the entire thing and
and had full enjoyment I think it's
great all the PE I had no doubt that you
would invite High Caliber folks and so
thank you all I know that the uh more
than 200 people that have been watching
have been uh enjoying
it can I say one more thing if we have
time yeah absolutely so uh we talked
about mantras right so I want to talk
about the secret Mantra of Kashmir
shavis and we you know you were talking
about all the different forms of Shiva
well there is a tricky form of Shiva
which there's a school of of shavis that
we call Tria and that's appeals to the
tricky part of us right so if you're
think if you think you're clever if you
think you're cunning if you think you're
a tricky person well you're going to
understand what I'm going to say and
what we're saying is that every time you
breathe you're reciting the Mantra every
time you take a breath you're reciting
the Mantra so if
you become aware of this and you realize
that you're you're reciting the Mantra
48,000 times a day so if you become
aware that you're always reciting the
Mantra you're doing japa all the time
you're doing it all the time and that's
the trick Swami G used to say you know
was that was that my my master
kush oh bubble man doesn't know he's
being on there sorry
guys so if you're if you're a trickster
and that that appeals to your mind and
you think you can crack the trick and
you can always remember this trick then
you're doing japa all the
time it's all the intention
that japa is soam
ham that's that's the syllable of it
soam ham and as you breathe in that's
what it sounds like if you listen to it
and and the other thing is hamsa is is a
Sanskrit word meaning the swan right and
the swan has all sorts of uh beautiful
connotation symbolically you know we
know as the ugly ducking becomes the
swan but the swan is also uh the swan is
supposed to be able to take milk that's
dissolved into water and just drink the
milk from it so it's it's it's quality
of discernment of being able to detect
the truth in the midst of of the
falseness right and so that that that's
hum and if you as you say if you breathe
that Mantra silently all day long but
are you conscious of it are you aware of
living it that way uh then you ride on
that
wave I would connect that mystery to the
mystery of Jesus walking on water see
that the the swan also goes into the
water but he's never like he comes out
of the water and he's fine he's like I'm
not wet bro I'm I'm okay I was in the
water but I'm out of it now I'm the
world doesn't even touch me I walk on it
like no problem like that's what I
do yeah yeah and and actually speaking
of Jesus that reminds me when you know
when you just said Chris that thing
about how Shiva is in this bud and we're
GNA you know every time you embibe him I
having grown up Catholic I immediately
thought oh my God that's just like the
host in church right you're given the
body of Christ right and I'd never quite
put that together so thank you for that
that's a really interesting way to look
at it Bingo like
that yeah an a bosson for the
win thank you so much
everybody it's been so so great man
happy Shiva
ratri thank you guys thank you everybody
you're Shiva to me thank you very much
yeah