[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble Man's World
um I'm going to take you guys through uh
a Jamaican video that I filmed a couple
years ago at emancipation Park in
Kingston recently I've put a few videos
up I put the chronics Kalisa and uh
kabaka pyramid with zinc fence band at
the at Tony cabonas or whatever his last
name is Tony's
bar um great show I have a bunch more
tunes from that particular uh show Exile
the brave opened up and I have a bunch
of him as well and I have more of j n um
both from an a free park in emanci Park
as well as from her CD release party and
then I have a bunch of other stuff that
I just collected uh over that particular
period this particular show that I'm
about to show you it's actually up on my
um computer right now just getting
edited this is a free concert at
emancipation Park uh reggae in the park
that they were doing every Sundays and I
had hooked up with I Wayne to tell him a
little bit about the YouTube
monetization and how he could
potentially be reaping some rewards from
his views as he did have some very good
views and I was pretty stoked to see I
Wayne as he's got a great voice um
really talented individual so I was
excited and halfway through his show
someone that I've waited a very long
time to see in concert I've waited till
3:4 in the morning and missed this guy I
waited one time till 9:00 in the morning
at a Tony Rebel salute and only as I got
in the van and drove away did I hear
them mention that he was going to be
taking the stage who I'm talking about
of course is szla kangi so in this
particular video we've got szla kangi
we've got I Wayne and um yeah they do a
variety I think szla does two or three
small short songs and I Wayne does a
really nice um new song I don't know if
it was a freestyle that he was spitting
or something that he wrote but he does
announce in the video that it was new so
I figure
I'm going to have a little sublimator
rip and get this party
started little sublimator rip through
the
mothership and uh I'm hitting the
congales little uh nice sativa action
get us ready for this video so uh yeah I
why don't you guys pull up a puff and uh
we'll watch this video
that's just a nice light sublimator hit
that's like the sublimator is still
heating up it's not quite the
temperature all I put in here was a
pinch of Bud if you can imagine nothing
more no dabs and I bet you get another
one or two giant beautiful
rips one more and we'll enjoy this
concert
all
right I
Wayne so this is the Ki enjoy
[Music]
guys I don't want to
from the very first time I bless my eyes
of
you are you
feel tears in my eyes tears
in I don't want
no
[Music]
to Mama and Papa
say things
separate
know why you got to be this way I
you do
you what do you
say emancipation
[Music]
B
man
big I
[Music]
[Applause]
up
[Music]
[Applause]
what
s you and all
the the place speak the truth and it
what it will whoever hide and do the
wrong will continue to do the wrong
still so fire
fire
mean your molested baby
Andes you are bring war from your
molested baby and the lady this mean
from your molesty babies and I the
ladies this mean from your molesty
babies so yo
ugly is
[Music]
ugly put
per
up
[Music]
never blood Shing
more balance it break it don't stop
it something
right boy wake up with boy wake up
[Applause]
with drink and dry drink some water and
dry but you know smoke and dry on
M
we
W the street
[Music]
B them up like some app Lea looking
[Applause]
like hey don't stop the people lyrics
some more new lyrics so like love life
Jamaica African people we can defend the
animal them
[Music]
right
andice
[Music]
C River
[Applause]
super
water drink it and then you after
drinking blood eating
[Music]
[Applause]
me strong Jamaica B
weakness balance
[Music]
sweet
we
[Music]
Jud
de liess breakless and speechless
[Music]
[Applause]
no
stay strong
we can't
[Music]
us DRS
up yourself one more w
just before I go
[Music]
right
the the
[Music]
oh