early. So, I was going to maybe start
with Micah. Bubble Man, you got
something you want to say? Oh, I was
just going to say there's Skunk Man's
here as well if you guys want to hear a
quick intro from him. I know a lot of
people know a lot about him, but it
might be a neat thing to hear a couple
of words from uh from the man himself.
Yeah, definitely. Sorry about that. I
forgot.
No problem whatsoever. Here he is now.
Howdy, howdy. Howdy, everybody in Hash
Church. Uh yeah, I I my experience with
green houses was I built my own
greenhouse about 40 years ago and then I
moved to the Netherlands where I ran
many many many professional green houses
with computerized darkening,
computerized watering and and uh I my
favorite way to grow is green houses.
Although
there's but uh I I I I I've been there.
I've seen most of the changes. We were
one of the very first in the world to
use darkening for uh to mature cannabis
flowers in the when we were in a
northern environment in the greenhouse.
And uh if anybody has any questions, I'm
I'll be happy to step up to the box. But
except for that, uh, I am what I am and
I think pretty much everybody knows me.
True story right there. Awesome, Sam.
Thanks for sharing. We bring out and
maybe skunk man. Sam, I don't know. I
would be interested to hear about your
progression of, you know, greenhouse
growing and and some of your maybe your
life deprivation experiences. Yeah.
Where is it on? It's on. Go ahead. Yep.
Howdy. Howdy. Uh the I I've been growing
in green houses ever since the first
year I grew cannabis in Santa Cruz. That
was in uh uh maybe
70 72 or something out like that. And uh
that was just a homemade primitive
greenhouse once. And friends of mine
were doing darkening for sexing, not for
flowering, but for sexing and that was
in Northern California. But tell tell
them what we just talked about about the
sexing and yeah, one of the problems
with the sexing was at that time they
didn't really understand what they were
doing. So they would darken it for two
weeks until the plant showed sex.
Whereas what the research that I found
when we were doing the research in
Holland was that most indica varieties
you can darken for one day and then two
weeks later they will show sex. They and
they will not stay.
And with with veg with uh excuse me,
with sativa varieties, sometimes they
need to be darkened two or three days at
the very most, but then two weeks later
they show the sex just and so uh it's I
mean I had a friend who produced
thousands and thousands of seedlings and
then darkened them off just for uh
sexing to sell early known female plants
to people. And uh a few times he cuz he
darkened them for 2 weeks, they would
not come back. So the customers were
rather irate that they had these little
plants that were, you know, 2 feet tall
and flowered off and they would not
return veg. Can you also tell the story
of how you discovered uh like greenhouse
light depth uh in in
Holl? Uh uh what happened was I went
into a crysanthemum greenhouse. I uh
because I was interested in building my
own greenhouse or or or buying one or
renting one or whatever. And so uh I saw
the chrosanthms were being darkened to
induce flowering and I a light went on
in my head and I went Jesus Christ. I
mean, I had seen people darken plants
with a tarp in the uh late 70s and early
80s, but I wasn't interested because uh
I I I wanted a greenhouse that was
multiple acres and uh you you you you
can't hand darken multiple acres. Well,
actually, you can if you have enough
labor, but it's uh
so once I saw what darkening could do, I
I instantly understood what this was for
cannabis. And uh so that was I don't
know, maybe 86 or something like that.
And
uh once I saw that uh yeah, I never
stepped back. uh for for the
Netherlands, you need darkening because
you you can you can grow multiple crops
a year or you can grow one big good
heavy crop and uh darken it and get it
out before the cold it comes and your
heating bills are $10,000 a day a week.
And can you also comment uh Sam on
earlier Mah was talking Micah was
talking and he mentioned how he kind of
likes to keep them a little bit smaller
which might be perfect for what he's
doing and and producing super high
quality flowers but you came in as a
sort of like oh I like to have really
big green houses and maybe just talk to
why that is. Well the main reason is is
I like big plants. A lot of the work I'm
doing is not commercial production. It's
breeding work. And for breeding work, I
start seeds, thousands and thousands of
seeds. And then what I do is
uh I I want to pick the best plants. And
to pick the best plant from seed, it's
very difficult to do with a a little one
or two foot plant. You grow it 12 feet
tall and you get a really good idea of
its positive and negative qualities,
right? And for for a breeder, it's it
it's really required. So I I that's why
I had a very high ceiling. My ceiling
was I don't know maybe 20 feet or so and
I could grow 15 foot tall plants if I
want get three, four or five kilos of
dried material.
Boom. Thanks Sam. Let me ask you Sam
about the sexing one more time. you
know, for people that are, you know,
maybe don't have a lot of power still in
Humboldt or, you know, these craft
farmers, if they were to sex their
plants, like you were saying, how long
if it was, it's depending on strain, you
would say, but if somebody was to do it,
would you say to darken it for a day or
two instead of the two weeks like your
friend had done? Because I experienced
the same thing. I've seen plants that
didn't come back out of the veg and it
was a huge pain in the ass. So, could
you talk a little bit more about that?
like your recommendation.
Is my mic on? You're on. Okay. The the
main thing is that uh cannabis will take
two weeks to express its sex, but one or
two days of darkening is enough to trip
the expression two weeks later. That's
the main thing you have to understand.
With earlier varieties, only one day. If
it's a very late late uh equatorial
variety, maybe it takes two or three
days at the very most. And then when you
put them back on a long cycle, two weeks
later they sex, but they don't stay
flowering. They are totally veg and you
grow them really really big and then
flower them off and you know what sex
they are. That's almost like at the end
of that you should also say you're
welcome because that was a gem right
there for those dude. Dude,
absolute game changer. Thank you for
dropping that knowledge. Yes, I think
would help that.
You know what I mean? Like, can we can't
we quantify things with lab tests
sometimes? Because I know that I've
talked to a few lab companies that have
said over the course of time some of the
greenhouse material they've been testing
has has tested higher in the THC, CBD,
and even the tarpin percentages. And I
know that the tarpin companies, bubble,
man, maybe you might know something
about that.
um with greenhouse material and the
tarpine production that you might have
heard about or known.
Let me see. Am I unmuted? Yeah. Okay. Uh
yeah, from you know, right from Tony's
mouth, almost always the light depth,
the greenhouse is going to produce like
a way higher level of tarpine
production. You know, not just a smaller
amount, but like a substantially larger
amount. And not to change the subject
completely, but while I have the mic,
um, one of the things Sam was mentioning
about greenhouse, um, triggering
flowering as well, um, particularly in I
guess it was in like,
uh, close to the equator countries where
they have 12 hours and 12 hours of light
and darkness. Um, and often people are
trying to grow with added light,
additional light. They'll maybe put it
on for another five or six hours. Sam
had an interesting bit of information to
share on tropical uh cannabis growing.
Basically what we found is that
uh e in the Netherlands when uh I would
grow big giant plants at 10 12 feet tall
over the winter uh I could give as
little as uh I was using uh these little
60 watt blue incandescent uh agriculture
balls agricultural bulbs from Phillips
and uh so they were geared towards but
but they were only 60 watts. And I would
use one of those for every 10 square
meters. So that's 100 square ft. And uh
it absolutely prevented flowering. Not
not only that, but you could use as
little as just in the instead of giving
them six or eight hours of light to keep
them veg, what you could do is just in
the middle of the night, give them two
hours of light. That's all they needed.
Yeah, I've been doing this for 30 years.
That's a big one for people that have
been especially in countries where, you
know, he was mentioning like only having
one generator, only being able to turn
on enough light in one section of the
greenhouse, you could do a quarter here,
a quarter there, a quarter there, and
instead of leaving it on for that eight
additional hours, I I I'll tell you how
severe I've done it. I actually uh was
storing plants under refrigeration at at
about plus 3 4°. So they're in a
refrigerator with lights and alls I gave
them was 15 minutes of light four times
a a day. So every 5 hours I'd give them
or five or six hours I give them 15
minutes of light. Totally prevented
flowering. They stayed veg. They also
weren't growing because it was so cold.
Alls I was trying to do was keep the
plants alive as a library. Did you see
that there was any reduction in actual
growth? Um, no growth practically. I
mean, under under three degrees there's
practically zero growth.
I wasn't trying to grow them. I was
trying to maintain them. Yeah. Yeah. U,
but my I guess my question is is, you
know, I think some people would argue,
well, they keep all these lights on
because not only do they want to uh keep
the photo period going, but they're also
trying to have the plant grow at the
same time. So, I'm just curious if you
saw any difference at any point uh in
your in your experiences where there you
could see like a a difference in growth
uh growth rates. The more lumens and the
more hours, of course, you're going to
get more growth, of
course. But that wasn't my goal. My my
goal was to I I had big plants in the
ground which I conserved in my
greenhouse. I had a small collection on
on eb and flow tables under under
hallides and uh just as a library and I
had a third collection in uh I had
specially made uh like a refrigerator
with lights built into it which uh and
and those I I gave them as little as an
hour a day broken up in 15 minutes uh so
that uh they never received really long
periods of dark at any one time. It's
awesome information. Thanks for sharing
that.
Yeah, I just met a guy in Humboldt. A
lot of my research comes from old old
school growers in Humbult County and
they said the same thing Sam was saying
as far as keeping the plants in veg. Uh
the guy came here recently and did a
greenhouse tour and he goes, "No, I only
have my light on in the middle of the
night for one hour in the wintertime to
keep them in veg." And I thought, "One
hour?" And so, yeah, to save on
generator and power and all these things
that people deal with, they can't use
all this electricity or access to it
maybe in the middle of the night, you
know? So, when he told me that in the
veg period he that he only uses the
light for one hour in the middle of the
night, I was just like, "Holy crap." And
now I'm starting to hear little bits and
pieces of it. And then, of course, now
Sam is kind of confirming that whole
thing, too. So, I mean, I'm going to try
it, you know, like I think it's pretty
cool. I want to try the sexing stuff and
play around with all those things. I
like doing experiments and and uh
another good thing to remind yourself is
is uh lots of lumens, less time, like an
hour, but less lumens, maybe two hours
to prevent flowering to prevent
flowering, you know, so keep that in
mind as your sort of recipe as you get
into it. Well, yeah, because a
Oh, sorry. So, I'm just I just want to
make sure I'm hearing you right. So, the
thought process is don't don't give them
a long period of no light. You're saying
just break it up and you're you're
turning the light on for 15 minutes
every hour. I've I've heard that and I
know Sam was saying that for his library
and part of his experimentation was to
keep these plants from growing but to
keep the library and so he said he dosed
them in a couple times 15 minutes at a
time if I heard you right Sam and then
at two hours and what he was just
confirming was the two hours for a low
lumen light
right exactly if you had higher lumens
you could use maybe less time thing you
wanted to share about talking about
lumens
BA. Basically, what we found is that
absolutely need lots of lumens to
produce biomass in
veget or more and pretty much all it's
going to do then is uh fill out the
flowers and uh maybe uh add a lot of
weight from resin and stuff. I found
lower light levels I'm talking about
from the sun or from artificial lights
actually produce superior product. Also
what I found is that the high
temperatures associated with flowering
really high temperatures it's not really
positive because it has a tendency to
vaporize tarpen right on the plant. So
lower temperatures, little bit lower
lumens I found produced superior product
here when we were on mute that uh well
do you want to mention it Sam? What was
it? I forget. It was about the size of
the resin glands versus the size of the
plant. I I just wanted to mention that
when I grew the identical clone big,
small, even in vitro, so that the
flowered off plant was only uh maybe an
inch or two tall when it was completely
flowered in ager agar in vitro in a test
tube. The resin is much smaller. The
resin individual resin heads on that
plant. when you grow it two three feet
tall like you're talking about for sea
green or something the the resin is is
uh quite a bit a bit bigger but when I
grew my same clone and it was 12 feet
tall the resin was again a little bit
that's important it's important to me we
we missed that last that last little
part but
well the the last little part was that
if your plant is 12t tall and you uh
flower it off and then you collect the
resin from that, it's again a little bit
bigger than the uh three-foot plant. The
each individual resin head is a little
bit bigger. And for hashmakers, that's
important.