what's up guys bubble man and Flav New
Year's Day happy New Year broy New Year
dude yeah man yeah super happy new year
so we are getting ready for our
adventure of snowmobiling Adventure
Matt's in the house man he's got the
dabso it's like the eight kind nine kind
10 kind that's the 12 12 hashes 12 kind
not sure about kind but definitely um
microns so we're going to catch up with
you guys up at Brandy one in the back
country of Whistler just wanted to do a
quick little intro and uh Happy New
Year's everybody up Happy New
Year we missed Aaron we missed Aaron we
missed Aaron Aaron definitely wants his
hit how does want to get in this game
here you go dude you're in the game what
are you talking about you got yourself a
seat at the
table a big old hit a big old hit dab
the slab dabs from the slab yeah that's
the way to do it this guy is not even
messing around it's time to go
that right there is unity in the
community
people careful Hold On Tight With a
Little Help from My
[Applause]
[Music]
Friends oh that was my finger you just
hit nice that's got the drippy
drip Jesus hit it hit it Flav finger
dabs finger dabs and dabs from the
laab all right Fab egg hitten to
snowmobile rying see you guys in a bit
all right guys we're at the Hilton Hotel
and this is where um basically we're
going to get onto the sled tour so let's
do it sleding
sleding
yeah
[Music]
really
very
[Music]
n
yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
e
[Music]
a
[Applause]
[Music]
he hey hey
hey hey hey hey
hey hey heyy he
[Music]
hey
uh we just got to the cabin here we're
going to grab the guys we're going to
head around back and we're going to hit
a little safety meeting Matt of course
is holding it down at the back of the
cabin oh this is a nice view you got
here for your safety meeting there Matt
oh man it's killer eh I'm liking it
January 1st I'm liking it can't beat
this stuff man no you can't beat this oh
[ __ ] pull my shades out it's so
beautiful yeah Future's So Bright 2015
unity in the community that's right my
hand [ __ ] freezing my hands are
[ __ ] freezing C boy what are you
doing in the BC mountains dude dude are
you [ __ ] nuts SM get high TR smoking
K High well you know what I'm joining
this
session you know
what I know FL how abely beautiful is
this though oh I will
epic so beautiful up here if you guys
want to check it out look at the colar
man the color is
Rainbow wine we are up in the Brandy
Wine and and uh you know the house of
the great Gardener is not telling a lie
it is absolutely spectacular beautiful
up here right now and we got up here on
snowmobiles well that's the funnest part
and we're on snowmobiles I did a little
bit of video on the GoPro go of our of
our little Adventure here hold this for
a sec
got to load this get I grabbed a piece
of the N9 or 10 or 11 kind he said don't
smoke in the helmets that's the the Only
Rule that's a good rule I think we got a
great guide yeah
yeah I think at the start he thought I
might have been the guy to caused
problems yeah he doesn't meiz and I was
just like I'm not that guy well I'm
trying to go fast too so so like are I
think I'm at the front cuz I'm like the
you know let's watch this girl she can
set the pace maybe totally that's
exactly that's exactly did I'm just
getting used to these crazy BC sleds
with the giant fins that all a sudden
you hit the gas dude you're
drifting around love these sleds are
like I'm like oh oh Matt might be the
guy he's walking back he's getting
excited you know he can feel it he's
like dude let's get to that bowl I can't
I get too close I get too close to Aaron
and then he guns it and all sudden of
rockets me in the
face I'm like oh I can't get even he's
tailgating [ __ ] bro I thought you were
from Canada
even the little pieces of ice hurt did
you too hear that rumor that we don't
tailgate up in Canada what I don't know
he said you're from Canada shouldn't be
here shouldn't be tailg I don't think
you've driven around a Vancouver
tailgate hard dude we have what's called
new
Canadians and um safety break safety
break our tour guide lets us have safety
break we're hiding behind this little
tiny cabin puffing on melty bubble 12
kinds or more o yeah safety bra and
joints and
oil Here Comes unity in the community
[Music]
in and some melty kind yeah I have more
by the way all right guys I'm uh I'm
going to head around but awesome safety
meeting with you
guys oh I'll grab it from the the
side all right we just took a break here
on in the Brandy Wine and uh Aaron's
little daughter from DNA is going to get
on her own little sled check this fun
out look at this little
[Music]
guy
H
[Applause]
Mars This It Go that stop okay you're
going to go in a nice big circle don't
hit totally guys know you probably want
to but I don't want you okay so this
makes it go that Mak stop you want to
keep going just keep holding on to that
okay if you get get scared at all just
let go of that right hand right there
okay just drop your hand right off cryst
are SI this is called hor Frost hor
Frost this is called hor Frost and what
this is is this this is a great example
this creates a really unstable layer so
when the when the snow falls on top of
this snow this will be the layer that
causes the Avalanche like if you get 10
ft on top of it this is where it'll
break yeah this is beautiful beautiful
hor Frost this is what like what would
cause the Avalanches in the back country
many many times not always but often
it's a fracture in the
snow really cool you guys want to have a
big puff down here or what damn right I
get the pipe yeah pipe do you have a
pipe I have a pipe get the pipe out
please he won't look he
won't this is so cool right on
Marley keep pressing it yeah every time
you press it it makes she go
more she's like I don't get it tell me
honestly you guys ever like just take up
and have ripped around here contest
little these things they actually kind
of really suck guys I'll show you right
now oh yeah I'll show you right now on
your knees like just but man the nicest
sled ever to get stuck yeah just pick it
up all
right
yeah you're going nowhere
fast you're going to follow
me
Mars push your foot on the P push it
push it there she goes keep going keep
keep pushing it yeah keep pushing it
keep pushing you know what here's the
difference right here between boys and
girls little girl keep pushing it keep
pushing it little boy stop pushing it
stop
pushing why are we like that cautious
women I was thinking voice of reason I
was thinking [ __ ] guys but that's a
nice way of
putting cautious women yeah cautious
women not [ __ ]
guys oh that's just so cute for
Mars oh yeah she's got it you know a
couple more runs and you'll see she'll
be like an expert that is so cool that
is so awesome I mean as far as little
cool extras go that's a pretty cool
little extra where the bub oh my God all
right Dave what do you got there uh
little cury cotum what do we got for a
Dabber a Dabber oh otherwise it's mini
dunks I got my dab right here
going
pushing
maybe well we got this I got a dab in
here going by yourself
girl it's sort of the American Express
card dude chilling out with these these
clowns these hilarious clowns no no hey
I'm joking obviously not all clowns suck
no hash clowns like H
city the city H the city H he was he was
a hash
clown we proudly be a hash
clown man some of the mountains hey the
epicness on
it there you
go going like that perfect killing it
W did your kids do this too when they
were little oh yeah of course all right
well got to like pretty
cool we're good boys I think we're good
over to the left one step one
step then once Aaron gets his helmet off
and there and his goggles and he comes
over for safety break dude this is so
awesome awesome to be able to actually
take a
dab out of the little mini Cor care
where behind you yeah come down with us
sorry
not we got going on here by the way guys
just to give you an idea what Flav
brought up for snowmobiling just a
little Cory sick mini awesome
piece oh it's your sled pie and I'm like
camera got to turn it off keep going no
you told me to keep going all right W
what's going on with this side um when
we were going down that big hill the trk
dropped off on it and like it never came
back
sledding it's tramatic always something
happens to someone sled really always
we're lucky we got the sleds out of the
mountains look at those
mountains that's not where yeah okay
yeah we just came from I wish we had
spent more time up on the top that top
play buy a sled dude that was sick buy a
sled maybe just sell a pipe and buy a
sled that's what I'm saying dude that's
the sickest St that's a video that's
pretty that's a video flab Flav's sled
pipe trade
picture time get picture Time picture
time nice you got the sun behind you
that should that should be a good four
black Shadows no it's
good so Sunny you got to get the SL in
it that was ridiculous
rip we won't tell your your bosses if
you want any of this either yeah it's
all good
man
rips in the back
country
Coursey should I hook homeboy
up of course he
should now Marley's just having time of
life yours oh no it's mat great Gardener
dude thank you so much it was just in
my we just got off the trail again Flav
and I haven't even taken our our helmets
off let's go peep out this cabin in
[Music]
Lake
Aaron
[Music]
Matthew
Sarah
spot Marley and
king oh my goodness
gracious anyone
this is just
beautiful nice little cabin what cabin
is this Matt is this the dab cabin go
check out in the dab cabin is it the
dabin hey you guys should come check out
this dabin oh we are in
the
just
all right so they got Smokies here for
us how's the Smokey there Matt Smokey by
the fire Smokey by the
fire damn Smokey's by the fire how's it
Smokey looking Aaron is that
propery up we're going to Smokey it up I
don't picture you guys as smokey kind of
guys having a smokey after I had a
smokey that's what I'm saying hey what
is this like juice and stuff P chocol
call the munchies there you go awesome
well it looks great
top quality all right FL sitting up in
Whistler up at the
lake dabbing it up to just dabbing it up
bro just dabbing it up we got these two
characters on the nearby why don't you
guys grab a chair and put it right here
this will be
great I'll sit right on the uh right on
the edge
here and just sharing a little bit of
our fun day dabbing up and whis
yeah
buddy oh that smell like super silver
hay Haze or sweet skunk or Congo or
something that was some nice Congo woo
look at these
characters yeah all we need is some sun
just kicking back kicking back in the
back
country so good so nice how wet were my
ass get pretty wet just stand up
here it is cold though well you
definitely AR from Cali what do you
think the temperatures - maybe 0° right
now [ __ ] it's got to be likeus well
how you can always usually tell us look
at the
trees see how they've lost a lot of
their snow maybe
zero now Mark in
there I'm so excited where's the dab
where's the dabbing I don't know where
you're dabbing from he's got it he's
making some now dud it's so cold I don't
even know how you warm it up just press
it and then roll it a Jedi man who's got
the
dab keep it get it hot you want me to
give the Dabber here bring the Dabber
real quick the Dabber jar now put that
on the hash it'll make it easier for him
to I think he's got a piece of hash in
his fingers I'm ready here I got it like
here you go hot she's hot you got lots
and cap it
too this is the gong show that is our
life jabbing wherever we go dabbing at
the cabin we're da we're at the dab walk
around at the cabin walk around there
and show them show them the cabin cool
little cabin we're sitting at it's
amazing are snowmobiles smies and
smokies that's what they
call dude so sick so
sick cabin that
out someone will get me need the dab and
I'll
uh got to give it up to FL for bringing
this beautiful little piece that most
people nor I wouldn't stick this back in
your thing just P them up with your
finger maybe or here just don't sticky
on
your with my little hand clean with the
things you need those if you're from C
and you're up in the mountains
boy smies with smies yeah smokies with
Smokies at the dabbing smokies with
Smokies all right how are we going to
get a dab now cuz this is hot going
don't just do it Matt we're smoking it
all anyway don't even worry about it
Matt got permission from flab to stick a
dirty Dabber in his Congo hash I was
waiting I yeah what a day did you ever
thought you would see this day I think
that's going to be cold but the time I
think you're totally right I can feel it
getting cold one sec
more more
four dude you just got to work the piece
up in your hand yeah you just got to
press really hard nice little bit right
now oh yeah now he'll give me too
[Music]
much eyes
closed ear
[Laughter]
right it's funny Marley's got ear mut we
have at the house oh yeah doesn't do
[ __ ] all right like today
back stuck behind back on the road I got
stuck behind that guy following you
today
here all right guys as you can see we
have made it back to our lovely Abode
here in Alpine Meadows after a six snow
mobile that was just too awesome that
was really nice telling you you guys
want to check out uh snowmobiling and
Whistler there's a multitude of of
companies that do it but I would suggest
black Hol snowmobiles great little tour
took us throughout the trails took us
into the Alpine let us do do a little
bit of side healing took us to a cabin
fed us oh yeah and then even let the
little one in our group um go on a
little mini sled yes which was very cool
that was very cool very very cool now
we're just sitting here relaxing we got
some hash up well I'm down
for the hash out mhm I don't even need a
Dabber no you've made a perfect Dabber
out of this pure hash yes St it I guess
we got uh Aaron's in the steam shower
Matt's in the hot tub Flav and bubble
man we D are in the kitchen yes we're in
the kitchen we're cooking up some
goodness all right my friend well that
was great being out on the S that was
awesome no dude that was I now know the
uh the sport my next sporting Adventures
will most likely be on the
snowmobile I honestly recommend it to
anybody who hasn't done that before that
was some of the most fun I've had in a
long time since I stopped down likeing
so this is just something it's pretty
awesome it is awesome I mean there's
just something to be said about like
being up in the back
country beautiful snowy Cliffs all
around you trees everywhere you know
stopping hitting a dude hitting a dab
brought you know I'm sure Mark will show
the pictures in the video that we made
so um absolutely yeah which was awesome
da dabbing at the dabin dabbing at the
dabin I too enjoyed dabbing at the dab
it was very
nice slow and easy you kind of got let
it melt off
first it's just about there there we go
give you another little
blimp dabbing at the
dabbing yeah you just got to love the
Epic beauty of Whistler from hanging out
one day on the mountain to hanging out
on across the street in a back country
area uh to going with the kids
tobogganing or sledding yeah which we're
going to do next yeah we've got a bunch
more sort of fun things uh organized we
should we may get onto zip lines we may
get to balance the trampol place yeah
zip
lines okay that'll be
amazing
yeah slow and
easy we should hit this Dosa too this
Dosa hasn't been hit oh no uh we we
can't because as I brought it over here
as I brought both of them over here I
realized no lighter no beine oh W but
don't they look nice they are pretty
look at that and we can hit it right
away afterwards they'll like book in the
shop for us here right I like it yeah I
do like it all right well I'm going to
hit another little hit another little
rip of this and then we'll see what uh
what the rest of the plan is for our
crew we have a huge crew
and not any single person is making
decisions it's all of us sort of
deciding what we're doing
cuz there's unity in this community as
well oh
yes the backdrop to this place is just
so it's just so amazing right the
mountains I mean I don't know if you
guys can't really see but there's pretty
much is that Whistler right there behind
us which one whist the one you see right
out the door to the left is called wedge
wedge man and that just like the sun
sets right on it so we get like this
beautiful like pink and orange sunsets
like it always has awesome colors on it
for sure it's brilliant yeah yeah I mean
I'm sure you guys have all seen the uh
the walkth through by now so you know
what we're dealing with here absolutely
and if uh you enjoyed the little bit of
sledding that you saw on this video you
can check out um another video I have on
here two of them actually which is
called Brandy Wine tea
and Brandy Wine Back Country I don't
know just put Brandy Wine Backcountry
bubble man or bubble man's world and you
should be able to find a whole hourong
video of me and my friends going to that
same Zone hooking up on a super duper
powder day with um some guys on dirt
bikes that had a conversion that had
sleds back I saw that yeah and so we had
lots of footage of them climbing the
mountains and going off little Cliffs
and stuff and it'll it'll wet your
whistle anyway if uh if you enjoyed the
little bit of sledding that you saw in
this video
and otherwise uh I don't know I guess
we're just going to continue to Puff
here and maybe this video potentially is
the end of today's video maybe it's not
maybe it's not we'll see yeah watching
have a good
[Music]
day