[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and well I wanted to do a little show
today giving you guys a little bit more
of a tease of some of my life up in
Whistler and in the pton area Back
Country I had uh quite a few uh emails
and messages from you guys uh asking me
about different different concepts and
you know asking me where I ride where
what kind of sled I ride and what you
know whether I do the ice climbing
whether I do crampons what what kind of
split boarding and so I kind of wanted
to give you guys a little background um
I've been doing back country photography
up in Whistler for the last four or five
years uh not professionally by any means
but really more as a hobby just whatever
gets me out there uh I get to ride with
awesome Riders uh got a really good crew
for the uh for the snowmobiling aspect
my buddy Ryan NAD who you may or may not
have seen in my Facebook feed but he is
uh kind of one of my mentors in the sled
world and he sort of brought me under
his wing and took me in and brought me
to some of these amazing places that I'm
going to show you today and today I'm
just going to do three-part clip uh
three different clips I'm going to add
into this video and I'll talk a little
bit before each one um but the the area
is Rutherford Creek it's the pton ice
caps and it's about maybe 10 minutes uh
south of pton and maybe 20 25 minutes
north of Whistler on the SE to Sky
Highway uh there's a creek bed there and
there's a sort of little turn in parking
lot on the right side and the left side
and I think now they're actually um um
plowing the road so you end up paying 15
or 20 bucks each time you go up there as
the road is fairly long and so after
driving up to Whistler pton area takes
me an hour an hour and a half from my
house takes me another 45 to an hour
just to get the sled off the truck and
get ridden up into the Alpine uh and
then that's where we're going to start
this video today so this video the first
video is we're going to go up to a ridge
I'm following my buddy Ryan and uh
[Music]
enjoy
don't
[Music]
you about thing
take
he me and never give in don't do
worry about a thing
they he's there believe me and never
give in
life is not hard as it
seems take it one day at a time and
fulfill your
dreams remember no one is an island no
one stands
alone in your doings always remember
you're a
theme all when things get hard and
lean
hold on to your faith and fulfill your
beam and
[Music]
don't never give in
don't all the take it good easy believe
me never give
test of time test of
patience just like in the days of
[Music]
patient remember the man called job he
dreed the rocky
road he know where he was going so he
know where he was coming
from believe in yourself my
friend as you pursue
just you go
to and
[Music]
don't all right so that was an
absolutely beautiful video you have to
admit some of that fresh powpow you may
not have seen Ryan and Chris till the
end of the video they were quite a bit
ahead of me and you could see the few
tracks that were ahead of me uh were
theirs so once we got up onto the top of
that Ridge we ended up dropping down to
the right uh driving a little bit more
uh on the sleds up into the ice caps and
then we found a really nice little sort
of open face um Mountain that we were
able to drive up on our sleds ride up on
our sleds jump off St tra you know put
the boards on put the skis on and then
send the sleds down ghost riding uh
ghost riding is really only possible
when there's no trees or rocks or
crevasses that are potentially going to
be in between you and where you're
sending the sled it does still feel a
little sketchy to do but I'll tell you
when you just rip down on your on your
snowboard and then your sled's just
sitting there it is one of the just most
beautiful thing so this is me
snowboarding up on Rutherford Creek just
a real quick clip
enjoy oh
yes
again on highest the
highest looking at me eyes so red
because head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke Co
that's why I don't
Grumble stly s
me
[Music]
must be burned like
must all right well that was kind of fun
a little bit of slow motion there where
you can kind of see the the the power
and the speed that I'm actually going by
first slowing it down and when the slow
motion turned to fast motion which was
really just regular life it seemed like
I was Trucking pretty good I'd say a
solid 70 km an hour or 5050 M an hour
for my American Breen out there I think
it's time for a rip we've watched two
clips and I haven't hit one so I'm going
to hit three rips right now starting
with
this so yeah Rutherford Creek is where
I'm going to try and bring you guys
again this winter I've got plans to go
up there this is the area where we H
where we found the ice cave so we
definitely want to show you guys the ice
cave this
year I've teased and threatened probably
two or three times in my videos that I'm
going to be making hash in the pton ice
caps up in the ice
cave I'm not going to share a video of
the ice cave today cuz literally I want
you guys to see it For the First Time
Fresh when we show up with the hash
screens and the bags and and all
that probably one of my most excited
projects that uh oh jeez that's really
going isn't it I better finish my
rip all
right put a little more in there than I
thought all right so that was number one
let's have a quick number two we got
some really nice Astro Boy
here sitting out on the card uh 73
Micron um well cured 6 months
plus that's the
stuffo I'll tell you that hit right
there
that's a hit that you take a few seconds
after you
rip
beautiful and maybe one more of this
very nicely aged cure now the first hit
I took was actually the CBD Renee
pressed out into a lovely disc pancake
Patty whatever you would like to call it
the second rip was the Astro Boy that's
out here on the card very little left of
that
and then the final one is going to be
this really old Hindu cush that I have
this stuff is old like I'm going to say
older than 5
years and one of the thing things I love
about an a cured bubble is when I drop
it into the denail it almost just I
don't want to say explodes cuz there's
no combustion there's no burning but I
mean I'm telling you the the the Vaper
is instant and so you can tell the first
hit I put in was a little bit more fresh
it was dry dry sift but it was just dryy
sift that I believe wasn't able to get
to that really really bone dry um wax
membrane Vancouver Island can do that to
you with all that humidity in the
air all right three wonderful rips
made up for the few rips that I didn't
take while we watched the first few
Clips this last clip truly is one of my
favorites um it's me peeking um one of
the mountaintops uh up in the pton ice
caps um I'm all by myself there's no
tracks and
truly if ever there was a religious
experience to be had or a spiritual
experience for me this was it so watch
enjoy and thanks for watching Bubble
man's World guys morning to come
soon all right ready
[Music]
now all
right rooted and
grounded are you rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and grounded I
take the time of meditation Mother
Nature Young
rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
grounded rooted and grounded I take the
time of meditation to see children
children go to
school when you gradated TR know the
rules people people the
food and if you don't love the
environment you shall surely lose
[Music]
shall be
one so we should protect life
entirely yes rooted and
grounded are you rooted and
grounded I'm rooted and grounded I take
the time of meditation just to love
other nature rooted and
grounded are you rooted and grounded
[Music]
rooted and grounded I the time of
meditation lead us lead us Le
the right medit and bear good
[Music]
fruits bend the tree before
it so the youth cannot see their
[Music]
go mother
father care for your son
yeah the children turn today the man and
tomorrow going to
[Music]
be so we should learn to protect our own
liberty rooted and
grounded get to rooted and
grounded I rooted and grounded I the
time I meditation Mother Nature rooted
and
grounded I'm a rooted and
grounded rooted and grounded daily time
meditation things I know you got to
learn
life it's out to love and out
to yes so no let no one move you when
you know you're doing the
right oh don't let no and fool when you
standing rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
ground I rooted and grounded I take the
time
meditation rooted and
grounded I'm a rooted and
grounded rooted and grounded I take the
time I'm
[Music]
Med
roed and
grounded I'm a rooted and
ground are you rooted and grounded I
take the time
[Music]
I
together we
stay oh
Str
SS I say the Le that you to my brothers
do and to him together we
stay I say the least that you done to my
sisters you
do together we
stay organize
the love we need to sa one kind G
showing
[Music]
signs one want the
word but it make no sense to me nuclear
Wars and using
[Music]
strategies Pro Se oh this why Seas we
stays together we
stay that you to my brothers you do to
him together we
stay I say the least that you done to my
sisters and do unto him together we
stay
people get
ready up you mighty race indeed so much
your M to feed together we can
accomplish what we need it's so easy for
us to unite Come My People Come See the
Light
Fight to sa the day
W together
[Music]
we my
S to him together we
stay and the mind the least that do
my to again
we
St
[Music]
brother one man want the world it seems
but didn't make no sense to me buing
nuclear Wars and using
[Music]
strategies spread in JS like five seas
oh I wish this would Seas together we
[Music]
stay that you to my sisters you do want
to him together we
stay and the mind the least that you my
to to him together
we
Brothers one
[Music]
spot
yes
againest look at
me because we find on Sal head people
always ask me say why you so humble I
don't smoke they cocking that's why I
don't
Grumble man I
heardly S
[Music]
media be burned like your teeth must be
cleaned rather vital for Spiritual iene
a king Salam mon ify the tree and he is
the wisest man we so propa prach her s
true speech so meanwhile the song called
leaders deceive man obligated to clarify
and teach you
know
[Music]
Marana
friend the
highest the
high