[Music]
all
right hey welcome to Bubble man's world
everybody it is snowing like crazy it's
been 24 hours or less since I did the
last video of being out on my deck and
it was beautiful and sunny and I was
sitting in my
t-shirt and uh well now it's not now
it's cold and snowy and I thought what a
cool little video if we came out and did
a sort of contrast video one
second all right sorry about that had my
son in the other room going off so I
think we're just going to get a dab done
here try to get a little dab off the
slab here that's actually a very large
dab but you know what
I say it might be Wow Let's Not Be
exaggerating it's certainly not going to
be the last dab of 2016 as we're still
quite early on in the day but it could
be one of the biggest of this particular
day I got it I didn't think it was going
to work I'm not going to lie I was
getting a little nervous as it is Snowy
out here very very snowy nice big flakes
great for Whistler great for the Sea to
Sky
snowmobile people I love watching the GL
uh the snow land on my Banger and just
melt immediately land on my pipe and
melt
immediately you know we got to do a TP
dip on this so I'm going to make
sure we time this properly I got the
waterproof unit going so we should be
fine get that Banger heated up nice cuz
it's it's snowing
all right we'll go boom we'll do a quick
little TP dip I got the sun shet sherbet
here oh yeah there we go very nicely
very nicely all right and in less than
40 seconds we will have the the
beautiful snowy snow stormy Mothership
dab session so that is what we are
getting done here 22 seconds 22
seconds and we should be
good we should be good
yes all right
W that was
killer only thing left to do is clean
the
Dabber not the Dabber sorry the Banger
only thing left to do is clean the
Banger and it is outside the
Banger don't see that too
often was such a big one it dripped over
top so we'll make sure we get all that
cleaned
up thank God for the DC glass cleaner
man I am loving this
[ __ ] it cleans glass better than
anything I've seen clean glass yet now
only hot hot quartz hot glass cleans it
beautifully sorry not hot glass because
if you actually put this stuff onto Hot
Glass I'm sure you'd have a very bad
time but quartz and its ability to
withstand thermal shock is is a safe as
safe can be
so I'm going to call it a day at that
coughing coughing coughing great little
TP dip there with you and uh yeah just
thought I'd show you guys the contrast
which can happen on this deck in less
than 24 hours so thanks for watching
Bubble man's world and we will see you
next time
[Music]