[Music]
we're rolling all right so I got organic
coconut oil and a little bit of organic
butter in here and then I'm taking these
organic pistachio on
oh yeah and I'm taking
this m Rock Murray River salt and that
looks like the Himalayan rock salt but
it's River salt I like it better than
the Himalayan so I should probably
mention that I'm here at SAS and what
he's doing is he's producing some of his
unbelievable I guess it would be called
not almond Roa but it would be peanut
brittle but pistachio brittle pistachio
brittle or pistachio Roa and it's
unbelievable caramel that he medicates
up and in Spain they call it Cosmic
candy Som is Cosmic Cy in Spain I call
it about a 3-hour
siesta in Amsterdam I call it almost
didn't get home one of the things it
does it's like food
incense it it
it it's definitely obvious that you're
using high quality concentrates to make
it cuz there's really not a ganja taste
but like a turp taste well I I mean like
I'm using like my favorite things to
smoke to me so hashes and concentrates
basically
yeah I feel you there so how long you
been making this stuff for S well it's
like seeing as I use cannabis as
medicine I discovered when I got with
Jesse she was eating space cake a lot
and I go how how do you eat space cake
so often man I go when when I eat Dave's
candy or something I go those are insane
I go I I can't function those are
nonfunction functionable candies but but
I can do that stuff way better now cuz I
eat hash three times a week at least
Little Dave ones I I mean like it makes
me feel so good eating hash it relaxes
my
body sleep better it's very good it
makes me produce more melatonin I swear
to God man a lot of the older dudes I've
been talking to out here they're they're
having some health ramifications and
every single one of them I asked are you
consuming cannabis they're like yeah I
smoke it I'm like yeah you know you got
to eat it you got to eat it you really
have to eat it man you have to I love to
smoke it but you got to eat it too
especially if you need it for medicine
smoking it's great so right there I got
I got the pistachio nuts roasted a
little bit right right I'm going to put
those
aside and then we'll do the next step in
couple of minutes all right may just
will kill it
and your before we hit the next step I
think we should hit a nice bowl of Tony
V's turt
melts the Mother Ship excellent like a
professional
boom
aesome step two all right kill it cuz
I'm going to tell everyone to and then
Adam gave it to me wow and I used it in
my court case I went in there cuz they
busted me with 14.3 kilos here in 2004 I
wasn't here I had St I had a stashed in
the walls in the roof you know and so I
had 11 plants up there
and so they're so dumb I said look I
grew all that on my
roof and they go how can you grow that
much and then and then I had expert
weaknesses coming first of all the bay
when I walked into the court he says you
can't bring that in they were like you
going to hit the judge with that one and
so they took it from me and then when I
finally got to speak they gave it back
to me so I could speak and and I said to
the expert witness who was James Burton
who grew all the weed for the
begin legal
medicine I said Mr Burton how much can
you grow on a plant like this and he
said about 2
kilos and I had 11 plants on my roof
dude and honestly da Dave probably
pulled all right let's see what we got
where's what are where we at here we
got three kinds of full melt let's get
that into the light right there there it
is right there that's that's that's
going in
this cacao butter cow butter and organic
coconut oil all all organic nice and and
how much did you use just like a little
dollop of each sort of thing or did you
measure that up no it's five G five G of
each of the hash yeah of hash and what
about the coconut and no I don't measure
that I do it by eye cool you've been
doing it long enough so here's a
question like like all the time I've
been cooking and when I had my bakery I
always I always um do everything I
except for measuring the hash CU I want
to know exactly how much I got in there
okay now I don't want it to burn so once
I get melted like that first goes
in ra organic raw sugar holy Moses and
then is that why that stuff so good well
that's just like sugar if you look at
homeopathic medicine it's almost always
in your sugar carryer of course yeah
okay so then after that I got um
this slamon organic vanilla syrup oh
nice from
Madagascar and so that goes
in also just a sort of guesstimation
yeah of what you and then this organic
maple syrup from Canada ooh the Canadian
maple
syrup well that's nice that got things
rocking didn't it and then
Sal I shitload more of the Murray River
sea salt because it's really I find that
the salt also activates the hash going
into your system interesting not just
the I guess the the the the the salt
will also sort of react the opposite of
the like it it's just amazing how like
when you use sugar as a carrier like
this I think it's the best way you could
think of using like as a med medicine
carrier right you can see why all the
homeopathic medicines are all on a sugar
base because they figured out that it
goes into your system really easy with
this and I find the same thing with this
hash candy does this turn into a liquid
eventually or oh watch I'm going to
caramelize it that's what I'm saying in
a little bit I'll add the nuts back in
but I don't want the nuts to get too
cooked so I just wait a little bit and
that that five grams of hash totally
gets absorbed by this in the most
homogeneous way
you don't have to worry about too much
of it going one spot
because I mean I've done it many times
and it really works yeah like you can't
see any spot where there's a
concentration of too much hash because
it's thin out it's thinn out in the
whole thing and the more it melts the
more it homogenizes and you didn't even
have to filter out any of the hash
chunks that were left over they just
will dissipate no because it's full melt
it's
gone and I find like full melt hash
mixes with fats mhm like they hug each
other yeah they like each they bond man
they sure like each other don't
they this stuff has to get hot I mean I
have it on the highest heat and it takes
it takes quite you know like maybe about
5 minutes before it actually gets hot
enough but once it reaches that
temperature it goes fast see it
liquidating yeah you can see it's
starting but you don't want it to burn
too so you have to it's um it got heated
and it co so is this hash is this full
melt hash the whole thing yes this this
your Legends entry yeah this is s he's
put 300 G I'm sending this to Colorado
what
you s full melt oh man look how [ __ ]
crystalline that those Heavies are
that's what you call Sugar yeah this is
a straight oh that's real sugar straight
booty sister oh there it goes that makes
there go loosening up a little bit okay
now turn the heat up
[Music]
again taking care of business while
making s's finest yes look at
this taking care of
[Music]
business I smell like I got to a tur
patch didn't I you do smell a little bit
like you got into the tur patch when you
smell like that I call you turpy and
Tony hi
there yeah I have that
thing okay all
right okay as fast as I get weed right
now it's out the door I can't hardly get
it fast enough you know what I mean
jeez was that on no was that on
pour more into your
sugar so what's your thoughts on this um
I'm pretty excited about it I personally
never made caramels or almond roas but I
have gotten into the feeding of my endoc
canabo system via a coconut oil infused
uh I use dry sift and sometimes hash I
mean I'm amazed how small of amount of
this I need to do to get a nice Buzz cuz
I'm a full-time smoker but when I eat
this it's it's amazing how small amount
I eat and it does what I wanted to do
and how many grams did you put in again
five gr a half five gram so I do about
four four gram per cup of coconut oil
but I think this might even be a higher
dilution in the sense that it is a
higher dilu much more than a cup but but
but I'm telling you somehow this
combination well you don't have to tell
meat even even the eugenol and the
vanilla yeah have something to do do
with the Synergy yeah I believe it
there's definitely something going on
it's different than the coconut
oil um it's an unbelievable tool for
insomnia oh my God it it is it's it's
the insom fibromyalgia fibromyalgia man
you don't have fibromyalgia when you eat
this candy so now I'm putting the
pistachios back in which you you you
umast those you don't have sleep
problems no and you're definitely going
to the bathroom when you need to
imagine that this delicious treat can
regulate your biological functions
through your endoc canabo system so you
got four fats you got the fat from the
pistachios you got the fat from the
coconut oil you have the fat from the
cacao butter and the fat from the cow
butter so I find that with four fats
like that it goes into system better
than if you just use coconut oil or
something excent just use multi fat
tactic
and so this will eventually just turn to
liquid yes like it goes slow fast and
then all of a sudden it just it's like
overnight and you s FP this is almost
like waiting to watch full melt melt in
the bowl yes it is I'm literally excited
waiting for s's concoction here to melt
into a caramelly almond Roa peanut
brittly goodness it's close too cuz it's
doing it on the edge of the pan whenever
you
excellent tasty
treats just one great way I'm sure you
have a variety of ways that you canum
this yeah Tuesday I'm going to make a a
p colad smoothie at my talk oh nice yeah
cuz that's a really nice way too I think
I've seen you do that before yeah I have
that's good yeah I've seen that maybe at
the the I find that at the Cannabis cups
it's a nice way to to share some it is
absolutely and everybody gets such a
little taste it's the only tasting it
really my friend used to do it at like
Grateful Dead shows and stuff he brought
like a a 10-speed bicycle that he took
apart and he set up the chain on the
back wheel so it went to a blender and
it was blender uh it sounds like a
friend I used to have yeah his name was
Brad he owned a hemp store I know a guy
named Michael did something like that
with a juicer yeah yeah this was a
similar thing but a blender and he would
make uh you know petal Blended drinks
petal power you could even make your own
juice you know he wouldn't pedal at all
okay so I say in the next 3 minutes it's
going to flip yeah it's sure a nice
color right
now oh yeah starting to bubble on the
edges so you get this into a liquid
state and then I guess pour it out on a
pan or something yep using this uh
silicone
spatula Jee this is just delicious
this is what we should do day one when
we arrive is come make a batch of this
with
s we should have this in our hey M
boy yeah
baby how's that Rescue
Remedy I
[Music]
thinking you know what you're just not a
little boy if you if you don't have a
story about jumping on the bed and then
hitting the dresser I just I just sang
five little monkeys jumping on the bed
one fell off and bumped his head mama
call the doctor and the doctor said no
more monkeys jumping on the bed I was
just singing that to him and he reacted
pretty good made me not worry so
much boy he's got an egg on his head
though oh it's the worst to see a little
children with pain I wish I could take
it instead of him sure of course
God from a distance now this almost
looks like some epic Curry that you're
mixing
up raisins and what about hash Curry
that will be nice hashish Curry yeah
oh anything with hashish generally will
be
nice has
restaurant a popup has restaurant
I have a friend who's dying in the well
he was in the hospital now he's out but
he's dying from prostate cancer and his
wife started coming over and getting
this candy from me and it helps him so
much I wish you could help him all the
way but definitely helps him have an
appetite and sleep and be more
comfortable
definitely okay there we go it's almost
there yeah you got a nice consistency
[Music]
now now this is so
hot
that does doesn't
it right back so goodness
hot
ti so I got this that's hot too yes yes
I got this
uh
pan that I'm going to pour it into
good
call oh my
goodness that's just
awesome this covers that pan no
problem you get that outside or in the
fridge
or do you just leave it cool out on the
counter I let it cool right here okay
and I and since I A lot of times
I I like to eat the pieces without the
nuts because I on teeth so I prop it up
a little bit just so that one part is
more nuts yeah one part is more not
nuts beautiful man well we'll look
forward takes about an hour to cool all
the way excellent and this part on here
cools a little bit faster and people
like Marcel usually taste it off of here
can we show the uh finished product in
the freezer yes that's like all cooking
shows and maybe have ch for ourselves
you ever watch juli's child she didn't
just make something she had the finished
product just like right here and here's
the roast beef
dinner and this will end up Jesus Christ
looking
looking like
this fast reactions for being damn damn
quick peanut brittle pistachio P brittle
you can see the pistachio that's in
there awesome and would you like a piece
I would love a
piece yummy
absolutely delicious yeah
sure well thank you for sharing that
with us
s sure the people will enjoy that muchly
and um what is the YouTube channel they
can check you guys out at uh uh s
Mission s Mission check it out I'll put
the link in the comments if you want to
see more cool [ __ ] like this come check
out s Mission and the smell is also
right
mhm it's great Ring a little you just
broke off your nutless
area well you can see that like it's
good glass the texture is unbelievable
it's good the sound of it yeah still
warm a little bit
yeah oh wow whole
thing one big piece this the warm a
little bit that's real thick down over
here too right
you have said before that you took it
out in
one oh
yeah so sweet cheers
brother yeah
[Music]