all right we are at the Magic Fountain
in Barcelona
came and came in 2004
Magic Fountain
it's a really cool spot to hang out
some epic buildings looks like it's all
turned off right now I think it turns on
at night but
cool nonetheless
[Music]
[Laughter]
oh my God
[Music]
thank you
I just walked around the Magic Fountain
here like I mentioned this is one of the
first places I ever went to in Barcelona
at my first spanibus which was before
spanipus it was actually called la
Fiera high life and a Gentleman born and
bred local to Barcelona said you must
let me take you to some of my favorite
spots this is a beautiful spot
overlooking the city you can see
everything in the city in the background
it's really cool and then bring a tripod
however
there's a small possibility I can make
this work we'll see we'll see sometimes
life works sometimes it doesn't
I think we're gonna go for the it
doesn't methodology here
sort of it's pretty sketchy you could
break my camera
let's try another option over here
this one looks a little better maybe
oh is that sketchy
sometimes you gotta go with what you got
and right now sketch is all I got
although you know what I could put it on
this case I think and it would be a
little safer
pull this out
Q-tips
we're gonna put this right on here I
think that's gonna be a little less
sketchy maybe maybe not I don't know
pull out some of the flavors that we got
from the masters of rosin which have
been substantial and wonderful I'm not
sure that I brought my Dabber
pain in my butt if I haven't
dropping things
luckily there was nothing in there
my little lens cap
oh and there's my Dabber too very nice
very nice
very good very good very good I'm not
sure where we're upside down right now
but nope
okay so we're gonna take that too
do this up
that on there like that
[Music]
and I think
will be a way to the races
a little crooked it's okay
do our best that we can we're just gonna
take a quick dab here because what a
beautiful place and if I didn't take a
dab I would be remiss
I have some of my tops here right now
we're gonna hit 47.
I believe this was skittles it could be
wrong I think it was one of the top
three though that placed
and we'll be hitting out of the Legends
Carter 2. so we'll hit this up one two
three four five on the top button
she turns on
her little visual
um all right still got 60 which is great
I only had 20 percent when I woke up
this morning I was kind of lazy
last night I spaced putting it together
oh yeah I'm gonna take a big one of this
you know what I'm gonna finish it that's
what we gotta do
we gotta finish these dabs so that's
another one finished
down the tubes
push the top button again twice once
you've turned it on and that ignites the
uh the the temperature I don't know if
you can really see the screen
but it basically shows you it climbing
in speed in temperature
and then once it reaches temperature it
basically
um turns on a timer for you
here we go
so tasty
and I have not been putting water in
mine
for the most part because it's going in
and out of my bag very quickly but the
water just becomes a pain
[Laughter]
not bad
so many of the rosins of uh masters of
rosin's entries were absolute fire
um I want to get my Q-tips out and do a
little bit of
washing
cleaning
gooping
actually pulled them out actually the
other pack oh yeah they're right next to
me I kind of figured I did but you know
what
sometimes it's easy to forget these
things
okay
it's good to clean this
as soon as you're done it's a very good
rosin pipe too I put a little bit of
melt in and there was some residuals
whoa we're shaking now aren't we
a little bit of residuals but otherwise
really good
and that's about how quick and easy you
can hit the Magna Carta I like the wind
effect actually I'm going to leave that
because it's a trip there shut her down
I had a nice dab I'm gonna go find my
buddy that I'm traveling with and we
will see you guys in a bit today is
really drive around Barcelona on
motorcycles and puff is in as many cool
spots as possible so we'll see you at
the next cool spot
foreign
Tower
this is so cool
up on the hill in Barcelona
can't really tell but it's pretty
beautiful view
just drove the Beast here the GS 310 BMW
I just drove it up this really nice
Mountain Highway I wish I could have
shown it to you guys on the GoPro but I
didn't bring my GoPro
but uh yeah really nice
really nice little restaurant up here La
Venta
and a little castle church thing behind
that I want to go check out
this guy's dogs are absolutely tripping
balls
quick stop at mirablon on the hill we're
in Barcelona
[Music]
really just good
dabs in the restaurant at Barcelona
so beautiful
I guess we gotta wait five seconds for
this um
[Music]
oh my God that tastes like heaven number
eight
[Music]
it tastes so good
wow
good one
I know
beautiful
um
[Music]
sorry
yeah
thanks for our art is the amazing world
it's all the themes of art there's all
the themes of our equipment those are
the patterns
[Music]
Q is the she is Snippets oh yeah that's
a Snicker table
[Music]
um
gorgeous
[Music]
this is awesome wow wow very heavy
definitely crushing it
it's interesting because it all looked
different to me and I didn't recognize
any of it as any blowers that I would
know
maybe it looks like Scotty Nichols Yeah
like a mandala style it's one piece yeah
encourage like a banjo almost too banjo
was what I was thinking especially with
the I didn't see the girl this this
one's definitely inspired by banjo oh a
thousand percent
up
it's increases
[Music]
These are nice
foreign
[Music]
I'm sorry
it happened
is
[Music]