foreign
[Music]
just bumped into Merlin here at the DNA
booth at spanibus we've got DNA behind
us having a party probably best not to
bring the camera over while they're
having personal conversations in the
board what they're saying but uh yeah
what a trip bumping into you in Spain
dude yeah
it's getting cooked with Merlin as old
getting cooked with Merlin all right
who's this guy Johnny [ __ ] B
you know dude Johnny being saving the
turf saving the terms doing the ICBC
thing Trump in the book humping the book
it even got the box of stickers nice
dude
did you know you'd find me here all
right at the DNA
absolutely awesome Johnny
[Music]
cash
[Applause]
[Music]
stop playing
oh [ __ ] yeah bro that's what's up that's
what's up
foreign
stuff right here
I'll go over that later
Dutch Passion
are you [ __ ] serious it just started
right it did no I swear to you hey just
made it down by the water after spanavus
what a great event that was W in the
background stayed there a couple years
ago and just uh just down by the marina
wanted to get the Vibes of the water and
the boats and it's gonna go eat some
food with a couple of buddies
let's see how it goes
so we're gonna start with Ava
please
two pesos Tristan
okay you go with professor
Bellissima
okay
yeah I haven't stayed here for a few
years but this is a beautiful area of
Barcelona some good skateboard culture
happens here
oh
beautiful Pier
I'm just over there Africa
what happened all right got a little
gift from some homie working for DNA
genetics
uh this is powered by secret society
hash Co our Terps don't lie so I'm not
actually sure what the cultivar was on
this one uh it says it's two grams of
cold cure though so that's really nice
you could probably get a nice up close
there if you don't block out the sun I
don't know if you can go up there
without just putting holding the camera
close to it you can usually get a
can you go closer
great well let's take a little dab oh my
goodness this is nice [ __ ] dude
oh God damn I'm actually excited for
this
what's crazy is that uh it is Barcelona
so you want to be safe
um you don't just want to kind of be
puffing anywhere in Barcelona but um
it's a pretty kind of wealthy area where
people are doing pretty good and they're
a lot of skateboard culture hangs out
here
I've spent some time here before myself
so I'm pretty confident that I'll get
away with a couple of puffco or a couple
of card Puffs I did get a huge kick down
today from puffco as well so I'll have
the puffco and the Carta going
toe-to-toe with one another and seeing
uh which ones I like and which times you
know
with all these devices I find the best
one is the one that you need at the time
that you need it
so there we go quick little pup
yeah that's beautiful
[Music]
like I said when you're in Spain
be careful be smart
you don't want to Puff too out in the
open it's not Amsterdam they do have a
bit of a harsh belief system when it
comes to the police in particular so
be low-key and enjoy your vibes
[Music]
what's up