all right all right welcome to bubble
man's world I'm sitting here with Kevin
from steamteam Jamaica the original
vaporizer just the steam chalice if
you've never been never smoked or
vaporized from the unit like this you
you can't believe it until you tried it
truly is the original vaporizer that all
these volcanoes and other units that
have come years later this is the roots
sitting in you know while this ganja
field at the Blue Hole is is not too bad
either all right and dabbin we're gonna
do some six-star bubble hash dabs on top
of the steam chalice mm-hmm Robin wood
esteemed team you know em on its a J
anything right no really I'd mind
vibration all right give thanks to the
Bob lush niceness you know
yeah and if you want forget this it's
team chalice you can always check out a
little bit of that steam tmz.com
now I mean made a vaping experience much
much nicer you know blessings I have one
at home that I got out here that I quite
enjoy it's just a matter of getting used
to the the procedures of having the husk
being able to create the coal being able
to you know keep your kochi clean and
and take care of the unit you know
changing the water out of the coconuts
good you know don't leave that in there
for too long it becomes stagnant you
smoke throughout a day no problem but at
the end of the day dump it out water
take care of it like you would take care
of any pipe yeah keep it fresh on keep
it with our fresh ruler you know give
thanks for blazing open with a steam
team well mine yeah my respect go first
baby greens greens fun to see you now
check the greens pond the scene we're
surrounded by them it's great some
wonderful tastes smells in the air
[Laughter]
all right no mine all right
voila we doors it's being team J a
Taurus mo your team punch so much done
with a job you know Steven on Davi
will supercharge steam yeah ma don't
want to make a fast tunnel
no one open
strictly our gonna choose a kind of real
cloud like I say
[Music]