[Music]
love big up
y y have some NAD t-shirt see and have
the new album slay presents normal SC so
can check it out if want to purchase and
patronize and have a brand new book it
to a book of no poetry people so
patronize yeah all
[Music]
right them all them all them
in a
traffic
Z put it to my lips I'mma pull it
slow pull it slowly look to my right
squ
my window signal to me yeah signal to me
controller
over window
[Music]
smoke roll
[Applause]
[Music]
the inner
C the in city where cross walk with
G with but
[Music]
heart
I turn
every
[Music]
[Applause]
simple forget your
step w w w w oh come in contact with me
in favor of me that's the prayer wo w w
wo
the Bible give praises
to H your mother H your
[Music]
father
Marana
[Music]
marijana
Marana
marijuana for just step
[Applause]
in oh
[Music]
yeah you know sometime we need to let ha
is down and have some fun breathe
breathe everybody all
right every boils and skirt everybody
all
right in a stepping eye are you stepping
eye are we stepping
high in a stepping eye h singing time
stand up and dance to man come on come
on lazy want no lazy
[Music]
what to go school and not
I only takes a
spark to get a fire
going and
going so come let's take a
walk where green herbs are
growing and
growing that's how it is with
G oh once you've experienced it you
won't
believe you will achieve and you will
watch
to sit on pass it on
[Music]
give me that give me that
let's go let's go let's
[Music]
go light it up light light it
up light it up light
up light it up light it up light it up
light up your light up
your light up light it up light up your
light up your
child come on come on one
[Applause]
[Music]
it I said now that we found her what are
we going to
[Music]
do now that we what are we going to
[Applause]
ah ah ah ah
[Music]
I was spr on my marijuana
cologne on my marijuana
cologne on
[Applause]
my spr on my
mar I was spraying on my mar cologne
when it Miss and caught me in my eye
that was my reply to the officer he
asked about the redness my eyes said my
t-shirt SP of ganja and he saw a little
stain and he's wondering if he could get
just a t for his
[Music]
bra what are we going to do
we what we
[Music]
[Applause]
going always got always
got just
always got all the
[Music]
way the helicopter get
the the
Earth so I jumped on the C like a crazy
dud crazy D I'm crazy like
[Music]
[Applause]
pirate shut up
[Music]
[Applause]
I just
yeah
I I
[Applause]
[Music]
come
on
I'm I'm All way
I'm I'm all the way I'm way I'm all the
way I'm all way I'm always got I'm I'm
way just I'm I'm way I'm way I'm way I'm
[Music]
place I'm
all go
[Music]
[Applause]
we are the
license
man say that again brother heav say that
again brother heav we have the license
for
M ah and
all Scrat clap your hand clap your hand
listen to the m man clap your hand
I CL your
[ __ ] sh CL your clap your give clap your
hand clap your clap your give me
[Music]
you ready you're ready you're ready
[Applause]
what
this what
this what is
here we
go unrest I and one more time one more
another
system is put to the
test
what come with me
[Applause]
teacher
teach lawyer a law preacher preach
police a draw
[Applause]
[Music]
Jama Jama
[Applause]
Jama
Jama green beard Brit
[Music]
[Applause]
clop
oh I did you oh I did you I did you just
say what's up with a random [ __ ] hello
hello I'm out
here was the
profanity was the curs no I have an
uncle his name is bngo okay bngo Clark
okay bngo Clark
in a c just
little
[Music]
[Applause]
no
[Music]
on hallelu
oh high high high high high high high
high see stepping higher leave them
alone
Hallelujah we up thees of
night
Hallelujah bad boy police bad boy police
bad boy police bad boy I police
[Music]
now before I go
I want you
to before I
[Music]
go I want you to
know bread fruit is the new bread baby
bread fruit is the new bread
baby bread fruit is the new bread
you right
[Music]
oh my sick
tree oh my sick tree freedom song for me
I said freedom song for
[Applause]
[Music]
me children we must
say so will never give the power to
[Applause]
a r come
crucify the
Dre time
alone oh time will
tell you think you're in heaven but you
living
[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
love love very much thank you for
sitting through this dancing through
this standing through this respect J
Love guy no get your albums
[Applause]
yeah all right all right
yes make some more noise than that
ladies and gentlemen no Ms you enjoy
that way more come on make some noise
if you enjoy that one say more
fire say more
fire say
pleas that's my name remember it my name
is MC Blaze thank you guys for accepting
me show some love for your MC One More
Time come on MC yes I'm somebody's child
you going to love me he going to show me
some love up in
this all right so ladies and
gentlemen uh remember we got to Big up
one more time skunk magazines all right
we got to Big up bourban Beach all right
we got to Big up cuan the wall works you
see me we got to Big up spanner light
engineer we got to Big up ziko aut love
my name is MC Blazer we got a we
have my co-host this evening ladies and
gentlemen I want you to show some
love rough house yes we have to pick up
Rough House loud all right right now
ladies and gentlemen let me introduce
our co-host this evening Mr Don
P was a love 102
FM come up here and show some love to
these
people he will not be drumming ladies
and gentlemen he will not be playing the
drums so DP go big up your Ru house
love once again Make some noise for
Blaze doing a wonderful job all night
Make some noise for the
MC Make some noise for the
MC when I come on stage I need energy
I've been feeling it all night relaxing
drinking something for my throat big up
Dave inside the
place once
again on the side of the stage there's a
presentation that I need to get
going with the young lady with the
trophy please join me on stage please
not yet in the meantime don't forget
next week Saturday inside Long Bay beach
spring break returns if you miss it last
year it continues next week Saturday
with the likes of Beanie
man szla kalangi half pint
hona Kip rich just to name a few so make
sure you come to Long Bay beach next
week Saturday biger prod chin inside the
place once again up Bella all the
hardworking sponsors who make this show
possible carlen and her husband all the
family big up yourself wonderful
wonderful wonderful can't get no better
than this next year is going to be even
greater big up all the herb farmers who
make the stage look so
fabulous Make some noise for the farmers
Make some noise for the farmer
please I know it's been a long night but
you got to keep the show tight and right
with your excitement this is all all
about high grade the 12th year
anniversary once
again we have setting up on stage one of
the Legends who will be joining on stage
in a few we have Andrew T still standing
by we need a where's the stage manager
we need some assistant to get these
equipment up for the artists we need a
stage manager to come on stage
but the legend of me drum across watch
take job once again how are you feeling
ladies and
gentlemen I can't hear you how are you
feeling still can't hear you how are you
feeling are you feeling
H thank you very much want to bring up
once again empress relle and all the
hardworking staff who make this possible
M mild and mellow big up yourself higher
grade band beautiful beautiful
presentation all night yall need to
start get some overseas tour okay I got
to talk to homar and make sure all
Engineers them all the musici want to
Big up BC Kon B player man Manas Manas
inside the house don't forget once again
April 6th inside bourban Beach Roman
Virgo live you don't want to miss that
show once again want to Big up the lady
I seen her dancing all night uh to me
she looked like she's about in her 90s
and she been dancing from 8:00 until now
beautiful Empress I know she's been up
there pick
[Music]
up this is
oh yeah oh yeah God Save the King of
Kings ganja Mar
L the sun is shin in the middle of the
night are you together sun is
shining Shin sun is
shining yeah
man I want you to
know yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
here it is sun is
shining and the weather of
changed love I've got for you I
arrange for the
rescue here I
am come to check you to love you you can
love me if you
try when the
morning yeah in a sunlight Sun sunlight
I want you to know I am a
[Music]
satellite Crimson to
CL I can take it over over and over
over
I I want you to know I'm a SAT light a
flash of light a satellite and the Flash
of light a light insight
[Music]
[Applause]
hello
hey I want you to break
sh love it love
it love it love it and love it love it
it it you
to the
[Music]
resue here I
is come to love you you you I can love
you if I try try
try try to love
[Music]
[Applause]
you I
[Music]
God Save the King of Kings and the Lord
of
Lord God save the Tre
life God bless Jamaica and God bless
Jama bless
[Music]
say are are
we are
are
[Music]
God
Mar lion Crown the
king Mar
lion the king of the life life life life
life
[Music]
life I am
your God is
black I can't come
back God is
life God is not a curse and
got God is not a curse God is a blessing
and bless bless bless
[Music]
bless here I
am to the
[Music]
resue
[Applause]
[Music]
togh with Dr
are we who are we
[Music]
[Applause]
who are we who are we who are
we music music music in the music in the
music in the music sun is
shining and the change
[Music]
to bless you bless
you I love
[Music]
you try try try try try
try you like
butly fly fly fly
fly up your wings and fly not take up
your wings and
fly take up your wings and
[Music]
F fly fly
fly fly your wings your hands are your
wings ear
rings what happened
okay why nobody said
no again
[Music]
captain captain
captain Obama come
down Obama come down
America Obama people from America run
away to Jamaica
America come to Jamaica
English come to Jamaica
Canadian come to Jamaica America
going to have a very good
time I love you kiss
[Music]
you to
move r
up wake up ladies in the wave and the
wave and the wave and shake your hand
and get of your grave are you
[Music]
okay and good the time that's it thank
you put your hands together a
scratch oh to make some noise
[Music]
yo
wa hey guys so we are now at the Rock
House I'm just heading up to see the
room Tony got
us thanks M don't worry you go huh don't
worry you can
fit thanks a lot all right man no talk
to you later right all right I'm over
here right
ah I think
so all right give
thanks so the rock house is a really
nice little
place really
sweet how does it open
Tony look at this little place other
than just breaking my finger on the door
let me show you
something two beds
upstairs bed down here let me just put
some [ __ ] down bungal s oh yeah look at
that that's
cool check this out it looks bad I broke
my wind looks good you come into the
bathroom yeah there's an indoor outdoor
shower no
way that is really
cool very
cool nice little spot here at the Rock
House just for the night we're going to
get it
done we needed a place to stay we
weren't heading back to Kingston tonight
so I think we're going to set up the
denail have a little session get to bed
we'll wake up we're going to share some
of the session with you guys and then
that's going to be the end of tonight
we'll have a few words about the
festival we'll do that in just a few
minutes
[Music]