[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble M's World
we're here uh on the uh I guess this the
beach of uh Nill the 7 Mile Beach and
we're at the Cayenne Beach for the 12th
annual stepping High ganja Festival
that's here in Negril this is the first
year it's ever been operating under a
permit to have ganja able to be on site
so there should be a fair amount of
ganja in there uh myself and Tony are
executive judges so we're going to get
to see all the flavors film them all
hopefully photograph them with the macro
and let you guys know what we thought
and uh yeah I think we're just going to
head in right now so let's do
it what's up
Maurice dude how's that for the intro
Maurice in the house right on
buddy how's it going Ryan good to see
you dude all right so it's time to go in
here entrance is yeah we we're going to
pay for the um tickets to go in all
right let's go find out how much they
are
[Applause]
[Music]
uh I'm
kill hello yes sir we're on the
executive judges list huh bubble man
plus three executive judge judges list
that's what Bobby
told bub
man guys what's that how much guys well
there's five of us but it was me plus
three that Bobby said he would put on
the guest list all right so going to I'm
going to pay for the rest right yeah all
right five of them and then I'll give it
three how's it going good good Wicked
stepping High
this is exciting yeah it is yeah we're
putting this on Bubble man's world
there'll be 10,000 people watching this
in the next two
[Music]
days all right good thanks do I need to
put that on right away or what what's go
on
[Music]
today right next to the
Maroons it's fine perfect thanks
[Music]
are we in are we in are we in there's
just people in the car that's wild
eh let's go in
I didn't know if I should keep waiting
behind you or if you all right then
we're just chickchat hello
guys chitchatting is good
[Music]
[Applause]
did we pay for the other
two I don't know maybe we have to
[Music]
[Applause]
wait police are here lots of them that's
wild eh
[Applause]
[Music]
hello Gail Zucker I follow you on
Facebook I'm Marcus Richardson hi Mar
see your photos all the time oh nice I
figured I should say hello yes pleas
right on this is Tony and Kelly and
Vivan hello hello have a great evening
de see you
[Music]
yes yes
[Applause]
yes we could have had a boo
1984 you want to come out early we get
we can do it
tomorrow he said never he never said
come I know it's
true I was happy to hang out and wait to
be
[Music]
honest me hungry food this guy's got the
best food dude right
here um
well what's going on over there hey look
at this look at this
[Music]
what's
up what's up yes very good very good you
guys are looking at the Quant
[Music]
cam hey po man what's up hey how's it
going all right very good to see you
very good to see you too it's been a
while hey yeah from the last time in
Pegasus Pegasus yes so how come you
didn't come down for the conference uh I
missed that conference but I came about
4 days later I had a bunch of meetings
yeah yeah so yeah I was uh you're okay
though I'm really good yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah really good happy to be here
right now yeah yeah yeah just come in
just walked in the door I've been here
for a few days in
Jamaica just walked the door yeah yeah
yeah that's not bad yes they testing was
what's happening there yeah yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah yeah man real good real good all
right guys bubble man here I'm with Bena
and Sue Sue and Bena at their wonderful
little table with ganja cakes and
coconut jelly and different uh sort of
shakes peanut and whatnot and they've
been kind enough to let us dab at their
table I got Tony over here
[Music]
Marin all right guys we get back to dabs
all
right who's got a lighter got a
lighter I'm okay
[Music]
picking this up just like I got to send
them our names and all that [ __ ] for the
for the
Manifest going to pick us up here and
then we're going to pick you up in b
[Music]
you got a dab
Tony
ktis dab him with it right
away wait wait for it to cool down a
little bit so it's more like a
steam all right it's good now
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah oh that would floor a lot of
[Applause]
[Music]
men that's got to be good right there
yeah
dude hello hello
[Music]
[Applause]
around let
[Music]
[Applause]
Tony i
[Music]
s we sell it for
you're
[Music]
[Applause]
good
meanon bub
[Music]
maned wicked good to meet you man
yeah can meet
you mega mega move of meet in America
about 30 years ago 30 Wicked nice it's a
long time man respect well let's get him
a
[Music]
[Applause]
dab what you do that we heat up the
quartz cuz it's clean every time then it
doesn't burn it hits like a steam pipe
cuz the oil is so pure that was made
with water and hash it's bubble hash
right on the right on the table there
must be
[Music]
illegal yeah well that hash is like like
breaking like where your head
[Music]
who's
R bubble has riage
Bubble look at
[Music]
[Applause]
that you don't have to really tell
anyone it's pure they just can know by
looking at when your friend has to say
it no no it's good it's pure it's clean
it's really good it's like man that's
salesmanship you just give someone this
and don't say
anything oh man this is the purest gum J
Jamaica could grow some of the
best made this is made in America by
Bubble
[Music]
Bags burning or no yeah no this is more
steaming that's why the water won't
smell bad it'll smell more
good hey we got good ganja cake here and
we got like jelly coconuts and we got
Did we tell you we were going to get
business going girls or
[Music]
[Applause]
what man
[Music]
I mean I know there's other people with
more suffering but that one got to me
dude I had migraine headaches for 2
years and I had to deal with that but
just came of a yeah mine too I just got
headaches all of a sudden then what it
was was a yeah get in there here let me
get this out of the
way what was it if you want to get [ __ ]
if you want to get pictures of [ __ ] like
that you should come by our place yeah I
need to that's what I need we're at
beach comr right by the pool should come
tomorrow morning tomorrow morning Monday
I'm in Spanish Town
[Music]
you know I've been filming this whole
time Tony while doing the
[Applause]
torching that's a good close-up picture
if you can get a portrait of just the
flame and the ball
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah Tony's getting the
[Music]
wicked well first we light it up to burn
anything that's residual left over from
the last hit then we let it cool
[Music]
down and then we get a perfect Vapor
hit all right here we go trying to do
the
camera
[Music]
[Applause]
sorry this is just a glass jar for
carbing it to make it uh restricted eh
yeah kind of like the hole in the
Chalice all right another another hit
for someone tones get her all right
let's do it we're rocking and rolling
here so I just wanted to get her Booth a
little
happening we all we should do this to
all the booths
[Music]
no that's why we keep reminding
everyone they got good ganja
cake yeah ganja cake much a slice how
much a slice for the ganja
cake 300 pretty good for how strong it
is it's a pretty good price three bucks
[Music]
[Applause]
one
[Music]
[Applause]
so this is like
[Music]
[Applause]
smoking it
go I hit it I didn't get it that hot
[Music]
[Applause]
it takes like a second it's like oh that
wasn't so bad you're like breathing and
then and then you can't breathe then you
can't
breathe what kind of is this water hash
water hash yeah it's not oil it's like
itall it's water and
ice no coconut
water just made with water and
ice yeah you're welcome to have one if
you
want you want me to light this up tone
yeah
here you want your bag like safe so you
don't have to think about it cuz I'll
literally put my foot on it like I have
[Applause]
mine yo I got the card the number I got
for you didn't work
86537 card is like ashy somebody was on
card no that was Ashley Davidson here
I'll give you my number right now it's a
local
number
865 ha
[Applause]
[Music]
it's nice
e that's the Gorilla Glue that's the
Gorilla
Glue take the rest of
that I was
saying Durban Poison I think is what
waiting for me when I go love the Durban
Poison I doo our friend BR it oh really
yeah he lives in Amsterdam he's an older
fellow in his 60s now
[Applause]
What's that
name Sam the skunk man they call
him he also bred skunk number one just
let it stay in your mouth hey you going
to hit these French guys behind
me
[Music]
Tony dab the French guys behind me yes
look nobody nobody knows here no Grill
cream that's funny a little dabble do
you yeah look at
that a little da hey Tony Tony look at
what her shirt says little do
you you're too young which one is
this you can use your hand as well if
you want
what want a piece of
[Music]
how you doing
man dude listen this is a legendary like
drum Master dud you got to hook him up
the next B is in the yard right so we
working for about hour can we go on and
watch that or what check it out so
Tony's just giving Bongo Herman a little
bit of uh of uh coconut oil extract for
for to rub on his skin this is cannabis
this plantus there's no alcohol there's
[Music]
no just
B all
right okay so another another dab
[Music]
[Applause]
on Facebook h on
Facebook oh no no Facebook no
[Music]
no tast
tangerine tast
[Applause]
how you do that how you do that
with a lot of
time Charles Charles up here real
quick uh no um
[Music]
that's
better me you do this just with
the I don't know you do
[Applause]
that let's go again here we go you want
me lighten up the Chalice with the power
wah light it up with
[Music]
here we go you're ready where you from
man from Winnipeg hey me too corn and
bread oh beautiful Winnipeg that's where
I'm from man from where Al me too Bowman
Avenue okay no [ __ ] peser peser come on
that's really that's like 15 blocks
away so he blew the water in so you
might have to go who did one guy come on
he blew the water in that's why you're
seeing the smarts but he's lucky he
didn't crack the
[Music]
quartz Jesus that's nuts
dude suck in
don't a little tip for
kides cuz he's going to go perform
soon
[Applause]
winnipeger's in the
[Music]
house he comes all the way out here from
Winnipeg yeah to get dabbed up by a
winnipegger yeah man pretty
funny
[Music]
[Applause]
it I know
[Music]
[Applause]
you know Kimo of course yeah you not the
guy that made the BS for the ice Ash I
did yeah I'm Gio's nephew oh okay I met
you out to Kimo's
place I put the band together for blue
Channel Jimmy
[Applause]
going fishing up up at our cabin that I
grew up at Co cool I'm bringing him in
this year in August August third oh
Wicked I'll try to be out there for that
either at nor city either at K or I just
mean out like I'm always in BC
okay okay right on you must know Chris
out here oh careful oh yeah Chris is
start no no no careful don't do that
that thing is this thing is so dangerous
ser
out you're heading out super good to
meet you man super good to meet you oh
it's just hitting it okay here he's
hitting it no no no no no no no no no
that's what I thought he's got a line
going I think here we
go what's he hitting
little Paris is in there
parish is in there nice rip Ste
bub Char good to meet you brother we're
on Bubble man's world you want to give a
shout out to Bubble man's world and uh
where can they see your
music yeah sh on YouTube
nice
[Music]
Rip's in the Z hey yeah right on
guys
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah do
it do you want to grab my phone number
yeah okay you got a phone
[Music]
I've never tried ganja before and I
thought this would be a good occasion I
think it's a great listen one time I had
a
guy listen dude I had a dude that looked
almost exactly like you a friend of my
friend Richard's from California who
owns dementia and he brought his buddy
over to my booth I think there's many of
me dude he
said he said I haven't smoked hash in 25
years but I think this might be a good
time start no no I [ __ ] you not we hit
him with one dab he fell straight back
like a board like like a board just boom
and then was like kind of shaking a bit
and then he opened his eyes and he got
up and he was kind of like he was like
wow that was that was an unbelievable
experence it was pretty funny to say the
least yeah man
865 it's a local number
you got it
86p 37 yeah you got it right this
is of course of
course what's burning it's not burning
it's steaming like a steam pipe it's
water hash made with water and ice use
water and ice get the resin off clean
Dum ready you got a pull I didn't get
any pull I BL in it BL in it last time
yeah
you were the one that blew whole part's
over if you do that yeah if you if you
blow water into it oh dude see that's
why we didn't want you touch know like I
just think it was blow you know what
Richie did that the first time so we
forgive yes he did do
that Mr spice he blew it right through
my mother ship and it actually actually
kst it at one time and it hit him in the
face the water that's how hard he blew
it
off we're going to make up for any
blowing you have going on there's no
need to blow man this is a game of
inhalation not
blowing hey are we selling some cake
now come on and some drink they got good
drink here
[Music]
too yeah but I activated for you inad
you taking the drops just take the one I
just showed you blue
one here this is ready for whoever's
hitting it I know you like the
drop Tony says I'm hitting it we no no
blowing no blowing all right once you
hit it you can blow whatever Direction
you want just don't blow through
this all right
[Applause]
[Music]
there we go that's a good rip