[Music]
myling
testing
[Music]
testing hi everybody good
morning how' we sleep last last night in
the fresh Mountain Air some whiffs of
weed floating
by nice I don't know I didn't sleep but
I'm glad you
did so we have Bubble Man up I've been
excited for this one that's a pleasure
hanging out with Marcus sometimes and
hearing some of these stories and
thinking man people need to hear these
stories we got to write a book or make a
movie or give bubble man his own panel
and do some story time so I'm really
excited to be able to give him that
opportunity I'm really excited for us to
hear some of this exciting history and
Rich culture of this plant and the
people that have been involved with it
for a long time and take it seriously or
passionate about it so please give me a
warm welcome for Marcus Richardson
bubble
[Applause]
man really really love
it I'll be dabbing honey bananas
today little Honey Boo Boo cross with
strawberry Nana from DNA
genetics it's so good it is so so good
almost need a third hand here but I'll
figure it out so yeah when Chay asked me
to speak this year I think we were
actually at antidote making some hash
together from his Sarah secret it was uh
that's another story but uh he asked me
hey you know if you want to what would
what would you want to speak about I I
don't ever plan my talks ever I've never
planned to talk just kind of come and
speak and so uh when he asked me you
know what what do you want to speak
about I thought you know what maybe I'll
just tell some cool
stories uh about my history and about uh
you know stories stories from the game
basically just kind of what we called it
before it got all corporate and legal it
was the
game anyway
um I got turned on to cannabis at 14
years old very similar to the scene uh
out of Half Baked with Dave Chappelle
when they're all young and they smoke
their joint and they're all giggling
that's when he's in the the the Super
Market store and he's like abaaba you my
only friend he's hugging the big Ababa
bar very similar experience with me and
my friends after we smoked our first
joint things escalated pretty quickly
for me after that first joint it seemed
like I don't know how much time went by
but before you knew it I was flipping
quarters and then ounces and you know
quarter pounds
and then I met this amazing man by the
name of Ron hickey and Ron hickey was
really you know outside of my father he
was one of my first mentors and he was
definitely my first Mentor in the game
Ron lives in the cies here in uh in the
cies in Proctor actually but he was
originally a Winnipeg guy and uh you
know for anyone that knew or knows Ron
an absolute Maniac Savage awesome person
and So within a very short period of
meeting Ron he started you know cuffing
me 10 packs like 10 pounds of weed at a
time this guy was a real character um he
did 11 years in Stony Mountain
penitentary for being a habitual florist
if you can imagine growing cannabis they
put him in prison with some of the most
dangerous people in
Canada he's got his own incredible
stories he should be here telling his
own stories because even what he did
while he was in prison and how many
stabbings he kept from happening using
cannabis to bring people together
instead of prison's a very divided place
by race more than gangs and so he really
brought people together in that way but
I met him very young I was probably 16
or 17 years old I had some some maybe 18
even I had some plants that were sick
and we went to his he had a hydroponic
store in the city this is a guy that did
six years in prison now he's got a
hydroponic store in the Bible belt in
Manitoba and I go there and ask him you
know oh I'm growing these tomato plants
and uh you know they're they're not
doing too good and he's and I'm like
literally probably look like I'm 12
years old and he's just like look kid I
know you're not growing tomato plants
why don't we just talk about what you're
growing this is like in
1992 or 93 this is very long time ago
very illegal you can get in a lot of
trouble he's just immediately has trust
starts telling me uh takes me down to
his basement actually and we start
dabbing oil he's got this crazy oil and
he's got hot knives and now we're
dabbing oil and he's telling me all this
crazy [ __ ] and he really brought me
under his wing took me under his wing
and allowed me to um to just be exposed
to the world of cannabis in a way that I
would have never been exposed Ron having
the only hydroponic store in the city he
basically set up everyone with their
grows and then what he would do is he
would go to each of those grows
throughout the day and help make sure
that they were all kind of being lined
up I'm going to hit this real
quick a moment of silence for the honey
bananas oh my God I wish I could share
this with all of
you maybe I will when we're done there's
not many of you we could pull this
off okay so I'll tell a few stories
about Ron one of the funniest stories
that I had with Ron was Ron was a real
wild man and there was just always the
craziest [ __ ] happening and so one day
he tells me I Got 5 gallons of
chloroform I'm like chloroform like like
the stuff you knock people out with he's
like yeah yeah the solvent chloroform
I'm like oo isn't that like super
illegal like are you even allowed to
have that he's like oh yeah it's super
they watch it super carefully and all
the bins have numbers and but I managed
to get some and I poured it out and then
I gave them back the empty so he's got
this chloroform and he says let's make
some oil out of chloroform I hear you
can make really good oil from chloroform
so we're we're in his house we're
soaking the weed in the chloroform and
we're we're doing the soak and we cooled
the chloroform we we froze like made it
very cold uh and then we put the
chloroform latent oil on like little
plates with a with a little hot plate
and a fan and was blowing this
chloroform oil out the back window of
his house about 20 minutes into this I
go
outside and and I see this big squirrel
and it's it's like dead like right by
the window I guess it got chloroformed
to death and so I you know Ron's a very
caring individual I tell him about this
he comes over he's basically crying he's
like oh my God oh my God I killed the
squirrel so we pick this thing up with a
shovel and we bring it into his house
and uh within 5 or 10 minutes this I I I
was like I think I saw it move I think
it moved wrong I think it moved and it's
sort of laying there with its its hands
up and it's little pinky is doing this
and then it's doing this and we're
watching it fairly
stoned and suddenly it comes to life
like 100% and starts tearing around his
house so now we're high on chloroform
Oil we're making chloroform oil we have
5 gallons of chloroform which I'm sure
at the time probably would have gotten
us like 5 years in prison just to have
that 5 gallons of Chlor form and we
ended up you know for about 40 minutes
chasing this scroll down it did some
pretty good damage to his house tore up
his couch which you know was just a
standard day I'll never forget his wife
Gail coming home and being like Ron what
happened oh we were making chlorop form
oil and we thought we killed the
squirrel and then the squirrel like tore
around the house and ripped up the couch
and the wallpaper and she was just like
okay like it was just the most normal
thing to her whereas most people might
think that that was a pretty insane uh
moment in time so that's what it was
like being with Ron every single day
that you were with him so a true Mentor
that really taught me that anything is
possible he was an incredible grower
still is a great grower really paid
attention to you know the flush and the
the giving plants love the intention you
know before I was exposed to it from you
know West Coast people dragonfly Earth
medicine is a perfect example of that
vibration of that like loving intention
Winnipeg wasn't like that we didn't have
a lot of that but Ron whether he knew it
or not he had that even though he
projected himself to the world to to be
very different than that that's what he
was really about uh and so he taught
that to me about cannabis and I you know
I'm very type A OCD much like Ron was as
well so we really clicked in that sense
I mean he's still uh one of my best
friends to this day uh love him dearly
wonderful man and really when people ask
me about my journey like how did you
become bubble man it started really with
Ron like Ron was the if I didn't meet
Ron I don't know if I would have ended
up on the same pathway that that I did
end up on with um here in in in the
canvas world so I'll just go through a
quick little history of these moments
with Ron you know just kept escalating
and he was facilitating all of this
exposure and all of this experience for
me to tap into from being at all these
different people's grows from seeing all
these different personalities and seeing
all the different things in those people
that weren't at the top of their game
projected and reflecting back to them in
their P plants through mites through
aphids through powdery mildew through
all of these different sicknesses that
the plants would have and you start
correlating them to these very specific
people cuz you know it was a very unique
experience to be able to go into 30 or
40 or 50 grows in a city in the '90s
where it was so highly illegal that
those people weren't even telling you
know their brother or their best friend
where their grow was and I was just
getting brought to all of them from Ron
you know Ron gave me Immediate street
cred with people that were like they
didn't know who I was I looked like I
was 12 and it probably made them very
very nervous growing cannabis in a city
where if you get caught you go to Stony
Mountain Penitentiary which is kind of
like the most extreme I we got to be
blessed for where we're at right now and
I know a lot of people complain about
the corporations and the the the
corporatization of cannabis and the over
regulations and all of this but it beats
being put in a cage for 10 years at a
time and it definitely beats being
pulled over at gunpoint on the side of
the road and taken and put in a cage
those things should have never happened
with cannabis so we do have to celebrate
the fact that we've gotten to a point
now where we can all enjoy cannabis
together at a beautiful Festival like
this and just uh give thanks be
grateful
um Ron sort of you know kept me going
down that pathway of like watching all
these people I I guess I didn't feel the
urge to grow as much of my own weed now
that I was spending you know 1215 hours
at a time Rah would come get me at like
7 or 8:00 at night and he'd drop me off
at like 10 or 11 the next morning we'd
just be going to grows all throughout
the night and he'd be helping them
figure out what was wrong with those
grows through that I ended up obviously
you know one of the best things Ron did
was he gave me cannabis of such a high
quality that suddenly people were like
that guy has good cannabis that guy over
there that guy Mark he he's got good
cannabis and so that's one of the
bonuses you know back back then Ron was
such an anomaly very few people grew
cannabis on the level that he grew it
and so having that also really bolstered
my ability to get into every group you
know from from high school what click
were you in oh I I don't know I wasn't
in a click I just sold weed to all of
them you know every click whichever they
were there's always weed smokers in each
of them and those are the ones that I
found I ended up eventually uh meeting a
pretty cool group of guys U Martin morav
Alex schi John guo Neil Chippendale
would be in there as well um in the
early days in Manitoba and we got it in
our heads as we were smoking cannabis
that we were going to try and get hemp
growing in our Province we sort of we
sort of started this was like 93 and we
start started doing research and finding
out that you know there are these
amendments in the drug and peace law
that was done back in like '
67 that if the THC is below. 3% 3 or
below that the classification of
marijuana would change to hemp and that
hemp would fall under a different set of
regulations that were not as stringent
so uh most of our supporters laughed at
us and told us we would get hemp growing
in the ground when hell freeze is over
but for those of you that have ever been
to Winnipeg know that a it is hell and B
that it absolutely does freeze over
every winter swear to God oh thank you
she hears my dry mouth my beautiful wife
of 35
years yes absolutely the
queen um so yeah we got into this whole
hemp activism thing we kind of realized
listen Winnipeg is not the place in 93
to be pushing the THC agenda or the
medical or the recreational all of ones
that we loved and believed in but we
thought we better come at this one from
a a far
angle and so we applied for hemp we
figured out a bunch of different things
long story short we basically got a
license an experimental license to grow
hemp in um 95 1995 we applied in '94 we
didn't get it that year there was only
two Canadians that got it that Year Joe
Strobel and Jeff Kim they were a tobacco
farmer and a lawyer from
Ontario but we ended up getting this
license and I'll never forget it because
we actually brought Ron to the field
when it was about 5 ft tall and we were
in my Volkswagen van and I drove him
right through the middle of the field
he'd only been out of prison for a while
but it brought tears to his eyes he
couldn't believe that we he was like
this looks like weed I'm like yeah it is
we sort of told a fib we sort of told
them that hemp was a distant cousin of
cannabis and uh because of that THC
percentage they um they accepted that
for whatever ever reason a lot of things
when it comes to regulation is not about
trying to make them see the light but it
is to speak the specific language that
unlocks the door that allows it to
happen uh and if you don't do that you
just you just bang your head against the
wall so we got this hemp license we grew
this hemp um I ended up moving away uh
to British Columbia soon after 96 uh my
wife and I we moved the west but my
partner kept at it and uh they built a
substantial thing with the hemp industry
in Manitoba they had a company called uh
Manitoba Harvest uh fresh hemp foods
which is you know the oil and the and
the seed that is available in all the
supermarkets that many of you have
probably purchased like that was a bunch
of just sort of stoned young teenager
guys sitting around dreaming a dream
that seemed impossible even to the
people who would share that dream with
us uh and we made it happen so it was uh
it was pretty incredible I moved out
west uh and linked up with the one
friend that I had out west I only really
knew one person uh and her name was
Hillary black and so she worked at hemp
BC uh for Mark Emory back in the day
and she was just really cool whenever we
showed up you know some of the other
people that work there kind of we we
just felt cuz we were you know Winnipeg
guys just these Prairie guys rolling in
we probably had strong Prairie accents
and just stuck out in a way that we
didn't realize we were sticking
out so we got a lot of the I'm too
school for uh I'm too cool for school
energy uh given back at us when we would
go to hemp BC cuz you know we you're
like we drive 25 hours to go to like
this this this
shop and um if no one cared it kind of
felt personal but Hillary cared and she
was always like y it's the wiip he hemp
guys what's up and we'd always have the
haze she's a big fan of the haze Ron of
course hooked me up with the haze that's
another
story um and so Hillary ended up uh you
know when I moved out to BC she was kind
of like in love with this guy Todd
McCormick and he was in Los Angeles
growing this huge in this huge mansion
um a big crop which was insane because
he was neighbors with Ronald
Reagan and uh no no it's it's worse they
got busted and so thank God Todd Hillary
wasn't there um but Todd did 5 years in
terminal Island um in
California um and he he's had cancer
multiple times and his spine is fused
together so he's like not that anyone
deserves to be in prison but it's harder
to be in prison when you have like
disabilities and you're and you're you
know somewhat [ __ ] up pardon my French
Renee B was also seen watering a plant
at that grow uh and they wanted to
extradite her she was up here in Canada
they wanted to put her in prison for a
mandatory minimum of 10 years because
they had one photo of her watering one
single cannabis plant out on uh the deck
at Todd's house so Hillary was trying to
figure out should I go live with Todd in
California or should I stay here in BC
and maybe you know she's like I have
this idea inspired by Valerie caral and
Dennis Pon and all the people that were
doing medical cannabis in California in
the early to mid 90s and Hillary was
like in fired by all of that she got
exposed to it through Grateful Dead
toour her and basically um was like I
want to start like a like a like a
dispensary you know but not a dispensary
and she'd be over at our house and I
remember her writing on a piece of paper
like these are the words I don't like
medical marijuana you know she went
through this whole list and then she's
like these are the words I do like
Cannabis Compassion and it became the BC
Compassion Club you know like boom I I
was one of the first Growers for the BC
Compassion Club uh and then through you
know my experience of selling cannabis
at the
time cuz I was pretty decent at it uh I
was able to help the club through that
experience I thought you know what what
I can do is when I'm out buying all this
cannabis I can kind of pull like small
lots of the nicest and just get it to
the club you know even at a loss because
it was like the Cannabis Compassion Club
started as
the most vulnerable people from our
society so there are the mentally ill
there are the homeless there are the
drug addicted and there are the
terminally ill and most of the time the
original members of the BC Compassion
Club checked all four boxes so these are
extremely vulnerable people no one in
their right mind was going to The
Compassion Club and being like like holy
[ __ ] I'm going to monetize this dude I'm
going to like I'm going to make so much
money selling weed to these people it's
not and so you know Hillary also for
many many many many years sort of
suffered the life of a popper because it
was always about helping these sort of
you know people that needed needed the
most help but that was an incredible
thing to be a part of um I was one of
the first medical cannabis court cases
for the BC Compassion Club I was coming
home with a little bit of flour really a
little bit compared to the day but 16 lb
or something and um I went through a
roadblock I think we might have also
been on mushrooms and it could have been
2 a.m. but that's neither here nor there
we went through this roadblock and to me
it seemed very set up and he had this
sort of you know clipboard and he was
letting cars through with without even
talking to them and then when I came up
he was like he just knew like I knew
someone had had had had
told um and so Hillary was like I'll be
testifying for you you know John Conroy
was my lawyer which was a completely
incredible experience um towards the end
or towards the middle John uh was being
asked by the lawyer and the you know his
the prosecutor and the judge what's a
good day for the next court case and the
and the his learned friend says uh oh
November 22nd uh such and such a year uh
98 I guess it was and John's like h no
your honor that won't be good for me
leans back into my ear and says because
I'll be going to the Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam with my client we were going
to Amsterdam together in November of
that year which we did and it was an
awesome trip stayed at the hotel Toren
next to the Anne Frank house but um yeah
so I ended up kind of going through that
whole court case the club was amazing
all the people at the club lots of
patients that I had known from day one
we're like coming I would send like a
school bus or a bus to go pick up any
people that wanted to come and show
support and then I would also like
donate flour just be like you know
here's an eighth or a quarter like just
every time they rolled up i' I'd give
them some flour because I knew how
important it was which we did also
through all the holidays and
whatnot but um ended up getting no fine
no time the judge ordered my money be
given back and the most intense part of
it was the prosecuting attorney who was
a total prosecutor cowboy boots like I
just he was just like the the the
Texan um prosecutor and John and him had
known each other for 25 years at this
point in time and at one point you know
this prosecutor comes up to the John and
tells him look so and so our good buddy
is in the hospital and is dying of
cancer and after listening listening to
this whole case which was all about the
medical use of cannabis and why it
should be accessible which is why when
medical cannabis was allowed and they
didn't bust them all that the judge said
in my case if we're going to allow
medical cannabis then we can't expect it
to fall from the sky like Mana it has to
come from somewhere and this is what
opened up
transportation of medical cannabis in
Canada this court case so yeah no fine
no time judge ordered my money be given
back I did catch a felony for it which I
got scrubbed years later um but I never
looked at it as a negative I thought you
know what this was incredible work that
Hillary did I felt blessed to just be
allowed to be a part of that work that
she was doing and once I got busted I
couldn't really sell weed anymore even
though I probably could have but to me
the way I knew the game it was like nah
I can't really do this anymore it's like
the maybe I'm a heat scorer maybe maybe
maybe they're watching me I don't know
right in the end they weren't and I
could have probably kept doing it but
instead I had to come to a Crossroads I
was really good at something and able to
make money doing it but now I couldn't
do it at all cold turkey and I had to
figure out another way to maintain
paying for the lifestyle that I had
acquired which was very different from
the one I grew up in Winnipeg so this
was like okay I got to get out there and
I got to figure this out and so I had
heard about this B system a two bag a
two bag water hash system from Amsterdam
I'd seen it actually um and I thought
wow you know what I could sell that I
could sell that system and so I went to
Amsterdam uh and I met with the woman
who I thought at the time who had
created this bag system in fact she was
just selling the bag system I would
learn the true history later through an
insane 5year long um patent lawsuit but
basically I went to Amsterdam tried to
get into selling these bags for her but
kind of rubbed her the wrong way that
day I don't know if you know a lot of
Dutch people especially ones that own
coffee shops but they deal with a lot of
Americans and sometimes at the end of
the week they've dealt with too many and
it's like they're intense and so she
kind of like lashed out on me I was
there to buy like 500 to a th000 of
these two bag kits and I I came home
super bummed cuz I was I really thought
this is what we can invest the little
bit of money that we have left and start
a whole company with and uh I came home
devastated and my wife was like why
don't we just make our own and I was
like what do you mean make our own she's
like yeah we could just sew them and you
could just sell them and so that was the
birth of fresh headies and bubble bags
and that's really where I chose the
silly moniker bubble man to promote this
concept and I don't know maybe there's
people here that don't know what bubble
bags are that scares me if you if you
don't but I'll tell you it's just a
simple bag system with screen bottoms
that allow you to use water and ice to
isolate the resin glands from the plant
to create a very very concentrated pure
pure pure version of
hashish and we had great great luck with
uh with that company and with the whole
process uh going online and selling it
creating an online business in like 99
2000 like right when that sort of scene
started it was like digital cameras were
just coming out online uh services to
take credit cards everything was sort of
colliding simultaneously for a lot of
different people to Pivot and switch
into you know web-based business and we
created this company and uh Wow Bubble
Bags really took off it was uh it was
mindblowing how much it took off and
what how how it just
changed everything like suddenly and and
I'll tell you the whole reason I wanted
to do that was because I saw John Conroy
take a paper bag full of money that if I
had gotten pulled over with it like 5
minutes earlier they would have been
like this is proceeds of crime he takes
that paper bag he goes to the bank and
just gives it to them because he's a
respective lawyer and they just cash
that money into his bank and I'm like
holy [ __ ] so instead of selling weed to
get money
I could sell something that people use
with weed to get money but I'm not
involved in the weed part of it and that
was another part of bubble bags I
thought if I can get money cuz here's
the thing even during a recession people
who sell weed are still making money
people who have weed money are like yeah
I'll buy some bubble bags for 300 bucks
like [ __ ] I want to make some hash yeah
I'll buy a Tumblr I'll buy a you know
like people who are deep into cannabis
have all the toys have all the tools if
you will and so I figured well this is
if I can create a tool and it's not that
we created it but we definitely
pioneered and bettered it two bags
weren't enough we have an eight bag
system now and the way it came about was
just uh it was just all of that timing
colliding simultaneously me getting
busted and it really led me to believe
too that um when you're manifesting your
future they always say oh it'll come in
ways you least expect it it's like so
many people spend enormous amounts of
time and energy manifesting a future
that they allow to pass them by because
they're so stuck on recognizing what
that manifestation should look like they
think it's an opportunity but it almost
always represents itself as an obstacle
at first and so for me to be able to go
through a roadblock years later and see
Constable John low the guy that busted
me with the Compassion Club weed and to
thank him and be like dude I I am not
upset with you in any way literally like
you helped change and pivot my life I
think I might have given him one jab I I
think I might have said there are
literally tons of hashes being made all
around the world thanks to
you yeah tons so I don't know uh how
much more time I have left that kind of
leads me uh it's 11:55 is anyone
organizing this at all or should I just
talk for a little bit longer yeah yeah
all right we'll keep talking I'll keep
going for a bit um so yeah and Bubble
Bags just by 2002 from 99 to 2002 it was
a Hustle but by
2003 it was substantial it was like
money coming in bags going out and more
importantly and I'll tell you another
time that I that it was pivotal for me
that I really knew that this was going
to be serious was one of my first
customers was a woman from Indiana and I
mean this is 99 do you know how illegal
cannabis is in Indiana in 1999 like it
is go to prison time let me tell you so
she's like this like Middle America
Church woman like just very straight and
very just like she's like I saw your
ad I don't I'm not sure that what I if I
understand it correctly but basically
what you're tool can do is make a
purified medicine with with with
marijuana she said and so I said yes
basically and so she bought a small set
of
bags her father was very sick he was 86
years old and he had wasting syndrome so
he weighed a very very very very like 87
LBS or something kind of what you weigh
right before you pass
away and so she had heard that cannabis
and I think she even saw it on a movie
or something like the munchies and kind
of like why would they make that joke
well cuz when you eat when you smoke
cannabis it gives you the munchies right
this is the generalization doesn't give
me the munchies but everyone's different
um so don't let me lose where my train
of thought was
going Indiana yes thank you um
Harvard Indiana woman um so she buys the
bags she sends me this crazy letter like
this is how long ago this was right she
sent me a letter and she a handwritten
letter and basically said told me this
whole story she said look I went I was
like out on the streets buying like an
ounce of marijuana I was so terrified so
she gets this weed she goes home she
bought her bubble bags in
99 she's like more advanced than most
hardcore cannabis users in the country
and she has no relationship with it
whatsoever she has the love of her
father and the worry of losing him and
so she she makes him the bubble I don't
know if she dried it properly or what
not but she put it in his corn cob pipe
this is how old this [ __ ] was he
had a corn cob
pipe and he puffed this bubble and then
she's like and he ate a whole McCain's
chocolate cake that night which is
hilarious but it's also what you did
it's also like oh oh right it's both of
those things and I think I reacted both
of those ways when I read the letter I
was like holy [ __ ] that's crazy this is
like I just thought it would be cool to
let people smoke great hash but there's
implications that go deeper into this
right which is that
whole Compassion Club relationship of
because cannabis has sort of two sides
there're this recreational which I
really call
recreational preventative it's the the
preventative medicine and then there's
the medicinal which is more serious
usually when Once people are like really
focused on cannabis as a medicine
they're fairly sick you know and that's
what I hope to see change in the future
where we don't have to wait till we have
stage three colon cancer to decide to
take cannabinoids there's sort of this
way that you can use it as a
preventative and I mean in my opinion
you know I was watching TV the other
night cuz my wife and I are staying at a
hotel and we saw these Pharmaceutical
commercials with like the most insane
side effects and I thought holy [ __ ]
imagine the only side effect cannabis
has is the feeling of
euphoria getting high like that is the
greatest medicine ever so yeah it's um
it's been it's been great to me
throughout these last 30 years of my
life it's been really cool to be allowed
to be in a position where we were this
Catalyst for hash making around the
world and um it's it's it's something
that I've been passionate about for a
very long time um I do a party called
Legends of hash I used to do it in
Amsterdam for many many years and I've
done it in Barcelona and I've done it in
Vancouver and even did one in Jamaica
but now we do them in Los Angeles and uh
they're really um a bridge to the
old um history of hashish and you know
paying homage to how that came about and
understanding these different places
that people went to use and smok cashish
and how different cultures grow and
collect and smoke cashish and sort of
paying homage to that but at the same
time bringing in the new and showing
this new methodology of like what we can
do when we increase that science of
extraction and isolation to get you know
these things that really didn't exist 50
to to 60 years ago that that now do
today so so um yeah that's kind of one
of my ways to pay back annually have a
really great party 300 350 people
hashish is the focus for the entire
party and there's a little competition
in there as well that people do and sort
of always enjoy that it's it's it's a
good time hopefully one day we'll be
able to bring it back to British
Columbia I guess in the
meantime I don't know if I have anything
else to
say I I think that's
it thanks
everybody thank you
[Music]
Chay
I
[Music]
saw that