[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
just a short little clip here today on a
beautiful afternoon I wanted to show you
just a few of my plants my mom's as well
as some mixed in they're going to go
into the next bloom potentially with the
lush XL Dominator like that I have on
the way shoutout to Kingston herb and
the kind people at lush for setting that
up we're gonna be doing a side-by-side
comparison and I'm hoping some of these
babies right here will end up in that
comparison what we're gonna do is have
the lush on one side and HPS on the
other side or potentially two separate
tents we'll see what happens anyway
wanted to show you guys what we got
going here today so we've got Metis
heyis this is just a little guy a little
bit bigger of an astro boy another Medi
haze from mr. John her fellow and what
else we got we got Haas the Hayes
crossed with the og crossed with the
skunk man I'm looking forward to
checking out the ha she's real nice next
to that we've got the East Coast Sour
Diesel stretching out like nothing I've
ever seen very very crazy long stretches
with nothing from the stalk where I cut
it all the way up to 6 plus inches
before there's growth sites keep cutting
her down next up we have another Medi
Hey so I've got three mini Hayes's that
are gonna be going into balloon should
be interesting to see what she produces
right next to the mini haze you see this
bush which I've yet to really trim down
and that is a sweet skunk this one I did
manage to spin down trim down this is
the Barbra bud and I've really trimmed
her down nicely and that is the original
Barbra bud that Matt the great gardener
gave me on the video there right next to
that is his Afghani nice little Afghani
a little side branch coming off there
these fats talk on that Afghani
Congolese
he's Bush on the Congo looking really
forward to flowering some con goes out
and then up here we have House of the
great gardener Afghani another sweet
skunk the one that I've posted on my
Facebook account the last couple of
times just really loving the petite miss
of this plant how it's almost bonds I'd
getting ready to go big
Barbara bud so this will be the first of
the Barbara buds and the size of the
leaf on a tiny plant like that you know
give you an idea of the size of that
thing and finally last but certainly not
least we have the 20 year old Jamaican
triploid so as you can see on this
Jamaican we have a triploid right here
we have this leaf we have this leaf and
we have this leaf all coming off the
base stem instead of a two leaf we're
rocking a triploid so that's always very
exciting to get that one two three I'm
sure you guys can all see it and that is
the Jamaican lamb's Red Cross from 1995
you can see another mutation in this
leaf here as we lift the leaf you can
see more leaf underneath it it's a bit
of a strange mutant but yeah so back
over the babies
all the different leaf structures what
can I say
I'm super excited to get these plants
all mothered out for future clones and
the ones that are going into the tent
I mean I'm super excited to check out
the possibilities between the led the
HPS the metal halides and everything in
between I'm looking forward to growing
resin for the resin production I want to
show you guys the profiles I want to
show you guys the melt factors and just
learn a bunch of new things as we're
doing it so stay tuned
keep watching bubble man's world and
we'll talk to you next time
[Music]