hey how's it going there facebookers uh
yeah just been posting a bunch of
pictures today of uh melty bubble people
have really been stoked on seeing the
pictures of bubble so I figured uh well
maybe we'll do a little video of
sublimating some so I just pull out a
little little little bit here and dump
her into the
sublimator now generally for the
sublimator to give an instant rip you
want to have the wand on top of the bowl
that heats the bottom of the bowl up and
that way when you put the uh material in
there it's it's ready to go but I've got
my sublimator turned on hot enough that
it should still give a nice milky hit
let's check it out
[Music]
it was a little slow going there when
the supplim gets hot enough it'll just
milk right up but still that t that hit
was super
tasty Pi another one
[Music]
all
right number two generally I would only
get probably one hit from a hit like
that in the bong but sublimator usually
gives me four or five
[Music]
one of the things I really like about
the sublimator is
uh lifting the wand you can put hash or
cannabis in there but you can also dab
your solventless oils in these little
dots here in these little holes that the
sublimator comes with so often
uh after you know five or six
hits I can usually squeeze out a really
nice little blob of oil which I got one
on this nail here and then it's just a
simple as dropping
that into the hole and taking the hip
[Music]
so there we have it it's one of the many
reasons why the sublimator is superior
to all vaporizers that I've ever
smoked cannabis hash and oil all
effortlessly all non-stop anyway bubble
on we'll see you soon