[Music]
hey guys welcome to the bubble man's
world I'm here with Brett from West
Coast concentrate and
from the sunrise Wellness Center
lots of traffic actually
very loud anyway DOM and Mac so the guys
were met the other day after Steve's
apartment they showed us the beautiful
water hash from concentrated X and so
we're coming down here today to pick
some up to walk through the their new
location here and really just to check
it out so you guys want to come with us
what's going
yeah busy corner yeah
just looking to uh get some medicine
[Applause]
I saw this as we came in and this is an
absolutely crucial piece in any cannabis
enthusiast or cannabis activists or
cannabis aficionado if you're in any of
those categories jackers you know number
one best-selling book of all time the
authoritarian historical record of
cannabis and the conspiracy against
marijuana and how hemp can save the
world the Emperor wears no clothes this
was a huge inspiration to me as a young
activist in Manitoba and it was really
the book that we got hemp growing
legally for the first time in over
seventy three years in our province so I
gotta go show those to that book
yeah that's amazing this is a great book
this is nice to see so why don't we head
in
you see we're in the clubs of course
this is Dawne you guys we met him just
the other day and
obviously the flavors he shared with us
were good enough that here we are a
couple of days later sharing any of that
so tell us a little bit about your spot
here how long have you guys been here
well welcome back to sunrise we're
almost about a year and a half a little
bit more
we opened up just to think July first
rate around cannabis day
it's be fun moving around since there
was about 40 dispensaries and other
tools 200
thank you trying to regulate it and
bring it back down so they get numbers
closer to what it used to be
going on there
yeah they certainly are so it seems like
you guys kind of have a special niche
just from walking in right away it seems
like you're kind of going for a quality
perspective absolutely you're not gonna
find 80 different strains here we try
and carry a smaller menu that ranges
from 20 to 40 different strains we try
and work with the same group of vendors
like very small group of vendors so we
have a good good idea of how they grow
things their standards their their
practices kind of ensure that they're
not using you know plant growth
regulators and other crazy different
things you definitely don't want any
medicine sure so we end up with a menu
that has more quality over quantity
we've got some stuff in the temple of K
Lakes we've got some stuff from humble
meds AC cypress we've got a pretty
pretty large salt on this menu in town
here as well we're looking to get some
West Coast concentrates on in the next
week here so stay posted keep checking
the Leafly
you'll find we've got some awesome
strawberry-banana from concentrated X
that you saw on house church the other
day you may have seen on Bubba Matt's
Instagram oh it's love that was locked
up that one's still sealed that's a
sealed mobile meds in ceramics see some
awesome an awesome macro photos of it
we'll put some over top of the video
when I so callously grab the container
we've also got some Golden Bear extracts
they are from up in Whistler they do
some really nice stuff they got some
true pink which I'll show you here
that's the true pink 90
that person I think we do
very cool you've done a video with them
actually okay yeah yeah yeah that's what
I thought
pretty close there
and then sometimes we can give it a
little
counter he looks like one this local yes
very nice well I definitely was the
solvent list that got me that put you on
my radar
it's so easy to speak so that's usually
what we reach for when we're reaching
into our Twitter honestly we do smoke
pho we do you smoke all that kind of
stuff but I find that the solvent list
whether it be public how much dry sift
or rosin it just works better for me it
gives me where I need to be with less
and with the added to side effects you
get from solvent extractions beautiful
did you want to walk us through a couple
of these beautiful graphics so I just
pulled out the borrower different ones
that we haven't seen before
Romulan Mikado by the temple of calyx
this is actually a biodynamic
example so they do total living soil
it's really cool too Romulan cross
Mikado which are two
Federation seeds crossed together mm-hmm
very nice kind of grapefruit nose to a
real head ringer of a sativa effects
real upfront the forehead
The Mikado always reminded me of breeder
Steve's grapefruit mm-hmm
next up we have a orange tangi by Tara
farms they're uh they're local producer
here in Vancouver as well mm-hmm believe
they they placed in the harvest harvest
moon cup with their lemon lime this is a
new breeding project that they've been
working on and it's kind of similar to
many of the Tanja's you see down in the
states it's got this really awesome
tangerine orange flavor it's very Cali
oh it took to me
hang me back end I guess I guess tangina
scaleo cross with
I wouldn't know but maybe this I should
know some reason I'm pretty sure he's
good men Sam said on how she acts the
other day so I was that was where I was
remembering from so yeah that has a very
nice you know that very when you rose
and then it's like orange custard it's
crazy delicious beautiful
next up we have the high rise Master
Kush by heavenly days only this heavenly
days definitely does some very nice nice
strains and concentrates in town here
this high rise is just unbelievably
strong very thick
smoke and
tasty and just super dank it looks
pretty tanky
last but not least next up we have a
blue god and that's by humble meds
really nice just kind of a I you know
I've seen this a lot NBC growing up it's
kinda reminds me of when I was a
teenager and it's just got that really
homey kind of smell to it kind of it's
hard to describe it so it's like
Christmas I'll tell you the color of the
pistol it the stigma hairs to me are
very reminiscent of a string that we
used to have called the poo pee oo h and
it was like like this is going back to
the 90s now but
it looked a lot like that
there's sweet smell
yeah that's a nice smell to it for sure
nice candy cane yeah
great canister be nice and hash yeah
it's it doesn't rosin nice I haven't
probably yeah I wouldn't do it we've
noticed that the god rosin he's
beautiful
well beautiful man it's nice to see that
there's a selection available so do you
guys do mail orders well we do currently
do the order just across Canada just
across Canada - valid and on PR
Edison PR but at not Mme you have an old
enemy or we will still honor it as well
okay okay so covered under the
injunction but for those of you that are
going to be asking me in this video if
you are able to order this up I guess
the next thing would be to say what
website you can reach us at
WWE I see you excellent well there you
have it guys if you wanted to taste some
of these fine resins that we've been
enjoying or dip into some of the fine
flowers here at the sunrise wellness
foundation it's it's on point my
spider-sense isn't going off I feel
pretty good about this place I gotta say
so thanks for walking us through every
we appreciate it I see how Horatio's
transdermal balm and his la gentleman
here as well yeah we've got a really
great range of medical products as well
whether it be teachers capsules no
edibles unfortunately because the City
of Vancouver won't allow it hopefully
they change that right but you can
usually get it done with textures and
capsules
Phoenix tears appointments with no way
to get around the edibles safe for you
to be just the same way your sonís would
be for you to sell tubs of coconut oil
extract yep absolutely could either cook
with or just eat and consume this long
as it's a prepackaged cooking oil we can
sell so next thing we've got something
so honey's here yeah those are kind of
classified as like honey changers okay
so they are you know there is a little
bit of sway with what they define
they just don't want confectionery and
baked goods yeah anything that looks
appealing to children yeah mm-hmm
totally well much appreciated event I
really
thanks for walking us through and you
guys out there in both man's world if
you want to check this place out
here
okay so what's the
really
cool
[Music]