[Musique]
pr why the Tim rock feel really good
give
[Musique]
man the thats
me the purpose the
the by
[Musique]
this is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of well I've been traveling to kingst 20
miless seping on j like the clock fres
vegation with trees and
flowers give me
B
don't give me one
[Musique]
and
and the thats
me the of
[Musique]
the by
this
the purpose of
the
the is not to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time I imagine the ro be
somestinging traps man
US
me in
my
[Musique]
and
i uses
[Musique]
W
foral to maintain my
focus we got many different kind of
herbs
I'm
gluc bronchtis
thec King Jama we got many different
kind
of I'm n I'm do I'm pr I'm
preach and a
[Musique]
reality go do your research and see
I more one reason
[Musique]
Seas
medAlp
the main
myocususe one
reason to maintain my
focus use her for medicinal
purp use the her
[Musique]
to
depr anxiety
relief breeding dis like
Asma strengthen the body's immune system
it produce longevity and long life and
long life and long life and I use
her one
reason use
the every
season the her for medicinal
purpose use the her to maintain my
focus I use the
herbs
reason I use the
herbs every
season use the herb for medicineal
purpose I use the earth to maintain my
focus
[Musique]
Jess
royal
kind of like
say
[Applaudissements]
igifij
marijuana
let just
[Musique]
SH we didn't get here
this is
awesome I think shot
is it is
but
last
sh
[Applaudissements]
[Musique]
party be even better
al are you
ro
go to
school people
and and if you don't love the en
you
200 been
[Musique]
ni
I got here
actually oh yeahet it was cloudy
actually it was
interesting
like right behind a cloud and then I
don't know if it was like reflecting on
the water back us
or
like the horizon for a few minutes
all
an
[Applaudissements]
but given
[Musique]
you
different
lel
i love
that I
know
[Applaudissements]
[Musique]