[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am sitting out on my deck today because
For the First Time in about a month it
is beautiful and I do mean beautiful I'm
not just sitting out in a T-shirt shirt
it's actually t-shirt weather it's got
to be 12 to
15° Celsius I don't know what that is in
Fahrenheit but by all means Google it
translate it figure it out it's got to
be 60° maybe 70 I don't know probably
not quite 70 anyway I thought uh I was
on my way home and I saw some beautiful
waterfalls and some beautiful ocean
front and I saw a Cypress Mountain and I
thought I need to make a video I'd love
to be hitting all these spots and of
course I didn't hit any of those spots
but here we are beautiful day you can
hear the melt in the background and you
hear the water running through the E
system of the house tons of snow down in
my front yard still but turning into
liquid quickly so I of course have the
new Mothership pickup give thanks to
high integrity glass art for the drop as
always uh for all your Mothership needs
here in British Columbia beautiful
little um you know sand blasted frosted
if you will mini uh with the new style
thick big beef cake ofz which fits on
just
beautifully um smoking a little bit of
MK Ultra bubble hash from the West Coast
concentrate boys and I really like um
the base of this particular rosin
doesn't have a very like overly strong
flavor to it like sometimes the MK Ultra
can very cushy so it's a good base for
me to be able to hit all these wonderful
tpin that I have from Blue River so a
gift from Tony uh the lemon tree not
carrying that one up on my website
unfortunately but all the rest from the
starg to the
Clementine to the Jack Frost to the
Tangi and we're on to the last two
Sunset sherbet and last but certainly
not least the three times crazy which is
I think what we're going to be dipping
right now a little bit of the three
times crazy clean this Dabber make sure
it's as clean as clean can be one thing
about the glass Dabber give it a wipe
each time I don't want any little
microscopic hairs or remnants of
anything that's non- resin non-
glandular on the end of this thing so
got a nice little dab
here get that it's pretty cold out here
so even bending this dab around the
Dabber and yes I will use my fingers
because it is my dab after all don't
need to have gloves for my own dab get a
nice big dip of the three times crazy on
there and we're going to go to town get
this up get that
opened and get this torch
going and as always what comes in handy
when you're using these quartzes a lot
of people ask how long do you heat it
for how do you know how long to heat it
for well I just follow the time you know
I heat it up for a certain amount of
time with the torch and once it gets to
that time I stop
I think my torch might even be dying
right
now it's hard to tell yeah it's dying
all right I'll be right
back all right so we got the torch
stopped and now we're going to take a
lovely lovely rip through this uh Frost
little mini it's got a real nice hit to
it I've hit it probably about a half a
dozen times so far shared it even on the
channel I just love the little size you
know 5.5 in looks so nice in the Sun and
just feels great you know like even
between the fingers it feels solid it's
uh we were talking today at the cchq
when we had it down we were hitting it
without touching it and we realized that
it doesn't even really tip when you put
your mouth on to it it doesn't have much
of a tip at all so it's pretty sweet
pretty
sweet all
right another 5 seconds and we're good
to go here we go
nice puddling in effect there got a nice
puddled out
rip and the beauty of that is that it
really cleans nicely with the Q-tips and
once you
uh yeah once you get in
there you can do a real nice job on
cleaning and that to me the you know
that whole not that I'm religious but
cleanliness is Godliness statement is uh
somewhat true to me keep your stuff
clean much more
enjoyable each rip give it a nice clean
no matter who's hitting it always give a
nice fresh
clean and uh I guess that's about it I
just really wanted to share a bowl with
you guys share a little bit about a
little of the sunshine and The View with
you and uh keep watching Bubble man's
world subscribe if you can share the
videos if you can and give us a like if
you enjoyed this one and if you're one
of the few people that I've had to block
walk from the channel cuz you're a
sociopathic maniac and you've continued
to register names and come back just to
give us thumbs down May the full m bless
your bowl sooner than later peace out
everybody
[Music]