[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world uh
just figured I'd come smoke a bowl with
some of my online YouTube followers uh
also the Instagram and Facebook people
always uh happy to answer your questions
I see a lot of questions coming in all
the time so I'm trying to answer them
and uh get videos done in regards to
particular questions that you guys asked
but uh today today's video is just about
enjoying a beautiful sunset so I figured
we'd load up the
mothership many of you probably
recognize the view I've taken quite a
few pictures of this particular pipe
here that view
background today instead of taking a
picture I thought let's make a
video so made some really exceptional
bubble the other day just loading that
video up right now uh with John we did
the fresh Frozen whole plant extract it
was absolutely phenomenal you'll see
that video coming up real soon but for
now have a nice sunset here we
go
[Music]
she's going down beautiful
sunset
we'll talk to you
soon