[Music]
[Applause]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my open wi the sun was up in my face the
wisdom of the wi keep my straight with
the S
[Music]
try to Perfection smoke synic I love
theet Founders we get the
fulling I
love when the rest consume the
meditation to CB1 and
tb2 can have n receptors in the brain
and body happiness for me and you you
got the T
[Music]
Dan
fin try to Perfection
smity I love the
street get
the I
love m e d i c a l medical cannabis with
the sick patient
m a d i c a l
can can make it I can do without the SP
let's up many many and then we are to
all the organic farmers I'm a
smity I love the
street we get
the I love the street
[Music]
s sweet
blessed love to we stud about Tri see we
don't know we don't Tri is already so
our assignment for this week is endo
cannaboid system get that done ABC bomb