[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh it's been a bit since I actually
mentioned anything about my garden I'm
uh just in the middle of chopping down a
little Astro Boy so the Astro Boy here
give you an idea of the quality of this
nugget is quite
nice very very nice nugget um it's been
growing for N9
weeks really nice smelling as Astro Boy
always is I've got my screen out I've
got one nugget already here trimmed
lovely I've also trimmed about a plant's
worth here and I've got another
plant and a bit right here so just sort
of wanted to go over the quickness of
how I prepare um my plants for washing
of course usually I cut them down fresh
do a fresh frozen these have actually
been hanging for a few days and I do
notice already just a little bit of a
difference even in how the resin feels
to touch so I basically just do a quick
snippety snip and remove fan leaves you
know when you're washing the resin off
of the plant you want the resin to stay
on there you don't want to cut it off
like the way you would uh you know for
if you were smoking just the buds I
understand that you want to remove all
that plant matter as possible I just
take it a step further and I say leave
all the plant matter so you can take it
all off with the
bags so boom
boom
boom and a
and about three more
booms just getting them right down to
nice manageable size
buds this will make for an easier
extraction now I also Sav the stock the
Stock's completely sticky and covered in
lemon lemon type smelling um tpin those
tpin are inside glandular triome heads
so why would we get rid of them so I'll
actually do um this is of course not
going to be a first run by any means
this is fan leaves and stock everything
in here will be just butt and then I
have a small pile of uh just the small
trim Leaf but I I don't get very much of
it because mostly I leave it all on for
the bud
run so this is the Astro Boy I had uh I
think I have three four plants of the
Astro Boy total this crop uh downstairs
in the tent I still have medic Kush My
Little Pony an
Afghan and I believe a
Hos number 10 hos number 10 from Mr
Burell so that's all exciting I kind of
uh I should probably leave those medy
kushes or medy hazes and the My Little
Ponies um however it is getting to a
point where I have to go away again I do
have N9 to 10 plants already prepped and
ready for the plant uh for the for the
tent and one of those is actually uh a
couple of them actually are the jamaan
so I'm
fairly interested in getting those out
so I may very well chop the medy haze
and the My Little Pony Even though it I
guess it's probably potentially about a
week to two weeks what you would
consider early for that particular
strain um I only have a few plants I'm
going to be running running them for
hash anyway and like I've mentioned
before that you know sometimes you can
affect the profile by cutting it early
or late and it's not necessarily a
negative uh effect so sometimes you want
to try it this is going to be one of
those trimes that I believe I'm going to
try it so I'll keep you guys informed as
to what goes on with
that and uh yeah I'll also keep you guys
informed with what goes in exactly to
the tent cuz I had it written down
somewhere I don't see my book anywhere
but I had written down all the different
strains that I have ready right now and
there's about nine or 10 of them and I
I'm not sure if there's an East Coast
Sour Diesel in there and a congales and
some Jamaicans and maybe even a northern
lights but it's a nice selection
nonetheless it's not everything I have
obviously just nine plants ready to go
so we'll uh keep you informed of that as
it
happens and once again this plant uh was
flushed for four jeez about five five of
the nine weeks that it was growing I
just
decided pretty much less than a month in
even to just start watering it and the
plant never really turned yellow so it's
quite
nice that medy
one OG flavors simple very simple simple
feeding product one part uh it's very
low in PH so when you when you dump it
into an eight or a 7 pH water uh you're
looking down at 3 to 3.5 so a little bit
of pH to bring it back up to that 6.2 to
6.8 perfect sort of cannabis friendly pH
and that's how this was grown basically
in that tent under 2600 wet light
bulbs uh Nano Lux were the
ballasts secret jardan were the tents so
yeah I'm really really quite happy with
how it all turned out especially for a
summer crop um Summer's always harder as
you guys know the bugs like to move in
in summer uh you can get heat issues you
can get me DS you can get all these
different things um aside from the
smallest smallest amount uh I saw a
little bit of white flies uh just on the
bottom and I
just just had the hint of a might or two
so I'm really glad that I safer soap
these before I put them into flour uh
knowing that summertime these bugs just
come out of nowhere and so that was good
I'm looking forward to cleaning the tent
right out once I cut those medy hazes
and my little ponies down as well as the
hos and The Afghani The Afghani looks so
good and I'm telling you it
smells almost identical to Old School
Romulan Romulan from Romulan Joe back in
the days of the Compassion Club you know
I hear so many people talk about that
strain and I don't remember any of them
being around back then I used to get the
herb from Joe himself I would trade him
my own Dutch Treat that I was growing
for the club I would trade him an ounce
or 2 ounces for an ounce or 2 ounces of
his herb and I remember that Romulan
very very well I've been looking for it
for a long time I am really really under
the belief now after getting the uh The
Afghani from the great Gardener that the
Romulan if it wasn't that Afghan it was
definitely an afghan that Pine py
incredibly piny taste that the uh
Romulan was so well known for uh really
shines through in Matt's uh Afghan cut
I'd love to uh ask him and find out more
about the lineage of that Afghan where
he acquired it and uh you know to follow
it back as far as possible obviously
it's an Afghani it comes from
Afghanistan but uh it's always nice to
know the story who got it when did they
go there where did they collect it you
know the more we can know about this
stuff to me the better I'm I'm uh I'm
always interested interested in
it so I'm just going to continue on here
cutting this Bud up I wanted to share a
little bit of it with you um I'll try to
get some macro shots of the living resin
on some of these buds I've got some in
the fridge already that I'm uh freezing
and uh you know who knows hopefully
we'll see a little batch of fresh frozen
come our way uh sooner than later I do
leave for Jamaica in a couple of days
here going back to work on the project
there um hopefully I'll get a batch off
before that so yeah thanks for watching
Bubble man's
world hey guys I just wanted to show you
that I'm done chopping up those plants
I've got two large bags of Bud um um
maybe 100 150 g of dry product and then
I've got myself all the stocks that I
chopped and all the fan leaves in these
two bags here so four half PB bags
pretty stuffed to the brim I'll be able
to Fresh Frozen um the buds wash them uh
do a couple of runs get a good chunk of
bubble like a 10 to 12% return and then
I'll be able to take that material and
I'll pre- soak that in a coconut oil
extract even though it's lower quality I
can still offer it uh to friends to
myself uh when I don't want to eat a
more powerful or maybe if I just want to
use it as a salv and then these two as
well the stocks and the fan leaps and
the small trim I'll be turning that into
a coconut oil extraction as well and uh
yeah I've got this one little bud now
I'm going to go I'm going to take macro
photographs of it for you and I'm going
to leave you guys with a little macro
slideshow so
enjoy
[Music]
oh I use the herbs for more than one
reason I use the herbs you want every
season
I from medal
purpose I use the Earth to maintain my
focus King we got many different kind of
hers
gluc bronchitis the
cancer a king Jamaica we got many
different kind
of I'm s nurse I'm s doctor I'm s priest
I'm s
preacher and it's a
[Music]
reality go do your research and see as I
use hers more than one
reason I use the hers throughout every
season I use the hers for medicine and
purpose I use the Earth to maintain my
focus
[Music]
use