[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome on this fresh Sunday after
hash Church to my little grow that I got
going on here I've just got my three
little plants going right now I'll show
you the healthiest of the three is the
Astro Boy and so I've given it one
little pinch so far since Johnny B
brought it to me uh it was in darn near
perfect shape I believed when I first
got it and then I noticed the tiniest
tiniest little bit of powdery mildew
which I clipped off and I gave the
plants a little bit of a hydrogen
peroxide soak you see this one is The
Afghani grow nice and stocky and
nice and
healthy so and then I'll finally I guess
I'll show you the Barb so here's the
Barbara so he she's the smallest of the
three but she's catching up and just
started to I haven't pinched her yet I
noticed the other two the minute I
pinched them the growth on them was
incredible the fan leaves widened up and
everything got bigger and it seems like
it really over the last just two nights
did some some excessive growing so what
I am doing right now now is um I had
some Devastation to my mom's while I was
away um I did manage to keep a lot of
them alive and so what I'm going to do
today is I'm going to be cloning those
moms taking the healthy reved um plant
matter that I've been able to grow back
after taking care of of of bugs
basically and um extreme dehydration
brought them back to uh uh good enough
on the tips to get some decent clones
and what I wanted to do is kind of take
you guys through my B Botanicare cloner
uh we went through it one time before
but I figured you know what I'll show
this people seem to like this uh on
Bubble man's world and I don't show
enough about my growing so I'll figured
I'd show this up and it's real
straightforward and simple this is a 48
plant Botanicare unit it's got about a 5
gallon Reservoir it's got a small little
pump a utility pump in the bottom here
that's going to aate uh and then we've
also got a ariation stone that's all
been hooked up and lined up and plugged
in and ready to go um I used um the
Botanicare products that they sent me
which is aqua Shield which is basically
um chicken [ __ ] that they've broken down
and they've got the total nitrogen at
.2% ammoniacal nitrogen and available
phosphates and soluble poach they've got
the breakdown there uh and I also Ed
power clone so this is uh you know
basically a product I'm I'm not even too
sure of potassium nitrates ammonium
nitrates uh it's basically a liquid
Advanced liquid formula for Rapid robust
roots from cuting I'm not promoting it
over anything else I'm just saying it's
what I have on hand and it's what I'm
going to give a shot to um it very well
may not even be 100% organic as I read
the nitrates but uh they're just for my
clones and the last time I used both
these products it worked incredibly so I
used them in a lower amount than what
they ask for on the bottle so the bottle
suggests using uh 15 MLS of this
particular one per 4 L of water and this
one suggests 45 to 65 MLS uh
per into one per gallon so also four
gallon uh four lers of water I did about
half to a third of those numbers and
I've got it all right here in the water
so I'm basically just going to take this
guy
sitting over here
gently pour them
in so you want to bring this water level
up I believe it's still the pump is
completely
covered probably use uh oh maybe another
half gallon or so I did have that pH to
6.3
and I've got my pH pen right here a blue
lab pH pen uh it's very important when
you're doing anything with cannabis and
feeding and clones and seedlings that
you just keep in mind that the water the
pH of the water the natural pH of the
water that comes out of many people's
Taps is very high upwards of seven and
eight and uh when you put in organic um
um synthetic or organic nitrates like uh
manures you're going to bring the pH way
down uh down sometimes to 2 three and
four so it's important to a have a pH
meter so you can read your pH and then
of course it's important to usually have
uh like a ph up which is going to be
able to get your levels up I don't use
PH down because I just use food and my
food brings the PH down from the water
and then I bring it back up with the ph
up so I got those two guys in there
that's air rating very nicely I'm going
to put a little bit more water in here
and we will get to the next step which
will I'll be bringing up the Clones to
show how quick and easy we can just you
know Mark them down the names of them
and get them each into a row so we'll do
that next all right so we're back with a
little bit more water here just get that
level
up see to have it covering the entire
pump they want to make sure that the
levels are up high
enough so yeah that's basically that
we've got the top down here all cleaned
up to Perfection so what I'm going to do
next is I'm going to go downstairs and
we're going to grab those clones and
then I'm going to show you another
preventative means keep in mind these
clones are still growing on sickly
plants that have been growing out of
Health I've trimmed down much of the
sickness in order to get rid of any
types of bugs that are around and uh
anything that might still be on there as
far as an egg will be getting dipped
before it goes into the cloner and I'll
be uh also giving the minor uh sprays
with the Clone be gone or sorry bug be
gone that I've got as a product which is
much like a a soapy mixture that breaks
down the the outer layer of the of the
bug and it passes away due to that so um
yeah I guess we'll head on down and grab
those
clones all right guys welcome back I am
now down in the garage with some of the
hurting plants this is one that was
actually very strong in fact I wish I
could show it to you this one actually
just started producing resin in its
stress when it was not getting water and
it was it was all bugged out which
quite amazed that I can't even see bug
eggs or any activity of bugs but I guess
I have been trying to work with them for
quite some time so this is a northern
light from Dr Atomic and I guess we're
going to take a few cuts um what I've
done is I've managed to take a little
bit of these sticky tacks and we'll take
a variety of these put them all around
this and tape them up so they're the
Northern Lights so I'll just write on
there
NL I can't stress this
enough doing this sort of thing making
sure that you do not assume that you can
remember because trust me you can't so I
wrote NL dock on that
one we'll start cutting some Cuts so
let's see what we got it's a nice double
right there there's a nice single right
there
boom one
NL let's get this another little guy
down here there's another NL very short
but make it work
all
right get another one that's even
longer boom one two three how many nl's
do we really need well I think we need a
nice fifth one and I think I see him
right
here boom so let's get these sorry
fourth one not fifth one let's get these
wrapped and
tapped there we go fairly easy easy just
wrap those
up stick the tape on so there we've got
our little bundle of of Northern Lights
clones say a sweet skunk
clone sweet skunk got cut way down
mainly cuz I just had to get rid of a
lot of her material so she's she's
hurting boys but that's okay cuz we're
going to make sure that we
uh we take care of business and we bring
them right back to the healthiest of the
healthy so grab one of these
we'll call it sweet
skunk all
right there we
go so a couple of sweet skunk Cuts one
right there
boom Another right here
boom taking these like it just don't
matter because it just don't matter I
may very well get rid of these plants
after this 1 2 3 and 1 2 3 4 then again
I might grow them out and pass them on
to well-deserving people so we'll see
what uh I guess two it's not a bad idea
to strip
them and strip them right down to the
bottom
there that uh it's going to make it
easier to to do the Clones
anyway and they're in an easy position
right now for
stripping 1 two 3 four sweet skunk
Cuts all
right and
boom there's our sweet skunk Cuts so we
got the Northern
Lights got the
sweets sorry the medic Kush was very
very very hurting I fed it some medy
one I gave it a couple of days of of bug
rehab a couple of uh cures of the bug
bug beone and I'll tell you man the
medic Kush is a strong plant it really
uh it really came back there's a very
small clones on here but I'm going to
attempt to uh I'm going to attempt to at
least get one which is going to be this
big long one right here and we'll uh see
what that does for
us get rid of that little
guy and we'll take this long guy right
here we're just going to go with one
medic
Kush because the plant is so small and
John's already promised me to bring me a
nice healthy one but this this is more
just a thing where you have to know that
you can bring your your babies back when
they've been uh when they've been
assaulted and my plants literally got
assaulted on this last trip they really
took a
beating and uh what do we got here
now have that open up a little bit my
bones getting all mixed up so we get
those back in
okay there we go sweet skunk medic
Kush Northern Lights what else do we got
this was the mum I got from Ron and I
think it's important that
we we keep her
alive we'll take a few of
these let see what we got here we got
this guy right here
boom even the clone of the AST boy
smells
unbelievable let's get
that
okay I'll just take the two of the Astro
Boy two healthiest clones off that
I'm going to take one Ortega which was
in full
bloom
uh well we'll get two
actually okay so these are the Ortega
they were the most hurting and they're
fully bloomed
out and man they smell
unbelievable so we're going to make
sure these make it into the cloner as
well man woo that's some sticky yicky
right there
Ortega got juice all over my fingers
it's just greased out greased out
cannabis plants so there's two oras
they'll be the easiest to discover
because well because they're in full
bloom so there it is a little tray of
clones 4 1 2 four and
two bring these up to the cloner get
them labeled get them put in turn the
cloner on and that'll be the end of this
video guys so let's go do it all right
so one more thing we're going to do
before we get right to um putting the
Clones in is I've got my insect todal
soap okay this is safer soap it's uh
omry om omry listed as organic materials
for the review Institute so that's the
product right there and this is
basically just a variety of soaps uh a
mix of different soaps that uh attack
aphid buds mey bugs spider mites Whitely
soft Brown fids Ros or Paras slugs a
whole variety of these bugs are attacked
through this stuff and what I normally
do is I mix 10 MLS per 500 MLS of water
uh and I spray it on the plant because
we've got such small clones it makes
sense that we dip them and we know that
100% of anything whether it's an egg or
bug if it still exists on these plants
it's going to be exposed to this soap
the eggs are uh broken down even faster
the bugs broken down a little slower so
let's do that we've got 1,000 MLS of
water okay through 1,000 M of water into
the into the container and now we just
need to drop 2 10 ms this is a 15 mL so
I'll put in
15 and then a a light
five give that a good
stir
okay we're getting there we're getting
there now I'm going to put on
this
part now I've gone and cleaned this
whole thing out it got bleach the whole
nine yards from the last time I had
anything in here I cleaned everything to
what I would consider uh very clean
there's one extra little guy right
there and so what I'll do is I'll get
the Clones I'll bring them over
here and as we go in actually before I
do that we'll make sure that we have our
labels so I did this last time not sure
if I have any tape nearby um I can I can
lay them down for for now though so
we'll start with sweet skunk this is the
another thing that I really liked about
the botanic hair it was really easy to
label the rows so we're going to start
with sweet
skunk sweet skunk and I'll just put that
right
there okay so that's our first
row and why don't we just get right to
that sweet skunk Come to Papa so here we
go got a nice not sure if I even brought
the scissors back up because those will
also come in handy yes I did just to cut
down the leaves I like to uh I like to
cut them down especially when they're
bigger leaves on a smaller clone it uh
that makes sense just get rid of the
excess so I will dump these into the
Soapy mixture and I will dump them all
the way up to the stock the whole stock
will be
exposed okay it's very delicate I kind
of want to just leap get this guy into
here
okay so there's
one one little sweet
skunk she'll pick up when she builds her
strength I did just give them a little
bit of
a a major soak so we're going to cut uh
I'm going to cut some of these
down I got rid of some of these big fan
leaves that
are that are looping this making it dip
all over so we got a lot of those out
dip it all the way down to the
stock all right
we'll go right into the next
one sweet skunks are hearty little
plants they'll uh they'll grow healthy
from this once they're uh right now
they're a little bit Droopy from the
from the excessive amount of soap that
I'm putting on on them but I'm taking
no um chances whatsoever and I'm making
sure that these things are
properly um rooted without any bugs
and that's why we take these precautions
particularly when they just had bugs uh
you know maybe a month ago or 3 weeks
ago probably well even two weeks
ago
okay another sweet skunk in the in the
pile these will be exciting to see these
guys start to root I have to say always
nice to see that and one last sweet
skunk we'll cut that down a little
bit R of that big guy and that big guy
cut these leaves
down already super floppy so they're
going to get even more floppy when I dip
them in this
soap give them a beating of their of
their life it's pretty violent on this
uh bug taken care of so this is why we
going to bring it right down to the base
cuz that's going to hold it up and allow
it to stand so those are the sweet
skunks four planted you see how easy
that is with the cloner we're literally
just stripping the Clones down I'm not
requiring any rooting gel everything's
inside uh the um unit and what I can
start doing right away which I haven't
done yet is plug in so it starts
shooting up the Mist it's going to make
some
noise you can hear that sound now that's
a sound that you want to make sure that
you always have on when you're playing
around with your cloner when you want to
lift this up and you don't want the
water to be spraying all over what's
going to inevitably happen
is you're going to go over to the plug
and you're going to unplug the unit and
you're going to do your work now I
implore you do not forget to plug that
thing back in because it's a huge pain
in the ass if you don't you your plants
will die fast they will start limping
and and not doing well so let's see what
we've got
next let's go for
NL do atomic of course if you guys have
been watching Bubble man's for for
bubble man's world for any amount of
time you may have seen doc Atomic come
by and drop off his Infamous Northern
Light strain and man were we happy about
it our whole community of course because
uh we share our our strains with all of
our community and so it really was a
wonderful thing that he did for everyone
there's that Med
Kush make sure we don't get any of these
mixed up these are the
NLS and
[Music]
so make sure these are all good These
are nice fat little clones I have to say
the growth sites are so
close it's
incredible all right so we cut that guy
down to a reasonable size give him a
dip all the way the whole stock and and
and and
plant all right throw them into the
little Cube which is going to get them
standing up nice and straight for us
make sure you have a good inch plus to 2
in of stock on these things you want to
make sure your stocks down low really in
the midst of all of the of the water and
the mixture that's blowing around down
there this is going to be key factor in
your clones cloning out
nice all right so we just clean the
bottom of this guy he's got sights
growing every quarter of an inch which
is one more reason why we just love this
doc
Atomic really impressive little cuts
cut cut cut all right and
dip you almost want to give it that
little blow just so it can uh release
all of its leaves from being stuck
together when you see that it just feels
like this shouldn't be like this so
these ones are a little shorter than I
like they're barely an inch but
uh they will still grow they will still
root these these rooting um Botanicare
and the the the units much like them I
mean they're really all very similar
it's not like I've seen that one unit is
is doing it so much better than the
others but these things really make
cloning easy and particularly for some
sometimes for people that find it really
hard you try an AOC cloner for the first
time and as long as you listen to the
simple mathematics the simple recipe
which is you know make sure you have the
right pH and make sure you don't uh
underwater or overwater Etc these simple
things you follow them and you can't
believe believe the great success that
you have and how beautiful the cuts are
and I have no doubt that these Cuts
right here that we're cutting right now
that we're load loading into the trimmer
into the uh the cloner are going to be
of the utmost quality I really have no
doubt of it
whatsoever and really the interesting
thing about all this and I should tell
this part of the story is that the moral
of this story is that I really just want
to show myself and everyone that I'm
able to um bring these plants back to
life that were near killed and I want to
be able to do that but the bottom line
is I'm not forced to do that because
what I did in the beginning which was
smarter was I gave these clones away to
a variety of my friends maybe 15 to 20
different people I don't know you tell
me the majority of the times I shared
them was on camera with bubble man's
world so from Remo and d420 K and Johnny
B and true a genetics Phil and a variety
of many other people from Flav 421 and
many many other people I have shared
these strains with and and that's why
right now as I speak as I'm cutting
these and keeping these alive I have my
friends that have already cut clones for
me on all the varieties that I lost and
they've already got them in the middle
of getting rooted and they're going to
give them and bring them to me as gifts
just one or two plants that's all I
require just to get one or two back
Johnny be's already hooked me up with
Astro Boy Afghani and Barbara bud so
that was really great um you know this
is this is how it goes when you do it
this way if you if you share your
genetics you're going to be a lot
happier in the end particularly if you
happen to lose a strain you never lose a
strain when you share it that's all I
have to say about that you share that
genetic and it's not going to be lost to
you you're going to be able to maintain
it
throughout all right so we got two Astro
boys
very small little Cuts so we'll cut them
down as low as
possible give them the
dip most important part make sure that
they're I mean honestly this this is
just a good idea to do anyway I mean why
wouldn't you want to prevent bugs on all
levels from your plants even if you
don't have them this is a great
preventative especially if you're
getting cuts from different people and
you don't know you know if you can uh if
you can trust their the cuts that you're
getting they might seem like they're
great one day and then the next day you
might just have this huge influx of bugs
everywhere it happens everyone's uh seen
it happen you really have to be able to
set up a proper quarantine for yourself
so that you can uh be receive plants
even that have bugs but then make sure
that you can do something about it to
the point where you can uh you can
quarantine the plants keep them away
from the rest of your garden and make
sure you get rid of those bugs off of
those plants the way I look at it is
never under estimate these little
bastards they are endless they will
never stop you have to not underestimate
them you have to fight them aggressively
and uh you know if you do that products
like bug be gone safer these organic
products can be used without worry and
if you don't do it and you get yourself
in a situation where things are such a
mess well now you're in a situation that
uh that uh you're going to be to try to
have to use some terrible chemical
substance that I would just personally
rather start over I don't want to spray
deadly chemicals all over my plant you
know all right so this is an medic cush
the one medic cush that I had it looks
real nice I think it's going to be a
nice healthy clone even though John has
offered to bring it back I love the idea
of keeping it alive myself so last but
not least we've got the big boys we've
got these Ortegas and these are going to
need to be cleaned out they are a lot of
Bud I mean literally I'd say this thing
is like easily three or four weeks into
flour which is uh I mean that's that's
pretty pretty big into flour for for a
cut and so I want to make sure this one
gets soaked I want to make sure there's
no bugs hiding out in this
particular cut and get it all soapy
up put him in the far end
there
Orga one
Ortega clean these the best that I can
removing any leaves that have a
discoloration or uh burnt tips on the
end I just pull those out of the from
the bud uh this thing is for sure going
to reveg I've seen it many times it's
not a miracle it's not really that
difficult to do it really is just time
consuming so it's uh it ends up being
one of those things where if you take a
clone like this please don't anticipate
that it's going to be ready with the
rest of your clones it will be the runt
so these These are more just an
experiment for myself I'm sure that true
genetics Phil would give me this Ortega
back if I asked for it but when someone
gives you a clone do your best to keep
that thing alive before you just go back
and ask them for it again it's uh the
least that you can do uh when someone
has shared such a speci special thing
for you so a row of sweet skunk a row of
Northern Lights a row of Astro Boy one
single medic Kush and right at the far
end we have the
Ortega so the
Ortega blooming right out under 18 hours
of light that's how she reacts to stress
the
Ortega
so we will what I normally do is
actually I would spray the inside of
this so I got got my little half gallon
sprayer here that I'll pour a little bit
of water
into see if we can do this ghetto
fashion way no
funnel just catching a little bit of
spill in the the bottom
perfect perfect we can take that and
pour it right back into there and it
gives us the perfect amount of moisture
that's on the inside of this lid now
and
then I will crack that baby on plug it
in so I always like to check immediately
I open these three immediately water's
coming out so I know it's
working I'll give these guys a little
bit of a
moisture on top just a tiny bit not too
much cuz they've got that soap on there
and I don't want to wash it all off and
then I'll literally put the top
on so we've got our clones ready to go
we've got our light everything's working
perfectly and I want to thank you guys
for watching this little segment of
bubble man's world I know it didn't show
that many plants but there's got to be
something that you can pick up from this
this is simply as simple as it gets if
you're using a par a power cloner or a
Botanicare or any of these type of
cloners this is one way of doing it so
thanks for watching Bubble man's world
and why don't we finish it off with a
bong rip come on I'm telling you all
right here we
go bong Rippa so I guess we'll hit the
sweet skunk it's one of my favorites
I've been really enjoying it a lot
lately see if we can't get that camera
to come down
here there we go there we go all right
well that was fun not a bad little
workout getting those clones cut up and
I got to tell you the way it feels when
you look over there and you see that 8 9
10 11 12 13 I just got 13 new plants
that I didn't have literally an hour ago
there's 13 new plants that are about to
burst into life uh they should come you
know root around 7 to 10 days they could
root as early as 4 days doesn't happen
very often but uh they should be fine
I'm really excited about this so one rip
for for uh for watching and we'll see
you guys soon on Bubble man's world
he
[Music]