you
working for me for the last few days so
aside from starting it over and doing a
few things I'm praying that this is
going to work but otherwise I'm gonna
end up doing a periscope if Facebook
live doesn't work so well let these guys
build an audience it is kind of early on
Saturday morning not even noon yet
I really just need to know if you guys
can hear me so if you're in the room and
you can hear what I'm saying mm-hmm I
would love for you to let me know
Dave Guzman Eric's Trek fuss it's a
nervous nervous Stephen welcome all good
oh good oh hey that makes me feel really
good I'm not gonna lie I'm not gonna lie
sucks when I can't hang out and talk
with you guys good morning there mama
good morning Brian Fox and Carlos Agia I
hope we're gonna have a good one today I
think it's time to discuss terpenes got
a big order in for Blue River Canada and
one of the strains we got in one of the
cultivars is called Karma's [ __ ]
Neville's Hays crossed with an R d1
which is the rare dankness one clone or
a cut that Scott created a bunch of his
seed line with so we've got the Karma's
[ __ ] that's gonna be going up on Blue
River dot CA as well as some other
special things a full full little five
MLS of gorilla glue and we got what else
do we got over here we got oh oh there's
a special one oh gee Kush who doesn't
love Oh G Kush I mean come on so these
are all gonna be up at Blue River oh
this one special black lime reserve
unbelievable flavor profile on this one
here really stoked to have it in the
selection what else we got
oh here's a new one mojito yeah mojito
so
the mojito with some indoor grown really
beautiful well I got block cleaner and
oh that's a new one
orange cookies two cultivars mixed into
one when aren't you talking about
terpenes well you know I just just got a
whole fresh batch of terpenes and so
obviously I'm gonna be talking about
them let me see what else we got a great
ghost and block cleaner which we already
had up on the site so those are nothing
new but here's something new Sour Diesel
cultivated in Jamaica Sun grown tropical
terpenes the first of their kind coming
to you via blue river and I've got two
nice 5 ml vials of Sour Diesel which is
great and we also have a couple of new
cultivars which is the Crown Royal also
grown and cultivated in Jamaica as well
as the white cookies so the white
cookies the Sour Diesel and the Crown
Royal all freshly produced in Jamaica
and then I got a little blue dream I got
a nice little vial of blue dream as well
so all sorts of different terpenes I've
been talking to the cannabis culture
guys actually I see Ollie as texting me
right now over there on BD Street if you
guys are around and want to support
cannabis culture they have been sort of
the longest acting activists in the city
and now they have a dispensary I'm
hoping on getting them some Blue River
terpenes I've also been talking to the
sunrise wellness center Max and Dom
they're going to be carrying these
terpenes and on Vancouver Island you can
check them out at leaf compassion one of
the five or six stores that Kyle has
there he's been absolutely killing it
and in the meantime I guess it's gonna
be time to do some turf dippin because
we can show terpenes but we certainly
better be enjoying terpenes as well you
guys can't really see off-camera but
I've turned my Pelican case into a
turbot case what better way to hold your
and secure your terpene
and jamming them into that Pelle case of
course for my little mini personals I've
got these ones which is a wonderful wave
to carry around a variety of terpenes I
think it fits like eight eight little
packages so you can see right there
nicely fitting close it up keep it
upright in the pocket I hate the idea of
the terpenes tipping and spilling over
even though we do have the proper lids
here at Blue River you're not going to
get any plastic degradation because it's
a special PTFE plastic that doesn't
degrade by via a hydrocarbon or or
terpenes so hey welcome Robert WI Laurie
to the room and Tyler sub-sect and
Michael Manos bubble man can you do a
video in your rosin press again and do
some flour rosin I will do that for you
the next time I get some really
beautiful hello Jenn Bennett as well the
next time I get some really lovely
flowers I will do a little video Remo is
going to do a video with me in the near
future with these flavours we're gonna
go do a terpene gauntlet with him on
terpene Tuesday on his channel and I
suspect while I'm there I'll acquire a
little handful of each of the Nuggets
that he has and I'll do a nice press for
you guys in the meantime I've got some
lovely hand mixed West Coast concentrate
always best to show you their logo
because [ __ ] do these guys ever do it
right
serious boys right they're really happy
to have them in my life no doubt about
it also got some of this dragon breath
rosin from them and then of course a
selection of okay let me see we got we
got this crazy Congo shatter and then
underneath that we've got some cookies
butter on a different little spot and
then one of my favorites which I've been
keeping in here this stuff is like red
glass this is 73 micron Congolese rosin
made from bubble hash and every time I
open it people are just like what the
[ __ ] is that so there you go let me see
if I just tilt this over a little bit so
you guys get a better
oh I'm smashing things there we go how's
that little quality action right there
yeah Jan no doubt who wouldn't let's
have a bomb rep or let us get medicated
whichever way you choose to decide I'm
going to grab a little this dragon's
breath dip it into a little of this
bubble hash and then I'm going to have a
nice little dip in some Cove Ella Sour
Diesel so you can see we got a nice
little if I can get that in there
without dropping it oh yeah oh yeah
that's a dip right there that my friend
is a dip right there I dab a fair amount
of rosin but I love me some bubble hash
there's no doubt about it yes they are
Calum they're going to be available in
both America and Canada you know one of
my big parts of bringing Blue River up
to Canada was because Canadians couldn't
access this product we were supposed to
watch the social media watch the hash
churches watch Tony and all these guys
have these amazing cultivar flavors and
we weren't to have them well I just
wasn't having it so that's why I started
Blue River Canada and have been making
it my mission to bring these terpenes up
to Canada for you guys all to be able to
have and we are doing something that
most people are not doing we're using
very very high grade cannabis grown in
greenhouses or organically or out on the
fields in Jamaica to produce these
terpenes these are not cold trapped
butane slab terpene these are not trim
run terpenes these are about as high
level of terpene extraction that you can
make it prawn is going to make it into
Canada soon Stephen I know that you can
has been discussing with Farah can in a
way for them to potentially bring the
technology up here and be able to start
brokering prana in two different LPS I
would love to also see dispensaries
being able to carry it as well that's
what I'm saying all right let's have a
dip here ross kaplan in the house that's
right
brother Jamaican Turk party right on
here we go
well it's all about kissing the cod
crisps too much drinking and kissing
cards you got a tough job worked out for
you brother Newfoundland I've never been
I can only imagine that it's an amazing
place ie the rock east coast of Canada
there's you know there's you've got a
lot of history to work through hey
Benjamin nice to see you I will break
out the Swiss next time I do a chat
I'll have the Swiss perk I got my
straight fab closeby but you're right
the Swiss perk should be representing
who love me some dizzle man I'll tell
you one thing about turf dippin is well
you can't believe how much more of a hit
you actually get nice Jen Bennett um
greetings Jeffrey from Flint Michigan
USA I would love to know what everyone
is puffing on and simultaneously I would
love to know where everyone is puffing
in so I want to see this the cultivar
that you're hitting whether it's flower
hash or rock or oil and what city you're
currently residing in while you watch
this little bubble man live feed
[Laughter]
yeah I love using these this is a little
trick that I started doing I realized
that these are the jars that the West
Coast concentrate guys make our perfect
fit on this on the halo dish and so what
I've noticed is if there is any residue
in the jar it heats up from the heat of
the of the nail and it slowly melts down
you get these little ninja rips where
you're you know you're dabbing out and
you're trying to carve your hip but
you're getting more of a hit because
it's dripping off of the jar so that's
what's constantly happening here with me
oh yeah that's delicious absolutely
delicious well hopefully I will be
heading down to these shops in the near
future to go see Ollie at the CC HQ and
to go see the max and Dom at the the
sunrise well in the center and more
people in Vancouver will have access to
being able to go and walk right into
these shops and purchase it's nice to be
able to smell what you're about to
purchase and for those of you that are
in other places of Canada by all means
contact me and get in touch with me via
Blue River extract CA if you want to hit
yourself some flavors and in the
meantime why don't we have one last
little dab to send you all on your way
I'm thinking cookies Roz and that's what
I'm thinking I'm thinking cookies rasen
and I'm thinking orange creamsicle
orange creamsicle and and and the
cookies it goes nice and there that
that's why Tony did the the orange
cookies actually which is the creamy
creamy creamsicle cultivar mixed with a
cookies melt one as well I got so many
people sending me messages while I'm
doing this at celeriac I'll join the
live feed brother I'm having a hard time
reading your messages and the messages
that are coming in Kyle from leaf
Compassion's hitting me up right now
he's got some interesting news as always
he's a frontline cannabis warrior open
up shops faster than most people shop
for socks
[ __ ] love it and let's do this last
dad shall we
well that one got me not gonna lie that
was absolutely stupendous it's a unique
thing with the terpenes you've never
really know how they're going to
interact with different flavors
obviously those cultivars that you're
hitting whether in a hash or oil have a
terpene profile of their own and
therefore they're going to intertwine
and mix with the terpene profile that
you've added on and I definitely prefer
it much much much much more than adding
terpenes to a flavorless isolate alright
good to keep the halo clean if you know
what I mean a little bit of q-tip tepco
that will keep things nice and fresh in
the meantime I have to go but I do
appreciate all of you guys and girls
coming and hanging out and enjoying a
little bit of a session here with me I
will try and make it on later today and
we'll do this again in the meantime may
the full melt bless your bowl sooner
than later peace out everybody