[Music]
hey guys what's up welcome to bubble
man's world welcome to flat for to one's
world where he where he owns a pipe as
sick as this you're gonna tell us a
little bit about this pipe ok so it's a
Daisuke roads roads piece from the team
Japan show they did in Vancouver two
years ago or something um it's obviously
Grateful Dead themed yes and I told mark
that I would wait to hit it with him and
two years ago two years ago and dice
skis hit it's got that piece hit up my
wife my friends but I have not
I've waited he has not hit this pine
waiting for this moment in time so
definitely you're up and if you know how
much I love the Grateful Dead you know
how hard that was to do dude this is one
of the pipes you were the most excited
about ever [ __ ] yeah 100%
and forever like this or the Scott
Debbie Grateful Dead theming did with
with June is like to my favorite pieces
of all time it's just absolutely a
stunner
I mean insane actually it's psychotic
it's psychotic glass and before anyone
comments we know that it is a 11
millimeter bang or in a 10 millimeter I
do not have any 10 millimeter 45 angles
out and clean so that's what it is so
you don't need to comment we don't need
your comments we don't need your
comments there we go there we go grab it
oh yeah look at that
got to use the hand otherwise it leases
yeah well I'm super excited more so to
watch you rip it good to even rim it
myself
yeah it's a little bit cool out so we'll
probably have to do a little bit less of
a time than usual yeah you know what
I've been I mean I know it's nothing new
tech or anything but I've been using a
heat gun lately well 25 second heat up
no cool guns
I got you dab her thank you thank you
what a beautiful piece of [ __ ] last
it's outrageous yeah this is it as good
as especially completely outrageous and
the blend of nice days work in June's
work together is [ __ ] this too good
so good and in in flats backyard of all
places
yeah they're the rare glimpse into my
back world i likey stumps bro thanks bro
it's wicked stump collection thanks dude
you think my glass collection is good
means nothing stops like most people
collect socks dozens and dozens of
stumps everywhere whole wall back there
just full of stuff exactly I need a wall
bill they needed a fence cut down a tree
put up some stumps put some stumps up
stumps and glass we're actually gonna be
throwing a stumps and glass party it's
been stumps and glass very good yeah
very good super super stoked at this
thing yeah kind of rosin you hit there
we can go q-tip it real quick off camera
get a q-tip tauf camera well I just hold
it and talk about this incredible
beautiful work of art really it's the
dot work is so ridiculous another show
you got the dancing skeletons the Jerry
bear gotta have the Jerry bear in there
and then you got the Terrapin turtle
just playing that guitar and the other
one looks like he's looks like he's
reaching up to the Sun Wow tell you that
is a piece of glass right there
such an incredible piece of glass Wow
took some pictures as well I'll impose
them on the video superimpose them over
the video so you guys can check it out
serious dot work right there though
check out the shakedown guy kind of
holding the little mandolin they're
covered in I guess he's not quite the
shakedown guy but he's sort of similar
what do you call the little guy and the
main disc in the center Uncle Sam
I knew he wasn't quite the shakedown guy
but he kind of had a shakedown guy look
to him you know just little q-tip biruni
maybe even a little heat and then a
q-tip or any I think it's a good call
oh yeah that did it that did it
this was the spinner carb cap that Pat
made me for my last birthday Stratos
yeah very nice cool love his work and
he's working with all the American guys
now which is something awesome yeah very
cool well he's a traveler too right true
true super truth likes to get around
this is mmm right well a little rip here
dabber doodle
dabber doodle very stoked to hit this
pipe it's been two years in the coming
we're gonna do a big video we had so
many plans over the last year it hasn't
even been funny no then finally it's
just a spur of the moment did you smash
that against in Spain yes again like a
third time yeah yeah cuz I got it fixed
in Spain I remembered it 14 hours later
in front of all you guys dude and then
got a fix and then smashed it again what
should I be waiting for you um I know
it's already cooling down substantially
yeah maybe even at 55 because the
outdoors is blowing well the variable
wind
yep there's many variables certainly and
that is that yeah that's 14 11 million
and 10 but we got it done anyway you see
the quick response always nice when
you're buddies there to pick and you
know what's funny it landed on his
smashed phone it didn't smash it it's
totally smashed alright oh dude yeah
I can honestly say I've never had a
banger fall out of my pipe while I was
just dabbing releasing the dam yeah
there's a first for everything even when
I was doing this part I made sure to
hold it yeah yeah because it just makes
sense but well I'm not gonna hold it
while I'm dabbing I have to dig out like
a bunch of 45 tens that are in other
cases
dude how's that I had no clue I had no
other clean ones nicest pipe I've hit in
a long time and I knock the banger out
of it
that's a bubble man special for you
right there on bubble man's world you're
only gonna see it here so don't try to
look for it anywhere else on YouTube
because a nobody has this pipe and B
nobody's as big of an idiot as I am no I
can't dude [ __ ] awesome
it was short but sweet I gotta get back
to my side of the water and yeah there
it is and there everyone this session
will be longer next time and they'll be
way more glass yes the next time we get
together it's going to be glass tastic
we're gonna talk a little bit about the
legends of glass and hash show that came
to be in a discussion between Flavell
fand slinger in Barcelona so we'll see
you next time guys
[Music]
bubbleman Suzuka machine I kind of
strain you out there
he's turning so clean and clear come on
without me da da da da da da da da this
is the diaper duty
I never do time without it da da da da
da da da
you see survivor do tiny WT fresh from
the instruction hundred percent pure
ganja subtle smokey surveillance clean
and pretty light count your votes abuse
this good friends just meaningful good
for the young hands alone for every soul
without me da da da da da da da da
he sees a rapper - I'd rather do take
time with are they da da da da da da da
da this is the devil you trying
[Music]