[Music]
so you got to give me a quick blurb from
my youtube channel on on the case today
well it was a pretty tough day in court
today yeah tell them what we what we
were there for okay well we were in
court today with former employee of mine
Owen Smith who was charged with
trafficking THC or possession for the
purpose after having been caught making
cookies in a bakery for a dispensary
that I used to own the cannabis buyers
club in Victoria that was four years ago
a year and a half ago Supreme Court
justice Johnson ruled that need medical
marijuana access regulations were
unconstitutional because they didn't
allow patients to make derivatives you
know cookies tea hash oil any extract of
cannabis is technically illegal you're
only allowed dried cannabis to grow and
use as medicine according to the strict
interpretation of the law the judge
again struck that down a year and a half
ago the court are sorry that the
Department of Justice appealed that
decision which is their very word today
in front of three judges at the Court of
Appeal of British Columbia appealing the
decision that would allow us to possess
cannabis resin and extracts as opposed
to just dried marijuana
yeah the crown appealed that decision
the Crown's wish the Health Canada and
Department of Justice is to essentially
have you know exceptions made for
cannabis marijuana but cannabis resin
and all of the other derivatives and the
Controlled Drugs and Substances Act and
their thinking should remain illegal
right and so yeah it was a frustrating
day a lot of the Crown's positions don't
seem very reasonable but the judges
unfortunately seem to be an agreement
with the crown before the Dave and
started you know they did read the
material beforehand so you know they're
gonna come in with an opinions but they
really did seemed really opposed to
granting an acquittal to Owen or
allowing him to just walk free I think
it really bugged them that the cannabis
buyers club they don't know the history
of the cannabis buyers club with when
they ran in the court decision is that
were an unincorporated nontox paying
non-compliant organization right we
don't comply with the single law not tax
laws Health and Safety Act you know
nothing you know and and so I think the
judges really struggle with just letting
us us go as an organization because
patients have a constitutional right to
this medicine hopefully Kirk was able to
convince them otherwise but you know
it's tough to say a couple of the judges
really didn't seem very favorable to us
but by the end of the day I think Kirk
ed had made some points that they might
not have considered earlier I thought so
as well that he made some decent points
and at least educated them a little bit
definitely and so we've got a bit of a
wait now people
you hear me yeah the weights gonna kill
us will not kill us but it's gonna be
tough
it could be three months it's likely
four to six months but it could be
eleven ten months as I said earlier you
can have a baby in less time than it may
take for this decision to come but it
will come and it looks quite likely that
we'll be going to the Supreme Court of
Canada now I I would hope there's going
to be a dissenting judge one way or
another but we may go on the losing end
you know and there may be a couple
judges go against us but we'll see well
it's the big fight Ted and I certainly
thank you guys for you know doing it I'm
there with you guys I'm ready to stand
on the front line with you guys as well
because this is an important an
important decision for a lot of people
in Canada welcome it's a very important
matter you know I hope we've done a good
enough job that we've changed things so
we'll see how it goes I think sue Minter
well thanks a lot