[Music]
well welcome to Bubble man's world guys
bubble man here with my good buddy
Horatio in the house sir and uh sh what
are we going to talk about today we're
going to talk about an interesting
little yeah we're gonna I mean on the
hash Church where me and Tony and K from
Tri Technologies got into uh tpin to a
high degree Kenny kind of isolated that
the main thrust was to I get at that 90%
of what's lost during the drying process
because that's what we don't experience
those are the most volatile we know them
from smelling Frozen cth that's just off
gassing and I kind of already knew that
if there's there's only so many ways we
can get back to the plant in its full
Essence and we've seen the trend of live
resin and things like that we've seen
live sift pop up here and there it's
pretty unstable but it's happened and um
I always look at sustainable methods to
recreate that end without the downside
so uh right now we're going to be
looking at uh some pecs uh we saw that
on our Mega chill episode is that the
Pineapple Express yeah packs nice the
packs
so this is the PEX wet it's been crushed
all day so that's never been
dry okay so you get the raw
raw interesting yeah so you can kind of
see I mean it's been going you know I
can literally remember being like uh
like maybe even before high school and
buying herb like this and thinking
at this herb look at how crazy you smell
this you smell it no but like feel it
bro feel how it's like spongy like that
this is going to roll so good and then
my buddy's like yeah it's like 80% water
dude the [ __ ] are you doing this is wet
weed so that's interesting okay we've
got the wet sample which is a nice kind
of in my opinion it's a great way if
you're going to go through a a series
what he has is fresh dry yeah so let's
check out dry and really I got to
package this up cuz this is still off
gasing like crazy and taking
taking the room so kind of when you
smell that oh yeah what's cured versus
what's lost yes exactly you can
definitely smell the smell much stronger
in this that is in that but is being
masked by all that water it's just being
held
back interesting and I wonder if that's
because the turps are preserved in the
fresh herb completely and you would need
to um you know release some of that
water in order for some of those tpin to
volatize and evaporate away before you
were released with that properly cured
properly dried herb well I do have a
piece of Bud up my nose I don't know how
that happened but my eyes are watering
but but my eyes are watering but it's
like the the confusing part about
smelling this is because it's wet you
can't tell the water from the volatiles
I mean I do no not until you smell that
yeah now if you smell this and then go
back to this I think you're going to be
able to smell those because this is that
smell without the the water it's those
volatiles volatiles without the water Al
many many are gone from there as well
well that's so now you have this is why
I T got to the point where I'm like okay
there's many ways to isolate Tarpin
there's whole tarpine packages and
because my developmental aim was on that
isolate knowing this came from this
means I'm know the TPS that I have right
are only what I would lose because this
is still representing good bud this is
what I know right what medicinal aspects
are present in because you I split the
water from those turps are these super
turps are these do these turps enhance
or high is it just a percentage of these
same turps we need a lab to test them
and find out the names of these turps
well I mean even just being able to test
through suggested they were the
sesquiterpenoids that were the most
volatile the super tarpine well it t i
mean now okay so for instance we've got
the dry and we know this PEX is made
from dried material I didn't try any um
okay livick technology I think dry
sifting is not a misnomer when you're
dry sifting you should dry and then sift
if you try to turn this into a frozen
Rock and then quickly try to pulverize
it isolate the
heads all throughout the pro process
every bit of head every w w look I got
to make a point in that dry eyes process
all of the contaminate are all I got a
second one probably you do don't worry
we'll fluff it um that just gets mashed
into a wet sugary paste right it's not
like when debris hits dry heads hard
heads brittle heads that in that bounce
you essentially make a smear Patty now
I've tried to keep it cold and cold and
cold and sift it and then try to dry
those remaining heads
but it's always been a polka do kidcope
of pasties that are essentially because
it dries perfect on the
diluted the the dilution that it occurs
on naturally on the plant that's where
it dries the best I mean that's kind of
why I mean we don't know where this is
going to last preservative wise but
being able to do this process correctly
versus reaching out to methods that
aren't appropriate and then being able
to reintroduce it back it's more of an
ultimate made experience then to try to
process wet material unnaturally now you
have a piece of butt on your nose tip
after I got one up my nose you know what
I was just noticing the sift just is the
perfect example of the flavor of that
bud but now instead of the water smell
missing like the way this smelled from
this you have that chlorophyll plant
matter Haze smell missing that you don't
even really notice when you first smell
this just smells like nice Bud yeah then
you smell this and you're like oh that
was nice bud with the smell of hay and
plant matter and chlorophyll along with
that smell that's kind of to process
your sift with that even just the juices
from that chlorophyll present are going
to be altering and bathing your sift you
can dry it but it's why it's called dry
sift it's um you know it really is I
know a lot of people are stoked on
trying to do dry ice and then clean it
from there but the problem is not that
the dry ice is making the hash wet it's
that the hash is wet it's never been
properly dried and they don't think that
it's wet what I mean I can get a result
but that result changed I'm like these
particles aren't supposed to be at this
Micron size but they're stuck here cuz
they came on Tri they get all clumped up
together whereas it's like now you're
trying to dry them all in this weird
Clump in a way that they never occur in
nature that's pretty much it you let
them dry in these like could you imagine
if you were trying to design a perfect
way to dry tricomb heads look at that
picture on the wall isn't that what you
would design the elaborated space just
like a bunch of nail heads and then you
just balance a ball on only the thing is
it's only nature that could do the
subdivisional spacing so
perfectly it's awesome clearly I'm
somebody who has the power to choose um
I've done the wet material I've looked
at the result and by the time I dry it I
get the same tarpine profile cuz it's
dry but with a whole bunch of [ __ ] in it
the quality changes and it can never
static nothing can change the fact that
the contaminants were pasted into the
heads wet yeah yeah that's unfortunate
so they're on like stickers I I'll say
it again when you're trying and playing
around with dry sift try with the driest
material possible that's a good
foundation to get you on the way for to
discovering new and great things if
you're mocking around with wet with wet
heads uh you're going to you know not to
say don't do that cuz maybe someone
that's the game they want to play or
whatnot and they might have a huge
Discovery but truly um I I believe dry
sifting is not a misnomer it's an
accurate description for what we're
doing we're
dry sifting even when you I cuz I
remember live sift oh my God what if
what if oh I got to try I got to try I'm
smart enough I can do anything and I'm
like this is neat but this isn't
practical this isn't this is actually
impractical and now I'm going to have to
[ __ ] my product um because somebody
who just puts in the harder work um is
going to get a better result now I'm in
a position now
where I can get the best of both worlds
but I'm also speaking to the fact I
dried this to get this and what I
isolate from this we're going to work
out ways to reincorporate that back um
it'll be interesting to see how that
affects white out um because of the
direct introduction of tpin to the
outside of the head so I wouldn't mind
doing some time lapse trials where we
just see that macro and see if it breaks
down how it breaks down does it dilute
does it become a shatter it's an option
that pure chlorophyll free heads gives
us so well I'm about ready to dip into
these
unadulterated pure chlorophyll free
heads it just looks so darn
nice clean my dab BR out so nice before
I put it in
there nice
little a nice little dab
all right I'm excited uh peex yeah
Express's the car
I don't know what that was that wasn't
from your head that was something
totally
different
excellent you going to hit some of the
packs yeah so I mean in the coming weeks
that's what I'm really excited about is
developing a technique to
reintroduce the UND dryable aspects of
the plant I mean we're always searching
for the message the messenger seems to
always be changing every new test says
something different you almost threw
away a a canabo that you didn't know
existed and um this is now your chance
to redevelop it so I mean that's kind of
why all these canabo with the
abbreviation of V seem to be so exciting
because we keep finding new secondary
thcv CBD
it's going in so I'm pretty excited to
see how are these precursor tpin are
they simpler why are they feel so wet
sure yeah no it's very exciting to learn
more and more about the profiles as we
um categorize and name all these unknown
tpin and unknown canabo for that matter
and perhaps even a whole new underlining
U molecule for all we know um it'll just
be interesting as the science goes
deeper into it and we have younger
people up and coming and going to school
for these specific subjects I'm really
excited to see what countries jump on
board and what universities get on board
for offering courses in agriculture and
botney and the chemistry well I
specifically of cannabis well I mean
when I hear these tpine names just
because I focus so long on herbs that
were medicinal and other type of
derivative products that I'm like I know
that name I know what it does I just
have to go back to my book and then I
get a whole new picture of what this can
this plant's message might be based on
those tpine profiles even when we know
that science of really discovering every
name to everything is always a Perpetual
Rubik's Cube spot even just going
through a name of 30 of the most
dominant and then matching it I'm
abolutely okay no alone 160 to 300 I'm
like it's not just a guess this is the
smell of pain relief I bet you I could
make an arom theic product that would
without the weed even just looking at
again that isolate without destroying my
medicine in the bud taking something
we've never known could people be
getting a benefit from whatever
Pineapple Express offers in just its
light tur profile yeah yeah so well if
it modulates cannaboids what else does
it modulate is the is the question right
can it modulate mood I believe of course
it can modulate mood that's the entire
aroma therapy industry is based on the
modulation of mood through the
inhalation of of of essential oil Vapors
through different um what you find is um
all kinds of plants have found without
legs have found their way all around the
world just because the tarpine profile
they put out controls human beings it
controls their noses it controls their
memories it's imprinted smell goes as
far back with us as sight to the
beginning so you know these plants
didn't get around the planet and don't
persist even when we want to bulldoze
without the power of those tpin Roses we
don't eat but there's a massive industry
off of those light
yeah based on our desire tpin are part
of human desire to to want those smells
and flavors and tastes is is a simple
desire of humans and if you read Michael
Poland's the botney of Desire that book
really breaks it down in a beautiful way
almost in a way that like nothing would
happen if it weren't for human desire
absolutely like it literally fires
everything that we do well that's when I
got to when I finally isolated this and
I'm like is this what the Growers are
living with is this how do they even how
can they recognize weed when they live
in such a pungent aromatically Rich
environment that even when the Great
Gardener's place is unbelievable how how
stinky it is I'm sure he's numb he must
be numb to it I think that he still
smells it but he's definitely slightly
numb to it what did you also have some
uh lemon oil there yeah we got some
Pineapple Express lhu I wanted to check
that out as well all right check out all
these different things you guys know I'm
not into the oils but uh Horatio uses a
turpine so he's literally making oil
with a
turpine a turpine that he produces on
his own and and cleans to a degree that
um makes this really beautiful nice
product so now when you smell that do
you feel you smell the dry weed weed or
the
weed well I mean that has a bit of a
funk from being in the bag yeah it was a
long date we it was a couple of hours
since we've did actually let's get it
out of the bag completely it out and not
that one I'll smell the other
one the want I crushed for
science this one's juicy God it is
closer to the to the a little closer to
the fresh but the dry has it too it's
different it has text of both of them
mhm that's pretty much now that has the
tpin reintroduced of that wet experience
but with that dry note I basically it's
either the lighter component like the
the Citrus you smell versus the one you
taste and
um an interesting
texture every strain is different
because if you noticed I can only
imagine how wet the tpin from that train
wreck we tried would be that would
pretty pry much be more of a liquid like
that's a pretty much Auto white out even
that train wreck I'm like if I had Turf
back to this this thing is a goner it's
just going to it's just going to go out
in the container but if that's the W
that seems pretty stable though yeah I
mean every strain is different for
stability this train wreck having more
um well it's gooey in the sense that
it's not hard and shatter it's it's a
little bendable and malleable but it
definitely isn't like dripping down the
parchment well everybody knows the
luming process removes all the lip and
as the current uh myth goes lipids
create the structure for Shatter um it's
not something I believe but my products
always been a softer degree because I
won't smoke those lipids if you're going
to do a non-polar extract you've got to
eliminate those polar components that
are not it's not the wax lipids from
something like sift right it's plant
waxes and they're a whole different
Beast um at a way higher concentration
so this thing is still having had this
thing on in like so
long I just feel like I want to take uh
vaporize some of that but the dry herb
yeah maybe I have
uh I've always got something within
reach maybe this guy yeah cuz I know
great Gardener was talking about well
what if I could get
to smoke Frozen bubble in my walk-in
freezer I should have the ultimate
experience and I think to a degree but
except for we can't leave the freezer
what does he want saying he wants to I
remember he was saying to know basically
to know the strain to its full degree
what if I um I think it was sifted or
dobble in a walk-in freezer and be able
to smoke the product so I think it was
just make the bubble and uh cure it out
frozen so it essentially never lost
those tpin okay and I thought well
that's interesting except yeah you can't
leave the environment um but I'm hoping
that uh there'll be a process for the
bud uh for the the sift for the bubble
for the L CH that's all whole and um I'm
not getting the turps from another plant
uh the turps come literally from this
dried bud so you know that bud smells
good when I broke it up there yeah you
know the bud wasn't raped for turps or
anything like that so it's getting this
up to 420° my little I guess they call
it the herb Titan I don't know uh trippy
sticks calls it the herbal unit so
that's what I'm going to call it their
version of it I think it's a
a few companies have a a similar design
but it's so far so good I have to say it
works pretty good looks like it's
heating up
fast oh wow get that super medicinal um
almost
uh what's the word like eucalypticola
oh wow no
no I don't know you tell me what that
is it's really nice sharp almost like
lime
rindes that's pretty
lemony it's getting like almost so
lemony so that you have to lick your
lips to even taste it you know what I
mean cuz it comes in like antiseptic
this actually PR [ __ ] good this I'm
telling you dude I like it I like that's
getting that's that's pretty [ __ ]
good that's a turp rip right that's a
real [ __ ] no cuz I usually have to
wait that's actually it's going that
actually tasted really [ __ ] huh so
now this becomes my next question is the
drying process that I'm using to get to
bone dry preserving more turps even in
that product while I've stolen turps
from it well is this what you call bone
dry at this point could get much bone I
think it could get this is about 4% I
think it's a little higher but I only
guessed that from this and how here's
the thing about that though the the hits
that we got I don't want to grind up
over the shatter but I feel like
grinding up a bit in my finger to feel
it those that taste though is um there's
a little bit of water in there which is
key to get that tarpine if you bone it
out you'll get these deeper smokier
Vapor ribs but you won't get the no it's
the thing is I'm actually I'm cuz the
thing is when you meter it you get it at
three about 3% and and then I'm thinking
what I where I've kept this Bud since
right cuz it does feel this doesn't feel
ready to sift if I ask my fingers I
think it's I think it's probably close
to like 6 to
10% just from the way it's like when I
broke it up and stuffed it in here yeah
cuz this is still in that smoking range
yeah I think you could roll a joint and
someone would be quite pleased like Remo
who smokes lots of joints I don't think
he would tell you that that's too dry no
whereas for me when I get ready for to
sift something no that's what I'm saying
I'm like I didn't sift this with this
particular I pulled this for the dry Bud
now like yeah there was dried for
smoking I wanted to see if it was an
actually good smokable product and
that's this handful cuz I didn't think I
had that and I found it that makes sense
cuz it doesn't feel sift ready I'm still
getting um it can still Patty but um
it's fresh I'm pretty excited about this
is a drawing technique for the smoke as
well um I don't know where it stands
when it comes to preservant compared to
the different rooms people use but uh as
an as an actual industrial
process so I hit the bud I hit the dry
sift now everyone's wondering is bubble
man going to hit that
oil is this oil oil
oil little bit of dirty bud I do want I
don't vaporize a ton but when I do I get
like neurotic about um I just go back to
being the smoker me that just collected
Ash for a living and I realize that I'm
like why am I collecting this vaporized
nonsense and I'm like I don't know
there's just something that tells you
you're going to smoke it again we're
don't waste it we could make coconut
Butters and you could coconut Butters if
you're serious about vaping there are
medicinal aspects that you could extract
into coconut oil um so anyone saving a
mountain of vaporized trash I don't want
you Chuck in it yeah don't do that but
we're not smoking it don't do that well
let's give this L shot all right let's
uh let's do it
up do I have it at a good temperature do
you think I should turn it down if you
would kindly sir yeah of course if
you're the L show guy so I'm not uh now
this is quartz So What temperature would
you like just drop it to 710 not as low
as that 350 stuff I do sure I think that
only works on titanium
I don't think it's needed for quartz
perfect we go down to 710 we can always
waste it to taste it it's not the end of
the world if can't finish like that yes
exactly well I guess I could use this so
now cuz that's my my question is cuz I'm
big on figuring out a way to introduce
this back into the sift what is the co
when how much hash traveled pressed
introduce what back into the sift
introduce the w TPS that's pretty much
the way to call them the wet turps um
but I've never been all my hash came
press press mystery press now there's
the new culture of the powder and we run
around with the powder well you know
what and I feel fairly a big part of
that because I always told people like
you know like you can see what if you
don't have anything to hide then leave
it in powder the only reason you need to
press it well there was two reasons
originally why we pressed hash and that
was to adulterate to raise the weights
with non- glandular material and then to
smuggle to move that product over
borders across into International zones
so we don't really need either of those
things in my opinion now and so I think
it's just a matter of uh cuz I keep I'm
figuring all my product with that much
with basically with this amount of
unstable tpin in it it's going to
everything is going to grease into a new
consistency just press it against the
table
I just want to get myself a little rip
and it just keeps coming more and more
and more just holding on itself he's not
an old oil man folks he doesn't have the
tech did I got the TCH what are you
talking about well you're not sitting
there what are you talking about
flapping and it's true definitely
not definitely not but I'm hitting a
little bit of my buddy's uh LH no
solvents uh well no chemical solvents
like BHO no
hydrocarbons used in the extraction
process so well we better have a little
rip of
it right temperature yeah
it's very
smooth then again I didn't take a
monster rip I think I took you took good
that's not my size ABS oh no no you're
good um this that unique everyone has
that why is it so smooth mhm I took the
lipids out you don't take those lipids
out it gets rougher and rougher now
there's many views of what removing Li
lipids are and I'm always been in the
gym your air camp and uh Winter Rising
is a completely different process than
dexing lemine is not even something you
can freeze and chill down and try to get
waxes out that's a butane only
phenomenon but if you go into tped
isolation if you go into the molecule
world of um essential oil extracts it's
a natural process it CO2 extracts tons
of lipids and they have to use a
secondary solvent to remove it or it can
be just as
they have to use a form of alcohol one
way or another you need a polar to push
it out if you don't use some form of
polar you're going to get caught one of
those discs well no what I mean by
polarity you literally push the fat if
you don't push fat out of the um nonar
and you just try to separate it with
temperature you don't get a complete jum
it's not a full profile it's a partial
profile of fat removal interesting so uh
well maybe one day we'll be over at
Horatio and we'll end up showing you all
this madness that he does in his
laboratory uh one day you never know
soon enough we're always working it's
totally possible but you should hit one
of these uh L so I feel like pretty good
I hit the I hit the sift yeah I hit the
bud yeah I hit the LH yeah I've got a
Pex I wish there was a way to hit
weto that's the only thing there's no
way to vape is with a sublimator you can
that would probably you can you can
literally put that butt into the
sublimator all turned that would roast
it oh my God I'm telling you would it
work in a volcano um I don't think so
cuz I when I asked people who tried to
vaporize wet weed they said I didn't
like the coral aspect and I'm like well
of course it's there but it's not the
and cuz I always wondered would my water
turn green um after extracting the turf
which is a stupid concept but um because
I pulled that water clean you tried that
water on that last video it uh it's
Unique in itself I'm developing a lotion
out of it that hopefully maybe we have
to demo by the time my laboratory is
ready for the public see I didn't take
much more than that dude that's all I go
for that's what I'm saying but you said
that I took a big one it looked big to
me cuz these dabbers are huge that's a
big hit is all I'm saying it is I'm
going to choke out where you probably
won't well whatever I don't think it's a
contest I'm choking out on my own
[ __ ] I'll tell everyone Horatio was so
wasted on his own [ __ ]
first we hit the
sift then we hit the bud although you
only really got one taste feel free if
you feel the urge to taste take more uh
rips on the well I actually is that
product in the stores yet yeah yeah yeah
I know um I have now got a collection of
itty bitty baggies like this but I don't
enjoy them cuz I've always I'm like well
I'll just roll one up since I'm watching
Dr Green Thumb and then I'm like two
hits I don't know what to do with this
thing um I was just in the mood but I
like
just puff that in like 3 minutes easy
you just be puffed yeah poof I'm like
Remo you are a
fiend I did like that I actually got
probably the best fate taste how much is
it how much is what these in stores do
you know these what these oh those 100
bucks okay they 100 bucks yeah sure you
a better price I just I have so many one
time all right I don't really want this
well I'll tell you I got it and once
again I I was like I don't think I need
this thing and then I stuffed it and I
used it once and I was like w this
thing's pretty good all of a sudden all
the bud that people have been giving me
over the last 6 months that I've got
stashed I started taking it out started
enjoying it and I thought man I'll tell
you if that thing can offer that to me
so how do I load it up let's do this
again you pop the top off
yeah dump the herb dump his herbs and
then just break some herbs I
put that over there end the T then I'll
clean this a little bit for you this one
there's a screen right there on the
bottom the piece that screws on which I
like this piece also screws off so you
can clean the screen yeah cuz I'm I
noticed the ones that drove me crazy
were the ones where I couldn't reload it
while I was walking to the transit yeah
well that's definitely a Reload while
you're yeah cuz it's got the just grind
me up above yep all right stuffing this
that's the
one oh yeah I am happy with how that
dried I never I basically I forgot I had
that so I only really smelling it today
all right it pops on easy push the big
oval button five times 1 two three four
five did it turn on yep okay hold it
down for 4
seconds okay yeah and then it'll go up
to 420° which I've been finding I was
doing 380 and it was just too light 420
seems to be the perfect temperature to
actually get it to a point where you get
that perfect Vapor rip and not burnt by
any means as you
no it was I didn't expect that I
expected The herbal hit I didn't expect
um a tur rip it's pretty good little
unit I'm not going to lie trippy sticks
they also sent me these which are
awesome they sent me like a bunch of uh
trippy wipes alcohol yeah but like you
know these full like three or four of
them
so thanks H uh uh
alilio Horatio alelo guys with your wild
names I've just got the classical
Biblical name it's all on our mothers I
would start hitting it right now right
around 400 is where yeah you'll get like
3 390 to 420 is just you get this really
you have to push the button no I didn't
think push the button no but you'll
already be getting some tasty ribs just
those light antiseptic
Tarpin yeah no no that remember when I
said the alcohol remember that alcohol
fraction I feel like that's where the
this part of the hit went yes for sure
it's I think of it when I clean when I
take the hit I think like you could
clean a hospital room with this smell m
whatever this is like how's that a way
to antip antiseptic a whole room where
you just have this crazy intense just
basically put the G put the Turing on
the atomizer and fog it out yep that's I
like it we're coming up with good ideas
here all the time yeah no this reminds
me most of the the alcohol portion the
portion that was the whitest and the
most yikes and it's good it's very
good that's I'm pretty I still have my
solo here from arer which ariser which
was a unit that I used for the longest
time but you can tell between these two
units it's got that pocket you know this
this is just too con damn convenient
this is more the home yeah this is for
home um but the reason why vaporizing is
to Quality Control an essay yeah I love
the fact that this is in glass but yet
this does not hit like it's in a metal
container well and someone else told me
they were like oh that thing has a
rubber thing and it tastes super bad and
I was like I don't taste like I'm pretty
OCD and I'm not going to lie like if I
PL taste plastic or I taste something I
don't like no I know that's kind of why
I'm looking at the construction to go
why do I think it's made out of one
thing but it behaves like another
because look the red is one thing but
look inside see this black here and here
that's the whole heating chamber that
you see in there so this piece probably
pulls right out probably goes to like
here this is made out of the same stuff
my vaporizer mouth piece is made out of
why I don't get bur to the mouth pretty
much that's a pretty good unit anyway I
can't say enough about it so far it's
been really travel friendly and it's
worked every time I've needed it and one
thing I really like about it is it just
it doesn't just die super fast yeah
which that drives me [ __ ] nuts with
some of these
units you know you hit the button three
times and all of a sudden it's blinking
cuz it's dead that's where Apex really
came in holy Christ with the five day
this is a five day battery from Apex
these guys no they put basically they
put the real batteries in the units they
they use what I Ed bird did it up he
really took the pen to the next level
and created the Apex pen in my mind is
not like a vapor pen of any sort it's
more like a comparable it's the battery
power to feed the experience I mean yes
the same reason why the sublimator is
borderline dangerous but it creates such
a borderline smoking experience yep all
sorts of different heads here so I could
do something like
this and
then I don't know I guess I need that
might be able to
like you know get that into there so now
you just push this button yeah and you
can take these crazy insane rips through
that so that's another little fun toy so
many fun toys to try out here but uh you
know what I had awesome little taster
test there um next time we're sorry we
did he did forget the little tpin we
were going to smell the tpin as well as
the fresh Bud the wet Bud the dry sift
the L I can honestly say this as well um
I definitely smell the slightest Orange
in this but it's by far the least I've
ever smelled in any product that you've
had and it didn't really overwhelm me in
the taste it still tasted substantially
like this the but I just finished smell
that can you smell the orange Citrus
smell in there I remember that diesel
cuz I remember smelling it and I'm like
this has got that this candied orange
this had a slight like a a slight
candied orange uh addition to the the
Pineapple Express which I didn't get off
the sift or the bud but I still smell
the tasted the flavor of this and this
in here which was it's pretty wild when
you think about it like he's using tpin
a turpine to extract resin it's a pretty
neat concept and one day if we can um
turn all of these turpins instead of
just into a single turpine profile which
is what um Horatio and uh Tony are doing
at this point K's taking it to the next
level and he's fractioning them into
individual tpin I don't believe he's
fractioned all of them at this point in
time but when we can fraction them into
their two to 300 plus varieties of
Tarpin that are present in
cannabis um I think it's just going to
be an incredible way to come up with new
ways to do things much like what you're
doing with delimiting it gets it's I
mean even when you look at well what if
we split it off and I'm like
I'm so look it's scary because we could
do 20 years of just chasing these
strains and the missing components and
then you have people who are going to be
able to isolate and say well let's up we
lost this strain but we know the
difference between what we have and what
it was was this tpine and that's when it
worked well that's it I want to be able
to recognize on graphs or in like with
the names of tpin and the percentages of
tpin it's going to be graphs I want to
be able to recognize like that's Haze
that's road kill skunk that's super
fruity that's blueberry that's warlock
that's God bud that's I the one thing
that because until we can homogenize
Growers I've found too much data of how
easily I can manipulate the dry SI right
in the grow and I'm like if it's in the
heads forget the plant material forget
wood forget everything else that comes
with which always had to do with [ __ ]
with Bud for its own s
if
smells get heads it'll be trapped in the
chlh material when I see suar is being
uptake from Salt products that's when I
get worried I'm like if we follow the
wrong tpine profiles if everything
tested was tested have you seen salts
invade the heads I seen sugars carry
over that are unnatural yeah absolutely
unnatural and to the point of distorting
the tpine profile completely and like
tasting bad or just no tasting like pure
sugar like literally like candy huh
that's interesting absolutely artificial
candy to the point of losing that
medicinal antiseptic aspect that's when
I I started to go well this doesn't
really that's not that's not like just a
a strain thing that you think that
that's a food regimen thing no because
I've now been able I just went through
organic versus inorganic and uh seeing
the actual result off the same clone and
now I have two different Growers who
produced a train wreck and um the
problem was every other strain this one
grower produced had the persistent
sucrose effect but what if he was
spraying that plant with something while
it was in flow that to me is the only
way that it I just don't believe that
this the plant the tricomb could pull it
out of the plant matter into the head
you well I don't understand I think more
like strings that produce natural sweet
taste why couldn't that be enhanced for
sure I can [ __ ] with the bricks level
spraying with
this is not these colada flushes and
stuff like I'm not talking about that
I'll tell you one thing when it comes to
the growing aspect of testing you can
only really ever trust yourself you have
to almost be in control of that to know
that your science is solid well this is
what I looked at I'm like what do you do
different and they're like I use
finisher and I'm like what's finisher
it's a bulking agent what does it bulk
with it promises sweetener so it
promises that it can bulk with sugar I
know how to do that to an orange General
how you add to a potato I know this art
for from add once you're adding messy
things into your plants yeah that's just
mocked up that's as bad as spraying your
plant that's like finishing it that's
what I mean that's kind of what I mean
I'm basically shedding light on if it's
in if I'm finding that flavor in this
head that means it's what you're looking
for what stimulates the actual
production of T and the mix phenols and
tpin well now I'm saying I know a
product that is negatively able to
influence that now is there a positive
side is but nobody does know a product
they don't even know it's phenols and
Tarpin that are producing all the
cannabinoids that are producing all the
tpin they have most people have no idea
of that simple scientific fact they just
know it works and I get so that's why
when I I always say I said it to Remo
the other day I said listen if you're
doing a nutrient company and you end up
with a lab and some
scientists get them to look into how
canabo are cooked into existence inside
the glandular triome head because if you
guys can start understanding that
relationship of how the phenols and the
tpin are produced in these organal these
vacs and plastids and push upwards if if
we can figure out why and how that's
happening you might actually be able to
feed the plant that gives it what it
needs to produce a higher concentration
of phenols and tpin which then produce
all the canono so that would be but
people don't know that well I cuz I'm
taking my agricultural background and
looking at it and going wait a minute I
could never never feed a field full of
oranges enough sugar to plump up the
oranges with sugar sugar doesn't come
from sugar but you can precursors though
but I remember from a child if I can
feed my yellow canary carrots and change
the pigment in its feathers right yeah
then I don't see any reason why the
sweetening agents don't persist
especially when when you read the bottle
label they say this grape flavors is to
enhance the flavor of grape and I'm like
but we don't grow grapes here
what is it doing here it's clearly to
either because I've seen people make the
not oh no we don't use the grape flavor
on our OG that would be a mistake and
I'm like well then you clearly
acknowledge that you just don't want to
mix the wrong flavor but you definitely
support that so in a more not the
bastard end I don't think people
realize there's no point in the natural
fall season where sugar just magically
appears in the soil for a plant to
uptake and unfortunately it gives a
pleasant result but I'm looking for
medicine so I find the more antiseptic
the more wild the turpe profile the more
chance it's going to be a real
experience rather than a sugar bear I
think the easiest way for us to get into
the new um the next 5 to 10 years of
tpine profiles that we're going to find
is to get into strains that do not
produce large amounts and take a long
time to flour cuz that's what mostly
everyone's avoiding right now so that's
where you're going to find things that
will have you the thing is that is so
true in so many other Industries there
is standard pump and out lavender oil
then there's Mediterranean long summer
dry Coastal season and that stuff I only
focus on if I want to be the best I want
to focus on the best what's the
complexities and subtleties I need to
know so French have the bomb lavender
well I mean the thing is the French have
a natural condition we need to study and
emulate it's as simple as that so I'm
like if I know this person admitted the
only different between them and all the
other Growers is this product and I read
the product and it says I contain masses
and I contain magnesium sulfate which is
epson salt I mean I believe it could get
into the into the um the plant uh the
leaf and stuff it's just like wow if
it's getting up into the Tricom head
when I could taste it then I started I'm
like this is an abnormal amount of sugar
for train wreck train wreck is supposed
to be a very medicinal strain not really
as much for fun but for effect and this
just tastes like a Candy Land Experience
a train wreck so I started asking I just
asked hey is there anything you know
that they did different than you do
different and they asked and asked hey
do you know do you know and then I
looked at the product and I'm like okay
I understand the point of the salt is to
bind the sugar into the plant to raise
its bricks level I use a refractor meter
press the plant how much sugar do you
contain this is a we read this to
project how much sugar will it be the
fruit right this is the fruit of that
plant so they load that plant with sugar
and it doesn't flush but it's not
something that negatively affects burn
so how would we know it's just you have
to test it that's thing is I really want
to test content in there well you taste
it I know by that same C wanting to
break down it it's more like honey than
ever and um I've never had that on
streams that are well testing into the
GC would really tell you yeah I what I
really would like to see is no sugar
added how much sugar could you add how
much sugar is there on the GC okay well
give me a strain that hasn't had no
sugar added it produces tons of sugar
what does it eat I want to that's the
ideal thing you get your greenhouse and
you're just growing all these different
varieties in three different ways from
Tuesday and then you're doing like these
tests where you can truly not just
control the extraction process but
control exactly you don't have to have
anyone's word or trust of what they
sprayed or didn't spray on it ex well
now that I taste it I'm like whoa now I
ask a ton of questions now I read every
bottle now I if you're in a position to
interact with your designated uh grower
um one last one for the you bet so it's
that's kind of what's exciting it it
sounds like a bad thing but Sugar's not
going to kill us in one uh rip no but uh
knowing that tells me I can go in the
opposite direction and find a new
Paradigm for the plant so I still
believe for all the potential
marijuana's offered us we've never
offered marijuana the perfect grow other
than random outdoor instances where it
got everything it needed the swore was
what it wanted just like I just keep
thinking about red volcanic soils
cannabis perfect drainage and the
strains that are desert Hardy and hard
to grow and indoor environments with
high humidity that's exactly what
Jamaica is built for in the mountains
were in the Flatlands it's a whole
different soil and a whole different
plan so I sorry I brought up Jamaica but
I just literally saw it in my mind where
I've traveled and uh how coffee behaves
and how you get your different grades of
coffee just by changing
altitudes the uh amount of uh well you
just imagine that high altitude cush
versus low altitude cush yep different
and then you find out that high altitude
is producing a one in a million turine
that
is whatever for whatever condition we
every day we're finding out more I think
someone sent me an article that the
liver has tpine receptors looking for
citronella and I'm like why are you
smelling for citrus and anti-cancerous
properties and I'm like really a key
there your liver is sniffing and
controlling your behavior to see those
terms so uh unbelievable man just like
the science on us as we know more about
how we're run um we'll run to the things
that work best so it's going to be
pretty exciting next five to 10 years
let's just say that much definitely
definitely definitely and a lot of
exciting characters seem to be falling
with the right crowd to survive um
instead of going for the short-term
product realizing when the government's
really start to pay attention when
pharmaceutical companies try to take it
all and legislate us out you what felt
the same way like I just got I it's been
only about I guess it's only been about
a year since I've been applied for a
license or been waiting for a license in
Jamaica maybe even less like six months
yeah and I just you know I it's
obviously been 25 years of my life in
the Cannabis activism and the Cannabis
world before that but uh yeah I just
felt like when I saw that it was
happening I thought man like the people
that are getting involved better be
really good people like I just felt like
kind of protective
of of cannabis and of Jamaica you can um
you can imagine my perspective I don't
emphasize the subject but I'm clearly
Jamaican and I can only conceive I'm
like what if J LH was a Jamaican product
through and through be pretty cool I'd
be pretty satisfied to go home like you
plant oranges specifically for it
there's already oranges Wai to get the
thing is I just look at I'm like there's
new money in your oranges is the orange
industry dying you know I want your RS
yeah and come work with me and develop
this develop that I want you to grow
this with your oranges and you'll
actually produce better tpin a higher
percentage of lemine versus the other T
and uh you know I don't tend to be
nationalistic publicly but um as I've
developed in my own process to something
that is uh competitive market
alternative to hydrocarbons for large
scale production of medicine um and its
extraction I'm not really concerned with
what you're going to dab in the future
I'm concerned with the thousands of
pounds of the invisible products that
are not for recreational smoking that
are going to be produced I don't want to
rub on something that has the frequency
even if you if you're a spiritual person
if you look at things that as
frequencies I don't want that vibration
going through and adulterating my
medicine on a level I can't prove I hear
but I feel it and I know it so it's the
derivatives that people are really going
to be counting on to save their Liv
that's where the hope is in the creams
and the medicines and the orals um I
make a product that's competitive
recreationally and I'm proud of it um
we're all smokers and we all like to you
know be purist but uh at the end of the
day if uh a bunch if basically if
arthritis which is afflicting many of us
if even just in Jamaica milons that was
a simple give back program where oh my
God I managed to isolate develop I found
a tpine that punctures right through the
skin and gives relief and I'm giving it
away it's way further than what I could
imagine if I'd have gone to med school
well you know that uh the second that
crd can acquire a license in Jamaica
will definitely be uh calling you up a
ratio it'll be exciting times to go home
yeah it will be absolutely taking the LI
the limitting to uh to the next level
and of course the dry sifts and the wet
washes and uh even gide up I believe is
uh going to be down there so that'll be
a big project if that can get off the
ground and we're just you know waiting
every day we hear new news from Jamaica
that the cabinet is is is is arguing the
the debating the the facts and I guess
they're both both parties it's
bipartisan they're both um everybody's
on board it's literally like the amount
of things they never thought well we got
to give licenses for tourism well we got
to designate yeah there could be Resorts
it's basically it's overwhelming the
amount of subtleties to actually make it
and I'm like yeah licenses to grow
licenses for tourist attraction loues
spaces designated smoking nonsmoking
beaches it's what people have dreamed of
and always that's what's always sucked
is you go to Jamaica and there's so much
plenty but you felt that same
prohibition whip yeah no matter who you
are no matter what status I'm like yeah
but you're smoking in your private
location you're not free Freedom isn't
really there so true if it can lift an
island economy back into a stage where
they're endemic products you cannot get
our sun you cannot get our soil you
cannot produce these strains no it's
their Niche Jamaica is Jamaica that's
why their coffee isn't a isn't can't be
copied so right I'm it's it's blowing
their minds and that's why it's going so
slow but every step of the way it seems
to be the more they weigh out each
factor seems the more it's going to be
viable seems it seems like they have a
lot to go over so I just you know I get
I see the releases in the newspaper and
I post them on my Facebook account and
uh it seems like the last one covered a
ridiculous amount of awesome stuff so
we'll just uh see where it goes
hopefully in the next couple of months
we're uh down in Jamaica I'm actually
going to Jamaica uh next week this end
of this weekend yeah and I'm going to go
check out the Bob Marley's 70th
Anniversary Birthday Bash in Kingston
and I'll be going down there and meeting
up with Tony and uh we've got some other
work that we're going to get done while
we're down there and yeah we'll just
hopefully we'll have some videos for you
guys down out of
Jamaica but before that we'll have hash
church out of Toronto this Sunday before
I fly to Jamaica and I guess uh damn
htio thanks for coming out man that was
awesome we're good puffing with your
brother and great products all of this
stuff wonderful thanks for watching
Bubble man's world guys we will see you
next time
[Music]