[Music]
hey everyone welcome to Bubble man's
world uh just a quick little shot today
a shout out actually that I wanted to
give to uh TGA genetics subcool and Jill
um I've known subcool and Jill for 10
plus years Jill even probably closer to
the 15 year mark where I used to speak
with her on true Stoners back in the day
when toxic and was toy and stepp and
wolf that whole crew we used to chat it
was one of the first can of chats that
I'd ever been on and we made friends and
I stayed friends with Jill uh throughout
her breakup with Jack and through her
getting together with sub and I just
thought it is one of the best things
that ever happened to her was getting
together with Sub sub and her have done
great things in the community if you
watch their their Twitter feeds or their
Instagram or Facebook feeds they're
constantly feeding the poor and giving
away toys and things to kids with a uh
you know lack of opportunity or disease
um they're really just generally really
good people and basically recently they
sent me a gift they sent me this t-shirt
which I was very happy to uh see that it
was was at least 50% hemp as well as
organic cotton and then they sent me um
three sets of seeds which I'm actually
quite excited about here um here's a
10pack uh subcool seeds the
science of dank and this particular
strain is the space bomb so yeah pretty
excited to uh try out the space bomb and
read a little bit about it I'm not
really too sure on the background of a
lot of these particular newer genetics
but he sent me the space bomb he spent
sent me the the time rack which I'm
actually really uh uh excited to try as
well and he sent me the Jack Skellington
which is a killer queen cross with a jtr
Jack the Ripper I'm going to go out on a
Lim and say super excited about trying
all three of these I'm going to be
cracking these in the next couple of
days sub I know you sent them out quite
some time ago but I only just released
uh received them today so I wanted to
say thank you both to you and Jill thank
you to TGA genetics I've got an astro
boy sitting right here for the uh just
for the smell I thought when I do a
video for sub and Jill I really want to
have that that Astro Boy uh sitting in
the background there so I was also going
to do a nice
rip because well that's what we do in
this community here we have a 120 Micron
uh F melt watermelon as I bang the plant
and uh going into the denail hitting at
about
750° into quartz
all right well I for one am very excited
to get these seeds going I will keep you
all posted with macro photographs and
video updates I'm going to be collecting
uh specific fenos in the female range
but I'm also going to collect the males
and save that pollen and who knows what
we will uh will see one day it's just
it's fun to do all this stuff it's fun
to grow cannabis it's fun to play with
the Cannabis breed a little bit cross
some
strains extract those resin glands
separate them into
microns experiment with how you use them
whether you're using them internally or
inhaling through smoke or vaporization
it's all just such a great wonderful
thing and really the whole purpose of
this video today was just for me to tell
everyone how thankful I am that I get to
call subcool and Jill my friends I'm
thankful for what they offer to our
community and I just really want to say
thanks guys you guys [ __ ]
rock Buble on