[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh today I just wanted to give a shout
out to my good friend Mr Robert conell
Clark and I also wanted to thank uh Mr
Mark D Merlin um both Rob and Mark sent
me a copy of the brand new cannabis
Evolution and ethnobotany now this is a
book that these guys have been working
on for approximately 17 years if you can
imagine uh it's an unbelievable amount
of content in this book introduction to
the multi-purposes plant cannabis is
chapter 1 we move into natural Origins
and early evolution of cannabis chapter
2 chapter 3 is the ethnobotanical
origins early cultivation and evolution
through human selection and then we move
into and that's a very huge chapter a
lot of stuff in there chapter four the
cultural diffusion of cannabis also a
very big chapter chapter five history of
cannabis use for fiber chapter six food
feed and oil use of hemp chapter seven
historical aspects of psychoactive
cannabis use for ritual and Recreation
chapter eight ethnobotanical history and
contemporary context of medicala
medicinal cannabis uh chapter nine non
psychoactive ritual uses of cannabis
chapter 10 recent history of cannabis
breeding 11 classical and molecular
taxonomy of cannabis getting into the
science and 12 the hypothesis concerning
the early evolution of of cannabis now
uh there is a final one as well 13 which
is homo sapiens cannabis and Homo
sapiens now this is the book that they
are kind of rocking the boat with that
is talking about the nlds and the the
wlds now that is a narrow Leaf drug
cultivar and a wide Leaf drug cultivar
both of which he's stating are from the
Indica family and that the sativa uh
rather than an actual species is more
like um a useful plant it's the hemp of
the species and he's saying Indica
branched out and created uh a wide leaf
and a narrow Leaf um drug cultivar for
obviously recreational and medicinal use
and that's covered in this book so if
you don't have one already go check it
out on Amazon um really cool that both
Rob and Mark signed this for me uh Mark
thanks for the great photos and Mark D
Merlin so yeah I guess I've got a few
photos in this here book always a
pleasure to um share photos with the
likes of Rob Clark for one of his books
I I see it as a historical context that
I'll be able to look at one back look
back in time and see you know to be a
part of a book like this a book that is
considered almost a university textbook
in my opinion and if you haven't uh seen
Rob speak before get on to Bubble man's
world look up Cannabis Cup uh episode 11
I believe from this year Rob does a a
beautiful speech uh he went right on
before Tony and myself and you can catch
our talk as well but I just wanted to
thank both Mark and Rob thank you guys
for doing what you do man your cannabis
historians your cannabis Scholars and uh
we need more guys like you in our scene
you do a very important job and I want
to urge all of you guys out there if you
haven't picked up marijuana botney wow
and you're way behind uh you can pick up
hashish after that and once you've read
those two thoroughly several times from
front cover to back cover you can pick
up the can Evolution and ethnobotany so
now this is going to be really for those
guys that want to geek out harder than
your average person it is very uh
University textbook like there's a lot
of information uh it's very well
documented and uh yeah there's the boys
right there Rob and Mark so go give them
some support and thanks for watching
Bubble man's world guys I appreciate
your
support
doesn't want to let me turn it off I
guess I'm supposed to share a little bit
more with you guys well here we've got
the atomical haze that was given to me
by the uh kind selection group uh my
good buddy Tim uh it's been outside for
its entire flowering cycle the last
couple of weeks and it's gotten a little
bit cold outside you can see the tips
are uh turning a little bit uh
reddish and uh just just what an
unbelievable view for this plant to
spend out the latter part of its life so
thank you everyone for sharing sharing
is caring we'll see you next time on
Bubble man's
world