[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh today is sort of a special episode as
uh I'm really filming this to thank an
incred an incredible group of people
that have uh really gone above and
beyond uh helping their fellow man so I
wanted to tell you today I wanted to
share it with you as many of you know uh
my camera was stolen at at the treating
yourself cup the champ show in Toronto
uh it was taken right out of the booth
we tried very hard to track the people
down that had taken it uh but to no
avail and so I lost the camera I lost my
ability to take awesome macro shots and
all these wonderful things so um about a
day and a half after the news of me
losing my camera um John Bell was uh
contacted by a friend of his
Elise now Elise works for a company
called Aurora uh and they are um a a
cannabis uh dis license production
facility that have been applying for
their license and are about to get their
license and are have a have a I guess a
facility somewhere in Alberta and so she
called me up and she was there when the
camera was taken and she saw the
devastation of both myself and John and
how it really you know from the
education that we were giving and
sharing and what we were doing and then
to be just our balloon be popped like
that uh it Disturbed her and so she
contacted uh Terry the owner of the
company and he's just a great guy and
they basically called me up within 36
hours of losing my camera and um between
the two of them they said that uh I had
spoken with them a little bit in regards
to potentially shooting their strains uh
with my macro lens for them when they
were uh ready and so Terry just put the
offer out through lease to purchase me a
new camera um without promoting their
company in any way which was really the
righteous thing about it they didn't
want me telling people about this they
weren't looking for free publicity uh
they weren't looking for me to tell
everyone that Aurora is the best company
and that we should all be supporting
Aurora they were really just uh rootsy
conscious loving people who wanted to
share uh and help a fellow human out who
was down and out who had just been you
know taken advantage of lost this huge
ticket item and I just want to put a
huge thank you out to to John Bell to
Elise to Terry and to everyone at Aurora
I really appreciate this um the camera
has been purchased it's on its way I
should have it in the next couple of
days early next week and I just thought
it was important to go online and and
share this information you know a lot of
local people are hating on the licensed
producers they're saying that they're
nothing but money uh grubbing greedy
corporate entities that have come in to
take advantage of the medical marijuana
situation here in Canada and you know
from what I've seen from meeting this
group of people and from the reaction
they had to my camera being stolen and
in particular asking me not to uh you
know to say anything uh before I told
them how I would say something about it
which in which case they said was fine
they never asked me to support their
company they never asked me to tell
everyone that they were the best and to
get behind what they did was they got
behind me as a community member and they
helped me out immensely so I just wanted
to thank you guys Aurora it's
unbelievable what you've done and I know
the YouTube Community is going to be
stoked as well because a lot of you guys
were crushed as well by me getting my
camera Stolle and I mean it just seemed
so non-deserving so I'm sitting out here
in beautiful British Columbia surrounded
by you know great Gardener genetics I
got Afghan and Barbara Bud over here
we've got sweet skunk medy Hayes from
John Bell and the congales behind me
I've got my Astro Boy up here I've got
my East Coast Sour Diesel right here and
of course my little Jamaican Lamb's
bread hybrid that I brought back from
Negril in 1995 so I'm surrounded by
beautiful genetics I'm surrounded by
beautiful nature and you know thanks to
people like uh Elise and Terry and John
and many many others um it's just great
to see the community supporting itself
like that and and to to be honest it
makes me want to do more for my fellow
man I did a few things today where I
called people up that uh that I could
help and offer the same situation to
them uh you know let me get you this I
want you to have it and you don't need
to promote my company or my bags or my
product it's not about that it's about
helping out when we can so on that note
I want to thank one of my good buddies
who uh comes and sees me in Toronto
every year and he brings me a little
little bit of bubble last year he
brought me the epic epic bubble I
photographed it it was like a 10 out of
10 and this year you know what he did
not disappoint I can't remember the
strain and I wish I could give you a
shout out bro but I of course out of all
these wonderful people I meet I spaced
your name so please add a comment if you
were the guy that gave me this wonderful
bubble I'm about to take a little dab
right
now in honor of of kind people in honor
of the generosity you know and so many
people told me that it would come back
to me and not worry it would come back
to you and I did just that I didn't
worry and it came back to me now I'd
like to add that Aurora isn't donating
the camera for free I have worked out a
deal with them in the in the past where
I would come and photograph their
picture uh their plants and their
strains so they're pre purchasing the
camera for me for work that I will do
when I receive the camera so to me
that's just awesome thanks again guys
oh that was a wonderful dab um today
also you probably will notice that I'm
wearing my Green Planet shirt so green
planet is a local company here in
British Columbia
John Bell's worked for them with for
years and I wanted to give them a little
shout out as well a lot of you guys are
asking me what my nutrients are that I'm
using to grow my resin and I'm using a
one part called medy
one it's uh sold and distributed by
Green Planet you can check that product
out uh it's reminiscent to me from
someone who hasn't grown for just over
15 years of Earth Juice uh I love it I
don't have to add anything to my soil
it's one part
super easy to um to pH and adjust and uh
it's been growing me some wonderful
resin really nice headyy melty resin
everything I've produced so far has been
full melt and that's with a variety of
strains so far and we'll see uh a
variety more strains come through the
tent and get washed I still have the
Astro Boy the Bubba Cam and the My
Little Pony sitting Frozen uh in my
freezer and I'm flowering uh Astro Boy
and my little Pony again down in my tent
and I'm about to fill the tent up with
some Barb Afghani sweet skunk
conal
hos and East Coast Sour Diesel so keep
watching Bubble man's world for more
updates and uh yeah thank you Aurora you
guys rock peace