uh Marcus is a very important person to
me
um not and yes he's a legend and he's
helped Pioneer the industry but my
personal connection to him was one day
when I was running a dispensary one we
did a Rebrand and did a um basically a
relaunch of our dispensary so I just
called up all of our vendors and said
hey you know what like we'd love to have
you participate is there anything you
can do and he himself
showed up with all his supplies items he
gifted a bunch of samples and was right
then and there from the start to the end
and so his dedication to being on the
ground assisting you know small players
like myself that I you know was new to
the industry
um it was just his generosity of sharing
his knowledge and his
um his clout I gotta say he is one of
the most beautiful people I've ever met
I spent a number of lunches and
afternoons with him and every single
time I I just can't get enough
so we have a very humble servant of Jah
and this is Marcus Richardson
please give it up
[Applause]
thank you yeah I'll probably sit down
here for a little bit we'll see what
happens
oh I begged her don't call me a legend
I'm just a humble servant of jaw
I'm the legend of nothing and if you
don't believe it I'll give you my wife's
phone number and she'll uh confirm
everything that I'm suggesting right now
uh yeah thanks everyone for being here
this is awesome thanks Julie and Canada
reps um since day one that I met Julie I
loved what she was doing
I love the idea of sensory science it's
very important we're learning we're at a
bit we're at a more basic level right
now
um in the Cannabis industry
unfortunately than say from the Hops
industry
but we're catching up and we're starting
to learn more about these different
volatile organic compounds and I think
events like this where we actually pay
attention to the sommelier aspect and
Trust our oil factory the one thing two
things I would suggest when you are
doing sensory evaluations of cannabis is
learn what your sensitivities are so if
you have like a sensitivity to
deliminine or a sensitivity to whatever
sort of compound could even be THC it's
important to take that into account in
the way that you evaluate the sensory
aspects of of cannabis the second one
would be to if you have uh and if you if
you recognize them a lot of people don't
but if you have blind spots if you have
um compounds that you can't perceive and
so understanding what your sensitivities
are and the things the compounds that
you can't perceive you might you know
someone might say oh this smells like
this to me and then the person next to
them is like wow I don't get that at all
it's like yeah well if they're missing a
single thiol uh that they are unable to
perceive the compounds would smell very
very differently to them than it would
be to you so those those are good things
but hats off to Julie and Canna Reps for
putting on events like like this and
supporting the front liners the bud
tenders you guys are the front liners of
our industry so we definitely have mad
respect for for what you guys are doing
and I guess uh I'll start by just
telling everyone a little bit about
myself I go by Marcus Richardson aka the
bubble man
um uh came from Manitoba originally at a
very young age I think it was 17 or 18.
I decided to become an activist in in
the Cannabis world we were in the Bible
Belt in Manitoba so we were like maybe
we'll do like hemp activism yeah we'll
do hemp activism because going to prison
with hardcore criminals was not my idea
of a good time and the prison that we
had outside of Winnipeg was very heavy
Stoney Mountain Penitentiary did not
want to be going into jail there as a
habitual florist so I avoided that we
did our hemp activism we got the first
hemp field growing in Manitoba in over
73 years that was in 1995 and my
partners went on to start the company
Manitoba Harvest with the work that we
did there so you may have purchased
those products at the grocery store or
whatnot I basically left in 96 from
Manitoba came to British Columbia
hooked up with Hillary black a dear
friend of mine who was just kind of
deciding in her life should I go
live in California with this guy that
I've fallen in love with or should I
come to Canada back to Canada and start
the BC Compassion Club and I watched the
BC Compassion Club you know get you know
kind of created on my living room floor
back back in 97 while I was living in BC
and Hillary was really one of the only
people I knew we had known her from
hempc from Mark Emery's place and so I
immediately became a sort of grower and
philanthropist to the BC Compassion Club
because I loved the idea of supporting
um the most vulnerable people in our
society people that are not only
mentally ill and terminally ill but also
homeless which is a pretty pretty
hardcore Trio to be to be rocking some
amazing people that I met back in those
days and we should all really thank all
of them for their pioneering work
because the whole reason we can have an
event like this today is is based on a
lot of the Civil Disobedience that
Hillary was practicing at the BC company
fashion club and that's how medical got
into Canada and Canada of course medical
opened the door for federal legalization
so shout out to Hillary black and all
the good Folks at the BC Compassion Club
I was helping them out a little bit too
much and at one point
um someone was trying to steal all the
Cannabis out of their safe trying to
steal the safe actually they drove a car
right through the front window of
Commercial Drive store back in 99 or
whenever it was 98. and so she asked me
can you take this cannabis home I'm
worried it's going to get stolen and it
was like I don't know 17 16 and a half
pounds and there was a bit of cash uh
that I I just took it home and that
night I went through a roadblock at the
Lionsgate bridge and got busted with 16
and a half pounds and six grand cash so
that was fun
um that really changed the sort of
course of what I was doing and how I was
sort of helping cannabis and the Civil
Disobedience I was practicing and that
led me to realize I wasn't just going to
be able to broker and sell cannabis at
the rate that I was doing which was at a
at a fairly High rate in 97 98 and so I
needed to come up with something where I
could I mean honestly I'll be honest it
was my lawyer John conright who inspired
this a great deal because I would give
him money like cash in a paper bag and
then that was proceeds of crime if the
police caught me with it but then he'd
take the paper bag to the bank and it
was like it was just legal money all of
a sudden like he was like literally
taking money from all these people in
the Cannabis industry putting it in the
bank paying taxes on it and it was legal
and I thought I need to figure out how
to do that
so I started a company called Fresh
headies and I started popularizing these
sets of bags that I co I coined Bubble
Bags which are the water extraction bags
that we'll talk a little bit about today
here that basically using water and ice
you can isolate the glandular trichome
heads of cannabis
uh and in a very pure form and we're
going to go through some macro
photographs and talk about that in a
little bit here as well so this company
was right at the onset of digital
cameras you know to give you an idea the
Sony Cyber Shot in 1999 was a 2.2
megapixel camera two megapixel camera I
was one of the first digital cameras
that you could take pictures of
something that was at your home and then
upload it onto the internet this was
also during a time where
cannabis.com
cannabisculture.com overgrow.com
cannabisworld.com all of these sites
were popping up and people who were in
The cannabis Community Growers and
dealers and hashmakers and breeders and
all of these different people were
suddenly like brave enough and they were
living all over where you could get in
serious trouble for this level of Civil
Disobedience that they were practicing
and now we were on a website and we
could all communicate with one another
and it was the most incredible thing and
the timing of that thing the timing of
me getting busted
um which I thought was the worst thing
at the time and I learned that it was
probably my own manifestation coming to
me as they often do which is as an
obstacle and then you have to get over
your own ego and see past the obstacle
and turn it into an opportunity I could
have played the victim I could have woe
as me I lost the weed I lost the cash
I'm busted I'm a Heat score or I can't
sell weed anymore but instead I decided
oh maybe I'll Pioneer something new like
water extraction not just in Canada but
all over the world through these
websites and I'll start teaching people
how to make this incredible quality hash
at their own in their own homes uh which
was you know the opposite of sort of the
other concentration that was popular in
99 two months after I released my bags
Indra
released the BHO method on neurowa.org
and that was you know his karma was very
different from my karma and I know Indra
very well
um he basically put this method out
there as a scientist but not
understanding that young people would
get a hold of it and then they started
blowing up burning their houses down
blowing their hands off and doing this
whole variety of things that is very
very dangerous so it was a unique place
to be in 99 as the water extraction Guy
versus all of these BHO communities
which I will say now the majority of the
people I know from the BHO Community
back in the day
they all smoke live hash rosin so we're
going to talk about solventless
extractions
um the three different uh practices that
I personally use my solventless quiver
but I figured I'd take you through some
photographs because
for me before I could learn about
terpenes and terpenoids and thiols and
Esters and esterification of terpenes
and cannabinoids and trichomes and
capitate stalks and all of these
different
sort of terminologies
I first had to see what they were and I
wasn't seeing enough with my naked eye
so around 2007 2008 I started practicing
macro photography and I started
photographing cannabis with a macro lens
and and bringing it to my eyes bringing
that world into my brain in a way that I
could make more sense of it and have a
deeper understanding of of what it was
uh what it is that is going on at these
levels so I just want to kind of quickly
walk you through some of these photos
and then
um we'll talk a little bit about dry
sifting rosin and bubble hash so let me
see okay we're going the other way uh so
this this is just a picture of seeds
just a picture of seed it all starts
with a seed uh Julie Julie asked me
earlier oh could you speak to what makes
a great quality how do you make a great
quality as a hashmaker
hashmakers don't make great quality and
I know that might sound confusing to you
but what hashmakers do and concentration
extract artists whatever you want to
call them
they unveil what the genetics the genes
and the grower along with the terroir
and the methodologies of growing all of
those variables that's where quality is
created the hashmaker does not create
quality he or she
unveils quality if it's there and we do
that through what we practice which is
purification we create Purity you want
it to be as pure as possible and you'll
see in some of these pictures some of
the hash that I've made
is just that extremely pure this was a
photograph of Sleestak uh crossed with
skunk number one from DNA genetics uh
and it was I don't know 2009 or 2010 in
Amsterdam and uh at um Aaron from from
the D or the a from DNA Don and Aaron of
course is the name of those two guys DNA
um he asked me to take a photo for the
inside of one of their hats so when you
took the hat off you would get this
picture of seeds and it all starts with
a seed so I figured let's start this
with a seat
uh next up this is a macro photograph of
a hash plant seed that was 25 years old
at the time of cracking I did not keep
it in a freezer it wasn't a refrigerator
for about the last 10 years but at room
temperature for quite a while and I
thought it would be a neat thing to
document and it's also the striations
the the harshness of the of the crack in
the seed you can really see how how
sharp it is and I learned something when
I took these pictures because what I did
not know this is also a 25 year old
plant from Jamaica that I collected in
1995 and it's uh I wouldn't call it a
cultivar because Lamb's bread isn't and
it's Lamb's bread not breath it's the
bread of the Lamb that's what the the
cultivar is called lots of people mix
that up and call it Lamb's breath but
it's actually Lamb's bread and this was
you know Lamb's bread would be in
Jamaica kind of like someone saying
sativa it would be more like for a genre
of plants than an actual cultivar there
is no one single Lamb's bread plant but
there are narrow leave drug cultivars
that are considered to be lamb spread
you know around Jamaica less so now
unfortunately but um this one I
collected in 95 and it was spectacular
just a cool up close shot and you see
how sharp the husk of the of the um seed
is and how delicate and slug like the
root of the cannabis plant is so these
are extremely opposing worlds so close
together and that veil of like a half a
centimeter a quarter of a centimeter is
is life or death because if the seed
touches that sharp edge and grows out
and opens itself up uh it will be dead
so it's a very delicate process shout
out to the Breeders that are creating
good genetics and there's a whole
process on how this happens without your
seeds dying and this is a big part of
that process so this is called a
bitumint and this bitumen is like the
sack that the embryo grows in inside the
calyx when the male pollen hits the
stigma the pistolate hair it travels one
single piece of pollen just like one
sperm one egg travels down into the
calyx and it creates one one Single Seed
this brown pad in the middle is actually
what's sitting at the bottom of the
calyx and then that material is this
membrane that wraps around the embryo
and it allows the embryo to birth out of
the seed husk without
um without damage so this is a very very
important part of seed breeding and if
you're growing seeds that produce a
membrane that is too thin you'll have
less success rate in your germination so
this is I don't know I find it
interesting maybe you will maybe you
won't just a couple more pictures of
this bitumen
because I thought it was so neat anyone
that's grown enough seeds has seen the
bitumen get trapped on the cotyledon
these are the first two leaves on the
plant and as any grower knows they're
they're called the cotyledon they're not
true leaves in the sense that they're
not serrated they're just round little
leaves and they're called the cotyledon
when the bitumen gets trapped on the
cotyledon the way this is if you don't
help it and remove it it'll only take a
couple of days before the interior the
epicado which is the part that we're
going to see next the true cannabis
leaves that are trying to come out in
the v the bottom of this photo uh they
suffocate and they die and then then
that is also a poor germination rate
this is just kind of cool I thought it
looked like a walnut husk it's just the
seed husk that the cannabis plant and
the bitumen has expelled after after
rooting and growing
and another photo of the same thing with
the cotyledon and that bitumen all in
one place they all used to be residing
right inside this little husk I just
think that's so cool personally uh and
yeah this right where this little piece
of light is is where we're gonna see the
Epic Auto produce
uh and this will also be interesting for
people so you see these little arms that
you can see right away the Epic Auto
looks like wet tissue paper and it is
pretty much that delicate and so it
grows these types of
non-glandular trichomes so these are
trichomes that have a different purpose
than producing aromatic volatiles and
cannabinoids instead they produce these
little arms that allow the Epic Auto to
pull itself off of the cotyledon without
getting stuck and anyone that's grown
has seen once again if you don't produce
genetics that produce strong enough
trichomes in this particular place on
that epic Auto coming out of the
caudalodon you can run into problems and
all of these things you can see how deep
this Rabbit Hole goes right literally
with your eyes you can see it it's
really quite something to start
understanding like what in the genetics
creates a strong success rate of
germination and then that's not even to
get into a count What gene synthesis are
present and turned on meaning you know a
plant that has a gene synthase of cbda
if it's in the off position that plant
will not produce cbda you can take that
plant as breeding stock and produce cbda
in in The Offspring because the synthase
is there but you need to breed it in to
be turned on so all of the volatile
organic compounds those are Gene
synthesis that are turned on to produce
these very unique profiles that uh that
Julie definitely loves because I heard
her talking about it I think it's so
awesome how much she Geeks out on
cannabis and absolutely just truly loves
cannabis and it's one of the unique
things about our community it's uh it's
really something that a lot of us
absolutely love you can see a little
damage on the cotyledon here that's
probably from where that membrane was
left on a little bit too long and you
can see it just starts eating into the
plant and that plant would have been
dead in a very very near future that's a
25 year old seed so I don't know how
many of you grow but maybe I don't even
know how many of you are over 25 years
old but when you have a seed that's over
25 years old or around that you want to
give it the best care are possible you
can see here the epicodle is absolutely
covered in trichomes now the top of it
is very white that's where the two
leaves meet they're going to separate
here very soon
this is just a cool picture of a
pistolid hair I thought it was like
buddies you know they're just holding
hands on the plant this is where the
seeds you can see these are other types
of trichomes that are growing on the
outside of this pistolid hair each
pistolit hair comes out of a calyx
sometimes you'll get two coming out of a
calyx and that's how the plant gets
pollinated pollen hits one of those
trichomes it gets sucked into the
interior of the pistolate and travels
down below and produces a Seedling to
pass on that to genetics
this would be the mycorrhiza sphere of
the root system so just a kind of very
hard picture to take but this is the
root tap and these little mycorrhiza
sphere hairs are the things that will
help the plant sequester the compounds
that it needs in order to express itself
in the way that it that you want it to
which is ideally strong terpene and
volatile organic compound expression and
obviously a nice strong cannabinoid
profile as well
so this is a picture of the Epic Auto
it's now growing a little bigger and I
wanted to show this because a lot of
people that tell me they grow say oh we
don't
um spray once it blooms once the
trichomes are in development We Don't
Spray anymore and I show them this
picture and say these are glandular
trichomes on the first set of leaves of
a Seedling
so yeah ideally particularly if it's
some sort of systemic systemic poison
Don't Spray those on on your plants
we're volatizing this stuff into our
lungs and it's probably best this is
also a picture of the Epic Auto showing
clearly bulbous trichome heads all over
the outside of it as well as once again
another type of glandular sorry
non-glandular trichome which is called
the systolith hair
so there's in general about six of these
different types of trichomes I've shown
you quite a few of them on the Epic Auto
on the pistolid hair and also the
systolith hairs here on the on the Epic
Auto so those are three types of
non-glandulars then we're going to talk
about the three types of glandular
trichomes
um which you know here's a couple of
them right here this is oh I don't know
what I did there I don't know what I'm
doing here sorry I think she has this
set up a little different than I
normally do bear with me
I think we're back yes okay so this is a
picture
um I took of a good friend of mine's
cannabis it was the Burmese [ __ ]
incredible
and this was Opus from Cannabis culture
days I liked it because it had a
refraction of a cannabis leaf in the
trichome head so these taller trichomes
are called uh capitate stock
and these little shorter ones aren't
actually capitate Stalks at a different
level of maturity but they're a totally
different type of trichome called
capitate Cecil
the first ones we saw that were just the
little balls stuck on the leaf those
ones are called bulbous and from an
inhalation standpoint you want a
cultivar that has capitate stalks and
capitates cecils especially from an
extraction standpoint and we'll talk a
little bit about that so keep in mind
all of the medicinal compounds some of
you may want to argue this in your mind
but science disagrees with you
all of the volatile compounds all of the
cannabinoids are found inside the
glandular trichome of this head these
capitate stalks are made of cellulose so
like the same thing a cardboard box is
made of
which is also what the majority of the
plant is made out of cellulose and and
fiber so really what what you learn
about cannabis that the same way when it
produces if you want to produce
wonderful cloves from hemp you don't
take the seeds you don't take the resin
you don't take the buds you take this
the the cellulose and the fiber from the
plant so you take the one from the hole
if you want to access the essential
amino acid-rich seed oil in the embryo
you don't squish the cellulose you don't
squish the fiber or the bud you take the
seed and squish that or remove the
embryo and ex that's where all of the
essential amino acids are produced in
the plant so it's not like this is my
opinion it's just the way the plant is
if you want to access the cellulose for
making paper you don't use the seeds you
don't use the bud so when it comes to
accessing the medicinal components
whether it's for um
recreational perspective or medical
perspective
it's all happening in this resin gland
and I have people all the time tell me I
don't like hash I just smoked the flour
and I just say well that's okay you're
still smoking the hash you just prefer
it diluted on biomass so that you're
getting less amounts of it and it's it's
different like when you smoke cannabis
it's totally different from when you
smoke hash there's no doubt about that
but if I take the resin off the Cannabis
and I do it really well and you smoke it
you won't want to smoke any more of it
like factual you just the resin needs to
be present on the flower to to create
the high that you're getting there so
glandular trichomes three different
kinds this is a Astro Boy photo I grew
this plant and I photographed it this is
a really good example of the capitate
stalk how tall it is and then
decapitates cecils next to it
when you're producing hash producing
cultivars for the hash Market you know
there's plants that have 40 bulbous
heads so 40 of all the trichomes on the
plant are bulbous and you have to
understand that
they don't extract in solventless
processing they don't extract with
mechanical screen separations they don't
wash off the plant washing and dry
sifting require this long cap this long
stalk with a little head on top where
it's easy to break it off and it snaps
off and then you use a variety of ways
to isolate those which we're going to
talk about for a few minutes after I get
through these photos
another fan Leaf this is always a good
sign you want to grow genetics that
produce large amounts of cannabinoids
I'm not as much worried about high THC
but I do like a very dense amount of of
trichomes and I want 90 to 95 of the
trichomes that are on the plants that I
wash to decapitate stocked and capitate
Cecil I want five percent or less to be
bulbous and if you isolated these these
glands into capitate stalks capitate
Cecil and bulbous you and you hit the
bulbous ones you'd realize they're
they're waxy they're thick they contain
a very unique oil compound that often
lights on fire if you have a flame near
it it's very much like the 45 Micron
bubble hash but very hard to extract and
it's the difference between solvent and
solventless when you have a solvent guy
say
I ran that material and I got 24 and you
have a solventless guy say wow I ran
that material and I got 14 these are dry
weights not fresh frozen where does that
difference come from that difference
comes from the fact that he's using a
solvent or she to isolate or to extract
and melt all trichomes present so all
the bulbous heads are going in there and
if it's 40 you're gonna literally get a
a 40 yield higher than your solventless
counterpart this is also important for
LPS and hashmakers to understand these
things so that they're not making hash
from the wrong genetics if your whole
process is to make dry sift and you're
using cultivars that are bulbous rich in
the glandular trichome area
you're missing the the boat you need to
kind of go back and be like okay we need
to have specific cultivars for specific
processes otherwise uh in these tough
margins that we're in it becomes uh a
very difficult this is a UBC rock star
from Remo the urban grower I thought it
was a good plant to show the anthocyanin
and striations in the capitate stock
these little purple colorets they often
come in through stress
cold different things that happen to the
plant in the fall that's why a lot of
plants produce anthocyanins and
antioxidant it's it's found in blueberry
skin it's found in
um all sorts of different flowers and
it's healthy to take orally not so much
to smoke it it is water soluble so your
water when you wash anthocyanin and Rich
products the water will be very purple
it doesn't very often translate into the
resin itself it can with rosin but very
it's it's less likely with bubble I've
seen it but it's far and few between
just a little bumblebee that landed on a
plant when Johnny B and I were on my
deck One Day filming a puff Wednesday
and this little guy came and landed on
it was one of Johnny B's buds actually
shows you the difference between the
size of an insect and you can see in the
corner here these are the glandular
trichome heads I thought it was kind of
a neat photo uh just to a horrify anyone
that wanted to see what an insect looked
up close but also to show the difference
between a tiny little insect yet it's
still like 50 to 100 times bigger than
those trichomes
some trichomes that were really showing
you know you can see these little
circles are different types of
organelles and so you have plastids and
you have vacuoles and plastids produce
phenols and vacuoles produce
hydrocarbons and those hydrocarbons are
terpenes and so these are the little
Labs that cannabinoids become cooked
into existence it's the reason why I
prefer hash over oil whether it's rosin
or or full melt bubble I find fomel
Bubble to be much more of like a five
course meal because the laboratory that
cooked all of these compounds into
existence is present it gets it's it's
in the resin gland so you're not
filtering it out with heat and pressure
that being said I certainly wouldn't
kick rosin out of bed for eating
crackers uh that's something weird my
dad would have said back in the day
about something else but uh I said it I
said it I thought this was cool too
couple trichomes pounding each other out
respect mom on some Jamaican tricoms
right there
remember what the cultivar was but it
was from my buddy Archie in Kingston
growing great weed it would have been
something gassy and cushy for sure
because that's what those guys loved
this is five minutes perfect this is a
picture of material that I washed this I
will talk about bubble hash real quickly
for those of you that know or don't know
this is a way to purify glandular
trichome heads into a very pure form
isolating them using water and ice
breaking the heads off they sink they're
very brittle in the cold ice water in
the mixture they break and they're still
affected by gravity so they sink in the
water while everything else floats you
end up with a very um clean product you
can see these are all capitate stalks
and cecils with no heads on them so I
clean that plant very effectively and
then you can also see when you clean the
plant effectively this is what your hash
should look like and this is what I
meant by purity this grower this breeder
produced an incredible genetic produced
an incredible expression of that genetic
grew to Perfection all I really did was
isolate the resin glands and purify them
so did I make it did I make the quality
no I created the Purity which unveiled
the quality
unveiling the flame this is some of my
mentor skunk band Sam's full melt dry
sift been sifted to Perfection this is a
much harder thing to do when you don't
have water on your side and everything
is falling through hopefully I'll get to
speak on the difference between dry
sifted these are dry sifted but they're
very clean sorry keep doing that but
we'll go back down here real quick
we're almost done I took a lot of photos
holy [ __ ]
so these are all dry sifts we can kind
of whip through them and then there's
some rosin and some dry sift pressed
this is some bubble hash that's very
fresh but what I wanted to get to these
are these are air dried products from
Barcelona uh really nice orange soils
and and heat that volatizes the product
while it's drying so we're not using
freeze dryers in this instance it
congeals together and it's very
different these are all Air dried
bubbles from back in the day uh
producing different colors this shows
the purity of the bubble we call this
six star full melt bubble uh it melts
into a liquid and it is really the Holy
Grail of the of the hash world I don't
think it'll be sold at dispensaries for
a while I don't think it'll be something
you see your customers coming in and
asking for quite as much as pre-rolled
joints and other hashes but uh we'll get
there as we do it together more rosin
what I wanted to show was what dry sift
looks like under the microscope so you
saw the bubble hash you saw the purity
of the bubble hash this is really
important from a bud tender standpoint
when someone comes in and they say I
want the best bang for my buck I want to
buy a grandma hash and there's a forty
dollar gram of bubble and but there's a
20 or a fifteen dollar gram of dry sift
you have to understand the 15 to 20
dollar gram let's say it's twenty
dollars which is half the price of the
Bubble at 40. the purity of this is ten
percent and if you understand what that
means it means 10 percent of this
product is glandular trichome heads and
active ninety percent of it is not which
means to get one gram of glandular
trichome heads you would have to buy 10
grams of this product at fifteen to
twenty dollars a gram so now you're 200
into your gram of heads versus the Forty
dollar gram that you could have got of
bubble so this isn't a story that the
COA is telling oh well this one's 60 THC
and this one's 30 so 40 bucks 20 bucks
it makes sense it's half the price it's
half the THC
that's just confusing people the reality
is you want to understand when you're
purchasing hash what is the purity of
the hash of glandular trichomes what is
the percentage of trichome heads that
are in that hash
um now don't get me wrong sometimes you
need sift like this I like it to be at
least 20 to 25 percent heads but when we
make our Hazel joints which are the pure
hash joints that have no paper and no
glue it can't be too high of a purity if
it's that full melt bubble and you go to
light the joint and it starts dripping
and melting and it won't burn
consistently then that product is not
going to be effective so there are times
where you want hash to be of this
particular caliber but in my opinion
it's for novel products where you and
and the fact is also it's a much more
Mellow Smoke and a lot of people that
smoke hash I'm sure you guys would agree
with this not most people are not
carrying around Rigs and smoking hundred
dollar grams of live hash rosin that is
a small percentage of the customers that
are coming into dispensaries they want
pre-rolled joints they want gummies and
different drinks and of course herb
eighths and and ounces and whatnot but
uh hash is still very much Niche so it's
all about kind of educating it's a fun
little rabbit hole to go down
um I have a bunch of different social
media you can check out I I my YouTube
channel is called BC Bubble Man uh
bubble man's world and uh there's a show
called hash church I would implore all
of you if you really want to learn about
cannabis and get yourself some phds go
and watch that show there's a couple
hundred episodes it's um me basically
moderating a panel of six to 15
absolutely inspirational incredible High
Caliber people who have lived the
experience that they're sharing patient
stories breeders Growers uh people that
have opened stores Bud tent like
everyone from every aspect doctors and
PhD chemists the whole nine yards we're
all getting together sharing about a
plant that we love and I do hope in the
future to me eat some of the most
gung-ho passionate obsessed Bud tenders
because I'd love to do a hash church
with some of you guys on I like the idea
of the information that you have being
shared to a wider audience because you
guys are the front lines you're talking
to people every day and uh yeah I take
this [ __ ] pretty seriously it's my
life's passion it's my life's work I've
never really done anything else other
than cannabis so I'll finish off by
thanking each and one of you for being a
part of the industry and being a part of
the community more important we have our
own culture we don't need it to be
recreated and uh keep doing what you're
doing sell tons of weed can you believe
you get to sell wheat that is [ __ ]
awesome thanks everybody
[Applause]