[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
damn nice early morning here on my way
to the great gardeners I'm just sitting
at the ferry terminal waiting for the
ferry to come in was gonna have a little
puff and I realized I only brought my D
mail and it's kind of big and large I
didn't bring a bowl for the mothership
so I guess what we're doing here is
we're gonna make the infamous apple pie
always nice to have a screen with you I
have quite a few of these in the car
when I roll so we're gonna be using will
use the pencil here broken in half is
skin we're gonna stick that through the
Apple make it so there's a bowl on one
end and a little mouthpiece on the other
I'll gently work the skin away and fit
that in there and basically we'll have a
pipe so step one make some juice
yummy yummy all right so there we go
come right out the other end
all right get that unstuck go through
the other end
[Music]
to jam it through a couple of times so
we got ourselves a nice little hole and
what I usually do for this part is I
usually fit the screen
and just with mine I usually use a nail
but I don't actually have a nail right
now so we use the the wipes tweezers
that she's got here in her car
we'll just gently poke through the skin
a nice round hole
this part is actually pretty key because
it really solidifies the screen it
really gets the screen stuck in there
and it gives you a nice little bite of
Apple too who doesn't like Apple all
right I'm gonna look something like that
and then wouldn't jam or screen in there
and our screens just gonna sit so flush
and so lovely and that nice so we got a
little mouthpiece on the other end I
think it's time to have a bowl all right
so felines lighters we got bubbles and
baubles all right let's see what we got
here happening open up a little oil
slick cuz we love those oil slicks real
nice way to keep keep the sift in place
so this particular sift is from flat 421
this is his MK ULTRA dry cept not sure
if you can really see that kind of a
little bit dark
there it is there we go until you see
beautiful quality I am I think I cleaned
this actually I did so this is like a
99% err
all right put that right in there little
rip I'm just good to close the oil slick
balls so it doesn't fall
I guess there's really nothing left to
do but wake that bake all right
papal reps
[Music]
lovely I'm gonna take a few more reps
and I think we're gonna jump on the
ferry here
[Music]
[Applause]
please do we need sort of the least
quality know what is that we need a
little bit fall I got my hammock I put
my hash might as well have a quick
little drip we're smoking that hey oppa
the great gardener
drei sympathy
we made and I cleaned up a little bit
now this would be the challenge and we
get the belie lit up
very puppet
must have patience
it's not gonna let me bless I say it
hey guys welcome back actually had to go
into the smoking area of the ferry here
it was just way too windy wasn't getting
the b-line lint and it seemed like a
silly experience
much easier to like a beeline here
I love it I only have four pockets
but I keep jamming the beeline liner
people losing them morning bacon wagons
a little rip
trips in the apple pie
do a couple around to the ferry keep a
bump into any friends
killer whales and dolphins on the
entrance into the Nile
we'll head on up to see the great
gardener so
let's continue on
[Music]
because I should be done this style is
identical they're not something trying
to make a sound like this but you get so
upset it up where cuz you're sweating me
to the paper like hours when I'm
fighting off trapped in the pain the
line
[Music]
hey guys so the ferry just landed here
at departure Bay in Nanaimo we've got
about a 20 minute drive to Duncan
luckily I have someone who can drive for
me today so I'm allowed to medicate yes
because as medical marijuana patients
we're not actually allowed to medicate
and then drive a car or so if you're
going to do your medication make sure
that you have someone to drive your car
for you anyway boom
[Music]
it's the choice
how
[Music]
oh wait no Rachel don't waste time here
just arrived at the great gardeners the
house of the great gardeners and I got
to walk inside and see Matt back in the
house back in the house of the great
gardener good to see you man hey you
know what it's a good dirt though just a
couple pounds we've half pounds on
rounds nuggets that's always looks so
nice
[Music]
is dank that smell
super stoked I guess I should go get the
detail we should set it up alright well
we're gonna go get the D nail I'm gonna
set it up when talk about some plants
and some growing we're gonna talk about
the MMPR today and we're gonna make a
little bit of hash so catch you guys in
a bit
awesome alright so we're gonna set up
the D nail that's just just going to
hear a little bit of the fresh frozen
and some of the dry set that he's got
hanging around it's always fine go to
use the confidence they like stuffed
full of hash
[Music]
yeah down here get some agree on Hayes
swords a different fun stuff Afghani
came across gosh
you got here holidays
good night good nice to get oh geez okay
Matt no problem do a little of that look
at this
it's golden yeah Mitch today go get some
of that sweet see the ones that are sins
we r like the fourth fifth and sixth
runs done oh really
[Applause]
didn't know if I have enough cardboard
so I have to oh yeah and this one is
microplane 19 it's nice and dry looks
great
and that one is whip straight little rip
should we try the 90 he says I don't
know let's see should we try the 90s
some of that
looking good mr. ninety over here 4545
microplane microplane and coming off the
cardboard nice chunks over here at the
end sometimes pop goes first
yes
there we go that was a little bit
lighter right the nineties lighter but
the proper color now it was kind of blue
there
right
let's have a rip that Hank
[Music]
haha I found thee what that meant before
the next dawn good plan it's hard not to
make snakes with hash when you got good
huh come on get it in your fingers a
little bit
rolling up the hashish India styles and
then we're gonna put it on the ceramic
dough a little ceramic dome that's
pretty good
let's see yeah I think so it looks
proper
let's darn fine now let's see your STIs
there was a burn on myself yeah you can
do it
I've faith in you
see the tipsy burglar
[Music]
slow and steady wins the race
that was probably so tasty here tyr's
[Music]
seven hundred and seventy degrees on the
quartz nail with the ceramic insert
equals C tasty
what are you saying about that just a
man super flavourful like almost like
geo cold just that's hard to compete
with that flavor I don't think that was
the 99 one either no no I think that was
just what comes off the trimmer table
which is still quite clean like probably
85 well clean that one and then we'll
compare it to a 99 all right sounds good
all right so I'm gonna take a little rip
while he's waiting for the ceramic to
pull down he wants to do the test on me
I think the first one was just his
lightly bounced very gently seed
collection type of thing over screens
single screen and it he got some
incredible quality 85 percent heads I
took that and cleaned it up to a 99% and
we're just going to show you the
difference
chunk of pyrite
there ya go
oh well that's good
well one thing about the great partners
strains as they do not lack labor flavor
they're so tasty dude yeah from the hey
homeland to the Afghani for the bar that
sweets done I mean they're all just so
delicious flavor I'm free I couldn't
tell you how many strains that is on a
lievable flavor we went through and then
it's just the best of the box over the
years over the thousands of members that
have sampled the strains and told us yes
that one works for us yes you know by
laughing and it's the super flavorful
ones it's a lot here it's not
necessarily the 20% THC I think no I
think that number has really no no sort
of like it has a small place that has a
small place that has one indication I
think it's been a bit of a deceiver
just like now with people like oh I want
to strain with just CBD or I want you
know Bakley because we really don't
understand the full effects of the
cannabinoid profile and how it affects
us you know it's one thing to say all it
had a certain percentage of something
and then just the student it that's the
thing that was helping you yeah when
really it could be that well but what
about all these volatile oils that
modulate and what about the different
cannabinoids the terpenoids yeah but
you're not interpret ions into the mix
and that's exactly people are you
finding that now with turkeys for
enterpreneurs from other plants you know
the mersin for Mango is a popular one
yeah people being able to experiment on
their own
sort of try and modulate your effects
that you're getting from smoking by just
you know eating some amang
for you take a rib it's definitely
something to be said for that somebody
said to that I think I think once we get
the terpenoid profiles done we start
understanding though the differences in
there in ice and that someone comes in
to a club and and they're looking for a
specific Turkey hmm God says this I'm
not looking for the CBE anymore I'm
looking for the alpha toluene I'm
looking for something yeah maybe in a
combination of two like that's why
that's why I think we're worth the
government's getting it wrong with not
allowing extract because this right here
and this stuff right here is the
medicine hit absolutely right this here
this here that's legal has the medicine
on it and it's the messenger and there's
a plant material but you don't need you
don't need the plant material what you
mean is this what you need in kind of
thing like this is like apples being
illegal but you can have apple trees
like you can go to citizen foods a
dynamic will treat you no problem but if
you take those apples off and like make
like an apple crisp you know it's like
it's like them telling you that you have
to eat the whole apple tree that's what
I'm saying they don't want to about us
use the Apple they don't want to I
always you can't take the Apple off and
even have to eat the whole tree yeah so
this is the fight we're fighting here in
Canada they have cannabis they don't
really understand that what we want
about cannabis
the medicine so much like when you order
pizza you open the box and take the
pizza out imagine you were being told
that you had to also consume the box and
then to take the pizza out of the box
would actually be a totally totally the
other analogy right now is the MMPR and
the MMP are saying that you have to buy
from a commercial establishment
essentially that's like saying you can
no longer cook food at home right you
have to go to a restaurant and buy your
food for the rest of your life so pretty
good analogy all right no more cooking
at home because why your use of power
using 220 power on your stove it's
dangerous cause fire and fire hazard
fire hazards how many fires are caused
by stoves
those are dangerous I think we should
ban them yeah and make everyone together
buddy make everybody go to a restaurant
see how that works
yeah that seems people can't grow their
own medicine
come on it seems weak remaining tomato
on my own I can make my own beer yeah I
make my own wine and I'm not opposed to
them having tomatoes available for me if
I don't want to grocery some grocery
store as a grocery store yeah you should
have that's important that hard scale I
have no problem with the large scale the
problem is they're taking the personal
rights away yeah that's definitely well
you know here we are we're almost in our
last month here back you know right
around the corner in the next day I
guess we're gonna be in the March and
once we're in the March that gives us 31
days before we find out about our
injunction when we find out whether
we're going to abide by the law and
destroy all of our cannabis mixing it
with kitty litter whether we're going to
say no we can't abide by this law and
continue to grow cannabis because many
are going to do that and then the other
option is that we win this injunction
and that everything
as is the MMP are still come in it's not
going to hurt their business for the
little guy to be able to grow yeah you
know and when I see yeah I hit but the
injunction still is just the it's just a
pic in the can down the road it is right
that is he kicks I can down the road all
the way up to injunction and then John
wins well that's for Kirk wins there's a
lot so there's lots of fights out there
there are that it's ridiculous there's
one guy out there that his daily limit
is higher than a hundred and fifty grams
so he's yeah he's not even allowed he is
not allowed to even order his daily
limit yeah so you can see they've got a
little a few little things that are that
are it's just a few little things if
they change this thing could just be
fine and no one would have a problem
with it we don't have a problem with
large production facilities and you know
what I mean and when I even say the
little guy like I'm even talking about
guys like Matt in the great gardener
like this is not a jar Joshua's grow
this is this grows a good amount of
medicine for a decent amount of people
but by no means would it ever you know
produce enough medicine for a portion of
Canada's medical and what about what
nominal I think people look at this and
they see your grow and they just think
that's just so huge you know not you do
what you talked about
exactly right way if you talk about this
it's not huge it's not it it's not a
huge endeavor I think I mean it's like
you know like acres and acres should be
under glass
beam grown sections like I'm from the
prairies so when you do things big in
the prairies it's not acres and it's not
hectares its sections and the section is
basically like a mile by a mile which is
interesting
and it it's kilometres but I'm certainly
eating our farmers follow sections that
we still use a mile by a mile that's a
big section of of land to be growing
herd and so you wanted one
this little guy I'll get the camera
close for it no see what we got we got a
few things to do today we're going to
walk through the garden of course
[Music]
90 microns sweet skunk baba
yeah
one more right let's show you at the end
of it looks pretty to her side 90 micro
give it at 90
let me see Oh put on and this is Bob's
no but what he gave me the other day was
is that no that was that would have been
dry stuff that's what I thought
was pressed
Alex
they could receive back in the car
- a nice Rebecca and the crew back there
the crew Thank You Percy terrific
give a shout out there located on
Hastings Street in between closer down
to my shop near Clarke then from the B
CMP like c CH new paper liners that
thing but you can google it to thank you
for seedbank
great canadian seeds great canadian
value can trustworthy people vancouver
seed bank great crew great crew
dick within the next couple of days
great gardener apparel website will be
up be able to get t-shirts pictures like
the wicked
I like the hoodies hoodies Scott's
hoodie really inspired me to get off my
ass and make a great gardener but I have
it GG + GG last couple other goodies are
there stickers lighters I guess we're
talking and hoping that Matt is gonna
join us is in Spain for spannabis he's
not sure if he's gonna be able to make
it happen but he's definitely gonna try
and gonna be there and we just raised
it's been yeah yeah but here's the else
- it's a great I've been for it's like
it's naive I loved like Sunday the last
day they go in and he could tell there's
been a party right Flyers are everywhere
fifty thousand people outside the
building around like trim it's a nice
venue
even the entrance it's almost like the
entrance to the Louvre in Paris we've
got this big glass pyramid it's just
sort of right at the entrance into the
venue and yeah be good
I don't hassle smoke away
and it's going to be 20 degrees maybe 20
degrees so yeah I'm looking to go back
to it I guess we're gonna pop a few more
bowls here and then Matt's gonna move
out there come on the same you see the
state and that's why we always put the
lids back on me except this one that's
something if it's that one this one here
and just on that I'd be on the ground
crying right now but that's not us god
is that great I would say so that almost
has a cat piss smell to it like that is
dead
very nice the fresh frozen there that
planed up to almost perfection with just
that the slightest tiniest little pieces
that are a little bit bigger and they
have this purple that s color compared
to everything else which is white it
looks really nice of course it melts
into an absolute and please liquid then
we'll make sure we get you a macro shot
of this particular hash melting so you
can see what we're talking about it's
really just liquefies and turns this
golden color also yeah I'm gonna get 23
more of those and we'll get into the
garden with Matt keep watching all right
we're gonna head upstairs to one of the
bloom rooms so Matt's already up there
light that looks better
thank you thank you
nanak catatonic room well this looks
great
I'll have to shoot it with the macro
lens yeah yeah it would be great get
some canna tonic this room was destined
for room number two but because the MMAR
is over at the end of March we had just
decided to flour out the bedroom it's
really a
nice little trikes on there
so this is full can of tonic well
catatonic do as much can atomic as we
can
yeah I guess when you grow with the
patient's want people are gonna ask for
the catatonic
we've got eight lights in here
eight lights the rooms only like just
over seven feet tall then you have
everything lifted quite a bit almost
three feet thanks all three gallons
almost three feet dirty
not very
that's so nice to see bugs
little ones sneaking out here
this is the catatonic that we used in
all the crosses to make a whole new line
of high CBD strains we'll go downstairs
and we can actually check some out in
the other room where [ __ ] we're
flowering the final phenotype selections
yes you can have a look at those they're
really interesting high CBD strains I
guess good for anti-seizure auntie
Caesar auntie it's anti-inflammatory
good for pain arthritis you name it
right like the CBD on the healing chart
incorporates about 80 percent of the
symptoms because the major symptoms you
go for what pain relief anti fascist
city yep
appetite stimulation
well it's great-looking herb so these
guys are there in week four or five and
we'll probably put them on water for the
final four four weeks of water perfect
nice flush just want to get that out
there flush your plants if they're not
yellow if the fan leaves aren't yellow
now that I guess they could be purple
and things like that another certain
strains go certain colors definitely not
overly deep dark right you don't want
the dark greens in there that dark green
it's just an indication that the
nutrients are still within the plants
you want those leaves to turn yellow but
that's the indication that the nutrients
are not in the plan
all of us a nice choice there
if I had one more year
I think the entire line available will
be all high CBD I see be the Afghani
dickweed I see VD sweet skunk high CBD
Renee I CBD John ghee you know so
bringing flavors and bring in what the
people love already and adding the high
CBD to it I like just it just putting
the high CBD into it sure right because
it's people who go to profile people are
appreciating why not and it's in its a
mix it's a mix of the of the of the
cannabinoids and terpenoids on the
strains that are already recognized as
medicinal strains and just adding a more
medicinal aspect or for it a sheriff
it's a winning combination
I like it we're an abd you heard it here
first
excellent you can see you can see where
that where that one plants is getting a
little bit too much my day oh yeah it's
kicking ax kick it out weird but look at
that few buds right beside it there it
was yeah it's not far away right it's
just the difference of like that
six knots and four inches support
assistances yeah there it is right there
you can see you can see a few of them
around the skips spattered around in the
room and they're always there all in
exactly the same spot and I think what
it is is not a they're getting the light
that comes directly off the ball but B
they're getting the light that reflects
off the shade and from the other side
there's just that magic little zone that
there's not much you can do about it
go to
oh yeah
some fatties boy
just leaking out it awesomeness
everywhere here
how's it going
so hard to do
you can need a special skill shots and
stuff oh yeah 2022 megapixel camera yeah
it's actually substantial
and looking like they're gonna do they
still have four weeks to or throw yeah
no no they still have probably five
ten weeks
sometimes eleven yeah push it
and then I guess you'll see some
variations in the process or do you
think they'll all be around oh yeah so
now that you sort of see these this
structure and you see how it sort of
takes off like this it's interesting
isn't that when we go down and you see
like the Afghani catatonic and I have
two different phenotypes down there and
what I'm after is is the Afghani
phenotype which actually happened to
have on the next table so you can sort
of look at the Afghani and now that
you've sort of looked at seeing what
this can atomic looks like when when you
see the one Afghani can atomic cross
down there you'll see that it's more on
the can atonic side and it's not what
we're looking for we're looking for the
Afghani traits with the high CBD to it
so right we think we've gotten pretty
close something especially with the Rene
I was showing you a little earlier there
the Rene is very nice can't
oh yeah alcohol soluble terpenes
beautiful
well that the macro lens is out and do a
little bit of triangle macro
so steady wins the race
always happy to be in a beautiful room
the Amelia plant resin approximately 1.8
trillion resin blends on these
particular tables I counted them myself
earlier
the most accurate effects it takes a
couple minutes
anyway we're yeah I'm gonna get the
macro lens out show you some a little
closer up on what's going on in these
plants enjoy
you
[Music]