[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
just a quick little short message I
wanted to share with you guys today I
had one of my employees call me today
and asked me in regards to a video that
did some explaining about the
endocannabinoid system pointing people
in the right directions how they can
learn a little bit about the
endocannabinoids system so I thought as
I was driving home from downtown today
on my way up to the bay I would stop
here where I used to live at beautiful
sunset marina right between Horseshoe
Bay and Squamish beautiful waterfront
properties here about eight of them and
I thought what better place to give you
guys a little bit of a low-down on the
endocannabinoid system so the
endocannabinoid system is basically a
signaling system that allows the body to
regulate biological function through
homeostasis of the immune system and the
central nervous system now it does this
through signals that are basically run
on the fuel that is cannabinoids now
cannabinoids can be produced
endogenously in the body through the
consumption of essential amino acids
this is why they are considered to be
the building blocks of life because
though they build cannabinoids and dajin
is ones inside your body plant
cannabinoids also known as phyto
cannabinoids
can also be obtained by the consumption
either orally vaporization smoking of
cannabis and they have a similar they
also regulate biological functions and
how you can know this without really
doing too much deep research is that
smoking cannabis increases appetite they
call it the munchies it Redden's and
puffs up the eyes this is actually the
release of ocular pressure extremely
important to someone who is suffering
from glaucoma and potentially going to
lose their sight the release of the
ocular pressure in an instant of
inhaling cannabinoids can save one's
eyesight so that's a pretty serious
thing as is the increase of appetite in
someone that's dying of wasting syndrome
producing an appetite in someone that
has no appetite whatsoever is is
miraculous it's why it seems like a
miracle when you give a small child once
drop of this oil and it can eliminate
hundreds of seizures daily down to one
seizure a month it's not a miracle what
it is is it is a very important part of
our bodies it is a very important part
of how we regulate and how we stay
healthy and it has been deemed illegal
for the last 40 to 50 to 60 to 70 plus
years and so now we're learning now
we're learning that you know not just
the smoking aspect of it but the really
important aspect of it has become the
oral if you're suffering really if you
want to prevent disease you should be
consuming phyto cannabinoids orally I
myself prefer to do that through a
coconut oil extract but there is a huge
variety of ways that you can learn to
extract the resins you can learn about
decarboxylation which is a it sounds
more complex than it is it's simply
heating up the resin to the point where
the acids of the rent of the THC CBD CBN
all of the cannabinoids that are in
Assen form they decarboxylate through
the heat and a carboxylic acid ring is
removed and what that does is it
activates the cannabinoids it activates
THC it activates CBD CBN so they become
activated once you heat it you never had
to think about this before because you
were smoking it and of course when you
heat it decarboxylation occurs
instantaneously when you're baking or
cooking or creating an oral extract like
a coconut oil extract we're going to be
using temperatures for certain amounts
of times and I have videos on this very
thing if you want to google coconut oil
hash extraction I did a really nice
youtube video that shows you how much to
use per cup of coconut how long to leave
the crock-pot on for how long and how
long to leave the crock-pot on for how
long and all of those things sort of
taken care of in that way and if you
want to check that video you feel free
to I would also urge you to check out my
facebook group the endocannabinoids
system there is some incredible
compilation of people in there putting
stories and clips and videos and all
sorts of really inspirational
information on
the endocannabinoid system on the
success story of people shrinking their
cancers eliminating cancers or at least
shutting cancers off to the point where
they're no longer detrimental and
life-threatening so that's a huge thing
so I tell people on the regular feed
your endocannabinoid system that's not
to say that if you're dabbing up a storm
that that's gonna take care of business
know it well to a certain degree if you
have glaucoma and you're smoking or
vaporizing you're definitely going to
see an immediate relief an immediate you
know medicinal benefit but if you've got
something more along the lines of
massive tumors you know tremors of other
things that might require a deeper you
know saturation of the endocannabinoid
system and it's one of the reasons I've
been so impressed with United cannabis
and with Blue River is they're acting
out program the activated cannabinoid
therapy program which really sheds light
and what it does is it creates a
landscape for a person to see a phyto
cannabinoid medicinal and preventive
aspect landscape that allows one to see
the importance of the subtleties of
actually stacking cannabinoids and not
just you know taking one plant
extracting it and using that as your
medicine but but extracting many strains
many plants and then stacking those into
these really beautiful prana products
that you can is producing and we're
hopefully going to be producing in
Jamaica with our Jamaica project here in
the next couple of months we're just
waiting to get our clinical trials going
our animal studies so that we can make
sure we know how safe it is but you know
these guys have a way of doing things
that you got to follow if you want to
play their game so that's what we're
gonna do so now I think it's time to
feed my endocannabinoids system I got
some beautiful seven star from Horacio
really nice nice sift and it's grape
crush and I'm hitting it out of the
fabric a egg with the DC glass banger so
I think it's cooled off enough
Rock carb
Rockstone was my pillow is the Bob
Marley lyric but how about rock cab rock
stone was my carb cap there we go
beautiful taste on that on that seven
star that Horatio is whipped off there
the added terpenes really push the
flavor over the top makes me just want
to hit one after another after another
after another which I mean I might as
well do really might as well do so yeah
if you guys have any questions on the
endocannabinoids system this is a real
short little video just giving you some
some background on it you can google
there's a variety of people dr. David
Allen who comes on to hash Church you
can look for him on Facebook he's an
endocannabinoid specialist specialist
Robert mal mal made I think is his name
he's also quite a doctor who's also very
involved and knowledgeable in the
endocannabinoid system you've got dr.
William Courtney who is of course the
specialist in juicing cannabis and
juicing the acid versions of the resins
and really explaining on how medicinal
preventative that those cannabinoids can
be as well so very exciting to have all
of these different people and of course
if you want to check out a really great
place to get updated on the regular
check us out at hash Church right here
on bubble man's world we usually put up
the link you know two or three days
before hash Church starts so you can see
the live countdown and yeah we go four
three four or five hours we talk about a
lot of growing and lights and hash
making but we also talk about the
endocannabinoids system and we have some
pretty you know valid people with PhDs
and Doctorate degrees and really
knowledgeable people in the industry
low-temp Turks if dabs are just killer
thank you for ratio lovin the seven star
dabs here today sitting on the house
sound in beautiful British Columbia just
to give you a quick little reference
this is probably about five kilometers
from north of Horseshoe Bay where the
ferries take you to Vancouver Island
right across the way behind me the
tallest mountain in the clouds is
actually the Sunshine Coast and then to
the left of that you've got bone Island
and to the right of that you have this
little little guy named Boyer it's right
behind me and then the huge islands to
the right of that that are multiples are
called Gambier island so I think that's
all I'm gonna share with you guys today
little endocannabinoid knowledge please
feed yours
every day thanks for watching
you
[Music]