[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
bubble man here it has been a while
we've been doing a lot of live videos
but we haven't done many actual videos
so today I'm heading over to the
Sunshine Coast here on the um BC ferry
very large vessel and we're going to be
heading over to the Sunshine Coast to
see high integrity glass art uh he's got
team Japan he's got Dosa over there he's
got his brand new facility that he just
built and we're really excited to go
watch these guys crush it and uh we're
going to have a nice fery ride on the
way there so I figured uh quick little
intro and uh let's show you guys some my
candy
[Music]
[Applause]
to the real
[Music]
authentic
orig
[Music]
indigenous iic food for man planting
irrigation where you
watering give me full weeks of flowering
full stra with the
raining with the full
bub chrisan where go through
the
orig indigenous
[Music]
orous
indigenous
[Music]
just from the beginning
be careful and you traveling know how
that Pi you
[Music]
medal well they had me at the back of
the ferry so I can't show you guys
arriving on the Sunshine Coast but uh
this is the next best
thing oh it's absolutely spectacular I
guess I kind of have to bring it in a
little bit bring this in a little
bit Kevin nail you have impressed me
once again my
friend you have impressed me once again
also high integrity glass art every day
all the
time fully ridiculous so we're going to
hit this we're going to hit this little
nail
driver and uh welcome back guys we're
here at high integrity glass art as you
can see whenever I have something like
this in my hand it means we're at high
integrity glass art today I've got a
real nice treat for you I got some glass
blowers in from Japan some glass blowers
in from
Bellingham and uh they're going to be
busting it out at one point today I'll
try to get maybe a few interviews at
least some footage of them making some
beautiful glass and uh let's start it
off with a rip shall
we start it off with a
rip I'm guessing this is some
Congo hash rosin that I
have all
right going with wrist technique
today making sure not to Chaz my
friend's
Banger ah the old Chaz Banger what's
going on Prince as you
said as you said
Chaz that's right if you guys remember
my Instagram Prince is the dog that I
made the meme out of where he's looking
over to the right and he's saying that
look you give someone when they Chaz
your new Banger that's Prince
[Applause]
booah
wow that was super
trippy the Dabber the Sor the carb cap
went so close down and the bubble
bubbled up the O the oil and it hit the
Dabber so when I pulled out the Dabber
it had or the the carb cap sorry it had
a full big rip of rosin on
it wow low
temp I think we can save that a little
bit and just give it one little
blast just a light little
blast spectacular
spectacular
spectacular I just want to finish it
back off with this beautiful beautiful
Kevin nail nail driver I think he's
nailed the name the piece is so
beautiful really really lovely great job
man I'll be taking some pictures of this
in the sun today and uh we'll make sure
that we get much more up close and
personal look uh on the really great
fume work that he's done on uh this
incredible implosion marble and uh the
dut penetration so stay
tuned all right look at the sections on
that to me and I'm not very
knowledgeable in glass but to me I see
an incredible amount of technique and
accuracy oh thank going on
here incredible
man yeah I spent spent spent so
much so many
hours for this one
yeah well it's incredible work as always
man thank you incredible
work right lens
today
wow that's just insane
size too oh
yeah oh my
goodness oh my
god well that's insane that's one of
these that's one of these
yeah wow so these are preparations that
you've done this is like like dot work
it's a like a Marini that's what I was
going to say yeah wow
can't believe how you guys got the
colors to
pop that's
incredible what's
that UV oh right you got the UV line
okay yeah check it out UV reactive oh
wow some of here too oh
yeah
jez and what about the other side
yeah oh wow look at that lights
up you guys are off the
chain
off wow you can zoom up like that like
you
get wow all right J's going to show us a
closeup of his most recent section
very nice oh my
goodness yeah that is just
incredible the detail is
absolutely
incredible very very very impressive
work my friends very
impressive that's
incredible jeez
[Applause]
[Music]
W my strike lightning as the morning
break my open wi the sun was up in my
face the wisdom of the wi keep my
straight with the sweet
[Music]
try to Perfection smoke syn I love
the we get the
[Music]
fulling when the rest consume the
meditation and to CB1 and
CB2 can receptors in the brain and body
happiness for me and
you horiz
herbalist
canist herbalistic can
special
herbalis herbalistic can
[Music]
pull it up and give it a
turn yes and I also got
hash full m edes all that dry sa make
you cool and relax and if you get some
you must come
back
heriz can special
origin
[Music]
indigenous
orous
[Music]
indigenous cre them from the beginning
care and you TR in and
[Music]
Pi me sex and
bring I
know
orous
indigenous just
[Music]
you want to hit some foone M Yes Man
[Applause]
[Music]
full full full full
woo oh yeah someone's going to have a
tore yard
up what B it's my
neighbor
awesome is it allowed on the street is
it I don't know I wonder on this street
yeah with a license and Sh with a
[Music]
sh oh yeah
hell
[Music]
[Laughter]
yeah he's having
fun oh this is wonderful that you have
this little trail that you can have fun
with this is really great man nice
[Music]
flowers was [ __ ] awesome bro are you
kidding me that was wicked have you
given all those guys rides uh Yoshi so
far nice he must have loved it he got to
you wanted to drive so oh that's awesome
hey no problem dude you can
drive very fun very fun can't beat it
really all right so we are uh about to
unveil one of the team Japan
absolutely beautiful pieces that all
three of these gentlemen uh all worked
on in the past and I guess uh yeah it's
just it's next level let's just
say oh wow that's really cool a little
Canadian Millie in
there a little there it is now you can
see
it there you
go isn't that much better
hey God what is that like a a
10 not much more that's for
sure oh look at the carb wow that looks
like serum I'm sure it's I'm wrong and
he's going to tell me something else but
uh it looks so cool it looks like it's
made out of liquid
such a nice little carb cap right there
what is this carb cap made out
of the color of the glass is just
amazing serum it is serum I got
something right so is the piece I got
something right nice there's a little uh
mat there sure you guys have seen him on
Instagram go check them out if you
haven't and in the
meantime J
zus honestly
dude this is just so
ridiculous so so so so head
wow wow is the sun ever high when my
camera can be this close and not
producing a
shadow isn't that incredible for
[Music]
[Applause]
when you in my zone
old live in the Gard when you in my
smoke sessions yo pass me the mic
homie pass me the mic like it's a blunt
I'mma light up these lyrics and spit the
funk 5K L base was shaking my trunky
broke the beat down made the crowd jump
I'm dope came here to get you all lifted
coming off of the top it's unscripted
hit this hold it in then exhale grow
with the great white Shake killer well
let's blow bomb get this on where the
party stay popping from Dust to Dawn
squares get gone make room we here came
step through the door in my custom gear
all in the ear now we about to roll keep
it live in the garden where ganja grows
light up the Dank when I'm M dop and
leave the microphone smoking when you my
Z going to get you high going to get you
lifted when you in my zone I get them
lost in a smoke cloud H it when you in
my zone my mic's like a blunt when I
ripped it RI it when you my I get them
lost in a smoke cloud
I'm in my
[Music]
[Applause]
zone when you in my zone going to get
you high going to get you lifted when
you in my zone I get I'm lost in a smoke
cloud when you in my zone my mic's like
a blunt when I R it R it when you in my
zone I get them lost in a smoke cloud H
it now I still got more to blow I ain't
done lyrics that flow and roll off the
tongue smok in my lungs my crew blazing
if you love weed let me see your hands
raising Light It Up rotate the Dank my
way jar filled and I'm ready for the
Friday night life feeling the groove
that's when she asked are you still in
the mood I'm like y step out back and
get tacked burn the whole sack spit some
more raps cat the contact when I bust a
run twist MC's up one at a time my
Zone's homegrown I'm so laced with the
game that was taught in the old days I'm
putting weed in the air for the folks
burn the mic to a ROP when you in my
zone going to get you high going to get
you lifted LIF when you in my zone I get
them lost in a smoke cloud hit it when
you in my zone my mic's like a blunt
when I ripped it ripped it when you in
my zone I get them lost in a smoke cloud
H it
[Music]
bubbl man set up a machine what kind of
strain you have
there so clean and
clear come
on we that in
da it's time da time time
dab
dab it's a Time Time Fresh from the
extractor 100% pure
ganja work this VAP clean and pretty
like ground the of use this good f
just been and fold good father Young on
the whole Every
Soul we're
dabbing da da da da da da
dabing it's a DA time time
[Music]
timeing time time ding in the morning in
the evening dabbing at supper time
dabbing when you're weary dabbing when
you're lonely dabing cuz we're feeling
fine some people ask me what is
dabbing I've got to show you my dabbing
machine that my Buble man bring in
[Music]
we it's a Dao time Dao time time da
da da
da time
da it's good for the end of canab night
system oh lovely oh
[Music]
great yeah we di in
da this is a DA time da time time we
dabing dab da da da
dabing time
[Music]
come on we
ding dab da da
da this is a Dao time Dao time time
we're
[Music]
dabing dab dab dab dab
dab time time been all
[Music]
right don't you worry hry about a thing
take
he's man never give in don't do worry
worry about a thing they care he said
believe me and never
give life is not hard as it
seems take it one day at a time and
fulfill your
dreams remember no one is an island no
one stands alone
in your doing always remember your
theme all when things get hard and
lean hold on to your faith and fulfill
your
beam and
don't
[Music]
wor about thing take keep he's he's man
never give in don't you
[Music]
worry about the thing
take
EAS me never give
me that's St time test of
patience just like in the days of
[Music]
patience remember the man called job he
tried it for RO your
road he know where he was going so he
know where he was coming
from believe in yourself my
friend as you
pursue just in what you go
to and
don't
[Music]
worry about a thing take you he's said
believe me never give don't tell
worry about a thing you he believe man
never he my people keep done the
positive that you're
doing hey kids Fu your back time to go
to
school if stop the got the rolling
You Youth what on the street side Lo
risings about the thing
they he believe me and never give
don't
[Music]
wor
take he's said man
don't
[Music]
you heyo
B why the timber feel good give
[Music]
me one man home man
real we keeps me
going the purpose have the we that to
the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
ding we have been traveling to Kingston
both 20 M hours
on fres vation with trees and
[Music]
flowers me
one that's the way to do it
of the
kill
[Music]
pizza
now and pause that pause that
now purpose after the we that keeps me
going the purpose after the weed that's
to the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine down the road there
be some cops setting up them
PLS
man we
me intervene in my bra St that and
behind your scene me and my team have
another
25 smoke it up
[Music]
clean my
now all right hey what's up everyone I
here with John Green from John Green art
and John is originally from Toronto but
living in Japan for what the last little
three years now three years so a decent
amount of time and he's here
facilitating projects with Team Japan uh
with uh did you want to name the artists
that are here currently right now we
have yos Rose roads ji Kima and disc
from slop yeah all just crushing it
right now about 50 ft to our right and
it's pretty awesome special guest Dosa
came up as well just got here yesterday
yeah no that was pretty incredible he uh
kicked me down this little Marini pretty
stoked on that super sweet never met
Dosa myself but I've always uh uh since
I first got uh exposed to his work as
well as the Japanese artist I've been
you know basically L an awe at the work
that they're doing so uh and I like that
the work that you're doing as well man I
know you threw a show last year in
Canada with uh the team Japan guys and
we have another show coming up in uh
Denver this October nice these three and
and four more and where's that going to
be uh Denver Colorado at any particular
gallery or uh we'll release details this
okay all right sum nice nice cool well
something to look forward to um yeah
it's definitely uh inspirational what
else is going on in the in the future of
uh Japan and the team Japan in the GL uh
Yoshi and and dce K will be meeting up
with Yin out in uh Europe they'll be
doing a bit of glass blowing out there
nice um and then I know there's a couple
guys working in the US right now at uh
ever dream awesome cool and where can
people uh find you out on the internet
there on Instagram John Green art on
Instagram or Google it and find my
website there perfect awesome man well
thanks for doing what you're doing help
facilitating and making uh it
comfortable for these guys to come to
Canada they're definitely yeah dude
they're crushing it in there so see you
guys in the B
[Music]
[Applause]
PE
orig indigenous
[Music]
me money organic food for man planting
irriation where watering give me full
weeks of flowering full St with the
raining
[Music]
with mus the Christian where you got
through
the origin
[Music]
IND
orous
[Music]
indigenous cre from the beginning
be careful and you travel in and out
that pick
[Music]
you sex and
bring I
know
origin
indigenous just
trip it was here on the Sunshine Coast
very happy as always to visit my good
friend high integrity glass art and of
course the Epic quality of artists that
he has in there right now blowing glass
really impressive going to look forward
to coming back and seeing uh that cup
put together because that was a lot of
work just on the back of the ferry here
people are walking on right
now and I think pretty much all the cars
are loaded and the ferry will probably
leave here
soon be able to catch a little bit of
that leave in the Sunshine Coast
experience so beautiful here it's always
just so calm and sunny and beautiful
it's definitely a nice time to come up
here in the summertime house sound in
general all of these islands gambir
Bowen Paisley Hut they are sweet can a
lot of them I think we're gearing up
here maybe one of the last people to
jump on the
[Music]
ferry me
money original original
original IND
you