[Music]
hey guys what up I'm here with Caleb in
nil Jamaica at the stepping High
festival and we're about to try out one
of his Steam ales where can they find
these
www. Ste ch.com or
www.al vapor ch.com Wicked well you guys
got that you can also find me on
Facebook I Vapor steam challenge awesome
we go check out Caleb he's got these
beautiful steam pipes this is the
original vaporizer unit this is uh using
the heat from the coal sucking it
through the way getting down to the herb
which is underneath filtering it
sometimes through water sometimes just
air with a nice bamboo stick mouthpiece
and uh this is how I'm going to be
testing the competition as I'm a judge
and I don't burn Herb I'll be hitting uh
one of these itel Vapor challenges so
keep an eye out
guys smells Goods like
[Music]
I remember let me say
I warm it up a
bit all right that's good I want to get
a bit of flavor off of it cuz it's the
fresh fresh butd and I'm testing it
principal original principal when we use
solution
[Music]
I'm going to go get my tripod first lung
here the Chalice is
ready can you hold it no yeah there we
go long don't stop don't
stop one more right
away taste it
[Music]
wow
yeah that was great number one
tested now what do I have to say about
number
one she was a little bit moist and
that's why I had to steam for a while
before it really started giving me hits
the flavor was really nice
yeah but I think there might have been a
tiny little bit of that sort of fire
cure going on where the smoke from the
fire got into the herb a little bit and
just slightly made the herb taste like
burnt firewood I still tasted the flavor
of the herb it was nice I'll have to go
write some notes down now and get back
to you on number
[Applause]
two we're now going to start with number
two
[Music]
so that's number two going to go give
that to Caleb and throw it in the steam
pipe hey
Caleb all right you sticking around with
it for a bit Mikey don't leave don't
leave man you're going to hang with me
man all right here we go Caleb okay
we're going to put it in this is uh
number two okay number two put right
yeah right away let's do it
[Music]
[Applause]
EXC s
[Music]
sorry
right have to blow in the sh a little
bit to get it back warm have to blow in
the sh a little bit yeah no problem
that's how the steam pipe
Works basically the equivalent of
heating up the nail each time so because
we stopped sucking on the coals for a
while they cool down now we'll need to
pull on the piece a little bit more and
build that up it's a nice part of
steaming how you you get that really
nice rip in your head cuz you constantly
inhaling exhaling inhaling exhaling just
to heat up the herb enough to uh dry out
the moisture to get the hit
[Music]
youbody
oh yeah you're going all right here we
go with number two guys
[Music]
that's a good
one it good it's going great right
now number two right off the
bat grab me way stronger than number one
much drier cannabis maybe not as strong
of a flavor but a really strong effect
propa all right so now I'm on number
three
this is number three right here that
one's pretty good I like that
one it's definitely in my top
[Music]
three number three for those of you that
Miss number
two looks like smoking right now
number
[Music]
one now we're ready for number three the
hazy OG
[Music]
nice
nice flavor on that one really nice give
it a
shot that smells
[Music]
[Applause]
nice one was that
one first so that's number
three all right doing an old school
style here in Jamaica original steam
pipe the first vaporizer once again
Jamaica takes first big
surprise all right time for number
[Music]
four I am oh that's okay problem problem
so I've been trying everything on a
steam pipe but we also brought the herb
iron and we may just very well do some
rosin Tech thanks to soil grown and uh
uh compassion from IC mag the originator
of the rosin Tech milking the resin
glass soil grown is being given credit
for mil the buds and that's what we
might do here today after we finished
steaming all six varieties or seven
sorry uh we're going to we're going to
uh dab
some basically heat press some dabs some
rosin out of the buds we'll be videoing
that so stay tuned
[Music]
this
[Applause]
[Music]
SE good tasting
Shing it for
posterity you
know that's all the r New York
[Music]
you don't want now Tony's hitting the
live resin giddy up what do you think of
this buddy gidy up would be
proud
yep you won't have to smoke for the rest
of the night yeah that's
Lots definitely going deep Hey Paris
said it got him number four all right
we'll come back to the ladies in a
bit Caleb and I are going to hit number
four all right ready I'll let you hold
it
[Music]
nice nice nice
number four tastes pretty nice there was
a bit of a fruity taste to it Alo number
one is the is the best grade maybe a
little bit of the AES got into
VAP while VAP clean
clean oh that was definitely nice I like
how number two and number three yeah
number two and three so far one of my
favorites of is a three ey hit number
four pretty good I'm going to go right
down what I think
now you have one
two three four right so let's take this
one out cuz it's kind of confusing right
now so this is Pure Plant extracts they
look
like infused into a plant here you go
this
one so this is hola kosher all natural
hypoallergenic this is plant fats in
five 10 20s and 50 milligrams that are
separated so this is
thca that comes in active or nonactive
phyto canabo so depends on the patient
this is P2 High CBD a low TCA so this is
ACDC uh Swiss gold Harlequin sour tunami
so this is not just like one CBD strain
there like five this one is a one to one
utilizing CBD strains that are rich in
cvd and cushions and indicia strains so
it's your one to one the black means
it's activated the white bottles mean
they're inactive and I'll get to why I
would do this this fourth one is a CBD
and CBN capsule so there's no T in this
one so what this one is is this one this
one activated degraded and broken down
to CBN and paired with this one
activated and so now you have the
combination of activated decarbox CBD
and CBM so collectively when you take a
five a five a five and a five that's my
stacking program instead of a Rick
Simpson Oil you now can stack your phyto
canono and your canono and it's
nonactive and activated and decarbox
format so you could do fives one week 10
the next 20s 40s that is what to heal
canc cancer so that would be like immune
system it'll start using as a
chemotherapy so so now check this out
this is all into an EHR software that
we're doing here and we're doing
preclinical and clinicals on these to
make sure that they're safer than
Tylenol because I'm not good enough with
114 times safer than alcohol I want 100
times safer than Tylenol talk louder
right so the idea here is that instead
of promising someone a magical strain
this is a combination of sequencing now
these are just capsules so that's your
immune system I also have sublinguals
and sublinguals allow you to have those
inactive and raw so now we can do the
lock your central nervous system and
your immune system so now you have
different notes like a piano or guitar
has 12 traumatic notes now now you have
those notes so I create act now what the
program so I create act now an avonoid
sequencing charart depending on some
inment as an example if you were
insomnia and you couldn't sleep there's
a 20 mgram P4 that has your name on it
that'll allow you to sleep 8 hours be
now if you're sensitive to it and you
slept 14 hours switch to the sublingual
drops and use two at a time four at time
and slowly key in your dose and then let
me know what capsule you need because
then we can key that in or I could do A
Time release trans dermal gel so you
have problems sleeping this is amazing
no no you haven't even gotten to amazing
yet so this is this is the P4 this is
the P4 trans dermal
gel doesn't smell like so this is like a
patch but you just rub it on so nobody
knows you're wearing it it's like a
clear gel that sits on your skin and I
can make this time release so would you
this is cbda and CDN combined so you
just do this right that's it that's it
and what will happen transdermal it goes
into the bloodstream release arthritic
pain or what did it my Dr come here come
here
here amazing so the sublinguals allow so
the sublinguals you can boil so they're
inactive and you can take them home and
boil them in water and you get activated
cuz boiling water is 229 inside the
little container you're hitting the 284
Mark which is what activates t a lighter
is 451 bakon is 350 all of those things
kill all the medicinal properties so
when we talk about raw foods it's 118°
and below and so with cannabis anything
anything under the 300 mark you start to
get into it phyto can avonoids and it's
Pam medicinal value but TP boil off at
104 114 120 they start changing
molecules and those are modulator so I
do a full plant full profile extraction
on a plant all three parities addressed
and the Turing pull back out and put
back into
[Music]
it all right so we're on number
five here's number five for those of you
that haven't seen number five just going
into the chellum pipe
all right this is number five as
well stick a little more in
[Music]
there all right how's it going
man getting some good photos nice I'm
going to have him light up this okay no
problem yep mine too side yeah my phone
blew up till it
[Music]
died back with Caleb and we're back with
number five let's get rid of that big
light behind us there there we go get
rid of that all right so here we
go you hold it bubble man make this
[ __ ] bubble
[Music]
really nice flavor on that one nice
reaction on that one
too great Spector and properties on that
strain right there this is number five
yeah number five really grab me by the
throat peppery in my nose almost making
me want to sneeze you should give it a
[Music]
shot gummy tastes like bubble gum y I'd
have to concur that tastes like bubble
gum number five let's see uh that's what
it is see you in a bit
all right number
[Music]
six number
six number five
[Applause]
best and now number six this is a cup
yeah we've got number six right here I
have number six right here and um I'm
going to take one more vape out of five
let's do it
[Music]
we
nice all right next up number six
[Music]
that was did you do five yep I just did
five we just dropped our coals we don't
have tongs
[Music]
[Applause]
I'm on six
now let me tell you thank
you can we go H over here Caleb a little
bit in a better life something to do
[Music]
Tony well Tony's finished all seven
strains I finished five I've got six and
seven we photographed them all and if we
have enough time we're going to do a
little of the parchment trick at least
try it with one butt and if it works and
we get a dab each then I suspect we'll
whip through the other six
we and get a dab of each one of those
I've got the torch right here got the
mother ship with the quartz bucket
it could happen I'm just
saying the even
ready I'm doing
[Music]
this to take
time wouldn't expect you know give us
six in half an hour
wor it's all a part of the process you
[Music]
know we're on six yeah we're on six this
is number six right
[Music]
here
something got we I'm from a we
[Music]
it's quite aead getting
nice is
investing got
interesting so
to arres that's real nice number seven
all right number seven that's what I'm
talking about number
seven
you
remember you must expect this event will
[Music]
be we found out we picked 735 and the
actual Ste Ste was here from Quantum
camp and they actually the test results
were 735 as well 735 to the Quan cam 735
to Bubble Man and
Tony amazing amazing it was close we
even had a
tie
[Music]
amazing pick ACC to number
number seven
was number three five follow the test in
this
[Music]
7 I don't know the
winners so we don't know nothing other
than the
so you have to based who you
know and then tell us what train is that
controversial then you can tell us is it
controversial correspond they correspond
oh okay so it corresponds to what people
think
too I even
know they
[Music]
the test come down to who judg the test
accordingly based upon your experience
based upon your knowledge based upon
your history with dealing with so the
last words is from the individual with
your experience okay you gave us
identical reading as what the computer
did pretty much it happy with that yeah
it gives you a good we can't we can't
well I gave you a human radar I said
it's somewhere between 10 or 11 and 14%
and most of the test results were
between 9.5 and 133% right up to the
core of what you said THD level that's
what the
reading computer
was perfect so we represented good
completely that's what I'm saying I know
we don't
know the announc
is we're all in
[Music]
the stepping High Festival 12th
annual n
[Music]
oh I use the herbs for more than one
reason I use the herbs throughout every
season
I for medicine and
purpose I use the Earth to maintain my
focus
King we got many different kind of
hers
glucoma bronchitis the
cancer King Jamaica we got many
different kind of her I'm s nurse I'm s
doctor I'm s priest I'm s
preacher and it's a
[Music]
reality go do your research and see as I
use the hers more than one
reason I use the
hers every
season I use the for medicinal
purpose I use the Earth to maintain my
Focus use the hers more than one reason
herbs to maintain my
Focus use the herbs for medicinal
purpose
my I use the herbs to maintain my
focus relieve
depression anxiety
relief treat breathing disness like
asthma strengthen the body's immune
system it produce longevity and long
life and long life and long life and I
use hers more than one
reason I used
the every
[Music]
season
e e