[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with my good friend Sarah
Sunday the founder of the karma cup
which uh I guess we're going on uh year
three now year three yes three that's
pretty awesome so that's what we're
going to talk about today we want to
kind of get a little update on what's
going on what's planned how it's going
to be the dates etc etc and I thought
what better way for Sarah and I to sit
down we've got some beautiful West Coast
concentrate uh bubble hash here and of
course uh some lovely Heavenly days
Rosen uh both sweet skunk and uh
congales so I did promise we would start
out with the sweet skunk cuz what better
way to really get into a conversation
about
a cannabis Festival is that what we
should call it yes cannabis Festival
that's exactly it exactly so don't be
limited in your thinking thinking that
the karma cup is just a cup that might
have been a misnomer in the early days
of naming it but the karma cup is going
to be much more than um than a than a
Cannabis Cup not saying that a Cannabis
Cup is is a bad thing it's a wonderful
thing when it's done properly it can be
an exciting uh experience to to be a
part of I've been going to them for 25 5
years myself but in this day and age
it's nice to see the sort of educational
factor and and more factors being taken
into play rather than just let's get a
bunch of people that love pot get him
into a small room judging give some
trophies away yeah yeah we're taking on
all the aspects of cannabis culture and
celebrating them that's awesome well I'm
really kind of looking forward to this
it's uh it's going to be on October it's
October 22nd and 23rd in Toronto which
is the weekend before Halloween sort of
Harvest Festival time everybody can
bring the goods oh yeah that's good
timing actually on that sense yes more
people should pay attention to that it's
also there's less going on so it's just
like a perfect time to get a crowd and
we haven't had a smoke out in months and
everybody's looking to have a good time
and get together again my God does this
resin has it ever taken on a nice um
texture in the in the sun you know it's
beautiful yeah I feel that we should uh
do ladies first
ohwe de no no my mom taught me well my
mom taught me well actually using this
as a carb cap okay it fits so perfect y
the only thing you really have to be
careful of is because there's resin in
there yes it'll melt down it'll melt
down and it was giving me endless rips
the other day I I was over with Brett
and I was just like I was like man I
can't seem to finish this this hit and
he's like bro look in your jar and then
he had all this freeze-dried bubble that
had melted down the sides and it just
coalesced around the bottom it was
pretty classic there you go okay awesome
thank you feel free to take half of that
or a third of it or all of it whatever
you like we're going to be dabbing here
for a bit so no need to get completely
zombified before we get our message out
to you
guys almost left Sarah hanging there on
the carb while I was yammering did you
guys notice that someone will be posting
put the carb cap on like come on man fre
it
up thank you oh that was tasty oh the
sweet skunk's so nice that was hella
tasty super nice so yeah like tell us uh
tell us a little bit about I guess you
know maybe let's start from the
beginning how the karma cup started cuz
it really was not something that I would
say happened naturally it seemed like
you were really like an a force behind
it saying this is happening yes while
other people were like I don't think
it's going to happen you're like no you
don't understand this is happening cuz I
remember when how all that happened and
I did get to be at the first Karma cup
uh it was a bonus cuz I was heading to
Jamaica anyway I just happened to be in
town for that timing but yeah like tell
us how it sort of started the the
thought of developing a cup and then how
the cup evolved into a festival and to
kind of lead us up to where we're going
to be in the next couple of months when
it happens okay so um my reasoning
behind creating the festival or well not
even the festival let's start at the cup
with the cup is as a grower I wanted to
get more value out of the competitions I
was entering so my thing is um I want to
give the Growers as much promotion as I
can for their products um so we have
like a profile online we we take
professional pictures of the stuff we
post them online we post them on social
media we give you links we you know you
can't there's more than just like the
possibility of winning a trophy and
winning some bragging rights you get
some lasting value behind that we
basically started that Trend I was
always frustrated that I'd find out
about High Times or some cup uh
happening and then you couldn't even
find pictures of any information about
the winners you just see a name and it's
like well what how useful is this
there's all this value there's all this
content that could be created so I we
try to maximize our content and create a
lot of lot of value for everybody
involved so I'm also um all about
getting um a good pack of uh contestants
for or good pack yeah pack of
contestants for these judges to um
evaluate um so I go around to all my
friends and everybody I know that's a
grower or producer has a company and I'm
like twisting their arm behind their
back and saying you have the fire please
bring it right
you know go I know you've got a lot
going on and everything but hey we
really want to smoke your stuff and um
that's worked out really well for a lot
of people they've made made their brands
off of it so I feel like we're giving
value to the judges we're giving value
to the competitors everybody gets a good
time now we're making it bigger we're
making it so that you don't have to just
buy a judge's pack to be able to enjoy
even if you're in a loow income or
disability issue or something like that
yeah which is always an issue for some
for sure well and it should be a
person's choice so now if you want to
just come in for the weekend it's like
15 bucks it's super cheap really
accessible to everybody I think it can
be afforded basically by anybody and
it's also um level like you know if
you've got a wheelchair or something
like that you can get in all my other
basically everything else was upstairs
so now now it's accessible to all the
price is accessible to all we've got
Festival amenities we've got like glass
live glass blowing five torches going
we've got a live uh visual art show with
lots of um graffiti art and other kinds
of visual art um we've got all those
artists the Glass artists and the visual
artist selling their stuff in the
marketplace we've got a glass
Marketplace and an artisan Marketplace
we've got a couple different vendor
areas for different types of booths
we've got um a medication zone for
patients um where there'll be like
extract artists and producers and
dispensaries located and we have um uh a
medic another tent um that's like a
6,000 fot medication tent Vapor Village
type tent and I've got we can we're just
going to have a large Vapor area in
there um plus six booths that face onto
it pretty Prime Booth I would say um and
part of that space is going to be chairs
like about a 100 chairs for our speaker
stage which normal is working with me on
the speaker stage and we're programming
some interesting panels to actually
really get into issues that are going on
in cannabis and Canada today and our
industry and um broadening and spreading
more information to everybody that might
be interested um I think that's a big a
big plus and bonus because that's uh
that's what gives the people that
ability to you know they can go and see
all the other stuff but it's like you
can really take something back when you
see someone speak at one of these events
where it's inspirational knowledge you
cannot believe that you're hearing it
and obviously the knowledge I'm talking
about would be you know any of the
medical sort of uh Miracles that people
call Miracles but are really sort of
descri Des as simple endoc canabo
deficiencies it's really important to
have that aspect of the education for
your audience and I'm definitely glad
that you're doing doing a speaker stage
yes it's totally important actually we
want to get all the aspects in there you
know we've got the fun we've got some
education we've got various types of fun
various types of Education we've got
some good food trucks coming I'm not
really using that as an income Source
I'm just trying to provide excellent
food for the people that are involved
well what a bonus you know when and I
think that the fact that you're not
coming at this from a from a like oh
I've been in marketing for 15 years and
I always liked herb I thought I would
put the two together I like that you're
coming from the it's like well I'm a
grower cuz that's I met you as a grower
that's you know before the karma cup you
were Sarah the grower and so that's your
perspective that you're coming at it
from like oh I'd like to see one of
these events like you know give more to
The Growers cuz that's I'm a grower yes
and so instead of like going around and
bitching about how all the other cups
weren't doing that you created your
own from a grower perspective so that's
uh it's very cool I look forward to it
October 22nd and 23rd I'm going to be
there I'm going to be there probably
under my bubble man brand and the Blue
River extracts Canada so we're going to
we haven't discussed exactly what's
going to go on but I suspect that there
will be some sort of uh tpine tasting
booth and maybe we'll get some uh
tarpine champagne some tpan made up for
the event but uh it should be pretty fun
I'm definitely looking forward to coming
and seeing it's always nice to see you
know who in that Community is
representing at this particular cuz I I
like to go to most of the events whether
it's you know an event for LPS or an
event for doctors or an event for for
for extractors or an event for Growers
or an event that covers many of those
things which I'm I'm really more of a
quiver guy these days I started out it
was like oh all he does is he smokes
bubble has and and I was like well no
that's not really true like I also like
dryft and I also now like rosin and I I
like to expand and have you know the
quiver it's nice to have a bunch of
these in here rather than just one yes
you know and I think that for for a
while this is what cops were MH and then
slowly but surely we're seeing you know
like man cannabis can bring a lot to the
table so much so that it can dilute you
in anything that you do if you focus on
too many of the aspects of it right I
have 15 categories this year yes 15
there's unev yeah I've got I added two
more Bud categories so I'm going to try
to list them all off I forget anything
I'm sorry no no that's cool you did just
take a giant dab of sweet true and
there's like 15 so it's like it's more
than two hands so it starts becoming
problematic Okay so we've got uh IND so
for the bud we've got indicia sativa
hybrid CBD organic we've got um shatter
like the solvent ex ract shatter indicia
sativa hybrid butter um THC distillate
solventless
um vapor pen disposable pen um edible
topical and functional glass I got them
all I use three hands so that's pretty
incredible when you think about it yeah
and the trophies are all um Handmade by
Patrick in in Canada in in uh red in a t
area I believe yeah he is up there
beautiful area y y I love that he's like
the hillbilly glass blower that lives in
the in the in the in the bush cuz that's
like my style yeah I could
completely live in the bush in a cabin
and be as happy well I kind of do except
my cabin's a little bit bigger it's just
a really nice cabin as all it's a big
cabin but we still live in the bush well
you've got coyotes you told me last time
oh yeah coyotes and cougars and we've
had big black bears on the deck yes the
black bear definitely were in nature
here for sure I'm in the country but I
don't get that quite amount of wildlife
on my I get deer that like to come up
and eat my tomatoes out of the garden
right my blossoms bastards so we should
talk a little bit more about the cup in
regards to um tickets for people that
want to come and just spend a day or
want to spend two days they don't want
to enter or people that do want to enter
let's go through the uh the cost of all
the different ways that you can
participate at the karma cup okay
totally um there uh we'll start out with
the the easiest way to get involved
which is general admission ticket and
you can get either um a one-day ticket
or a weekend pass off of the website
which is
www.the karmac
cup.com um there's just a buy tickets
button on the front page super easy um
it's through Eventbrite I think it you
buy it right on the page it's super easy
um so that's that's easy um the next
next way you can get involved is by
either entering or judging I have an
application for judges on the on the
website again the karmac cup.com really
easy again button on the front page
apply um we go through and basically
just make sure that you're um can handle
the capacity and have the ability and uh
experience or we're looking for a broad
range of different types of people but
um especially medical patients people
who really consume right cuz it's a
tough job taking like you know the first
year I had 80 entries and the second
year I had 100 um so um oh entering
that's I guess the Third Way you get
involved is if you're a grower producer
Baker um topical maker some type of
cannabis product manufacturer you can
enter this year I'm limiting the C the
number of entries to two per category
except for edible which will be one per
category um I've got full details online
about um the the amounts uh different
categories it's uh www.the carac cup.com
entry-form there's again a link right
off the main
page um yeah and for people out there
for a grower that might be watching all
these YouTube videos and seeing all
these different characters you got Remo
and John Bell and d420 K and Bubble Man
and all of these different people that
you're looking at you know you can go to
an event like this and the majority of
them could be the people that you're
competing with you know if you want to
see how well you stand in the in the
game if you want to show people that
you're a great grower and kind of get
that word out cuz everyone believes
they're a great grower but it's
definitely a little bit nicer when a
whole bunch of other people agree for
you and you get a trophy with yeah and
you get a little thing and then it's a
recognized thing so it's definitely for
people that are trying to get jobs in
the industry whether they're trying to
get their herb picked up by a dispensary
or they're trying to get a a job with a
dispensary it's not believe it or not
going to hurt you to have uh a Karma cup
win on your resume um the I should the
last thing I should mention is that the
the date I actually needed in our hands
is September 8th which is really soon
it's the end of next week basically so
if you're interested in entering there's
um a link off the the front page enter
the karma cup and um we just ask you for
the information and get back to you
about how to get it to us perfect yeah
so we're there's enter any one of the
categories
sounds pretty simplistic for sure I hope
that you guys watching Bubble man's
world uh enter something in the
solventless category as I would love to
uh check it out I'm not by any means a
judge but I'm sure that I I'm there I am
a judge you told me you would guess
judge oh I am solventless okay sorry I
am a judge I'm a guest judge so if you
want me to judge your material then I
would love to see it show up uh in
Toronto at the Cara cup for October 22nd
and 23rd although you heard her
September 8th or 9th it's 8 September
8th so get your bags going maybe sift
might be a better short then it's dry
man so many different beautiful ways to
enter solventless nowadays yeah rosin is
great I do I do suggest that if you
really want if you have something
incredible in the dry sift or bubble has
range that uh there's just so few people
really at that level that enter these
cups that uh it's definitely it's
anyone's game at any time I mean any of
these things could easily place you know
Heavenly days they're Ros and beautiful
absolutely West Coast concentrate I'm
sure they would have no problem I'll
definitely be letting both of them know
uh to enter in the solventless category
of Wonder thank you Karma cup yeah every
all the judges will be so happy now
would you like another little dab I
would love another little dab you know
me it's like when Remo says what time is
it what time is it Remo with the classic
point it's just one of the nicest people
ever always look forward to visiting him
and Sandra truly a saint yeah and
involved for so long in in the Cannabis
industry I'm sure uh if he can he will
be at the karma cup I I I I'm gonna
twist his arm tomorrow actually yeah I
mean he's pretty easy as long as he's
not like
in Spain or something exactly I'm sure
he'll come it's it's all good and um I
love I love R and row and Sandy very
much so I having them there would
definitely make me very happy and see
who else we can rope in there's um I've
got a few contenders so it should be get
noton is coming of course he is so there
you go if you want to compete against
the great Gardener you want to see how
well you can do against Matt bring your
solvent list to the table your rosin
your bubble hash and your dry sifts it's
always uh I know there's some amazing
amazing quality in Ontario because I
have friends that live there and share
little bits with me and I'm I'm
definitely going to contact a few people
and say you should try to enter this cuz
it would be very nice now that you're
judging especially is going to be more
fun absolutely yeah it's always fun to
do a little judging especially when what
you're judging is really worthy yes yes
well and I'm doing um full lab testing
and paying the big bucks we go for the
MB Labs excellent yeah so um excellent
I'm sure that was another thing that we
hadn't quite covered yet but there you
go the karma Cup's going to be doing the
full lab testing so microbials and
pesticides not the pesticides that's
$300 a test that's that's that's uh
totally but uh I would love to do that
if I could I really would you know what
this brings up another Point wouldn't it
be nice to see the the game improved and
lab testing in Canada abely like I feel
like I I I went and surveyed the entire
landscape of who was out there to do
this testing and there's not very many
places and most places take a long time
and are fairly expensive well I think
for the fact that considering it was
basically on the law on the books
considered trafficking when you brought
your mm mmpr cannabis or cash or
extracts to the lab and gave it to them
that was trafficking I think because of
that a lot of them stayed out of it but
I think now that the government is
allowing for mm mmpr acmpr patients to
um legally have their materials tested
so when they give it to the labs I guess
basically the I don't know if the labs
are going to be having to acquire a
special license to be able to possess
they they have to get a licensed dealer
right right now so I don't know if that
will change in the future right makes
sense that something along those lines
I'm not really down with all the
[ __ ] regulations at the same time um
it seems to be somewhat needed as I've
seen in the non-regulated market
anything goes and of course anything
goes means if you can trick someone into
purchasing something that's not as good
as what you said it was a lot of that is
happening in the dispensary uh and in
the black market industry right now and
un you know it's insane what the LPS
have to jump through but part of that
you know I'd like to take the [ __ ]
out that they're all having to jump
through and just make it real like make
make the playing field level for
everyone but it's like listen you have
to jump through the I don't care how
much it costs you have to we're doing
pesticidal tests on this we're doing
microbial tests we're making sure at
least for a medicine if it's a
recreational thing well my God they sell
cigarettes is recreational so probably
you don't have to regulate it too hard
you could probably literally make the
Cannabis radioactive and still sell it
legally in a recreational Market but for
a patient Market it has to have a little
bit more of a higher driven ethics I
think yes well I mean we have to try
right yeah and that's what we're doing
so I look forward to seeing you in
October for the Cara cup yes uh well you
should have lots of fun people there I
think Patrick's going to come and blow
glass absolutely and I also talked to um
Crockett the other day and he said he
was going to be trying to make it out
not not necessarily to enter he didn't
know that that was a possibility but
definitely just trying to be out there
and connect love that wouldn't that be
great yeah I was speaking to him as well
and both he and his wife and they're
lovely people um I've I've uh had some
dealings with them before we've had some
coffee it was good um I think that we're
on the same level and I don't see why it
can't
happen well I'm looking forward to it I
hope that you guys out there in bubble
man's world can get the word out you can
check them out at their
website which is the karmac cup.com
that's uh t h e k a r m a cup
p.com so pretty much from there they can
get as much information about this as
possible yes absolutely that last dab
got me stupid I'm about to finish
getting properly anymore I'm
like gobbly go is coming out of my mouth
that I don't didn't quite mean and you
know you're getting me [ __ ] up well I
you know that's you're what you doing
you're the real deal suddenly I won't be
able to like ex uh
articulate I know you I know you can
handle it well I can handle it will I
make any sense no I think more than you
think yes anyway thanks guys for
watching we hope to see you at the karma
cup October 22nd and 23rd I will be
there and thank you Sarah Sunday for
coming and hanging out with us thank you
thank you very much peace guys bye