[Music]
do you have all right so what is this I
have is this Barb or Homa that's that's
the hom okay is this the one I cleaned
yeah oh [ __ ] yeah this looks really nice
just on the rim here greased right out
though where' you put
the what are you looking for two dabbers
right in front of
you no the ceramic disc oh it's on the
Dabber right in front of
you cool
oh it'll be almost cold now that ceramic
is pretty
good it is pretty darn
good oh
wow some nice nice
nice pretty excited about that
okay we're getting it out
[Music]
there uh hey
dry sift cleaned the [ __ ] up on the
ceramic dish and uh ready when you are
man ready
[Music]
oh
list old people they tell you no
[Music]
Li
you you
[Music]
all
right so this room is uh all the canonic
uh CBD High hybrids uh we got Afghan
digweed Warlock and Renee in here and
some of them we have multiple phenotypes
so let's have a look at them and uh you
can you can uh see which one you
[Music]
like so here sits the
Afghan ah the Afghan now you're going to
short Christmas
tree Indica all the way right so we
wanted to create a high CBD version so
we crossed it with the canonic that you
saw
upstairs now I have two phenotypes here
of The Afghani cross with the canonic
this is the Afghan canonic number eight
this is The Afghani canonic number six
you can see this one's a little bit more
short Stout the bed structure is similar
to the bed structure of the Afghan
whereas this one shows this one shows
you know side branching out sort of the
main stock uh and more of the canonic
traits that like we saw upstairs
when
choosing you know which one is going to
be the Afghani catonic or CBD Afghan but
right now our bet is right
here interesting and that's just from uh
how it looks and how it grows and then
and then the final one will be sort of
how it smokes we'll make sure that it
smokes similar to The Afghan and then as
long as it does then sort of the CBD
afgh will be born now we know it already
does uh that's why it was chos and we're
down to two we started with 50 uh
so excellent oh they look great find
some gems I like them right side by side
too these ones are definitely a little
bit taller and have that more pronounced
Cola
yeah stretchy right they're stretching
yeah perfect right perfect example A lot
of these we hav't top but some of them
we have so like this one we never topped
this one we did but so you can see this
one has four large tops where this one
that
[Music]
doesn't I got uh in another room I'll
show you top versus uh non-top
experiment everything in this room has
been top uh no has most think some of
them haven't been top this whole table
hasn't really been
toed look at the got a good experiment
the other to show
it I love the difference in the color of
the leaves there yeah the light green
and a little bit of the intensity off of
the adjusted Wings there'll be two
strips that go down and work it's just
it gets enough of the crossover light
that that set that strip requires a
little bit more nutrient than say down
the middle strip right um you know I've
tried everything to raising the lights
lowering the lights you can raise the
lights within the adjusted Wings you can
squeeze the adjusted Wings in and out we
always end up with those two strips but
oh well yeah it's interesting yeah it's
interesting stuff but here we get we
really get the advantage of the adjusted
Wings cuz the adjusted Wing hits the
adjacent table whereas normally you
would have a wall here you get the light
to come here and bounce to come back in
well here it bounces off of that that
and comes over here and this what
bounces it comes over here oh it's great
so this is a great experiment to sort of
show how many
uh tables you can do and and you sort of
gain light by adding
tables and so we've got our afghanis
then we've got our Afghan
canonic and then we got
[Music]
our over here it say dig weed
ah the digweed and what is the digweed
the digweed is uh now it's a sweet too
cross it was a member of the Vancouver
out Capac Society they started up a
couple sweet uh Sweet Tooth seeds and he
ended up getting two really nice
phenotypes one ended up becoming the POI
which is a very popular strain at the
vix and then he ended up giving us the
other one and we loved it just cuz its
flavor and its structure it's easy to
grow it's it's uh you know super thick
stocks it could really hold its weight
so we ended up taking that sweet tooth
and then Crossing it with the Afghan
that you guys saw over there to try to
give it a little bit more of that
Christmas tree structure and and
strength
uh and then it got its name because dig
weed the cat it's his favorite strain he
loves it so he's a he's a famous cat
that's known to trim bu
and he has a good old time so this is
his strain digweed and then we cross
that with the canonic to get some uh CBD
in it now this is the only phenotype
that made it all the way through the
gauntlet uh to the end of uh you know
looking like
digweed uh you know finishing growing
everything that sort of digweed is and
has the CBD marker in it so this di
we just have a couple little extra acgh
canies thr some of this and if we come
down
[Music]
here we have the CBD warlock now this is
one phenotype this isn't the phenotype
this is actually the phenotype that I
don't
particularly like uh it doesn't really
have the the Warlock it's just that sort
of diesel
gasoline uh petroleum sort of smell so
greasy and and uh it's such a such an
amazing flavor and taste and feel that
to have a CBD warlock it really has to
have all these traits to it so I have
another one it's not not here uh it's at
another room uh it's a little bit better
but it's
it still had you smell it it still has
it still has that uh it has the the
smell just not it's
there it's definitely there and then on
this table we have the Renee the end of
the Renee project the
Renee I'm definitely going to be stoked
on Rene as always
yeah so here we have the Renee number
two this is the a number seven this one
isn't uh this one doesn't have the cvd
marker for it but it's it it was such a
a beautiful plant that we had to keep it
and then it didn't have the CBD marker
yeah it doesn't have the CBD marker but
it's such a beautiful cross between the
two that we just had to keep the the
phenotype you can see you can see how
beastly it is
yeah and then this is the
rc11 rc1
and then you can see so if you zoom in
if you sort of zoom in on those tops
yeah you'll see that you know they're
not very small and the
hairs don't really extend like I want
them to now if you come over to like
this one's the this one's the seven you
can see how it has that sort of
Snowball Effect to it and even and then
even the number two the number two
it's not it's not as good as the as or
as the number
seven but it's just it's the way they're
stacked and and the healthiness of the
of the plant compared to the 11 but
these are both renes they're both renees
and they're both High CBD so we just got
to figure out which one's better well
Rene sure has an amazing tpine
profile yeah yeah
[Music]
awesome so yeah this room will finish up
in the next 4 weeks and I guess we'll
shut down oh well or John Conroy will or
Kirk tuca the great lawyers in our
community will get the injunction and
get us our personal grow rights back
because
because look at all the great work
you've been
doing gives us the
opportunity figure out what the members
are you know they what they want so
we'll we'll actually take say those two
afghanis and and we'll give them to the
members of the
club and let them choose let them choose
which one's best sure cuz it's they
always they'll always let you know for
me man that one I got up I got I've had
ladies I've had ladies show up and they
be like I got out of bed for the first
time in 2 weeks because of that specific
strain just like I'm here today because
I smoked out strain and allowed me to
get out of bed and now they want to tell
you that you can't grow it anymore I
likeed your analogy earlier of uh you
know you can't you can't make food at
home anymore yeah yeah it's illegal to
make food it's illegal to make food at
your home now you have to go buy it in a
restaurant that's the analogy to what
the the mm mm cancellation is is you
can't buy food anymore or you can't make
food at home anymore you can't use your
stove at home anymore because your stove
is a fire hazard it has the capabilities
of burning your house down it's going to
burn the community down so you can't do
that you have to go out and you have to
take your family to a restaurant every
single night and eat every single day
every be a little more expensive but uh
you know what it'll be safer it's safer
for the community right right that's a
great that's a great that's a great uh
plan I don't know I got to I got to say
I feel pretty safe right
here like in this
Garden I feel safe
warm yeah
wonderful it can't go away the house of
the greatek gardener can't go away and
nor can any of the other Canadian
Growers who have licenses and are
licensed to either grow for themselves
or friends family loved ones
we need to have these rights we need to
be able to access this
medicine and most importantly we need to
have it be an open gene pool you know
you can't Corral it into such a small
amount of companies because you'll
inevitably turn the Jean Pool into a
into a bit of a trailer park well you
just regulate the clubs right the clubs
that are existing already service tens
of thousands of people why why are you
not just regulating the clubs like it's
just you're just a ridiculous
program uh you know the only people that
can access it are people that have
millions and tens of millions of dollars
that can build these super sophisticated
systems to grow a plant that's already
been helping people
for Millennia million
years like if you need a really you need
to really grow it in a in a sterile
environment like it's these aren't
pharmaceutical things these are like
tomatoes do you grow your tomatoes in a
super sterile lab and then irradiate
them and then iriate them and then send
them back grind them into pulp right you
want to make your own
alcohol make that we can make that at
home you can make beer at home you can
make you know why why can't why can't
people just grow their own medicine why
we why why you allow people to grow
medicine for 12 years and then all of a
sudden say nah you can't do that anymore
well the bottom line is it's not going
to happen we're going to fight it no
one's going to allow this to happen the
government has to sort of give their
head a shake and realize that it's fine
to bring in licensed producers but not
at the expense of personal
production definitely not at the expense
of personal
production yeah well thanks for walking
us through this Matt once again always a
pleasure beautiful
garden well uh I got my fingers crossed
for well for all of us but
for you as
well I hope you get to keep doing
this one country or another hopefully
it's Canada yeah whatever we can meet up
in Uruguay if it worse comes to the
[Music]
worst we heard something go CL
H what's going on over
here this is a canonic room coming
waking
up beautiful this room's full of
experiments the first two tables have
been topped and then the second two
tables were left alone but then the
second table we've gone through and sort
of moved buds around to make sure
they're all the same height sort using
the screen right
as right and you can see how it's just
like oh it's a just nugget
yeah I love
it clickity click have things like this
in here right just messing around where
you took the whole took the whole bud
and and tilted over like that one over
there oh yeah getting all the side buds
the sort of look at that one over there
the side bud to turn up and be their
totally be their own time yeah that
one's even nicer
yeah staircasing
Nicely versus those ones where we just
left them be left them natural way right
is this all catonic again
y tough expects like what do you do with
that that's the problem is is that this
stuff have to get akak so steak them
out and
AIC that's
okay yeah it sure looks nice all this
nug
God it just seems like I was in here
just a few weeks
ago and how many more weeks left in
here what we got uh starting to fatten
up pretty nice or another four weeks
another four weeks eh it'll take us till
like March
25th or
26th then you going to roll it all up in
kitty litter then we're going to demo
then we're going to demo how to destroy
your
cannabis you do demo like that just so
the people know how you take your
cannabis and grind it up put it in water
and mix it up you have to get the the
exact sort of slurry got to get the
right slurry up and then you take it
down to the police station and you ask
them what you're supposed to do with it
what do I do with it now and just give
it to them you think it's a danger dous
product that' be a great
protest it would
be is it is how ridiculous that it all
is do it with Shake though do it with
like St I don't know I guess that's all
you can't that all of it's good use all
of
them how ridiculous hey turn off shut
shut down April 1 get rid of
March 31st you're allowed your 3 month
supply April 1st you're only allowed to
have 150 g and you're supposed to
destroy all your medicine that you grew
and then buy it at 5 to1 a
gram
from an
LP yeah I mean that's like that's like
that's like almost cruel to the people
cruelty to the people
back of the day they they they it's not
almost cruel it's sadistic and it's
sick like to give you to give
you a a memo that tells you the process
of taking cat litter and mixing it with
water and mixing your cannabis in with
that and destroy it like who job was
that like that must have been a a a sad
day you know what I know another way of
destroying cannabis just smoke it we
should go try some let's let's go smoke
some yeah let's go destroy some cannabis
resin Matt and I are going to show you
how to properly destroy your
medicine the great Gardener and Bubble
Man
way see you soon
[Music]
la la la it's the way that we rock when
we doing
nothing o la la la it's a natural high
that the UT
[Music]
bring
ooh la la la la la la la la the real
thing o la la
la as Ste
coconut stly up the
Press into he with the re grab need need
to proceed to me the keeper off the gate
open the heavens at 247 we give him R
and Awakening with every po I take
it's the way that we rock when we doing
nothing la la la it's the natural high
at the
UT
[Music]
o
o them we shipping unpacking it
Distributing stocking it hidden Troth
and locking it blond bling never St
Mark just want constitutional reform
pharmaceutical drug so we cultivate we
and want the one of one or two police we
at the west but then we sell it in at
the East donate up the from percentages
we bck up all thealist and planting in
the
field
La it's the way that we rock when we
doing
nothing la la la it's natur hi
[Music]
at so the sunrises in the endless Skies
floating T and chocolate je with eyes
open orange Ash ice cream prepare for 20
p.m on to my lung soever I'm smoking
while I'm choking from my tush B pushing
B we pull PPP pushing hand super siiz
Molly telling them people the healing of
the nation is the trees so why legalize
the urban set
free la
la it's the way that we rock when we do
all right back with the great Gardener
and we're about to uh lift up the dry
sifting uh yeah got a little bit of Hy
I've been running for 24
hours awesome 24 hours serious this is a
holy look at the sift stuck on
there this is this will be a seed run
so uh what a great smell though the uh
we we would have run the for the 10
minute and then the 1 hour
run and then we get all the seed out of
it once you have all the seed out of it
then we then we throw every all the
plant material back in here for 24 hours
and then this what what grade comes out
of here we use for uh meta
okay turn that
off
booah well there's a green
[Music]
[Applause]
la
[Music]
this again hey what was
H haa the name comes from uh from uh
Chris Bennett's new book heom sort of a
heom Som Cults or
tribes of uh ancient times comes from
sort of the ti Shen Mountain range it's
like the man this image here is actually
a cave painting in the tenan shin
mountain range that comes from the Som
heom tribes which are some believe are
the original cannabis Farmers that made
the potent strains hold that up 8,000
years
ago oh
yeah so that'll go to metal
beautiful awesome
awesome as you can see they're not
wasting any parts of the plant here at
the house of the great Gardener
everything right down to the last little
bit is used collecting seed collecting
resin yeah let's check it
out
yeah there it is it is
folks there it
is we're here with Matt the great
Gardener and some of his secret private
reserve why don't you tell us what's
going on here Matt well we have
everything in here this is mostly our
fresh frozen uh collection canonic
Afghani you'll find things like micro
plane versus
Civ and just you'll find things like
sweet skunk
99.9% gland head oh goodness
gracious and you'll find barbar bod and
jt15 and
hyoma and so you've got MP for the
microplane yeah MP for microplane the
size the date should be on actually this
one this will be
microplaned but most of the new ones all
Mark either
or uh how dark that one is I have gy 25
oh yeah that's the other one that's dark
like that the JT these are the early
early early
Civ uh techniques where there was a lot
of water still trapped in there they
went really dark mhm compared to
uh just let me go grab the sweet skunk
ones sure
nice big bags to sift in
the oh here comes some sweet skunk
coming through coming
through got
it sweet skunk gets her own
section as it should be sweet skunk so
with this one because we waited a little
longer for our
patties to dry before we sifted
them I just want to find the same size
sift 45 what are you looking for 90
plain 45 that would be the big one
so whereas the other one the Civ was
darker we've we've got it to a point
where it's a little bit lighter but
still the micr
plane is a little little bit
lighter mhm but not a not such a
dramatic
difference that one looks nicer they
both look
great I appreciate both their textures
and their colors and they I just know
this when I look at a hash up close like
this and I want to smoke it then
everything's
right so let's smoke some shall we all
right you can't be right next to a
freezer full of hash this nice and not
just smoke a bunch of it so we're going
to get back to a bunch of puffing and
we'll catch you in a little
bit
73 73 73
sweet scope coming right very good very
good and is that the 73 with the 90 bag
or the AKA real 73 pre 90 bag I don't
know what you're talking about well
before I added the 90 Micron bag all the
90 Micron hash used to go into the 73
bag so for those of us that used to make
it back in the day that don't that that
now the 90 came along and it really
robbed the 73 of a lot of what made it
special and so basically we call the 73
that's pre 90 Micron bag we call it the
real 73 cuz it's got all that 90 in it
too take a hit of the 90 and the 73 and
that's the real
73 all right all right 73 we're doing it
so it looks like we pulled sweet skunk
73 microplane out of the freezer this is
a very light
color and I just put it next to the dry
sifts here to show you kind of the
different colors this is you know two
dry sifts this is H
99 this is Homa 99 and this one is and
this this one's a afgh heom mix right
definitely have more of a yellowish look
to them but then again this one these
never were exposed to water and they
were never um Frozen for for that matter
either so this was both this was made
with water and also Frozen basically
kept in the freezer after probably out
onard cardboard for what a week
yep well let's dab it up all right
checking out a little
Barbara that is some crystally
[Applause]
[ __ ] so what is this this is all that's
uh this is Barb right here all Barb
right here yeah and this is a this is uh
Afghani in the front Afghani yeah
afgh aghy cross with the John ghe seed
in it anyway well that was funny oh
that that's the uh Sour
Diesel I just have to change
my my white
balance here let's go white balance you
can oh that was the one right there I
think it's
frosty Frosty trikes that's a big fat
nuget it is a big nug is that it's
Afghan that's the sort of main Cola
beautiful absolutely Splendid and what
do we have here these are all Jean G
Jean
G feminize Jean G coming to the
Vancouver Seed Bank soon coming to a
Vancouver Seed Bank near you awesome
well looks good
man so these are femmed yeah F
jt15 then how did you fem these little
silver tho sulfate oh yeah STS just
brushed it on no I spray it on sprayed
it on through liquid a couple weeks
before flowering or actually I'll uh
spray it on throw that plant into
flowering for a couple weeks and then
flower the rest of the room so
it's just
ready get some Rosses and stuff done oh
beautiful look at these yeah I know he
these are
uh White Rhino that I these are been
these were made in the 9s those are
insane yeah they're like 20 years old
lovely uh the oldest seed I ever held I
was at skunkman Sam's house and he came
out and he put this little jar like a
little jar like that in my hand and
basically um it was the seeds from that
like
mummy like the 4,000 year old seeds or
whatever
beautiful don't you feel like you have a
lot of uh
power almost yeah in the seeds you know
like it's like man it's all right there
the genetic lineage of like so many
different
plants all right so just finishing up
day two here wasn't really able to get
as much done as I wanted to I wanted to
do some photography going to have to cut
that short um let's go say bye to Matt
he's just working in the room
[Music]
here can aonics
all right Matt how's it going good good
man thanks for coming out again dude
thanks having you guys out thanks for
having us man it was a great time this
table looks
great it was uh as always a pleasure and
hopefully we'll be able to hang out with
you in Spain in the next couple of weeks
banabas for spannabis exactly and uh
more hopeful is that you get to still be
here in a month and a bit John Conroy
injunction
go joh Conroy go John Conroy all right
dude well honestly thanks for having us
out again and uh we'll be in touch soon
see you later everybody peace
[Music]
in a theard s Andre Park music a bubble
steam a bubble bun a bubble from morning
to dark and the fire B the just blaz up
in a theard s Andre Park music a bubble
steam a bubble bunch a bubble from
morning to dark and the fire on the FL
just
a one thing to over about Jamaica we are
the confidence of the African continent
in our I no influence is greater and the
state of the nation is test why the
people suffer fromase of the Mind enemy
as de so them worship the blind but the
real black madon is the rightful Divine
and the king and queen crown same time
my SRA Park music
a Buble B chice of Buble from morning to
dark and the fire on the FL just
BL in a theard s and Park music a bubble
Steamers a bubble bu bu from morning to
dark and the fire B for
just the fire just a blaze
up burning out the evil
while the music free the
people
oh the herb I bring the
healing and the word I bring the
knowledge where would take up Wicked get
shake up when the conscious wake up in
theard Park music bubble Steamers a
bubble bunch chice a bubble from morning
to dark and the on the
just in a
s music bubble Steamers a bubble pun a
bubble from morning to dark and the fire
on the FL just a
BL from generation to generation the
tradition of righteousness is passed on
from the
anent setting up precedence of excellent
ritual Devotion to the Mastery of the
instrument strings with percussion and
voal Bing vibration one to other the
most meditation with the highr marijuana
in a s Park music a bubble Steamers a
bubble bun chice a bubble from M to dark
and the fire on the for just
[Music]
the fire just a
Blazer burning out the
evil while the music free the
people
oh the her I bring the
healing and the word I bring the
knowledge what would take up Wicked get
shake up when the Consciousness wake up
[Music]
la la la
it's the natural hide at the
[Music]
UTP
o shipping and packing it Distributing
stocking it hiden trth and loing it BL
blazing never start Mark and just want
constitutional reform pharmaceutical
drugs on so we cultivate we B GRE want
the least one of one or two police we in
at the west but then we sell it in at
the East Don the from percentages we
pick up all theist and planting in the
field it's the way that we rock when we
doing
nothing la la la it's a natural heart at
[Music]
ooh so the Phoenix sunrises in the
endless Skies floating T and chocolate
je with eyes opene Ash ice cream prepare
420 pm foring on to my lung soever I'm
smoking while I'm choking from my tush B
bushing B we pull pineapple pushing hand
super siiz mly telling them people the
healing of the nation the trees so why
not legalize the urban set Mar
free la la la it's the way that we rock
when we doing
nothing oh la la la it's a natural hide
that the UT is
[Music]