[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
I'm here with Dee 420k and we are about
to do the Blue River extracts terpene
gauntlet
I have 18 incredible flavors that I've
had sent over from mr. VIRs aura Tony
from from Blue River and you know just
to kind of go through them real quick
we've got lemon Kush we've got orange
creamsicle we've got purple punch
we've got sunset KB we've got pineapple
cream sickle or pineapple cream and then
we have Tahoe og triple og a gooey
gorilla glue vitamin C B D cheese bomb
red congolese oh my god let me tell you
is that a cross with something no that's
a congolese there's a green Congo and a
red Congo they're separate they're
different
chem dog venom OG smw which is the
strawberry Mindwarp
and finally but not lat you know last
but not least we got the cherry ak-47 so
this is what we've done we have taken a
drop out of each one and placed it into
oh sorry I forgot the purple Hindu as
well which is the one here at the end
that doesn't actually have the small jar
because I only got large jars of purple
Hindu so I pulled out a couple of drops
and put it in here so each empty jar
without the label has maybe a drop or
two maximum
in it and that way we can dip each hit
into the turf jar without actually
affecting the original turf job but may
be contaminated with your rose 100 same
time these terpenes are these terpenes
are solvents they would chew up our
roses and that's a good good call you
want to tell everyone what you're using
as your base for today well I've got 120
dry seft OG Kush it's really thick and
it's dark but very powerful
nice cast and it's um it's good it's
really good I love it it's it's what I
brought to smoke as the base flavor
tartare with so I'm not getting any
contaminate across I think it's a good
idea we both talked about it earlier
before filming that it would be best if
we hit each rip with the same product
and just go all the way through I'm
using some of the West Coast concentrate
rosin this one is it's a purple purple
candy Kirra believe not not with
anything else mixed in so yeah I'm
pretty excited to do should we should we
start the gauntlet yes 18 ribs we're
gonna try and do it in under an hour
that means every minute and 30 seconds
either Darren or myself has to be taking
a rib every three minutes we each have
to take one new rib to get to get under
the 1 hour mark so I'm pretty stoked I
guess we'll go let's go purple hit you
oh good very excited about this little
and we're also doing just little ribs I
think that's a good thing to to explain
to everyone we are not doing you know
what we would normally hit 18 of those
ribs in a row this is really all about
the terpenes and the cannabinoids are
mostly in this situation the carrier for
the terpenes because we don't really
want to hit pure terpenes I find hitting
them with the cannabinoids to just be
the perfect perfect rip um one thing
that I've known that I've this is all
every one of these strains is turps all
from the marijuana strain that
they are all cannabis derived there's no
other things involved here huge thing I
wanted to point though because there's
all kinds of creamsicle and stuff like
though yeah but they're not Terps from
the strains their profile is created to
taste like that and the actual kind of
cannabis Turkey and you know marks tell
don't our PhD chemist and hash Church
says terpenes or terpenes I tend to be a
little disagreement with that when it
comes to the inhalation of these
potentially caustic potentially solvent
based terpenes I want to make sure that
they're coming from cannabis the plant
that produces them that we have been
inhaling them off of for thousands of
years and I just prefer a cannabis
derived keep in mind we're also smoking
a profile
we're not puffing any pure terpenes here
these are pure cannabis terpene profile
so it's a variety of terpenes that we're
hitting so I guess we start we start my
friend let's very that's Cheers yeah
dude
cheers cheers Cheers
it was the nail Cheers I liked it I've
only done it one at a time but it was
good
well it's also nice to use a base that
you're so used to because you recognize
the differences in the flavors what do
you have to say about that I have to say
that the temperature makes a huge
difference we should mention that we are
both hitting under 600 degrees
Fahrenheit we're at about five hundred
and seventy eight to five hundred and
eighty or five hundred seventy seven to
five hundred and eighty and the lower
temperature with the Terps always seems
to make it a little better you'll get a
lighter hit in the sense you'll get this
smoke off on the map nodes but the
terpene rip that you get from that low
low temp dab we're not quite as low as
some people some people go under five
hundred degrees oh yeah west coast boys
they like that one guy likes it really
low yeah yeah low temp dabbers yeah so
what do you say about lemon cush very
very nice that you could taste the
citrusy in it well that was purple no
that was purple Hindu this is lemon cush
that's what I meant by what do you think
of this one no oh right like it's just
come on if I could have you know one of
those sleep apnea machines at night and
have that pump into my face that's
awesome would be perfect I am very very
modulated off of the first hit I have to
admit like it's such an amazing great
feeling you could go and enjoy yourself
for an hour on this vibe whereas we're
just gonna of course shatter it with the
small yeah
the flavor lick your lips it'll be on
there really nice here we go
lemon Kush purple Hindu was beautiful by
the way
oh wow now there's a there's much more
going on in the lemon cush in the old
way in its levels there are levels going
on there I don't even want to exhale but
I want to keep it but did you notice
that the taste on your lips versus the
taste in your mouth versus the taste in
your throat they're all slightly
different the way it fractions the
flavors right now it's all on my lips
it's it's all in my head it's hard to
describe though isn't it so it's slaver
wise it's um I mean I'm thinking kind of
like that silly as it sounds it's a
party in my mouth it's a party in his
terms a party in my mouth flavors um you
know I came here with a headache to 8-3
I had a headache oh man
these travnik take these two it's it's
gone I can feel it gone
uplifting just the smell of those Turks
to me is something that that does
something to you you know like that now
this is orange creamsicle this is the
bubbleman brand that's dropping right
away Superbowl weekend coming up here at
Harbor side go check it out if if you're
in town in California this one I find
amazing because when you smell it out
here if you can catch the waft I want
it's it's creamy
I want the dope from that I want to see
the dope on the house from that and that
Lee it's creamy from a distance yet like
six receipt when you get it close to
your nose citrus we thought so it goes
really when you get up close it grabs
you but down over here it's more like
the cream so you get that orange
creamsicle it is not a tan G it is not a
Cali oh it is not a skunk number one
it's got some really unique flavors and
I think we're gonna get dip in here
right a wedding
telling you man dippy it's getting tippy
with it yeah we are just doing little
rips it's this is not like the gauntlet
of dry sift know where we were taking
full-size rips but this this is about
really understanding the subtle nuances
of the modulation not that he destroyed
our debt not getting destroyed on 18 we
know if we take 18 roots of rosin or
bubble hash or dry sift that we're going
to get double do very very stoned this
is more about just understanding the
subtle nuances of the terpenes and those
modulations what I find and we were
talking about the way THC starts as a
buzz it has a real loo and then it has
this thing and I can't remember the name
skunk man Sam called it it's like a
synth a door something it it it ends and
that's the sort of the burnout or the
whatever and he was saying that the
terpenes they kind of just turned that
part of it off so he hit the buzz and
then you just kind of keep floating on
that buzz there's not definitely you
know orange creamsicle this is gonna be
a treat
let a little bit of that one out your
nose just the tiniest little bit I
thought so too I wouldn't do the whole
hand I just let out a little bit and
then I blew it out of my mouth but the
flavor in my nose now from letting that
out is just this incredibly orange
citrus it tastes like [ __ ] orange
creamsicle right that's the that is
bottom line I'm gonna go [ __ ] get an
orange creamsicle does this with that
bloat out of the booth that blown out of
the the nose and I got the Terps in the
nose hairs and that it's like oh it's
incredible when I first smelled the
orange creamsicle because obviously I
wanted to it was the brand the photo of
abhash shut up right now so you can see
the orange creamsicle hat I wanted to
have it right away so to be able to have
the terpenes these are cannabinoid free
terpenes there are just terpenes present
in here Wow Oh God
holy this one think purple it's just
like though that was so strong oh
because I didn't add the second word
think punch it's the purple punch POW
right in the kisser
holy okay for the people at home that
aren't getting the experience there are
multi dimensions going on in these
flavors and as you move them away and
move them closer to your nose you
experience those sort of flavored
dimensions differently and so that's
what he just experienced as he was going
in and out
he was you catch the spike of these
flavors that are elusive this one not so
elusive it's really like pow yes sir in
front of you right now like wow Jesus
let's get the buzz too
this is if we did this one oh okay I was
gonna say jeez we're already forgetting
I'm so buzzed out from what have we done
for three we've done three dude all
right someone's probably gonna be like
did you see bubble man's put up the goat
head fingers that's definitely like
Illuminati definitely devil-worshiping
yeah it's definitely not it's stoked on
Terps is what it is all right my good
buddy here's a purple punch to you punch
to the face right here we go just
sparring with my buddy purple punch
[Music]
[Laughter]
holy is right let's have a glass of
water holy
you know the purple punch it smelled
very strong to me but its flavor was
almost elusive and I don't know if
that's because I blew it out my nostrils
that one was very different from the
orange creamsicle blowing it out my
nostrils was more of that expected Qi
raspy like I feel like I'm gonna sneeze
type of thing hmm hmm what would you
have to say on the flavors did you catch
the flavor I caught at the end hmm that
and flavor on the back of the tongue
purpley like well what's that strain
purple punch this is the purple purple
business straining purple punch you know
that's the string purple punch down in
Cali
we've got strains up here everybody gets
strains mixed up and changes names oh
yeah this strain reminds me of something
that that I've had before ro said that
about this one this is the sunset KB and
listen KB what's Kb
I have no idea it's killer bud that
maybe it's on my my label as sunset KB
now I let ro smell this yesterday then
right away he said whoa and then he went
whoa that reminds me something from my
past hmm it's a Celtic feeling it's a
little bit you don't smell if you put it
too close that one's one you kind of
have to go far and close far and close
and you'll catch it in the in-between
mm-hmm so yeah that's number five number
five
these types of terpenes have any effect
well it's definitely making me
lightheaded like you know like like some
people would have gas or some [ __ ] you
think it'd get some [ __ ] up because
well you know what there isn't there is
an argument about that the lot of the
people that I kind of call them haters
cuz I don't think they're creating a
proper open dialogue yes we do not okay
first of all we do know that inhaling
terpenes on cannabis has been done for
thousands of years for maybe tens of you
know 10 to 50 or 60 years people have
been smoking or maybe even longer
concentrates you know at the next level
not just hatched but like oils and
concentrates made into you know
extremely simply murdered Houghton's
know and so the terpenes are very high
in some of these concentrates very high
in fact almost as highest and higher
sometimes than the flavors that have
been tested hashes that have been tested
with added terpenes so Tony added
terpenes to one of his roses I think at
the Emerald cup and then there was a
product that had a higher terpene
content than his and they didn't add
terpenes so we are used to inhaling
these terpenes at a fairly high dose at
least for the last 10 or 20 years but at
the same time we do know that terpenes
can act as solvents they can break down
plastics and that there probably is
going to be a level of that sort of
huffing now I like to think that we're
much more like you know inhaling on a
level of like aromatherapy where you can
pass around a bunch of aromas and people
would we're not like you know what I
mean in like a baby I don't see that
taped worth I don't get enjoyment from
doing nothing from this I really it's a
subtle thing that I like about these
Terps it would definitely be a nice
aroma to have throughout the house all
the time right
like just subtly yeah all you needed is
so it yeah how do you feel after five
tert menthe hits though eight I feel I
feel like close to his baked as I could
be yet I know when I hit this I'm
to be more elevated and what about the
term baked baked does it work against us
to use these terms in the recreational
you know market is that is it a negative
word you know I have a kated yeah but I
mean even that one seems like a sham and
that we're hiding seems phony reminded I
don't know what the term is maybe you
guys can come up with some great
comments at this point because like
something positive that doesn't have the
negative connotation that's like yeah
you know exactly go smoke another joint
all right so sunset can be
oh my god now that's that's incredible
how that was like loud like citrus but
not really citrusy you know what I'm
saying and it's almost changing more in
the back of my throat where I'm getting
a fruity flavor to that a fruit basket
exactly it's not citrusy but it's loud
like never library wow that one was
really nice banana strawberry and some
[ __ ] memo and some lime to it some
set sunset kb is definitely huge herbs
are very very flavorful that was so that
was nice when we got going on here we
got pineapple cream and we got OG Tahoe
og
this one goes right on the other side of
this one yeah keep them attached to
their dabber you know so they're
touching each dab or so pineapple cream
oh yo you just put that one down I just
put this one back sunset KB and then I
pulled up the next one it's just
pineapple closed right somehow I'm
staying on the ball it's not gonna hit
last I don't know I'm telling you these
are micro hits to we're definitely not
hitting I'll show a camera shot of like
the size of the hits that were hitting
they're just little too little you know
maybe match heads of rosin yeah not even
a match head
it's sure okay we got to get through
these well we got to get through them
and I have to say like I feel right now
off of these five or six whatever we've
hit now small rips better quality
whatever you want to call this once
again hi if you will with none of the
negative connotations a better quality
high is achieved especially with the
different terpenes and all the
modulating I mean we this is for fun we
could literally use just one terpene a
day and and feel the effects of morning
noon and night and how the modulation
changes that strain but this is just a
good old fun thing to show
and this is something you guys can do
yourselves blue river extracts calm you
can literally go on there and you can
order many of these strains if not all
of them so if you're in the US I know
that blue river is going to be opening
up in Canada eventually I'm trying to
help out with that and that'll be at
blue river extract CA so hopefully you
know people will be able to get to play
there's a lot of different people making
terpenes I think everybody needs these
in their lives you know we love to
recreationally smoke this and always
have but the medical benefits everything
about it makes it such a bonus such a
bonus that what we're doing and then all
of a sudden there's something else that
makes it medically better it's beyond a
bonus let's just after being the black
sheep of the family right for all of our
lives
thanks and then to be like oh wait a
minute now I can you can help me with
this like this is something that can
help grandma and like Uncle Bob and
everybody Oh auntie Jill and like yeah
everyone say I was kicked out of my home
at 14 cause a couple of joints that fell
out of my star Saucon the stairs by my
dad through my dad takes my coconut oil
it needs it daily because it helps with
his IV I said he loves it he says thank
you he's proud of me thirty years later
yeah forty years yeah thirty years later
30 years later so please don't give up
hope when truth is on your side it's
hard to lose you know I people always
say oh you know like you're such a good
debater I'm like there's no debate when
it comes to cannabis there's no debate
it's like either right you're not [ __ ]
gonna be wrong truth is on its side and
it's you know it's brought us here today
for the turf dips I'm dipped I'm a
pineapple terrine I'm cross the old
young there we go we're doing this this
is fun
oh wow oh that second hit was definitely
pineapple the first hit I hit I blew out
and I thought it was gonna have a really
strong taste because it was obviously
the first hit it had very little taste i
carp capped it and hit it again and wow
that was a world of difference it does
taste almost like a like a pineapple
coconut or a little cream thing a
pineapple dessert
yeah like a sorbet or something yeah I
taste the coconut in there though it's
pineapple coconut trippy that's really
treated a lot of man it's like a pina
colada
except not like a pina colada it's like
pineapple coconut all right here we go
man
Tahoe og is not gonna get things any
lighter for us let me tell you this once
was heavy
I'm higher I can feel it in my eyes if
you'll rip my eyes behind my eyes top of
the eyelids I only got 12 left there
well you know David we did the the dry
sips going with yep well most of the
videos ever are always starting off
we're very you know aware and boom video
right on point but stop and then by the
end of the videos we are everybody says
their laughs are just there's there's
yeah there's it's tribes where it says
gee 420k is off somewhere and I'm
sitting limits down there like this just
yeah just staring somewhere about 30
seconds it'll come to it we've made it
through one row of three rows wicked I
think we're doing fine let's not get
ahead of ourselves we're actually at the
end of the first row we it's the first
row yes Tahoe gee
well so here we go what did you dip it
[ __ ] did I dip it bro didn't dip the top
oh that's why I put it away they thought
you did dip it dude
I apologize except you're getting a
little excited
I accept your totally excited here in
the in the tur plunge all right we are
you'll interplan gently
yes I love it bro that's that taco cut
forum
whatever the cookies it's it's deep it's
that is a deep Tahoe og just yeah it's
crossed my eyes holy cross my eyes
there's only twice that I've drank my
water and they'll be able to mark all
these funny things down like oh did you
notice they uh they drank their water
after the so and so when the Tahoe and
then yeah Tahoe was one of them people
pointed oh who said I don't one I think
it might have been the pineapple one
that I had or no the one that I took a
drink on oh the pine the purple Hindu
the purple punch purple punch you're
right yeah you're right I like you going
no listen to this [ __ ] I don't
know if we should start over with og
again let's go let's go blue dream in a
dream it is dream it on the dream let's
go blue dream this one literally got
like a drop put in it so we really have
to poop oh yeah no there's more than
actually so will the dream classic I
mean to me it right away the first thing
I smell in it is the commercial mists of
it now don't get me wrong I'm not
dissing on Blue Dream it's got a
beautiful smell it's great herb that a
lot of people can grow and get yields on
and make a nice-looking product you know
kind of like a triple-a or whatever they
call it today quads yet it's it's got
that commercial favor to it though that
like the sugar bear
the Jamaican the you know although it
was juicy the juicy fruit all the
commercial ones we had you nailed it
dude those that you smell it there you
know but now try to get past that sorry
about my telephone and get into the
actual past the commercial flavor of it
there's a nice profile to be had in blue
dream I do enjoy I think that I liked
about the juicy fruit was it was the
very start of it I liked the first
couple joints out of the bag behind it
was just wore off but the flavor of and
the taste was just something else I
should be fine I was gonna unplug it if
it if it lights up again we'll go unplug
it so I'm dipped do do bells even nicer
on the dip rather than from the jar you
get of a more open air it's another
thing about the terpenes they are so
different in if you change their
environment smelling them in an enclosed
jar is very different from taking a drop
of them and placing it on a glass dish
in open air see what I'm saying
all right buddy can you dream
definitely had a lot of the juicy fruit
Jamaican sugar bears flavor mmm there's
something else there if that's just so
pronounced it's very nice it's pleasant
it's nowhere near as powerful as some of
the ones we've tried already like the
last one it's subtle it's more silent
subtle but it's flat it's flavorful like
it's it wouldn't be something I get
tired of like I would if I was smoking
the juicy fruit you know what I mean
that's still a flavor oh if I hide the
terms I'd be dipping double dipping
triple dipping which ones that the red
the red congolese right oh just wait
dude you are not gonna believe it
whoo I had this one eight times in a row
yesterday I hit it once and it was it it
was like boom boom boom boom aluminum oh
my god
yeah that is beautiful it's the one that
is beautiful it's I think it might be
like wow might be my favorite my
favorite out of all of them one favorite
it's like the only one I hit eight times
I'm not exaggerating I hated it's eight
times in a row it was like I just
even today I was hitting it on the Skype
with skunk man Sam and he had his
collection out and he was like which one
should I try and I'm like uh-oh pull out
the red Kongo he's like okay and
he hits it and he's like oh I like that
one
yeah I'm like no he's like cool tell me
what other ones I should hit I was like
well right off the bat hit another red
Congo posture over oh my gosh I dipped
you again with a oh no I did dip it
sorry no prob dude no problem
let's uh let's do this right no you did
not didn't see here we go you guys can
start working that stuff down yeah it's
funny when you just get a little bit
like completely destroyed you know just
a little bit completely destroyed and we
are more than completely destroyed
alright red Congo terpene gauntlet
number 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 what if what if
6 turned out to be none Jimi Hendrix
googly
oh yeah that was everything I loved
about cannabis landrace spicy exotic
perfumey uplifting vivid loud like
speechless dude holy [ __ ] bro I'm
telling you the red combat nothing it's
it's a giddy high all of this yeah well
cuz we're uplifting oh and oh there we
go
I swear to God as crazy as it sounds in
the middle of the gauntlet right 9in
right we got another nine to go and I'm
literally considering taking another hit
of the red Congo before I move on let's
do it the cheese bomb let's go oh it up
lets you follow it up with one so we go
through the whole gauntlet but then we
finish it with red with the red Congo or
unless there's one we find that it was
hurtful punch I mean I like the red
Congo more personally but you can finish
it with is that purple pods really stuck
in my head well not maybe the one you're
they finish with try this cheese bomb
amazing differences now there's gonna be
carry awfully there's going to be a
similarity of a few terpenes in every
batch and you could pick that up you
know I think to the subtle knows the
person that doesn't have the ability of
a very strong olfactory they might say
something like these kind of all smell
the same even though there are really
quite vast differences huge differences
there are minor Silurian
you'll be like oh I smell and then I'm
right away it's like like smell that
that is like similar to what we've
smelled and yet nothing like anything
we've smelled catching that yeah it's
hard because that's rolling about every
one of them like that okay go ahead red
congolese holy crap so good dude so good
blowing and I don't know I haven't hit
the cheese bomb yet there's a few I
haven't hit yet so you're really the
first person I've hit all of these
flavors with I did it to you again yeah
I'm gonna stop doing that maybe I gotta
be quicker maybe it's me not you buddy
getting off gonna stop what we're
[ __ ] very cannabinoid saturated well
we're saturated we are endocannabinoids
that's the most terpenes I've been in my
whole life
Turbie tert we're at the gas station
getting turfed up here on bubble man's
world and we're just glad that you guys
are joining us for those of you that
have your Blue River terpenes with you
we're about to hit another one keep up
oh that was nice nice cheese bomb now
not funky cheese at all
more like cheesecake bomb came out just
I don't know that was a really pleasant
taste it wasn't funky it wasn't really
[ __ ] it wasn't a punch like - that
wasn't a brunch but it was definitely
not super subtle either like I can I can
taste it in my mouth fairly strong taste
on my lips and believe it or not each
time we hit one these are so pronounced
you can do it with essential oils it is
very different each time very different
so and I've tried those Turpin's that
are you know like done from a whole
bunch of other terpenes I made into a
profile oh yeah
not from cannabis right and then they're
you know mixed with the clear or you
know put on some rosin or whatever
dipped or dropped onto some some hash
and I can't tell the difference no no I
know but I was just like take your time
I think would you would and I think
we're hitting a rip every minute and a
half to three minutes where do they go
you were talking about laughing being
giddy what this you remember that about
what we did with the speed you got
speeding tickets oh yeah and we did we
both and I thought my manager didn't pay
out pay it I was worried oh yeah
I didn't pay mine yet we paid ours twice
really yeah hmm yeah lucky for them they
paid us back the once I was so like
intense about him paying and he paid it
twice
so then he got it the check back in the
mail here we go
vitamin C B D hadn't mentioned that yet
had I this is the vitamin C B D this was
an award winner jeez I think Tony and I
we took first at the Emerald cup with
the vitamin C V D rosin SAP that's
busted out under the brand you know what
I've got an idea
mmm I'm gonna turn my nail down just a
little bit I'm gonna go down a little
bit more like maybe say let's say 540 so
you have to push the square button once
yeah and then just go down to 540 you're
good but in the CBD lovely pretty nice
has a similarity the what was the one
that tasted similar to the oh the blue
dream I find the vitamin CBD to have a
little bit of a blue dream esque flavor
to it
whatever that terpene profile is that we
spoke about that's the CBD
yeah vitamin CBD it's called so CBD is a
CBD strain obviously yeah I know that's
it's a bit of a misnomer because
obviously I don't know why they put
choose to call it CBD over anything else
but it's not good anything to do with
sea wheedies well it has everything to
do with CBD and the fact that it's a
high CBD profile plant so CBD is
probably the highest percentage of
cannabinoid okay and then it might be a
ratio right it's only one or ten to one
I
I'm not sure off the top of my head I
should know but maybe someone will know
and they can post it in the comment
section does anything change because of
the CVD or the THC in the terpenes I've
always thought that they would probably
find that the terpene profile obviously
it's the it's the modulator so I
wouldn't be very surprised if it didn't
modulate CBD effects that terpene
profiles that are specific to high CBD
strains should be as much paid attention
to as the percentage of CBD so when
you're when you're really high and you
say well now yes and you smoke a CBD
isn't it supposed to level you out call
me down get you a little like take it a
bit if you were hitting high amounts of
the cannabinoid yeah and if if the
terpenes modulated without the CBD
present absolutely because with that
last toke
literally I'm not stoned anymore okay so
there you go so your bio acid says this
[Laughter]
[Music]
okay so we're getting the Gorilla Glue
real nice I've heard so much of this
about this yes just glue is great really
glue is like boom pow snaps the terpene
really really represents the flowers
accurately anyone that grows gorilla
glue or knows gorilla glue very well as
a smoker and aficionado of hashish of
concentrates they are gonna [ __ ]
recognize this [ __ ] so so this is gonna
kaboom as fine as you are
okay I might need another CBD head
Oh glue real nice glue hit at 5:39 let
me tell you it's just a taste just like
the full melt it tastes exactly like
gorilla glue full melt that made me like
picture caramely beautiful faux melt
gorilla glue in my hand rather [ __ ]
need another one here how about a couple
of smells while your another nice thing
is to hit it and while you're you're
tasting it smell it while you're tasting
it and you pick up different nuances
that certainly you might not be able to
pick up on your nose alone oh it's
powerful it's powerful its powerful it's
really like just [ __ ] in your face
that CBD one gave me a very lemony taste
without the citrus yeah less though the
citrus Ergo is a very soft lemon a lot
of people call it a cherry taste but
there is a fruity taste that I also pick
up on different CBD strains definitely
that one is is also something quite
quite pick off the top of my head oh I'm
excited for this though number oh yeah
Oh like maybe 12 this one might be my
favorite
just now smelling that you haven't tried
this one I
holy smokes okay so I'm not gonna tell
you just smell that it's good clothes
it's not offensive that one oh right
I think pink as soon as I smallest that
is a Kiwi I just think very nice soft
pink color
alright badge terms
that's the point ours chair having fun
here we're trying to make the video
somewhat serious but come on we're doing
a gauntlet of 18 ribs it'd be serious
after 12 reps in didn't you just say
that yes you know what it's even scarier
is we are actually 12 ribs
tastes of that before you did cuz the
smell or not has been just and you know
what it reminds me it reminds me of
really nice head of ours didn't even
explain that to someone like a whole
bouquet of the best smelling flowers
yeah but cannabis flowers like there
you're right though there is a floral e
like beautiful other like the right case
so this is an interesting thing that
Darren's doing here is with the smelling
instead of trying to break it down with
with words there are pictures that are
appear in your head when you smell some
of these and I didn't get it at first
but when he sent the flowers and then I
said cannabis flowers right at the end
of that I picked up a hint of what you
were talking about those actual know
like flowers and I wasn't talking bad
terms I was talking actual the color
pink soft pink is what I seen first
smelling it like God is that nice I like
the way you just said that so seriously
and I wasn't actually talking about bad
curves on the discussion this is your
five star three-minute water turn we did
this one might be the longest time we've
waited yet but come on we're 12 in and
there's we're no slouches we're doing
the good work here we'll go backwards
and do it again
maybe doing the good work of the Terps
so love to learn about terpenes you can
do a couple of google searches you can
join my facebook group called all things
terpene i would love to see more
discussion there of course we're looking
for people we don't claim to know a lot
about this stuff we're not telling you
that what we're even doing right now is
safe
should be done nor are we condoning it
if you want to do it you're a big boy or
a big girl by all means try it
I'm sure the science in the next five to
ten years will be very strong and
through the bio I said I have to admit
like just the way it makes me feel I
feel that it's a good thing I don't feel
too hot I feel and I don't feel wasted I
feel anxious it's been so long since we
had a Terp red very nice aftertaste
getting that florally aftertaste really
strong lavender II definitely pinkish
and purpley blues yeah that's beautiful
it was very nice not really every one of
these tokes when you exhale it and then
you stop and sit back hmm you feel every
single one is a different little level
it's easier I'm not convinced it
direction there's no real ceiling right
it's kind of like a little bit of a just
put us over here kind of whoa we're just
halfway
set a nice tone you ready to get heavy
triple og might want to take a bit of a
bigger dab for this one just saying god
that's a little bit bigger than I was
gonna go good still going quite small by
anyone's standards by no means are we
trying to claim that we're taking
monster rips just do it in 18 yeah I
can't do those ones some reps well I can
but they hurt me I recovered I could do
a monster up like that well hey you know
what think of it this way we're set
tone for the video and the next guy to
get 18 types of terpenes you should do
it just take a half gram rip with each
Terp a couple of drops you know do the 9
gram here's here's an idea
what's that I'll throw out our you dip
you dip before you throw your ideas at
me this these young guys on the channel
love to live ok at them at this place on
the smokers nose they're okay we're
[ __ ] then they he was saying you
know you know how they got those videos
of a bud coated in some key is quoted in
some moon rocks shattered like dipped in
Keith yeah yeah but there's buds that
why don't we do buds with rosin with
waterhouse yeah dry sift and coke the
buds like that you could well yeah yes
me maybe we should put a video like that
I said do it yeah your solvent list
we just told the world you guys better
be honest way to get fast man you guys
are one I know they watch too so triple
og already yeah those oh geez adjust
they've got this extremely earthy and
deep deep I don't even know how to like
nice subtle differences you can pick up
in the ends too cool especially now that
we've turned the nail down wow you know
that's one that one hoses the eyeballs
oh my god take a super super deep
inhalation and tell me that's not like
chocolate or coffee
mmm good deep
what can it fightin oh man well [ __ ]
then I guess my mineral stem this [ __ ]
up what you really need yeah I know that
I closer just wait close to give them
the chem dog this came home dog
yeah the chem dog hmm here we go
some unadulterated never touched chem
dog dabs up let's speed this [ __ ] up man
we're almost done what good we've done a
great job I think we've done a great job
we have four left for left out of 18 so
we've done what is that so we've done
like 63 and we have 17 left to go is
that how that works oh yeah that's
that's what we're doing we're doing it
[ __ ] it that's 14 rips in math yeah 67
and 17 that work so I'm gonna leave this
open so we can smell it while we exhale
or asthma cough
whoa oh yeah
hey so Kimmy Kim Jong edge got the good
word on this cam dog but it was very
very legit came from an incredible
grower it helped show other friends of
ours in the community how to grow
definitely guy knows what he's doing
that cam dog is just great
yeah that was beautiful Kevin dog for
the win had me coughing a lot I mean my
god that's the first time we've had a
seen an edit just coughing like a maniac
that was beautiful you ready for some
venom oh absolutely
G venom ulch oh it's goose the Koosh a
little bit of that cage going in there
know that you like that one that's that
reminds me you know a dot takes me know
that takes me back to the [ __ ] days
where these these brothers these older
boys taught me how to grow I was just I
was so happy with going in cutting
clones trimming weed selling the [ __ ]
for [ __ ] getting it for 275 an ounce
straight up all the time and I was happy
at all of it doing it for [ __ ] all of
course cuz that was fresh brand new into
it thank you and I'll tell you something
why the strawberry strand store source
oh yeah no no strawberry strains that
they had wasn't a very good yield er at
all but the smell of it was something
phenomenal and this is exactly that
smell so there it is right there people
ask me what are these Terps for if
you're just not dipping them if you're
not putting them into food products if
you're not putting them the olfactory
memory triggers that these things cause
I've seen many people since I've shown
them have memory triggers from their
past and be like wow man
like yes totally brings me back totally
brings me back like that's the days when
I WI first got was able to be a part of
doing something with a grower those guys
[ __ ] venom Lords the hell out of me
bad
well here's to those guys [ __ ] rights
thanks boys I'll tell you an interesting
thing I find out about the Terps is this
it makes you want to keep having a
session
it's exciting to keep going it doesn't
it doesn't kind of taper off it just
keeps growing through this beautiful
just soaring what this could be a thing
right here I mean I'm talking
forget about vapor lounges and bars with
alcohol and stuff what what about the
tert bar or the turf experience where
you go to dinners you gather with people
nice glasses brought to the table at the
end of your food maybe even in between
your dessert and your food and you have
a Terp platter that comes out of courses
man
you choose your Terps that you guys all
want to try and then you have this
beautiful experience we're just taking
micro doses and getting I read a Terp
dose with your mic with your with your
house in between courses to eat just
like matching wine with food stuff would
be I could eat right now I have to say
I'm not so totally stoned right now that
I couldn't eat a nice meal right now and
I can always we've also also this pretty
extreme to go through 18 flavors each
I mean I'm sure someone's done it
somewhere but I've never seen anyone do
it so who could answer that question
accurately lots of people out there in
the world but I bet you it's the first
time you guys seen it on YouTube if you
have seen it before post the link in the
comment section because we want to give
those guys a high five I'm telling you
what are we 14 and 15 and 16 in - loved
these lost user oh my god did I plan
that you probably did but subconsciously
cherry ak-47 and strawberry mind-warped
let's keep it in order and go for the
strawberry mind work good oh [ __ ] okay
yep mm-hmm
you know I guess the next sort of levels
of this stuff these Turk parties is
taking is is matching Turks with other
Terps and mixing and seeing what that is
I guess for sure you know like the
Jeffrey the Jeff is the the Jeffrey when
you don't wipe your dabber with your
deborah rag here you could end up kind
of each time producing a little bit of a
Jeffrey effect and picking up effects
from the other ones although you know
I'm sure we've had a little bit of that
happen by no means I've been wiping my
dabber on this little guy but not every
souls 2 times 18 - imagines brand-new
balls that's it there's a [ __ ] truth
test there's the next level well let's
do it next time like that good then
maybe get a couple more people in here
because we've shown that we can do it in
a fairly short time I don't know what
the timeline is but don't I know we're
definitely not two hours into video now
triple dub those these are [ __ ]
you gotta go check out D 420k on vine
i'm bc bubble man check me out as well
he's got these just ridiculous vines
that i think they could go viral there's
Bhangra triple dip double dip long
ripoff triple dip it's funny dude have
you dipped yes they did ok so we are
dipped the strawberry Mindwarp 17:17
thrip turk modulation here we go nuts
with flowers they're ours 3d flowers wow
it overpowered my bong in my and my nail
and everything Wow holy [ __ ] smell your
carb cap dude my car cap smells so good
Wow interesting very interesting
well that is special have a smell while
you're tasting it I find that that is
definitely the double dose of really
everyone has a different olfactory sense
do you have that you talk about that
pipe last pass Church which one where
you'd have the double bull exactly the
vaporizer and then a strip yes he's kind
of like this yes it was terpene
modulation
I was I was lightly vaping off the Terps
and some cannabinoids and then using
hash in a separate Bowl this pipe melted
together only at the top mouthpiece
where the two vapors collided for the
first time it was it was a beautiful
thing but this is some next-level [ __ ]
that we're onto right now let me tell
you we're actually on number 18 we're on
number 18 we motored through these dude
I'm almost willing to go through the
backwards now I'm joking
18 is cool I wanted to make a short
video I didn't want it to be 2 hours for
holy [ __ ] hopefully it's under the hour
limit I really I kind of hope so anyway
but give that a little wipe ski and go
fresh from my last hit although this
isn't my last hit because I'm definitely
finishing it with a big [ __ ] rip of
Congo yeah
and I'm taking a pretty big rip with
this strawberry my weight off to [ __ ]
him check it out mmm yeah just go a
little bigger for the last one or second
last one this I didn't I think I want to
take a rip of some of that rosin you got
over there or something you're always
walking around my stash brother of
course you know thank you
ya know there's no great tune number 18
strawberry Mindwarp once again Tony
Lazzara dude thank you so much for this
experience
we're doing amazing things super happy
to help represent blue river up here in
Canada and be a part of the United
cannabis team Ernie and Tony and the
good people at Harborside Steve DeAngelo
and [ __ ] here's for 2016 everyone Cheers
oh my oh my is right the low temp dabs
are so nice oh yeah
Wow yeah holy [ __ ] Annapolis whoa that
what I have to say if it did land on
that being the last one I wouldn't have
been upset that was the cherry ak-47
honestly honestly I would not have been
upset about any of them being the last
one there's not there's not one thing in
there well you know what my brain is
telling me the juicy fruit imitation was
the only one that maybe didn't belong on
the pedestal well I wouldn't say didn't
belong but I would say it would be would
be the one that that I like the least
out of all of them
yeah but I loved it I would not exactly
can't get out of bed
rockers type thing when I ran out of
blue dream last time I was bumped out of
18 kinds something has to be at the end
of the [ __ ] that's right there has to be
something that's your mind speaks has
that's what a purple punch purple boston
red congolese so let's do this up
properly finish our video I'm gonna hit
my butter here my butter rosin you're
hitting the shadow rosin all right now I
hit the shadow rosin for every one of
those rips now I'm gonna just do a
butter rosin for my last Congolese Red
Congolese and wonderful
I hope yeah I hope it inspires you guys
to do a similar thing have fun with your
terpenes get together with your friends
you know be safe
be understanding that we're still
learning and hey I urge anyone that has
an interest
chemistry you know phyto cannabinoids
and terpenoids to study right now PhDs
can be written on phyto cannabinoids and
terpenoids of cannabis and it's you guys
that are going to teach us all the
important things that we need to know to
use these as safe modulators in the
future so give thanks everyone for
watching bubble man's world's read
Congolese purple punch peace out peace
[Music]
[Laughter]