[Music]
hey welcome to bone man's world everyone
I am here with yet another unboxing
video this came from the good folks over
at load elapsed I've never actually seen
this unit in real life I'd only seen
pictures of it it's sort of an electric
dab RIT I wouldn't compare it to the
puff co although I did see them time to
comparing it to the puff Co but I'm
pretty sure it's a wired device so it
might be more of a comparison to like a
vapour tail or a unit like that so it's
supposed to be unit for dabbing it's a
pipe I saw it it looked pretty cool and
it looked like something I wanted to
check out so I guess we'll start with a
small box first probably some of the
accessories that came with the unit
that's usually how it goes in the front
there all right so we've got a dabber I
believe it's a glass tapper so you want
to be careful with that right there
dabber these are gonna be components
that I saw yeah so there's the you piece
that goes underneath the pipe I watched
on their website at little apps I
basically watched the guy you know you
know put it together from right out of
the box so hopefully I'll be able to get
this right and I won't have too many
pauses in here but I guess we'll see
okay so we've got this is the magnetic
Bowl there's also a little nail that
fits in there
we're seeing it's probably in here so
I'm not even sure how this thing works I
don't know if it's the nail that's
conducting the heat and create like I
really I'm not too sure what the design
of the pipe is even though I've seen it
on video I haven't seen it in person so
okay and then there's that all right
just the L must be with the other stuff
so I'll keep this stuff separate and
then we'll open up the big box
okay here we go nice looks like a box
with inbox shipping details interesting
slow case little labs doing it upright
and to read this first excellent right
huh
might as well crack open that accessory
stand nice little wood stand - I suppose
hold these components I'm not even sure
if that's what that's for or not
probably not these this must be for the
dabber and of course all right so put
that there so let me just guess this is
probably just an empty case that the
piece goes and oh yeah look at that
as keys it has nice high-density foam
cut into it for all of the components so
that is a pretty nice touch I'm not
gonna lie right off the bat I remember
seeing this you want to push out the box
to remove the sleeve it's nice to watch
these videos I have to admit I know that
their video was probably oh there's a
picture of the unit right there actually
so it's nice to have these unboxing
videos and I'm sure they did a much
better job at it than I am
but hey I might have different people
and it might be still nice for you guys
to see so rather than just send you over
there you can watch this one and then
you can go over there and watch a proper
unboxing video
alright the two sub sectors are in the
black the two susceptor are in the black
silicone carry case alright thank you so
let's see this cut out really well
there's your base and here's your glass
and then there's your silicone cases as
well as more of these little guys in the
dabbers and a pipe cleaner which is
always nice okay so that's what they're
talking about the susceptor so I guess
these are little nails so these are the
nails and then okay I got all of these
other components again as well all right
so let's start with moving this over
here I know that how they started was by
unscrewing the bottom the grommets
already in so that was not in in the
actual original
such a strange angle for this
I think that's right I head over to the
glottal labs okay that's the step by
step you must season the magnetic nail I
do remember that I remember this part
goes in here so this little part comes
off this is the little guy you will
slide this into there some paper this
will click just make sure that's right
all right so we got that figured out
basically the grommet was put in the
wrong way when it came so I confused me
I went and watched and now it makes
sense I've got the little u pipe
actually it was another one so this
little guy goes under here
the long piece goes right into the
center and the short piece goes into the
grommet that this Center cut a piece of
glass that slides down into there making
it so you basically have an all glass on
glass on glass hit so we put the base on
there and put the bottom of the unit on
which is fine that's good now we're
gonna want to put water on here you put
water up to about a third of the way
down put a little water in there
oh that's just about perfect right there
okay then we're going to drop this
little guy on right so that goes on top
of that then you have this little a
guest titanium nail that's open on one
end and closed on the other and it goes
inside this little piece of glass and
that little piece of glass goes right
there and then yeah I guess you get your
pipe right there and your pipe cleaners
and your little Gabor's and then it's
just a matter of pulling out our
electronic components for this little
bit and pull up a chair and sit and have
a quick down with you guys see how this
unit works I'm always excited for new
technologies when it comes to dabbing
always always interested to see what
people are working on I always think
that the next best thing is right around
the corner so not to you know not pay
close attention to the works that people
are doing and so little labs caught my
attention with this little unit soon
enough we will have an idea
so all right right in the front there's
a push on the button let's got a light
and then I guess blue being the coldest
and pink being the warmest there we go
maybe didn't goes to red yeah it does go
to red so you can see that tiny little
bit of smoke that just came out that's
that little bit of that little bit of
seasoning that's coming off the nail
anytime you've ever used any type of
metal component you know that it's a
good idea to make sure that that is
clean before you start hitting it so the
way it said on the well it says right
here important make sure to turn legend
on and off for each session Oh before
using legend
must season the magnetic nail the
susceptor to do this turn the dial to
red and leave it on for 15 to 20 seconds
let it cool for five minutes and then
you're ready to begin alright make sure
you turn legend on and off for each
session legend their legend heats
extremely fast the biggest mistake many
users make is leaving it on for too long
five to ten seconds is all you need okay
so let's cool that down yeah it's got
quite a coil that's wrapped around here
so I'm gonna pull up a chair down here
you probably wait that five minutes and
then I've got some flavors right here
I'll be starting on the lowest temp for
this particular unit oh it's got a great
little great little how-to book that
shows you know in really nice clean
photographs shows the whole process I
mean this is simple simple simple I like
this okay power level zero blue no heat
level one a little darker than Purple's
level two much more purple is level
three than sort of a pinkish is level
four then we're getting into red level
five and then almost a Horan's level six
so also there's error modes if you leave
the magnetic nail out I guess what
happens is you don't get that heat it
doesn't heat up and it'll start flashing
on you so it'll flash orange three times
when it's over temperature it'll flash
orange until susceptor is inserted when
you leave that out so so also Bluetooth
you can Bluetooth download the app press
and hold button on legend legend will
enter pairing mode and flash a teal blue
color the legend will hold a solid teal
blue color when the device pairs well we
gotta do that I gotta get my phone
alright so let's go see if we can't find
the app the app amok slow control of
your Legend go to okay so you got to go
to low to labs to get the lab no problem
so this is all part of it loto low to
labs.com
lota labs comm backslash app so that's
easy pretty simple so I'm in here
welcome over the years 21 load alleged
iOS app low deluxe iOS app I want legend
so we're gonna go buy OS app there it is
a nice picture of the pipe we'll go get
so go to local labs download install the
app on your phone open the app and
follow in the directions okay
I'm gonna download this cuz we're
waiting for this to cool anyway right
now so this will download after
downloading the app and following the
directions you can pair legend with your
phone press and hold down button on
legend legend will enter pairing mode
and flash a teal blue color the legend
will hold a solid teal blue color when
the device pairs well let's see how easy
that is so far it's been very easy
I guess I'll create an account why not
let's do this let's be bubble man let's
do it
alright oh yeah you got to put the what
here that's funny I just put bubble man
I didn't I put bc bo man I didn't put I
didn't actually put at icloud.com
just definitely good to have so now
we're gonna sign in that was very easy
to set up I don't have to wait for them
to send me in an email or anything like
that they let me pick my own password
fast enough and I guess they're a new
enough company that all the names
haven't been taken yet so that's time
nice okay so we're gonna hold this down
alright so there we go connect to
legends we are connecting a pair yes
pair we want to pair with this guy
register this legend yes name your
legend bubble man's bubble man's legend
then there it is now I've got my legend
here she's all paired up I can put it on
what
I want easy enough that's pretty cool
now I'm definitely controlling this
thing I want to do a fairly low temp tab
but I don't want to do a cold down I
don't want to do a super hot down so
they didn't say it was 10 seconds of us
let's see what this thing can do but
they give me a carb cap it must have a
carb cap right like I can't really
imagine that not having a carb chat let
me see if you missed the carbon cap
maybe this works carb free let's try it
out shall we
oh it was interesting I've never hit on
a pipe before that didn't have a carb
that actually still hit pretty damn good
now I think I heated it up a little bit
too much I think I'm gonna even go for a
lower down but one of the things I read
in the book is that it gets up to
temperature very fast 5 to 10 seconds so
I suspect this unit is a unit that you
want to have your dad ready when you
turn it on almost like the dream
cold-start unit and that's what I'm
gonna do for the next tab because I know
I've hit this resident enough that it it
just had a little bit of a different
taste almost like it got heated up to
750 degrees instead of 680 and lately
because I've got the temp tech USA I've
really been paying Louis attention to
the taste of the hit and associating it
with that actual temperature of that hit
so definitely got nice and lit off that
hit that's for sure let's let's go again
and let's go almost right away this time
oh yeah that tasted fire
yeah I got a car of mine got it
important for the low temp dabber make
sure you turn it off right away because
as fast as you're getting it it's
heating up and so I think this unit is
pretty damn cool I love the way it's
different you know you know it's still a
pipe but it's a little bit different
than what most people have been coming
out with oh yeah that's magnetic that
holes right in there and that's real
nice that just pulls right out and this
will be super easy to flip and clean so
actually see how hot that is not too bad
I did have q-tips I was going to use but
I'll just do that later on pretty cool
little unit all around I like the feel
of it I like that it's different and
then it's not that same old same old
bomb I feel like people who are new to
cannabis and maybe new to dabbing might
find this of interest really clean unit
the glass just goes on and off real
simple real easy to turn on and off and
you know works obviously with any dabber
that you have you know not too shabby I
think that getting a great-tasting head
out of this probably won't take me much
longer than three or four more hits even
my second hit was just tremendous and
then it even gave me that smokey hit
towards the end of it so for those of
you that want to get that wasted to
taste it you know that cold start where
you really get that enjoyable rip but
then you also want that punch with it at
the end you leave this thing on even on
a low temperature I didn't go up to read
I can't imagine this thing must be at a
thousand degrees at read probably
something Johnny B would like for his
pain shout out to Lauder Labs for
sending this to me this is just the
unboxing video I will be using the unit
over the course of the next couple of
months and I'll let you know how it
holds up whether the glass is sturdy
whether the components hold up how the
pipe fits and feels in my everyday you
know office life how it sits on my table
and how other people react to it as well
so stay tuned for more on little labs
you can check them out at little labs
comm they're also on Instagram thanks so
much guys
may the full melt bless your little labs
legend sooner than later peace out of
everybody
[Music]
Sony's strike light seen as the market
break my game is open why this one was
up in my face the wisdom of the right my
gets that straight
[Music]
obesity I love the zoo