[Music]
hey good morning everyone it's 6:30 in
the morning right now pitch black
outside I'm about to head over to
Vancouver Island while gonna go over to
the fairies in Horseshoe Bay which will
lead us over to Nanaimo and then we're
gonna drive down into Duncan and we'll
be at our destination hope you guys are
ready for a pretty awesome trip we're
gonna go see these great gardeners and
they really know what they're doing over
there they've got a seed crop hang in
they've got some a bunch of hash ready
to be made both dry sift and wet wash so
we should be having a good time today
I'm just gonna hit a little rip of the
dry sift that we made yesterday with
Jhanvi haven't seen me do this in a
while I packed my d nail so we're
hitting the swiss perc with the beeline
anyway we've got a great trip plan for
today so come join me let's go for a
ferry ride see you soon hey guys so both
7:00 in the morning now the sky is just
starting to get a little bit of color
I'm gonna throw the big screens in my
truck here when we catch an 8:30 ferry
4x2 screens here we've got the some
bubble bags tumble now Dean ale so we
basically got everything that we're
gonna require to have a great trip over
at the great gardeners and yeah we'll
catch up with you guys on the ferry
[Music]
one of our special guests during our New
Year's Eve run here on jamon that was
the Disco Biscuits
[Music]
oh really even with the sled I'm just
over 20 feet
I'm with the sled I'm about 22 I'm being
honest
I'm 20.8 otherwise all right see what
you get for being honest in this world
no thanks a lot see you later
series
[Music]
[ __ ]
[ __ ] up here at the front of the ferry
but I think so on the ferry
heading over to the island it's cold but
what a beautiful sunny clear day just
this is the back of the ferry where
generally you get the last wind and if
you're for British Columbia or if you've
gone to the Sunshine Coast or any of the
Gulf Islands Vancouver Island included
you know that the back of the ferry is
where everyone goes to pop so you bring
your joy you bring your trip you stick
you bring your pipe there's generally no
troubles to be had puffing at the back
of the ferry
so yeah beautiful day to be heading over
to see the great gardener really excited
to see what those guys are gonna pull
off today I hear they have a beautiful
seed crop so that should be exciting to
work with we'll make a little bit of
hash and we'll just take you guys for a
little trip through BC this is one of
the bonuses of living here for sure I'm
gonna go grab a snack
[Music]
how's that for a Pelican case collection
these are my Marcel's that I'm bringing
with me just a couple of my pipes you
know
[Music]
[Applause]
I was going up suck my dick
[Music]
I think we're at the right place
doing that
hey how's it going man yeah set
everybody setting up the microscope a
little camera oh yeah house of this
right gardener yeah beautiful so stoked
to be here man little bubble dry in here
some bags hanging here we go beautiful
what we got going here this is a big
test room mostly high CBD phenotypes of
a lot of favorite strains from the
Kobashi Club so we got high CBD warlock
high CBD a high CBD digweed high CBD
Renee beautiful so these were all
crossed with these are all catatonic
crosses Hannah tonic crosses and
we started off with 50 seeds of each
[Music]
down to 20 within the production and
then of the 20
by roughly about five here is the
phenotype that we were looking for is a
warlock so five of them had warlock
characteristics and it of those five and
we CBD tested them roughly about two of
them came out high CBD so now we're
pretty here I got the candy cannon tonic
eight and then back tears he came to
talk
now we're trying to just figure out
which one's best we've been that way
we're going to put into the members of
the club and we'll let them decide which
one they like better right excellent
bioassay CBD line and you want to give
just the people that you know who are
watching I know a lot of people are
hearing a lot of things about different
cannabinoids and CBD in particular what
why are so many people looking for CBD
CBD carries a lot of the medicinal
healing effects without the THC high so
a lot of people are coming to medical
cannabis not from the recreational
cannabis and they want more healing
properties and not necessarily getting
really high absolutely so some people
like to you know they want to go to work
and they want to be able to eat a
lozenge or either either eat something
that's not going to get them high and
make their job difficult but in with the
high CBD strains they can have it they
can know
paint goes away information goes away
headaches go away and they don't
necessarily get high from it so right
now could they deal with a lot of clubs
yeah the high CBD is
is sought after the canna tonic that we
have it's everybody wants it it's the
popular choice I'm noticing as well for
kids with Tourette's syndrome and other
forms of epilepsy yeah that's the high
CBD is virtually no THC we haven't gone
on we haven't found one yet I know
there's a few out of there but we're
still we're still looking for that
elusive high CBD low THC phenotype
beautiful it's gonna take a little quick
walk through the aisles here
you guys have done a great job building
some nice rooms it's comfortable in here
the airflow is good
you got your ballast tie which is key
then all your Reza's are outside in the
hallway
drip-feeding
when they're small and hand watering
baths
sure
you foliar spray as well
preventive is always good to be
preventive
we have flour yeah
I took the Barbara excellent look at
this
screens are out more importantly start
it with the house of the great gardener
[Music]
very nicely I'll talk Leona tonic that's
the high CBD beautiful well done Ryan
racks now at the end oh yeah walk
through
and what kind of temperature and
humidity is are you looking for in here
[Music]
control mm-hmm
but doesn't feel muggy in here at all it
definitely no no if it gets too hot we
have fans I'm more concerned with the
air blowing down and just keeping a
constant airflow still takes seven to
ten days for them to draw here and then
we'll go into bins and then from there
we'll treat them right flip them get the
moisture out and then from then destock
them and then back into bins okay oh
good process all this all the shake is
put on screens no that's what I'm
talking about right there this is what I
want people to see this is how you do it
people you don't have to go and buy
expensive racks from restaurants you can
build your own this is perfect
he's got them dated and named this is
really nice to see this is just so much
resin lost when not done you those
sitting on here since December 13th Wow
it's ready it's ready no it's ready for
that and you know you have catch trays
on the bottoms or on the very bottom we
have little trays that clip onto here
mm-hmm
so it clips onto here and then you pull
it out and then you flip it beautiful
and then you move it down you're holding
X going out but all he ever gets
flipping once and that's it
from there and scooped up and excellent
either put through the tumblers through
the tumblers to the to the nut to the
bakers gosh then to the Baker's tumblers
bags and bakers never still us you see
it it's sort of dried to hatch but if
he's a little bit marshmallow ease it in
the middle yeah so it's those a couple
more days to go
[Music]
this is a barber bud seed room little
frosty that is somebody's have been it's
very frosty and we manly is removed but
it's you know a lot of the fan leaves
work personally well there's a cake and
this is why you do this over screens cuz
he just literally knocked off eight
hundred and fifty three thousand gland
heads I didn't catch it and we're
catching them all absolutely but they
wouldn't be caught without those screens
you can see if I just oh yeah do you
have a seat separator that you guys user
just do it on a couple sort of again
homemade machines you know just run them
through holes no I'm not even a use
night is more sort of gravity and pump
and airflow you've seen those laser
perforated whole sheets though those are
pretty good with a little vibrator I've
seen as long I've seen the one with the
blows the air up and blows the shop up
right yeah that's nice and through the
tube or whatever yeah those are pretty
impressive too Wow ingenuity so
basically the work here is to de-seed
these do stock them you don't really
have to do this stage but because the
fact that we miss that we want to
capture the trichomes right always want
to keep the surface in front of you
clean is when you cut it off and it's
the screen thousands of trichomes have
just fallen off that button you collect
that so you sit here you know it's you
know it's a try when I could sit here
and use my fingers
even need the Fiskars nobody I don't
need these scissors like I can operate
this whole thing with just using my
scissors but but this but it's soft and
still if you squeezed it mm-hmm
it's good so we'll sit here and do a
little debugging do a little debug I'm
gonna take a few macro shots of that
resin to show people the quality that
you're working with and then once you
have a little pile in front of you just
lightly push it forward you always want
to make sure that the bun falls directly
on the screen
let's go downstairs
[Music]
you always tell where workstation was
yeah that one was definitely well worked
[Music]
nice pile of sift
the other car it's got something here
for you
so will you keep these four separate or
just mix them all yeah they're all the
same
[Music]
and what happened put my shades on
thank you glad you did that work on
screens quick test throw it here throw
it in your hand squeeze it for a second
I mean yeah
[Music]
Oh anaerobic that's a word so word
closed aromatic aromatic quote a Rolnik
aroma I like it quick
Romek
[Music]
so he cleaning your sifter the tumbler
get it all clean very important
absolutely
I was showing just the other day we were
using forced air to clean just the
screens like to get a more powerful yeah
me too we weren't working with enough
power
like even put it in a small box or
something with a little intake and then
a bunch of air that just blows it from
multiple angles and spins it oh yeah
yeah you can definitely see it
and there goes more resin than most
people will ever see
yeah well
I guess we're getting ready to do a
little dry sifting they're upstairs
deceiving that Barbara bud and Matt here
is cleaning out the large Hall reader
inserts the tumbler and I've got my
tumble now as well as some big screens
he's got some big screens so we're gonna
play around it make some cries - you
need some help
no now before you say anything the last
room that went through this was we
called it the 48 hour and a 72 hour run
it's a it's already done a 30-second run
I got like a minute run and then we go
to an hour run and then we do a 24 hour
run and then we go for 24 to 48 hour run
and then we could do the 48 hour to 72
hour run well so this is the spin or
nine hour to 72 hour run so you're
cleaning it out and we're just cleaning
it or skip vacuum it out all right
sounds good
[Music]
so time to make some dry center of that
because it's a seed crop we're gonna do
it for 30 seconds ten minutes one hour
run at which point we'll take it after
we got the seed out of it bring it back
and we'll bring it back for 24 hour run
and then we'll put it in 24 to 48 hour
run and then we put it in for like 2
days 48 to 72 hours
[Music]
so wouldn't we just dump it in there 15
pounds or 10 pounds of Earth five pounds
of Earth gonna be ten five yeah probably
five it's lucky that high well within my
storage limits of my MMA our license
yeah it's got a stopwatch this stopwatch
30 seconds one minute will be one minute
ready one minute one minute run just
leave the lid off it's happening ice in
so it's nice to be standing next to a
nice large unit the tumble now doesn't
come in this size and fortunately have
left when they occupied this particular
is a gardeners that's the 10-minute run
and oh my god the smell is like shish
kebob
is so strong yeah there's only that
corner and look at that you can see the
difference of the colors on the top it's
almost marinas tinge and as you flip the
resin over you can see a much bolder
resin underneath so we'll get to that
later separating those two grades and
we'll show them on a plate and green and
the gold separator pile there Tommy and
outside
[Music]
five or ten minutes
and as you run this long or Lord from
harder harder and harder female
blackheads from the capitate stocks as
for the pears the flat pattern grab a
piece of hard work heavy SIPP is a good
something better than light sift tends
to be down with it rather than glad to
the sift
covered everywhere you need like big
scoops like painters tools or you know I
won't really know for sure cards are not
cutting it for the great partner you
small lazy smoke
[Music]
okay another microscope and check it out
boom Oh anyone anyone anyone anyone all
right for 1913 why don't we head on over
to the devastation one hour run that
time for ten minutes
[Music]
that's over here somewhere
these guys
[Music]
right up real fast
more deaths
[Music]
I will do a little tumble now run
afterwards - after you've run this for
10 minutes yeah perfect that is a nice
smell
not so much on the outside but after the
24-hour
and you saw that one that was but have
been broken it all out there's a lot of
work Lorient especially her seeds
[Music]
sorry sure yeah yeah papaya that's so
deep when you can see the screen where
the screen was hit night that looks like
some hundreds of grams you might want to
get some type of tough tub in there
it'll happen it's what you're gonna want
to get some sort of tough and then write
all that out that
[Applause]
[Music]
that's a good amount it's a good amount
of weight right there for sure and it is
dense you're right it's it looks denser
when you think or it is denser than you
think it's denser than it looks
you're covered so you've gotten to the
point where Barbara has been well sifted
for an hour and those big fluffy buns we
hide I have this sort of like this but
you gotta get the seed out so we do it
onto the screen so all the seed and
everything nuts will already fall
through
breaks up all the band get in particular
it gets out all the see usually do this
with love I thought we stopped all the
teens authority harvested
loose stuff fall through
happy to do it all end up end up throw
with that then from in there you get the
CD do
ready get them
but they're in there and separate those
further using the scene screen
separators and pulled them out by hand
yeah we have a couple other wind
machines that will blow the chip blow
the chaff away and then one more after
that one more system after that that
uses the angles and lets the seeds roll
down perfect then you put a fan on their
clothes off so a good amount of sift
came off of that off without Barbara
looks pretty good so that's the one-hour
run so then after we get the seed out
we'll actually put this back in back in
the sifter and do a 24 hour run okay and
the last little bit in the 24 hour to 48
hour run and that stuff will go to
edibles tinctures awesome awesome there
we go
it's the great gardener today's chores I
was pulling everybody taking down a
little catatonic icdd
been hanging
for just about a week perfect we're
gonna put it in the bins leave the lid
off the bins overnight and then we'll
sort of then we'll little flip them a
couple days probably three four days
what five is then we'll destock it goes
back into the bins and then it's just
the process of every day you go in slide
your hands behind your hand to the
bottom of the bin and it feels a little
moister at the bottom and you sort of
flip it up and show up and you reach
your hand to the bottom and it feels the
same as the top and you can sort of put
the lid on it
at which point to the next level you can
cure it for however you want or you can
smoke it it's ready to go beautiful
some people like pyramid some know and
is this a seated crop no this is this
regular crop I know medicine crop this
is a medicine crowd
[Music]
beautiful