hey guys bubble man here just uh doing a
little photography macro photography
here in Remo's room beautiful UVC chemo
Kush um yeah I'll be sharing these
photos in the near near future the thing
is absolutely covered in resin super
beautiful there's actually a whole row
of them here behind me um I'm going to
shoot that and then we're going to head
on over and we're going to
shoot um the blue cheese which is over
here this is the blue cheese here this
guy right here absolutely ridiculous
covered in resin completely we're going
to talk about the rock star we're going
to photograph the rock star another real
beautiful strain bong Guru and then of
course last but certainly not least
we're going to talk about um the Kosher
Kush from DNA genetics this thing looks
like Girl Scout cookies man it is
absolutely Beau beautiful super nice oh
yeah and I better not forget
Karma genetics the Beast back
here I believe this is the white OG and
this thing is uh pretty ridiculous as
well so yeah we're going to have fun
nonetheless I'm in a room full of
monsters I love it this is where I'm the
happiest and uh yeah I'm going to get
back to macro shooting so I can share
the pictures and we'll see you soon on
Bubble man's world