[Music]
all right well welcome to Bubble man's
world I just bumped into this crazy
bastard right here I better take that
down I look like I'm
glowing um and what does he put into my
hands right when he arrived this is what
he puts into my hands a a Marcel like
ready air trapped sick Sherlock and then
with a d marble on the other side which
I personally am friends with both these
dudes have been friends with them for a
long time not as connected with Dr Rex
as I used to be but still when I saw it
it put a smile on my face dude and the
first time I saw one of these marbles
was a long time ago oh yeah and on such
a beautiful little piece so what do you
got going on there full melt um the
White full melt the white well excellent
full melt the white here's the full melt
the white you guys can see that I think
pattied out a little bit pattied out
finally finally no problem there we go
kind of
grabbing uh what do we got to light
some
boom and I have this torch as well in
case we wanted to take a dab wonderful
so uh we just bumped into each other
because we are taking our sons to a
movie our my son's first movie so this
is a pretty epic moment it's going to be
funny it's the Penguins of Madagascar
yeah he loves it usually for with me
with my son I usually go see sort of
more of an older person kind of movie
and but today it was it was this was the
choice and I thought you know I should I
should let yeah I should let these guys
know yeah no it's it was uh really nice
to invite us cuz um Owen is beyond
excited to a hang out with Tosh and you
and B see the Penguins of Madagascar
which he loves
so it's a family affair here on Bubble
man's world
today that was a ripping awesome rip
that I just took uh on Bubble man's
world here today the that thing actually
rage I hit it like a dab though I didn't
like smoke it like a Sherlock I
literally just smoked it through in one
hit I just got the uh the first shipment
from the stuff from the pipe Masters
collab oh yeah yeah so it's
um see if you guys can catch that
so I got this and I got the Gordman JD
Maples Den Sherlock Rick and this guy
excellent yeah I found my Dabber ey as I
was searching for the uh tools of the
trade I wasn't sure what you had exactly
but I brought uh some gifted hash which
is I believe chemo bubble from our good
friend hyand oh yes and then there's
some it's sitting in sweet skunk dry
sift and then I also have some d420 K
that Uber
goober like ridiculous dry sift that's a
year
old and has just greased the [ __ ]
out that'll hit you yeah that was a rip
so anyway we thought before we went and
saw this movie we would share a little
uh bong rip with you guys a little
Sherlock rip give props to Marcel give
props to D give props to all the Growers
and all the ha
smokers what he from the industry let's
go watch a movie let's go watch a movie
see you guys in a bit