hey good morning everyone bubbleman here
welcome to bald man's world it's about
five in the morning right now and I am
gearing up finally today to head over to
Toronto for that next generation
financial conference that John and I are
both speaking at and then on Friday
we're heading over to Jamaica for this
project that we've got to brewing so
we'll keep you informed on how that's
going I figured I'd wake up today and
have a quick little puff my Swiss perk
is a little bit dirty but nonetheless
got some full melt dry sipped here that
I made the other day and I figured i
would share a bowl with the YouTube
audience so I'm gonna be seeing my good
buddy Chester you guys have met Chester
before on my trips to Amsterdam he was
the dude that was doing the tuk-tuk
riding with me I of course haven't
forgot you Chester we got your astro boy
we got your sweet skunk and of course we
gotcha Congo Chester's been growing
probably for 40 years he's a really old
school good friend of mine and I'm very
happy to be bringing him some genetics
so let's have this quick puff and we'll
get on the road and we'll go meet Johnny
be at the airport for a little Airport
session that's what we always do
all right that is the power cloner 45
plant botanicare power toner that you
can hear in the background bubbling and
away um I guess there's nothing left to
do but grab these genetics and get on a
plane once you come join me no you
didn't you didn't oh my god that would
have been so funny what's up guys just
got here with Mike and Johnny be at the
airport [ __ ] dude Toronto Jamaica go
Mike okay I'll go see a man good to see
it so I guess we're gonna get our
luggage throw it in there and come out
and have a puff so I'll catch up with
you in a second here
alright so we got our bags checked our
bags a jack I got my oil slick summit
trippy stick tripping up I say old boy
oh boy let's get trippy let's get
trippin throw a little fresh frozen
astral
and fresh frozen
oh it's got fresh frozen so are you
excited for this trip gun
I'm going to make it too did I know yard
of course I'm excited we're pretty
excited how can you not be excited we
speak at the next gen conference in a
couple of days and in great speech it's
going to be good it'll be a good
conference there should be some good
people i expect them to be a lot bigger
than vancouver there's a larger
population out east of course and
there's a big financial district in
Toronto I think it's going to be one of
those epic life changing events
or at least memorable we are potentially
historical I'm going to say it could be
historical Friday is going to be the day
to really start watching bubble man's
world if you haven't before this Friday
is the day we land in Kingston Jamaica
at the Norman P manly international
airport and we will head into the city
and we'll go make sure we go by
emancipation Park maybe hook up with the
nomads pull up a couple of other friends
see if we can't hook up with cloud
in Kingston actually he's even gonna be
on
a long coat code in Ashley I think they
are
so you know it's definitely exciting
times now why don't we go clear security
yeah do I do that I want to hit this
definitely catch you guys on the plane
Oh
you want
have enough
richmond
how we can shout back from the video
I like little Conte
so that pregnant girl
ain't no casino
without hear that last pitch around me
alright well John we're here in the back
of our car of our good buddy a finger
boy in the front here Ashley say hello
hey what's going on dude Ashley we're
going downtown out you know the other
day don't worry these guys are a big
part of the Jamaican project that we are
a little bit hush-hush on but they
picked us up at the airport and now
we're just while there puffing a doob
what do you got popped in there Johnny I
maxi slump in some Dennis Hopper I'm
playing on record music Oh some reggae
music Richie
gonna be a great trip get you guys in
Toronto one minute warning heading into
Toronto what it looks like in its 420
happy bunny a great love let's make sure
this is working wow we always want to
make sure the d-mail is working I kind
of poached the whip hey guys welcome
back hey welcome back there we go see
the little bow it gets it down it's my
whip i damaged the whip so i should well
yeah i damaged it when we poach the d
nail in barcelona arsenal hamster what
if we push that detailing is better
alright so come on baby give us that
once you see this little dock right here
and it's going down said right below 900
is usually when it quits yep figure this
one it is it's like this one he's up it
does it's just like the little piece in
here that it's measuring with i think i
damaged it when we blew it up Dino has
done me nothing but solid by the way as
we talked about this and actually to go
back before even talking about the
d-mail John and I were laughing but
before we started the video and we're
gonna do a video on this you know how
they do mean tweets you know you get
famous people reading tweets that are
just cruel and unusual unusual and they
read the minutes hilarious well John and
I have been getting some very cruel and
unusual comments now I'll give you this
ninety-nine percent of you guys are
awesome it's just that one percent this
is that one that seems to be intense on
crushing our souls and they're just like
they're why I hate yeah I don't know I
mean I it's all good it's kind of crazy
but at the same time we're happy to be
doing these videos for you guys and you
don't want nobody that telling us that
you know this bad thing or that bad
thing about this is really gonna get us
to not know actually makes me smile yeah
more'n that are we see it the more than
realize that we're actually getting to
more people and educating on a bigger
scale but it's awesome you know the best
thing about it is we're here sharing on
this uh oh see what just happen there
see what just happened I wasn't a little
talking something he showed me that my
mind got completely distracted full Mel
dry sift itself pressed itself look at
that eh Booya ones that are smell
amazing okay weirdness yeah right so
what we realized is 11 with a buddy make
sure you always have suffered skillet
tools separate skillet tools is
important John and I are of course
you're spending an enormous amount of
time with each other lately in hotel
rooms and planes and traveling all over
the freaking world it's good it's a good
thing I enjoy it but at the same time we
have a lot of the same things we have
similar pipes and same skillet tools and
t-shirts and hats and Vince person all
the people that were friends would give
us these things and if we're a trip
recedes they're going to give us both
shirts and a 4 over at Medical seeds
they're gonna give this book shirts in
if you know where dança sends out a
hoodie will he's sendin him one out too
so we have a lot of the same things so
we're starting with like label or
stomach your shield on my figured you
know John I like it oh it's a very nice
thing so um great great great trip
coming in i miss the session at the
airport but it was so cool of ash to
pick us up we got picked up we had to
get in there so we did the session of
the car of course what you guys saw jam
this America yeah geminus Reagan and now
we're doing a session with you guys so
we're going to keep this short we're
just going to a couple of bowls each and
yeah then we're going to go up enjoy
this love the city for a couple of days
and mining see around
nothing to try ahead to this and then
can move on to this stuff that I may
actually late last night because I
realized I was running out not like well
[ __ ] I cut down while my stuff it's me
hanging and I'm like dude I gotta trim
this stuff up so I did a little balance
and you know what the rest is a frozen
for when I get home beautiful this dry
sick that I clean yesterday just turned
out exceptional can't believe how nice
it turned out actually it's nice to roll
into town with with a melty dry sift and
be able to you know share it with
friends d nailed abs and I'm hoping on
even getting a little wing while I'm
here well I brought some fun till that
tennis hell yeah you did I saw that I'm
gonna describe all your maintainer Tsar
fun-filled hums got like about 10 or 15
men Tanner's just stuffed full of nice
herbs just not stuff but I nothing
around so nice but what I've done is I
did that bad Goomer 420 label with an MK
ULTRA g6 oh yeah and then we have in the
roster we have from the demo hopper so
then of course the one and only many
that's a bubble Man one that one there
is the house oh the hostel like the Haas
we like pause so you know what though
these are probably gonna turn up some
gifts somebody smoked a few but
definitely not taking the DS with me to
Jamaica so uh I got two four six eight
nine it looks like 12 people are going
to get lucky well I think one of the
people right off the bat is our driver
today hun if they picked us up at the
airport I think we should at least give
him one and if the girl puffs we should
give her to you know I wanted one yes
because I mean they picked us up at the
airport they carry out all our bags they
brought two vehicles just so they could
carry all of our bags it was just me and
John yeah but they Mountain begging you
have one guys will show the picture
right now yeah that's ridiculous yeah
that's really good all right so one more
quick one and let's face it got meetings
we got to go meet up with harry in the
next gen crew don't we did with the MK
house MK ULTRA and of course I put it in
the house of great garden around
container it's just a little bit but you
must what were you able just later I
just like the first balance of that
beautiful i always talk about hit it
right now I'm smellin Gabbert an hour oh
so good to be in Toronto puffing bowls
two more days and we're in Jamaica what
we've been saying that a lot but it's
not going to be cool so yeah dinner and
meetings tonight it's more we have more
dinners and more meetings oh here's one
if I get this video if I get this video
up in time you guys want to come down
and meet us chill out will this pop some
bowls we're thinking of going to vapor
central on Yonge Street or no is it on
the other one catch me I don't know look
it up on google it vapor central we
might end up there either I mean I guess
potentially tonight but that's a little
early more like thursday i'm going to
say thursday night after an extra income
from yeah they're going to be having a
party probably they're all going to be
sitting around drinking and stuff but
well maybe maybe we'll announce at
nextgen that we're going to be going to
the vapor central and if the people who
you know don't have the interest on not
drinking that they can welcome us down
there
nice little long Hoff party exactly a
puff party a puff party alright well I'm
puffed up pretty good I needed those
types of grips we have some stuff to do
that I was meeting through the guys from
next gen conference and since six
o'clock in here group six o'clock so
everyone not see harry and hey we've got
24 speakers here over the next couple of
days be good huh it's gonna be good I
want to try fell a little bit more of it
give them little clips of almost you
know everyone speaking so they get a
better idea there you go last time I
really only videotaped you Kirk Jodi and
what's your name Alison know a gentleman
he'd Rihanna Adriana Herman start
melanietravels it was great it was good
and I'm looking forward to being part of
this time so uh I don't want to go head
up there and we'll catch these guys
later let's do this all right hey guys
it's the end of the night here but i
thought i'd share this as I was gearing
up and I was going through this product
grunge off friend of mine owns this
company it's actually quite a really
good product I guess I originally saw
this quite a few years ago in Amsterdam
and someone had told me that it was like
from a soybean oil extracted from a
soybean so it's a type of oil it's a
sort of organic cleaner works hella good
but how I keep my mother ship clean as I
fill it up with grunge off a little bit
run under the base there but that's okay
I fill it up with grunge off and I let
it soak overnight and then I also fill
up a glass and I've got the courts Bowl
and the other piece my 14 to 14 male
male the male and basically this just
makes it so it's real easy to clean in
the morning I'll show you guys will do a
quick rinse and everything will clean
out perfect and that way it makes life a
little bit easier for us as we're
traveling we're gonna have to get take
this to Jamaica and a couple of days you
want it to be clean
leave Jamaica we want to make sure that
it's clean coming back into Canada so
anyway thought I'd share that with you
guys have a good night people watching
old man's world and see you all