[Music]
all right guys we just got to the show
the puff and tough someone just brought
by some
cones bubble has man that's some sweet
share right there how how's that rip bro
how was
that some very okay sorry you no no no
no introduce yourself man Benny from
bads hits Imports umoh heads the
medtainer boys and bubble men were kind
enough to show me some really really
delicious nugs I believe this is what
the medic cush this is Med Kush grown by
John you actually could smell this
through the [ __ ]
[Music]
camera unbelievable unbelievable a
Goosebumps when I'm smelling it we're
going to CR that over those are
goosebumps show us those Goosebumps
again oh my God [ __ ] are those ever
clear bro too bad what do you think of
that Johnny got goosebumps when he
smiled your your herb now now I'm going
to tell Benny that we're going to crush
this over screens tomorrow we're going
to grind up every little bit of this
Harvest just those glandular heads and
I'm going to Puff it with you on Sunday
full m dyps yeah and I'll still smoke
those nugs after that's
done yeah buddy Med One Med Kush Mater
my medicine
awesome all right so on the right we
have a tun boobs collab and on the left
we have a Saki Bomb hoobs collab both of
these are
one-offs the Saki Bomb is the only one
with a three hole perk in the middle the
T Funk has a three-hole disc perk as
well just not as big as the sack bomb
you're not like with the custom mouth
pieces that eliminate Splash so no
splash on these little guys yeah that's
key right there you're going to have a
small piece put in a splash guard sweet
and the Omni nail just looks ever so
sweet on te water what up what up what
up so what are we going to be looking at
here bro so this is the Dosa J R Robin
Hood collab this is the smallest piece
Dosa has ever made in terms of a mini
tube it's 5 in
tall has a fully functional tie bucket
signed by Dosa J red and Robin Hood
2014 see all the sign the line work is
just
exceptional it's so hard to work
something this small it had to be done
with a hand
torch yeah there's that dose a crust
opal too yeah they're using ENC casement
on it is just unreal stringers to
actually make those sections in oh yeah
bring that opal marble back around there
we go let me get in on that guy and you
have two different colored Opals you
have the fire opal on the bottom Y and
then the icy opal on the
top and then a full tie bucket as well
crushed opal a little dose of I already
said if we start pulling man that looks
great in the light a d and a
face
speechless well I only have one thing to
say let's hit it
yeah all right guys we're about to hit
this sick little piece that MJ mororo
head brought with us he's playing with
some Barb 99% dry SI what do you think
of that make dry
yeah
we be quick there's no torches allowed
in here so def to be a little bit uh
careful with how we
Tor doing the back torch in I think
that's a good idea I'll Stand nearby as
well so nobody's the Wise One straight
lowkey torching straight lowkey torching
at the Champs
EA up that honey
bucket yes proper it's not going to hit
itself oh there we
go stoked to hit this piece
[Music]
old pendant carb cap very good
that
isce H you one
up get that bar going in there prob to
hit it at least
twice that [ __ ] tasted so
[Music]
good heats up faster than that second
time with the fors boy really
nice bar
r
heads I'm loving small pipes smaller the
better I just you know it used to be all
about the big huge giant Airy hit and
now it's about the small concentrated
tiny little
hit that's the true flavor
sa very
nice of course yeah for one more time
girl needs to hit the lady
presses so fast in the hands and the bar
just boom
[Music]
press this
is I know
[Music]
yeah dabbing it up at
Champs say hi to my friend that was
awesome catch up with you guys in a bit
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world I'm here with my good friend Sarah
Sunday that we have only really hung out
on the internet so here we are yeah now
we're in person we do video chats all
the time and I get see her weed but I
can't really tell how awesome it is
pretty awesome and I kind of believe
Hera well we're in person now
so show me some of her
we yeah
this right away
I like
you 6 seven weeks
kind of show you a little nug there I
don't know if the camera will fast this
is over this is probably take 10 days
over
that later
L okay yeah all that's lilac beautiful
lilac cush
yes section you got some amazing going
on to give you guys a little heads up
these guys are not good these guys are
not great these four roers are the
master
win fly from all
over we about 80
competitors so those guys there all the
best in the world so everybody take out
to go by the section and see what's
going on these guys are great
beyond everybody pleas check out and
back Andy lots of thank
you can't get it to show
organic nebula cured for a couple of
months I hope that we can get it in
there see the camera there we
go two Monon cure on the organic
nebula oh and the whole
bottom how's that for a a vault
wow cash crop Ken and what's this one
called again it's called Jazz F Jazz
but there it is jazz
butw I think we're going to do a dab or
to me and Sarah here super Stoker was
able to show me her nugget we not done
oh my God we're not done yet sir the Box
this one like the nicest one yes I
that okay this one so far is my favorite
this one right away honestly reminded me
of being at
SAS now let's see if we can get that
there we go so she calls this one ay
and it definitely has some very strong
hazy undertones I like
that oh yeah that was great they were
all really beautiful that
great oh here we go Med man seeds with
the wet west or
east it's it's nothing to do with East
Coast Sour Diesel it's often confused so
it's actually ter West Coast Sour Diesel
not to be confused with East nothing to
do with East he also calls it kerosene
push now but now it's been sort of
somewhat branded he's a pickle with
lovely so you grow out a variety of
different SE company
stuff loyal to anyone the best find
I really want
CL she wants to send her your
interesting clones if you want to see
some stuff produced on an exceptional
level get in touch with Sarah how can
they get in touch with uh friendly I
guess Facebook Facebook Sarah Sunday
probably the easiest
way oh yeah some nice weed here Remo
check that out I think you should check
it out how are you great
I'll all right thanks for watching guys
I'm going to say goodbye to Sarah now
we're going to continue to look at her
awesome
nug oh yeah
awesome peace oh thank you oh excellent
I can't wait
[Music]
[Applause]
in not in the hole but in the little mo
all right Che glass girl dabbing it up
are
you all
right and that was bar
like how was that amazing The Taste on
that will last for minutes yeah that's
so
good good job Matt thank you so much
you're
welcome all right I just had a friend
show up a longtime uh Bubble Bag user
and a fan and he just brought some Tahoe
OG by for us to check out check this
little nugget out right
there let's get that clear come on grab
it there it is Tahoe OG and more
importantly because everyone knows I
don't five brought the Tahoe OG bubble
hash be very careful way super crazy
Calo like uh Tangi flavor on this I'm
going to take a dab right
now decided to take a
dab here we go dabbing it
up taste as good as it smells champs
Toronto all right so this is that OG
Tahoe
OG with the 90
and the 120
160 oh
yeah it's 420 at the bubble medtainer
Booth let's [ __ ] do this guys back
420 you're not in you're not in he's in
oh yeah he's in oh
yeah oh yeah we're not smoking we're
vaporizing that big cloudy smoke is
really just Vapor it'll dissipate in
minutes happy
420 CH hey wait I'm
in I'm going to hit the congales
no 420 RI Mr cookie get in there
dude oh Phil of freshy that's the asend
of mine yeah yeah but I don't want to
have I don't want to have aen I know you
got Congo yeah I got a nice
little from
did you grow this and make
it just make it buy
it beautiful Mr
cookie yeah it was they said it was
Keith but it was actually
bubble wow Congo dry sip bubble whatever
awesome that is some paper thin
goodness lemony goodness nice to
see
right
always Germany people in Germany and
Berlin were like are you
cra London Wy
Stadium could tell
girl how
many all right and our 420 session
is now a 421
session all right we got meder John
showing Ross reati some of his gold
which one we got
My Little
[Music]
Pon what are you decide for me you a
cush yeah give the med
cush so whole plant extracted off of the
plant using bubble bags the whole plant
went right into the bags how's it going
dude good to see you man on so I'm not
going to hit you
too oh yeah the
screens happen we're just just dabbing
it up you know John and I do our
education together all the time we show
people how to extract just the pure gold
Amber Tricom head that's it nothing else
no that's the medicine that's the
medicine and that's really what we're
doing that's what we're all about right
exactly what we're all about so I mean
best part of here full melt dabs all
right on there and there you go no need
to touch the bowl at all touch the ball
just take the hit just take the hit nice
and slow and steady wins the
race feeding your endoc canabo system
can involve taking vaporizer hits
through dils or eating
medibles you don't touch the bowl and
the way you go yeah don't worry about
leaving smoke in it sometimes a little
bit will be left over but it's just
Vapor I notic
you oh
[Applause]
yeah oh that's that's my goal isn't that
nice yeah that is nice that is the
medicine I like how it's not like
causing me any problems right now
right
after well that's the thing better John
has neck and back injuries he can't
cough like a maniac after every hit
that's the thing so it needs to be Pure
Clean and proper no plant matters no
plant matter
Ripper small one and then maybe we'll
hit you up
with great let me catch my breath for
I'll take one in between 11
a.m. all right Johnny B
boom I have a different loud talkers
back on Bubble man's world Bubble maning
Up in the house what was your name aille
ail's in the house on on the camera and
show yourself yeah yeah bubble man
holding it down these guys brought
number one buddy the k f melt bubble
hash so we're going to do some rips Ripp
dabs man yeah dude [ __ ]
rice you saved that for how long a year
6 months six months that's still damn
impressive F what's up Jason got
the
man taking in the rigs
man D out get you fresh Supreme d
oh that's so
nice smell
that da da buddy I haven't heard that
one yet oh yeah da nice oh you got the
dab shirt on buddy rep that on C bro all
right
dude hes foam out it's a great world
when more people have access to stream
range that everyone's heard of and wants
but maybe doesn't have it in their
Gard access to it exactly we need to
help out of their reach man yeah bubble
man go to bring it International
together yeah man share share your
genetics all
[Music]
right
yep all right
back in a
[Music]
bit right in the door to a
dab how you
doing all the way from Holland to dab in
Toronto dab away the day yes okay let's
do
that oh I love it so nice perfect
[Music]
quality must mon for
yourself I I
I how it going
dude good to meet you
[Music]
man it never stops here we literally
worked for 7 hours today at the booth
and now with all our good
friends here in the room dabbing it up
with Marlon
Asher
Simon Simon dabbing it up
[Music]
the
day
[Music]
away I'm ready to jump up and walk out
of here with
[Music]
everyone rela
anyone else for a dab
[Music]
AO
Johnny Make Way for Johnny
[Music]
B and the power of canabo
education and pass it
around it's all
[Music]
about Mothership in full
effect are we going are we
done Sim wants a rip feed him a good
[Music]
Oney
one DJ Med
[Music]
[Applause]
Barb was that
barb dude look at that greasy look at it
[ __ ] like it's
ridiculous it was powder this morning I
have powder ridiculous well here I will
have some powder to I have some powder
right here pull up the powder there the
Barb
powder
[Music]
cheers so from this from this like what
an hour two hours to this well I had it
in my pocket all day yeah but it did
that pretty fast didn't it it didn't
take hours I want to see the no it looks
like it but the longer the longer it
goes the greas this one greasing right
in front of me really no but it's
it's almost that ridiculous all right
all right we go Cabana we're going to
hook up with Remo and crew see you in a
bit
[Music]
wait I don't know what do you say Remo
it's pretty awesome man let's head on
[Music]
up it's [ __ ] crazy Place awesome
place what is that is that all like
crazy hot chicks
that's
[Music]
ridiculous
[Applause]
yeah pretty
killer we are ATA Savannah having a nice
meal with a bunch of in folks
berer at the end there we got horo we
got Johnny V got Simon for Ser SE we're
having a nice
meal be popping
soon we're already
popping a medic a long day
[Music]
I got to find my car while I'm
videotaping this ridiculous you never
see and I got
[Applause]
the don't see this in the
[Music]
restaurant what about
wow it's
[Music]
15% look great
you
[Music]
[Applause]
this is not going to be good for my
trans well welcome back to the end of
the night guys sitting here with Horatio
and Johnny B Y that was a nice crazy
restaurant experience it was quite fun
Copa Cabana Copa Cabana we had um it was
the Top Model something Miss Canada
Universe Miss Canada universe and then
there was also random things like weird
salsa dancers Brazilian salsa dancers
dud coming up cutting beef oh yeah that
was nonstop all the the the beef uh that
they served holy [ __ ] I a vegetarian so
I didn't eat any but uh John can tell
you about that part hey you what was
pretty good but uh
delicious you know when I got the bill I
was like Wow but then I really thought I
was surrounded by like
50 super marel in a
sense all pretty hot it was it was
pretty good night it was nice to see it
was actually it was really nice to see
all the different races and all all the
differ the whole thing about it was
actually pretty cool it's entertaining
oh yeah yeah it was uh Remo and Sandra
invited us all down for that dinner so
it was quite a bit of Industry people
Simon from Syria seeds was there and
Matt and Sarah from the house of the
great Gardener and the mailman brothers
were there and lumo Canada was there Tim
Timon was there it was a nice group of
people it was fun it was very
interesting you know it's a interesting
as in saying that we walk into this
restaurant and there's people dancing
and it was
fun all right for a night blazing a
little bit of
food so we we figured we'd finish it off
on day three of the Champs which is
really only day two of the Champs but
day three of mine and John's
adventure and uh yeah we figured we'd
end this night with a dab so that was
mine guys I'm I'm right in here got you
here you want me to load you or you got
something I got some 90 all right
beautiful I got some 90 My Little Pony
you see that real like uplifting high
right now ah perfect thing right before
bed real good for bus up to like 3 in
the morning John go to bed so last night
we were up till 2:00 because we were
puffing on My Little Pony it happens I
remember in Amsterdam puffing on Scott's
moonshine Haze that [ __ ] kept me up till
4:00 or 5 in the morning 5 I just got to
town so it's still BC time for me this
is not good not good at all yeah I'm in
the same boats though we're fine it's
8:48 in BC ear yeah
so today was a really great day we had a
great time there was some good education
going on lot of different people that
came into town um looking forward to um
actually you know the the next the next
uh event that we're going to be uh
hosting and see where it's going to
happen yeah it'll be interesting I mean
you know tomorrow's really the start of
Champs today was just businesses to
business so tomorrow will really be the
first kind of day of feeling what how
much public uh um you know will show up
and how much interest is there's going
to be in this particular show and a lot
of glass there was definitely a lot of
glass there you know very interesting
how how all the glasses set up and we
have all different blowers and dude we
have a great Booth we we have probably I
think we're going to win best booth
there is no Best Booth I don't think is
there but if there was you just took
Best Booth yeah we just took it Best
Booth in the sense we're happy to share
dabs with people we're happy to share
information we're happy to share Good
Vibes we're the educational booth and
you can come by and you can learn a lot
and you can buy yourself a met T some
Bubble Bags do a nice bong rip off of
the
Dil VAP you know what yard and if you
can't if you can't come by and make it
we'll be filming it all and showing it
to you here on Bubble man's world so
thanks for watching everyone always