[Music]
can't
no it's
because some uh
[Music]
Hightech
glass CH
glass what's up dude t-shirt do I want a
t-shirt one sure I'll take a t-shirt
from the dinam
crew do you have a XL yeah that's an XL
awesome dude thank you no problem you
want another one good thanks no one's
perfect sure thank you not taking the
back right
on OG Kush Moby Dick
Bob
headquarters there's the house of the
great Gardener those are our
friends that's our
friends Second Nature
Hydroponics
sublimator the sublimator booth with the
seed
vaults how's it going dude job
yeah I do a dab Mele
cheese looks
good let's go hit the
dino right Quebec
Imports yeah it sucks oh this is Ross's
Booth let's check it out I haven't even
been down here
yet hey there's a bubble bag shirt nice
to
[Music]
see
yes I got sad news oh no somebody so
[ __ ] serious as cups out of their
[ __ ] display cabinet are you serious
[ __ ] cannbis
cups we just found out now that someone
has stolen serious seeds is Canabis cups
not even Canabis cups like they won in
like the '90s
[Music]
that's now I'm just getting a bad taste
in my
mouth this is not
cool people are here stealing at night
though I mean at night before that's
that's not like during the show that's
like they showed up this morning and
someone had opened up the case and took
their
[ __ ] I would like to be seen with them
how about a couple happy new customers
right here with my frames from Bubble
Mano loving it
I want to see that product I want to see
what you make we'll have it up for you
all to see you soon have a great day
guys see you again right
on people are nice wow people are
awesome you know people are really good
they they love what we do that guy's
like can I buy those you screens with
your resin on we're being positive yeah
that did that guy just leave with a
clean set of screens John no he left
with this the set of screens that we
used yesterday to make that fresh frozen
so he left with some amazing screens to
him that's life-changing cuz I got medy
kush resin on my screen like to him he's
like that's awesome so that's awesome
for me to know how of he likes super
awesome another guy they going to like
longtime subscriber supporter yeah heard
about my
camera
dude this guy heard about me losing my
camera and literally brought me a camera
and gave it to me today how kind are
people backing it up and saying not all
people are
and I just want to sayi thank you so
much pretty [ __ ] kind of you so now
we're going to look at his nugget he
grew some nice nugget here and what uh
what are the varieties here that we're
looking at uh that one is called THC
bomb THC bomb yeah it was from BC Bud
Depot all right what about this guy here
that's chocolate thae chocolate tie it's
from bog seeds bog yep that's my buddy
yep we also have a a sour bu as well
from him back in the
day
bog is that another bog yeah
bog awesome nice little mixture nice
little selection
on what do we got here and the man John
himself yo John himself dude John John
John listen chocolate tie John got a
chocolate thae duie yesterday
oh my God you know what's great about
this chocolate pie doie how your par
smelling still giving you this still got
it got it he gave me a camera you are so
awesome you know what that's what is
that's what people are about you know
what the good the will always show up
here because you know what that's what
we're about we're about showing and
sharing and loving and you know what
that's great guys and know I got to give
you a watermelon joint yeah watermelon
joint let me hook that up and wo that
might be dangerous we got let's put this
safe yeah definitely put
that whoa we're spilling hash here kind
of a hash travesty was
that not too bad considering these are
dunks and they pick up real easy picks
up awesome hey I'm going to show I'm
going to give this guy this you got to
give him a nugget there you guys go asro
boy you can smell it just like
there you go dude thank you very much oh
thank you I want to hand you a nice big
nugget anybody want to some seeds Dron
food dispenser right herebody want SE
check them out I am I am Dragon 420
they're spicy if you don't mind spicy
hold your hand out cuz these are yummy
anybody want to snack on it oh there you
go dude right on what a character giving
away hem seeds out of the thing right on
awesome dude
your hand for H seeds who likes yeah
I'll have some H seeds thank you dude
give thanks I made that for the dragons
then
but really oh yeah I took the seats on
the on the den did you and yeah did a
little pitch to the dragons we're really
well received you can check it out on
the CBC site book for singing Canary
cool and uh you know all the dragons
actually we had them sing in the jingle
got them eating hemp seeds cracking
jokes about weed
uh Arlene was ripping a little bit on
Kevin she's like oh come on Kevin that's
not the first time you've had cannabis
on your lips and uh all in all this
right here is the dragon's food and I
was telling them I was like it's a
special uh seasoning it's a jerk roast
and as I said it I kind of looked a
little bit over towards Kevin there and
I he gets his back up he's like a jerk
roast eh and I'm like oh [ __ ] why did I
say it like that and then uh I'm like U
Bruce you're half jic aren't you and
he's like well as a matter of fact my
lower half is and uh I got the dig in
right on Kevin and uh he pulled me
through on that one and it was a it was
a good little clip if you get the chance
check it out right that didn't make the
final cut though so heard that Wicked
yeah awesome Che thanks for the seeds
brother I haven't been filming much but
I just got some good news from the great
Gardener third play Seed Company CBD
heom it's coming soon first place
solvent
list
bar grown by the great Gardener clean by
Bubble Man first place Spain first place
Toronto what's up next Amsterdam we're
coming all right to Amsterdam with the
Barb yeah buddy congratulations dude
maybe chili oh like that back to span
you
won this video Horatio is the video that
says [ __ ] chance is over it was pretty
fun sucks that my camera got stolen
bring it back if you're watching this I
would love my camera back I we can hang
out and talk about life and maybe help
you become a happier person so you don't
have to steal from people but uh yeah
thanks for watching guys Mike mailman in
the house Champs is
over see you
[Music]
later you know going to the dinner the
Coalition dinner oh I don't know
anything about it what the Buras one
[Music]
yeah or the Kit Kat Club I don't know
they're all over different places really
good thank you
[Music]
hey are you taking a hit of the
awardwinning Barbara Bud dry sift of
course I am all right
then but it's just vaporization
right
vaporizing in the hotel man just VAP
important that what mumbler you always
know this is just Vape okay he
disappears all right
[Music]
black saw from across the room what was
hey you never saw
[Music]
this so the only I
don't yeah I grow um giant Chilla rabbit
you can
take you can take
it what happen John got to we got a fine
yeah what we get a fine for apparently
apparently we were puffing in the room
so they find us we're puffing in the
room what did we get find 300
bucks but iiz my medicine so it really
doesn't understand what it says smoking
here and after after actually talking
with my lawyer which is a friend of ours
um which is a great thing he's advised
us that we're not really breaking any
rights depending on how the policies are
but it does not say no
vaporizing smoking plus I already lost
my camera so we can't be paying any
silly fines like this so why don't we go
eat dinner with these guys and get over
there that Haze in the background
actually is just paper all right let's
go
peace [ __ ] City
eh here we go
go
still [ __ ] on construction from last
year that annoying here we are John it's
late at night we're walking we've had
our our
dinner and I think we're going to head
back to the hotel just in front of the
CN tower there and go uh I wish
hey look this guy's [ __ ] around with
the
lion all right this is our party join
our party this is our party FL party man
flash yeah
Flash oh know what time night it
is I'm going to stick with my alcohol
look at those dudes it's the end of
another great night here in
Toronto have a good one