[Music]
guys bubble man and John here we just
got to the convention we're setting up
our booth we've got green planets right
beside us medtainer and bubble bags are
in one large long booth and everyone's
just chaotically putting [ __ ] together
right now I'll give you a little a
little pan on that yeah that's not us
hey John no people are building
three-dimensional frames and [ __ ] boxes
everywhere John and I are a little more
lowkey
uh so I going to go grab my it and get
it over here and uh yeah we'll go we've
got the med pains we'll see you guys
here in a bit once we get the booth
built up we
go John and I are getting a little
closer to making our boots look good man
I think it's kind of coming along dude
big thanks to the weed guy Mark cloi who
did up these posters for us of our the
photographs of of medy kush buds and
skunkman Sam's dry sift and Remo's uh uh
UBC chemo we've got um pictures of the
zombie cush from Ripper seed at the
front of the booth we kind of we're
doing it up here I think we totally
hooked it up so I'm just actually now
finishing up one of the last things we
do here basically putting my bags on
display John's got the medtainers he's
starting we're mixing those all
throughout it's buildup day there's no
business being done today everyone's
just building all their [ __ ] and uh
we're no different we're I think we're
going to go get that dmail though soon
bring it back down here though it's
going to be an exciting day today you
setting up me few people but tomorrow
industry and you guys will be here
Saturday Sunday
yeah we're looking forward to seeing
everyone definitely come by the booth
and say hi to us we want to see you we
want to show you the hash we want to
show you the techniques we've got all
the screens on point here for dry
sifting both sides we've got the large
ones here we've got the bubble bags and
the medtainers basically you need to get
your herb broken up washed cleaned dry
sifted where the ones we've got you
covered we got you covered so we'll see
you guys in a little bit John and I are
going to finish up here and smoke and go
we got a Medicare he wait wait I got I
got
one the part is we able to just sit here
beautiful going try my that one was very
light yeah M was too well you know what
because hit this thing that's what we do
we SM them all the time it's not like
we're going to leave them just sitting
there packed that's like leaving a bong
pack it just doesn't happen know how I
just reached over right there and
grabbed it cuz I was sitting there
relaxing I always keep it
to another shout out for Mark POI with
the cush cup that'll be coming up again
pretty soon yeah we've got his party is
going to be at Vaper Paper
Central on Satur Saturday Saturday night
yeah Saturday night so try and get a
ticket for that if you have it
already now the half all the elements
hit like trickly always does like a
bomber
awesome get in there I put mine down but
I didn't pack it down here we go now
this is the key with the tripy stick a
lot of people say they don't work they
work when you work and when you need it
to work believe me you can get this
thing to work
trippy salute all right Alibaba Luke
from Paradise and Jay from Twister John
B in the house these are our first
friends that have showed up in Canada so
far welcome Paradise seeds twister meder
Wicked hey if it don't bubble we're
toble yeah all right guys welcome back
[ __ ] getting this booth done up mat
the great G's in the house Remo's in the
house Med man's in the house actually
we're going to we're taking a quick
picture here
from
the
there Lucifer the bringer of the
light oh Johnny's in there
now holy [ __ ] I don't know much camera
left crazy
nice that's going to be brief
Interruption there right thanks guys
how's it going bud here you got a hug
for me man what's up how you do
great do great thanks so much do you
need
one
okay there's 10 in total holy [ __ ] yeah
so uh yeah man well I'm a
ker way to get her done oh yeah okay
we're going we're going out to puff some
concussion so we'll be back for another
vid guys and uh you can anyone that
wants to Jo us anyone that wants to join
us all right we got a little
bring it over bring it
over see you got to show the people that
stuff problem okay then I got to see it
next is it going to tune in there or you
going to you oh there it is there it is
there it is focus it is very good
quality it's Absolut awesome quality
it's the Astro Boy from TJ genetics
through it myself with the inspiration
of guys
like you know what I'm going to need me
and
I got to go first
first I've on a diet
from awesome is awesome
a
[Applause]
hits sad to hear went under not under
G of rushy oh that was
wicked oh yeah get right in there man
dude it's not every day that Remo just
is your
cameraman that's
awesome I let that little bit bubble on
the outside John oh Johnny's in
there Champs vaporizing at let the TR
show cough begin we don't burn that herb
we Vape it while we're at Champs
otherwise we'd be outside which is fine
we can go outside if we want to smoke
joints big Smoky fumy bowls holy awesome
hit John well we could do that we can
roll a joint and go exide that would be
acceptable right we got to go set up our
boo that would be acceptable it would be
all right well thanks for stopping by
for H tot awesome see bit we're 519
right across from Ross's gold right
across from serious seeds come and check
us out we have dry sift that we've
managed to keep in a Sandy form yes
that's hard traveling across the country
it's hard every everybody's house like
go do I'm like can I borrow your freezer
can I borrow your freezer making room in
people's freezers putting it in we have
a fridge in our room and I've got my
little bit in there as well and I've
kept it in powder as well we going try
I'm going to pull out a piece sort of
like a little piece and then the next
day or maybe even half the the day I'm
going to pull out another piece so then
so then by by Sunday you'll see the
difference between sort of greasy and
how
it it'll be amazing it presses in a
quarter of a second I did it yesterday I
had a piece that was white fluffy powder
and I just went like this and opened my
fingers and it was pressed goopy like
tooe fing got a big steel pipe got all
kinds of uh of uh fresh frozen that
we're going to like press out into
pieces of ass like right in front of you
we'll press it out so come check them
out come check us out at our booth here
at 506 and 407 you'll see Remo walking
around you don't have a booth do you
Remo no uh green planet's launching my
product they're right next to us right
here I'll be hang with those guys you
can find all of us very nearby walk
around we'll hope to see you all here at
the champ smoke awesome yeah all right
have a great time everybody see you
around let's get Mr Remo in there yeah
guess camera person thanks for being
here buddy thanks for having me let's
roll a joint now mention mention that
one more time cannabis doesn't kill uh
brain cell actually what if you're
having a stroke I just leer this
recently smoke a joint cuz what it does
is uh the Cannabis helps protect your
brain cells actually puts a protective
coating around it so you lessen the
brain damage so there's there's a tip
there it is right on you heard it here
first from Remo I never knew that
actually strok Dr Allen over recently
yeah that guy great so I learned all
about Strokes like crap course though
excellent what do you think of the Giant
tricomes and and did you see your res
growing on the back there on the back
wall those tricomes yeah you grew those
tricomes I recognize those it's got that
purple Keo Kush right there nice dude
that's sweet hopefully we'll get a big
shot of you under that oh here I got
something to show you of course you
do oh there it is it's got that purple
to it very nice that's by entry oh
excellent you did entry rockar yeah
rocking brought some purple but and
that's nice we should crush that over
some screens let's crush the whole thing
over screens what do you say mine
screens oh I don't want to do
[Laughter]
that so we're just going to crush all
your
bud right here we got them all right
here boy if you want we have some water
and some ice we can definitely take care
of thatwhere are you dabbing up John did
you get a dab of that it's in the green
uh some of my uh I believe it's the
Astro Boy could be some medic
cush but I think it's AST boy I think
it's do you mind if I shoot a video at
the same time please no I'm going to
turn my camera off right away and for
those of you that want to watch the
continuation of this particular video
you can see it on the urban rainbow
channel on the urban raino channel right
on
thanks see you guys later
[Music]
we still s
how's it going Johnny
B H a nice Bowl yeah
excellent a long day look at this looks
[ __ ] great bro I think we uh talk
loud I think we've done a great job here
look at this
you Canada Bubble
Bags support a little bit of
everything got to support the
BET
absolutely so part of what we're both
here about throwing medicine producing
great medicine looks great John where
the where the medicine I love you with
the Tricom background I love that triome
background because that's truly what
we're looking at truly what we want
that's what we want isn't it and you
know what that's what you're having
that's what we're having right here
fresh frozen all right 90
beautiful it's been a good day so far
it's been a great day it's nice that
we're able
toize paperized only
[Applause]
here we got here about 5 ago was
actually a long day it has been a long
day slow but steady and uh now looking
at being H things are happening here at
the uh Champs treating yourself cup expo
here in
Toronto come check it out tomorrow for
businesses if you're interested in
wholesale and come check it out on
Saturday and Sunday for just a walk
through if you're just the general
public see you soon hey guys just got
here with John we are are on the eighth
floor of the Intercontinental Hotel and
they have like a nice little sort of uh
styly styly little spread here don't
they see if I can change that light a
little bit and just
go so what are these little guys oh AI
tuna are you kidding no oh my goodness I
didn't even notice that some fresh fruit
plate here got some hummus down there a
little bit of we got some um o look at
the there we go this is more true to the
color so we got these AI
Tunas some nice fruit plate little
tomato stuffed looks like oine almost
like an eggplant with
veggies cheese got a nice cheese plate
this is my favorite lemonade and
cucumber
water and then uh come back around this
side what we got some
osas ooh and little sort of burritos
burritos killer and all these sauces
these are sauces um awesome well I don't
know about you John but I haven't eaten
breakfast or anything all day I was here
for breakfast why why don't we set up
our little camera in the cor and we'll
have a seat right over in the corner
there let's um welcome back to Bubble
man's world guys oh we're here on the
eighth floor at the Intercontinental
Hotel and um we showed you the little
spread that they have put out this goes
out throughout the whole day I guess
it's a Preferred Guest thing got some
beautiful selections of the ATI tuna
with the stucked tomatoes and the humus
and veggies mini samosas both with
Tamarind sauce and with Chutney I'm
ready to dip in what about you bu oh I'm
so dude haven't eaten all day so stoked
on these mini
samosas yeah
M I got to say Toronto is treating us
pretty good on this trip so
far most excellent
I guess John and I are going to finish
up our little snack here maybe hit the
Trippy Stick a couple of
times and we got to head over to the uh
Coalition the mm Coalition for rep
against repeal see that in a bit they're
having a fundraiser tonight at VAP on
the lake so we're going to head down
there after this go upstairs get the Dil
and and head on down so see you when we
get down
there uh John and I are back we got the
wind taken out of our sales a little bit
we were on our way to our dinner or not
our dinner sorry but the uh fundraiser
for the mm Coalition against foral
appeal and uh we got on the cab the cab
driver didn't know where it was there
was like literally I remember looking at
his GPS when it said he was showing um
Lakeshore boulevards in New York City
500 miles away I know the 91 km 91 km
was the closest one that he got which is
wrong we're like 23 kilomet away right
now or 23 miles away sorry
anyway we drove around for a bit dropped
got him to drop us off cuz it was insane
and uh now we're back at our hotel and
John let me load you up a bowl dude yeah
I need seriously fresh frozen fresh
frozen M down here like I always am
wherever you
like so it was a long day setting up
took us s hours to set our booth up and
see all our friends and kind of get a
bunch of videos for you guys to watch
and
um yeah I guess right now John and I
just going to have a quick little rip
each we're going to head down across the
street to Jack asers go grab ourselves a
bite to eat and then just yeah we
haven't even eaten that was the other
thing we thought all day I thought that
this thing was a a dinner and so we
never ate and then we realized at about
7:00 as we were going to head down there
uh or I guess 7:00 uh yeah 8 minutes
after 8 here Toronto 8 minutes after 8
right I've got all these wrong times so
what because you're looking at computer
and your computer says Vancouver time
and we're my phone says Toronto time oh
nice so that little hit after running
around not being able to actually hit a
dil and do actually a true rip cuz we
were just trying to get there just
changed everything I just woke up I just
like oh my God I just so needed that
it's truly what medicine's about I'm
pretty sure you just witnessed that I
was bagged after that hit I just like
you were laying on the bed 10 minutes
ago I didn't think you I was done I I
was like that cab driver just everything
today those banners putting up all those
Wicked signs it was a great day you know
the only thing that was a bit of a
bummer and you know what sometimes I
follow this in my life sometimes when
there's events that occur that don't
that that that are telling me maybe it's
not right maybe it's not working out
maybe I've learned as I get older to not
force those things now it is a real
bummer that we don't get to be there for
the Coalition but it's not going to stop
us from supporting it it's not going to
stop us from asking for you guys to from
support from you guys and and we're
still going to keep on fighting the good
fight here in Canada so I don't know
what do you say we go grab a bite and
then we'll do maybe a little city uh
we'll do some rips around outside in
downtown Toronto we're going to walk
across the street we're going to eat
we're going to walk AC back across the
street do a rip and then walk into the
hotel so
that that's just around Toronto does
does that qualify it's awesome okay
great that's what we're going to do then
so we'll see you guys in a little
bit peace
all right here we are indeed without the
tripod this is a unique way maybe we
should film in front of the mirror all
the time like like e here them we just
like hi we're going down fast that was
like 12 floors we're heading up to Jack
Asters if you guys want to join us come
join us see this L
tomorrow sry
John this restaurant's pumping eh it
always is that's where I always want to
be
aier beautiful good food we go check it
out outside anyway just want to get the
fresh air of walking half a block
[Applause]
in the city hey yeah thir thing you
really got to point the camera straight
up to catch the skyscrapers in this city
we should have crossed that's what we
should have done look at these two
characters oh right on let's
see we're here with local BC head shop
owners ignite Brandon and
ran how's it going sh what a trip where
you guys going right now we're just
going in the we're up there at 1540
let's dab tonight in our
room mother Shri ins solvent
[Music]
list 1
hour what number are they what number
are you
guys 13
what1 awesome got I don't know what she
said 1301 131 1301 those are our friends
from Vancouver this is the kind of life
that we
live like we're coming up the we're
coming oh good folks from Vancouver
those are our friends they used to run
the cchq Mark emer's store they ran it
for many a years and they did a [ __ ]
great job now they got their own shop
called ignite I think they have a couple
of them in Vancouver no just one just
the one maybe they're maybe they're
looking at opening another one either
way they do great business they're good
[ __ ] people and I'm looking forward
to dabbing with them later looks like
the party's on John it is on and there
we are right across the street at Jack
aers
[Applause]
[Music]
no want allow
to you get angry you get mad rest of the
all right so here we are at Jack
asers what's that oh that's our got
dabbing Park we'll be dabbing over there
after our meal potentially although
there's a good one right over here
too just up here in around the corner
there's a good little Park air
setting all right so we can do an
outside inside thing whatever you like
how's it going how are you hey guys we
just got to Jack asers back the
restaurant nice
place jack
[Music]
loud then we came in here a lot quieter
probably pretty
loud
talking we're going to order some good
food and then do some dabs in this
restaurant here
yeah get back
to the menu and definitely get some
[Applause]
dab all right guys we are in the streets
of Vancouver you can kind of see the CN
Tower in the background that would be
Toronto so that's where the best part of
about live camera work live camera work
exactly so we were in the restaurant we
were going to do a dab in the restaurant
but the lady that worked there honed in
on us pretty quick without pulling even
out the rig or the torch and just was
like I had my ball of bubble and she's
like what is that and I'm like this here
this is just my [ __ ] I'm putting it away
and she's like oh well what what is it
and I'm like it's bubble has are you
familiar and then she said uh oh not in
my restaurant you know I don't want that
stuff in my restaurant and then I had to
explain to her that it would be like
seeing like um any medication from any
person that was using any type of
medication pills or whatever it's just
like that I explained to her that I just
had it out for a brief minute it was
going back it didn't stink up for
restaurant and that uh yeah that we
should be allowed to have our medicine
where wherever we go so we're out in
front of her restaurant it's just across
the street right now yeah we figured you
know what what better place to do this
but right here right within her view
let's hope she's
watching all right so why don't you hold
that up I really believe that she was
actually hold it up for me she watched
bubble M's world she honed in right away
because she's actually watched us puff I
would be surprised she's a secret puffer
it was amazing that she knew it was
unbelievable that she knew crazy it was
kind of crazy like how did she know we
didn't pull out the dab I had the pipo
it was Bes me she know how did she know
I had that hidden camera like what are
you guys doing so you know what here we
are the streets of Toronto shout out to
flab 421 for this awesome gift of a pipe
FR for you dunks
great great work did you see that that's
what you call skill while dunking a dab
of bubble
has in Toronto while after eating you
need to
medicate well well demonst 10 nail these
tiny little [ __ ] Nails 8 mil nail 8
mil tell I'll tell you what you thought
that with 10 mil I will are you going to
dunk me dky donky Vil as they say in
Holland okay you want me to turn it on
cuz you got you need two hands to turn
this torch on there you
go we got the wind down right now so I'm
toring it out that was a great H I think
I think she's drooling in the window
over there right now yeah hi we're
smoking hash right here so we're about
to go hang out with Brandon and ran and
after this dab we're going to head up to
our room and have a little dab session
with the ignite head shop owners our
friends awesome best places always go
there they're great people but to see
them walking across the street as we're
going to have dinner that was awesome it
was like hey he yeah hell yeah that's
not how you turn it off would you like
me to do it for it yeah okay this is how
you turn the Tor off boom right on the
back it's a trick one put your Dome
on and we'll dunk you
valy if you like a little bit of a a
carv nice little pipe nice little pipe
in
indeed
well puff and tough in
Toronto we'll catch you later
it's going changes colors
for
[Music]
all right look who stopped by how's it
going everybody what that we thought the
night was over 1216 we were supposed to
bump into Brandon and ran and we saw
them on the on the road outside on our
way to Jack aers which we thought we
would do dabs inside the restaurant but
I think the lady that the restaurant
honed in on us or maybe she watched
bubble man's world I don't know but she
was definitely she was definitely she
was like what is that what is that and I
said oh it's bubble has are you familiar
she's like oh I don't want it in my
restaurant and I said oh no no no just
imagine I'm a diabetic and this is
insulin like this is my medicine and I'm
not using it in your restaurant I'm just
actually putting it away and it's not
stinking the restaurant up so oh oh oh
she says all right but I like to be able
to tell people a different perspective
yeah we were just on the patio out of
the Dr shot down vaporizing no one said
anything oh ex she they looked I saw her
looking at it we were inside the
restaurant with a blowtorch and a little
pipe I got my little pipe like
this
really
hilarious this is what we have this is
sitting on the table this is sitting on
the table I got my pipo it's beside me
it's funny the torch is sitting down I
got one of these this is one of these
little B he got one of these balls with
hat right here and he's got SP on the
table she's like I think I actually
replied it's my [ __ ] I'm putting it away
yeah and she goes what is that and I
said are you familiar with bubble hash I
can't have that in here well we can't
have that in my restaurant and I'm like
oh I absolutely can 100% I just smoking
in your restaurant we went outside and
smoked we met an incredibly kind
security guard named Cohen who stopped
and chatted with us for maybe 10 or 15
minutes and like he was cool sent us to
the place to buy water sent us up the
street to Neil's the guy that runs the
corner store right around the corner
from Jack aers and he was super cool too
he's going to be watching your guys'
videos trust me he's watching Bubble
man's world right now so when you go
there when you go to the store which is
right you walk right to Jack aers and
you turn left okay perfect right go
right to the end it's not very far
you'll see his store it's just towards
the end it's a little tiny corner store
on the left and his name is Neil so
definitely say hi to him yeah super nice
guys I like meeting people walking
around in downtown V uh Toronto since
we've landed we randomly bump into
people and we're like yeah well we smoke
cash airplane everybody we were on the
airplane and and this he used to going
to the bathroom this lady stand beside
me and all of a sudden I start talking
about cannabis the anal cannaboid system
and she's coming back now she's like
I've now I've now baited her I've
wheeled her and Mark's down and he's
like oh yeah well we do a Sol s St go oh
my son smokes butter yeah yeah she was
bummed not that he was smoking cannabis
cuz she said I don't mind about the
Cannabis it just seems she wasn't really
into the butter thing and she didn't
know exactly why she just thought it
wasn't good and and we were like
confirmation Mom it isn't good you don't
like it because it's dangerous it's
chemical exposure it's potentially some
bad things that are inh you know so it
was cool we turned her on John gave her
her his card and I gave her my card and
hopefully uh she'll be turning her son
on to uh yeah please the best part was
is when we got off the plane for a
luggage she came over to us brought her
husband over so this show will be
getting uploaded tonight the one we're
filming right now Saturday yeah maybe
Saturday oh Saturday right tomorrow's
the um business to business business to
business wholesale so if you're in a
business come by we'll still be there
and on Saturday for us we're going to
pick a time when we're going to crush
that weed over the screen yeah we've got
some really nice jars of weed John has
around the corner here that we showed
you already the uh the watermelon Astro
Boy we're going to be crushing that up
over start at 1:00 making some dry SI on
Saturday fre 1:00
420 but but we're going to start at 1:00
okay we'll finish at 4:20 we're going to
finish at
4:20 and because it's going to take a
little bit we got two B wirers we're
going to you know slowly work it with
the scre card it up nicely we'll spend
some time between 1 and 420 and at 420
we'll be hitting dabs with full melt
watermelon
I to bring the steel bar over I got a
piece a little piece of 2x4 a steel bar
and we can heat the heat the steel bar
up although you don't need to heat the
steel Barb bar up for Barb but for the
uh water hases and stuff we can heat the
steel bar up and then put it in in that
parchment paper and we can make some
super thin cuz we'll have the cooler
with ice you know what I have I have oil
slick parchment paper but we can even
use have you seen the raw parment paper
yet yeah I did yeah we can even use
these as as
well on top of each other yeah these are
like uh they you can cook cookies and
stuff they oven and stuff you just you
can press hash in these really nice
literally just roll over it
boom we have those like one on top of
each other yeah exactly I'll put one on
top of the other coming over they come
to that'll be a great video I got we're
doing it you heard it here first for
sure that's what we're doing all right
here we go do a medley a medley h
there's nothing like a medley like one
of those caramel those coffee bars you
got with a different col are you sitting
over there not getting any of
this jump in at some
point of
course I was going to go over to uh The
Vape on the lake but I heard that The
Gardener's down to like one lane and
traffic is next few days it is going to
be busy it's going to be a nice busy get
me
I love that we're all kind of close
together well you know what um with the
next one we'll plan it and we'll we all
be like like this one two
only was like we went
for good night everybody hey thanks for
watching guys as always we'll see you
tomorrow at Champs business to business
if not we'll see you on Saturday head on
peace cheers GG