[Music]
good morning everyone welcome to Bubble
man's world it is almost 420 in the
morning yeah early flight today with
Johnny B uh we're getting to it we're
going to do the Champs show this is
Wednesday uh
21st and we're starting the Champs on
Friday I believe on the 23rd so we're
going to be there with a couple of days
to spare hopefully we'll bump into some
of the good people um I have of
course been
consuming my coconut
butter God it just reeks like Barb too
such a nice little way to get the
day started
a little bit of
the coconut butter just the tiniest
little bit will give me a real nice Vibe
I'm going to bring it on the plane
so I will have it with me and I guess
really I just wanted to share with you
guys a little bowl this morning just a
little
bowl got my bubble pressed out here drop
that in there little the OG cush and
then tiny little bit of the
Barb
99% she melts right in your hands that
one let me tell you just have the
tiniest little bit out on the card and
it is
melty all
right we got our
beine going to go join John at the
airport for a nice quick flight about
five five hours or so to
Toronto got myself a Game of Thrones I'm
going to watch going to get blasted off
the coconut oil we'll have a big Vape
session out in front of the airport when
we get there and uh yeah we'll start the
day with a wakeen baker 419 I guess I
better Yap for one more
minute maybe we better call John
actually let's see what John's doing for
420 let's see if we can get in touch
with JN in
time all right here we go let's see what
Johnny B is
saying Johnny
B all right we're almost at
420 let's give John the one minute
warning happy well good morning John one
minute warning is over and it is 4:20 it
is
420 oh you're doing a bong RI I'm
driving you give me a bomb right
now wow you're already on the road
B yeah I just left the house had to go
get gas I'm leaving like
Al 3 minutes after I gra my te awesome
to drive it home well I got you on
camera say happy 420 to all the
listeners and the Watchers and we're
going to see you at the airport in about
45 minutes happy 420 on a pup Wednesday
yeah Johnny we'll see you soon brother
see you soon brother
peace that's John 4 in the morning and
the guy's in a bloody good mood always
in a good mood that's what we love about
John B that's why we like watching him
we enjoy hearing his stories and seeing
what he's up to cuz the guy is just a
great guy anyway Swiss perk
rips coconut oil dips and it looks like
we're off so we'll see you there
peace
t
fil Johnny B waa and his neighbors they
drove me in how's it going bro I you
know what dude are we going to Toronto
we're going to go to look at this I got
my bong bag I got my trip dude it's good
to see you that's awesome dude I'm so
happy today we're having a good day so
you're you're [ __ ] you got more [ __ ]
than you need 10 suitcases well one's
full of maters then I have this one then
I have this one full of weed weed I have
to carry fresh the whole thing is is
we're going to be making dry SI War at
Toronto so I have the Astro Boy and I
have the watermelon and we're going to
crush it over screens dude let's uh
let's do that for sure we're like let's
uh let's check these bags in and then go
have a sash I think we're going to do
that okay right on right on we go
in support the now hey there's a
medtainer on the ground there
wow how did that get there
but whose is
it show me that did we really just find
that I just found that on the ground on
the ground like someone just ditched all
their joints right before well let's
take those with us we'll keep those
joints we'll keep those joints that's
awesome you just found well I just found
and then pointed it out to you that
medtainer container was on the ground at
the entrance to the airport and I'll
open it up one more time just because
it's hilarious
holy smokes it smells dank too I know
medtainer John picks up the medtainer
this is not listen these are one joints
tooe they're not even listen we are not
making this up we just walked in that
container was on the Ground full of
joints this is uh this is the day we
start 1 2 3 4 5 and and a half roach
let's go check
in that's just
awesome now there's a guy that found
five big fat joints on the way into the
airport today now that is a happy
guy happy guy Johnny
B
okay Johnny
B hey
[Music]
John all right it's nice and Loud out
here at the van for
airport you never know it's like 5:30 6
in the morning right
now
[Music]
he is
PU what we but that's okay the guy who
lost his medtainer on the way into the
airport he was puffing while we were
[Music]
puffing
John was wondering if the guy's on an
international flight anyway this is our
big huge giant airport session we're
going to continue on PO some trippy
sticks eat some coconut oil and head on
in we've already checked in so it's just
a matter of going for security which is
pretty chill here in Canada then jumping
on our flight all right Toronto here we
come see you a b so that was a cust not
Customs but Security checks it was good
John's titanium set off the uh alarm and
he had to take away off basically all of
his clothes it's okay not really I just
had to take my belt off guy in front of
me had to take his shoes off but I put
my Trippy Stick right in the thing and
uh I got my bong yeah me too I ran mine
through the machine got to love being
Canadian it's a nice thing jump on that
plane c-51 c51
c51 yeah so we were filming at security
and we were told you can't film at
security so we're not filming at
security anymore we're not allowed to
film in security but we're allowed to
bring our weed through hey you can bring
your weed in your hash oh we're going to
have to get off here I guess it's
breakfast time done breakfast time we
got some uh egg cheese Quant
things not bad at
all we got 15 minutes to wait for our
flight so we'll be trippy
sticking and eating
see you guys in a bit all
right Dil here we go got
B Johnny
B all
right
hello good
morning goodness here we go this is us
right at one
that's okay
[Music]
toar
there you
[Music]
go
short back Island
time there you go now
[Music]
that's
yeah
oh
yeah oh
yeah try and do good try and do good try
and do good and follow
you try and do good try and do good and
will follow you see I
sh Stay Focus that's what weire show
love to your brothers and
sister evil my evil live up show up my
people
Heavenly Deliver Us from the
wicked lightning R to and
[Music]
Fire Can't
show love people respect you
remember
one try do good try and good try good
good Follow You
seey
tryy Follow
see sh
[Music]
[Applause]
oh Do It
Feel Love is what we want yeah come on
my people let's launch yeah now is the
time to go yeah negative life let go
yeah tell them black
Mar love
is and
know
oh
oh oh my my my my yeah my people try and
do good try and do good try and do good
and good will follow you see
Ro so uh John and I just realized we're
sitting in some preferred seat here up
in the front row and uh offered
everything they just offer sandwich
coffee sandwich coffee drink wrinkles
cookies whatever this is pretty sweet
yeah this is some good airplan service
definitely worth a 45 there's our
awesome steart us right there yeah
taking care of
us let
J good try and do good try and do good
and will follow
[Music]
you yeah yeah yeah oh
yeah
[Music]
M bring sucess not live do like the rest
working SC to reward know that I'm young
and I'm going to keep on running
on Ain giving up no
way way
[Music]
yeah you you work
to
there now there is
not you you work to
the I know where I'm coming come and I
know where I'm
going some try for
this
some want to see
us the
mountain we can't you do anything then
with no de with no
is you you
I'm young I'm T I got to keep on working
up Ain giving up no CU I GL away there
there is not you
know continue continue work to the
to there is no there is no there is no
giving up my continue continue working
to
the I know where I'm from and I know
where I'm
going some try to
discourage don't me
[Music]
knowledge here what just happened there
a little bit of cannabis education to a
a concerned mom and father who were on
the plane and as they were waiting for
the bathroom I started talking about the
endoc canabo system and she's mentioning
how her son is on butter and well here
we are picking up our bags and she wants
to know more about how and what we're
doing with bubble hash and proper
natural extractions knowing that her son
is going to use cannabis for a
medication she wanted to find out
cleaner ways and methods well she's
worried about him she's worried that
that that he's inhaling something that's
not safe and she's worried that
potentially GES and stuff like that
potentially the kids that are making it
could could blow up so I mean it's was
really nice to be able to get that
education soon as we land here in
Toronto it's a good sign yeah man well
welcome to Toronto dude welcome to
torono here we are
welcome to Bubble man's world dude
you're in Toronto we made it safe and
sound and uh none of none of this Trippy
Stick [ __ ] you got the treating
yourself bomb out first place John's
first place winner for medy cush Med
cush 201 11 well we're going to hit some
many but fresh roll them now dude let me
load you have a bowl oh it's already on
C let's give you this
one and of course I just bought a
lighter from our good friend here oh
yeah
M came that way he's like here's a
lighter these guys were all having
cigarettes when we rolled up and we were
like we're here to smoke but not
cigarettes we need to smoke to we do
need to smoke what we're doing we're uh
smoking hash at the Toronto Pearson
National
Airport great oh look at that just melt
melts into a liquid
beautiful yeah so we literally just
landed 2 minutes ago where the cabs are
right behind us we're going to head over
to the hotel here in a bit but uh before
that we thought
beautiful thing to take a bong rip at
the airport fresh frozen fresh frozen
cheers buddy what you going to do at the
be line always nice to be here in
Toronto back again of course this will
be the fifth anual treating yourself uh
Cup and the first ever champed Canada
show so really looking forward to being
here um of course spending it with you
guys and showing you what we love to do
best and uh what this community is about
hell yeah right going to be fabulous
week I tell you that it's going to be
good keep watching Bubble man's world
and we'll see you a little bit later
peace guys shirts are pretty famous all
over Boston we're actually going to
build um Benway park with them and tell
us about that shirt a little bit um well
dork strong for Boston Strong we uh in
memory of both the um the Boston
Marathon victims right and the two
following firefighters Michael Kennedy
and the T Walsh that died in uh L and
fire in Boston rip guys both gentlemen
love to smoke these uh mustaches CU be
mustache ask you a question and I'm
going to do this in honor of them this
is in honor of them beautiful and on our
puff Wednesday on PFF Wednesday a per
person to Puff on a Wednesday with us
I'm
M fresh frozen want to light me up sir
and I'll light me up before I go here I
go
guys just hitting the fresh frozen
killer that we it's a hat I'll do a come
on over it's puff Wednesday I'll do a h
that dude awesome we're having a puff W
but he comes over he's like is that weed
puff Wednesday just give it a p this is
the best puff Wednesday ever dude guys
you made my day oh you want some more he
says he's like he goes we going to PO of
course well you got to give him a little
puff I was
like we're Hing everybody
this is funny very tasty stuff you can
see this on Bubble Man's World on
YouTube yes
oh can you take a picture of me while I
take a of course yeah professional I
hope I hope I don't get Stu you're not
going to get
stopped
ready
Rock
here
little
SM I blow it out at the
camera don't hold that in whatever you
do that's about 60% THC oh that's his
out of here
now
awesome well we had a good time we
definitely did thanks for the puff
Wednesday guys for me one more time
Wednesday
can move the
mountain with confidence you do
anything
with is not keeping
go continue continue work to
the No No there ising up
my no
[Music]
noing
all right rolling
up
there they've been expecting us
John I see someone holding on a sign
bubble man and
John John B
and that's our hotel up there I think
we'll be going up to one of those
windows soon and having a
chuff we did get the Executive Suite so
we should be with the top 20 20 to 26
all right cash we made
it we've made it to our hotel here going
to head on up there somewhere and get
puffing Budd all right man so we are
check in time or what back again all
right yeah it's been one year since John
and I have been here and uh well I think
we're going to Puff it down harder this
time than we did last year so we'll see
what
happens hello good afternoon how are you
today not too bad good afternoon check
in for Bell John check in for
[Music]
bell all
right what's up Johnny hi you know not
too shabby eh it's always nice nice
little view of the shitty I'm not a huge
shitty fan myself but if you're going to
be in this shitty you might as well have
a view of it I guess and all the little
Ants
Marching man that's
scary you can just videotape these
people good thing this isn't a
dop all
right uh denail session John right now
all right that's what we need the desk
for how's that oh it's so nice so John
was a bit choked when we got to our room
he wasn't feeling it beds are a little
closed for a couple of dudes what are we
Fred and Wilma yeah we have computers I
need a coach I need hardwood floors all
right so we're going we're changing our
room we're moving all right well we puff
this onep into this guy nature sure you
got your passes we just got them oh yeah
for the
party so the weed guy just uh we just
blazed down they filmed it for their
Channel check it out on his YouTube
channel our little hangout here which is
at uh I'm so baked unbelievable Mark
cloaked full melt to the Dome the weed
guy all right morning take it easy
guys all right Johnny Johnny and Avery
in the house on puff Wednesdays we're
still doing this puff Wednesday thing
it's a great day Wednesday at 4:20 a.m.
in Vancouver yeah GL we did and now
we're puffling here with some I phoned
him for 4:20 this morning I was like hey
John it's 4:20 blah blah blah blah blah
I'm taking a hit and we met at the
airport about an hour later we found
five joints and a medtainer on the way
in you guys just flew in today yep oh
wow just today so this is for hardcore D
hter who just got some Beau nice fresh
frozen nice with the fresh frozen this
is her first time smoking solventless is
that correct yeah right everything
before this was like shatter BHO stuff
so wow on a hit that you just did un
shatter you'd probably be coughing oh
yeah like I would be cough long so how
was
that so where you
just it is a little
che3 I could imagine what it's like
overlooking the ocean but really
anywhere in was like two
grand a puff Wednesday going on here
Johnny Blaze puff Wednesday with Johnny
B and he's getting My Little Pony
because I think we talked about
this I hit him pretty
hard but it's like an initial cop it's
not like that followup like I can't
control cough was a little bit that t
see this one that uncontrollable thing
seems to be a little bit of a chemical
issue where all of a sudden you've done
some crazy concentration you're
like oh I've coughed thrown up many
times from D well let's get you on the
Sal off of
that we were just talking to some
parents some concerned parents for their
son their son was probably 18 or 19 or
20 and and somehow we started talk John
started talking to her first and then we
ended up talking were about cannabis and
concentrates and you know not solvent
free basically you know not the extracts
that are using and not just safe to make
safe safer to smoke exactly safer
overall and I just said from a parental
point of view you'll just appreciate it
he'll still be able to use his Rigs and
imagine your mom turns you out like I'm
at this Sky bubble man and John be at
the airport they gave me that card he'll
be like what we we really thought we
should have invited her on this and did
a little interview with her and been
like hey you know whatever his name is
we're talking to you right now we met
your mom at the airport dude get on the
solvent list kick what are you doing
hitting the shatters all day long your
mom's worried you're with her 20 minutes
and she's almost ready to try something
yeah literally we went out and had a big
bong rip out in front of the air airport
that was great were you guys were
already flying with your glass I assume
yeah we pulled it out in the airport
walked out front that one right there
and had a huge session and like people
off the street were like is that weed
and we're like it'sh he like can I hit
that and some other girls like I won't
it was unbelievable actually how do you
guys like Toronto Airport as opposed to
your airport CU I fly out of Toronto all
the time and they you know they just
seem like a little bit more you know
well they're they're so big the
airport's so big they see so much so I
can't imagine that a rig is really on
their radar all right one more dab I'm
getting out of the
way hit a big one babe oh going fill
this one
up
hey this has been a great puff Wednesday
we met some pretty cool
people had some great Puffs eaten some
good food bumped into some familiar
faces a little and it's just the first
day John I know so thanks for watching
Bubble man's
world and have a puffy
[Music]
Wednesday