[Music]
well good morning everybody good morning
John morning Mark good afternoon
actually is it option now we've been at
it for a little while sold some dry sift
screens tracked down some Med containers
uh John and I have had a few meetings
with a few different people and now
we've been graciously invited to a uh
grow somewhere here in the metropolitan
Toronto area yeah nice medical grow so
we took them up on that we have a couple
of meetings later on but we figured hey
let's take these guys to a grow so you
ready to head it or what we're ready to
take you
guys out of here yeah we got the Dil
packed the bubble hash and the dry sift
is in the pocket everything's ready to
go yeah let's go jump in a cab and go uh
check this this place out nice all right
all right
[Music]
I guess you could say that
yeah all right so John and I have just
arrived D here at the gro show the show
and uh I guess we're going to knock our
way in here and uh secret meet the guys
want to w we SEC whoa he's right there
dude right on bro bubble man's world in
the house good to see you bro on man
what's going on all right you're going
to take us on a little tour here come on
in got this nice little medical grow
we're talking about come on in all right
well let's just get the right light here
there we go that looks
proper wow boom boom beautiful oh yeah
nice so this is uh tell us a little bit
about your show here bro this looks
great it's a Cooperative effort it's uh
a Perpetual Harvest obviously you can
see some different weeks going on it's a
lot of California
genetics um we're kind of in a
transitional phase I'm sure everyone
else is in a way kind of post injunction
we had uh kind of these buildings were
largely empty
the buildings were largely empty and
we're having some
uh uh you know we're just getting back
to full steene right so um couple kind
of cool things going on see like kind of
what stands out to me is the weird kind
of state F we've got going on yeah um we
ran trellises for years and like that
but we decided to trellises yeah we had
2 by twos and TR everything trellis and
we went away with that we were kind of
thought it was making a bit of a can
that we didn't really want we wanted
some more air flow and so we've gone to
uh this different kind of we're 5 weeks
into the new staking what uh you looks
like you got some kush happening here
yeah we got some U there's a mix of OG
and Candy cush in that section here
these are our nice bu so I'm little
famar with I walk right up to this well
you know what I I don't know what the
medic push is but having a smell of it
the other day what is it a bit of Bubba
a bit of uh it's a bit of Bubba manin m
yeah yeah yeah we got a lot of
California stuff and uh pushes like
uh this is fire this is fire this is
fire you can see the fire in it it's
fire fire love the darkness on
[Music]
it look pretty good beautiful
awesome
flavor
beautiful right underneath find the
bottom of this big look at this nug big
huge nug I got to go down this like I
said this ready to come down what your R
you have PRX and uh you just run PR mix
PR mix y experimented
experiment no we don't add any extra got
anything in the bottom of your pots any
any
Rock chromic chromic ni and uh the
job all right lovely place you got
plants in all levels of flower
here this looks like about three 2 3
weeks in maybe
four a beautiful electrical set up looks
like they've done things proper here
it's always nice to see yeah
everything's proper
proper
yeah yes
yeah three of the units have Cabas
yeah looks great dude how many lights we
got in here I think we got 150 how much
80 oh sorry sorry 80 and flowering in
here 80 right here y
strain we got here this is the same
strain that you just saw finishing over
there this is the pre98 bub ah the
pre98 everyone loves the 398 here it's
actually you know what yeah yeah that's
the fre sorry and then we got some green
cracks here a little Cil SE in the
house
bub that is the bubble man what's up
dude are you working it I'm working it
man sorry good to see no dude please is
a great situation we're getting back on
track that's what I'm saying I love
getting my hands dirty especially this
kind of dirt this kind of dirt right
things look great they're getting there
better they're getting better and better
I love it you know a little trial and
err here and there love the tables on
the wheels that's a key right there
that's efficient you know it just works
right I had a friend build his tables on
uh pipes no wheels he puts them all on
pipes and then literally the tables are
super long and he's only got a 12in row
that goes between any and you can with
two fingers you can move and the things
from here to the end of this room with
like plants on it and you just literally
like go like this just roll it it's
unreal super nice this is a new one this
is dead head OG um dead head OG this is
the first long I think we've got this
one you guys pick this up in Cali as
well
still trim my hand like see you got a
lot of you go in there you do a lot of
hand all right get a nice shot hold the
looks
good yeah
absolutely this is always the best
shot
oops
Bine all right this guys's got a great
little thing going on
here real
nice see we let it finish like we don't
uh big on has an flavor and everything
else y just bringing out some new plants
here we're just keeping them off yeah
going to go see The
Mamas let's get this white balance
proper there we
go moms and what kind of strains we got
going on here oh let me see I think we
got uh 398 Green Crack we've got our
best strongest nicest funkiest strain
right here is uh it's a Ken dog and some
of some people call it a San Fernando
Valley cush and the Clones got mixed up
in the beginning and so some people know
it as the San Fernando but it's a Ken
dog and it's super nice super cam
beautiful and uh we and this you have
the Green krak in here and you have your
pre98 got I believe there's he probably
has a few mothers downstairs I got I see
the dead head OG down here but we've got
a headband we've got a a Alien OG we got
here is this the same as the Y yeah so
we got the orang looks nice
man this is the one it's the one that's
the so start taking clones
[Laughter]
johnan for you guys anytime John loves
that cam I love the cam you know this
one I think is uh we call this one OG
beanie it's another very
similar nice super funky got a pink
crack some pink cracks Here Pink crack
eh a littleit crazy this thing looks a
little gnarly yeah it's co gnarly like
the Green Crack same thing weed him a
whole bunch today and [ __ ] down and
they just like it's funny when mothers
become it's like cuz it's I don't know
maybe it's just from my perspective I
haven't like once you just start taking
care of a mother I'm sure it's like cut
her down cut her down for me every time
I cut it down I'm like oh I could these
areon I could give them away to my
friends I could you know what I mean I
have a hard time time just cutting those
tops and tossing them in the garden I
know I have a hard time around here too
and we cut off a lot you know clean them
up sure
absolutely I got I got my my this we
both some of the Bubba SC the way the
folage stacks up on them John you know
what our only kind of failure was I
think not bring in some of ours wouldn't
it have been cool to be like have some
Congo sure would here's some sweet skun
do you need an Astro
Boy well you know where we're at guys
ready to go what a great reason to go to
Vancouver you know what I love this view
right here this this reminds me of you
getting on the zipline a zipline that's
what this makes me think of where's
where's his zipline that's all it's
missing here that is pretty sweet view
this is the first I come to in the
morning get a good look at the Garden
see see things are happening my buddy
here if you don't mind no no not at all
you want to get a m or you want me to
just
you know what this this uh doesn't have
a lot of flavor to it right doesn't have
a lot of smell to it you know what this
this is actually the dead head right and
it's starting to get this lemon but it
should have more uh wild maybe it comes
later kind of weird and well if we're
going to go 10 weeks with it at least
and see what happens what do we got
right here this one right there that is
our headband that's the headband yes
is more flavor on that one yeah YouTube
channel man bubble man's world bub man's
world bubble man's world so yeah just
some silly sort of ridiculous bub
bag all right here we go
what do we got going on over here boys
and if you I remember I to show you the
fitting how I do my peeling yeah just
peeling it off yeah just peeling this
one Le but no I do that right yeah not
taking the top just taking that one just
taking this one little leaf it causes no
stress to exp my B difference just the
one leaf not the leaf it's just one of
the mains there we
go all right
this thing looks like a house plant
yeah what is this one I think that is
our tac tac
eh dude I love the old
school these are all getting ready for
the next run yeah
DNA uh somebody gave us the strain of it
it's not very
good oh yeah this one's got a bit of
meldy yeah that's the problem with this
chain that we had
here this one smells nice going to come
down you know we save them CU everything
changed candy cushion bub mix in here
those are the two it's trippy how
certain strains are more susceptible to
things these ones [ __ ] killed us to
Milo man we had to we had to throw so
much [ __ ] it's not funny you can see you
can run it into hash yeah we yeah we uh
but not oil the oil will melt away the
milde uh if you wash it with
water it'll
just wash
away the other stra down there res [ __ ]
it is
the one down there that's yellowing
that's the kosher push when you started
trying out the koser we change it up
here we put all trans the side of walls
cuz that was John talking about there's
not enough air in some places oh yeah
next door this is what we need to put
next door as well well this does feel
good right away and when you feel good
in your room I got to comfortable I
think your plants are too yes I think
so where's kosher I'll come around the
back there yeah back in the back purple
no that's that that's the same as that
tall stuff that's the bub OG C oh the
bub OG but all these this unit in the UN
next door you turn all into the San
Valley these are all San Fernand going
here I got some finished over next
door yeah it's such a pck plant we're
having trouble dealing with it but SM
and which one is
this oh yeah
sticky DNA representing all the way over
here in Canada thanks
boys oh yeah these are like amazing
smell it's Beauty on the red oh yeah you
can see it glistening oh yeah just look
at that just hardly touching got show a
little oh yeah those San Fran those are
the Beauties I love
them beautiful maybe go back over there
Bill does an amazing job on these star
so you know they're always on top it a
lot work manck
okay yeah well you're not growing plants
you're growing tricomes right true and
when you get this many plants
W it is a lot of
work San Fernando Valley
Cush sfv
[Music]
a lot of this stuff was going to make it
right it got brought in here and it's
saved by the uh
injunction nice clean electrical these
guys are
rocking love seeing that all up the oh
you can tell by how clean it
is Corner
everything did they make some funny
jokes yeah cold it can be from cold it
can be from genetics it can be from like
a variety of things
purpling but you can generally tell when
it's a stress some strains just go
purple yeah man oh look at these little
stockies have niell these ones here
they're all Sado in here now but these
are the ones these are on week
n these two some forgot to water when I
was
away
[Laughter]
water I had to rewat them after they
came back
it's just hearty like rocks they're
going extra weeks now
too yeah very very lovely Roger you can
theic quality awesome awesome I'm dying
to make dry sift out of this actually I
would love to try to do
that yeah dude we'll make sure with dry
sift that you use buds that don't have
any
milde I just saw one that had you want
to avoid you can wet wash milde you can
clean it off it washes
away here trar to get little hey if I
took a picture of it you'd see it under
a micro lens it looks like little ant
bodies that are connected one little
section to another little section and
they grow in Long strings and these got
affected because we had a cush on this
side that we took down the week before
and I believe that's kind of spre start
spreading it around oh yeah sanan never
used to Happ see we're running uh
yeah exp the Hy hydroxy odor processor
and so that uh how does that work well
these are demo units we're trying to not
in just this one unit to see how to do
it's suppos to between the air but what
what's inside there is there I couldn't
tell you okay you don't know if it's
using water or if it's using carbon it's
carbon I believe it's a carbon yeah you
know the old school guys from the ' 70s
and the 80s they were using 55g barrels
and the whole room before it blew out
exhaust it would go through a 55g barrel
drum of water like right to the bottom
like a bong and then it would bubble out
and then he had a top on it that blew it
out no smell like a humidif the water
robs the smell just like a bong it just
sucks the [ __ ] that's cool little uh
molecules right out of the air very cool
I just want to walk down to the end
canabus you guys have a lot of work cut
out for you here hey I know man man I
know it's nonstop too people don't have
any idea people think it's [ __ ] yeah
oh you just grow weed yeah what a cool
job he yeah yeah you're a
hippie These are nice yeah it's just
crazy how much of a learning process it
is though he Raj every [ __ ] day every
day you learn something pretty sweet be
uh here in Toronto and get invited to a
nice facility these guys are pretty
pretty sweet guys pretty nice dudes and
uh yeah they've got a pretty nice grow
going on here with some nice
strains smells
great got another boss hydroxy odor
processor oh we smelt the goodness when
we got here outside all right little bit
little
bit little
bit the lights just went out beautiful
good night girls good night girls see
you tomorrow night and
night my gr license over there oh that's
yours on the door there we're all safe
that way you know you got to be man we
just took tables out of here to make
more space cuz of uh you know
everything's extended now so we're
getting that space opened up out for a
little bit more all right so just some
more little babies here's all the little
girls here getting them ready you always
need room it's amazing look even four on
the chair yeah literally it's like we
need a chair here yeah just whatever can
help we're getting rid of these
reflectors we're going to make I'm going
to get another type of reflector F
inside okay so we can get higher with
the light so you'll be a lot more space
too breathing space for these plants all
right and these are going to be these
are basically ready to go for flowering
yeah these are going to be brought down
this week so you start them in like a
three Gall we started in this little uh
was that a two that's the two gallon
these are the two Gall then we going to
the 15 Gall here here is where they
finish off
awesome 15 Gallons you know go big or go
home I guess is that what they say
nowadays well no they say Grow Big Grow
Big or grow home grow
home you guys light in there yeah just
right now it just went food I guess
everywhere else too right I think it
goes this way is it going first second
third fourth is it like that I think so
all right Johnny we're going to open up
the new uh I'm not
disclosure new T I know hanging out
somewhere else um checking out some
Stellar [ __ ] and we got this new T5 that
we've always been talking about man here
so I'm stoked cuz uh hangs three
ways pop here oh know viral gr T5 roll
it right over down set it down
lift her
up more tape on those two
edges these guys are doing it it's like
Christmas time for
Growers [ __ ] yeah oh yeah there we go
She's a Beauty yeah that's nice each
individual one sheath yeah and this is
the
bottom oh those are [ __ ] nice this is
what I'm excited for B turn that baby
around oh yeah look at that at that oh
yeah my buddies are right beside each
other he made a little thing but this is
cool they'll be like over here your
buddies right oh yeah like Closer Closer
Closer literally right beside it yeah he
custom did his own sheath he's OCD yeah
yeah we're talking about you right now
Ron you guys maybe saw him on the video
when I went to the cies and made hash
outside guy in the
snow because we've been talking about
this exact same thing marus go I get my
buddy Ron one of those yeah but now it's
a product and you can just buy it and so
who sells this in virro grow or hydrarm
hydrarm designed and engineered in the
US distributed by Hydro Farm all right
here go look at this designed and
engineered in the US in tiny tiny little
letters made in
China it yeah of course
awesome well [ __ ] and you got to get I
think these are the new 60 is it 67 100
or 6500 K the new
uh uh luminum put up to
60,000 6,000 6400 K tubes 6400 yeah
those those new tubes they say there
they are we got to plug to plug that
thing in or what plug it in over there
that' be great to see it plug in do that
what do we got to unplug nothing
security system the orange one the white
one oh the white
one boom I like that I like that there's
three switches for it yeah that's pretty
no [ __ ] have different stages I guess
they even open I thought it was going to
be
thirst right all right dude that's
pretty tight you turn the next one on
the this one no the other one turn that
off that one
well you had it stagger yeah you can
stagger you can stagger them too like
one in every other one come on lot of
guys are doing that staggering them the
put the whole thing in so what is the
what's the retail on one of these come
on what are we doing retail on one of
these if someone's got to go buy one um
I cost of 300 but I think
the 600 bucks so yeah these are 5 to
$600 retail we do have the four if
you're a shop you might be able to pick
them up for $400 $450
perfect yeah but that's a 12 dude look
at that that's that's like you put that
in the back of the
tent
boom these is what you line all your
walls with yeah dude give it yeah
perfect you get about 30 of these the
bottom serious there we go there we put
another 30 above the top and now you get
that bottom growth just fine awesome
what if we put in some like EDM music
and like a you can actually walk into
your room basically in short get at the
same
time my [ __ ] a awesome start here
first I'm definitely not getting one but
I want one
smaller oh [ __ ] you heating that [ __ ]
up or what you're like low temperature
dabs around you oh nice I don't know
about you guys I usually use a cap I
don't know if you run a cap very much or
you don't do it anymore just going to
hit it just hit it we're just going to
hit it you're hitting it it's your pipe
you're here we go as long as the hash
hits then you know you have the right
temperature looks
perfect little
mini nice low temp
da the 398
buba which is buba hit with number call
Little this yeah
thanks awesome
who wants a DA John wants a
d on it up oh
bedro bedro yeah that's best guys that
are working
2 FP
DC get the guy with yeah I'll take
dab who's
up
dabing the guy with the sore back
first smells like Moroccan smells like
just a nice
pocket except to gets you super high
yeah I
know but it does have that kind
of especially coming off the nail on the
low temp you know what I miss man I know
I miss I'm getting like the Malawi gold
like just that [ __ ]
dice things you just never see here yeah
you just don't they just so ahead right
here we go yep Spain's creeping up now
Spain's on it man we were just in
Barcelona it was [ __ ] awesome you
guys go fan of his cup or oh yeah yeah
how's that it was great yeah oh yeah got
so many great friends there like just
basically had the time of our life
filmed cruised around made hash with the
Ripper seeds guys made hash with Javier
for medical seeds went and chilled out
with Jamie at resin Club went and
chilled with uh s and all those guys
that were visiting just the gong
show Hammer
sure I got [ __ ] sh the
water bub man when was the last time you
saw me get high at work never never
there it is there it is he gets the Bigg
he get the best one you had to heat it
up
[Laughter]
oh yeah got to hit
sweet you guys do low dab using a lot of
chemicals and stuff he a full m bubble
we would like to get that up hot cool
down and hit it nicely and you get a
better dab so is just so much more
tastier and you're getting totally like
wow that's tasty as hell it's just SOL
it's just made with all white ice and
water everything you
have that would be My Little Pony My
Little Pony My Little Pony which is is a
pre98 Bubba H with a camper Union which
I call Bubba County which is cross I
didn't that some El I I cross it with
the northern lake number five skunk and
we call it My Little Pony because it's
um
nl5 John's Little
Pony stram that I'll be working with but
yeah one one of
my like you doing this the guy with the
back to get in and as you can see it's
hot now and that is not ever hit nicely
not much
better hell yeah now we're doing some RI
tasting the you
need toow that's okay we start low
rather than high work ourselves in we
work ourselves up we don't start high
and work ourselves down need just a full
melt perfect resin right there looking
very let me see one sec here I got a
thing that I can do he's got a thing
that he can do here it is here it
is no I can't do
it there they go there's a proper
hit there 398 bu acoss you just got a
gift given to you there by uh sir Master
grower here at the facility what uh can
you tell us about this guy
it's the uh it's the chem dog and it
helps one of our patients specifically
with cluster headaches it's actually one
strain specifically that's been able to
help him he's cut his medication down by
80 or 90% okay that's that's amazing
could I ask you do they smoke vaporize
or or use metaal he's smoking it so just
joints or bowls but he up to about half
ooun a day with this Str but that's
incredible but compared to any other
strings he's tried this is the one
specifically that is really helpful so
not only is he eliminating harsh um uh
pharmaceutical medication that plays
with the chemistry of his brain um but
he's also if anyone has any idea what
cluster headaches are uh take the worst
headache you've ever had and multiply it
by like a thousand I used to have severe
migraine headaches with with and I'm in
the same boat migraines I've never had
clusters Phil turns white when he gets
his clusters and he just disappears like
this we're going to we want we want to
take this back to uh to BC and we're
going to go and see Phil yeah dude and
we're going to take this we're bringing
this back to you Phil it's going to be
awesome we're going to do a little
continuation on this show and we'll see
if uh maybe uh maybe how this works for
your cluster headaches and we'd love to
see if we could get the Sweat Band out
to these guys to uh pass that on to some
more people out here that are suffering
from cluster uh headaches because
laboratory that can test and do a
comparison you know what true genetics
Phil's company would love that AB
oid test we're looking at all the
different ecies and and this is the one
reason that we're looking at Future
licensed producers and stuff like that
because of the the research that can
actually go behind and what they're
looking at and what actually can be able
to obtain to help patients worldwide so
you know what what I really like about
that is being able to have those tests
done now bringing that to Phil cuz we
know Phil how how you suffer and stuff
like that so we're going to bring him
that and uh we're going to go from there
seeing Whistler in about a week Phil
puff
Wednesdays oh man what a nice experience
that was it's [ __ ] awesome man you
know I'm feeling better and better about
Toronto uh every day that I stay here
know again we're talking about medicine
they're talking what we're doing here I
mean it's really friendly nice guys they
got a great Vibe they got a nice grow
they're humble um they're willing to
share they're just yeah I like these
guys I'm glad that they invited us here
it was very kind and very trusting to
invite us here I mean I know you guys
feel that you know us from our videos
but in reality I mean you really don't
so whenever you approach us and you uh
you know introduce yourselves uh we're
really happy that you do it's always
nice to meet all of you sometimes if if
we come across that we don't have time
or we we haven't said hi to you properly
we apologize so busy so busy super Sor
not trying to pull any of that [ __ ] we
look at everyone as equals whether you
have a beautiful 150 like show or
whether you have a small little pipe and
you want to share a little bowl of your
hash with us we're uh we're willing so
thanks everyone for watching thanks for
we've got a little bit more of an
adventure here on Bubble man's world but
we're going to end this one for now and
we're going to see you next time on
Bubble man's world hospital that our
very own John B was born at what do you
say John it's pretty cool you were born
there I was born there 197 you are with
it in the
background
1971 Johnny's hospital it's my
Hospital awesome hanging out with these
guys they gave us a ride back that was
so kind of dud [ __ ] great seeing the
the place going to cover my crazy hair
we're going to go hang out with now Sean
kushman there he
is yeah buddy we're coming for you
guys how's it going
markad Mark nice to meet you met you
before Haven
I I'm not very
good you
guys good to see you dude jeez how's it
going you guys coming for a dab great
now man we haven't had a dab let's go
have a dab all right we're
dabbing we're going to head up to our
hotel do a little bit of eighth floor
food action and uh dab it up with Sean
kushman and crew This Is How We Roll
bubble man's world five
minutter welcome back to Bubble man's
world guys you saw as we were getting
out of the cab we bumped into Mr kushman
hi guys so uh we figured we would do a
do a quick little dab with
him uh a little bit of my resin that I
grew the Astro Boy yeah yeah I'm
familiar with it I I've been dying to
try it actually wet washed it with John
so uh one for you
buddy I don't have the quartz cart cap
out just now but we'll get that
later so did you have a good event
you're working at the sublimator booth I
guess yeah definitely trying to reach as
many people as possible since enrio
can't be there with this year's event
yeah crazy story about enrio I guess you
viewers probably know by now enrio Bard
was arrested in a large sting in Quebec
that involved 80 cops and hydroponics
owners and Seed Sellers and Growers and
green houses and houses yeah yeah it's
really really deep just full [ __ ]
like full on just just figure you know
they prosecute somebody for four packs
of seeds I mean come on four packs of SE
meim emry sold a million of packs of
seeds and he never got charged by the
Canadian government no the most he got
was a fine yeah from from us from us
from us from us usually here in Canada
we know how to which reminds me you know
seeds Mark's going to be back in about a
month Mark Emery will be out of yazu
City he will no longer be in Mississippi
as a resident of the US but indeed I
think the US consuming Mark Emory for
those 5 years truly did exactly what
Adam Bowen wrote about his song uh
puffing on the Tricom which was Uncle
Sam has ingested marijuana in the form
of Mark emie and I think he's going to
start seeing things a little bit
differently Mark went into prison and
within 6 months the prosecuting attorney
who prosecuted Mark started to work on
legal cannabis in Washington and with
Jody's help like think about that that
was the guy that prosecuted him and put
him in prison he's the same guy that
worked on getting cannabis allowed in
Washington state so Mark had an effect
just by going into their prison and
being consumed by them he's learned to
base he's playing music it'll be great
to have him back yeah yeah we can't wait
for him to come out there I can't wait
to definitely see him and hang around
with him a little bit when he gets out
and I'm sure that he can't wait to see
everybody when he gets out of there too
well apparently it's going to be here
first right here in
Toronto get out here first yeah so we'll
be coming out here probably for the
[Music]
uh all right Johnny's loading it up
Corner camera Corner camera
rips very nice so we're just going to
continue to puff some bowls here but I
wanted to share a few minutes showing
that Sean kushman was in the house
mentioned the sublimator booth who he
was working with give your support to
those guys try and get in touch with
them definitely support sublimator guys
order their products and uh yeah other
than that pass the B around here oh yeah
up hit a little bit of medy here right
now load them
up yeah I believe you got to try it
yesterday the
[Music]
JFK peace for now guys