[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world guys
I'm here with Johnny B and uh we're here
in Ontario at weed MD one of the uh
future licensed production facilities so
uh we're going to take you uh in here
and give you a little show nice take us
in Johnny hey here we
come all
right all right all right so here we are
at the Vault Johnny B um
yeah you know you know the best part of
all this
guys what's that this is where they're
going to store pounds and pounds of weed
like pounds and pounds of weed heo more
weed you've ever seen in so this is the
vault as you can see these guys are not
messing around this
door very thick looks like that might
stop some uh thieves from getting in all
right we got a 2T thick plus
concrete
and so Health Canada is not joking
around here they want level 9 to level
10 security which down in the US I think
that's like nasson Pentagon style it's
pretty ridiculous the whole thing is
tied in with cameras you can see a
camera up in the corner there I believe
Health Canada has access to all the
cameras of all the facilities as well
they will so these are so this facility
is just being built obviously it's not
finished yet um they're in the middle of
uh acquiring their license and I I think
the building's 25,000 ft so we're just
going to do a little bit more of a walk
through machine what's this this is the
Destroyer the Destroyer this is what
they have to get rid of all their like
trim and stock and all the little extra
uh herbs and stuff what hell's that
[ __ ] bin over there we'll go into
here this bin over here is going to be
manure and it's going to mix in with the
material that they that they Rune so it
can't be processed or cleaned any
further manure manure they're going to
take what they call waste that is
actually medicine and mix it with [ __ ]
yeah that's can and then we can grind it
up and feed it back to our plants I
guess right I guess so but it's a pretty
big serious unit you know what it's
going to be a big meat grinder it's big
grinder big grind very cool all right so
there's this
Vault water so the only thing we want to
get rid of is uh the chlorine right uh
if you want to use Organics you don't
want chlorine in your water will kill
your Organics there's two Caron filters
to take care of that uh one other thing
that's going to be added is two UV
lights okay yeah those work great Y and
that's about it
cool I know that Mario was talking about
about this damex control system and he
was oh there he is right there tell us a
little bit about this thing
man um it's a dosing system and you just
put your nutrients in here your your pH
Down your
micronutrients and then a computer
system will then initiate the irrigation
according to the humidity needs of the
soil wow and so you can really control
things on a different level with a
system like this yeah you can adjust
your dosing uh whatever the PPM you want
you can lower your HP to your desired
level the system then injects fresh
filtered water through a spinning system
that mixes all the nutrients and then
once it all the nutrients and mix sends
it over to the water room to the water
room awesome we're talking about
standardized exactly what we're talking
about we able to TA get well you're
getting you're getting the science down
here everything's done with computers
we're getting there they're precise
heating programs all the time nothing's
really changing too much where if it is
computer's monitor it there's not people
coming in here with gauges and sticks
and kind of winging it exactly there a
computer system in the office and um
what it does that's really is that
monitors all the levels at all times so
if you change anything in your feeding
cycle and you get good results you can
go back and say okay this is when we did
this yeah and it shows you okay now it's
easy to reproduce the same effect
because you can see where the changes
are taking place on the computer
it logs everything that's excellent
exactly what we're talking about here
and that's why we're uh well that's why
we're here explaining it to you and also
the other good thing is you save out
countless of hours of watering
everything by
hand yeah no that's completely
ridiculous to try and water the nice
thing about this system it um if you
need to water by hand for any reason
it's just a matter of switching a valve
and and you're off to manual Vol can you
show us where this is yeah of course
yeah let's check it out
so I guess this is still under
construction here look at that power box
they definitely have some power enough
power here to power approximately 10,000
lights 10,000 lights 10,000 lights yeah
well that's not even that's not an
electrical room that's not even an
electrical room that's just the panel
just the panel all all right so now we
have a whole bunch of stuff going on in
here we're going to need explained okay
so we're building here a mother room on
the right hand side oh nice um once we
build out phase number two there's going
to be two floors here yeah so we're
going to double up on
Space uh this section here will be the
bedroom for now and in the front corner
we're going to put a little floating in
oh okay and keep in mind this facility
is only half built so there's a lot of
things we still need to implement in
here sure this is all part of your
cooling system here he was telling me a
little bit about this earlier yeah these
are the chiller
systems it is uh the the whole system is
cooled by glycol and it's uh 30% more
efficient than your standard gas heat uh
I mean um
electrical Electrical uh air
conditioning system and who you guys had
these guys come up from Colorado to set
this up yeah uh that that was the Hydra
innovations that came Hydra Innovations
okay right very good people yeah it
looks great so this is a closed loop
system that operates and pumps into both
rooms from your tanks that is correct
okay okay well I guess we'll head into
the got a punch key code no matter what
we we go into security absolutely key in
and out and out in out there is a any
room with any growing AC Security on
both you have to use the code plus you
have to use your key card to get
into and then of course each key card is
monitored by the person who owns that
key card the key card is uh so it's all
computer monitored and it's all
registered to the individual keys that
tells you who's been in and who's been
out of what room rooms how how much time
has been spent in the rooms in Canada by
Health Canada standards there has to be
like a responsible person in charge and
that's one of the challenging things in
our system is that not everybody working
in the facility will be a responsible
person because the clearance requirement
is really deep so the way this works is
the responsible person in charge can key
in and then people can follow them in
cuz it knows that there's a responsible
person in the room and then if the
responsible person keys out he'll clear
the room and then nobody can key in and
when someone told me they move that's
interesting Ducks it's like ducks you
move like ducks w a lot well I know but
but Ducks move in in TOS yeah that's and
you know what I just put the look in
here here's this Dynamic control system
we were just talking about now there's
there's another box here is this just
like a I mean relay box or how is this
working here the computer for the room
computer for the room this this secret
board here Will will initiate the
electronic irrigation system that's that
is connected to the aquamat system and
basically we have these moisture sensors
yeah I want you to tell us a bit about
these aquam mats oh the aquam mats um a
very good way to uh save a lot of
water and also save a lot of time having
to uh I'm disabled and I did this myself
and this thing is what 40 ft long and
weighs 72 ft long 72 ft long you can
literally move with uh couple fingers
wait a second
here that works oh wait did the broken
side that's pretty pimp I've never seen
that before so these these mats feed
based on these sensors yes where the
pots are sitting the sensor will will
tell you at at any given time what the
moisture level is inside the soil you
can then choose when you'd like to
initiate the watering you tell the
computer and every time the soil reaches
a certain moisture the computer will
then automatically uh do the watering
for you and there's no drip emitter
system this is pushed up
through yes this is uh done through a
capillary action okay so it's a membrane
system that's feeding actually through
the mat yeah there's a special layer on
top so the roots cannot penetrate and
there's a special layer on the bottom
that will only allow the water to go
through once there's pressure applied to
the m interesting cool that's
unbelievable another note another note
about the water as to the damage attack
is that it's actually dosed where the
tanks are where we were earlier and so
that's where it's fed from and it's
automatically dosed and that's premixed
through these
mats all the valves are coming through
the rim and all the different at the
beginning of all the Ben so here's a
question in regards to feeding because
you're feeding a food through the mats
do you think that the mats themselves
will require flushing of salts yeah yes
yes so there's two ways you can Flash
the mat is using water with hydrogen
peroxide or you can just use regular
water and PH down to 4.0 4.0 to knock
everything out
interesting that's a really cool
technology I have to say um I'm
impressed so you guys got about 100
lights in here there's 102 lights and
there's another additional 50 lights
that will be installed
in between these lights uh to uh to
illumin the sides of the plant and these
are your closed system air conditioners
you see all glyc cool system these
coolers oh oh These
chillers we're down to check it out
though check so you can see there's a
lot of work that goes into this for you
people that are watching this is not
something that you just go out on on a
whim this is a very intense
uh
large project so these are the the
condensers that are feeding the chillers
oh wow
careful yeah that'll do
it that'll do it for
sure then the the the the water tanks
yeah the glycol tanks the glycol tanks
ah the glycol
tanks the back here with all the tubes
oh wow so it's not it's not an enormous
amount no I mean that is it's it's a lot
but you'd think for the size of the
system that it could end up being a huge
piping too what is that like 8
in it's 8 in huh we justall that in your
tent we did didn't we nice big pumps for
that and so did you guys have a special
company that come in and and do this or
did you guys this is this is all Hydro
inovation from Boulder Colorado they
came and did it all they came and did it
all that's great
yeah let me turn this stuff on here it
up here hit the
switch that's some pretty serious uh
those are serious valves there's some
serious valves that sh and there one two
three before the actually ready no not
let's test it hey got clean Johnny look
at the tea now that's nice
that's we nerd out on this stuff what
can we say yeah like hey thanks for
taking us through a little walkthr guys
that was really cool weed MD watch for
[Music]
him