[Music]
dude puff Wednesday and Chester's in the
house all right how we doing good to see
you man has it been since Amsterdam
since we filmed it was Amsterdam so if
you guys don't know Chester go back in
the video and watch our exclusive tuck
tuck rides through the streets of
Amsterdam I didn't even know what a tuck
tuck was yeah that's sort of an Asia
thing if you've traveled Thailand or
India you know southeast Asia you'll
definitely know about the tuck tucks
both the bicycle ones which is what we
were on it was a blast yeah no it was
good for what a way to travel I'm
telling you you're you're right like on
road you're on the road yeah like on the
RO the best thing about that is that
they go into the the sidewalk parts that
no car
in right remember when she was slowing
down through those two little so that
was nice that was nice so you guys saw
when I left here I grabbed some cuts and
those cuts were for my good friend
Chester so we've got them right here God
loves me in this uh nice styrofoam box
that's all cooled inside with um Frozen
packs yeah oh yeah we're not messing
around here beautiful that's beautiful
so I only cut three I was extremely busy
and had uh had quite a bit of uh diving
into the box you know yeah exactly so
let's go through these right here we've
got uh the Astro Boy so that's the
that's the TGA
genetics Hollow 13 male pollen smacking
an Ortega cross with
c99 it's really nice wow that's a crazy
one that's the bubble right there if you
want to take a little rip of it wow why
don't I give you a rip of my own fresh
Frozen bubble that I Grew From This Very
plant well why don't you
yes that's awesome that's a great idea I
support that whole this is beautiful man
this is
incredible yeah so that comes that came
from my good buddy Ron wow oh yeah
brought those if you watch the videos we
were in uh Castlegar near the C in the
cies near um near Nelson and that's
where I picked up that particular
one and now here I am in Toronto passing
it on
wow oh
tasty still going nice paper
rips very nice so there we are with the
Astro Boy wow I think you'll do really
well with that I think you really like
it it grows incredibly it seems to be
fairly resistant yes um from things like
bugs and milu oh yes yeah yeah well they
won't be running into any of that with
us hopefully you just never know though
right nice to know though is nice to
know and then so secondly we got the
breeder Steve cut the sweet skunk God
now that's a special thing right there
that's a very special thing knowing's
breeder Steve too like it's more than
special uh thank you brother took a long
time to get here but thank you Steve man
for real it did didn't it oh
man good for you Stevie yeah so that's
the sweet skunk a longtime favorite in
British Columbia it's a hazy skunky
variety that everyone loves even people
that don't like the it's literally the
salmon of cannabis people that don't
like fish but they'll eat salmon like oh
this is good that's what the sweet skunk
is to people who don't smoke or like
herb wow it's just that one that
everyone will hit yeah it's just got
that certain sweetness to it eh and then
last but certainly not least the Congo
oh the Congo the Congo is another really
nice African sativa yeah yeah really
just nice up there with the sweet skunk
in the sense that it's it's a good
stable sativa to have in the uh actually
got a chance to see this plant grow at
um almost 14 weeks it was spectacular
nice it was like I had never seen
anything like that I hope you do
something similar oh my yeah take it to
15 yeah exactly take it all the way
through well my God sharing is caring
sharing is caring share your genetics
yes indeed share your genetics please
and on a puff Wednesday too bad Johnny
Be is downstairs right now he feels like
he should be here yeah he's doing the
nextg conference pre meeting before the
dinner so of course their medical
adviser for the nextg uh group and so
he's got to be down there and be a part
of it but otherwise I'm sure he'd be up
here well Johnny we'll hold a fort for
you till you get here buddy yeah he'll
be coming up soon and we'll smoke a pure
hash joint with him and Tony and
Ernie and maybe we'll convince Parish
great to see Tony again great to meet
Ernie man we with Tony in Amsterdam and
we had a blast you know we had about 10
days together and everybody was just
stoked we ever having nothing but fun
and and doing a lot of work man doing a
lot of work yeah no it is a lot of work
it's endless uh filming and editing and
then in the meantime working out deals
introducing people figuring out
logistics and then it's there's all
these different countries involved now
there's all these different oh yeah it's
pretty pretty outrageous how it's sort
of it's it's on a mass it's on a massive
massive conscious change for sure you
know it's over you know it's over it's
done I think I heard that last nail yeah
me too I think yeah I think they just
got the last nailed they just trying to
figure out how to um well whatever they
do that's what they're trying to figure
out what to do we wouldn't have a clue
what that is trust me but yeah it's over
we're we're going we we we're there we
it's the medicine that's done it it's
the acknowledgement and and the
education that people have got with the
medicine and uh man it is being
worldwide recepted everywhere whether
it's called RSO or the cannaboids
cannaboids cannaboids is it absolutely
the tricomes is the medicine absolutely
in the future will be infused tricomes
in everything herb herb is the messenger
and bubble is the message yeah that is
right true that is so we're going to
leave you for now Chester's got his
genetics we'll see you in a bit when we
puff that pure hash joint all right good
to see you buddy good to see you man
thanks a lot this is a wonderful
wonderful thing got to do it God love
you man you got to do it welcome back to
Puff Wednesday guys it's always good
puffing it's [ __ ] Thursday at 3:00 in
the morning isn't it we're puffing in
Toronto this is like a different puff
one is that it it what an incredible day
we puffed we drove for hours outside of
the
um uh City out of Toronto and we visited
this beautiful facility called weed MD
uh in which you'll have seen at the
start of this video because I filmed a
bunch of
stuff um that was real nice real nice
facility that was you know very well put
together those being buil the beds were
nice pretty epic [ __ ] the Vault The
Vault Vault was cool that whole watering
system and how everything's standardized
for the exact same nutrient and the
potential thousands of square feet of
greenhouse for outside so really just
pretty cool to be going into these
places that was a good chunk of the day
with great people we were with uh the
United cannabis guys uh Ernie and Tony
we're with the weed MD guys uh Robbie
and Allison and Mike ended up showing up
later really just a great team of people
that we're uh looking forward to doing
some sort of affiliation with in the
future we also had an incredibly
powerful meeting today after our dinner
with all the weed MD guys uh we had our
Jamaican contacts come out to receive
the packet from uh Yukan and yeah it was
just a really cool thing well hopefully
uh we'll be leaving for Jamaica on
Friday there no hoping we're leaving for
Jamaica on Friday there's no hoping it's
true but tomorrow before that which is
today you speak in what 3 or 4 hours 5
hours three yo I got to be up I got to
be the event 3 hours something it's got
to be up in two and I speak in four
awesome which is is going to be epic you
know it's I'm looking forward to it you
got quite a good lineup nextg conference
yeah you know what we got it going on
quite exciting uh it's a big big talks
about it here people are um hey they
like what we're doing they like the
education you know what um
it's a lot of fun because we able to
come out here and do what we do here
every day is educate you guys on on
exactly what we're about what we're
doing we're just U being
real yeah you know we seem to be
learning a lot in the process you know
in this supposed education we are
learning more I think and I'm learning a
ton every day it's quite amazing it's
just the information that is is actually
flowing now and and it's quite nice and
even talking with people about it today
like 10 years ago we wouldn't do
anything like this because you were in
your family going to jail losing loved
ones this that and and now it's really
we're able to come out and start talking
about it with you so yeah it's awesome
man it's really been a great quick trip
to Toronto um I'm going to film a little
bit of NextGen tomorrow so I'll share
that with you guys tomorrow um got to
give Chester the cuts earlier so was
good to see him in Parish him and his
son came in from the Ottawa area and of
course he's always a character to hang
out with no matter where or what or when
I've known Chester almost 25 years and
he's just that's cool he's a fun guy
he's definitely a fun guy he got to good
Insight you know uh good wisdom uh you
know he's got good information he's
being around the scene so he's uh he's
he's looking out for for better interest
in uh the people that are in the
industry absolutely that's the best way
of putting a good people I'm going to
give you a dunk you going to dunk me
yeah or maybe it'll be a dab it's going
to dab but I've had a long day and uh
wow 5 hours in the car was
uho yeah 5 hours in the car was you know
what sometimes you got to do that guys
got to get down on the
adventure and it was worth it met a
great group of people saw a real nice
facility in the middle of really being
uh put
together real potential
what else Johnny
well I found that belt I was looking for
you did you got your belt this was very
important for John to get a belt to hold
up his pants for the uh I mean who would
want to have their pants fall down at
the uh see when I was at the last that's
like your worst nightmare when you're
speaking Yeah talking weight has to
Sound
by shows them losing weight which is a
good thing but and know at the same time
I still can't believe you paid $
160 well there's
nothing I paid like 50 for this one in
Whistler and I was like wow that's an
expensive belt M Inlet yeah yours is
like made by the you know from like baby
cows or something it was the only store
around super fancy Toronto like like
running around asking people in the
malls going down oh this is the best
this is the best part the most expens
you're going to love this I run across
the street limping go down the escalator
and walk into a building I'm looking
around for shop to see restaurant
restaurant restaurant and they refer me
wsib work safe in if work safe basically
in Toronto which will be my talk where
and I'm laughing because my talk is
about wsib tomorrow and I'm sit staring
out of the building looking for a belt I
run across the street the only places
around work safe here in in Ontario is
all these expensive shops I guess that's
where everybody shops when they work
there they make such I not get into it w
I remember where that place was cuz you
point it was right across from the hotel
that we stayed in last time yeah cuz you
I remember you pointed it you're like
hey that's the work
thing for me I don't even see these
things but I never had a big battle with
I fight for patient rights that's why I
do what I do right education uh pain
control and it really it's U hey grow
your own what I always say grow your own
that's what you're doing grow your own I
think we're puffing on your own turn it
into resin and enjoy it in all the forms
that you made
think um I'm soaking my um my Hitman
tonight with your M soaking method right
now yes yeah we showed you guys that as
well and uh I'll be doing that with this
Dil right away we're going to wrap this
video up in a few seconds here um just
kind of wanted to wrap puff Wednesday up
and say say you know hey we we it was a
good one we didn't miss you no
absolutely we did it all throughout the
day it was a long I've Never filmed a
puff Wednesday from like 7 in the
morning to like 3:00 at night until into
a puff Thursday morning it was a damn
near puff 24hour Wednesday it was it was
very nice anyway guys as always thanks
for watching we appreciate it we'll gu
next puff Wednesday is going to be in
Jamaica yeah we'll see you we'll see you
well we'll see you in less than a week
cuz we're going to I'm going to upload
every day that we're in Jamaica the next
time you see puff Wednesday we will be
in Jamaica