[Music]
production
hey what's up welcome to bubble man's
world I'm here today with Phil and he's
going to tell us a little bit about his
breeding company and his strange dude
he's breeding for his own personal
medical issues and we're gonna take some
D mail rips
awesome he loves the grow room be sure
that those vitamin lights in there for
him [ __ ] yeah yeah d4 20k and those guys
up in Prince George swearing but the
vitamin lights rewrites that very trifle
production yeah they really like the
whole over that CFLs educated use
compact fluorescents take a couple of
plants and flower with them and the
results are absolutely amazing
I've grown single plants have grown
multiple plants understand just still be
Tricon production how they're not just
great yields the track of production be
when we thought right here this little
plant here that you brought down this is
something we've been working on for a
couple years here this is an OG 18 grown
from seed when crossed with West Coast
savages own mail we got the West Coast
Sour Diesel beans from Mad Men they were
a gift
half ago he a little bit of nice
glandular producing mail no beautiful
and smash that onto our blueberry
Sowerberry been an OG 18 would be give a
little history on that that would be the
Jew gold that's wool the og teen that's
what they used to make the Jew gold in
LA they use that to make the kosher what
everyone calls the kosher coach right
DNA genetics came out with the the og 18
that was their first release of their og
cush they reef Amman the history because
it came out where they came out with a
phenotype that was more lemony more
candy more sour and a little bit better
yielding so they just reversed her again
and then that's where we get the e OG 18
from okay great and all that history is
just a personal favorite for for
medicinal use and for all-around just be
great a great smelling plant and a great
looking plant I love the name sweatbands
here's that little sweet skunk dries it
for you my buddy down let everyone know
after you get this hit
[Music]
maybe your seed company and maybe just
sort of talk about the history of really
what brought you does start your
breathing nice oh man I'm telling you
everyone that's hit this week's gun is
done exactly that yesterday Remo went
wow this is a special when he said it as
well he said you know this is the one
where you lighted in a room yeah a lot
of Lies a lot of gimmicks [ __ ]
sure lassic CD industry you bought
exactly the seed industry was pretty
seedy you order her package seeds from
anywhere calling it God but you
germinate it and you get weird looking
plants it don't even look like cannabis
tea I stuff it doesn't germinate you get
seeds that aren't even modelled not even
healthy seeds there's just a lot of
uncontrolled stuff going on and Steve
industry a lot of give me stuff that
just wasn't helping customers internet
patience lot of [ __ ] it's a lot of
time and energy as well when you're
growing from seed and you're looking for
that you know especially to breeding the
amount of time and energy it becomes
incredibly
almost exponential to give someone seeds
for examples oh here have some seeds for
that person to take those seeds and grow
them that's the real gift yeah but I
mean unless you really know these seeds
are stable and they're gonna grow what
generally God is a perfect example
because God by these God there's nothing
like it's just so it's so specific that
those terpenes and you can't to crack
those seeds and not get those that smell
that would hurt a lot
bujji cursed rice if from d4 20k
all melt does that yeah when the quality
they're absolutely a little bit about
sort of the cannabinoid profiles that
you look for I know that you uh you
suffer from cluster my cluster migraines
up with trigeminal autonomics of algae
in the whole word basically it's a
right-sided semi orbital migraine that's
telling the right side of my face is
basically
[Music]
because he's on beta-blockers and just
be like no energy zombie devil yeah
zombie doubt on the medication getting
gastric ulcers Pentagon sirs
continuously because of the heavy
medication the injection so that they
had me on were completely taking me out
I heard we're starting to follow it as
you know I have long hair I'm gonna lose
it
it was my hair was coming out so that
was those were your alternatives to
canvas to this absolutely harmless
lovely plan right here that's able to do
you so much it's the opposite of
harmless it's very full yeah it is
benign it's a benign helpful herb yep we
love it as I'm sure most of you watch
them do as well here's a oh gee coach
tricep trip for you
just boils to I get there
oh yeah ah yes so might head up on the
mountain today I'm not sure I guess it's
Super Bowl Sunday today so we're having
some Super Bowls these are Super Bowls
we sure are super this is our sort of
Super Bowl Super Bowl might take you
guys up the mountain a little later on
and we're waiting in 20 minutes or so
from now one of Phil's tents are gonna
go on so we might take you in there and
just show you a few strains you can talk
put a few you're a few of the
cannabinoid profiles that you seek
perfect you can do I can also go in and
do a green light and a couple of other
ones to see if we can show you guys
something ladies
so the cannabinoid profiles that I look
for well because of my condition it
doesn't just cause the pain it's not the
neurological pain the main thing is the
neuropathic and the neurological
problems and you need to find strains
that directly go for that directly
target that extremely extremely
psychoactive pirates do that but you
also have to look at what's happening
after the headache I'm getting nausea as
developing post-traumatic stress
disorders
bpfv starting to cause a lot of problems
that's just from the horrible experience
of going through the headache and then
being afraid
just after shaking just pandering is
another one gonna happen like eventually
you just go crazy yet an attack well
they call them cluster moderate
migraines for a reason because they come
in clusters you get one that goes goes
away you're sitting there you're sweat
kind of goes away you wipe the sweat and
tears and then the moment you stand up
and breathe the Wallops do again and you
fall down to the floor and that's when
you're kind of shattered and you don't
really know what to do it just keeps
hitting you over and over and over again
gets you to a point where you're just so
worn down and not healthy that you just
you'll basically take anything and
cannabis has always worked but the
doctors for some reason we're just not
did not want to let me use cannabis
solely they felt that I needed to take
all these heavy this heavy medication
and I needed to take pills and
injections and I needed to go take blood
tests and all sorts of body tests all
the time that was just unnecessary I
wasn't sleeping I was 123 pounds I'm now
a hundred and sixty pounds so you must
be more afraid than most at the thought
of losing your ability to grow your own
medicine and to maintain your own
genetic and cannabinoid profile you know
lineage maintaining my genetics and
maintaining my health directly depend on
my ability to grow if I'm not able to
grow legally then there's only in one
other way you don't really have the
luxury of applying to all the different
companies buying herb from all of them
and finding out which one works because
you've already done that well um exactly
like I was I was a part of an article
that was just put out in a local
newspaper and it basically says that we
don't have the money to go through the
trial and error process again with all
these big license producers
I can't go through the 40 strains these
guys have at 8 to 12 dollars a gram and
a long to grams of each to figure out if
they work but I don't I don't I'm just
gonna ask you you're not a plant matter
guy you know we don't on citrate we
don't said quite a few
is garbage very small on this planet
it's only a very small perceptions
everybody
that's why this is so so so little wet
washing those enterprises
attracting something so so so small
something so so so big so you know you
need the fresh plant you need the
availability to have the trim to have a
close trim well that's just the thing
right and of course that's one of you
might want to juice your leaf thank you
know you might really to you from your
stocks is that want to eat the buds you
might want to extract the resin from the
buds and eat that or smoke it or
vaporize it or whatever these are the
options you have when you grow your own
cannabis these are not the options you
have when a licensed production facility
is offering to sell your cannabis bud
only probably I'm guessing not even in
bud form they'll probably brine the
plants down into a powder and sell it
like that I was required by some
standards to they say to get rid of mold
and bacteria
for such exploits clearly there's so
many of us patients are willing to buy
their product right now
I see a place for them don't get me
wrong really see a place nice as
producers you know there's elderly
people there's people with kids that
have that syndrome and stuff they don't
yeah some people don't want to go to the
dispensaries or don't want to grow there
go with the guy down the street that's
kind of maybe screwed them over before
that but at the same time everyone needs
to have the right to chill with their
home in medicine we indirectly in the
Canadian Charter it says we have access
to cannabis in all of its forms and
three
give direct access to so if that's the
whole plant and its leaves producing and
it's trichomes for absolutely and it
buds for tinctures and we'll see toil
exactly for being a breeder I use I use
my mind on viable seeds I think just
like how's the great gardeners yeah
he does he knows about it he didn't see
the highlights of the job I all have
seats on my post every morning it's it's
just one of those things like it gets
into your system
that's it that's my new mantra you need
your endocannabinoid system daily now
that is Wow that's also so G could say
that's Chrissy from Prince George
without D yeah that's D 420k this one I
cleaned that one he cleaned really Oh
so there's a difference great so grab
yourself one there and oh wow dangerous
might want to go pointy I think I left
it a little dirty on the other end but
oh and it's just stuck together
it hasn't been pressed yeah I know it's
like that's like horrible Howard you
have to kind of shave it I'm scared
yeah it's so lovely looking so these
producers definitely for about 90% like
I commented on your Facebook the other
day but 90% of these produce there
90% of the people will benefit from
these producers there's a large portion
of the population that will do really
really really well of the of the city
population and people that have more
money that are living in suburban areas
though they're able to afford that and
they have the luxury exactly that will
work well for them but the people that
are a little bit more rural the people
that are living in more stretched out
communities outside of the Greater
Vancouver area Toronto Manitoba stuff
like that we need the ability to grow
because we're so far away from
dispensaries and we're so far away from
the city and the hostel and bustling
where these productions are normally
happening and designated to happen in
these agriculture areas we live nowhere
in here where these are going to be
happening so everything has to be done
by mail and we're sitting here in the
woods suffering from a condition waiting
for a package by the mail that might not
make it on time there I mean you could
break it down even as simple as the
disconnect of getting a medicine that's
just you know potentially grounding
irradiated and like grown by someone you
don't know and you never as opposed to
your plants that you've collected that
you've acquired through your own
personal bio acid
that you've grown that you've loved I
mean anyone that's ever growing cannabis
can attest that not only is it great for
the fact that it gets you cannabis resin
at the end of the disciple but it gets
you excited to grow and most people that
grow cannabis will also be inspired to
grow some tomatoes or some cucumbers
do you just start growing so it's
another one of those things that should
always have the right to grow we're
gonna with that said we're gonna pop a
few more bowls so we're here with film
I'm checking out one of his sweatband
tents
so what is this a four by four by four
six inchee movement for six and change
these are sweat pants
tell us what you liked about this plan
well this is the OG 18 West Coast Sour
Diesel but basically just the best of
both of those worlds I wanted to take a
really really strong sour sour diesel
and cross it in with a few leek m-miss
of the og 18 and just kind of play off
whether those on each other and create
something that was perfect for my
condition that started starts on the top
of your head and goes down to the tip of
your body and just goes to every single
tip of your fingers and your toes hence
the name swept and it starts up here
goes all the way down for your whole
entire body so how much how many more
weeks to the east have I'll have about
four and a half five I take the swept
into like a leverage well
especially I usually pollinate a couple
of branches for bat frothing like this
one right here is pollinated about four
or five years ago it's a semi swollen
Kalin's isn't it it's a little seeds so
once I pollinate it's about five or six
weeks until the seeds on the chair and I
usually pollinate around week three or
four when there's a nice nice flower
clusters already forming right so yeah
so about 11 or 12 weeks usually and that
especially with the push heavy strains
think of dominant strains you let it go
that extra week nice amber heads you add
to the salary tones you bring out more
flavors more sedative with that a
stronger some would say a stronger her
but you let it go a little bit longer
right
especially for neurological diseases
stress pain sleeping anxiety you might
want something a little bit more
sedative so letting it letting letting
go a little bit longer achieves that for
you awesome man well you know thanks for
sharing the information with us where
can people check you out online true
genetics right now on Instagram we just
have an Instagram page we'll have a kick
up right away and a website in the
springtime we'll have five or six
strains stabilized and ready to go by
June testers if you want to get a hold
of us through an Instagram more than
willing to take new testers to get
things ready for everyone to have
strains like this for everyone
soon awesome dude awesome awesome
see you soon again on bubble man's world
peace
all right pill just decided to show us a
sleeping room he's got the green light
we're gonna check out what what they
flower
this is Hannah
[Music]
oh wow that is the silver rock star from
that man sees this one we selected
because it just stinks like blue cheese
dressing
specifically rotten as rotten as it
could ever be but lovely at the same
time
and if it definitely it can be pulled
down in nine weeks if you want that's
why it looks a little bit further along
than the rest of the room is it can't be
pulled down but again for that extra
aroma and set it up effective just
stinky stinky stinky smell you let it go
as long as the plant can
[Music]
- campinas of the Saturday with that one
shot where they've been
awesome there Kevin
[Music]
you