[Music]
all right welcome to both man's world
I'm here in my somewhat pre-spring clean
up garage and I have received a most
incredible package in the mail I have
received my peer pressure my I guess
they have a particular name on this one
this one is called I saw it on about
along the long peak so check this out
this is one of the peer pressure rosin
presses that of course if you watch the
rosin episode of hash Church 2.0 I
believe it was Eric who came on or maybe
it was Josh one of the other maybe both
they came on to talk about their unit
they've got the little unit that amps up
the pressure on the side they've got the
recipes that you can program in it's
really quite a nicely advanced unit you
can tell it it's a rosin press not
started by cannabis aficionados not
started by welders but started by
engineers maybe a combination of the
three in fact so what we're going to do
is we're gonna do a little unboxing here
so why don't you guys stay tuned for the
uncrating first of all great-looking
crate when I spend as much money as I
spent on this unit they retail for about
8,000 US you want to see it show up in a
proper package you don't want to be
worried about the integrity of the
shipping so it looks like so far that
they've really done a good job
Booya
nice that the screws come right out it's
not like a difficult battle to get them
out spoke too soon actually I spoke too
soon again so really excited to get
pressing with this unit and try it out
of course I love for those of you
they're gonna ask right away what about
your sasquatch I love my Sasquatch unit
I use them all the time but one of the
things that this unit really sold me on
was the fact that you could program you
know your your batches into the unit
which is a big deal if you're if you've
got a person who you're paying to really
know this stuff but maybe they don't
have the time to do all the pressing and
they need to retrain some people a human
like this is wonderful because you can
retrain with with the programs you know
you've got up to 30 programs that this
thing will take and they've all got
numbers and you could you know program
for moisture content for press time for
different factors in the melt or in the
resin in the amount of time that you
press for the heat that you press for
all of these things are going to be
fairly important and they're the subtle
nuances well look at this right off the
bat this looks great I'm gonna bring the
camera over and show you guys what I'm
looking at here okay
so here we go right off the bat you got
some plates we got some pressure some
screens a giant oil slick make a nice
job packaging it up it's pretty pretty
heavy for sure got some scoops well they
even threw a little butter cutter in
which is quite nice I don't know if you
guys have seen these units but they are
very nice they come in handy got all
sorts of different brackets dual
pressure tubing so I guess there's a
little bit of pudding putting things
together man they even sent a really
nice skillet tool I'm picking up the
resins so I guess what we'll do is we
pull this stuff out and we'll pack it
over to the left here and then we'll
gain access to what what's inside okay
there we go all right
makes it nice and easy packing it
exactly how it was here oh it's a
different size peer pressure rosin press
rosin bag accessory alright the quick
flip interesting alright ok one more
level has been opened and I of course
want to show you guys what's going on in
here looks like we got t-shirts t-shirts
and of course how rosin is pressed well
they got a nice amount of literature
here peer pressure Pikes Peak and the
long speech so we have the long peak
here I believe this is the long peak the
unit that we're looking at ten by three
plates with dual pressure control 100%
60 by 61 aircraft grade aluminum heat
plate assemblies premium heat rods 60%
more available force than the Pikes Peak
v2 coupled with unparalleled pressure
control with the dual pressure system
pure pressures industry-leading press
wear full-color LCD touchscreen
technology press wear offers total
control of eurozone extraction process
including the ability to save and store
up to 30 preset recipes with multiple
pressure stages premium quality
components backed by industry leader
customer service engineered for long
term durability and reliability the
longs peak is truly built to last eight
tons of force pneumatic oilless and
maintenance-free cylinder save up to 30
preset recipes built and colorado
touchscreen LCD
sounds pretty good to me i'm looking
forward to getting in here i'm gonna put
the camera back on the tripod and we're
gonna further open up the package here
[Applause]
love the professional mists of the
packaging on this unit he's absolutely
stellar she's really well
well done here diggin Anna beefing but
guess what I'm not gonna look I'm not
gonna luck all right let me open this up
a little bit more because for some
reason I'm Way cut off ah there we go
there we go there we go
all right so okay well I suspect
[Music]
all right here's our unit let's open it
[Applause]
all right sucker
well she is packaged so beautifully
blown away the product a even made it in
the first place but just it someone
would sell such a nice product and not
packaged it up the best to take
[Music]
all right so I think what we're gonna do
is lay it down on these all right add
the unit that goes on the side of it not
too much to deal with
looks like I've already even already got
plates that they sent me they're just
merely extra
all right so we got our long peaks
pressure gauge that goes in on the side
guessing these are pretty good there's
one there's two okay we're gonna get the
allen key out for this little guy we'll
make it happen here in a few minutes all
right I also wanted to show you guys
this I ordered some parchment from these
guys and check out the professionalism
on these parchments labs this is awesome
there's literally like a thousand pieces
of parchment in here pre-cut perfectly
to fit into the press and so we're gonna
get that ready right now hey guys
welcome to bubble man's world I'm here
with Cory or from from ACCA alternative
cannabis consumption awareness boom I
don't know if you guys saw but we did a
little thing about six months ago yeah
in around six months so yeah right well
we did a little demo it was live I was
kind of on a google chat skype type
thing and Cory ran the process in front
of a group of people all those safe
extraction methods and rosin pressing is
definitely one of the top things on our
list for safe extraction exactly so this
is the peer pressure that the long peaks
long's peak press from peer pressure and
man we just did a little test run I know
it's dark but we really wanted to share
this with you we didn't want to wait
till tomorrow so we got the unit set up
we got the beautiful touch screen right
here we've got the plate seating up to
210 top and bottom and I'm gonna show
you what the camera up close actually
why don't I do it right now show you
right this second what we got
going on here what they've got in this
this press fraud the computer yeah it's
really cool really well done alright so
here's the screen that we're dealing
with and so you can heat up your plates
by simply clicking on that and going
save and that will save save your plate
at the temperature that you're putting
in I made a little mistake there so I'm
just gonna fix it get it back to 210
we've got a recipe that we're running
here we're gonna put that on and we're
gonna put that on we're gonna run recipe
number five yeah here it is you can see
flour 10 grams on the two by nine bags
115 microns medium pressure medium speed
sorry with 16% humidity or moisture
content you can see our air pressure is
kinda low over here but we haven't
turned it on and then also I want to
show you another part of this press
that's really cool which is on their
website as well they've got the safety
emergency stop right here that you can
just hammer down and that stops the
whole process and then they've got the
dual buttons one on the left and one on
the right and this allows you you hold
these down for five seconds and that
engages the press it doesn't move the
plates parcei but what it does is it
engages the press and then this
particular one also has plate speeds how
fast and how slow they're gonna move and
then this is the real doozy right here
this is the dual unit this is the amping
up of the pressure we're coming in at
about 25 to 30 psi on the Left we're
coming in at about a hundred on the
right and you can probably hear a tiny
little bit of a leak i didn't have the
teflon tape but this is something you're
gonna want to do if you're setting this
up I can feel it leaking right there
just a tiny little bit should be okay
and this is the little toggle shift that
allows us to go back from a over to B so
this is where most of the pressure is so
we're gonna you'll see us using the
toggle to the right more often than the
left and I guess Jay is over here
preparing the flowers and what we are
using is
some beautiful beautiful where is my
bike so you guys know this one very well
the solid solid solid fielder right is
so nice is the unique European profile
with a good yield right we flipped the
bag inside out already yeah beautiful so
we I didn't have the tool I was gonna
show you guys this really cool tool that
these guys came out with flip a bag
another bag for them so they've got this
very simple simple tool that I'm sure
anyone can do I'm gonna shut that door
there sits inside out well it's you got
the seam on you put your tube in push
your other tube in the bottom perfect
and then that just flips the bag just
like that and you want to use that tool
to press out the corners to make sure
that they're coming out and then you
won't get any product caught in that
seam that's really beautiful
then on top of that they have these cool
little funnels that fit right into their
bags and I'm telling you this might look
simple and not that impressive I was
stoked when I watched the 10 grams of
powdery bud just flow right into no
problem we're gonna get back to this
here in a second this peer-pressure unit
is just beautiful super stoked on it
long Peaks for those of you interested
in finding out more you can check it out
at peer pressure comm and this is the I
love it when you go through and you can
see the watery view through the place
that is great you got a little parchment
holder here that you can use if you
decide to we didn't use it the first
time we just had a couple of magnets
that we used but yeah very very cool
little unit of course this unit has
these feet on the end of it but it also
has some other ones that go on and put
feet here as well as screwing into the
back feet so you can move this whole
unit down to lay down on its side to use
as the elysian research and the gorilla
press
using the gravity aid as as an extra
added bonus so this press does both
we're gonna be using it this way today
the press is heated and ready to go and
I guess well why don't I set up the
tripod right on the plates yeah let's
see see what we get you there