foreign
[Music]
hey what's going on everybody Welcome to
Bubble man's world quick little unboxing
video it is a Saturday kind of a day off
for me today but I received this from
Funk dot art Steve on Instagram he owns
a company called uh at hash head
Outfitters I'll put that link in the
description of this video and he was
kind enough to send me a box this is one
of his stickers right here you can see
if you recognize this hash head
Outfitters and uh yeah just gonna crack
this box open
really quick
and kind of see what we got going on
from him so I'll hold it off to the side
I'm using my desk as a stand-up desk
these days a little bit healthier on the
back not that my back is in terrible
shape but it's nice to have the uh the
standing ability with the with the
stand-up desk so first up is this kind
of cool
um corduroy hat so we'll open this up
if you do want to see I like how it
comes everything is sealed in sealed
bags this reminds me of back in the day
Harvest keeper bags packing packing lbs
out so right off the bat we've got some
pretty cool stickers I'm a big sticker
guy so I'm always happy there's one of
his classics
we got the hasher instead of thrasher I
think that's super cool I really like
that I hope Thrasher doesn't give you a
hard time about that
and then uh yeah
I don't even know what this says but I
like it it's a Halloween something about
smoking hash
stock Crush smoke hash I don't know it's
cool I like it uh let's check out the
Hat though
oh yeah this is some old school trippy
corduroy action
gonna be going to see Harry Mack tonight
myself maybe I'll wear a new hat
oh yeah oh yeah
different
I like it I like
I like they actually threw a couple of
these in he threw another one in in a
gray color probably gray is more my
color
but you know what sometimes it's cool to
try something outside of your comfort
zone and this blue is pretty cool
bunch more stickers in here same three
except that one that I couldn't read was
in a different color
stack
Kush smoke hash stat Kush smoke hash
you be the judge maybe I'm getting old
yeah there we go there's that and
another hasher I really like this hasher
I want to try this gray one on
because why not
I'll tell you one thing these hats are
cozy cozy cozy cozy on the head really
cool hats it's got his little hash head
Outfitters logo on the back definitely
go give this gentleman a follow oh okay
this is my style right here this is I
mean I love these these two are super
cool and I'm definitely going to be
wearing them uh if not
um maybe I'll have a contest and and
give one of them away this one right
here
Is My Jam This Is My Jam this is a
friggin nice hat
oh yeah hasher and I really love that
logo on the back
probably could go with putting this one
more up
to three felt a tiny little bit loose
but it could be wrong oh no
three of this now that is a hat you'll
see me wearing
maybe on hash church this Sunday which
is tomorrow 9
00 a.m got a great group linking us up
on there so come check it out this is
the Cotton snapback hasher hat
of course he hooked me up with another
one of these and another one of these
hasher you know being a skateboarder
growing up in the 80s early 90s Thrasher
obviously a huge brand never thought to
turn it into hashers I think it's pretty
cool and then oh this right here this is
the poundage this is the big one right
here this is the one that uh this is the
one I'm most excited about I won't lie
not that I don't love getting stickers
and hats but I always love getting
myself a nice hoodie and this hoodie
really feels proper another sticker
another hasher
and uh yeah this is a proper hoodie holy
smokes quality it's got the hasher right
on the front
you can see that right there nice and
embroidered really nice quality on this
this is quality and then right on the
back I think this is styley too this is
proper let's give it a shot right now
get it on
all right
not too shabby always stoked on getting
some new
oh yeah that's nice this is a thick
hoodie this is a winter hoodie oversized
head which I love the oversized hoodie
part
throw it on with a cap no problem I'm
hashing out dude I want to thank Steve a
lot for the opportunity to send this he
is of course a sponsor this year at
Legends of hash uh which is happening in
Los Angeles downtown Los Angeles
December 2nd and 3rd there's going to be
a dinner evening on the second and a
brunch on the third unfortunately all
the sponsorships and the tickets have
been sold out but if you want to get in
touch with us at info Legends of
hashish.com to find out about next
year's event or the next event that
we're having maybe even uh in in early
part of 2023 maybe not in Los Angeles
but maybe somewhere else
um yeah and otherwise really stoked on
this Steve go give them a follow you can
follow him at func dot a r t s t e v e
on Instagram you can also find his
company at hash head Outfitters that's
h-a-s-h
e a d o u t f i t t e r s
thank you so much for sending this stuff
totally loving it and uh I'll make a
point on supporting your company here in
the near future and I hope that you guys
can as well because it sounds like Steve
is a pretty awesome guy uh otherwise
let's say uh May the full mouth bless
your bowl sooner than later