[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
it has been a while since I've posted a
video let me tell you I have been busy I
have videos compiled from the Caribbean
in Jamaica and I have a bunch of videos
from my recent trip to Colombia that I'm
going to be sharing with you today but I
was so excited I like to keep my videos
in order but today I got a package so
that I've been waiting for for a while
thanks to high integrity glass art for
turning me on to the wonderful people at
high-temp Tech USA so you can follow
them at instagram at temp tech USA i'll
put it over the screen here and this is
a really cool little unit in regards to
in dabbing and temperature so obviously
we've had these electric nails for quite
some time now which is great it creates
perfect temperature but it's not quite
convenient for traveling so there's all
sorts of little different pipes out on
the market from the puff Co where you
can do your your your dabbing you know
while you kind of go and it's convenient
I still love my puff Co and my other
convenient dabbing tools but I love my
banger and my glass pipe the most so
this is kind of gonna be a multi-part
walkthrough it's an open box of a temp
tack of course we'll be promoting a DC
glass cleaner and I'm also going to be
promoting on this particular go one of
the XL Grail banners from JP as well as
his incredible see if I can get that up
to you guys a little bit look at this
how great this stuff is beautiful carb
cap fits right in there this is not the
core reactor it doesn't have the big
piece of quartz in the bottom but it is
an excel Grail there is the Holy Grail
right there can see your right through
it blink blink anyway I've had this for
I bet you over a year since JP and Wendy
sent me the Terps slurper the core
reactor and this XL Grail huge apologies
to you guys we're not putting this video
sooner you can check them out at Toro
glass on Instagram and I will put that
up on the screen as well and I'm finally
able to get to this
one of the main reasons I haven't wanted
to do this is because I've been on the
timing game I've been timing the banger
which works great when you're by
yourself obviously most of you are aware
of you know heating up your banger with
your torch or a certain amount of time
usually 10 to 20 seconds letting it cool
for 40 to 55 seconds some of you guys
are now onto the cold starts which is
much how the puffs cope uh pipe hits you
can do cold starts with this as well but
this unit this unit right here which I
say we open right away I'm very excited
about I've only used it once I used it
over with with high integrity and was
just completely impressed yet with
everything about the unit reached out to
the company and said how do I get my
hands on one and they were like we'll
send you one so huge shout out to temp
tech USA I know you probably have
companies all the time trying to get
units out of you and whatnot but I'm
very happy that you managed to send me
one I'm very excited about the prospect
of using it right now you know this unit
measures the temperature of your banger
it's a very cool laser thermometer built
into this little stylee box that they've
produced not this particular one but the
box inside the box and will show you
very simply how it works temp tech USA
there we go there's the picture and I'll
show you what this little guy does
because it is very very cool see ah
there we go
there we go no need to rip I when they
sent me a blue one how beautiful is that
my son's favorite color they'll be very
excited not that he'll be using the temp
tech but he just loves all things blue
so nice packaging put away nice and
secure definitely doesn't feel like
there's any problems with this unit
often when you open a box on something
sometimes you feel it and it's shaking
and it's made
sounds it's not supposed to to make this
thing feels very solid so let's see if
they hooked me up with a battery they
did they did hook me up with a little
9-volt battery that goes right in the
back door right there and this it's the
unit there's the tech temp USA so you've
got your switch on the back you switch
that you can set your temperatures right
here I guess I'm not sure exactly
because I haven't looked at the guy why
don't we read the guide and find out
exactly what these buttons do this is
what an open box is all about I want it
to be the experience that you yourself
would have if you bought one of these
so the specs our temperature range is
between minus 50 to a thousand and
twenty degrees Fahrenheit so between
minus 10 and 549 sell Celsius we're
never gonna go that high let's be honest
accuracy is between plus and minus two
percent that's great I can handle that
response time is about 0.8 seconds
emissivity emissivity it says see the
table on the back page for emissivity
values of some common materials a more
comprehensive emissivity towel table can
be found at temp tech org pages
emissivity emissivity table I'm not sure
what that means but I'm interested to
learn about it distance the spot ratio
twelve to one operating temperature
between 32 and 122 degrees Fahrenheit
storage temperature between minus 4 to
122 and of course required battery is
nine volt now it says the further the
target the larger the test area is as
the distance between the tenth the test
object and the temp tech increases the
size of the area being measured also
increases below is a sample ratio using
the formula used to calculate the
distance to spot ratio interesting so
it's got distance the spot ratio times
test object size and inches maximum
measures distance in inches
eg 12 to 1 times 2 equals mass maximum
measure distance of 24 so that just
shows you how far away you need to have
it so
let's go with our setup here install the
battery and move the power switch to on
all right we'll do that
to set emissivity move the power switch
this one's not actually turning on move
the power switch seven to the off so let
me see what we got here well if the
power switch seven to the off well I
think what happened is is they put a
battery in but they turned it on and
shift it on so the battery is actually
completely dead so what I will do is I
will go find a battery and I will be
right back this is all about the open
box experience right you got to figure
it out it says to possession the sensor
under the target object when temperature
readings are complete with the power
switch the opposition of the scanning
will stop additionally the data holder
indicator and last temperature reading
will be displayed to decibel additional
adjustments while the temp tech is
peridot and press the Fahrenheit Celsius
button to toggle between Celsius and
Fahrenheit or press the backlight button
to toggle the backlight on or off it
should be protected from thermal shock
allow 30 minutes for it to stabilize
before use induction heaters arc welders
an electromagnetic fields objects of
higher temperature so I'm gonna go find
a battery we're gonna get this thing
operational and I'll be right back my
apologies to the company they actually
put a brand new battery in here but they
said it just on top so the battery
wasn't wasn't actually plugged in the
battery is sealed and will require
opening so good on the company for not
doing what I thought they might have
done which was potentially shipped me a
dead battery it's often the way you
think when you open these products you
kind of constantly I know what happened
what happened it's not working and it's
it's a true open box experience I didn't
want to give you one of those you know
polished up everything's working
perfectly I want you to see exactly the
experience that I had which I have to
say was certainly not too bad so we're
gonna go
this put that little battery in there
thumbs up nice and easy close the door
and now we're gonna turn this on so hold
all right install the battery remove the
power to set emissivity move the power
switch seven to be off position then
press the function buttons three to get
to the emissivity adjustment screen I
don't think I'm gonna be messing with
that screen at all I will use there we
go let's see I want to go b2 I'm once
Celsius but I want to go to Fahrenheit
so there we go said Fahrenheit we're at
seventy two point three percent it's
funny because I'm Canadian and obviously
we use Celsius up in Canada but when it
comes to dabbing it's very much been an
American thing that has inspired us with
the electric nails and so on so we've
gotten very used to operating with a
under Fahrenheit rather than Celsius so
I know Fahrenheit I like to hit around
550 to 575
I've got my excel Grail in the bong I
haven't talked too much about this but I
have some absolutely beautiful beautiful
bubble hash from concentrated X this is
120 micron wedding cake trying to take
some macro photographs for you so you
can see that up close and then we also
have some really lovely strawberry
banana look at that quality this is the
sixth star when you're hitting the six
star the last thing you want to do is
hit it in a way that it's too hot I'm
loving the idea of being able to use
this thing and not have to you know it's
as simple as this right here actually
that's how we're gonna use it we're
gonna just put it right like that
and first we'll heat up the Banger
probably only for about 10 seconds I
used to heat it up for 20 but there's no
real reason to go much past if I can get
it up to 700 degrees and then let it
drop 50 to 100 degrees
or you know 150 degrees I'm sitting
right at my perfect temperature so we're
gonna simultaneously try out the temp
tech the excel Grail from JP the
concentrated X full melt then we're
gonna clean with the DC glass cleaner I
wish I had some glob mops because I
could promote that company too and of
course shout out to oil slick for our
oil slick silicon that the pipe is
sitting on and I guess shut up too big
shot from blazer as well so quite a few
different tools that are required for
this particular methodology of dabbing
whatever you've got use it maybe join me
I will say that one of the main reasons
I haven't used this is if you see my DC
banger that I've used see how cloudy
it's gotten from not being able to clean
it properly now that's not necessarily
Chazz as much as it's just not being
able to clean running out of DC glass
cleaner not having q-tips and not always
knowing the right temperature you know
these banners change you get used to one
banger you end up with a different
banger while I traveled I had the hotbox
mister hotbox banner which was double
the depth of this and half the thickness
well because if you had held heat very
differently and I found that it was at
30 seconds or less I could be hitting it
without having to let it cool for for 40
or 50 seconds so these are all different
things that you have to worry about when
you don't have a temp Tech USA we've got
one here today so why don't we get on it
I'm excited here we go
oh I don't have a damper on the table
let me go get a dabbler real quick
actually after those few seconds let's
see what our so that's six hundred and
thirty degrees six hundred twenty six
degrees how much I heated that up was
almost perfect so we're gonna have to
redo that a little bit I'm gonna go grab
a dabber because I think getting some of
this wonderful hash out of the jar and
into the banger is going to be pretty
essential so once again bear with me
alright and one more company to shout
out D nail for the dabber here so this
is a nice little dabber that fits right
on their halo dish and actually fits
perfectly on my DC XL banger as well
we're gonna be using the JP Grail and I
think very hard hash to get out I often
find that you want to cover the top of
the rim as you're digging around because
it can fly out and end up everywhere
worst case scenario in your eye I have
on the other hand broken off a nice
little piece so we can get a nice little
dab nothing too big often I get asked
hey why are you taking such small dabs
why are you why don't you hold it in
long enough why don't you listen I damn
how I doubt I can hit 50 dabs in a day
if I want I can hit five and you have
the same freedom as well so hit the dabs
that make you the most comfortable
whether those are micro Deb's cuz you're
new at this or whether they're half gram
dabs because you've been doing it
forever this is the spice of life that
cannabis offers us so just do what you
like I'm gonna take a nice decent dab
out of a brand new banger so I'm very
excited the mothership Kline is as clean
as a whistle so let's try this again
shall we
keep that banger up for about 10 seconds
all right drop that right over there
700 800 degrees I got that up too it's
now at 766 750 748 734 so you can see it
going down so pretty fast so probably
around 650 I'm gonna hit it this is
gonna cool it down substantially and
I'll probably get that 550 575 hit so we
are at 650 let's do this
absolutely perfect temp and now my
banger is at 463 degrees Fahrenheit Wow
incredible flavor on that strawberry
banana 120 micron bubble hash shout out
to you concentrator decks for finding
that phyno shout out to DNA for putting
it out there and just shut up for me for
puffing it right now and in being in
full enjoyment level level 10 so we got
a nice perfect perfect temperate the
banger will be very easy to clean thanks
to the no Chas aspect of hitting the
temp tech hitting it at that perfect
temperature we're really gonna be able
to experiment and find out what is the
temperature where Chas occurs is it in
the 700 is it in the 800 degree is it a
particular quality of oil this is just
cleaning perfectly which is you know how
you want to see a brand new banger clean
when you've just hit it for the first
time well I just it's cringe worthy when
we make the bangers you know get jazzed
and get that foggy kind of look to them
so I will be a little bit insane about
cleaning this just because cleanliness
is next to godliness
let's commence Sam has always said and
yeah eventually your cleaning and you'll
see your your q-tips are no longer
getting dirty beautiful
so there's a nice clean banger you ready
for another rip and the temp tech USA is
is a great success I mean how sweet is
that just to have something that's this
light and portable uses a battery
obviously I'm probably gonna want to
carry it in its box and make sure that
it's secured I don't want it banging
around and put the back of my bag I
could probably break this thing pretty
easily and it seems a little bit
delicate but in regards to a tool that
is available that's not a big
thermometer that you have to hold a
laser thermometer in your hole I think
this company has done a really cool job
fitting a niche that no other company
has fit and of course we've seen the
Tochi which is the big heat gun inside
the unit that heats up the banger more
like the beam but quite different from
this I think this particular product is
going to have great success in the
cannabis industry I have been super
excited to use it when I first saw it I
just thought what is this high integrity
glass art being the connoisseur that he
is I left an open mind and I thought
after one sink single-use that this was
a tool that I absolutely would require
and need to have so I guess turning it
off after use is not a bad idea it says
once you're done on the instructions to
to turn this the power switch off once
once it's done scanning so maybe it's
simple to turn on and off each time I'll
learn more of these simple nuances of
the unit as I use it over time but I
just absolutely wanted to share how cool
it was with you and in the meantime do
long you know a video long in waiting
and long and coming for the Jaypee Toro
Grail I do still have the core reactor
and I still have the Terp slurper that
you're gonna be seeing videos from and
then I'll probably do a video maybe with
flab and some super sick glass where we
have all three of them and both of us
hit each one and kind of give our sort
of what we think of that of the hit this
core reactor hit beautifully it's very
big I personally love a large surface
area it's got the ground glass on the
bottom with the Grail into it which
gives it more of his
when the oils on there which also
seemingly made it a little easier to
clean and what a beautiful carb cap this
is one of the nicest I've personally had
a nice big hole on the top that you can
seal right out and then it's got that
little you know bent nozzle at the end
that is going to give you your full
spinning and ratio I think this would
work quite well with the Sapphire
comments that I got from v-mail
haven't tried yet but I'll throw in a
couple in the meantime I'm probably
gonna continue to puff here and enjoy
some of these vibes but thank you guys
for watching and thanks for supporting
companies that I believe in temp tech
USA is one to watch for DC glass cleaner
obviously most of you will already know
about that concentrated X bubble hash
maker and JP from the for the toro grail
thank you all for making this video
possible and I guess I'll finish it with
my most classic may the foam L to bless
your bowl sooner than later
[Music]