foreign
[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world it is I the bubble man and I'm
here today to do a little unboxing video
got a little bit of let me see if I
can't clean the lens here
doing a couple of little three dots you
know what we welcome those dots
okay so today I wanted to do a quick
little video for you maybe we'll start
with a dab because that always seems to
be a good idea we've got some beautiful
dogs right now
um all sorts of really lovely things I
think I'm gonna hit this
little
little good Goods
okay see if I can't move that back a
little bit okay I think I can get a
little bit more height on the camera now
sorry for my sketchiness there we go
all right here we are so yeah I got this
box right here we're gonna do a quick
unboxing video this is a really cool new
company that I found here in Canada so
it might not be very good for my
American listeners but I'm telling you
from the Canadian perspective this is
really cool I live in a home that does
not offer delivery really at all there's
very little delivery that comes to my
house and So lately I've been looking
into a couple of different companies to
try and find food that can get delivered
to my house and that's what this box is
so we're gonna do a quick dab
a very quick dab and we'll shout out all
the crew Nephilim glass for the marble
setup JP and Toro for the terp slurper
and Dustin Revere for the drop
shout out to all of those guys and I
guess we better thank blazer for the
torch
so many so many different groups to
thank
um oh I might have to hit that up a
little bit more we'll see what happens
here
so this is some hash Ross and I'm about
to hit this is some strawberry banana
hash rosin Just Gonna Take A little dab
not looking to get completely torn right
this second all right
wow that was almost like uh
a low temp dab hit it up a little bit
more
very light
that's what you call a tiny tiny little
dab but really
I'm mostly just to dab to make it seem
appropriate for this channel because
this channel is full-blown dab content
but I do want to show you guys this okay
so I just got this
this is the general
Pizza
assembly this company is called GA Pizza
Gap pizza.com if you want to check them
out so like I said I live in a place
where very few people deliver it's
ridiculous and so I ordered from this
company you can go check them out at
g-a-p-i-z-z-a.com and this is how the
Box arrives right a little bit of a lift
here
a little bit of dry ice right maybe do a
little sifting later with that we'll see
be careful when you're touching dry ice
it can burn and hurt your fingers that
was close right there so here's what we
got inside of here we got these
beautiful Italian style thin crust
pizzas this one is the cheese Wizard
it's got provolone mozzarella Grana
padona padana and pecorino Romano just
for this pizza right here so I ordered
two of these ones because I thought
I need two of those
then I got three of these this is the
Mila Margarita this has mozzarella Grana
padona and basil and that is that
particular Pizza in a nutshell I
actually got three of these because
Margarita is actually my pizza so
there's three of those
and then finally I got these plant-based
pizzas this one is a plant-based
mozzarella pumpkin seed parmesan and
fresh basil so this has no dairy in it
it's just a kind of a plant-based vegan
pizza if you will and I actually ended
up getting three of these as well I
don't have to pull them all out I'm sure
so
eight pizzas in total cost me 80
Canadian dollars with delivery they
delivered them right to my door and I do
not live uh in a close area uh for for
delivery so I was really stoked on this
and I figured you know what it's not
exactly cannabis uh content but let's be
honest we all know one of the major side
effects of inhaling cannabinoids and
terpenes
is ordering pizzas and now if you're in
Canada anyway you might be able to do it
in America I'm not saying you can't but
I know that this is a Canadian company
or at least that I was able to order
from them here in Canada so go check it
out the next unboxing video I'll be
doing for food is going to be the salad
company that I found they are called
inspired
go.ca or.com you can Google that and
check it out and in the meantime I'm
gonna take another dab because that
first dab
it wasn't much let's be honest there was
not much of a dab there so we're gonna
put our second marble set together here
keep this little guy
little guy and dab it down
it's been a while since I've actually
done many videos of course I've been
doing the Merlin getting baked with uh
getting cooked with Merlin we will be
back for more episodes that is for sure
happening hash church is picking up
steam I've got a mushroom conversation
that I want to start having a mushroom
dialogue I'm not sure what I'm gonna
call that show but it's going to end up
on the YouTube channel as well
and uh yeah so keep an eye out for all
of that content and then these little
unboxing videos of something that's not
actually a product that someone sent me
but actually products that I myself have
ordered so you know the pizzas and then
the salads as well were just spectacular
I couldn't believe how fresh they
arrived um we ate them all before I was
able to do any type of unboxing video
but shout out to Dom and Max from Up in
Smoke because those guys live in an area
where I can actually get my salads
delivered to they won't deliver to my
house so it is nice to have good friends
like those guys and it's just one of the
many reasons why I like to support those
guys at Up in Smoke in Vancouver if you
guys have any cannabis needs and you
want to go to the store to buy hash or
flour and you want to buy it from guys
that actually have deep knowledge uh Max
and Dom are the guys you want to go see
foreign
much better
that's it so you guys can't really see
this but off camera I am dunking so I've
got my little isopropanol vial right
here I don't have my Banger basket yet
from Mike lagru but I am a waiting one
and it's just a quick clean full dunk of
the Banger and I'll be honest
I haven't tried it yet with DC glass
cleaner I will for certain do that but
um there's just no way to clean these
tarp slurpers with with um with Q-tips
if you hit them enough little bits of
resin end up getting locked away and uh
it just won't stay new and these are so
valuable and and so precious to me uh
that I am just down with taking the
utmost delicate care of them and so
that's what's happening there in the
meantime I don't think there's much else
to say
toaster oven and see how well they taste
I you know from everything I've seen
they look and taste delicious for now
may the full male bless your bowl sooner
than later I may go cook a pizza and let
you know how it is
[Music]
no no no no no no no