hey guys I wanted to give you a little
bit of a update on my Jamaican my trippy
whal phytol laxi growing three leaves
out of each stem instead of one and even
growing two over here separate branches
out of one
leaf anyway just wanted to give you the
update I have finally taken a cutting
off of this plant it'll be the first
cutting that I have ever taken I took it
right there and I've actually got
it growing safely back here here this
one right here that I'm pointing at so
we have uh reer man's Harmony then we
have the Jamaican Lamb's bread hybrid we
have Remo's UBC chemo cush and then
finally at the end we have Dr atomics
Northern Lights so there's the update
just wanted to tell you guys about that
and uh hopefully I'm going to come back
from Jamaica that plant's going to be
rooted and healthily growing and my
mother's going to be bushy and I'll be
able to start sharing it with my friend
friends like Doc Atomic and Remo and
Matt Johnny B so yeah thanks for
watching that's the update we'll see you
soon on Bubble man's world