[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
I'm sitting here at the University of
West Indies on the campus just in front
of the Usain Bolt the track that he
obviously practice on for many years and
helped him win some gold medals in
running obviously one of the fastest man
on the planet and I guess I'm here to
talk to you guys a little bit about the
standardizations that are going to be
coming to Jamaica in your future and how
we're going to be able to test the
cannabis that all the local farmers and
all the companies that come in and make
their attempts at growing whether
they're using local farmers or whether
they're bringing people in I'm not sure
I know we have the plans on doing a
little bit of both obviously using as
many local people as possible one of the
worries is standardizations and one of
the machines right now that's being
promoted as the new standard in Jamaica
is the quanta cam from steep hill and it
is quite a unique machine it's really
neat you can grind up the herb and it
takes this little photograph and
moisture and it sort of has a reference
of the product that's photographing and
it references the many many types I
don't know if they've done a thousand
tests for different strains with gas
chromatograph or LLL CP or whatever it
is liquid chromatograph I'm not sure
which ones they did but it's basically a
reference model it's the beginning of
what we will get to in the future but in
the meantime at the University of West
Indies they have all the machines on
point here on campus that would be used
in regards to standardizing the medicine
and being able to test for microbials
molds THC potent percentages cannabinoid
percentages and then also stripping down
and breaking the terpene and turpin
terpenoid contents down and of course
there's even mono terpenoids and Cesc
with terpenoids and the science gets
more and more and more complex the
deeper you get that is one of the main
reasons crd and you can has signed a
contract in an MoU with the university
west indies because we know that they're
the people for the job they have all the
students available they have
the machines available and all it really
is is a little bit of a synergistic
relationship of us bringing a few key
people in to help train the for instance
the proton h-nmr that is being used here
they have two of them a 250 megahertz as
well as a 500 megahertz and we're going
to be going to see those in a little bit
those machines have the ability to do
more than most and the things that they
don't do GC and liquid chromatograph and
then mass spec all of these are
available here with people who are on
them and trained and know how to use
them and I think when you can and crd
just brings a small amount of key people
in to do some training you're really
going to see some standards take place
here on the island in regards to
cannabis so I'm not going to talk too
much more about it but I want you guys
to go check out United cannabis is new
page I'll put the link for their YouTube
page right in the bottom of this video
so you don't have to look and Google for
it you'll just be able to click the link
and you can see Tony vizuri along with
maurice ellis from sun spice seasonings
discussing a little bit about the
situation here in Jamaica and a little
bit about the proton hmm are so go check
that out and we will catch up with you
guys soon on bubble man's world guys as
always thanks for watching gonna film
sometimes campus be relative
[Music]
it's the building over there that we
were going to do the greenhouse project
only thing
Sam today or now we're going away I want
to institute of applied sciences
[Music]
looks like park
definitely does just parked by the
banana trees month on toxicity reports
we're not able to do this and they kind
of trapped us
[Music]
the card was a faculty of science and
technology
the medical sense that you were up
before services engineering these rules
they're in life sciences
physics
[Music]
ok
so
and we had this time
sets
[Music]
saddlemen offer
Oh
[Music]
five
we just want to find out what your team
that's not working in a closed room town
can't use their other drugs you know
let's find out what's good with it and
then the rest let's stop using like it's
not going to solve
it's also dimension
[Music]
that's really good for me I've seen too
much anecdotal evidence and see what it
does hundreds of thousands and they rely
on it and they want comparison people
being musical my 11 on p2p has violence
[Music]
anymore it's gonna attract know so be
very careful this magnetic new killer
resistance so you want to stay out here
you can stay just read that it's not
gonna muck up the cameras though huh
well you're more expensive than mine
sorry this won't this isn't this is
prime this is on magnetic fell I just
mean the components in the camera oh I
don't think so
this one you can't get around because
it's too much this is
extractor even though it doesn't belong
to us so I do supercritical co2 is this
supercut you're saying this is
supercritical co2 that's what i use it
looks totally different than that okay i
can show you what ours
it's pretty cool you know you can get
though and I'm six well click done and
you can pretty much so this is where we
do most of our drug hub interactions
Varian has got water over now as you may
buy the ax Ackley on or whatever they
are did the data is pretty
this is something brentwood really like
okay I started kids company six years
ago nipper velocity
reformed a us-based company
graduated from before as well as
seasoned agricultural scientists we've
got i'm going to spare your show but we
so they have the principal palace which
is why is that interesting so I'm
fortunate daddy called release a big
part of our boards and I to assist
another five because that's CSU in
Colorado one of you guys it's on our
team graduated many moons go from there
he's been using
studying
[Music]
so that's what ever over here
just past
bring somebody
in today's
[Music]
rabisu separate oh no it's mostly great
experience useful so this would be the
workhorse we have our community so it
was hard this one is this one I've seen
for this one so the inverse multinuclear
can hear asleep it's just we
so someone is standard here realizing H
bills each
must certify the crops and certified
products sustainers we met it's a
process
we just want answers backgrounds yes
my parts are you trying to find
[Music]
clearing again I'm not sure what's being
done yeah but that moment is tuning for
research but the Magus
yeah that's what we do we extract those
for clients and test enough and do some
due diligence on the equipment if you
don't mind is just going to go minute
just so we take the pictures and show
another scientists toys you have
[Music]
nice