foreign
[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world I'm just walking the streets of
Vancouver here trying not to get hit by
bikes and cars they're everywhere and I
am out in front of burb
one of the local dispensaries here in
Vancouver owned by a really cool dude
John K one of the founders anyway and
he's got a space upstairs that we do
book club in so this is called book club
this is a weekly Gathering where we
um
promote our different products get
together it's kind of a vapor lounge
Vibe there's live music sometimes
there's DJs there's a dab bar there's
all sorts of couches and Chairs set up
that are really great
all sorts of companies come and offer
free samples from gummies to drinks to
dabs and so I've got a brand new piece
from the good Folks at Mothership one of
their prototype pieces and I'm going to
be going up today and running the dab
Bar for a little bit and given some dabs
of some dragonfly Earth medicine so uh
well we might as well get to it
foreign
list
oh yeah yeah adelco said I'm on the uh
freebie list oh yes of the yeah
should I you want to check uh might as
well right
dude
[Music]
oh yeah just bumped into this young
fellow
one of these fellow hash Aficionado oh
yeah taking this up to Barbie
let's see who's here let's see who's
here
all right all right looks like we got a
session going on over here and another
session going on over here
nice to see you nice to see you nice to
see you just gonna do a little footage
here Johnny B's in the house what's
going on Johnny B what's going on dude
it's dark I can barely see you it's
Chase in the house
John's in the house is in the house you
got the dab bar I'm gonna get him behind
this dab bar and set up
emergency
room it's a special moment absolutely
yeah
okay
yes and uh please notice the extra air
movement in this room because I've
installed more fans and then more fans
and then more Foods so and then after my
own part there we go
oh and I guess I've grabbed the camera
so um
so try not to [ __ ] it up John
[Music]
oh girl I love this guy
no fight
the Proto the photo the Prototype
Mothership pipe check this thing out
this thing is gonna hit Like A Champion
that's gonna be a good night tonight
that's for sure it's never been hit
yeah they're all set up nice wow wow
yeah impressive
prices
110 for an ounce bro where did you get
that I got it like two days ago
if that
happens
yeah
we're gonna break it in right now
we're gonna set up the camera here and
then we're gonna get right back into
hitting this beautiful blue
is it on it's on really okay well listen
this is the break-in hit got some
dragonfly with medicine it smells like
strawberry guava I'm not sure if it's
exactly that cultivar the new prototype
from uh prototype Mothership pipe uh
here at uh book club about to dab it up
a puking beagle carb cap
is this the Frodo
[Music]
like just
[Laughter]
[Music]
on there
because if you're talking [ __ ] about
someone I'm recording
it's always a good I should wear a
t-shirt that says that you should too my
old music
you go you go home and watch your videos
and just hear all this smack talk in the
background it tastes like it needs more
but it's like it tastes like what
yeah you're right it's like it's really
it's smooth it's so smooth it's like
five
all right I haven't really been videoing
anyone but you just hit it what did you
say after that Liam fire okay I thought
it was beautiful that you said beautiful
fire what about you man it's pretty
sweet right beautiful piece
we got uh one Johnny [ __ ] B passing
the joint over there catch that on video
real quick
[Music]
thumbs up
little tiny [ __ ] dab you know
[Music]
oh
that's good
no it was like eight dabs
oh it's super smooth the pipe seems like
it's almost not working it's so smooth
[ __ ] dude I did a huge [ __ ] chunk
it looks so [ __ ] like bitter dude
what the [ __ ] is going on right now
yeah oh dude you're not even smoking
anything
[Music]
thank you
guys
okay
Cali it's like turned into rotten
pineapple yeah
give me high
yeah
they all have this unique funky smell to
them yeah
[Music]
oh and then that's like a loud like
funky
sweet though oh yeah this one's the one
that like seems the most dry I mean like
pull it right out of the jar yeah
they were I was like does anyone do this
like no one no they were like well
over there
[Music]
that'll be some of the best flavor
you've gotten out of that last one so
nice dude how smooth is that
you don't even feel it yeah
foreign
[Music]
Tony B's just dropping [ __ ] while he's
taking his dab he's just knocking [ __ ]
over so I can giving everyone a heart
attack in the back
not even [ __ ] blinking
professional Johnny hold the glass hold
the glass
finish off peace Brother good to see him
yeah
[Music]
oh just looking at the the bubble the 90
you that we squished into the into the
fresh breath yeah so I can see it better
yeah
[Music]
thank you
peace out Johnny B
[Music]
all right that's a wrap book club
January 20th 2023. you get a bunch of
dabs broken the mothership pipe and it's
time to head home I gotta go to Whistler
in the morning
well I don't have to but I want to peace
for now
thank you
[Music]
foreign
have a good night for sure we'll see you
later
[Music]
foreign