[Music]
all right guys just got here to the
Vancouver Seed Bank in cchq on the
second floor off of Hastings and I think
we might have a little uh
little session going on here some
well-known folks in the industry it's
not that no see it's even more than that
what happens is is that 18 break the
plane give thanks you're so dark I can't
even see you there it is it's Matt it's
Matt the great Gardener which I guess is
marijuana man's in the house holding it
down as always good day mcm's in the
house holding it down pretty much as
always drugs drugs drugs drugs so what
are we puffing on here Matt drugs this
is our a finger hash rosin that has purp
purposely been left out for over a week
just to see what happens to
it oh this was the finger rub Ros very I
made a little rosin with finger rub and
I was also very impressed oh it's it's
great it's crazy so super flavorful this
one is like is piny lemony like just
what strain did you say it was we just
just GG one
oh okay yeah yeah of course this has
like the Mad pining this is I mean I'm
still saying it uh as a very serious
thing that this is the closest reminder
I've seen of Romulan Joe's Romulan since
back in the '90s I was going to say
that's going back yeah and I don't see
it all the time I see it when he puts it
in a in a container and he closes the
container for like a day and you open it
that smell to me is Joe's old Rong and I
just I miss it so you can check it out
in the gg1
The Afghani
one put the hat back
down yeah uh enrio was explaining to me
the importance of keeping this down and
not letting it cool even for like a
couple of minutes I like it for that
aspect because you can turn this unit
down yep and hold it in and I can dab
and I can put weed underneath cuz it's
not so hot yeah this little [ __ ] lid
keeps that thing no it's on point it
would be hard to carb that thing any
other way and he was saying that this
makes up like a certain percentage of
the mass that is heating up the atomizer
and so if you just leaving it up like
this for a minute or two changes it can
take away that sort of like I don't know
how to put it into words any other way
than the sublimator accesses magic it
just has this little point where it's
like I can't get that anywhere
else true do you have one of these close
to the best dab I've ever oh my god
dude yeah I'd say so I still use my
denail for dabbing
resins oh yeah like but I love the
atomizer putting have you ever tried
putting that in the atomizer as well no
cuz that also hits a little bit
differently where's the atomizer this
whole bowl is the atomizer and it's one
of the things with the sublimator that
the one itself is really only heating
the atomizer and of course if you're
dabbing off of it but for herb so what
are you got to take this you take this
whole unit on yeah you just lift this
whole thing out sometimes you'd lay like
a bed of weed or you could even just
take hash and drop it right in there and
hit it like
that just drop it right in there never
done that never dabbed in there yeah
I've uh I played around a lot with the
sublimator when I first got it and uh I
was just amazed this is the heating unit
though right y but it Heats Heats this
up that up and then just go like
that no what I usually do is I would put
like a larger chunk of hash roll it into
a ball or something and then put it in
and then put this on yeah drop it right
on top of the screen or onto um a little
bit of
herb we'd be here all day figuring out
how to drop that in let's just dab it on
the top I'm down for another little dab
de has not
has see if Mike's here got a real nice
tight screen in there are you see I just
did
it was good great Gardener is doing me
up here look at this great Gardener dabs
dabs it just leaves nothing right
there's nothing and then you look back
at the spoon when you're done and
there's like there's always at least a
little clear Dome on it it's just
liquefies on
the made it with finger I made it with
finger hat yeah yeah I got that Romulan
flavor
that
Pine oh my God lemony Pine it's it's
like Mr Clean it's like inhaling a Mr
Clean bottle it's like it's like Pine
it's awesome yeah it's like some I feel
like I just somebody's washed the walls
with pine saw and you've walked into the
house I agree yes they uh they got you
on the the menu here Matt yeah yeah
right here the one that's all sold out
yeah all sold out I can't believe it
look at that eh that's not the one
that's not the one must be that one
there you go
boom really good prices on those
too yeah we can't it's hard to keep them
in stock well he doesn't bring them to
me and then what I bring them I bring
them in they sold out sell in days I
love sell them time to grow more totally
always here at the seat bag hell
yeah awesome come see these guys if
you're in Vancouver
they've got a couple of uh of options
that you can come and check them out two
two just on Hastings but I think this
one's the fun the fun one personally so
we're here all
day come see them it's marijuana man
come blaze a bowl with him and buy some
seeds Matt he won't be here it'll be
like super fluky if you hit Matt if you
get here and Matt is here he's going to
dab you up too but he's not going to be
here we're going
riding B
m
[Music]