[Music]
all right so uh Kelly and I just made it
to downtown Winnipeg I used to actually
have a hemp shop just around the corner
here called The Hemp exchange and uh can
we fit through there yeah we can yeah
okay well let's do it this a bit
dangerous but let's do
it put all my bags on the side so I'm
not touching any
[Music]
cars so we're heading over to Vapes off
Maine I guess it used to be Vapes on
Maine and now it's Vapes off Main I like
it just to the left here hey I know that
guy little Reggie the rot
[Music]
what's up
brother what that that girl just sitting
in cells I I just walk in there's no one
in there and her back was to me and I
said he said something hey you looking
for something I said yeah my buddies
must went to a different place and he
said oh they just left and then Cory
turns around I haven't seen her in about
a year she's ow what the [ __ ] what was
she working there hey who was the girl
was just sitting in there I know where
oh that was working the girl that was
working on all the paper no she was just
sitting there writing yeah okay yeah
yeah that's the girl we sat right beside
her yeah she was just sitting at a booth
writing trippy so this is it we're
heading in should I turn this off first
it doesn't matter
good yeah I put this wall up built this
wall put all right service window in so
is this like a little dispensory right
here well this was going to be the this
is where you pay your ad when I built it
this was where you paid your Mission got
into the lounge but this is going to be
a bit of the medical marijuana resource
center side of things okay but I don't
know what they're
doing like I said I haven't been here in
a long time since they got it open well
let's go check it
out crime smoking marijuana is not a
crime using drugs generally is not a
crime and uh assassine to hurt people
more by enforcing criminal law on people
who smoke
or use any drugs for that matter and I
say d lies let's take them under the
hands of the criminals and uh and and
start making our our streets
safer um so your point absolutely I uh
finally turned the camera on I've been s
I've been sitting and talking we we are
at Vapes off Main right and it started
as Vapes on all right cool and that was
was it Eddie from the beginning Yeah
Eddie and B here been involved Eddie
and EDD I learned about it through Bill
uh from his Facebook page seeing him
post about it when I first saw the the
words Vapes on Main it got me excited
cuz I'm from Winnipeg originally I
haven't lived here in almost 20 years
but I thought uh definitely nice to see
a vapor lounge here in Winnipeg and uh
my hats off to these guys uh for doing
it and we've been sitting around this
table puffing for the last hour or so
and having good conversation and uh yeah
I just thought I would give you guys
from Bubble man's world a little bit of
a glimpse into Vapes off Main and maybe
uh maybe we could go around the table
and everyone could kind of introduce
themselves and tell us a little bit
about your cannabis passion kind of
crazy how it how fast it went actually
like I I I am I was here a year ago and
I was here when everything started with
Eddie and Bill and at the first main
location like it's on Main and it really
got like we started talking on Facebook
we had a post on 420 saying hey we're
opening a new
cannabis a week after that somebody from
CBC comes and asked to have an interview
and I was like okay sure sure no problem
I'll give you an interview with Bill and
the the management and after that in a
week we got every I was like CTV CBC OIC
Free Press doing everybody doing their
own reports it and I left a year ago and
now I come back and it's a new place
downtown crazy things are happening
around the place so it went fast that
was super fast and and Bill do you think
that the media was interested in uh do
you think you having a history as a
police officer in the city and now being
an outspoken cannabis activist and
really outspoken for the plant do you
think that br a little bit of that media
in was that part of the attention that
they
were I mean I it could have it could
have I've been speaking in the city for
quite a number of years now for law
enforcement prohibition know for Le
right yeah Le and since over 7 years now
8 years writing letters and everything
so I'm and then in my previous position
in the police there was fairly high
profile position as well staff Sur major
crime in the street
came late 9s and then I said the hell
with that [ __ ] I got out that's 2001
and uh uh I was already familiar with
cannabis of course I mean I grew up in
the 6s but it wasn't something that I
Wasing the police department to enforce
sure because I could care less about it
and I didn't have a nose for it and if
you didn't have a nose for it you
been and so I essentially like a lot of
offic I don't want to run off at the
both here and take all the time here but
as far as Vapes on Main goes that was an
interesting thing I'd been to Toronto
I'd been to Vancouver
uh new Dana few people I spoke
for
regarding Y and Johnny Tran and Leah K
came with Eddie my one day we met them
at a demonstration and they said we're
looking for a director to set up private
sort of a h Club private club but that's
what I'd heard that it started was a
private club it's sort of a they're
called Social Clubs in the problem they
private whatever we can have out we want
but the um I figured it was a good
opportunity to give the cause a bit of a
kick in the ass simply by
getting in because I've already been so
active and I thought I'd be remiss if I
didn't get in to Simply you know you not
not give my sanction to it so much as
saying hey I'm with the I'm with the
people here on this this is the kind of
thing we need in this town and
dispensaries are going to be next
absolutely Vice magazine came out to do
an interview so it went great well
that's awesome and it's slowly just
grown into the entity that it is today
well we're here because uh
the location is kind of a what's the old
tur
Bohemian beatnik hippies I [ __ ]
dating myself the U but over here is
exchange District part Y and they have
they just went through the red gay
Festival here they not it's a great spot
it's just yeah it's just Prime spot it's
literally where we had our spot like 20
years ago the hemp exchange like right
in the exchange place now isin place now
we it nice well we smoked a lot of weed
and hash in that building let me tell
you a lot of weed and hash got smoked in
that building for sure yeah yeah I mean
yeah like Bill said I mean things really
took off cuz I I just heard of the whole
thing like uh when they put out that
newspaper thing they kind of put it out
and uh I think fre press ran it and CBC
or whoever ran it
and yeah it went [ __ ] man definitely
after that a lot of people started here
and voted I guess my position you know I
mean I don't understand you so well
person then the as some of my friends
are here in the medical aspects and the
intricacies of plan s I'm not that much
into that I'm a crie guy and I seen
people stop this [ __ ] no crime
anymore no victim no crime and I'm
talking about all drugs yeah since
because we can't afford to have the kind
of vience we're seeing in our streets
like Siri BC for example 40 shootings in
the past two months or whatever it is
absolutely I mean that's all cocaine and
heroin and whatever it is it's all these
drugs that because they're not regulated
or legal that they're able to other
people can just take control of them
that's right and that's that's why I I'm
with leap on that issue too we got to
pay control and of course cannbis
considered part of that for people don't
understand that most of the Cannabis
Growers now are mums and pops and and
more in the professional growing they
don't deal with in other products or
none of their drugs simply cannabis and
uh um that's the big difference in my
view I support the cannbis people I
don't support the other drugs but I say
let's legalize and take it out of the
hands of the criminals and the cartel I
agree 100% it comes down to seems like
Common Sense really considering if you
Black Market profits we already know
what prohibition did because back in the
day of alcohol prohibitions and and it
was the police force who really took a
serious look at the at prohibition when
for the first time in the history people
just started literally killing the
police that was under prohibition all of
a sudden it was a war they were shooting
each other for alcohol and it was like
well this is insane considering most of
those policemen drank alcohol on their
time off even under the under
prohibition they still went to the speak
easys or the whatevers and ended up
having a drink or two and now it's like
we we they they realized way back then
that eliminating alcohol prohibition
would eliminate all the crime that went
along with it and just regulate and all
those old company uh all those old
people that were Smugglers and
Bootleggers are now the biggest alcohol
companies on the planet literally like
the bronfman well literally it's rumored
that Al might have been down here in
this in this I wouldn't be surprised
this the
hotel so this would have been filled up
with uh alcohol barrels at one point he
was to do hung here
like hanging out at Al's place here with
Al it's a historical place for
prohibition we should get that story
down
that's where a guy like David Mal David
Maline comes in handy cuz that's what he
does he would literally hear that story
and then he would figure it out he would
just follow it and find it and do fi
follow the history and then make it
available in some cool little book or
piece of paper or something he's
definitely like a lot of people should
look at that guy in regards to his
activism and he's portrayed himself over
the course of the last 20 years he's
he's also he's hardcore man I firmly
stand behind David Maline and most of
the things that he does uh cannabis
activism related I remember we from
Switzerland when we went to Mel beans
place and they were arguing about
something and then when we were leaving
you were saying that
was or something what what dude from
Switzerland raw guy him and his
girlfriend oh Chris Iverson that's
hilarious oh it was so funny but then
what blew my mind
was that uh Bill Smalls blew my mind
there cuz he was playing the oh yeah the
reefer song the reer song we leave the
Viper yeah in his
bedroom it ever The Joint 9 ft long or
something s Dre go to Joint 5T long 5T
long yeah because you're a
Viper that b some old school like 30s or
40s
uh Style music yeah I know that the
brothers blew my mind I didn't even know
he was a pro musician and
here we're going to continue to Puff
ourselves into a frenzy here but thanks
for watching
guys tell you the story even Mark em
probably does know I was involved in the
arrest of Mark em when he was here
really
wow I'll tell you it was only because I
was intelligence unit at that time which
was kind
of you know straight we did surveillance
anyway surve was in he was when he was
in Winnipeg on a demonstration outside
the public safety he got arrested and he
got arrested well I he took his bong his
Vancouver cans bong and he still talks
about that bomb he's like still like
wants that bom don't ask me I was a guy
sitting there kind of watching and
saying cuz I was to go there and have a
watch and I knew he wanted to get
arrested fence he came to get arrested
yeah so I I said okay pass the ball you
know it's funny because if they just
that was my role in the [ __ ] thing
okay pass the ball and mean two cops
walked out and took them whatever not in
handcuffs or anything and just escort
him back in the public safety building
and I guess
heed promis appearance notice in those
days but I don't know like a bong in
that day was the key on that one simply
because it's a traffic it was the same
thing he passed the joint and that's he
did time aatul I think he did 30 days or
something it was kind of like wa what
like 30 days yeah 30 days oh well Mark
was always one to push the envelope in I
thought it was ironic too because uh you
know just laughing like crazy what a
stupid thing for us to be wasting our
time
we had all over the place but I mean he
wanted to get arrested and push the
cause and I admired him for it even as a
c from
afar I did oh yeah absolutely because
even then there was a lot of us guys on
the job who were
not uh uh the drug Warriors right that
uh you saw from The French Connection B
we used to see people try and emulate
those kind
detectives no we see if there was no
victim I didn't want anything to do with
it well that's the you're homicide
detective like I wanted a
victim I honestly I've never met a
homicide detective that cared about
cannabis they don't even they don't even
really care about drugs in a sense like
they'll you know what I mean like if
they need if they just want some
information like we just need to solve
this murder I don't care that you had a
bunch of heroin just tell
how we operated because that makes sense
you're trying to solve a [ __ ]
homicide which I met many heroin addicts
and some of the homicides here was quite
uh enlightening for me you know um not
what you expect that's real police work
but and then when I started to get
involved F leap and they came home they
articulated pretty awesome law
enforcement against prohibition it's it
you know very powerful group of people
to stand up well they won't appreciate
me sitting here talking about it cuz I
went my t-shirt but because it's such a
uh we'll put the website the video This
legal operation gentlemen if you are
watching and I'm Bill Vander graph of Le
sometimes I speak from you for you
sometimes I don't I say kiss my ass the
uh the fact is it's a legal operation
going on here I've already checked Vice
magazine you remember saw the the
yard so yeah absolutely I mean I'm mm so
I'm definitely happy I I was going to
ask my hotel today for instance I mean
I'm staying at a nice hotel in the city
spent a fair amount of money and then I
want to know where can I use cannabis
cuz I know if I walk out into the forks
and sit in the middle of the thing and
pull out my mother ship and a big
blowtorch start torching my nail which I
did in all in my defense this morning in
front of the forest and then I went down
to the river and I did it there and then
I went on the bridge and I did there
most of the people were just looking at
me yes but I thought I wanted to ask the
hotel like where where can I medicate
and it's like it's amazing that these
hotels don't have anywhere that they can
tell their patrons their
customers where they can go do this
safely and because they can't do that I
can potentially invite unwanted
attention into my life by being in a
city that I might not you know be aware
of of how it works so
it is what it is I'm glad that the Vapor
Lounge exists and uh we're just going to
continue here with this group of uh
great individuals I'll put all the links
on how you guys can get in touch with
these guys and uh we'll catch up with
you guys in a
bit well all right guys we have made it
back to the beautiful hotel here the in
at the forks and uh we got the sun
setting behind us uh with the city of
Winnipeg really kind
of prominently displayed wouldn't you
say h oh yeah got the Richardson
Building and the old Bank building
there's not too many high-rise buildings
but that is definitely right behind Al's
head there the majority of them and then
the $350 million giant big finger from
the uh the Human Rights Museum which uh
you got to admit it is a pretty unique
looking building now can you go up to
the top is that what that top part is I
haven't been there yet but I do believe
you can get a long ways up there okay
okay I'm not sure if you get right to
the top or not but
thanks for the Water by the way I know
contractors uh that work there were
shaking their head the whole time they
never seen anything like it no and yeah
the one guy was drywalling like five
stories up on a scaffold type of thing
come on use the the
butter oh I know what I'm looking
for the Dabber which should be beside
you there and the resin is the Dabber
there too inside yeah
beautiful all right well we've been
hitting this LH as well as this rosin
pretty
heavy it's been quite nice I would say
wouldn't you oh yeah so we thought we'd
finish it off with the last session here
at the end at the forks sun going down
in the background couple of nice rips
out of the Mother Ship not like there's
been any short of rips out of the Mother
Ship but uh I'm going to do a combo
rosin LH
rip
o nicely
done monster
dabs use my right hand so the camera
actually shows
it oh will be required to flick the
switch
that was a te's rip as you can see the D
nail was at 74° and now that I've
clicked the switch flick the switch
she's climbing beautiful thing about
these things they don't take that long
to heat up the few times in my life
where I've actually done what I just did
which is put the Dabber into the cold
Bowl um I've managed to sort of get my
hit in me like probably a minute
later so not too
bad well the analog I think's a little
slower to warm but yeah this is fast
you'll see like in less than a minute we
will be ripping this bowl yeah it's
already up to 300
yeah halfway there so there's that is a
good
thing
359 got my Dil set at about 680 today
we've been uh on this trip I've gone as
low as 580 and as high as 750 so quite a
wide variety of uh of rips we're getting
up to 500 here starting to feel some
good heat coming off of
that it should be nice A little L mixed
in with a rosin you can even see their
differences quite clearly on the end of
the Dabber oh
yeah so I'm at 600° and I'm going to go
for it I don't mind a low temp dab at
all
nice hey on the low Tempa you just keep
getting
rips
[Music]
lovely would you like one of
those little combo rip
sure all righty
then well it was a nice trip back to
Winnipeg I did miss a few things that I
wanted to do I kind of wanted to take
the bubble man's world audience to where
I smoked my first joint and I had plans
on doing that and I could still
potentially do that tomorrow morning
wake up real early and just decide that
I'm going to drive out there but
tomorrow is my last day and I fly out
tomorrow so that is the day that I'm
usually kind of scrambling I get a
little more anxious and I'm traveling
with the family so you just want to make
sure that you have the
time good good to see you know I enjoyed
today hanging out at the new dispensary
in town uh Glenn was super cool guy Mark
was a great guy I looked forward W to um
checking out Vapes off Maine and meeting
Bill uh vandergraph yeah ex cop and uh
you know speaker for leap law officials
against uh prohibition as well as
cannabis activist locally here in
Manitoba so I just thought it was nice
to see him as well and meet those guys
from Vapes off Main it was unfortunately
I didn't get to meet Eddie the founder
of Vapes on Main but hopefully we can uh
um meet him maybe as well tomorrow
morning if it works out before I fly out
here but but uh otherwise I wanted to
wrap it up guys I wanted to thank Reggie
theate for taking me around Winnipeg and
showing me uh showing me around today
being my host and uh thank all the good
people of uh Winnipeg Manitoba for doing
the good work and continuing the
activism and continuing the important
work of educating the masses as to the
importance of uh saturating your
endocannabinoid system not only for a
medicinal uh and recreational methods
but also for preventative because
there's no need to get sick
uh if you can take the right things to
prevent that so yeah you got anything
last words you want to share reg know
it's just good seeing you had a good day
right on dude another good one yeah it
was good for sure well we're going to
continue on puffing some bowls and
drinking this fancy water from the in at
the forks and uh thank you guys all for
watching Bubble man's world and I hope
you appreciated this Winnipeg Edition we
will uh talk to you soon
peace