[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world uh I'm
here with Brett from West Coast
concentrate and we are going to be doing
a review
today of The Vape exhale they got a
great little uh little pamphlet nice
little brochure tells you how to use
unit yeah I was pretty impressed with it
I'll photograph it and inlay it into the
video so you can see the Simplicity of
you know step one turning on the unit I
guess we can do that yep little red
light goes on on the on the top you can
wait for uh if you turn it up to a
certain temperature you can wait for it
to turn green and then that indicates
that temperature apparently it's pretty
sensitive yeah I've never used the unit
before so it is quite funny that today
both Brett and I who have never used
this unit are going to review it so I
guess the title should really be the
review from the total Noob perspective
exactly this isn't the accurate review
of someone that's used the unit for for
a couple of months learned all about the
little intricacies and sort of subtle
nuances and mastered The Sweet Spot of
tweaking it to the point where yes this
is how the unit Works we're total noobs
today we're total noobs and and and we
thought we would also nail it with a
tarpine gauntlet so we weren't sure if
we should do
just pure Tarpin which could still
happen or if we're going to do dabbing
bubble hash with Tarpin uh we're going
to see what happens as we come along
here so the pamphlets great it's
definitely nice and clear and precise
explains the whole unit the unit comes
with a really like Dude tell me that's
not a fat that's a fatty little piece of
glass like it feels like it's like 7 ml
thick it's definitely it's definitely
probably 8 mmce nice pipe that just fits
right on the top um the unit itself
takes uh these little nails
and I believe we should have one laying
around right here absolutely they they
give you this cool little wooden piece
that fits five of these and I guess you
got one that can be in the unit as well
they sell them in five packs like that
which they sent us a nice little five
pack yeah super nice yeah not too shabby
and so this little guy here uh you fill
up with your concentrate or your your TP
dab or whatever it is you're going to be
hitting you drop it into there you put
the pipe on top and uh because we're
thinking of doing pure turp rips here
for the beginning I think that's what we
should do now that I'm getting it
feeling it you know um that we should
definitely keep this from getting hot
before we put the turps in cuz just from
dropping that in for a few seconds it's
warm look like quarts are out as well
yep exactly so it dissipates its heat
very well meaning that if you left it in
there for a pretty long time you're
still going to be able to pull it out by
the top it also has a little ring on the
top that you could possibly I guess grab
let's see yeah that's totally totally
doable and this piece just doesn't get
warm at all uh it's still on the red so
we're still uh heting up still heating
up I've heard that it takes a while the
initial time to heat up it's it's a
fairly accurate unit in its temperatures
from what I've heard so um I guess what
are we starting with I think we're going
to do this let's do it I think we're
going to do pure turps bro let's do it
let's do pure turp so let's just start
off with uh with this guy right here
triple OG
okay maybe I'll leave that one for
dabbing and we'll go in fresh uhoh for
the TP dip uh oh the big jar you afraid
yeah little bit should be you should be
yeah just a little bit and we're green
too green so I guess what he said was as
we drop it in we'll turn it down yeah so
that will lower the temperature of the
heat that the unit's putting out and
allow us to get you know all the
flavor did that go in or did that go out
it's hard to tell I think it went it
went in wow that's incredible so let's
start with
that nice uh here hold that yes sir I
don't want the TPS a never leave your
turp jar undone and then again when you
have a nice uh vial a a sorry Dabber
that you have TPS in it's best to try
and keep it from from dripping down so
let's see what we've got we've got our
green so why don't
you let's see what we can do here we're
going to give you the first one okay
this cord is going to be absolutely
ridiculous for me yeah do we want to
turn down at all or just yeah we're
going to turn it down as we drop that in
so you can just turn it right down now
to 1/3 Y and give yourself the freshest
fullest straightest TP rip I can see the
tiniest little bit I have heard that the
units are whistlers when you don't put
the water in definitely a Whistler how's
that for Taste it's crazy tasting
crazy well I it's not too much of a
punchy in the face damn
yeah nice that's phenomenal is it done I
don't think so really yeah should I just
share yours I would try it you may want
one of your own as
well yeah it's dissipated dissipated
which is
okay let's pull cool down like
incredible Jesus enjoy
that all right I said Jesus because
uh well that was extreme extreme
dropping right there so uh we're at
temperature here I'm going to go up a
little higher cuz what Tony was
suggesting was we go up to about the
halfway point on the temperature gauge
there's no markings the temperature
starts at what I would say is about 7:00
and it goes down to the other side to
about 5:00 so half would probably be you
know between 1 and uh 12 and two
somewhere so I've got it up to half it's
going red right now and I guess what
Tony said said is get it up to that
little bit hotter and then just drop it
uh as you drop the the nail in so the
temperatures uh which makes sense the
heat the heat in the unit is getting
lower as you're nailing I would have
thought to start at a much lower
temperature and then lift it up a little
bit but hey Tony's been the one tweaking
this and playing with it so I trust his
judgment turn that down I'm excited to
see what he
thinks so yeah as you see a little
slight Vapor
build that's a good one
oh that's the air flow down
there orangey or
what incredible I know it's total triple
OG in the back end on my tongue and
whatnot but at the beginning it was when
you said orangey it was like rhind yeah
and then it just shifted even as I'm
talking now my entire
mouth is just completely satiated yeah
tast it on the lips as well very
different from dabbing it off of a nail
by itself I found that that was very
like almost abrasive yes it it is the
direct heat like you were saying earlier
definitely is a little bit more harsher
on the lungs let's say you get more at
out of once um but it's almost too much
to
enjoy that's just a nice little tur
machine right there it is definitely a
beautiful little tur machine all right
so we'll go for a new nail as we are
doing a new flavor we're going to hit
the purple Hindu I got a total buzz off
that man I have not smoked any hash all
day and like I was telling you they
defin no doubt that they definitely
bring you up Elevate you and I think the
different varieties um really really do
different things coughed into the thing
there I'll I'll edit that as well a all
right Lucho editing to be
done we'll try to make it as smooth as
possible for you I know how that
goes you're probably pretty good at it
though
just want to get you a nice like not
huge dab but like a partial appreciate
it all right there you go sir turp a lot
ready to drop in and go sir turps a lot
purple Hindu I can't believe the feeling
I have from that single I got you thank
you a different flavor than I'm used to
yeah well this this is really a unique
unit in the sense that it's going to be
a lot less abrasive than those nail hits
for doing um straight pure turp rips Y
and you can see it's pretty uh is there
turp still in there I so so pretty
efficient in terms of uh
clean the flavor that you get
overwhelming your mouth and your palette
is crazy nice well I'm definitely going
to go for one of those once this cools
down I'm excited all
right so little purple punch I like the
way we did the cord that's that's a
that's a that's a winning situation
right there it is actually I'm going to
turn it back up a little bit get that
temperature up to par cuz remember we're
turning it
down getting it up and then we're
turning it down so I guess next time
when we do it
um when I'm cooling this mhm just turn
it back up to its halfway point yeah
learning prepared yeah we're learning
we're getting it done you know what so
far is so good we're on our you've had
your second dab I'm going on my second
now I feel completely Spacey yeah like
it's definitely a heady Spacey almost
likeo that's trippy I know and then when
you we've only had one and then when you
dab hash after you made it through 12 of
these the modulation is like oh my God
it's real all right green we
go fits nice too
I you can put water in the unit of
course that looks like it
yeah that looks like it tasted
amazing I can't even describe it yeah I
know it's completely surreal
yeah you can tell the canabo are really
just these like nice friendly little
things that just in you know they
they're companions to the tpin they're
just yeah one without the other is not
as special by no means it's different
for sure though man it's definitely
trippy different I don't know your
opinion but for myself I almost almost
rather the Turpin alone than the canabo
alone oh yeah for me anyways yeah you
know by no means do I need them
medically I use them more so
recreationally and medically for my
separated joint um but the tping seem to
just help me out they don't leave me in
pain that just smelling them will you
know help me out more than dabbing A
little dab of pord
right jeez it's like the Medicine Cherry
AK-47 time yeah it became really
apparent to me uh as soon as you know we
had access to the tpin that the THC and
well the the canono were less of
a less of a big deal than I thought they
were you know know everybody wanting
high THC strains I'm impressed for with
how buzzed I am off two little turp rips
that's what I was trying to say yeah
it's unbelievable I know and it's nice
too when you haven't smoked hash in the
morning you're able to really tell yeah
well I I smoked a lot of hash this
morning so it could be that I'm
modulating all that uh I had a Skype
call that went for like an hour and a
half with skunkman Sam so I can't even
count how many bowls we get but it was
real for certain myself I uh I didn't
smoke any this morning so it's nice to
see the effects for sure I'm just
waiting for this to get green here yep
no problem no problem we got uh Cherry
AK we're on number three and we have
three more clean nails so we'll go
through the next three um which is the
red kongal The Long Valley Royal Kush
and the
ACDC and then we'll do a quick cleaning
of the nails we'll just torch them to
make sure they're totally clean and
yummy so we don't get any aftertastes
from the past previous
rips yeah you're hitting the Cherry
AK-47 yeah like I was saying earlier the
Cherry is definitely like a nighttime uh
tpine for me you want to go for a nap
after this one I definitely don't want
to go for a nap after this one but it's
a turpion that I use to uh to D my
hashen before
bed yes yes good stuff that's
phenomenal that's another one that's
just super hard to explain and because
they're a variety it makes sense out
they're hard to explain yeah that one's
a little warm I turned it up for you as
well so you're green get this to cool
off real
quick fcking
oxidizers there we
go see that second one go in
yep so really it's okay you just get to
take it right to the Head
turps to the
head all
right Cherry AK for Mr bman all right I
just turned it up cuz you had it at 1/3
yeah and we start at 1/2 okay and then
go down to 13 yeah so and it went right
away
beautiful kind of fun little way to load
it yeah it's not bad at all
just the lightest Vapor as
well oh man though
yep that just taste completely and
exactly like AK-47 like the bud the
sift yeah that's just
insane that might be the one that tasted
the most like the FL I mean they they
all have that very strong Gorilla Glue
is very much Gorilla Glue some of those
kushes but this is
just yeah it's bang
on it's definitely one of those units
that leaves you just kind of wanting to
keep hitting it until you're done and
then more even after that it's
definitely a little bit counterintuitive
in that sense that even as I'm hitting
it like I could see hear someone typing
no no bubble man suck slow like inhale
less and and go slower because you don't
want to cool the chamber down and I'm
not sure what kind of a chamber they've
got in here and how efficient it is it
seems like it stayed exactly at
temperature so
yep are you ready for the red
congales I'm definitely ready for the
red con dude me
too most excited for the red
Congo dude happy that you're you're like
hitting these first I'm excited and then
passing it down to me and I get to see
it on your face and get to hear you from
you and it's nice I appreciate it dude I
appreciate it as well this is very good
much thanks to uh Tony for hooking up
the relationship with the vapex Hal
folks
and of course much thanks to the vapex
hail folks and yeah great unit
especially for tping we haven't dabbed
even hashing it yet but for tpping it
seems to be a little bit more Superior
than say just dabbing it on your hot
nail thank you that is a thank you sir
full drop of the red congales and what
we're going to try and do this time I'm
going to try and inhale slow so I don't
yeah I'm going to try I'll be conscious
of it do it do it like I said we're
total noobs hitting this thing for the
first time so in two months from now we
may very well be hitting it differently
I would have had water in it Tony uh
urged me to leave the water out it would
be much more flavor yet you're milking
it up real nice and
tasty oh my God that's phenomenal
that looked so good I think that was it
dude I think you you took it
out wow good job wow we me smell the
bone oh my God it's just that spice it's
yeah I'm excited to see how you explain
that that's almost celery esque to me
really like it's but not celery but it's
definitely got that undertone in it that
vegetation yeah that vegetation taste
and then that red cono is oh oh I'm
stoked to give it a shot look at that
you just clean there's no residuals
there's nothing at all I have to get one
of these bro I think I have TPS well we
got a code we got a code for the people
that want to give it a shot um the good
Folks at vapix hail created a code I
want to say that it stay
melty but I should check just to make
sure because uh oh it's Stay turpy Stay
turpy makes sense s t a y t e r p y I'm
going to put it across the screen
capital S capital T um you use that and
you're going to get 50 bucks free vape
nails when entering the code that's
obviously when you buy a unit uh such as
this they're going to send you one free
box of nails so that's a $50 value
that's pretty good yeah and it gives you
the access to to be able if you are
dabbing T beans or different hashes to
you know use five different varieties
exactly without having to clean up
exactly so here I go for red kongal just
like you hit it slow and easy he slow
and steady I can see it milking up
jeez it's a great
experience gentle I would say gentle is
a is a nice word to describe getting
your celery
yeah but then as you exhale it it turns
from a vegetation to a spice exactly yep
it's definitely peppery it's got that
beta carara offene in there
but some other unique things that I just
don't recogn I just don't see enough of
but it's it's probably that mercing
pining delimine combination sativa Haze
sort of uh tarpine profile yeah our
pallets would be a lot more used to it
if you know we weren't in a Prohibition
based age where everybody's growing
cushies exactly well I left a little bit
of a oh a little bit of a ring in there
two drops hey little Golden Ring
nice all right so that was the
longal oh we have the Long Valley Royal
Kush next well I'm not going to cry
about that I'm definitely not crying
about it had the most
intense cush smell that I've smelled in
a long time coming off a turp actually
yeah that might be the strongest cush
yeah I've ever smelted in the turps and
and he's made some great
ones thank y'all
had to double you up bro I appreciate
you very much I had to man I had to here
we can get rid of that so it's R
away turn this up a little bit
little really enjoying this turp
Gauntlet it's quite different from The
turp Gauntlet that uh D 420k and I did
with the bubble hash that one really
felt like a pretty we got to do this we
got to you know we were like but this
just feels like man I could do like a
hundred of these exactly it's not so
much of a of a stone ey but it CH yeah
it doesn't get You Higher and Higher and
Higher it just goes like z z z you're
you're you're changing the direction of
the of the effects and
it's it is a damn beautiful thing let me
tell you really
enjoyable yeah you definitely feel like
you can do it all day wow and I've been
waiting for this unit basically to do
this sort of experience because I
haven't heard of another unit that
exists that I could really pull this off
no I have I love the quartz Nails
sliding into the glass and that is just
uh yeah it cools down nice and quick too
so we can put our dab back into it and
you know oh man can have a hit exactly
rather than waiting 10 minutes totally
oh my god do
it I will I will do it
Long Valley Royal
Kush
wow that's definitely the way to hit it
is nice and slow so you don't cool the
element you're getting consistent heat
the whole
time which is allowing you to vaporize
those uh Turin
efficiently God yeah that's one that
makes you come back for more that's that
cushy cushy
gas it's gas on the SO gas yeah on the
exhale mad
gas it's the Mad
gas yeah definitely no turbs left in
there give that a smell no it's uh it's
draining them good with the uh
temperature and I think I feel the
temperature is really a good
temperature I'm not feeling that I'm
getting any sort of distasteful burnt
popcorn any of that stuff it's just this
beautiful it's almost if anything some
of them are just extremely
subtle that you could see in a normal
session people would miss it yeah yeah
some people wouldn't have the palette
for it they'd say well it's not strong
enough it doesn't give me enough of an
effect I definitely see that happening
yeah but for a connoisseur who's you
know super into different varieties they
would definitely appreciate this
experience um my God yeah and not not
saying that anybody else wouldn't they
just may not have the you know pette to
understand why why the taste is so
subtle and so complex just like food
there you go sir thank
you smell the tiniest little tiny little
drop I didn't think it was tpps
but might have to just uh wear those
turs that was red congales for
sure it's definitely a little bit
nerve-wracking with the value of the TPS
and the drops and this that and the
other thing but we're doing about what I
would call quarter drops these aren't
$10 uh US dollar drops if you're
watching and you're freaking out um
they're more like $250 cents and I would
definitely say that is so well worth the
ab like I would pay five 10 bucks to hit
a dab of it let alone yeah oh nice and
clean yeah that one was phenomenal this
is the what again uh that was the um
ACDC oh wow yeah those CBD strains they
have the real strong flavors and taste
that's for sure yeah I I think you'll
like that
one make sure we're we're clean as a
whistle I know you can smell it too
there's no there's like no residual turb
smell on it just it smells like warm
quartz ex yeah I was just going to say
that just smells like warc like it's
trippy didn't realize they were quartz
at first but then when you see how
they're cut yeah you understand and you
you see that it's like that's hard
quartz is hard to to work with for
sure all right squeeze that little tiny
mini almost nothing Dropout
beautifully I like putting this unit on
here it's pretty yeah it's mesmerizing
just seeing the little bit of vapor that
you are creating knowing how much flavor
that little little bit of vapor is is
pulling him
through it's a pretty phenomenal
experience yeah that was really nice
yeah different too it's kind of
unexplainable that's the ACDC by the way
true enough it's got this like Flavor of
herb I used to get way way back in the
day that just reminds me of like herb I
puffed in high school that wasn't wasn't
the kindest wasn't the best flavor but
had a particular flavor that I just
would get time and time and time
again so we got uh six
down oh [ __ ] what cush cleaner cush
cleaner brother Jesus cush
cleaner yeah we're excited about this
cush cleaner we're not going to lie M my
God definitely an overwhelming taste and
smell no matter what you dab it with it
seems like the Kush cleaner comes
through over
anything she's the boss she's definitely
the boss when it comes to
Turin There You Go sir thank
you couple of mini mini quarter
drops oh yeah got a little bit left in
the dropper for
me
exciting that's definitely the freshest
like cleaning supply one so far like
it's phenomenal taste it's got that
lemon scented pledge in there
definitely I definitely say lemons over
oranges for
sure yeah that's uh that makes
sense yeah and just like again that's a
pretty long smelling turb but there's no
really residual smell
Beautiful I'm not waiting very long
either you're noticing edits each time I
grab these I wait about a minute but
it's just long enough that I wouldn't
want you to sit here and watch me you
know blowing on it or whatever so yeah a
minute between each one all right I
think we're
good the reason for us cooling them down
in between uh tur pits as well is
obviously to avoid it from just
evaporating as soon as you put it on a
hot surface
yep cheers brother cheers I'm excited
he's going to go crazy on this one I
know for
sure it's just so overpowering and that
hit is
crazy yeah I must have put a drop in
there
hey if you're going to put oh my God
yeah yeah it's got the zest and The Zing
of the Jack Frost for sure y but then
something
else
lemon well that zest is lemon to me it's
a lemon zest but then there's like
there's this back end of the cleaner of
that of that Jack herrer of that like
strong spicy haziness and it's super
subtle but it's right in the undertones
of the end of the Rip but I can still
taste the first yeah the first
that is so good I could take 10 more of
those me too yeah so which one did we
start with do you remember so the that's
a one no we had didn't we have one other
or is that it one okay perfect so we'll
start in this little corner and we'll
hit a nice uh a nice fres I can't
believe how good that was dude
yeah that was like insane in the
membrane anytime I see the the smallest
amount of turs he just F on the beard
yeah beards like I love it beard oil
beard oil all right so we're going for
some CLL cavella is really nice oo
yeah
Co that was a big
drop it was a good one thank you sir not
going to lie was a good one I mean hey
when you're doing a turp gauntlet with
your buddy who's driven in from the city
with 12 flavors of
tpin and you this is the first time
you've ever used The Vaping tail God is
that nice coming out of those two little
slits on top I never even really looked
at it looks
tight anyway $2.50 dabs those those
quarter dabs are are more than enough
but I have to say when you do an
accidental half drop or a full drop I
don't think you'll be upset said it's
quite a really nice enjoyable way to
enjoy you know not every dab yeah no but
one it's once in a blue moon which I
think you've gotten like three now yeah
they're pretty yeah they're pretty good
I'm definitely not complaining awesome
this just nice it's definitely a great
experience y you know an experience that
I've not had before I've never done
anything like this either and I've done
all sorts of things with the turs
yeah definitely nice hit coming in I'm
sure you'll see the reaction as being a
super
tasty my God yeah what I really loved
about that was it was so smooth the
whole way flavor is really coming out
now like really coming out now when you
say complex it's complex in the sense
that most palletes don't recognize it at
all I could imagine my palette barely
recognized it and now as I'm talking I'm
getting the full Taste of Sour Diesel
coming out in my tongue and around my
lips it's down my throat you get such
satiated turp rips there's no way from
running from that taste it makes sense
that the code for the discount would be
stay melt Stay turpy Stay turpy yeah I
like that you know for the longest while
I was about to melt melt melt and now
it's seems to switched over a little bit
and now because we've achieved the Melt
it's very nice uh compliment to add some
pure cannabis to turbines 100%
all right so we are going for the AF
gooey AF gooey I'm happy about that I'm
definitely happy about
that I'm excited to taste it alone is
what I'm excited for because I haven't
had that yet I've just had it oh you got
a beautiful Drop there okay
beautiful as you guys know he just keeps
giving me bigger and bigger drops and
myself as well included it just seems
like we're we're kind of rounding the
bend here we've got only four flavors
left including this one so he's on his
fourth he's got three left after this
he's got the C orange og creamsicle
coming down the line he's got the Swiss
tsunami are we going to finish it with
the Gorilla Glue wow how was that
different than I thought it was going to
be I only had it with ha wow factor I
like AF goey yeah I just wanted to pull
that guy out exactly we're pretty much
finding that 90% of the time when you go
back for the second rip this thing is so
efficient that you might be tasting the
rip from being
but because the water's not in there the
turs aren't holding the flavor I bet you
if we put a tiny bit of water in there
it would taste like the Jack yeah the
turps would hold that they would be held
in the water so good good hint on that
one Tony for uh letting us know not to
put the water in however as we've gotten
through this super quick it's we'll see
what happens we'll see what happens we
know what's going to happen we know
what's going to happen it's nice yeah it
is nice yeah exactly oh my bad look at
these idiots [ __ ]
that's awesome all right so we're going
to hit this uh AF
gooey super stoked getting kind of used
to the feel of this machine too thought
it was a bit Tippy at first I'm not
feeling that anymore making room for the
extension cord changed everything yes it
defin I'm not knocking the turps
over
uhoh half gooey that W grab me by the
nuts let me tell you little warm or or
just a flavor no it was like the
different way of hitting it I talked for
a few seconds while it was in there so
when I started hitting it it was already
like evaporated in the tube and it just
it was a little more like less oxygen
more turps probably but yeah exactly and
definitely uh I might do the next one
like that too
yeah it definitely does say in the
pamphlet down turn it up definitely does
say in the pamphlet as
well um wait till the The Vapor starts
emitting out of the tube right so there
you go and that's all also not for Pure
turps though so no that's for cannabis
yeah pure turps might be just uh
whatever you like they're your turps
they're your uh you know it's this is a
learning experience um hitting turps
like this and you know of course there's
going to be people that are out there
saying what's the safety precautions is
it safe to be inhaling these we're not
promising you that it is this is
something we're doing on our own and you
feel the urge to try a bioassay with it
as well by no means are we saying we you
should go out and huff tpin 24/7 and and
you'll be fine but I do have confidence
that we have been inhaling these tpin in
profiles in cannabis and hashish for
thousands of years and it hasn't caused
us any problems as of yet so um we'll
see what happens uh in the next 10 years
in the science of learning about these
tpin uh there might be certain ones we
want to Omit there might be ones we want
to breed for that are that are you know
you know the strongest of the modulators
but uh what better way to learn when you
don't have a a chemistry lab than to use
your bioassay and uh and test it out for
yourself yeah you definitely hit the
nail on the head there there's no really
better person to tell you how you feel
from something than yourself yeah you
know and I mean it's true the science
will come out and uh I mean I don't see
any any bad effects coming from this um
just in terms of myself and I've been
using them every day for for a while now
and I'm sure
B man would agree I just like the way
they make me really feel nice and not
nice in a way that's never again
replicated that you're searching out and
you're chasing the way a lot of
different um drugs actually do to
people um like that chasing of the of
the sugar high or chasing of the
whatever kind of uh Speed high I just
find that it's it's a it's the it's
similar it's the same it's always happy
and uplifting
that one was strong was that one strong
that one was the C orange og creamsicle
it it almost tastes like did you turn it
down or did you turn it down great great
I definitely turned it down excellent
excellent oh burn nice and clean or
aerated off nice and clean I'm digging
the files I got to say these these
little uh these little guys could be uh
I'm sure Blue River could figure out a
way to uh make quarter drops available
to just make it real easy to put them in
this of course yeah cuz I'm a little
nervous with my dropper I'm not going to
lie getting my orange
Calo OG
creamsicle and that one just dipped in
there so
beautifully all right so drop that drop
our
T we'll watch for it to come through the
little th there you
go you just see a little bit of a
mushroom cloud emit from the the little
quartz tube
there that's going to be a nice hitting
wow still coming out there you
go holy
[ __ ] that one is nice it's orange creams
go on the start and Calio at the end yes
super
Calo yeah wow I'm just I'm just
completely blown
away by the quality of the flavors yeah
every different variety is a totally
different experience in terms of your
taste buds which leads to a totally
head yeah holy
[ __ ] really
nice really nice Swiss tsunami is next
on the
menu one of my one of my favorite ones
There You Go sir thank you hit that up
it's your
fave these little droppers got to be
careful oh
yeah just a couple more flavors left
Swiss tsunami and the Gorilla
Glue I like the CBD flavors me as well I
always find when I give them to someone
as well they'll be like oh what was that
no matter which one it is if it's a CBD
strain you know one of these ones that
are considered high CB Street CBD why
why I would say that I am definitely
more on lines with what Chimera said on
hash Church a few weeks ago which is I
look forward to the day that we call
these things what the constituents are
that make them up the turpine profile
and the cannaboid profile that's what
the name much so much more than a name
yeah of course you
know it means a lot more to the end end
user than hey this orange creamsicle is
good yeah exactly yeah that the last one
I just hit was phenomenal I'd say almost
the longer you let it emit out the the
the more
flavor
yeah kind of what I noticed on that one
as well that I did like
that oh she's coming right
away definitely one of
them one of the more enjoyable ones
there too really really tasty once again
that's
uh I mean almost hard to describe
definitely fruity it's Jack froses but
not not as zingy yep doesn't linger as
long doesn't linger as long but it's
definitely got or maybe it does but it's
a more subtle less like yeah yeah you
know cuz it's still there yeah it's
overpowering at first and then just
dissipates nicely where some of them
hang around you know you kiss your
girlfriend a half hour later she's going
to go what's that t lingerers the
lingerers [ __ ] lingerers [ __ ]
lingerers that is of course a movie uh
that we are calling out right there and
if you think you know the name of the
Movie that that little scene was from
where Buddy says to his buddy
lingerers type it in the comment section
even if someone already typed it in I
want to see how many of you know what
movie reference that is it's definitely
a stoner movie or a cannabis Enthusiast
movie if you don't like the term Stoner
let's get to our last one bud let's do
it Gorilla
Glue let's do it and I'm feeling pretty
modulated I wouldn't use the word stoned
but I'm definitely feeling
something vibing Vib yeah it's
definitely a good little Vibe it's a
Vibe we're just holding a Vibe down with
12 flavors 12 cultivars of tarpine
profiles here from Blue River extracts
we are of course the Canadian
Distributors for the Blue River extracts
so if you're looking for Blue River
extract you can uh send an email to the
West Coast melt at
gmail.com cuz many many people are going
to say where can I get those Tarpin
where can I get those Tarpin and of
course vapexhale you guys can pick those
up at vapex hail. comom and these guys
have uh they have their [ __ ] together
pretty good they've got a pretty great
um customer service going on and just
all around they want to make it easy for
you use the uh code stay turpy St a y t
e r py and you'll get yourself a nice
$50 value of these nails I think it's
nice to have extra Nails it's definitely
a necessity if you're using uh it's like
having droppers for tpin yeah exactly
you could mix them all up but it's not
as enjoyable of an experience in the end
plus you're paying you know for them so
you want to be able to use them as
efficiently as possible I'll tell you
something that I've never had the
experience of that Darren and I didn't
even have in our turfing Gauntlet and I
guarantee you it has a lot to do with
the water in the pipe each one of these
I got to taste it unadulterated I did
not taste a single rip of one of these
where like particularly where we went
from say uh the Long Valley Kush from
the red congales they're very different
tast tast they have very different
profiles I never tasted one after the
other like you said too less of a
lingerer in the water I believe so it
just yeah it just delivers that profile
that you put in and the quartz every
time has no smell to it other than you
know warm quartz so that leads us to
believe there's no Turpin left in there
yeah pretty cool aspect of the unit for
sure if you're looking to do yourself a
little uh if you're looking to have a
little tarpine party with your friends
and you've got half a dozen to 12
flavors this is defin defitely a nice
option I still for sure the minute we're
done this I'm going to want to do some
TP dipping yeah yeah but that being
said nothing wrong with taking a freshy
oh that was a
big last one so it's got to be went for
like a damn near full drop actually look
at that there you go there you go here
we go let that adid for a rocking that
full drop of the Gorilla Glue oh yeah
let it Adit he says let it Let Her Go
Let Her Go interesting the other one
pushed up
harder
o phenomenal hit that's definitely one
of the bigger
ones if you'll let us
know wow
yeah that was really nice the the doll
was turned down substantially so it was
actually at a much lower temp than I
normally have hit the other
ones that was tasty
good so there we go we've got 12
cultivar of tpen in their purest forms
uh profiles tarpine profiles these are
not uh single tpen in these These are
tpine
profiles that was pretty [ __ ] awesome
I want to give that like an 8.5 out of
10 it was definitely yeah great
experience great unit great T beines
great company I give it a nine out of 10
all right I'll bum I'm bumping mine up
to a nine out of 10 as well we've told
you where you guys can hook up with
these we hope that you enjoyed the video
um we're probably going to go off camera
now and hit many many uh TP dab uh
modulations get those phyto canabo in us
we got the West Coast mounts right here
so the fat lady has some hey thanks for
inviting me up I appreciate it all right
all right guys we'll see you next time
on Bubble man's world cheers guys peace
dud so we just thought we would throw in
uh at the end of this Gauntlet um a
couple of dabs to show you what it's
like to actually do a turp dip so we're
going to hit a little of the West Coast
concentrates we've got some beautiful
Green Crack God 73 and some green crack
God 120 let's go 120 let's do it it's
got such a nice profile and we're trying
it out of the vapex S and we're going to
try it out of the vapex S so I'll turn
it up a little bit we not going to go
big yeah a little I definitely get that
um that impression that it you know it's
super efficient machine so you don't
need to go and drop a big glob on it by
no means I think I want to dip into the
red congales I don't think that's a a
bad
idea so a nice little TP dip as you've
seen what I've done is I've made a clear
bottle vial with one drop next to all my
10 drop vials and those are the vials
that I prefer to dip in I wouldn't want
to dip uh
into a full 10 drops yeah I just don't
think it's a good idea yeah it
definitely it depends if you're smoke if
you're down to the last couple drops you
know we understand that you don't want
to to take it out so there it is just a
tiny little dab in
there I think we're going to have to go
much higher on our temperatures than
just turs yeah just waiting for it to
get green
here and then we'll have a couple of
dabs we'll see what's going on here do
you want to tr try putting some water in
the bom I definitely can all right well
we'll see if we did this correctly we've
got this little guy loaded with a bit of
water I think it's just the top piece
and then the bottom doesn't chug at all
you wouldn't want the water to go in and
and leak into here
so I think I'm going to give it a
shot little bubble dab kind of excited
about
this
wow I'm sure that's going to be quite an
enjoyable
experience doesn't look like it wouldn't
be getting a lot out of that little Dad
too are you kidding
me that was
crazy tiny little bit hot definitely a
little too hot but
efficient
wow that's my first dab all day too for
me
so interesting
too to loaded into a nail and hit it
through a pipe it's just diff it's
taking away the it's definitely taking
away the scooping out and then dropping
at glob and seeing it all bubble you're
really just kind of naive to what's
going on in the in the unit obviously we
know what's going
on damn that was pretty sweet it was
pretty
sweet I'm excited to try it at low
Temp and let's try it at a lower temp
you know it seemed like it gave off a
little bit more than say like a nail
would you know like a little bit more
efficienc put tiny pie in too man I know
I've seen
that it would have been something that
you and I would have dabbed yeah exactly
no problem and we had to split that one
and it was still strong what would you
like to TP dip into for this one um we
do
let's you pick you
pick I'm grateful either way oh go for
the Kush cleaner that's a great pick I
that's why I let him pick
I figured if I'm going to pick for you
yeah and for me I might as well pick
something that we're going to fiend over
yeah and you know it's looking like we
thought that we were hitting the turps
on uh such a low temp but it's almost
like I think we should we should try
hitting the hash on that low temp as
well and it would little bit lower
anyway I think we you we had it turned
up substantially more although it gave a
cloudy Rippy super cloudy you know what
I'm saying definitely know what you're
saying all right so here we go let's put
this
in turn that down a little bit than you
sir just going to wait see a little bit
let it heat up yeah dude tasty super
tasty I'll take a drink of water before
clear my palette with as it went
green oh look at that it's coming up the
bottom that is ready to
rip oh you can smell this
that's unbelievable I'm pretty surprised
at how much it's ripping for sure like I
smoke cash all day day there's twice as
much in there this time I'll grab a
little HP
too God does that smell
[Music]
good that's one of my favorite ones so
far that
combination whoa
wow that cush cleaner is
unbelievable does it tastes good as if
you're getting 40 rips from it at least
10 I'm glad we showed them what it was
like with the hash cuz we're doing just
pure turp
rips people might not have realized that
this thing is a champion if you want to
actually take Serious [ __ ]
hits
wow and he did by no means put like a
quarter of a gram dab in there maybe a
0.1 maybe 2 jeez she's done though
that's
phenomenal I love this little wooden
wooden guy too
it's well I'm going to give a big thumbs
up to the vapix hail um really really
glad that we threw some bubble hash in
there from the West Coast concentrate
crew
dabbed it up uh Ted it up with uh with a
couple of nice flavors the cush cleaner
being like an all-time new favorite up
there with the master Scout Jack Frost
combo yes and uh yeah you uh you guys
need any more information about this
video I'll put it down in the comment
sections but once again thanks for
watching Bubble man's world see you guys
next time peace