hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
Johnny B is in the house yo Apex yeah I
was just getting it ready I like it I
like it with the Trippy Stick straight
glass oh yeah on there beautiful I I
kind of like it that way just hits
really rip it so listen we're giving you
a quick message today I'm going to
upload this right away we are heading
down to Pacific Northwest garden
supplies in Squamish British Columbia
which is on the way up to Whistler down
the SE to sky highway we going to um
celebrate vendor day we got a barbecue
there's going to be some tunes some
barbecu we're going to be hitting the
Dil like it's going out of style we're
going to be promoting our products John
will be there answering questions about
medtainers and talking about dry sifting
and the fresh headies tools I'll be
there answering questions about wet
washing and dry sifting and basically if
you guys have any questions for me and
John and you want to come by Remo's
going to be there as well as well as
some other vendors method sevens method
sevens which I've always got mine I love
you in the P love my geopod so you know
what we also grow onx for uh dealing
with the water filtration and stuff like
that there's a lot of good vendors out
here today owners of companies are
coming down to educate you so come on
out this is the day one this is uh this
is this is well I call it Mission
Mondays but today it's melty Mondays
it's melty Mondays in Squamish so we
hope to see you down there and uh keep
watching Bubble man's world
peace it's perfect how we both walk