[Music]
hey guys how's it going welcome to
Bubble man's world sitting here with
d420 K we are uh we're really just
getting over that turp SES aren't we
yeah holy Christ holy [ __ ] man that was
some goodness right there I have to say
that uh I went home and napped it just
tasted so good I was just remember six
hours I got home at 5:00 I got up at 9
or 10 [ __ ] oh I slept like a [ __ ]
LA and then I got up for hour went back
to bed yep I didn't wake up till the
next day at like 9:30 it was a sleep in
for me by like several hours nice so uh
D and I are here outside of the hospital
at the Vancouver General Hospital we're
going to go visit our buddy Johnny B who
just had some uh spinal surgery a
surgery he's been waiting on having for
literally a decade and a bit so it'll be
neat to see him I'm not sure if he's
going to want to be on camera probably
knowing Johnny B he'll be welcome to be
on camera but def we'll let him decide
for now we thought we would just have a
little TP dip got the purple punch TPS
got some uh purple candy Master Scout
bubble hash and uh we literally
literally just went and scooped up water
from the puddle on the street dirty
Vancouver bong dirty Vancouver bong
water we don't give a [ __ ] post your
comments right off the streets right off
the streets of Vancouver although this
Street's pretty
clean yes it is it was a clean
puddle as far as like you know when you
say dirty East Vancouver I bet you I
could find a dirtier spot well we could
go down to Pigeon Park oh find a puddle
of piss yeah that's disgusting I'm sure
of it or a piss in it pissing it plus h
[ __ ] everything else just pissing it
let me turn that truck off so we don't
get that vibration there we go there we
go maybe this guy in the layered Wheaten
will just drive right into the back of
us oh that was a disappointing little I
heard it no I'm not looking for it I'm
pulling out a new one it's probably in
here somewhere well maybe if we were
actually [ __ ] it's my truck crack or
something we might spend about 4 days
looking for that one we dropped after
we're finished doing what we're going to
do now right or in between Hoots but uh
we don't do that so well that's probably
why I have like 10 gram of hash on my
floor yeah I've got little nuggets all
over little hash spots all over my floor
around my [ __ ] computer desk too oh
yeah yeah yeah where you Puff the most
for sure right yeah all right well I'm
going to break this in half cuz it's
unnecessary with the TPS to quite go
that big but let's go dipping it into
some some
purple oh yeah
such a nice smell such a nice smell of
the purle punch beautiful we're going to
torch this nail
up little bit of
water oh thank you there D oh look you
found the piece of
hash the one that I dropped I'm not even
joking that's it it just fell out of
that toilet paper when this did yep not
even joking bro I couldn't make that
[ __ ] up
that was amazing that is awesome cuz the
other one's in the
jar that's awesome that was pretty funny
well see I'm like what the hell that's
what happens the universe you think I
was going to burn you there I was just
making sure you weren't
good the universe treated us very well
by returning that piece of hash right to
the [ __ ] spot he was going to put it
yep I got a little glass jar for uh
using as my carb cap oh it cooled off
pretty fast actually
yeah not bad TP dip bong rip let's make
this happen TP dip bong rip TP
dip yeah those videos
are pretty funny but I get
bored that's
all they're
great oh my
gosh I love the fact that we're
uh
medicating before we head into the
hospital yes I like
that oh my god did that taste delicious
even through the dirty Vancouver puddle
water I have to say that was pretty
delish let's get Darren a TP rip bong
rip that purple
punch remember the purple punch was the
one that brought you back
[Music]
M purpley purpley goodness so yeah we're
going to see Johnny B doubt we're going
to have a session with him but I'm
definitely bringing the turps in so we
can smell them and then uh we're going
to see breeder Steve also so hopefully
we'll get to film a little bit with him
see if he wants to go on camera and do a
little bit of chatty chatty chatting
oh yeah milking
it it's a rainy ass day in the city but
uh you know after a bong rip well
actually it was after Darren told that
woman to [ __ ] off really super loud out
of the window everything changed from
that moment on it was kind of like a
heavy Vibe we were a little bit kind of
having a rough morning and then then
someone just gave me the finger for
basically for nothing for nothing and it
was his opportunity Darren saw the
opportunity there's the plug if I can
just pop that off all of this will
release I opened the window just that
much just so I could get my lips out
even so they could hear me it was like
that and just was [ __ ] you it was loud
it was anyone that had ever listened to
Hash Church would have been like that
sounded like d420 K but I think it was
[ __ ] you instead of bong rip it was
[ __ ] loud so loud that when Mark took
a look in his rearview mirror at that
moment it's true they both they turned
around turned around with chicken heads
chicken necks chicken headed it rubber
necked it rubber neck and like hard core
it was we were we were a half a block
away by the time you actually got the
window open and said that half a block
away yeah it was uh a good Vancouver
City Block
half oh yeah two bong two bong reps
before we head in to see Johnny B yep
I'm going to bring him in a little pen
to smoke if he doesn't have one of his
own just in case he wants a rip or
anything you know yeah TP dip yeah and
uh go say hi hi to Johnny last night I
talked to him and you know he said he
feels 100% better and uh Johnny is the
type of guy that will say I'm feeling
good when he's not because he's just
doesn't want to put his energy out on
people like that but I phoned him and
asked him
and he told me the vibrations the the
the the pains that he'd get in his arms
and his leg and all that kind of stuff
have are gone like literally he got out
of surgery on his neck he's in a neck
brace he's in a hospital bed and he's
saying I feel 100 [ __ ] per. that's
something man I'm really really happy
for [ __ ] a he said the same thing to
me
JB JB yeah like we're going to see him
right away let's get you a rip this is
awesome and then we'll go see Johnny B
we'll go see Johnny B Big Johnny
hopefully he's doing real
good I love that too he said the same
thing to me about the uh vibrations
being gone and yeah it's a big deal
having that kind it's a lifechanging
thing man who could even imagine right
who could you I got into a little I got
into a little go-kart accident in
September I remember and I actually had
a fracture in here somewhere I still got
to talk to the doctor after after the
MRI now the feelings the the vibrations
and the little bits of shooting pain
that I get from that down my arm and
down this leg MH man Johnny [ __ ]
probably has gone through some
unbelievable pains with his injuries
true I just said sorry to D because I
just gave him a pretty big dab my
goodness look at this get it in
there big for TP dab in anyway you know
I know a lot of the people watch
watching they rip way bigger rips uh but
with the TPS it's it's very very
different this is an awesome one oh
yeah all right well let's just put this
pipe down here on the on the in the
little hole there and we're going to
grab this camera we're going to go see
uh Johnny B I need to put point
something out point it out it was the I
think it was the Purple Venom that
brought me back it was the straw the
Venom that brought me back the purple
punch was the one that punched me right
in the face that's right it did and I
had that out the end we'll hit the Venom
OG when we get back to the car that's
what I'm saying all right see should
look and make sure they're all closed
right I
try d420 K is just bused my nuts about
the tpine vials right now yep so that's
a vgh right in front of us yes sir looks
like the Batman Building I am just
peeled right now I feel you dude that's
the word I like to use PE elevated [ __ ]
yeah
saturated all right
well here we
go it's cold
hey come up
here and then it says do not enter do
not feed the birds feed the birds of
course we're going to feed the
Birds bir
in
information yep that's where we're
heading right to information
sorry what time easy
peasy easy peasy
all the way down to the
elevators Centennial El
Wicked yeah you know
what I so far haven't gotten the creeps
[Music]
room 946 I think he said
right yeah he wrote me a text is that
what he said 946 yeah he said
946 99 this
way down the road
yep
[Music]
946 this way
942 943 945 we're getting real close
it's going to be this one on the right
or the left all right I think it's this
one right here 946
yep 946
dude Johnny B hitting the pen is are you
hitting a
pen oh my god dude it's just a hospital
crazy to see you up in the bed dude how
uh tell us tell us what's the deal that
was a big deal that's 10 years in the
waiting 11 years in the waiting for what
you just went through
well easy and simple um posterus
cervical L be Fusion C3 to C6 they took
out my C4 because my spin cord was
deflated and compressed so when they
took the C4 off my spinal cord inflated
like a balloon and with that gave me my
relief the burning of my knees went away
and the burning of my my feet my hands
had neuropathy so that's changed that's
vibration that been in my body for the
last 10 years it's gone it really took
an effect on July 14th in 2014 when I
got a car accident and it pinched the
cord and it caused major and that's
where the burning really started and
that's where they found what was
happening and here we are in almost like
a year and a half two years later
and damn I had surgery yesterday they
took it it's like jeez you got an open
wound in the back of your neck and your
feeling great oh dude don't be moving
don't be moving you're freaking me out
you don't have to move be hey guess what
we brought TPS for you d420 has got the
TPS in the in the Pelican we thought
we'd come give Johnny B A little bouquet
flavor of TS we're on the spinal W so
this is the c unit and this is where a
lot of trauma people are so you hear
alarms going off and stff you hear on on
on on support systems and breather and
stuff like that so I'm actually very
lucky to be but I mean this this is a
very serious word and yeah I'm I'm quite
uh I mean inous cuz I got and I was able
to stand up and most people know I have
to get up cuz my knees burn so bad my
knees don't burn anymore and and that
was that's that's 10 years in the making
of my these BR and so what uh what are
you choosing to do for um I mean
obviously they must have you on all
sorts of medications or the Medicare
excellent and and of course I have my
supplements this was the peanut butter
bar that you ate earlier that I ate
earlier what I was doing with that was
put pure CBD oil on it actually I got
Pure CBD and I'm using the CBD for
inflammation on that I got this of
course I have my whole little array of
oh yeah you got the meds right there I
got my green bars I got my suppositories
but you have any Turpin I have no tur
then that's what we brought we filling
yeah we've got the whole whole tray full
of tpin for Johnny B to uh to go through
and check out so many flavors here dude
it's ridiculous like uh let's see this
one is oh this one's purple punch here
let him smell this one purple me open
that up and just give that a little waft
under your nose uh close and far as you
know to catch to catch the
uh purple punch on that
one
wow not too shabby hey but how it
affects pain
and and for me because of my neck what
I'm going through this is this is what
we call like really medical right so I I
can feel it like it's it's like it's
taking
that that relief off but then it comes
back right away cuz now it's coming back
again right now yeah it goes away right
away when you smell it pain isn't there
I call it the wow factor hypers
sensitivity that's interesting oh
yeah let's uh let's do that do that
interesting look at that you got the
hole we just shut this thing up bro we
just shut this thing up where's the
light switch I mean
Jesus I don't the red one no that's says
exam should be a light switch right
there yeah right should be a right light
switch right there should be right
behind
there Swit either there on the wall yeah
it says exam it's a red switch is there
one that pulls no oh yeah yeah there's
one that pulls go oh yeah damn I did not
want to touch anything on this wall
there's a switch right there this one
that says suction
regulator TPS hosital food get in there
D oh check it
out water little tea bag in
it do some modulation with
this orang juice little smelling little
TP in here I'll get you another flavor
to smell so that was the purple punch oh
I want him to try the red Congo oh AF
[ __ ]
actually AF gooey
actually there we
go having a huge session at Johnny be's
hospital
bed oh it'll go suck on it it's just
doesn't have a a lid but it uh a
mouthpiece sorry a lid
[Music]
pachios you kind of got a like it's a
little it's a little slow going we'll
reload
it um a goey gooey a
gooey so many wonderful flavors to smell
oh
wow that's amazing isn't that nice that
one's got a a variety of flavors going
on in it and it's very uplifting yeah I
don't know if it's fruity though or if
it's what it is but it's definitely
like even from here I can smell it
really strong it's like a cushy and then
it's got like a fruity to but yeah it's
like Fruity cushy yeah like a fruity
which changes the fruit aspect fruit
bowl maybe that's going slightly bad
that that that that first one I could
actually feel how help this one didn't
the purple punch help it just it kind of
something a little release or something
it released this one does
well we've got a ton to go through here
so let's uh put this one
away try that purple punch
back let's try strawberry mind
warp man I like that one I always smell
like a strawberry banana esque smell as
I take it away after you do get banana
right and if you smell it enough times
you'll that banana turns into you can
see the similarities between a
strawberry have that that purple punch
again yeah I just want to see something
right
now just got to find it I'm getting this
noodle soup with slight hints of
TPS which is nice yeah it's not bad
purple
punch even the lid is it it does
actually here for 10 minutes my pant I I
was curious cuz the other two weren't
but this one is smell it off the lid
it's coming
really strong off the
lid like it actually the smell is so
there it's like the pain goes like
this interesting and because I'm sitting
here in pain right I can only imagine
right so um but the other two didn't
that's why I wanted to P back on that
yeah I was just curious I was just
curious because one thing you're looking
at is Hell tur are mulating everything
right here's one that uh everyone loves
chem
dog yep I remember that
one and when I bring it to here here's
the difference the lids are killing how
about this when I go here exactly helps
with my pain when I take it away it's
gone really with the purple punch it's
it takes longer for the pain to come
back
interesting what I noticed with it is
that from different angles and distances
from my nose I could smell things that I
don't smell otherwise like they have
their very fine areas of where you can
pick that
subtle smell up yeah it's
interesting I'm zooming in on Johnny's
bolt marks like Frankenstein see that
yeah they bolted my head actually bolted
me to a table bolted his head to the
table screwed his head right to it yeah
all that one a little
smell that is the red congales
M the red
con land race tpin tpin that aren't
present in a lot of the other flavors
that they have similarities and
differences but the differences between
SM this is different smoother yeah it's
just with that little bit of spice in
the background that's that's part of
that Haze family where you you catch it
at the end and like oh that's the
haze yeah dude it's one of the ones I'm
the most excited about I'm not going to
lie I can really tell by smelling it
yeah it's right away it's like that's
Mark it's super uh uh beautiful oh
here's a nice
one everyone loves this
one lemon
cush lemon Cush
the I love I love
Kush and this one isn't doing anything
for
my interesting not like like the last
one that l r one did purple punch was
the strongest purple punch was the
strongest cuz like I just feel my neck
right now it's like interesting and all
we're really doing is having light
smells right but this is the whole thing
of tped modulate right we all that so
for me this is huge you'll like this
one that's quite a difference in smells
that's the orange
creamsicle oh man I'm telling you like
the lids are incredible the more P this
smell the more it l you the that's nice
tilt brain it takes over your brain and
it's also like what I find about it
that's strange is when I smell it I find
that I want to
picture pictures in my mind this this is
you know if that makes any sense this is
another one so this is like four orange
cream is good I think you're also going
to like pineapple cream I pretty much
love
turs well exactly obviously
obviously that you love turs pineapple
cream how did I do
that that's a deserty
tasting and smelling like a like whipped
cream and fruit salad with dominating
pineapple in it like my paint still
there the other ones are taking over it
that makes sense and it's I'm just like
for me I'm just like you know close your
eyes and really like breathe it in
gently not just really close but also
from a distance yeah and and it's it's
it's almost like it's enhancing a little
bit of fig so tense right
now
wating making a tense
wating so we can find ones that we don't
guaranteed there's going to be turps
that heal and the turps that basically
don't Pur another great
one I really like this one and someone
told me it was sunset sherbet crossed
with OG KB or something OG something and
they said in those Sunset KB in the
comments KB stands for kind bud yeah oh
my God I saw that I was like oh I never
knew that yeah an OG stands for Original
Gangster or ocean gr it's not ocean got
it ocean GR how's that though Sunset KB
it's okay okay I like it oh I love it
let's leave Johnny doesn't like the turp
no Johnny Hates the
turps maybe it's
cuz had a whole bunch of [ __ ] smells
of it
already got too many TPS in his nose
pette like oh this one's interesting
chocolate
[Music]
go from a distance and then slowly kind
of bring it up so until you can just
it's on the edge of really being
powerful cuz some of them are also too
strong to smell right close to your
notse some are good I like the pineapple
cream and the orange cream schull and
the purple punch this is this is help
for close this is triple OG I'm not
surprised with
that oh yeah it's deep that one's deep
hits the right I just felt that one yeah
go into me like down my old factory and
it's like it's soothing my pain it's
just like I I can't wait to watch this
cuz I'm going to be curious right yeah
of
course that's another Smo again I'd like
to talk to Tony about it well hopefully
Tony's coming up here one of these days
sooner than later or if not maybe one
day our Jamaica project will we'll get
off the ground and we'll be able to go
down and do the good work do the good
work we were so inclined to do that is
the Gorilla
Glue it's also a very strong strain what
got doing it for
you as I thought it would it's not it's
just like it's a strong one yeah no but
different right different than what your
what would really be cool is if we had
an idea as to the um
profile this one's the Blue
Dream interesting
you know pretty pretty pretty popular
strain down in Cali can can be grown on
a commercial level and still produce a
pretty nice product but see see if my
paint was turned on it was like a nine I
SM this think it's turning it down to
like a four a five ohly [ __ ] I'd be Hing
on That All Night the other tur the
other one's turning it down to like a
four the first one's turning it down to
it's like my Pain's high and it's like
turning as mod say the other ones
weren't a few of these
are I used to do it with um eucalyptus
oil okay headaches i' kind of like
breathe in you could lifp too and then I
just felt a little bit of a relief so I
can kind of understand where you're
coming from but obviously I've never had
spine surgery bro I can't imagine what
you feel like right now plus they
screwed into your head your head must
hurt it does holy Christ what is that I
was like oh they drill holes in my co
scar had to drill your head cool
scars cool scar yeah right away Darren
was stoked on that this is the cheese
bomb you get some [ __ ] bolts tattooed
on each one of those
scars you could they're right on your
hairline
yeah fenom no is this Venom OG
or I I think it
is let me smell just like turning it
down like a seven that the first one
that we pulled out there that blue one
cheesy that purple punch that one so far
is me much like that one that line r one
Cherry AK-47
I like cherries though I like when his
eyes eyebrows go up Darren's into my bed
right now looking at stuff check this
[ __ ] off I know he's all like filming
the corner of the room like looking down
I'm watching you you actually had it
perfectly
framed when I saw you doing that I was
like what I would end up doing if I
didn't I know cuz I look over Dude I
take my eyes off the camera for a second
second and I'm out of frame dude but he
does have the nice wide angle L well
buddy you've yelled at me too many times
and beat me with sticks that to make me
not Cherry AK-47 [ __ ] screw that up I
cannot screw that up on the camera I
like that one a lot I like I hate
getting beat up by my bro bubble M for
some purple hand M uses a stick a big
one but it's made out of toilet
paper it still hurts
like a fourth this yeah purple Hindu I
had a feeling you were going to like it
I don't know if it just has that purple
name in it and the purple's hdden full
full uh I want him to smell that that
strawberry Purple Venom the or Venom OG
Venom yeah we're going to get to that
one very soon cuz it's one of the last
ones that we have left to do you can
leave this one behind too awesome there
was one moment in there that I hit the
pause button Yeah by accident it's okay
and I clicked it right back on right
away like it was it it be a transition I
missed a
second all right so what's up we made it
back uh we're here at breeder Steve's
apartment uh little condo complex me and
d420 K and Max and Dom Max and Dom are
in the house from the sunrise Wellness
what Center Foundation Foundation I like
it I like it so these guys are some
young connoisseurs in the city they
brought some nice buds for us to look at
and some uh some of Horatio's pure thca
and some other nice glass and such
things so why don't we just get right to
it and check out what do we got here got
some hash plant 13 this is a temple of
KX strin really awesome organic Artisan
Culvers theyve got some really nice
exotic strains it's absolutely beautiful
I really want to photograph it with my
macro lens another day that old school
that old school kind of heaviness yeah
exactly what do we got here next one is
the hashme
hashme also by the temple
the temple very nice very nice looks
very clean
and looks organic like got that really
earthy kind of flavor yeah looks earthy
exactly and then finally here some
warlock oh the Warlock remember the
Warlock Steve what did Steve go Steve
had this amazing warlock from Magus
genetics back in the day in Lugano
Switzerland and uh I went to visit him
one time and got to make some really
nice uh water hash from it
beautiful very nice very ni nice
excellent i've smoked some of the quite
a bit of the product from their guys'
shop what do you got here as well right
here I'm just rolling up some Bubba pie
crossed with the uh let me have a smell
of that on camera so they can get the
turp expression I haven't smelled this
yet oh yeah that's definitely pie yeah
cherry pie
M yeah the Bubba pie cross red hid new
I've never been disappointed with
anything I've smoked from their shop
let's check out their glass piece here
in our last minute of this video as we
run out of our so tell us about this uh
piece of glass real quick so the main
the main piece is by brosan quest Quest
did the tube brosi did the marbles and
then uh little Alex Inwood bucket on
there everybody did a really good job on
that yeah damn I thought the bucket was
came with the piece for sure for sure he
did a really nice job on that looks
proper well awesome guys thanks for
joining us here on Bubble man's world
for such a short little visit we're
going to get tpin we got all 18 flavors
of tpps and maybe next time we catch up
with you guys you can let us know what
you thought of the TPS let do it I'm
good awesome all
righty we are out
[Music]