[Music]
oh yeah all right wicked hey we want you
talking but come without them we'll go
when do people run she look cosplayer
look who's here it's a bubble man's
world evolved over time respect I
haven't seen you here once to have your
back with respect old time friend
respect friend for life we ready
[Applause]
[Music]
come on down real good
herbs jump into pools for its proper
you push the power button you see the
red little time it's recording all right
welcome to bubble man's world I'm
sitting here with Kevin from steamteam
Jamaica the original vaporizer just the
steam chalice if you've never been never
smoked or vaporized from the unit like
this you you can't believe it until you
tried it truly is the original vaporizer
that all these volcanoes and other units
that have come years later this is the
roots sitting in you know while does
ganja field at the Blue Hole is is not
too bad either
right and Dabin we're gonna do some six
star bubble hash dabs on top of the
steam showers mm-hmm Robin wood esteemed
team you know em on its a J anything
right now
really I'd mind vibration all right give
thanks to the Bob lush niceness you know
yeah and if you want forget this steam
charters you can always check out a
little bit of that steam tmz.com I mean
made a vaping experience much much nicer
you know blessings I have one at home
that I got out here that I quite enjoy
it's just a matter of getting used to
the the procedures of having the husk
being able to create the coal being able
to you know keep your coochie clean and
and take care of the unit you know
changing the water out of the coconuts
good you know don't leave that in there
for too long it becomes stagnant you
smoke throughout a day no problem but at
the end of the day dump out water take
care of it like you would take care of
any pipe yeah keep it fresh on keeping
with our fresh Lord you know give thanks
for blazing open with a steam team well
mine yeah my respect go for it the
greens greens fun to see you now check
the greens pond the scene we're
surrounded by them it's great some
wonderful tastes smells in the air all
right so this is at Angie as well yeah
it's beautiful sets our tangent yeah
right this is [ __ ] that's for where
you and I live that's just that's just
definitely do that's what I'm saying
doesn't matter where it's from no it's
just an if is it is a tank or is it not
there but you don't see like not
everyone's producing this quality or in
Jamaica in Jamaica true enough Yemen
some though I wonder what Geronimo is
I'd like to link with him again one day
soon I don't know years ago look at that
custom trim by wobba himself yeah one
inspecting this crazy guy jumping off of
trees guys that nothing to save mine oh
yeah I'm on your side mine
oh man whew my girl
yeah my who's going 40k a different
tangent yeah are we steam in that what's
going on yeah I figured some I can't be
mean okay are more if only we had a
steamer we have a steam joke is it's
always a change it's never not steaming
yeah you know that's what's up rooftop
session yeah yeah
when they just left them up yeah they
said the table with you Oh beautiful a
great place to fly a drone
yeah yeah right I mean come on so what's
the name of that one now that was the
Congo twister twister is this all
twister no let me see the twister is
just for the camera need to get into a
better light yes yes yes
[Applause]
it's dense it's nice I know this but the
baby just gave me
bubbleman we are yeah it's raining
button thanks I'm dad we are absolutely
gonna take some devs I'm gonna film for
a few minutes and I'm gonna pull up my
dab rig and we're gonna hit some dabs I
just love that wobba is just trimming
I'll just sit in here we just missed
your second down there we go wicked yeah
my taste man awesome sweet sweets we got
mighty nice and all these beautiful
cured buds beautiful
[Music]
you