hey everybody welcome to bubble man's
world and welcome to the wake-and-bake
episode 88 and what a kind of funny
little time we had in the chat this
morning I've already given away a karmic
up ru elite pin one more time you have
until the 28th to get your entries into
the karmic up if you're gonna be a part
of it come down and see me I'll have a
booth and I'll be chillin up down there
doing my thing I guess
in the mean time how is everybody
MP that was pretty funny someone won the
contest this morning I'm like send me
your address and he sends me his address
but he wasn't the guy that won so we
were laughing about that definitely not
a problem MP it was all in good fun and
oh no sound I hope you have sound can
everybody hear me or is there no sound
on this here we can fix this no there
should be sound
can anyone hear me or is there literally
no sound I just need to know if one
person can hear me I'll continue on no
sound at all well that's weird
oh I can hear it screw you guys that
throws me off too let me tell you
alright let's start with a wake-and-bake
because let's be honest I need one there
is sound look at the chat room just
blowing out can't even keep up with that
[ __ ]
gonna have a nice little wake and bake
this morning if we can get the oil from
being stuck to my fingers it's really
not coming off is it sometimes little
shards of rosin can stick to your finger
in a way that you just can't get it off
I think I'm just gonna stop trying
because really it's not so bad to have a
little rosin on your fingers right a
little bit of Ross on the fingers wake
and Bakey we're doing a turf dip today
oh yeah we're going in deep we're going
in for some lemon tannin I love me some
candid dad oh she's fine she's so so
fine his D 420k okay with all the fire
yes I believe he is d 420k is up in
Prince George not in Prince William's as
dr. Natasha had said in the episode two
days ago so I think he's okay
yeah alright then let's let us hit well
let us hit this dab in membranous of all
those who have no dabs well Manitoba
dude you know how its it goes my friend
He Who smelt it dealt it so I'm guessing
it was you my friend
shall we alright let's do it
hope everyone's ready come on big
squirrel nuts
Leatherface coot Daryl Cornell and melty
heads flu and Bret Q stinky bomb NYC
4/20 wild dragon Dylan Thomas and Gann
skis Martin Olsen's thank you for
smoking pot nine-inch colas and Pedro
Robles thank you everyone for coming in
dude I don't make the rules bro whoever
smelt it dealt it can I say hey right on
your sounds not on that's pretty much
what I saw there's no shell there's no
sound it's like we'll turn your [ __ ]
sound on my god Kayleigh that was in
Negril where we recorded that me and
Omar you want to hit some full melt yes
[Laughter]
how many times a day do you rip well as
often as I can I'm not gonna lie ripping
doesn't really affect me the way it
affects a lot of the people that I smoke
with I don't really get destroyed
well sticks the way you get a legends
shirt does you go to legends you don't
get a legend shirts if you don't go to
legends and each shirt is unique and
different to the legends that you would
go to and so of course I could make a
ton of cash selling legends shirts
people asking for them all the time but
I think the really cool thing about
legends is that if you don't go you just
you don't get to represent you have to
go to represent oh dude last Sunday's
hashed Church was my favorite my top
favorite it made me realize that nobody
on the panel is the most important that
has Church is bigger than all of us and
that we proved it by all of us leaving
the panel and having a completely
different panel Natasha did a pretty
incredible job along with Hilary in
moderating and organizing and setting up
all those women they straight owned
hashed hurts let me tell you I'm not
sure if they knew how well they were
doing the whole time but I know some of
the women were a little uncomfortable
that they don't normally talk in that
sort of setting but well my thoughts on
that DJ 3000 who asked I'd like to know
your thoughts on CBD isolate do you
think it's a good idea or do you believe
in the full plant extraction try not to
get locked up in one's own belief
systems do I think it's a good idea of
course it's a good idea regardless of
whether it's gonna be a good idea for me
I know it's gonna be a good idea for
someone monomolecular medicines along
with terpenes can be made into very
accurate recipes that can be recreated
time and time again and for people who
suffer from Crohn's and from the
Parkinson's and from different forms of
epilepsy particularly neurological
problems they require sometimes very
specific ratios that need to be very
very accurate
when we grow cannabis sometimes
variables can change something can
change from one crop to the next and you
can actually change your terpene profile
just enough that you probably would not
see the same effects for that patient
now so for me I want everything that we
have I just because I don't use mono
molecular medicine doesn't mean that I
wouldn't fight for it and I would
certainly say the people who are against
it why not spend your time and your
energy maybe doing something a little
bit more positive like fighting for what
you want that you don't have rather than
fighting against something people do
have and that they do want we got to
stop fighting for what's already there I
mean for real
that's my opinion and I think it was a
great question and I was happy to answer
it made me feel like another bond rapid
knocking lie knocking my god the bar
grab Turk gifts are just so delicious I
think I'm gonna go in for some lemon
tree this time I will go for a little
bit of smaller dab the new pen was
designed to work with Terp sauce that's
not to say it won't work with a whole
bunch of other things but we designed
the new pen to work with a terpene
infused rosin like distillate which is
not a distillate we didn't use any
chemical petrochemical solvents I think
that you guys will see the pen is gonna
be very nice it's we've been working on
it for almost a year just so you know
this shirt I think this shirt is like 25
bucks
it's a embroidery so it's a it's a hard
patch you can get him up at bubble bag
calm exactly so Dauntless sauce all
these people have been doing these a
distillate pens and they put in fruit
terpenes or whatever gold dropped put in
the blue river terpenes and they were
crushing it so it was really a true
inspiration from gold drop and our
friend Gary who owns Omicron that maybe
we should create our own pen I told Tony
I can't put my name on just any pen I
just can't do it I I don't like the idea
of people buying pens and throwing them
away that's so [ __ ] wasteful so we
started talking about eight months
to go and started discussing the idea of
potentially creating a reusable pen a
pen that can be refillable and a pen
that has no wires no solder no
insulation no plastic no motherboards
near the element that can that can heat
up so it's listen we may learn that the
pen can be improved even even better but
trust that Tony and myself and Gary has
spent eight months designing and
creating and coming up with this pen so
that we could feel good about putting
the bubbleman brand in the Blue River
brand terpene name on that pen as well
as Omicron because I mean he does really
high-end work I wouldn't want him to put
his brand name on anything that was less
than the best so that's what we're
trying for we should have them by August
first and for those of you that are
wondering yes we are selling them filled
up with rosin and terpenes that'll be in
the California market Tony has a new
company that he's working with that is a
delivery service called Anki delivery
and that's going to be delivering those
pens all over California we definitely
gonna be bringing the Pens to Jamaica
I'm hoping on getting the Pens up in
Canada once the legal mechanism exists
for that and we'll try to get it into as
many states as we can for now we're
focused on Cali keep in mind the Pens
for us was like it's kind of like the
bubble box the pen is very much like the
bubble box I want to turn people on to
how to enjoy these extracts with
terpenes and without in a way that is
next-level
and so if we can get them the best pen
possible that leads them into a dabbing
experience because that's what the pen
is like it's like hitting a really nice
dab it is so unbelievably tasty you
can't believe it and the bubble box was
a very similar thing I was sending
selling the bubble box to people who are
joint smokers and I was trying to teach
them about making hash so they'd be
breaking up their buds and rolling their
joints over this little screen I'd tell
them you know you know after many joints
lift up the screen card through this
first screen to this to the bottom and
then card for awhile and suddenly people
who were just smoking joints we're
getting full melt dry stuff the holy
grail of extracts there's many
paths down this road of extraction and
trust me they're exciting each and every
one of them but the end of the path is
perfectly grown micro encapsulated
glandular trichomes resin heads isolated
to near perfection 99.9% heads yeah you
know how it's the Holy Grail ask anyone
if they have it next time you're at a
cannabis event and there's like hundreds
of people in the audience and if you're
up on stage say hey could you please put
your hand up if you have full melt dry
sift and you might see a couple of hands
go up I did it at the Cannabis Cup years
ago everyone will have oil everyone will
have oil boxes and boxes of oil
very few people although much more than
in the past will have a full mount
bubble hash you know maybe maybe a dozen
maybe two dozen but full melt dry sift
you'll be very very very surprised that
just not many people have it it's not
that often that you see it 99.9% heads
that's that 99 dunk him up on me this
stuff was just both of these were not
really what I would call now these are
99.9 percent heads however both growers
didn't really hit the mark and so they
were kind of like what does full melt
actually mean okay nine-inch colas a
long time ago and about not 2000 maybe I
was at the Cannabis Cup and I was
hanging out with skunk man Sam and we
were smoking on his full melt you know
clear dome dry sift and we were smoking
on it on a screen on a very tight tight
stainless steel screen in his little
pipe and I'd be like yeah when it's when
it when it melts like water I call it
full melt and then Sam says yeah and
when it's really really high quality not
only will it melt like water but it'll
bubble up these big giant clear domes
and I'm like yeah that's the full melt
clear dome and that's literally the
moment that we point the phrase FM CD as
well as full melt and as well as clear
dome both all three different kind of
titles if you will so that's where those
titles came to be
that's right Connor Jake is very few
people have it and when you have it
you're a rock star look at cubed he has
it rock star you know suddenly that [ __ ]
disappears less of a rock star it's the
big it's a big deal to have full melter
I sift not many people have it and it's
one of the things that bubble man brand
is absolutely going to be bringing you
in California in the very near future
already been talking with some people
about sift that they have to clean and
well Macke
Chloe grow something I believe was his
name that one he I asked who took the
picture of me in the Avatar which was me
smelling the buds in Jamaica and he said
Johnny B and I said you won and so he
won so let's have another rib shall we
let's do it yes I did zero one two three
four five six seven eight nine nine
eight seven six five four three two one
zero
nice palindrome name by the way I like
the space it really sets the tone hard
to say it depends on how much we pay for
the pounds I mean we just really you
know we're not trying to destroy people
we're trying to sell the for the lowest
price possible
yeah I'm hitting the Sapphire aqua every
time I'm at home I'm hitting the
Sapphire
unless I'm torching and then obviously
I'm hittin the quartz
well the escrow Tacoma we do use local
retail partners ideally ideally people
that have licensing in place that are
already growing or have processing and
want to you know bring in our brands we
can come in with the SOP and some people
trained up make sure that the quality is
on point cuz I just we just can't put
the brand name on just any quality yummy
so yeah it's about it we're definitely
looking to what well you don't clean the
Sapphire the Sapphire just gets gets a
q-tip you don't put south a DC glass
cleaner on sapphire it'll crack sapphire
can't change heat that fast all right
let's make gold and dry sifting it was
full melt 99 percent dry sipped and I
got it from a whole bunch of super
strong bud with tons of track the
brighter screen there you go a lot of
times people think it's 99% but if you
look at it under a microscope
99% is really hard to get this is a
abracadabra it's actually quite hot well
let me hold up the other one cuz I do
have another one here just put it
together for it this is the one most
people like like even more than the
other one Flower of Life well not
necessarily trim it I'll I'll we'll
bring in people and potentially you know
it's SOP so depending on the company and
the professionality and whether it's
worthwhile to assign contracts and get
that information the SOP in the know-how
is very well protected with sift we
would probably send someone to do that
job someone could come in and do you
know five to 10 kilos in a couple of
afternoons so uh yeah I do I have my I
have both my rosin presses if you see
there's one right here there's a
sasquatch and there's the v-2 sasquatch
a bunch of extra plates on top there's
my my air compressor the DeWalt there's
my pedro smiley lamp
sweet sweet there we go
true full melt yeah well maybe one more
hit we've got 262 people wow that's
pretty sweet we're usually around 200
I'd love to get this up to 300 I'd love
to get it up and beyond but it is what
it is we do what we do oh thank you
whoever just said that about the Hat I
don't know I'm not Health Canada you'd
have to ask them those it's the
government listen if you're gonna have
that attitude with the government you
should do this send in your application
and if you get it within a year you
should do a backflip that way and when
it comes back in like four or five or
six months you'll be so happy because
it'll be way less than a year but if you
expected in four or five or six months I
bet you it takes a year it's the
government they're the worst
they're like the only people worse at
communicating than the government are
telecommunication companies so like
Verizon and AT&amp;T and Virgin and Fido and
Rogers and [ __ ] Telus those companies
are literally the worst at communicating
which is amazing when you think about it
because they are a telecommunications
company it's kind of a weird irony I
think yeah that's that's how it that's
how you do it melty heads puffs with the
maids you like that John Maddox oh
thanks Bret Q thanks for the support of
Canada I wish I'd give everyone licenses
I'd let everyone be involved I'm very
inclusive if you haven't already noticed
they might be Nine Inch colas call my
1-800 number at one 866 melting okay
where can I send you some hat pins for
that hat I have some hat pins I have
this one from nerd and I have I thought
I had a swagger pin
in here we all have this Illuminati one
from from the female crew I actually
have a lot of pins and each time I go in
here oh here we go
here's a hi Dolph pin you know the hi
Dolph unit stand up unit
I got true Kanna from my bro true
and then there's Schroder hitting the D
nail I got the OCD labs oh yeah I even
got one that someone made bubble bags if
I had more of these I'd give them away
but I gave them all away would be a cool
giveaway now you can send a pin to peel
box for seven for p.o box for 74 I'll
just type it into the thing for you for
seven for lies baby C V o + 2 e oh boom
there you go you can send that [ __ ] it's
in that [ __ ] I might have two of those
Illuminati pins Dylan I'll have to see
if I do I'll give one away one of these
days well I like living water more than
dead water that's for sure my good
friend Mitch has been turning me on to
that I got turned on very very long time
ago
yeah pharmacy you said you were sending
a box a while ago I'm definitely I
always go to the p.o box cuz I hate to
forget so if you say you're sending
something let me know and I won't you
know just randomly not go to my P o box
for 10 days everything was straight
trikes now when you say straight trikes
are you talking about the entire
trichome or just the heads or were the
little stalks in there - Alonso because
that's what most people don't understand
is the entire trichome is not active
only the heads are active it's dry sift
with stocks in it is very easy to make
its we call it farmers grade but getting
the stalks out is like the most
impossible like most difficult really
really really difficult thing and the
word the pot the word is in the in the
photos you know when you see
really beautiful perfectly you know
isolated glandular trichomes heads yeah
dawn 710 heads like heads like dried
trichome heads you know see those little
kind of heads there good evening Andrew
to you good morning and good afternoon
to everyone else I think that covers it
all it is the Holy Grail
it's 100% yeah I mean it's just farmers
grade lots of people show me sift it
looks gold to the naked eye when you
don't know you don't know and when you
yeah yeah 150 160 180 200 140 it's all
farmers grade John we only care about
the heads that's correct and here's the
thing when you separate out the
trichomes as buddy was saying and it's
all gold and there's no herb you know no
green in it that's fine but that's not
we're not even close to done yet now you
have heads in a ratio to stocks that is
almost like the ratio of trichomes that
you had to plant matter so you have to
clean it twice you get the sift off the
bud but then when you get the sift you
think you've done a concentrate you
haven't you've done a farmers grade
isolation what you really need to do now
is you need to get rid of that 80%
contaminant that is non glandular okay
it's the stock it's the system of hairs
it's it's it's non glandular material it
is not glandular trichomes heads so what
are you saying there Shelly Simpson I
give good what I love any grade well
luster that's cool I personally it's not
even a grade though glandular trichomes
stalks is not a grade if you isolate
them out from heads and you try to dab
them you will not have an effect other
than like you just dabbed cellulose or
paper whoa MD 73 I get blonde - and you
get blonde - from washing bud stem
because those glands seem to be just the
the lightest and and freshest color ever
they I've always gotten near white when
it comes from the stock even the st.
stocks that have come from a
an older crop that went a week and a
half past due and had very amber heads
still white on the stalk so there's
definitely something to be said for the
the stock hash I've made bubble with
just stock you can do it too you
literally get exactly what that
gentleman just said the whitest hash
it's quite neat well it does take a
while dirts you got to put your time in
you got to put your time in you got to
put your time in
I don't smoke pho anything I was at a
friend's house the other day what did he
he's like hey you want some of the he
had his his distillate that he was all
and he's he's getting some some some
trichome some resin that he's gonna be
putting on it but I'm just like I don't
care about it at all I will try to find
a picture of it though so you can see it
he had quite a bit of it this is his
distillate some of it was very clear
they were doing their thing with it but
I just it does you know once again I
wouldn't fight against it I'm glad
people have access to it but it's not
for me I'm not excited about smoking
distillate I'm excited about smoking
really beautifully grown cultivars with
beautiful extractions you know of all
sorts from DRI sifted obviously dry
sifting is a huge one because you don't
have a footprint you don't have a
footprint when you dry sift you know mmm
that's important this lid is what you do
with bad material it's what a lot of
people are doing for sure it made the
outdoor cannabis community here very
happy because everyone just takes their
outdoor that wasn't selling I didn't go
to the Turk mansion actually and they're
just you know turning it into
cannabinoids
which is great the world needs more
cannabinoids you know it's just not my
I'm not interested in focusing on that I
have a little bit different of an agenda
for the for the community that I want or
what I want to release and so that's the
beauty of the spice of life we all get
to choose what we want to choose so yeah
you know for me survivor
I mean not just solvents but like the
petrochemical based solvents that's
really who I'm trying to skip out on the
best that I can but it's near impossible
I still put it in my dirt bike and in
Mike you know sled and in my truck and
in my boat and in my van and in my car
am I gonna do
hopefully I'll go electric one day well
that's good Sal that you have that
access to be able to take it and get to
sleep it's pretty darn important you and
Amelia what is Amelia and Terra laughs
and that Terra's always saying funny
[ __ ] well I mean scale domes not really
a dumbass he's actually very intelligent
and has a PhD to back it up I know where
he was coming from but at the same time
I know exactly where Sam was coming from
- the beautiful thing about information
is you know it's it's about like
shallowness sharing information that he
knows to be true
Sam is saying listen whether it's true
or not we don't really want to be you
know like well Sam doesn't really want
to be but what Sam has to understand is
because he has a very strong belief
system that there's the other side of
the coin of the people who will still
continue to sell that [ __ ] in the
industry regardless of whether it's been
cleaned or not so if they can clean it
there is absolutely no argument that
that's that that's better than if they
can't I mean they're already selling it
people are inhaling poison dude all day
long all day long so I got to understand
I was on Sam's side of the fence but as
I realize hash Church is so much bigger
than us and our little opinions and I
look at the information I see well it
was you know [ __ ] I wouldn't have said
it either
but that's why I hashed churches a panel
that's why hash search has a bunch of
different people so that someone will
say it you know oh you're welcome Tara
Lee I don't know if it was a shout out
but how about this now I'm sure yeah and
I'm shout now people that asked me to
shout them out on their birthday my god
there was a guy who said it was his
birthday and I think it's his birthday
today and I definitely have to spend a
few seconds just going through my inbox
here
to see which guy this was we gotta wish
him a happy birthday what a shitty thing
for me to forget about if I already
missed it and I apologize dude I just
hope here we go hey B man if you could
give me a happy birthday on Tuesday the
18th it would really make my day
I can't catch the stream live because
I'm at work but I watch us as soon as I
get home every day and it's literally
the best part of my day
all right everybody happy birthday to
David for ker I want everyone to have a
rip for David and his birthday right now
I'm absolutely gonna have a rip and
let's [ __ ] have a rip for David all
right what an easy thing to do if we can
just make a guy happy by spending a few
minutes talking about him and
celebrating his birthday for him he's at
work right now he's not watching live
but you know what he's gonna be pretty
stoked when he gets when he gets back
that's nice to see all you guys wishing
him a happy birthday like that very very
cool right on David
I'm glad I didn't forget it is Tuesday
and I pulled it off Wow fan love well
right on David I do appreciate your
commitment to the show and this ripped
my friend is with you did Kenny threaten
you what what that [ __ ] who said that I
was weird anyway let's have this rip
let's focus on the birthday shall we
let's do it
birthday rips Oh birthday rips that was
some sweet skunk dipped into some lemon
tree whoo I will I will chalice chugger
we will give him a pin we'll give him an
are you elite pin we're giving two pins
away today and I'm gonna send David a
email and say David you get a pen you
get a pin not a pen a pin and let's
thank whoever it was that says this
chalice chugger
you can thank chalice chugger David
because he's the one that said we should
send you a pin and I agree I'm gonna
give chilling like a villain something
for finding an ant on my egg then I
think we'll be uh we'll be giving you a
pin I think that's right proper no I
mean Joseph Lewis who the [ __ ] is seeing
a higher trichome count and how are they
doing that are they counting their
trichomes I photograph many many
different cannabis plants and I can tell
you that trichome density tricone growth
changes all over the plant it's
ever-changing there's constantly
trichomes growing at new times and and
maturing at different rates but you
could you could measure the cannabinoids
and the terpene content to find out if
you're getting more but having a higher
concentration of heads won't necessarily
give you that if the wax membrane is so
thick and you have a very very small
amount of the goods inside so it really
depends on how well you grew those
trichomes
I think Turpin aider personally I don't
believe in it it's not something I would
tell people to buy I'm not trying to
call out the product I haven't used it
but I did go to Ramos I did visit his
grow when he was using it and I just
felt like San Remo like all your [ __ ]
was is amazing like this Terminator does
not look any better than the
one next to it that doesn't have
Terpening or like it's just beautiful
beautiful grower so Remo can throw any
product and do is grow and as long as it
doesn't kill or affect his [ __ ]
negatively that those companies are
stoked because Remo is a really good
grower obviously he based his food on
that I haven't used his food as I was
staying in a more organic line although
I heard recently he did announce that
his line was vegan I'm not too sure
about that I'm sure it's true if he's
saying it a lot of people I know are
grown with it and having fun I'm more
interested in brews teas compost the
soil balance Pro that Peters been
talking about I have a real interest of
learning about those bacteria it's
interesting stuff
yeah Remo is damn straight he's he he
knows what he's doing
oh yeah yeah you just can't get one size
head although I will tell you that there
are sized heads in plants that if you
separate them all out by their different
sizes you will have a favorite mm-hmm
well I think they're already kind of
like these fruit Terps and you know
false Terps as I would say Wow well I
think indras full of [ __ ] if he's saying
[ __ ] like that and if he's saying [ __ ]
that I said I can tell you for sure
Indra might be losing his mind I'm not
too sure why he would say that on his
live stream I think it's one of the
reasons I'm you know Todd left was Indra
was getting more and more negative and
negative and really the last few
episodes he was on the only reason he
was being nicer is because I had to tell
him listen dude like if you if you saw
him when he first started his Instagram
account it got bad fast I mean he went
from being this really cool spiritual
old guy with amazing stories to very
very negative and nasty fast and so I'm
not too sure what's going on in his head
I'm sure he's feeling a little upset as
he's you know in this sort of experience
with Todd but I wouldn't fan the flames
Indra I think you should drop it and I
definitely think you should keep my name
out of your mouth when you're talking
about things that ice
because that that just doesn't sound
sound right at all it's too bad it's too
bad you know I liked Indra III like
Indra I just I see he has this dichotomy
where he's just this he's he tells these
amazing stories he's all spiritual and
then all of a sudden on this other side
he's socially poisoning and he's saying
things that are really nasty and I don't
know I'm not gonna spend too much time
on it but it's definitely true that you
could see a little bit less of Indra in
hashed Church I mean you know I just
don't want to see that I even in hash
Church chat he'll hold it down and you
guys ask him all the questions about his
machine
I really would wish you didn't I wish
you would ask him that stuff in private
and not make it all about that while
he's in this chatroom so now I've said
my piece and it is what it is I hope you
guys are still baked and I hope you guys
are I mean well todd has his only show
Kaylee and it's a pretty awesome show
you can check it out on his channel
and I don't think Todd will be coming
back I think it's it's a growth for the
better it's a growth for the better and
who knows maybe you'll see Indra on his
show in the near future who's to know
all right well last rip of the day and
here we go Todd's channel is talking
with cannabis you can google it
gave a couple of pins away celebrated
David's birthday and puff some beautiful
bowls anyway guys thanks so much for
coming in have a wonderful day and made
the full Mel bless your bowl sooner than
later peace out everybody