hey what's going on everybody welcome to
the wake-and-bake episode 82 42 people
waiting in the room that's not too
shabby I guess I started it quite a
while ago and wanted to give you guys
some time in the chat room for hanging
out and chatting hopefully my little
microphones working here everyone is
good we're going live are we going live
doesn't seem to want to go live but just
restarted okay there we go
we're live what's up what's up what's up
how's it going Samuel in well water and
melty heads and bingo and octo and John
and Evan and saved by and and an amide
and sticks and Collin and Alex and
Elliott Nick and Kevin and Madison I
could do this all day cuz there are a
lot of you suddenly there are 89 of you
watching just like that we started a
rippy dip dip shall we I think we should
did I miss the giveaway nobody's missed
the giveaway I got it right here
oh no I'm horizontal I'm coming through
proper on my channel
anyone else am i coming am i coming like
a cellphone for everyone else or am i
proper good morning good morning proper
excellent that's what I like to hear
excelente good good right good threw me
off there chase threw me off Chase has
been throwing me off a couple of times I
even sorry that I caused you any strife
with the book hopefully you can let that
go I did see the private messages going
on on Instagram that you were still
upset about it and while I'm sorry that
you were upset about it but hey why
don't we have a puff and start this day
off right let's just start it off right
just start it off right no Brenton you
did not miss the giveaway it's still
happening it's still happening a little
bit Evan I've played around a little bit
I've I've tried a few different things
with the static tech from the paint
roller to the glove to the DVD to the
fat book you know I'm they all work
pretty good
I'm not going
say that they don't but at the same time
I have some other techniques available
to me that work a little bit better like
substantially better and so I mostly use
those techniques but why don't we have a
really really quick rip here looks like
the torch is on low oh no offense taking
it all chase
no offense taking it all we're all good
brother
losing my torch thank God just in time
and yes I do have a little bit more fuel
so it's all good hopefully you guys
enjoyed that video I posted the team
Japan the hub studio you can check out
the hub studio on Instagram as well as
high integrity glass art as well as oh I
just grabbed some did you do this one
sweet skunk better get it going yummy is
I don't think Tony is proper extracts no
Tony's on Team bubble man brand
that is so delicious absolutely happy
birthday to Tommy West son who turned
three years old today in Texas I also
have a very close to three year old son
who turns 3 next month on the 27th of
August so enjoy that bro
how sweet is that what is sweeter than a
little three-year-old boy or girl for
that matter they are just so absolutely
innocent and sweet at that age the
things that come out of your mouth just
drop your jaw to the floor half the time
they're so beyond cute oh the volume
seems low well let's turn it up how
about that how about that are we good
Mitch I love that you guys give me the
little bits of you know you help me with
the quality of the feed and I do
appreciate that the microphone may have
been turned down I can turn it up even a
little bit more ah yes well I've got the
16 year old the 14 year old and the 3
year old I'm not too sure if team Japan
pops and here's what I would say about
that Japan is a very harsh place when it
comes to cannabis smoking smoking in
public would not be the smartest idea
smoking on videos would not be the
smartest idea and I would not share even
if they did because they still live in a
very prohibition based place and I think
it's best for us to just respect they
did not puff the entire time I was there
so I'm not lying when I say I did not
see them puff and I respect their
privacy if they do want a puff that's
fine Jon that's great that you know that
but let's just sort of leak you know
allow it maybe not be the best
conversation for this particular sorry
about that guys that was my mentor Ron
Hickey middle of
and then phones showed that he was funny
knowing money he'll probably call back
three more times so definitely expect at
least one or two more interruptions and
in the meantime that Suites kind of
tasted so damn good I think it's I think
we're gonna have another one I think
we're gonna have another one there is a
very big cannabis culture growing in
Japan it is absolutely the truth there's
no doubt about it
I'm sure that's why John Green has
decided to live there and sell Japanese
glass you know that they're blowing a
lot of glass makes sense that there is a
marketplace for that glass I won the pin
giveaway over yes hey man I love the
wake and bakes haven't missed any you're
my mentor and you never call bubble man
sorry drew I the thing about a mentor is
it's it's easy to sort of pick who you
want to mentor you but it's not until
the mentor picks that he's going to
mentor you that really the relationship
begins at least for me I mean I'm not
talking about that you can't be inspired
by different people online but for me
like my mentors have been friends in my
life they have been people who have been
present in my life throughout my days I
would see them in times and it was
really their decision that allowed for
me to kind of study under them it's I
have lots of people call me a mentor all
the time that say that I'm their mentor
and it's it's an honor to know that I'm
inspiring some people but it really is
this relationship that it's when the
mentor decides to see something in you
that reminds him of something he once
had or something that is you know
similar to his core foundation and his
belief systems that's when you get
picked and that's how it just yeah
that's just how it happens it's trippy
but it is what it is Japan grow cannabis
would be cool hey thanks Elliot
well they do they do but it's definitely
symbiotic in the sense you know like you
definitely it's it's usually the student
who wants the mentor but when the mentor
chooses the student that's why
you're like yes like I can't believe you
know for for me I felt honored when Ron
decided that I was kind of a similar
character to him and that he would bring
me under his wing and he would show me
things and put trust in me that was very
very like let's just say out there for
the time being it was a huge
responsibility and level of trust
pharmacy bros what Ron put into me when
I was very young just just out of my
teenage years really and so not quite
the same but similar with skunkman Sam
who you know put a huge trust and faith
in me by showing me his technique you
know something that I could have easily
blown up and shown the entire world and
just been a liar and and my word not
been worth [ __ ] but he he put his his
faith and his trust in me and generally
when one of my elders puts their faith
and their trust in me I will go to great
lengths great lengths to maintain that
integrity well you know I met Ron by
going into his hydroponics store
I met skunkman Sam by having a booth at
the Cannabis Cup and doing bubble bag
utter hash and popularizing full melt
resins which he had been living for 20
years already and yeah that's sort of uh
yeah there are a couple of Ron Hickey
videos up the grand chiming to his house
in the Kootenays and there's one called
feeding your endocannabinoids system
where we do lunch breakfast together we
make bubble together out on his deck I
think we do a tour of his grow but I'm
trying to get him out here I'm trying to
get him to move out from the Kootenays
get him back here out on the west coast
and try to do this greenhouse project so
Sam is a a man of many many things I
could not just call Sam ass if man of
course as a smoker he loves smoking sift
but he's much more than that he's a
master breeder he is he is like cannabis
incarnate he is just like he is he is
kept cannabis sorry I got a little bit
of the hiccups here maybe we should have
a bong rip maybe that'll get rid of my
hiccups what do you guys think
the reason I didn't take my bond rip
right away there was because a friend of
mine told me when you first fill the
torch that it's best to not turn it on
right away I guess there's a seal inside
the torch that gets cold when you put
the gas in because it's quite cold and
that seal can blow and the torch will
start leaking gas even when it's not on
and it won't hold gas anymore and I was
like what a great tip for torch culture
I was thinking that I messed mine up and
I wasn't turning it off enough but I
guess I had just pooched the previous
one by putting in fuel and then lighting
it up literally like a minute later so
might be something you wanted wha
you didn't piss me off somehow Peter M
who's the first person to call you
bubble man well that was me chase I came
up with the bubble bags and I came up
with the name Fresh Hetty's and I came
up with the name bubble man where do you
see the beautiful urban 50 to 100 years
oh wow I don't even know man who's to
say that's that I'd have to really
figure that out think about it thank you
Andy I'm coming to the Karma Cup as you
all know I got this really cool
are you elite pin I guess you can't get
a shout out to your father David Pro sir
we only have so many days left kind of
gentleman loving man I know Wow he's
only got a few days left well I'm sorry
to hear that
do Z we will give a shout out to David
and I don't know you but I know that you
have people that love you I know that
you touched people in a very unique way
and that you've probably made the world
a better place while you were here if
you have people in my chatroom asking
for us to give you a shout-out so we are
gonna give you a shout-out and the
shout-out is that yes you are elite and
so if you would like to do GOG send me
your address to BC bubble man at iCloud
I want to send you this little pin and
it's the ru elite pin and a shout-out to
your father David poster yeah me
alrighty here that was a nice nice
little moment to share with GOG and
David and all his loved ones bless up
bless up bless up no got to make that
happen
we gotta celebrate not just the
birthdays Tommy but we got to celebrate
the deaths as well I they're sad and it
sounds weird
but do you want to celebrate your loved
ones or do you want to mourn them and
that's you know mourning is natural I
don't think it's a choice that we we
choose it just happens and everyone does
it differently
but if we could choose what we want to
do is we want to celebrate our loved
ones our friends and our family those
that's that's what we want to do we want
to celebrate them so that's what we
shall do yeah man I lost my father
suddenly very different from it sounds
like the way you're going through it my
father was taken from me very suddenly
in a motorcycle accident along with his
wife and it was shocking and it affected
me in a way that I had
no idea could affect me so I have you
know empathy for people who are going
through losing their parents or any
[Music]
loved one for that matter well that's
still pretty fresh and II for me it was
ten years plus and I was still feeling
it very very very very strongly
yeah well water it's a crazy thing right
it can create some serious anxiety it
can create some intensity we we in our
culture have not really prepared
ourselves properly I mean you see how we
go to school they don't prepare us for
anything they don't teach us about banks
and loans and paying taxes and
businesses and equity and purchasing and
like all of the important things that
you would think that you should be
getting ready for in life they don't
teach you about so why would they teach
you about death why would they have any
inkling to want to share knowledge why
would we want to celebrate it right we
just mourn it in our culture and because
we mourn it it's um it's not celebrated
it's not discussed too much and even
when people are going through it it's
uncomfortable for other people you know
it's almost like they don't want to hear
it even though they're there it's like
I'm there for you but it's like I don't
want to hear about death it's like I
don't want to die it's like well guess
what we all get to go there together it
seems like a pretty crazy thing that
we're all like one of the one things
we're all gonna share in common is that
we're all going to die that's a pretty
heavy conversation that I can't believe
more people aren't having but I guess it
is what it is people are freaked out
it's yeah take some psychedelics and
you'll see it's not quite as scary there
are different levels to this [ __ ] and
this is just one of the current levels
that we're experiencing now I don't just
call it just one because personally I
think it's probably one of the most
valuable and one of the most precious
experiences to have in the grand scheme
of things when you think of the concept
of all life you know soul energy coming
from a single source a whole a one
and then fractioning off into what we
know as this experience and then going
back into that hole well it seems like
if we came from there and we're going
from there this right here is the
experience take the third hit all right
I'll take the third hit let's do it
yeah we all came from the same place too
which is pretty trippy I'm down I'm down
all right he's ready for a third rib
three is a charm
three is a cosmic number and if you
haven't checked out cosmic trigger by
Robert Anton Wilson well that was one of
the first books that got me into all
sorts of crazy volume one two and three
oh it's no burden let me tell ya hey
Harry Dolan welcome welcome you haven't
missed much we've just been hanging out
talking about you know [ __ ] like death
losing our loved ones fairly intense
conversations for a wake-and-bake but
you know what it's all it all needs to
be covered and I think that you know
much like our perspectives they're all
they all come from this one source
whatever perspective you want to look at
it through it's all sort of the same
thing and that's sort of sometimes hard
to understand but eat about six grams
and mushrooms in a dark room like
Terence said and you will understand
quickly welcome Rob rosin glad you made
it - glad you made it - it's one of my
favorite songs standing on the moon such
a beautiful song if you can catch the
right live version of it Jerry just
baring his soul if you don't know
Grateful Dead standing on the moon
google it
YouTube it go listen to it listen him to
sing listen to him sing those lyrics
mushrooms in the dark room yeah Terence
Mckenna would say years ago that if you
want to crush your ego cuz for Terence
he what he saw in the psychedelic
experience was that a lot of people were
holding on to their egos they weren't
quite dissolving their egos fully they
were doing these one and two kind of you
know lighter trips and he kind of came
along and just said look if you just eat
like five and a half grams five to six
grams dried and then go into a dark room
not a pitch-black room but a dark room
that has shadow there it's it's
I can't even explain it it is more like
a DMT experience than a mushroom
experience it's definitely something
very very very very intense and we did
it in a room that had the smallest
amount of light and the light was
shining on a mandala that was hanging on
the full size of the wall and we laid
there with our heads to it and it was
one of the most experiences of my life
it was definitely one of the experiences
where I learned that the soul the
experience the you whoever that
experience is and - the ego because I'm
pretty sure the ego stays behind with
the body can leave it just can leave and
it's like it's not until you let go of
the ego that you can actually it's
almost like the ego is what traps the
soul in the body and through
psychedelics if you can crush the ego
enough blow it out of the room for four
or five hours you can really release the
soul and you can have these sort of
cosmic experiences that are above and
beyond most everyday experience so yeah
and you're looking down at yourself
exactly so when you can leave your body
but but without your ego pretty crazy I
don't know about that I definitely
didn't hear that Sven that's crazy
insane experience I hope that that's not
the truth and let's just hope that
that's not the truth yeah yeah I bet
there is something going on there well
it makes sense right because the ego is
what convinces you that you're you that
you is it when really it is not and it's
not until you blow the ego out that you
really experience that and it's very
sort of like you know it's an extremely
psychedelic experience but it's very
touching soul searching experience that
can bring you to tears that can just
make you feel the most intense aw and
beauty and inspiration that you could
ever imagine I think that society should
have things set up for safe consumption
of these substances for places where
people can go much like the way you can
take your dog to a park or your kid to a
park there should be areas in nature
around cities that you can go to to
experience psychic
experiences you know amongst comforting
environments with with people who are
aware and with just like the whole
experience right you wouldn't want to
have like a big cat what do they call it
[ __ ] cotton candy machine or something
just at the psychedelic park that would
be no thanks we're not having any
soft-serve ice cream or cotton candy but
if you want to cut us up some fresh
slices of fruit and some ice waters
maybe some bowls of hashish that would
be on point for certain yeah that's what
I'm saying
yep great idea right I mean it's
important why are we forced to go do
this in a place first of all like we're
not supposed to be doing what we're
doing that creates right off the bat you
know there's intention that's not your
intention that becomes a part of your
experience and this is of course where
the smaller doses and the ego holding on
and fear falling into place that can
really throw people off and they'll say
how I had a bad experience on that
substance it's like are you sure you
didn't have a bad experience on that
substance because you know people say
that substance is illegal and you're not
supposed to do it so you have this
underlining feeling of like oh I'm doing
something wrong or I don't want to
interact with the within authority or
law enforcement right now any of those
energies and thoughts while tripping can
direct you in ways of places that you
would not want to go in my opinion oh
I'm getting excited I'm getting calls
for for this video I'm gonna be filming
another video in a couple hours here and
that's going to be the JEP the team
Japan with dosa Cup I believe doses in
the cup as well like he was there I know
that they made some pendants him and
Yoshinori but I'm pretty sure he'll be
in the cup as well so we'll check it out
I'll go we'll go see what's going on
I'll bring the 4k camera take it out
onto the the deck and film it in the Sun
super super stoked to see this it's too
bad almost that I posted the video but
whatever this can be the second part
it's going to be very short I
not sure if the artists themselves will
be there if they are I'll try to get a
small interview with each one the best I
can and oh is there a troll tell me what
the trolls name is and I'll I'll hammer
the troll
I will hammer the troll oh here we go
I see the troll you're damn straight I'm
wearing above Marley t-shirt straight up
you know Bob Marley most inspirational
reggae artist to ever live light the
fires cannabis activists extraordinaire
you know cannabis activists
extraordinaire you're damn straight in
fact not only did I get this shirt at
Bob's house but what did day me are
sorry what did Rowan say to us after
hitting his dab and walking away What
did he say he said I want to see it come
on we know someone's gonna post it in
the chat room we got a city we got to
see it respect to the dabbas respect to
the dabbas yeah dude you got a go bro
you gotta go it's kind of intense to
have that kind of like intense just like
horrible horrible hatred and it's just
quite the opposite of what we're all
about isn't it trying to create division
you know by whatever it can be to divide
men and women it can be to divide
straight and gays it can be divide white
and and colored it can be anything that
they can get their hands on to create
division and of course we all know it's
to divide and conquer so this is silly
these are like some socially sociopathic
maniacs that came up with these concepts
so if you find yourself thinking in
these ways you know I would say start
consuming cannabis in a big way you
definitely hey take it easy Indra thanks
for coming in brother have a great day
we'll see you when we see you probably
on tomorrow's wake-and-bake
I would suspect hopefully yes we are
less powerful divided that is a very
true story there's a crazy like cartoon
called ants
that they did in like the late 90s maybe
98 or something and it's one of these
kids cartoons but you know the wasps all
have the ants working for them and
making their food and it's like there's
not that many wasps and they're they
kind of talk about man if these ants
ever figured out how easily they could
control us it's really heavy-duty if you
haven't seen that movie you should check
it out because there is a whole lot of
[ __ ] going on in there and a bug's life
right
they are definitely dealing with some
heavy stories underlining of a simple
cartoon that I'm almost blown away that
that it was able to get produced and
made into a movie I do need like a troll
Bell exactly all someone would have to
do was hit the troll Bell and I'd be
like oh looks like the hammer needs to
be dropped then again I could just make
a bunch of you guys moderators in the
room and you guys could be hammering
people but the funny thing is when you
do that sometimes people get out of hand
it's like yeah and then the next thing
you know I'm getting emails saying hey
that guy banned me by accident it's also
hard sometimes to ban people because as
you guys are chatting I'm trying to
catch his name and push the thing next
to his name if I go to push it and it
moves up one well then I've just
accidentally banned someone who didn't
deserve to be banned and we still have
to listen to the hateful spewing z' of a
[ __ ] seriously insecure possibly just
upset dude or woman I don't know I think
people are upset I think people are
stressed out and I think people are you
know whacked out on bad diets and
alcohol and tobacco and caffeine and
Pharma these are all things that are
gonna be hectic on your nervous system I
can't even imagine all of them holy [ __ ]
I mean recently I saw that the actor who
played Lafayette on True Blood just died
at 39 I was like how the [ __ ] did he die
and then they're like oh he stopped
drinking alcohol he was a heavy
alcoholic he was he stopped drinking
alcohol and his body went into full
failure his heart just couldn't keep up
how hard core of a drug is alcohol
that it can stop your heart if you drink
too much of it and then stop drinking it
that to me is demonic that is like a
demonic possession that got so deep into
him that he could not get it out it's
like where they tell you oh no we can't
get the demon out they'll die it's like
whoa alcohol is not a drug it is a
spirit they call that sit that shit's
spirits for many many years and it
freaks me out I definitely am NOT like
inspired to try and prohibit anything
but it would be nice if humanity came to
the conclusion that alcohol is a [ __ ]
Conn much like what John Mayer just said
recently in a rolling stone interview
saying alcohol is a [ __ ] con I never
felt like I could get enough it's the
ultimate chasing of the Dragon and more
worse than that you know the chasing of
the Dragon just leads you into deep
opioid addiction and usually it's not a
pretty sight alcohol addiction seems to
be more socially acceptable and you can
just operate it throughout your whole
life people that are just hardcore
alcoholics waking up and strapping on a
gun and going and being a cop or
whatever it's pretty [ __ ] up
everything in moderation I'm down with a
little moderation myself
I personally don't enjoy alcohol because
I grew up for what I consider Winnipeg
was like an incubator of alcoholics it
was a lot of people drinking alcohol on
an abusive level and it freaked me out
to be honest the energy freaked me out
completely I didn't like it I just sort
of tried to stay away from it I don't
really like bars you know I don't like
concerts where they're serving alcohol
because there's just gonna be people who
are completely unpredictable that will
be there you know abusing alcohol to the
most insane level yes a lot do leather a
lot do I mean if you're drinking a lot
of booze you're probably smoking a lot
of cigs you know yeah it's true well
let's talk about something a little more
happy Brett Armstrong like feeding our
endocannabinoids systems the polar
opposites of all the drugs that says
they want you on Alcohol Tobacco
caffeine sugar and a shitty shitty
shitty shitty diet if
they can have you on all those things
and not using cannabis they've
definitely won the game that is their
most profitable agenda so what are we
going to do we're going to try and cut
down on our sugar and our caffeine
intake we're gonna try and stop smoking
radioactive cigarettes completely and
maybe alcohol completely just for a
while to get it out of the brain to get
it out of the system so you can feel
what you feel like being it's good to
know what you feel like being and you
know if you are drinking for reasons
that you're trying to numb and uncover
potentially not drinking and using
cannabis instead will stimulate thoughts
about those different issues and instead
of burying them you can dig them up and
maybe plant a seed of positivity in
there and then start feeding that every
day because you know the old story the
native story of the grandfather telling
his grandson that there is a battle
going on in each of us with two wolves
and you know there's the good side the
white wolf and the black wolf as he says
and the the little grandsons like which
which wolf is gonna win and he says well
that depends on which one you feed are
you gonna feed your light or are you
gonna feed your darkness
maybe moderation maybe a little bit of
both but I prefer to feed as much light
as possible yeah do you enjoy eating
root vegetables like cassava yeah I like
some root vegetables absolutely I mean
when I'm in Jamaica I'm actually getting
a lot more access to that than I am of
course Irish I have the Irish blood in
me so I do love me a good potato I'm not
gonna lie
I'm actually like a potato fiend I could
eat potatoes for it with every meal a
hundred different ways
I [ __ ] love potatoes maybe that's
something you didn't know about me guys
but I'm sharing it right now
guilty food pleasure oh I don't know
maybe Pizza I love pizza I've had it all
different ways from raw pizza to vegan
pizza you know full meat pizza I was not
always a vegetarian
oh this banger is rather large it's not
just you medicated pizza you've been
watching Samuel you've been watching
there you go Devil's harvest although I
will tell people who are trying to feed
their endocannabinoids systems that
smoking joints although will be a great
way to stimulate appetites and induce
sleep and reduce ocular pressure but and
do a whole variety of other things oral
consumption of it on the daily is
something I would definitely say is a
good idea as a preventative whether you
eat a little bit when you wake up or eat
a little bit when you go to bed or both
and some in the middle of the day I
don't know but you should definitely be
doing it because it's a it's a good
thing to do feeding your
endocannabinoids system through oral
consumption not just the smoking of
cannabis so try to do that on the daily
anyway I think that we are good to go
we've got a pin going out to do J og and
his father David we're thinking about
you are you elite you are elite my
brother this pins coming to you send me
an email with episode 82 wake-and-bake
in the title then I want you to write
the are you elite pin and then your name
and address if you want to write
anything else just do it below that I
like it when it's all nice and I can
just copy and paste and keep up on
sending out all these giveaways I
actually have like five or six backed up
right now so I got to go now and go send
these giveaways and
I gotta go and film in the city with
Team Japan so thanks everyone for coming
in hey snug not good to see you dude and
your [ __ ] pillow idea that you were
talking about so many years ago has come
to a reality and I love it bro way to
push through you know I really didn't
see your vision but I think you're doing
good and I'd love to give some snug nug
pillows away on the wake-and-bake
channel so hit me up at BC bubbleman at
icloud.com
i'll give you an address and you can
send me some of those pillows or if you
want you can hold on to them and I'll
just do the get well it's probably a
good idea if I have at least one that I
can show but then I was gonna say you
could also ship it as well so thank you
for that and thanks everyone for
watching hanging out being a part of it
200 people spending your morning with me
I do appreciate it and may the full male
bless your bowl sooner than later peace
out