hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to the
wake-and-bake
episode 87 I just having a fun little
conversation in the chatroom sticks with
Terps was like oh I like your legends a
hash Church you got on I was like how
the [ __ ] does he know I have a legends
of hash search on [ __ ] anyway he was
seeing the photo the avatar that I
changed yesterday in the YouTube page
hey you guys want to have a little bit
of a nerve-wracking sickening moment
with me
yesterday not long after the amazing
all-woman hashed Church panel I went to
go onto my youtube channel and it was
gone it just said err you can't access
this account and I started going into my
phone and I went into my computer and I
went in on my other computer and it just
it wasn't really working it was kind of
working like I could I could go into a
page that had YouTube opened already and
I could push play on the video and it
would play no problem but I'll tell you
nerve-racking happened again this
morning I did a little Google and found
out that YouTube's having a little bit
of problems I can't tell you how sick I
felt of the idea of losing my channel of
losing my ability to come and hang out
with you guys every morning of losing
that all-female hash hash Church panel I
was sick to my stomach I'm not gonna lie
thank God I googled quickly and found
out YouTube is indeed [ __ ] it was a
little scary I'm not gonna lie
so we got 107 people watching 113
whatever it jumps it drops 908 we've
been live for a couple of minutes and
yeah just you should download an archive
of all your videos well Brett Armstrong
most of my videos are archived because
I've produced them by editing them and I
have all the raw footage the edited
footage etc however wake-and-bake
episodes and anything that I do live
like hash Church those need to be saved
so I'm going to be doing some saving I
would also ask you the public if you
have your favorite
so go and rip it off with YouTube it
would be appreciative because if we lose
all these hash churches wouldn't it be
nice to have someone say I have them
bubble man now I've got some time and
I'm gonna try and rip as many as I can I
think I have the first 30 or 36 or so
but I need to rip the rest
excellent chase that's what I like to
hear well good good yeah this is a
classic dude this is the only Barcelona
legends of course I got sick to my
stomach and couldn't be there I showed
up and yea jebediah Haney we know it
dude the the hash Church episode
yesterday was one of the best a stretch
oh so it's whatever those women did a
stand-up job they crushed the men in my
opinion not in regards to their
knowledge and their information but how
they went about sharing it how
compassionate they were to one another
how they allowed each other to talk
what's up bee Beecher I just thought it
was [ __ ] great I loved everything
about it I learned from it and I'm going
to step up my game I'm not going to
allow these strong male personalities to
walk all over hash Church anymore and
it's you know what I don't want to
offend people and I know the minute I
start giving people a little kind of
like hey you know like it's not cool to
tell everyone we owe you it's not really
cool to tell everyone that you you know
like just the little things that some of
the panel members have done over the
years I just want it to be
I don't think piranhas is available in
Denver I just want it to be a good show
I want everyone to be get the exposure
that they require at the same time I
don't want it to turn into just about
that person and so I'm having a little
bit of problems with a few people who
seemingly can't talk about anything
other than themselves and I get that I
understand how most of us are talking
about ourselves a lot of the times but
you know try to step out sometimes try
to have empathy for the person talking
and put yourself in their shoes and
listen to them rather than to try and
you know get something up off of your
you know like crush the person but I
just want to see some of our more mature
members you know be as kind and
compassionate as the ladies were because
my god they
classy I was a class act now some of the
stuff that was being in chat was
unfortunate was being said in chat it is
weird how guys just can't seem to deal
with powerful beautiful articulate women
and there was a small a few guys that
just couldn't do it they just had to say
stupid [ __ ] they just had to say you
know things that were coming from their
insecurities and I saw a little bit of
that light you know I I let Sal go on
one that definitely hurt one of the
panelists feelings when he said
something you know that was it was
hurtful and it made this girl feel
really bad and it was probably because
he's insecure and upset and maybe he's
older I don't know and I have nothing
against you salad you were by no means
the worst ones because I let you go with
it but some people got banned so I dude
come on we have some ladies these are
our mothers and our sisters and our
grandmothers how are you around those
women are you not if it's off-topic and
doesn't interest you then a split
tastebuds you don't need to say negative
[ __ ] I don't think it was off-topic at
all
I think they stayed on topic the entire
time and talked about cannabis which is
what hashed Church is about yeah I mean
it's sad to see super sad to see these
sort of sexual insecurities or
intimidations they did a great job I
just want to thank them from for coming
out and I'm gonna definitely have many
of those ladies on again no of course
not
well that's not your taste bud 420 some
of those women do make cash in fact I've
made hash with some of those women so
imagine how wrong you are and it's not
about making hash some of those people
are helping people palliative Lee died
the end of their lives some of those
people are teaching people about
cannabis that are elderly and in old age
I mean in my opinion it was [ __ ]
awesome I'm surprised you're here
actually defending that it wasn't
awesome like honestly it was great I
thought it was really top-notch and
hashed Church is not all about making
hash it's just not you know and those
were women not girls you know there's a
different girls and boys are children
men and women are adults
yeah Hillary Blackson absolutely
legend 100% she's awesome person she's
one of my best friends and I don't think
girls hate salad all I think Sal just
got a little uncomfortable and that's
okay it doesn't mean we have to now bash
on Sal this is the mentality of a chat
room and I'll tell you what you guys are
an incredible chat room because I've
gone around lately and I looked at some
of these YouTube live videos that are
out there the may weather the mechanic
Conor McGregor holy Christ was that
negative then I found live Simpsons and
family guys if you want to see the worst
YouTube comments you could ever possibly
imagine go look up a live Simpsons or a
live Family Guy and watch like 10
minutes of the chatroom it made me feel
sick to my stomach I felt sad for these
people that they were creating this
energy amongst themselves just getting
it you are a very [ __ ] cool chatroom
Nine Inch colas and we owe it to
ourselves because we want to hang out
with cool people we don't want to wake
up and piss each other off and fight
with one another and that's why Sal
today you are the winner my friend you
are the winner and I'm going to give you
a t-shirt if you tell me what size you
are just to tell you that I'm not
bitching about you no I'm not I'm just
trying you were used as an it as an
example of what was going on yesterday
so if you will allow me to sell I would
love to send you a t-shirt today I've
got small I've got large I've got double
extra-large and I like you Sal I've seen
you say a lot of cool things in the room
and I definitely don't want you to leave
the room or not be a part of our group
because we enjoy what you have to offer
and what you share I just it was
unfortunate that one of the things you
said yesterday really pissed off my good
friend and made her feel bad about
herself you know we don't want to we
don't wanna make people feel bad I don't
know if I have the extra-large Sal I
think I might have taken the extra-large
everyone's an extra large I got three
times extra-large
I got small I got three times
extra-large and large the only other
option Sal is that I could send you a
pin would you rather have a pin I could
send you a nice karma Cup pin I could
send you one that says are you elite or
I could send you one that says karma cop
but I don't have your size
shirt and I feel bad about that yes he
says he's an extra-large but I only have
large and three times extra-large three
times is really big but I guess you
could always shrink it what we got here
Sal is this like the biggest shirt ever
this is a pretty big shirt you know what
[ __ ] it let's send it to you buddy let's
send it to you you can you can shrink it
it'll fit in the meantime Sal if you
don't mind sending me your email a sort
of address actual address so I can send
you that t-shirt it is a B C bubble man
at iCloud dot ho he said three times
Excel well wonderful that's exactly what
I have
don't be so sorry dude don't worry about
it at all it's it's all good we just
gotta sometimes realize that little
things that we might punch into the
screen can actually feel make people
feel terrible about themselves and I
know your imprint your your your vision
isn't to come into the chat room and
make someone feel bad about themselves
and sometimes we might not understand
when we're when we're speaking from our
insecurities and not our heart that the
same way when we speak from our heart
and we can touch someone and they can be
humbled by it they can be you know
really appreciate the empathy it's quite
the opposite when we come from our
insecurities when we shoot something out
it's like a dagger or like a razor blade
all of a sudden my friends bleeding on
our arm holding yourself in the corner
saying I felt bad I'm just saying so
let's try to keep it positive let's try
to keep each other positive and if
someone's negative I think it's okay for
us to turn it around and go into it and
discuss it now if someone's a troll and
their hole means and impression is to
just come here and hijack the the
conversation than to try and hijack it
into a more negative than the banhammer
is like in full effect
we just get rid of those people we don't
need them so what do we got nine
seventeen and only one hundred and
forty-seven viewers in the room what's
going on we usually have a couple of
hundred by now kind of surprised
actually I guess it's time for a little
Viking back east yeah you know what Sal
didn't even say the worst thing okay all
he said was
that he was happy that someone else was
gonna talk that does that that talks
about something other than sex and my
friend who brought up sex well it was
hard for her to bring that up she felt
like she was really kind of putting
herself out there so you know when we
put ourselves out there we don't want to
get we don't want to get smacked nobody
wants to get hammered except the trolls
the trolls [ __ ] love yes Sean so
YouTube is acting up I'm not gonna lie
it made me nervous my channel
disappeared a couple of times I wanted
to go into it I went to start the video
and it was completely gone I'm not gonna
lie I was shouting my pants on this a
[ __ ] shouting my pants just a little
bit sex is a hot topic not only a sex a
hot topic it's a topic none of the guys
have ever covered and I guarantee you if
we did we'd have a hard time doing it as
mature as the women did those women did
it great yeah it really was luster
everyone ready what do I recommend you
clean your courts well I use a DC glass
cleaner but I'm smoking at a sapphire
today so I don't use it on sapphire I
just sharted myself it's true not true
[Music]
greetings Ron Jones from Pendleton
Oregon hope you're doing well
no pisses people off for Morgan when
you're from Canada and you call it
Oregon do you not like that yeah if you
want an argue them don't do it in
Chatham House Church if you want to
promote your products and you want to
promote yourself and you want everyone
to answer you're getting a million
people asking you questions go do it in
another room
give them your emails it's not cool to
take up the hash search room for your
personal sales
I've been so uncomfortable
telling the people that are doing things
that I don't like cuz I don't want to
step on anyone's toes the gloves are off
I'm coming hard everyone needs to step
the [ __ ] up or a goon no it's Oregon I
love the Sapphire no it cannot handle
any quick temperature change like that
Selena was wonderful great job very
empathetic and compassionate girl doing
a good job out there in the Okanagan all
of them really all of them really were
amazing some I didn't even know I liked
Rosie I thought she was cool she had
great information she was really
articulate no I just dabbed on some
God's green crack - a turf dip which is
crazy because I have many Terps that I
went and picked up the other day I went
and picked up typical dello Sour Diesel
picked up some Clementine from Blue
River and then I also picked up the
lemon tree my last vial of lemon tree
and I picked up some sour tangi because
they [ __ ] love sour - Angie why
wouldn't I very nice well there you go
foxy she's a very very nice person like
very her and Hillary are kind of on par
for just how kind and considerate they
are in this scene we're gonna do it
again mmm
great welcome back Mike Hendricks we're
just talking a little bit about all the
Terps on the guard green crack well you
know Green crack is a pretty classic God
is very unique I would like to get the
terpene profile for God bud because it
has this soapy strange terpene mix I get
the tiniest little bit about it but mmm
but not quite what you get from just
straight God also I'm you know I'm a
bigger fan of
exotic narrowly drug cultivar terpene
profiles so those are the ones I prefer
the most what do I think about back to
the future I liked it it was a great
movie all three of them you know if you
grew up in the 80s you were [ __ ]
loved in that [ __ ] even watching them
recently with my kids was kind of
enjoyable what are you gonna say nice
emcee oh yeah exactly you don't want to
be smelling your blue river and when you
get it in the mail I'll tell you one
time Tony sent me some it was a 4 point
5 ml vial which is a large bottle I
don't have one just to show you but well
actually yeah no no there we go so it
was one of these full of terpenes and
it's luckily we use these pouches that
we use because they're sealed inside ok
and so one of them came broken smashed
into a million pieces so the terpenes
were just liquid in the package so I I
opened the package I poured the terpenes
out into the fresh thing and I lost
maybe three drops so that was pretty
pretty incredible cannabis specialist
yes month I don't think I will be
bringing any bubble man brand Mike Quinn
but I will be bringing blue river
terpenes so if you want to get your
terpenes on I should by then have the
new Jamaican cultivars that are coming
we've produced 400 MLS if you can
imagine that's a lot of terpenes like a
big friggin jar and we're going to be
releasing those in the near future on
blue river Canada's website so all you
Canadians that want to try out the
Jamaican terpenes they're coming your
way soon I've pretty much sold out of
the other Jamaican terpenes I have a
little bit left but I'm down for a rip
for those of you that are gonna buy
Europeans use the code Blue River all
lowercase two zero one seven Blue River
2017 that's gonna give you 30% off of
your order and trust me it will be
appreciated because Eastern cheap
and the Karma cup actually seeing is
that we're speaking it
they have till the 28th that's 11 more
days if you're entering if you are
entering the karma cup please get them
the entries to them on time before the
28th of this month and if you're
entering a solvent list product add rice
after a bubble hash or even a rosin I
will look forward to smoking your
product because I'm pretty sure I get to
be like a celebrity judge or a special
guest judge so I don't know what they
call it maybe it's just a judge maybe
I'm putting myself higher than I really
belong I get to be a judge so what I'm
asking you is for any of you out there
that want to take I would love to see
your hashes I know Sarah would love to
see your buds your hash your pens your
solvent your solvent less all of it but
for me I would just like to see your
solvent list and if you don't enter come
by my booth and let's have a DAB out of
the ship as I get back a pot in the
sorry Jeff I free getting phone calls
getting my mothership whip caught in the
drawer I'll have to call I free back
that's a good brother for mine that I
met in Jamaica he's actually my friend
that introduced me to Kidd his I so mad
props this this rip is for Jeff I posted
recently a post on Facebook about how
the energy of Rastafari has brought the
most incredible amazing people and I
felt bad that I didn't have a good photo
of Jeff to post because he's definitely
one of the influences in my life meeting
me in Kingston introducing me to kidís
and while I'll tell you
yeah and Mark is kind of correct and and
um I - sure in a sense except that once
you get the terpenes extracted the way
we do it there's zero footprint left and
there's no way of actually proving that
it comes from cannabis it's just a
profile that has zero cannabinoids it's
only legal product so we've had ours
tested at a few different borders by a
few different law enforcement facilities
and they don't come up with any
cannabinoids there's is literally no
footprint sharing that this is a
cannabis product other than the fact
that and in the gray area is that we're
allowed to do the extraction because we
have licensing and permits to
do that so we create a product that's
almost like this leftover product that
is no longer illegal because there's no
way on proving that it came from
cannabis so that's it good sir here in
Canada it's a little different federally
I can produce terpenes no problem I have
a license and permit to process and yeah
they show up anywhere in the US I don't
sell in the US because I'm not part of
the US company
I am the Canadian distributor which
means I get to sell in Canada nice have
you guys seen the harmony Whitney
Harmony one with the little fretted
glass in the bottom not ones my my
favorite of course I support
psychedelics where have you been
are you crazy [ __ ] love psychedelics
here we go everybody
dab a doodle bud rich only two
reciprocal countries want to get my
permit in Jamaica as a patient I should
be able to go back and forth from
Jamaica with product but these are these
are things that are happening here in
the near future reciprocity is not going
to happen overnight right now no boat
I'm still working on it mine's inclined
been talking to a few different
companies been talking to Brian from
Vitol been talking forever flower in
greenhouses even had a conversation with
reefer man who apparently has quite a
bit of greenhouse knowledge
well those Japanese pieces are
next-level dude I mean come on they are
completely next level nobody's doing
[ __ ] like that
those guys are literally from another
planet and if you really look at what
they're doing they're deep they're
they're using detail like the same thing
that I became well-known for which was
becoming OCD about hash isolation and
isolating it to the absolute cleanest
that you could photographing skunk man
sans isolations and showing them to
people and having them be like jaw on
the floor I really feel like these
Japanese guys have done the same thing
with glass they've just taken this thing
that's existed for a while but people
have been doing incredible work but then
they purified it they got it so
concentrated and so small and so macro
that it's just you can't [ __ ] believe
it
oh I didn't scoop that piece Samuel that
piece will be like $100,000 I am a
photographer who gets to shoot a lot of
glass if I scoop that piece I'd be
puffing it all day long now this piece I
absolutely scooped give thanks to Corey
for the custom mug for bubble man
[ __ ] love this thing I can't show you
too much of the bottom otherwise I'll
spill my water all over the place that's
good yes I do shots I'm gonna have both
occasions are true artisans well I mean
I don't like sure that's a pretty huge
generalization that's a large group of
people that's a big chunk of the world
but some Asian people are absolutely
incredible artisans those Japanese guys
from Team Japan Yoshi
genichi and they suck those guys are
absolutely incredible
artists I was and dosa to [ __ ] humbled
to be in their presence while they're
doing their technology humbled they
crushed it absolutely yes Smash Brothers
Asians there's all sorts of Asians in
the world there is Caucasians of which a
pair
they I am a part of I don't know why
we're [ __ ] Asians it's kind of a weird
thing but it is what it is all more ways
to divide people that are all just
people definitely you have a Gabba dough
it's not always accurate although I will
say at one point in time in my life I
was potentiating my stereotype to the
most accurate [ __ ] potential you
could possibly do big dre D hair
listening to fish and the Grateful Dead
dry on the orange Volkswagen van smoking
reefer eating mushrooms just literally
you know playing frisbee golf I was so
like an absolute [ __ ] stereotype to
the stereotype we're in [ __ ]
Guatemala printed pants I mean the whole
nine yards right so it's kind of fun
kind of fun today I'm a little more
chill we're all humans we're all humans
how about that one specie the human
specie
yeah frisbee golf Jeffro he's the love
frisbee golf I mean my God how wonderful
was that if he were someone that loves
to smell joints and see parks oh you
know what I'm never the only white guy I
have been in a few places in my life
where there's only been a few of us but
I'm good with that too I don't really
care although I do feel like a weird
insecurity and this is a kind of a funny
white person insecurity first of all
when I'm in a hot country I already know
that I have the wrong skin if I had the
ability especially because I'm very
sensitive to the Sun if I had the
ability to change the level of melon
whatever it is in my skin not melanin
whatever the the the protein is in your
skin that controls the lightness and the
color if I had the ability to turn my
skin very dark while I was in hot
countries I would do it every time
because my skin is [ __ ] when I'm in
Jamaica I gotta hide I gotta stay out of
the out of the Sun I turn red I don't go
Brown
I go red pigment well pigment then I'm
telling you if I could [ __ ] turn
myself like black like darkness black
when I was in like the tropics so I
could go out and field and photograph
for hours my my Jamaican farmer friends
are out in that field for ow
I can honestly tell you if I did that I
would be in the hospital no [ __ ] joke
I just can't I I got the wrong skin and
so now if I went up to you know the the
the up north and now you're in cold
environments well the skin works great
no problem I like it
but dude Daniel I am a redhead I swear
to God without having red hair
I'm basically a redhead that's how I
burn in the tropics it's really a bummer
yeah I do SunGard I've had them down
there I've spent six to eight weeks at a
time down there or so I know yeah I
don't know why I said well I didn't say
melatonin I thought I said I thought I
said melon melon in the melted
anyway I misplaced I'll have to go in
it'll probably be close to that though
if I go and look at that I just turn red
it's brutal especially because I want to
spend a lot of time in the fields I want
to spend time flying my drone I want to
do macro photography I want to take real
photos and then I want to just spend
time being in the field and these fields
are out there out and open there's not
so much melanin yeah okay there we go
perfect melatonin make you take that so
you can go to sleep at night but
one-sixteenth ginger in my beard there
you go let's get melty actually well
that's how it happens sometimes yes I'm
looking forward to going down to Jamaica
and filming some footage of the growth
of the processing facility of the
bottling and packaging plant of like all
the different sort of things that are
now fitting together as we as we come
together on this project it's pretty
[ __ ] incredible
five years man if I could sail a boat
down there and live that would be dope
well you probably could son girl you
know I met some people down there in the
90s that were doing just that
my buddy Terry who had the boat he had a
catamaran called the Lion of Judah and
he lived off the coast of Negril there
it's a 580 right now Oh excellent
Ivan Martos you should have her watch
the story of Hilary telling the story of
her
one year old grandma gettin turned on to
cannabis I don't know if any of you guys
saw that story I've known her grandma
probably since she was like 82 or 83 so
a fairly long time maybe even longer
almost 20 years anyway what criteria do
you use when looking for property well
earthling I'm not too worried about
property myself I'm not the farmer so
usually the farmer and a few other
people I'm a processor so my processing
office my lab wherever our lab I should
sake is Tony processes with me it can
kind of go anywhere we don't really care
as long as we have some power as long as
we have access to water you know these
are the things that are most important
for us otherwise it really doesn't
matter where the field itself is now if
you asked that question to our grower
well he would answer things like access
to water
vicinity proximity to the road you know
is it a stupid like hike into the bush
40 minutes we can't do that that's
old-school prohibition we need to pull
trucks up right next to the field and
have it like right there so these these
are these are the ones that are going to
be the future of cannabis growing you
don't have to climb into the mountains
in Jamaica anymore that's the
prohibition mentality you don't have to
plant five acres of peanuts so that if
the police catch you in the forest near
you're going to field you can walk them
to the peanuts and say that you're a
peanut farmer you don't have to do that
anymore in Jamaica either so really
looking forward to make just got that
son they got that water the some in the
water are the two things that they can
really everyone can afford in Jamaica
it's available to everyone so shout out
to Tony let's have a seat Cuban chronic
I'm hitting a bubble hash rosin right
now
yes John Ritchey spice well I wouldn't
say wrote that song for me I think he
writes songs for everybody but I'm the
character in his life and he wanted to
share through song and so he wrote a
song not about me but about dabbing I
turned him onto dabbing so I mentioned
in the song
yes I'm grown I gotta go see rads oh
[Music]
yeah thank you everyone
everyone's loving the Hat today how
about this guy is he looked properly
awake and baked or what I would say so
ooh yes melty heads well four corners I
don't know what to tell you I don't know
what to tell ya yeah you know those
songs that cannabis specialist John
Mason Luton Fire all doing the full
mount rhythm that was pretty awesome too
bubbleman with the food myth bubbling
it's one of my favorite lines from
original I think the word dabbing
started out with a bad reputation
especially when I came out and started
dabbing hash and people were like what's
that I'm like it's dabs and they're like
dabs dabs was BHO people thought dabs
were vho so I think what we did since
then is we opened it up to the fact that
dabs are much more than just the pho
they are you know isolated
cannabinoids and terpenoids from the
plant and they're [ __ ] awesome how
can you not love dads now if your dabs
are soaked in chemical solvents and my
capital oil soluble contaminants that
are present in the particular solvent
you use well that's not awesome at all
but do I have to open the tinychat I
thought you could just go there and it's
always there we're did what term
originated but rich where did what term
originated dabbing I have no idea I'm
not sure if we first said it I know that
my friends were dabbing back in the 90s
with oil when they created the mayor you
know most of the thumbnails on the
videos are picked automatically they
just choose them in red and randomly
generate three thumbnails and choose one
sometimes I'll go in and I'll pick a
different of the three and the odd time
I'll go in and I'll create a custom
thumbnail and make that the thumbnail
now if I don't choose a thumbnail and I
go make say a live video that hasn't
gone live yet it'll show my avatar from
the top page of the YouTube channel so
yeah it was pretty neat for a long time
a new person would come on hash Church
and it would be them who was the avatar
and I wasn't doing it I was like holy
[ __ ] this is amazing I'm not sure I'll
have to find out from Sara I sure hope
so I don't think we're releasing any
pumpkin spice flavor no hot and I had
two original dabs from the 80s yeah
exactly well waters my friends even was
hooking up a step higher because they
created this thing called the mayor
these were the guys from the Kootenays
known as the holy smokes voice my old
friends dustin sunflower paul de filiz
and allen Middlemiss these guys were
constantly they held down Nelson BC
which is like a fairly large like a
small little town right
like on near the border and if you can
imagine throughout the 90s a lot of
people would just take weed because they
grew a beautiful weed it was kind of
like our Humboldt or our northern
for Nia for British Columbia the
Kootenays is known for growing
exceptional cannabis and people would
walk that cannabis across the border
because it was so easy they had known
these trails for a long long time
whether you wanted to go on a quad or
whether you wanted to just walk you can
take a backpack with you and walk across
and you could turn your $1500 pounds
into like thirty five hundred dollars or
three thousand or whatever and so a lot
of people were doing that the holy
smokes guys they were not Smuggler's but
they were the cannabis activists of
Nelson so they were constantly in court
they were constantly defending
themselves and they created this thing
years ago called the mayor like the
mayor of the city and it was like a
propane torch and bent over the propane
torch was a spoon like a stainless steel
spoon that was like like clamped to the
neck of the torch and so when you turn
the torch on it would just be hitting
this spoon and then over top of the
spoon they had a glass bell that fit
over top of the spoon and went down into
a tube that went into a pipe a glass
pipe and it was called the mayor and
that's how breeder steve got turned onto
the dabs and that's how like many many
people in the 90's here and DC got
turned on through those guys that
bald-faced logic Nelson's amazing for
anyone that sneeze or snowboarding
that's the [ __ ] backcountry place of
course made quite famous by well Travis
doo-doo-doo to do interesting a skillet
yeah but a lot of knobs have a chemical
coating you shouldn't inhale well and
listen these were nobodies saying that
this was the good way we did a whole
bunch of stupid [ __ ] back there and I
don't know if I'm gonna participate on
Friday Mike atomic skier I haven't
gotten an email I got an email asking to
be on it I wrote them back saying I'd
love to be on it I haven't heard back
from them then I talked to him a little
briefly in this show and he thought I
had a problem with him and I assured him
I had no problem with him whatsoever
so yeah if I hear from him and I have
time on Friday I'll go on the show
absolutely dry sector wet shift that is
the question but the answer is whatever
you choose there is no right answer you
know there is no right answer
anyway 235 people glad to caught up to
our regular numbers I am going to be
heading into the city
today gonna go check out the Terp
mansion winds of west or winds west if
you check them out on Instagram I guess
I should probably give you the right
account just in case let's see oh there
he is right there
he is winds west wim d SW est apparently
they're visiting in from the Okanagan
right now and they've got a bunch of
headed pieces over there so I thought
maybe I'd go film a little bit puff some
bowls and see what was what may happen
may not feel free to go to the tiny chat
app I don't have time today to do tiny
chat but I'm pretty sure I don't have to
be in there for it to be open I think
you guys can just go and it's always
there I'll try my best sticks but more
likely I will go live on my phone
depending on how awesome of the tert
mansion is so uh yeah we gave your shirt
away we puff some Bulls sound send me an
email BC bubble man at iCloud calm and I
will send you that triple XL share of my
brother and no hard feelings I hope all
is well with you and yours and I hope
that well how would I say it
may the full melt bless your bowl sooner
than later peace out everybody