[Music]
hey what's up guys morning here with the
great Garder about to do a little bit of
a I guess morning sesh a morning sesh
but a not quite wake and bake sesh we've
already had food we've already baked a
bit but it's 230 we've got the ceramic
insert cleaned very nicely we found out
that the torch definitely does clean the
ceramic better than trying to scrape it
with a skillet
tool and just grab the gold dab there
Afghani yes the afghanis you can go
closer with that one too it'll actually
Focus ni that one's the barbar bud 73
bar such a nice coloring flavor on that
Barbara he
120 beautiful what's to start
with hea you just said hea oh Afghani I
meant but this is oh this one's a
Afghani heom dry sift we made
yesterday that's the
one that's a mix that's the one let's
hit that one let's hit it let's drop
that on the ceramic
uh
I'll lift it
up give them the
viewy
though mey yeah nice
taste I think I I'm going to
hit what are you going for I think I'm
going to hit the Barb 45 the Barb nice
difference in the colors I just want to
show them real quick the Barb you can
tell that there's a difference in tpin
right there one is almost a reddish
color this one here this one has much
more of a blonde color to it and this is
the 45 the reddish darker one and the
more I wouldn't say reddish but almost
the orangish tinge to it compared to the
the more blonde for sure there you
go pretty stoked on this little ceramic
insert that Dil sent me um now that
we've actually figured out torching it
and getting it um getting it properly
cleaned it's it's a pretty pretty neat
little unit just paint the the the Melt
right onto it and it
just bubbles quite
lovely nice save
though it's not as Tippy as you think
think
hey m i find just a right angle you hit
it on the side it find when I touch it I
I'm more inclined to touch it in the
middle almost then on the edge on the
edge it tends to do its little I'm sure
the guys will figure it out this was
originally designed to insert into the
titanium nail my titanium nail that I
have was a special nail that they ground
down and the walls were a little thicker
so it didn't fit into it so I figured if
it sits on the tie nail like that it
could sit on the quartz nail like that
so they were surprised they had no
intentions of using it with a quartz
nail but uh I'll tell you I have every
intention of using it with a quartz
nail anybody
else off
camera I'll do one more on camera which
one you going to hit I think I'm going
to hit this Barbara
120 the light the light have you seen
the
light all right let's see if we can just
paint that on there you're losing it I
lost it I better heat it up
first sometimes it's best to heat the
Dabber up just a tiny little bit on the
nail or on the
ceramic you can
literally pick up a nice big
rock and paint that on
there
bring around the
rosie makes you
Rosy around the
ceramic that was delicious we're going
to continue to do much of this and we'll
get back to some hash making uh probably
in the near
future more importantly some uh some
interviews with uh great gardener about
just how he runs the the garden little
bit of uh the people that help him and
just sort of an allaround you know I
know a lot of you guys have questions
and stuff so we'll get to some of those
questions as well all right
[Music]
peace