hey everybody welcome to the wake and
bake episode number 78
we got another session happening here
today what's av all those great people
out there in puf puf land we got octo
tom in the house and big Chu and Ryan
Axton and one sub-10 alright let me just
make sure we're all working here we're
working we're working pages in the house
Samuels in the house chillin like a
villain
Alan muta tjuta there's Amelia lavender
Austin Bram the island haze and small
tubes I want to hit some of that island
haze what's going on everybody it is
kind of morning still 10:40 here on the
west coast I have an exciting day
planned out for me I have not done a
bubble man video in a long time I'm not
talking about these live videos I'm
talking about
yes Ella sewed 78 I'm talking about
filming with my camera editing adding
music having transitions and so today
I'm going to be heading up to high
integrity glass art and apparently Team
Japan is over there right now dosa is
over there right now and they are
blowing up a storm on the torches that
high integrity glass art has put in and
super stoked super stoked to go down
there in film I've never met the
Japanese crew I've never met dosa so I'm
very much looking forward to you know
just being the humble filmer showing you
guys all this beautiful beautiful
glassblowing that's going to be made and
you know I'll probably see flap-flap
lives over there as well and he'll
probably come over for a visit but I'm
actually heading over to high integrity
glass art slinger will not be there but
boy wouldn't that be awesome and I'm
sure with him building the facility the
way he did I think his interest is to
invite glass blowers he's got beds for
them to sleep he's got torches for them
to work on and it's a great idea for his
business what better way to get you know
to gain control over the pieces that are
blown than having them be blown in your
own studio so without further ado I
think we should have a big old dry sip
trip this morning we're gonna get get
busy with some sift yes I dropped a tiny
little bit but you know what we won't
cry over spilt milk sometimes
got to pour a little out for your homie
although you know when I'm pouring it
out from my homie I prefer to pour it
out in to my sapphire dish that's just
me
how Paul and you have to be to invite
dosa and team Japan to your place you
have to be baller extreme baller
extraordinaire
he's uh he's balling but remember
everyone job provide it's all there for
you it's all there for you this was a
gift from Richie spice he has a song
called job provide and oh right on Dan
Richards you know I had a few people
contact me and say they didn't receive
the gifts I sent and that kind of bummed
me out
I'm gonna have to resend I guess I have
no idea Samuel I'm so I'm sure he's been
pretty good he's busy I don't talk to
the great gardener very often myself but
he's over on the sunshine on the island
doing his thing where we got in here
where we got in here oh good to hear
yeah bingo I think most everyone did but
there was a few who didn't and I was
just kind of bummed out about it it's
it's always a bummer when you tell
someone you're gonna send something and
then they don't just don't receive it a
UPS didn't drop it at my door so it took
forever for me to actually get to the
store and pick it up oh [ __ ] I didn't
even realize that she sent it UPS oh
good morning Indra good morning Pedro
Robles and iron wolf and bud richest ECX
a dubs and Ryan Axton and dabs for days
and hopefully green and Cuban chronic
and stick with Terps I always like to
say hi to everyone I always like to say
hi to everyone it's nice to be
acknowledged
don't you think let me get rid of that
real quick it's amazing how many
messages I get and how many things come
in on my phone while I'm doing these
videos it's absolutely unbelievable
so yeah I was tempted to do the
wake-and-bake from the ferry I thought
that might have been fun and you know
what if I see something really cool on
the ferry I'll go live you know if
there's some whales or dolphins swimming
around on the side I'll film it with the
camera make sure you guys get to see
some of that and yeah
in the meantime I'm really excited I get
the ferry is in one hour and 15 minutes
and if I were in a car I'd probably be
leaving soon to go and drive and get in
line but I'm on a bike so I'll be
getting on the ferry first and I'll be
getting off the ferry first and that's
the beautiful thing about being on a
motorcycle it's quite a bonus yeah what
new genetics do you recommend Jesus I
don't know I mean I there's a lot of
great genetics out there obviously the
strawberry-banana from DNA and the
Crockett boys is insane this oh gee 18
we recently made some melt with down in
California is absolutely insane any and
all hay strains ghost train amnesia
[Music]
really any haze anything that's got that
exotic sort of terpene alene pining
Carrie awfully mix is something that I'm
always stoked on for the most part
narrowly if yeah I'm not like I mean
I'll smoke anything don't get me wrong
but I prefer the good narrow leaf yeah
yeah DNA it's got some great selections
there's no doubt about it from day one
since meeting those guys they've had
great selections they do great work and
they're great dudes so it's pretty easy
to to support all in all I've been
hitting some green crack the past couple
of weeks there you go dabs yeah Green
crack is pretty nice and racy
Oh injures got a show - this Saturday
I'm gonna be competing with Todd but
don't worry because on Sunday you know
where I'll be I will be on hash Church
and I'm not sure if we're going to be
doing what we're gonna be doing this
week on hash Church but it should be
pretty good I put the word out to a few
different people and we'll see what
transpires on what materializes hey very
cool Evan got to be like in that ah
there you go there's not you're not the
first one to do a show right after
hashed Church let me tell you there's a
few people that kind of figured out that
time slot it's kind of like being the
string cheese incident back in the day
when fish was touring or Dave Matthews
it's like those guys would always go and
tour literally the day that fish had off
in between the two places that they were
traveling from which was brilliant
really you know that you've got a large
audience that just came off of watching
a great show and then boom there you go
that's that's a pretty good slot but
there are a few people that have
definitely done that slot I can't
remember the names of the shows but
there's there's a couple that do their
shows right after hash Church on well
you know what sach it's called being
inspired I don't look at it as copying I
mean sure the the little insecure child
inside of me might be like but who cares
about that in reality it's not copying
its inspiration what how do we we take
steps in a ladder well how did the next
step in the ladder get there if the
first step said oh you're copying me
hmmm it's like no I'm the next step in
the ladder and then the next step and
then the next step and then the next
step and it's how we climb it's how we
elevate ourselves it's how we raise the
bar so don't look at it as copying so
much as keep in mind here we go here we
go
I was not the first one to sell water
hash bags isolator bags were the first
bags
everyone bitched and whined and said I
was copying I was copying I was copying
well 10 to 20 years later I can assure
you that they all say bubble bags set
the bar bubble bags brought the new
brought the new level so it's like it
it's it's inspirational to have new
shows coming and and and coming up and
creating new they're fitting and filling
gaps that are there that the the maybe
you know when you're the first than
anything there's gonna be so many gaps
and everything that you do and then the
next people that come along can fill
those gaps or fill some of those gaps
and in the end it's always for the
people you can never have enough we want
more we don't want to fight against
something that always exists and having
a YouTube channel is not competition
especially here in the cannabis world I
mean my god I work every day at this and
I get a hundred and sixty people of
watching you know with a couple of
thousand views Joely Olli has like 1.5
million YouTube YouTube YouTube he's got
his own little thing and he does bond
rips and it's ridiculous and hilarious
but that [ __ ] gets hundreds of
thousands if not millions of hits every
time he posts a video so when I see
videos like that I don't think about
competition in regards to me and my
friends Remo was one of my huge
inspirations Remo had his channel years
before I had mine and I watched his
channel and I kind of got inspired by it
and I talked to him and I asked him what
camera he had and these are the this is
how we inspire each other and because
Remo is not a scared little boy he just
shared all this information he's like
yeah I do this do that you can you can
get this camera it's so great thank you
so much Remo and because of it I've done
the same thing for anyone that's asked
me why not same with my macro
photographs anything that people want to
learn you know if I hadn't shared the
information some of the some of the
people that are doing and doing great
things today they might not be doing it
on the same level you know and I feel
the exact same way because Remo and some
other key people shared information with
with me including me monkey who was from
overbroad days the sky this guy from the
UK man he gave me so much information on
macro photography when Jason King the
author of the canna Bible would not tell
me a single
I asked him if he would show me some
tips about macro photography because I
had an interest and he said yeah as soon
as you show me how to manufacture bubble
bags and sell them all around the world
on the internet that's exactly what he
said to me so yeah my channel I think
started in oh five but I didn't really
start posting till around twenty twelve
or so well that's exactly in Amelia I
don't really feel so much that it's
competition okay yeah I was a little bit
shocked when Todd was not coming to hash
Church anymore and had started his own
show with many of the panelists that
have been on hash Church before but that
was just a scared little boy in me and
after the community sent me many many
wonderful messages saying hey you know
just keep doing you it's all good and it
is all good it's gonna be good his show
will be great I'm not gonna be against
it and you know I think that my show
hash Church is going to be about
inclusivity
it's about including people and not
trying to create only the cream of the
cream of the cream because I think
everyone is the cream of the crop in
hash Church I think I love my bros D
420k and John Barr fellow you know they
they sit there they laugh they share
what stories they can and what
information they can and I love them for
it they may not be chemists they may not
be doctors with PhDs but they certainly
belong on the show they're they're a
part of it and that's why that's why I
want to be inclusive and that's exactly
it injury you know having someone tell
me that someone I'm not going to come on
if so-and-so is on your show just seems
childish to me and it doesn't seem
inclusive and so I'm gonna continue on
the way we're doing it be inclusive and
invite as many people on as possible and
most paid miss potheads well I don't
think I'm on that list myself but
there's some pretty famous pot heads out
there like real famous people obviously
Bob Marley maybe the most famous herb
herb aficionado on the planet
and then you know many of his sons you
know right under that snoop obviously
huge back in the day woody was pretty
well known for it and yeah he's dead
he's dead it's true but he lives on you
know he may be dead but he's the most
alive dead person I've ever come across
I mean holy [ __ ] yeah good to see chase
welcome Willie Nelson some of his mind
yeah someone this mind is the man I want
to get him on hash Church that's who's
gonna give you getting on hash Church in
the near future I also wanted to get the
jungle boys on hash Church talk to them
a little bit and maybe I'll get the guys
from the real Green Dragon who are some
old-school
Cali growers that they just really
started Instagram you can check them out
the real green dragon and yeah we're
actually working with them here in the
lab in the next couple of days we're
processing resin for the real green
dragon and we just processed some for LA
Kush so a couple of companies down there
that the bubbleman brand and Blue River
and whatnot will be available at and
yeah nice to be produced in five star
plus uh Anthony you won't be
disappointed I still have a bloody K so
that I got to get back to these
giveaways but you know what the problem
with the giveaways is I stack all the
things that need to be shipped and
sometimes people send me emails that are
a little confusing they don't say what
episode and what they won and so I have
to kind of go back and it becomes this
sort of silly thing that it's just a
little bit difficult for me to keep
track of so 11 o'clock man it's soon
half an hour I get to go to the Sunshine
Coast I'm not sure if I'm gonna go live
on the Sunshine Coast or not and if I do
I'm not sure if I would go through
Instagram if you guys don't follow me on
Instagram you should be see bubble man
because I might do my live from the
ferry or from over there on Instagram so
we'll see what happens and otherwise
yeah I don't know any good any questions
today anything you guys want to talk
about what do you say what do you say I
met Berner one time seemed like a pretty
nice guy
oh yeah that's not cool Raymond but you
know what he's kind of a he's kind of a
character oh good to hear Danny we like
to inspire let me tell you Oh mister
melt I would say in the near future
you know maybe in the next three to six
months we're working on it we're working
on it
that rosewood box gotta like it
you guys did I miss the bakery nah dude
we can get more bakery Mugen Hagen
you've on to you Vaughn to bacon even
Bacon's vacant okay let's do it
burner is up there maybe sub cool yeah
some cool is a good dude I don't know
you know I hear everyone bitching about
everyone all the time I've met know most
of these people now burner I don't know
as a friend at all I met him one time in
my life through my friend Emilio from
trippy sticks out my other friend
David's place in Barcelona called HQ
hemp quarters and I sat for only a few
minutes before I split and went and sat
with my friends but ya seem like a fine
dude but man he gets a lot of hate I
think the more real or not the more real
sorry I just read someone say be real
the more known you become the easier it
is for people to just hate you I'm not
too sure why but yeah be real met him a
few times as well it seems like a pretty
nice dude
I got some turps triggers yeah right
Ryan I had Australian people emailing me
for days begging me not ever to do that
again in fact I think the Australian
Legislature legislation passed up some
policy saying that I'm absolutely not
allowed to do it anywhere in the world
if you can imagine it's I was devastated
I'm not gonna lie I was devastated see I
can do that that's Liverpool I was
devastated
sometimes I kill like not in a good way
but what can I say
did you miss the giveaway survivor you
did not miss the giveaway you didn't in
fact you won you won a bottle a DC
cleaner send me an address bc bubbleman
at icloud.com you won the giveaway bro I
wasn't even gonna do one
alright let's follow exactly exactly
exactly everything that all of you said
exactly that's how I felt
that's how it should be [ __ ] this
contest [ __ ] it's gotta be like
count of concentrate set it's gotta be
brilliant with capital letters the ant
was brilliant you know that one just now
was brilliant and I'm not joking
you did win it might have seemed like I
was being sarcastic but you 100% won the
giveaway survivor send me an email bc
bubbleman at icloud.com i want you to
mention the episode 78 the name that you
were under what you won DC glass cleaner
and your full address and i'm gonna ship
you a model so how about that what do
you have what do you have a favorite hat
you know I have all sorts of favourite
hats but they're not based on like
what's on them although this one might
be close because this this guy this guy
is [ __ ] cool I mean honestly the guy
that drew this like he has so much
character he's just like hey
you want this leaf grow room from
William these guys are the bomb so
obviously anytime I can support my
Brazilian brethren and sistren I'm going
to it is a great hat it is a great hat
I do wear Adams hats all the time fly I
just like the way they fit they're
simple it's not like a logo that's like
too much most people don't even
recognize what it says and I like the
purple underneath and how it fits my
head and that I can change the size I
love that my son can pull it off my head
make it smaller and put it on his head
and that brings a smile to my face what
about Mexican brethren well come on I'm
always gonna support them as well I'm an
Earthling so I support all earth people
regardless of their divisions of race or
color or belief system I look at them
all the same I support them all yeah I
got purple friends I got maroon friends
you know what you know it survivor one
time dude you won the giveaway how sweet
is that I'm gonna give you one of these
you're gonna get one of these yeah a lot
of people thought it says Flav it says
fly I have never watched house of cards
people tell me I should but what are you
gonna do I'm glad you're here toasted
toaster grow yeah dude
you must be so stoked how wicked is that
you come in you like did I miss the
giveaway and you won the giveaway that
was literally the line I was waiting for
to give something away today and you
were the one now I know there's gonna be
three people that said I actually said
that line prior and then you're gonna
send me screenshots but I am the pump
and the pump don't lie yeah well some of
them don't want to let out their ribs
Dylan some of them some people hold on
to [ __ ] you know they just hold on to
[ __ ] in a way that is almost
unbelievable I should probably do one
more monster sifter if I gotta tell you
it is unbelievable how strong full melt
dry sift is as you puff two or three in
a row I'll never forget the first time I
smoked
to skunkman Sam man that wasn't it that
was an experience it really was an
experience especially because he
for-sure for-sure for-sure was trying to
kill me oh right on negative glow well
I'm I'm happy to be a friend I'm happy
to help I'm not sure you want to you
know follow me everywhere but maybe I
can offer inspiration here and there I'm
fallible I make my own mistakes
maybe one day I'll just share a bunch of
my mistakes with you guys some of them
are good some of them are bad but it's
just about a positive outlook you know
people are always wondering it's it's
how oh how did you how did you get where
you are how did you do what you did and
I'm just like I just had a positive
outlook even though in the negative
things in fact most importantly in the
negative things it was when I had a
positive outlook that the negative that
energy that intense energy there's so
much energy in that moment that with
with positivity you can transfer that
energy into good and it is like a big
crack you know out of the park Grand
Slam everyone hit the bases whoo-hoo it
happens it happened to me it can happen
to you
David I'm blessed in life you know even
when I wasn't blessed I was blessed I've
been blessed with health which to feel
good to me is the most important thing I
love people so my value in life comes
from people not people that are
well-known or famous or whatever or they
can do my personal agenda well but
people I see every person as a person
who can help you and more importantly
that you can help if you couldn't make
someone's day better by saying a couple
of words or giving them a [ __ ] eight
dollar bottle of balm cleaner why
wouldn't you why wouldn't you and then
the way I look at it is it's contagious
it gets passed on you know someone
smiled at me the other day it was just a
lovely smile and I and I literally
minutes later I found myself helping
this guy deliver his Pat his he had
these things on a roller super heavy
bunch of boxes and I just lifted it up
over the lip to let him get into the
store that I was walking to I probably
would have done it anyway but as I was
doing it I felt that woman who had
smiled at me just a nice smile good
morning it's like it's nice to be nice
to each other I'm not sure it's a good
idea to be living in cities that are so
close that we're all miserable and angry
with one another and complaining
constantly yeah Toni Brazoria is a
genius [ __ ] great guy
we work really well together Tony and I
like peanut butter and jam very
symbiotic and always always always doing
great things you're gonna see a lot of
what we've been doing you know Tony's
been showing little bits and pieces of
the lab work and you know the new
technologies with the terpenes and some
of the new products and the you're gonna
see a bunch of new things that are
coming out and we're gonna be talking
about Jamaica in the near future as well
so there's lots of good things happening
um
I currently do not own shares in scene
AB not yet I'm working out to make that
happen in the very near future
apparently they say I do but I haven't
seen the documents so I really will be
waiting for those documents but yeah I
would definitely you know United
cannabis is doing great things prana is
an amazing product and the fact that
it's in harbor side and Steve DeAngelo
loves it but the fact that it was it was
the basis of Riverrock success I think
that we're very very very excited at the
prospects of being able to one day
produce the raw product medicine in
Jamaica so we can produce prana and ship
it worldwide out of Jamaica Sun grown
tropical grown you know lion bred
cultivars from Jamaica
I've seen some cultivars with Valentin
Terps absolutely off the top of my head
I'd have to go through my list there's
if you go on SC labs you can go through
their terpene tests and most of like
Tony Blue River all the ones we had done
our public so you can click on it and
you can see them they're also at Blue
River extract CA and Blue River extracts
calm under terpenes and you can look at
all of the different terpene laboratory
tests and it'll show you
Valentin's towards the bottom just look
for one that has some present it's
always a very small amount but it's
there it is there yeah yeah man it's
gonna be good it's gonna be good trust
me we're very excited about it yeah head
ear if you know it's not a bad idea
dude I'm right down the street from both
harbor sides we'll go check it out dude
they have bubble man brand they have
blue river they have prana well the
super dupe that's oxidization it could
be water present that's doing that if
you don't dry it properly if you dry it
in a paddy and the water stays there
that'll you know magnify the light
that's getting into it it'll oxidize it
faster get the water out break it into
powder use a desiccant to with gravity
to pull the moisture out of the resin as
soon as possible and if you want to
preserve the color you can put it in the
fridge and keep it cold and the color
will stay the same however take a little
bit and go both ways and you'll see the
preserved is often a little more racy
and the cured is often a little more
Spacey so it really depends on what you
want for your high those are total
generalizations by the way I don't want
you to think that that's the way it's
gonna be all the time but it is kind of
a generalization you know you cut the
the cultivar down a little early it's a
bit racy I eat blonde Lebanese hash you
cut it down a little late it's a little
more Spacey ie red Lebanese hash same
hashes just cut early cut late hey they
see a lot of product Frankie a lot of
product to get in there you really got
to have your price point and your
quality has to be on point
IG for what's hat
FATA Mike I miss that cannabis cup
winter 2017 there you go there you go
man take Mexican bud and concentrate and
clean it so you don't have to break it
and send it over I'm sure they're doing
it dude I'm sure they're doing it
concentrates are vast they're all over
the place
Oh actually that's great to hear Savage
I'm glad that that that came oh look at
this and it's mitt little little bum bot
little bum bot needs to be blocked out
five-star you pop those reformat seeds
no I have not I've held on to them until
the greenhouse gets here yes I have
smoked Hawaiian strains from the early
90s
I crack up at the banhammer well
sometimes we gotta banhammer she's been
here for a while I haven't been paying
attention Amelia you know I'm listening
it's not easy to just gain my attention
with a nice set of boobs or ass I have
been with my wife for 29 years extremely
committed and you know a nice set of
boobs or a nice sort of nice ass is not
going to be grabbing my attention
anytime soon but it may grab the ban
hammers attention yeah ban hammer let's
have one more puff let's do it then I
got to get out of here because I really
do have to go to the Sunshine Coast and
I'll try to go live I'll try to do
something in the least you'll you'll be
there for the video so the video is
always fun right here we go
what's that Amelia you grab what some
lyrics or something they're difficult
[ __ ]
everyone thinks that Frankie
everyone thinks that but when you get
into a level where many many people who
have that same level and some who have
even a bit of a higher level it's you
have to understand like those guys see a
lot of material or they just have their
own greenhouse coming down with five
thousand kilos or whatever and they they
they don't need it so it's like who
knows price quality it's got to be one
of the two quality always sells quality
always sells no one ever says no to
quality like that's it's the thing about
cognitive dissonance when we think what
we have is you know I'm not saying this
about Frankie cuz Frankie very well may
have the utter and complete kill I'm not
saying that he doesn't but let's just be
honest Frankie is everyone everyone
believes they have the utter and
complete kill and sometimes often most
times they don't it's like it's like if
every restaurant thought they were the
best and it's like actually you guys are
all three-star and below and these four
and five-star restaurants are actually
the ones that are quite you know on
every level from the environment to the
dishes to the food to the service to
everything is just better and so it's a
weird thing every yeah he's he's all of
us we've all done this we've evolved on
this oh dude I hear you bro well the
2400 K pounds you know and down to like
much lower people are selling for
fifteen
tene some 4:12 all these greenhouses are
coming down I feel you bro I feel you
but understand tomatoes cost about $10
to grow so the day of you get in two
thousand dollars a pound are slowly
coming to an end we're gonna grow this
[ __ ] agriculturally bro we're gonna grow
this in fields acres and [ __ ]
hectares and sections large and then
guys like solvent las' mind and myself
are going to extract them and then all
of you guys are going to dab and smoke
it that's how it's going down
it's not gonna happen any other way I'm
damn sure making sure of it
and our acres get floured soon and think
of the acreage that I bet you it's not
that many acres that you would need to
produce the world's resin think of how
much oxycodone and fentanyl and all of
these morphine based drugs all of these
opium based drugs 90% of that opium has
grown on a tiny little island off the
coast of Tasmania
they grow tons and tons and tons of it
but it's for almost the whole
pharmaceutical world and so I think we'd
be surprised that we could get it done
in a pretty decent amount of land to
grow the world's resin oh let's not get
political no no let's not do that that's
like saying let's all argue about
vaccinations let's all talk about our
religious beliefs [ __ ] that's funny
we're not gonna do any of that hey how's
it going solving this mind I was just
talking earlier how badly I want to get
you a on awaken bake or be even more
importantly on a hash Church and just
talk about resin and talk about hash
making and talk about [ __ ] all sorts
of real [ __ ] be good to have you dude I
don't know why we can't seem to make it
happen but let's try to make it happen
in the near future and now that I've
said it on a chat
everyone's gonna keep making sure they
ask me each time hey what's going on
with solvent let's mine is he gonna be
coming in ah you want to give the world
a beautiful slice of chocolate cake
sounds like some I know who that sounds
like I know who that sounds like don't
think your joke has not escaped me as it
has not it caught me right here see
there's even a little red mark now where
you got me see that [ __ ] can't even make
that up
oh well 34 minutes I don't know I'm
having a really good time I'm enjoying
the conversation today I wish I was out
on the water but I have got to go soon
here and yeah messages are coming in and
well it's been a blast everybody always
enjoy these wake and bakes you know
we're gonna have another one tomorrow
you know we're gonna have another one on
Saturday and maybe we'll get solvent
let's mine in on one of these waking
bakes and we'll see what's happening
have yourself a great day everyone
survivor don't forget to send me that
email bro you were just in time for the
giveaway you're the winner today bro
you're all winners
thanks for coming and hanging out and
made the full Mel bless your bowl sooner
than later everybody peace out