hey we did it we did it we did it that
took three tries just so everybody knows
welcome to bubble man's world everybody
and welcome to the wake-and-bake episode
62 I am of course still out camping in
the world of beautiful British Columbia
about to head off on a epic epic [ __ ]
oh I'm not seeing anyone's chat oh there
we go come on let's see the chats guys I
revived the DAB Matt today thank you
bubble man ah excellent Sven excellent
Sven you haven't been sending me insane
emails have you that don't make any
sense and like talk about aliens and
getting some crazy emails from this dude
hey what's going on Martin Gillis from
Ireland
sir globs lot slipped streams old-timer
big t the grow green show whoredom at
anthropods a CLE Danny Moe natural
alternatives obviously I could keep
going like this all day but I suspect
we're gonna get another 100 or 200
people in the room so I'll probably just
stop right now but really [ __ ] good to
see everybody we're definitely gonna get
our wake-and-bake on and we're also
gonna give away another dab mat now the
reason I've given away the oil slick dab
mats for the last three days in a row is
because I'm not writing anything down
it's a little bit confusing to try and
do work while you're away on a camping
trip but we've given away too so far
we've got the third one going right now
I guess I'm gonna do a simple pick a
number it's going to be between 1 and 50
you guys can start guessing right now if
you would like and we'll be given a DAB
mat away nice labor of love that's what
I like to hear 511 love the clouds 842
1717 32:43 34 33 32 34 45 36 33
1218 233 4549 248 30 28 4166 231 24 27
148 25 holy [ __ ] really nobody come on
guys you haven't said it yet how about
we go like this it's between 1 and 40
it's between 1 and 40 all right come on
come on I'm looking for it I still
haven't seen this number it's quite
hilarious I just want to have my bake
you guys are killing me I like it when
you guess first and win 83 is definitely
way far
in the loop we got a poor connection oh
oh oh we got a poor connection all right
let me go through here and check it out
we still haven't seen it okay it's it's
a number between one and 30 you guys can
do this I know you can 15 rice amos has
taken it
rice amos you win 15 is the number I had
in my head
herb farmer sorry you came in a little
bit late rice if you want to send me an
e-mail at BC bubble man at iCloud there
everyone's guessing 50 now that's
awesome a BC bubble man at iCloud calm
that's okay but rich I am the pump I
didn't see it it's not on my screen the
phones and the computers are a little
bit different but don't worry it's just
a $10 dab mat and it's really nothing to
be upset about
I'm the pump you're the inside of the
pump anyway let's get our wake-and-bake
on to me I just wanted to get the
giveaway away I just want to have a bake
with you guys have a little conversation
definitely don't want to hear any
bitching but hey we can congratulate the
person who won even if you guessed
before them and it showed up on your
screen and it didn't show up on mine it
doesn't make me a dick I promise I
wouldn't try to [ __ ] you over a $10 dad
mat and in fact I'm probably not gonna
stop giving these away until everyone
has one Shh it's a secret all right so
let's get on with a little glacier melts
today we're gonna hit some glacier
mounts this was super greasy Oh greasy
greasy greasy Thank You Phil from
glacial melt glacial melt snot glacier
for those of you that think I'm
mispronouncing it because of course I've
gotten messages about that as well it's
always nice when people are willing to
help you out when you make a mistake all
right
this stuff is super greasy really gonna
be a nice rip looking forward to havin
on some raw garden what's up lounge
liver lizard
Kelo n oh gee Peter s you know as I
start to see Josh Warner all these names
are people that have won things on the
channel how [ __ ] cool is that dabbing
on recon og right at home with the
correct time sup all right let's do this
let's wake and bake
cuz I gotta get going I'm leaving for
home today
and I want to get a four-hour ride in
still great if dr. Bob said that have
them contact me or I'll contact him and
we'll do it out I would love to do that
with dr. Bob he's a huge inspiration to
me hey happy birthday Josh Warner forgot
about that
happy birthday hope everything is going
good on your birthday oh really my sound
is switching on and off well what can I
say we have a very poor connection and
we're lucky that we even have this
connection at all I will not be missing
spannabis 2018 trust me I got a lot of
emails from a lot of people asking me
what the [ __ ] were you not doing at the
Cannabis all right let's do this up
what's up Birds couple of birds joining
me for a rip
oh yeah I can hear my friends lighten up
bikes in side-by-sides rock the Chazz
nah dude that's just because I'm camping
it'll clean off very nice there's very
minor Chaz on my bowl right now just a
matter of doing a little hello clean
will get that Chaz all nice and clean
that's the beautiful thing about the DC
glass cleaner and we're gonna give away
a bunch of bottles of that when I get
home that'll be the start of of the DC I
have at least ten bottles to give away
so and I'll probably hit up sasquatch
again an oil slick and mothership and
dab mats and see if they have an
interest in supplying things I love the
idea of given a little thing away
nothing major nothing major older
cleaner
well the cleaner is called there we go
getting better right a little bit of a
little bit of a piece back here I got to
work on but otherwise I'm quite happy
with how my bowl looks yes the end glass
cleaner alright guys probably only
really have time for one today as we are
about to get going here
but thank you guys as always for joining
me I don't know how many people we have
in the room but it's probably 100 or 200
and that's really [ __ ] cool got my
oil slick shirt on today tools to help
you concentrate what a [ __ ] great
logo he has tools to help you
concentrate ah thank you Peter for some
reason in my connection solo it won't
show me what's going on but thanks
everyone
honestly for coming out and spending
time I feel like I'm getting to know you
guys all your little avatars and you're
a good group of people I have to tell
you that we take care of the trolls
together you guys are helpful
you guys are positive and I'm just happy
to be a little bit of a part of your day
whether it's morning or evening or night
and just be good be happy be loving
[ __ ] a everybody bubble on and may
the full melt bless your bowl sooner
than later peace for now
Louie Louie