hey we're live a little bit of a sketchy
connection here probably cuz I'm beside
my house and who knows we might have to
move this connection we'll see if we can
go live here in a second otherwise I'm
going to try and get a better connection
it says very bad connection so you guys
let me know if I'm coming through okay
the chat still hasn't started over
yonder
good morning had been a long time since
I made a wake-and-bake well I'm glad you
made it Samurai Sam I hope you can
actually see and hear me because
apparently this is a terrible connection
not just terrible but very bad that's
what my phone's telling me anyway I'll
see what happens if it's gonna give us
some love or what ah just taking my time
here still haven't seen it go live on
the other unit there morning Cuban
chronic and gastro grower juda number 41
Sully 501 Jordi sandal can you see me is
the connection okay is it okay I'll wait
because no one has answered me I still
don't even know if you guys can see me
at all so once someone answers me out of
maybe one of the 50 or so people ah
there we go lag in the bubble is here
good morning good morning I see you
bubbles
okay well excellent excellent I hope
everyone's doing well I'm gonna be
giving away an oil slick today
get that out of the way real quick and
simply put Todd McCormack had a good
friend his living with him at the
bel-air mansion right before he got
busted that was the the bus that Todd
served five years for on Terminal Island
and there was a gentleman who lived
there with him and I'm wearing his face
on my shirt today
and if you can tell me what this
gentleman's name is you will have won
yourself a oil slick here this is great
for pressing rosin or keeping your rosin
on and we'll see what we got going on
let's see what kind of things we know
all right we can see you looks great
good good good excellent so now someone
answered the question it's bouncing all
around
bouncing all around Wow chat is moving
so fast and no one has answered the
question yet no one has has answered the
question yet I'm just gonna keep an eye
on the chat until someone can answer the
question of who this gentleman is it was
arrested with Todd McCormick at the
bel-air mansion he is an author of over
almost 40 books actually and yeah he's
sitting on my shirt right here tell me
what his name is author of almost 40
bucks self-help offer author I want his
full name
I want his full name you need to say
that again dude it's mad laggy well
enough people are answering I think that
it's probably okay I want this
gentleman's name
he lived with Todd McCormick in the
bel-air mansion was doing some projects
with them when the mansion was busted
and it's great that you've given me his
first name but like I said before I want
his full name
so one name's not gonna cut it don't
even bother answering if you're just
gonna guess one single name keep going
guys this can't be that hard oh my
goodness Michael Jackson in and out good
afternoon from the UK you guys have a
lot of work to do and your activism let
me tell you there we go
melty heads you didn't spell it right
but you know what I'm gonna give it to
you because no one else even came close
melty heads is the winner today this is
Peter McWilliams Peter McWilliams was
arrested at the bel-air mansion put on
bail and told that if he used cannabis
while he was out he would have they
would take his mother's house away who
of course put her house up for the bail
Peter suffered from non-hodgkins
lymphoma and unfortunately he passed
away by choking on his own vomit as he
used cannabis to as a natural antiemetic
so very sad story wanted to sort of
where Peter's image on my shirt today
and give a shout-out to Peter McWilliams
all the great work that he did as well
as Todd mcCormick
and in the meantime melty heads if you
want to send me an email at BC bubble
man at icloud.com we would love to
send this to you yes yes the oil slick
slick sheet 48 by 16 PTFE roll ATS 122
centimeters by 41 centimeters for you
so our IP to Peter McWilliams another
drug warrior drug war warrior who was
taken out before his time it's sad when
when the drug war got so bad that they
were even just taking out you know sick
people it's it's you got to shake your
head really but let's raise our bongs
for mr. Peter on this beautiful Monday
afternoon I'm gonna get myself a little
dab here I'm gonna go in for the Terp
dip because I can and I should of course
all right yeah the pump sometimes does
that you know you just sometimes the
pump does that Alright Kouvelis our
diesel it is we are in the future yeah
it's all lagged out today it's nice to
hear you guys tell me how lagged out it
is makes me feel good about the about
the chat and about the whole
wake-and-bake episode really makes me
want to continue on I I was stupid to
pick this this spot it's beside my house
probably if I just jumped off the
internet connection it would have been
much better but apologies guys not the
smartest move from the bubble man today
so I'm just gonna have a quick rip maybe
we'll call it a day nice quick
five-minute we can make session we don't
all have to be 45
oh I know Jeff it's just the whole
conversation so it becomes kind of like
why bother kind of becomes like maybe I
should have just like take a quick rip
and end this I always try to just I feel
like a responsibility every day but it's
getting to the point where you know what
maybe a 5-10 minute one is worth it when
it's just not I mean my phone is
flashing very bad connection
very bad connection but unfortunately I
have so much stuff here that it would be
impossible for me to move everything and
we'll just have to push through get a
couple of bong rips out of the way if
possible and yeah good stuff John great
you know here's the bottom line whether
it's a really bad connection or a good
connection suck it up and deal with it
there's no really reason to make the
whole chat about how bad or good the
connection is let's just talk about
something I'm here for maybe five more
minutes if you guys have questions if
you guys want to get into some hashish
talk if you want to have a bowl
that's what I'm saying let's let's not
worry too much about the lag on the
connection otherwise it kind of hijacks
the conversation and then all we're
talking about is the connection can you
kind of see the value of like we could
be talking about hash dry sifting bond
ripping bubble hash making curing
sieving micro planing proper curing of
the plant material to gear it up and get
ready for hash making so much yeah
Vinnie you know what the whining really
just it hijacks the conversation and it
changes the vibe as you can tell I'm
slightly annoyed glad that it's working
out now that's wonderful we were patient
and it went away and now we have a
decent connection so let's have are you
a certified legend no I'm definitely not
a legend I'm not the king I'm not the
Prince I'm not anything that's anywhere
above anyone else I sit at the same
level ground level with everyone else I
am a humble servant of Job well I would
offer you some advice if you're asking a
question say in a chat room with 200
people put the person's name in front of
the question then and then they'll know
who you're asking the question - I
assume all the questions are asked being
asked to me as I'm just trying to answer
them but if it's not for me just put the
other person's name in there and we'll
hammer it out pretty good well long did
you drive the herb to make hash well it
really depends on which herb you're
talking about
did I forget my of course I did of
course I did I don't know what Alex QC
is on Instagram but I'm sure we could
get him to answer us easy enough are you
there Alex are you there my brother if
everyone wants to actually share their
Instagram feel free to if you guys want
to get each other following each other
on Instagram now might be a good time
for everyone to put up their Instagram
name it might be a good way for you guys
to connect on Instagram and of course on
BC bubbleman and mafioso no I'm
definitely not a mafioso interesting
question though yeah throw up your
instagrams I'm going to clean my bowl I
went to get my q-tips there so I could
clean out the Chazz not that there's any
Chazz right now it's actually pretty
clean it's actually pretty clean X
double XL is definitely a serious bowl
to clean whoa what about that's
something that's never happened before I
ended up getting resin all over my
finger cleaning that she was a dirty one
all right so what's everyone up to on
this beautiful Monday afternoon
oh Vitor is taking off on us
peace out Vitor any tips when your
bubble doesn't full melt I love this
question doesn't pool melt and kind of
gets black and burns yeah Cuban chronic
I got a great hint for you grow better
weed bro that's bunk I'm not trying to
be mean but for real dude if your shits
burning black and it's not melting I
mean the bags are the Word of God
they're basically telling you that what
you've grown or what whoever's grown
that you've accessed is no bueno no
bueno no bueno no bueno it's amazing how
many people ask that question hey how do
I get mine my bubble to melt it's not
melting and the answer obviously it
sounds terrible nobody is excited to
hear well you have to grow better weed
but it's a very important message to
learn from the bags when you put
something in that you think is great and
it doesn't come out great
the bags are the Word of God the
eggs are the pump you are wrong and the
bags are right so how you got that
bubble to burn black is incredible
because often the food the salts do not
really transfer into the glandular
trichomes head the things that would
make the the ash black on herb for
instance are salts in the plant matter
that don't really contaminate the
glandular head meaning I have taken
glandular heads from organic material
that was grown outside but was never
properly flushed and so the material
burned very dark and I ended up taking
that same sweet skunk and turning it
into hash and the dry sift and the wet
wash was really nice it smoked smooth so
I don't know if the person that you got
that material from was spraying
chemicals on it to make it burn black
like that but definitely that doesn't
sound good and if it's not melty if your
bubble doesn't stick together if it's
not if it's just like sand that falls
apart it's low-quality its you've grown
what I like to call Tootsie Pops which
are you know those little lollipops that
are a thick candy coating and then a
tiny little bit of the goodness in the
inside we don't want to see pops we want
water balloons we want water balloons
that are blown up so big they're about
to burst because the balloon itself is
as thin as it could possibly get and on
the inside the water that would
represent the cannabinoids and the
terpenes and they the profiles that we
seek so most people are focused on
vegetative growth they are focused on
vegetative yields how much can I get and
how fast can I get it and unfortunately
because of that the resin tends to pay
the price the integrity of the quality
it pays the price you can still take it
and purify it to 99.9% heads but if the
resin heads are Tootsie Pops instead of
water balloons you can see and trust me
most people are growing the Tootsie Pops
I'm telling you and it's just like thick
wax heads with a tiny little bit of oil
on the inside and that wax tends to burn
a little darker it doesn't melt the same
way as the oil it's just not what we're
looking for it's the carrier it's kind
of the pizza box and that's that's my
metaphor for today maybe one more
bong rip we are having before we head
off all right does anyone regulate the
thickness of the wax head during growth
does anything regulate the thickness yes
luster burn I'd suggest that it's
regulated by the ability of the grower
and the genetics of the plant to express
itself perfectly so it needs to express
its terpene and cannabinoid profile to
perfection and in order to do that all
the variables have to line up
I've had many companies tell me for
instance
Ramos company talking about nutrients
and getting the plant what it needs to
grow into this massive structure a night
I said listen if you really want to
focus on a nutrient company if you
understand the science that phenols
phenols and terpenes hydrocarbons and
alcohols are the building blocks for all
of the cannabinoids and terpenoids
inside the glandular head then why don't
we try to come up with a food that can
somehow manipulate or increase those
levels of production in the plant
because if we can produce more building
blocks more hydrocarbons and phenols
terpenes and FINA alcohols that pump up
into the upper membrane of the head the
fibrous mat that cooks those
cannabinoids into being if we can raise
those levels to me that is a point of
interest much more than trying to raise
the levels of growing you know oh the
troll hammer who do we have to get rid
of you just tell me what's his name I'll
get rid of this [ __ ]
let's fee sometimes it's hard to tell
who's the spammer Oh Sophie or the
spammer okay we'll just block you real
quick there we go hey if you want to
find me oh man people must be must be
bored I picture that as like a fifty
three-year-old overweight balding man in
his mom's basement sending out those
links the troll King too bad the troll
King met the troll hammer today and did
not stand a chance sorry Monica you as
well are gone it's quick also going off
on the spam train hey the next time I
see one I'll pay attention now I'm on
the spam hunt so
we'll make sure if we see anymore that
it's kind of funny though like that that
people are coming on here and and doing
that did you hear about the biochemist
who implanted th see developing genes
into citrus fruit and able to grow
oranges with THC doesn't surprise me
definitely heard about yeast was another
one ah Thank You Celeste steel gardener
I hope I've been a good one sorry for
being such a human and fallible but
that's the way it is hey there's Betty
looks like Betty is also looking to get
locked out on the goodbye Betty alright
no more that it is the Internet
well yes or no it depends on what kinds
of trichome there is a quality
difference there's a profile difference
in different types of trichome heads now
you know there are articles that'll tell
you there's six different types of
trichome heads but really what they're
talking about is cystal if hairs and
other really what I call non glandular
components so really there are three
trichomes that we're looking for and
really only two that I'm looking for now
from a medicinal standpoint absolutely I
would always not leave the other ones
behind the bulbous heads the ones that
are less appropriate for the smoker the
connoisseur but that have great relief
for people with different elements
Crohn's and cancers and pain related
diseases there are you know different
cannabinoid profiles in the bulbous
heads as from the sessile and the
capitate stalked and so you know the
smoker generally looks for something
along the lines of a sessile or a
capitate stock and the bulbous are these
little ones that are stuck to the leaf
and these ones are the ones that beef up
the oil returns and make it seem like
Bubble returns are small
yeah I don't know about that natural
pine bug spray I've heard all sorts of
things
remember Remo was using the turbinator
but I'm thinking that it was producing a
much higher you know those things need
to be grown and very very
environmentally controlled rooms where
you have scientists kind of writing down
all the information really keeping track
of things and the reason I say scientist
is because you're gonna need some gas
chromatograph some HPLC you're gonna
need to do some work where you test
these materials before during and after
I'm just not into taking anyone's word I
love the idea I got a company got in
touch with me recently soil I don't want
to mix up their name but this soil
company got in touch made and producing
living soils beneficial microbes the
whole nine yards probiotics and they
have a claim that they're also raising
oh sorry Clara Olson just saw you there
let me block you real quick you thought
they just mentioned that they were going
to be releasing a product I don't know
if it's in the soil but that basically
can manipulate terpene levels and raise
terpene levels so once again I never
really really trust um yeah I knew you
guys would get a hold of that listen
alright I get a kick out of that I'm
kind of the class clown I'll often say
little things for a laugh so it's a
punchline it's like a comedian so please
don't ever get offended with me I
sometimes you guys send me emails like
that I've embarrassed you in chat
there's no embarrassing anyone in chat I
think you're all great I'm not trying to
embarrass anyone and don't be worried
about being liked shown to be wrong or
something don't let your ego and your
insecurities attack you from your inner
self it's okay to be wrong it's how I
learned almost everything that I know
today and that means I had to be wrong a
lot of the time
to get this kind of knowledge stacked up
particularly in regards to cannabis
knowledge I had to be wrong a lot to get
to the level that I'm at now people ask
me how do you take such great photos I'm
like well you're only seeing the great
photo and not the ten thousand shitty
ones that I took before the great photo
so valuable mistakes instead of costly
or sorry valuable lessons instead of
costly mistakes the boats gettin picked
up tomorrow I am going to get the boat
tomorrow look it's an [ __ ] I'm gonna
have to get rid of her too even though
she just put up hearts I have a feeling
she's gonna pull some spam action on us
and you know what we can't be having
that we are getting some serious sex
spam going on today oh I got her thank
God for digital photography oh wait wait
there's another one
Dora Olsen well it's an amazing amazing
amount okay I got to go guys thanks for
watching everybody send me that email at
BC bubble man at iCloud calm and made
the full Mel to bless your ball sooner
than later everyone peace