hey what's up everybody welcome to the
awaken bake episode I wonder if I can
turn this around nope
it locks up that's okay we're sideways
it's good enough I drop my hash last
little bit but it's still enough in
there that I shouldn't be just throwing
it on the ground that's for sure hope
everyone's doing well today on this
waking bake episode 63 I see there's a
good amount of people in the room we've
got 40 or 50 people sorry that just
jumped up to 80 cool very cool
yeah Wow I have carpet I wouldn't be
these don't break you got a spike these
on tile or concrete to break them justin
trudeau cush indeed I hope everyone's
doing good we were talking a little bit
about people were talking a little bit
about you know how you finding a
cultivar that is mold resistant and/or a
cultivar that is good for the west coast
everyone wants to know what a good good
cultivar is for their environment so a
real simple way is for people that can't
seem to find the truth out there is to
do some simple research research where
your environment is are you in a dry
area like in Arizona are you in a wet
area like in Washington those two areas
are very different and they're going to
have you know certain things will be
easier to grow there and it's very
simple powder is powdery mildew
resistant cultivars generally come from
the tropics they've spent you know
generation upon generation growing in
the tropics where mildew exists and so
they've created resistance ease to it
and you know cultivars like Afghan ease
that are in the dry arid mountain ranges
that do not have have never been around
powdery mildew they have no resistance
to it they almost attract it so you plug
it in on the west coast somewhere you're
oh geez and of course you see the
pattern of many many many many many many
people getting powdery mildew so there's
a lot of that we're going on the worst
alive aren't we over here well good all
right good we're good I thought we maybe
we're dead out there for a minute so hey
let's do something fun let's give away a
bottle of DC glass cleaner really
the wick really quick talking like my
son putting an L in front of everything
the video that we're going to be asking
the question for today is called it's a
puff Wednesday so it's called puff
Wednesday and then it is called
mothership elite 3d EXO fab session so
if you like I could potentially plug
that in for you guys because it is a
little bit of a little bit of a all
right here we go
so there is the name of the video right
there puff Wednesday mothers should
believe through the EXO fab session it's
in the first few minutes of the video
and what I want to know is it's actually
in the first two and a half minutes of
the video so if you watch the first two
and a half minutes of the video all I
want you to tell me is what happens
that's a little out of the ordinary what
happens in the first two and a half
minutes that's kind of like a little
shocking and if you can tell me that
remember I am the pump I don't want to
hear any whining when you've mentioned
it so let me know let's let go watch the
bong yes I am the chronic he hits the
bong so I am the chronic has won a
bottle of DC glass cleaner so I am the
bong if he wouldn't mind sending me a
email at BC bubble man at iCloud calm
and I will send you that bottle a nun an
unopened one you will get an unopened
one so right on I am the chronic Oh
we'll go watch the video dude it's crazy
by the way that's $100,000 pipe that
he's smoking on and he'll and he
literally hits the [ __ ] bong with the
torch it's unbelievable you know you got
a wonder about some people's kids just
joking he's a friend of mine but
seriously a hundred thousand dollar bong
and you're not gonna take better care of
it holy [ __ ] some people have more money
than they know what to do with he we
didn't even you know I didn't even know
he did that in that video if you watch I
don't even react I actually watched it
later and was like wow
ship just take out like a $14,000 chip
on the pipe hundred thousand Canadian
I'll have you know so that's only about
seventy thousand can us so not quite not
quite as crazy as one might think so I
guess it's time for a wake and bake here
ya little vatican bacon well hash stuck
to the bottom of my pipe will be open
when across this border mine had holes
poked in safety seal ooh
that's weird that's okay though if they
want to open it no problem they can open
it new problem what's a website to get
the glass cleaner uh try googling it nor
cows nugget I think it's uh Amazon but
try googling dark crystal glass and you
should come up with it pretty fast
missed the giveaway hey let's actually
do a rip here what the hell too much
time
all right so this will go till about 50
and it's time for a bong rip it's time
for a little wake and bake it's time to
get ourselves inspired it's time to feed
our endocannabinoids systems uh hasn't
left a film on my quartz it could leave
a film on your quartz if you left it
there but I just clean mine up with with
the q-tips and it's been fine but I'm
definitely not forcing anyone to use a
DC glass cleaner I just myself find that
it's very convenient and useful and for
those of you that don't that's cool too
but man I've always thought another
means produce move but it's not clear
your mind Papa Papa what's your secret
thought it's well it's just my the way I
am Brandon it's just how I operate would
you give us an inspiring story about
educating people about the
endocannabinoids system well I mean it's
a pretty incredible system you know I
would look at into dr. William Courtney
dr. Bob malla me dr. David Allen and
probably a few that I'm forgetting about
it's a very important system it's it's
almost like the crank of two wheels that
turn and the two we are the two pedals
that turn are the central nervous system
in the immune system and when you get
that crank going perfect
there's homeostasis that's creative and
you get your healthy your body is
communicating as your body is unable to
communicate and remember it's
communicating because it's operating all
of your biological functions it's
responsible for all of your biological
functions it's pretty heavy its turf up
shall we
oh yeah nice and low temp there well
there's always a little trick when you
get a real nice low temper you can just
give it another snack boom that ought to
do it no need to waste it hey Alan I'm a
bubble man's younger brother actually I
really only need to kill clean the
banger the rig was cleaned yesterday
midday when you puff the kill that [ __ ]
reclaims pretty fast clean that banger
pretty nice
judy judy judy well today I was gonna
talk a little bit about bubble hash you
know I was gonna talk a little bit about
some of the tips and tricks that I have
found useful over the years one of the
things for sure is people that have
washed using the bubble bags water this
is a water extraction process for those
of you that don't know I've often
wondered why they're getting a cleaner
material out of the second batch this is
because they have not done a proper pre
cleaning so if you're using outdoor
material if you're using material where
the people have been sweeping a lot in
their rooms and don't have proper clean
I'm the more licensed production
facilities that I go into the more
professional builds and greenhouses that
I go into the more I cringe at the
thought of black pots on a concrete
basement floor with dirt all over the
place it's how I started I'll admit it
it's fine for a personal grow but I
don't think it's the best situation to
be growing for other people so these are
little errors that can happen and what
happens is is you get dust all over the
plant little little bits of dirt and
dust and so a great way to get that get
rid of that is to take that material so
you've got a pound you're gonna run a
pound at a time maybe in a twenty gallon
kit you take that pound and you put it
inside I like to use kind of like one of
those portable sinks that you clean
dishes in when you have fans kick mad
[ __ ] up especially if the shit's there
to kick up in the first place but a
portable little plastic sink that's
about this tall and I'll put the
material in at all gently massage it I
don't want to knock off any glandular
trichomes heads what I really want to do
is I want to make sure that I am
allowing the dirt in the debris to
dislodge and it will sink immediately
and I just kind of massage it very
gentle and this is one of those things
that is hard to teach it's very much
like sieving someone asked me the other
day what's the best temperature how much
moisture should I leave behind before I
see even I said well that's the tricky
part
therein lies the conundrum there is no
perfect number each and every time it's
variables that occur and they have got
to be learned to be seen you have to
learn to recognize what you're looking
at and when you have a really high
quality resin and you don't know it and
you press too much moisture out with the
pressing screen well you've just pressed
that patty now you're gonna have to
throw it in the freezer and you're going
to be forced to microplane I'm
microplane only when I'm forced to
microplane I feel that micro planing
shreds the heads it opens them up it
really it opens them up to oxygen and to
light and not necessarily the worst
thing in the world but for me I prefer
my micro
encapsulated resin glands to be micro
encapsulated not shredded so that's
that's how I like I learned a lot thanks
for helping me step up my game so yeah
in the in the pro in the regards to
these these things are hard to learn you
know how gentle do you massage because
some people might massage so and then
you realize you've knocked a bunch of
resin off now of course that resin will
be easily trapped but it'll be trapped
with all that dirt and debris ie take
the water from that container pour it
through a 25 or a 45 micron bag you'll
catch all the heads but you'll see how
much contaminant is in there for real
same thing with the moisture content of
the patty very very tricky to know I
always say the cold of the room the more
of a sweet spot you'll open up ie if
you're in a warmer environment and you
have high quality resin it'll be easier
to [ __ ] up and be forced to microplane
before you know it then it would be in a
colder environment the water content is
what's going to allow the the hash to
sieve perfectly through the sieve okay
that water content you have to know what
it is I can't there's no numbers I can
explain to people I don't know the
numbers each and every time they change
and the variables change depending on
the size of the head depending on the
percentage of wax membrane versus oil
inside the head all of these little
variables that take place create the
effects that you end up with and it
really is a feel it's much like when you
heard chimera if you were watching
hashed Church yesterday say you're like
the hash whisperer it's not like you
were just pressing that hash you were
you were listening to it you were
looking at it you were smelling it and
I'm like yeah I use all my senses when I
when I make hash that's how I feel I'm
at my best when I can can you dry out a
patty of hash successfully well Ryan no
you can't and yes you can is the quick
question now say Ryan that you are in
Arizona and you were talking about a 25
micron patty but you just say patty 25
micron heads are so much smaller that
they have less picture marbles in a bowl
large marbles in a bowl will create
larger spaces between the marbles
smaller marbles in the
will create much much smaller spaces so
less room for water to be trapped
seemingly easier for the patty to dry
higher quality larger heads very
impossible to to draw a patty like that
particularly if you're not in Arizona
but you're up in Washington State so
often people forget to mention the
variables when they ask questions or
when they answer questions or when
they're telling people and teaching
people they teach them based on the
variables in the environment that they
themselves are used to but you have to
understand I've been doing this for
almost 20 years and about five to eight
years ago I came under the understanding
that I'm talking to the world and that
everyone has different environmental
variables and now I have to take that
into account so this is very this is
where in lies the confusion when we're
trying to learn about these simple
processes so the real answer to all of
your questions is this how do I get
better how do I make the best hash
you're going to have to make some
mistakes you're going to have to stop
being afraid to [ __ ] up and jump in with
both feet
happily ready to [ __ ] up because in that
[ __ ] up you are going to learn so
much more than me or anyone else could
possibly teach you but I think it's
probably the most valuable thing that I
could say that if you listen to anything
that I said today and don't it's it
sounds like a great quote and all but
really think about it go make your
mistakes we all fear them weak nobody
wants to make their mistakes we get into
a position where we're like we want to
play it safe but when you really start
doubling down and you jump in with both
feet each and every time the mistakes
are priceless they are they are not
costly mistakes they are valuable
lessons so that's what I could say about
that awesome drew good to hear pharmacy
bro in the house bingo Lombardi sticks
with Terps Jeff Roe áall oh yeah that
was pretty good little knowledge drop I
think it only lasted about seven minutes
but yeah so those are the two parts in
my opinion getting your material clean
the processing part is
super-easy I mean putting in the ice and
putting in the material and dropping it
into a machine and turning a dial and
filtering it through bags a monkey could
do that let's be honest lifting up the
bags and scooping it out with a spoon a
small child could do that now I'm not
condoning that small children go and
make hashish I don't want to get myself
into any trouble but I'm just saying
it's so easy to scoop it out the really
only hard part is when you're going to
be drawing it or preparing it for drying
and curing if you don't do that
correctly you could make all sorts of
mistakes for instance I told people four
years on the west coast particularly in
my area that if you wanted to get the
moisture out in the west coast in the
winter or fall it would be a good idea
to use a desiccant I found food grade
cardboard to be the safest it didn't
contaminate in any way but that's
because I was sieving my powder
spreading it thin and always when people
send me pictures of cardboard with piles
of hash on and I'm like no no no no no
no minimal you have to you have to
basically squeeze stretch that out thin
it out I want it very very thin so it
almost looks like nothing's there it
can't be touching itself and if it is
touching itself it'll create larger
patties that will stick together and
then it will pull cardboard fibers off
now I photograph all my hash with a
macro photograph so when I have someone
who's done it incorrectly pull up a big
patty of hash with cardboard fibers on
it and tell me that I'm an idiot because
I'm using a desiccant that allows fibers
to be pulled into the final product
I say no you are doing it incorrectly
and if you follow the rule not the rules
but the the simple directions
instructions if you will you will do
that it will come out the right way you
know you can't change a bunch of things
and then expect it to come out the same
well here's the thing about the
parchment paper it works to a degree I
now use pizza boxes for years now where
I closed it over the parchment paper
that I have in the bottom and it's very
very nice in that sense and the part and
the cardboard surrounding it still
manages to pull out the moisture but
there are some hashes that really do
require the direct surface area of the
desiccant the parchment of course is not
a desiccant it will not really absorb
too much water it will for a little bit
but it won't it not it doesn't disperse
it and dry out the same way that
cardboard does so yeah definitely be
very careful what's going on the hash
blade sounds great but it's not how the
alternative music okay yeah you know
what pharmacy I can't even remember if I
said anything to you I was a little you
know someone said something earlier they
had said oh hi times blah blah blah blah
but I won't go on in a rant and I was
like oh thank you like in my hand I said
thank you and I thought yeah pharmacy
was ranting it's like dude you know what
I would say get in touch with him if you
want to offer help and make it better
but yeah it's hard to rant you know it
got away from him last year he's a good
dude man he means well and he's really
like he's good people
so yeah just I'm sure that he's just
trying to make it the best event that he
can and anytime you make something like
that I'm sure there's gonna be
impossible logistics to deal with have I
ever been to a volcano well yes I have
I've been to volcanoes before I guess
one was in Panama shell in Guatemala I
think there it's surrounded by volcanoes
actually I can't remember Santa Cruz and
there's like two or three of them right
there but yes I have well you know what
listen Indra and Todd constantly we're
getting into it I love them both I did I
do feel that when Indra originally came
on he spoke a lot more about just his
stories and cool things and since it's
turned into a business for him he's
really just talks about the business end
of it it's always about his product it's
always about something that he's do
that's gonna be a business and I'm
really really really careful to not try
and over promote any of us you know I
don't really promote bubble bags you
don't hear me promoting my products on
hash church because hash Church has it's
gotten a little bit bigger than us if
you would you know it's bigger than me
for sure I want it to be the most like I
don't want it to be promotions you know
I want us to promote what we believe in
and I understand that he believes in his
product so and I believe in mine but we
have to we really have to maintain an
integrity so Todd had brought on Tim as
a guest and I just thought out of
respect Todd is really much more than
someone who wants to come on and promote
the products that he's selling and he's
more along the lines of wanting church
to be the best that it can he's trying
to bring great people and trying to
create great dialogue and to me that's
really really important now don't get me
wrong I'm stoked interest God all his
businesses and I think like I'm I'm not
upset with Indra it's just like imagine
that hash search is bigger than us you
know Todd may come off as a dick but
he's not trust me he's just he's just a
unique person that has a really unique
foundation all of this that came out of
almost dying as a child
so his cannabis and he's gone to prison
for four you know five years of his life
he served in a penitentiary I I really
love Todd he's a great friend of mine so
it's okay if you have your opinion about
him for sure but just be careful at
knowing that he is really one of my
close friends and
yeah I don't you know I don't I mean
you know Sam's Salmon injury used to get
into it as well and I don't I hate the
idea of people like trying to tell
people who they should thank you know
that was one of the things that didn't
sit well with me when people would say
oh Rick Simpson turned me on to this and
it saved my life and then Andrew would
say well you need to thank me I showed
him how to do that and it was like no
you didn't show him how to do that it's
he's making something different so I
love him he will be back on hash Church
he's not kicked off by any means but I
have to let people know every once in a
while that no one owns a position on
hash Church hash Church is ever changing
the panel changes different people come
on
and if someone is not on it doesn't mean
necessarily that they're in the outs
with hashed church so I still support
Indra
I'm glad his businesses are doing good
and I want people to go and check out
his product you know I did ask him if he
wouldn't you know stay in the chat or in
coming to you know we asked are you mad
at me and I said well I don't just want
you to come in and turn it into a
commercial for your product and I will
say that I listen I watched him in the
chat room the whole time and it was
pretty much a commercial for his product
like he's I understand that I've created
the place for him to come and sell his
product but even the chat I would love
the chat to be about what we're talking
about I would love the chat to not be
people who want to come in and promote
themselves and so that's just where I'm
coming from that's where my that's my
opinion so I hope I didn't offend anyone
by saying that I sure don't I like I
love those guys they're amazing and
having Indra come on hash Church has
been a huge blessing you know but I just
I just think that people have to stop
overly advert I mean even Tony who's
like constantly doing it do you see how
much he dials back and doesn't self
promote even though it's hard for him to
talk about prana or the bubble man brand
or blue river because those are the
things that he's doing constantly and
he's innovating and he loves to share so
it's it's very different you know I have
to be careful I just I don't
want you guys to think that one day hash
Church has turned into some sellout
promotional thing where everyone's just
there
you know from self promoting so I think
it's bigger than us and I think that you
guys like it because of that and I think
that if we change that it's a tough
position pharmacy bro you know it's a
tough position for sure hey you know
what don't Bret maverick I'll say this
about Bret maverick I [ __ ] like Bret
maverick I think he's a character I
think he means well I don't think he's a
bad person I don't know enough about him
but I kind of get a kick out of him and
a few things that he said have have
really made me laugh and I there's a
good reason why that guy has a following
and anytime anyone has a following
there's gonna be a small group of people
who just hate the guy and say negative
mean nasty things and I don't really see
what the purpose is you know I don't
really see what the purpose is yeah he
is what he is I'll get him on again Chaz
the banger exactly Bret brought us the
Banger chasm so yeah you know trying to
do that trying to do that mama trying to
keep it positive and yeah just trying to
we please explain the process of
spreading the hash thin and what you
used to do so while kicking me out it's
very simple I'll put a first of all when
I say get a piece of cardboard I it's
not a small piece it has to be like an
extra-large pizza box or something now
if you had a very small amount you might
be able to do all the bags on there and
just do a with a marker as you how it is
is simple okay imagine you have a cheese
grater or not a cheese grater a parmesan
grater okay because that falls a little
closer to what we're looking for so
imagine I have it up here and I'm doing
this if I don't move the grater it all
falls in a pile on top of my pasta but
if I move it around the pasta I can put
a thin layer as thin as I want or as
thick as I want evenly spread over the
surface area of what I want covered so
yes I have videos where I'm doing this
and you can see it it's easier to see in
person but we're talking about it we're
here why not answer the question so I
gently will push now I'm using a cold
spoon and I'm using small amounts of
bubble in a cold
environment if I'm in a warmer
environment I'll use even smaller
amounts of bubble keeping the other ones
cold for to just keep that structure of
how it wants to fluff and fall apart if
you allow it to self press and gravity
to hold upon it and more moisture to
remove you'll be forced to freeze it in
microplane which is going to bust up all
the heads so spreading it thin is easy
from my perspective you just great
not great sorry push with the spoon
gently through the sieve and it'll fall
like little droplets now just spread it
thin there's nothing no tool you can use
because it's wet bubble if you try to
use anything to eat to move that stuff
around now that it's fallen it'll be a
nightmare it has to fall properly and
that's how it has to get there everybody
understands past that just keep them in
about the meds sharing the process and
helping people get quality if the leaves
them to your products great that's what
I say big squirrel nuts that's exactly
big squirrel nuts basically nailed it
right there look I'm not opposed to me
or my friends selling a product that
people are stoked about having it's why
I talk about the cleaner it's why I talk
about little things that I like I don't
like a ton of things in the industry I I
have a fairly you know most of the
things in the industry I'm kind of like
that's not something I will have a use
for but when I find something I have a
use for I'm extremely excited to show it
to people and I don't get paid by these
companies they don't give me shares and
their companies they don't give me
anything so yeah well sometimes they'll
give me products and now I'm just giving
all those away too so I'll keep it like
they don't give me anything
although friends still do give me little
gifts that I appreciate and am very
thankful for Aloha rich Griggs from
Hawaii I hope you're having a beautiful
wonderful day in paradise really I mean
[ __ ] people go there travel from across
the world just to visit for a week and
you get to live there bro so boom that's
awesome yeah there you go what's with
these thermal bangers well a banger
within a banger right it's just the way
you'll see all sorts of different
innovations with the way when we find
out the importance first of all terpenes
are important we finally learned
so much about that that now that we
understand how important they are and
what they're doing to the cannabinoids
that obviously how they are inhaled how
they are evaporated what surface area
and what temperature they are evaporated
at we'll have the facts on how you feel
like how they feel in your body it's a
fact
you hit a low temp banger it's tasty
it's beautiful it will not rock you the
same as a much hotter rip and also off
of different surface areas there are
subtle differences and I find that
there's a quality of preservation that
occur in surfaces that allow heat to
dissipate evenly if you will and hold
heat oh you know in but not for too long
you want it to dissipate evenly titanium
holds it for too long no bueno I'll hit
it if I have to but yes he means a
higher well no no no no no he's not he's
just meaning that of the glandular
trichomes heads you know the there's a
high percentage of terpenes there's
higher percentages of terpenes what's
the difference between a turf and a
flavonoid well I would say Google would
definitely be your friend there probably
a Wikipedia on each one would define to
you exactly what terpenes and terpenoids
what class of isoprenes those are and
then you could go into flavonoids I have
less experience with flavonoids I
haven't researched it as much and much
like skunkman Sam because they are non
active when smoked or inhaled there's
never really been a reason to try and
find out what was going on there Oh
where's the troll troll troll tell me
where the troll is I love getting rid of
trolls we can get rid of Miranda alright
Miranda where
are you Miranda I can't even seem around
are you serious oh there she is oh right
she wants to have sex with us all right
there we go sorry sorry we're all good
here we're just puffing bowls no need
for is the troll lunch ah it's a great
cartoon I've watched it with my
three-year-old son what's his name now
Guillermo Guillermo del Toro a troll
hunter I think it's a cartoon it's heavy
duty man serious all right let's have
one more rip and we're gonna say goodbye
yes we are one more little dab
let's pop another shall we ACO oh sorry
dude which I was in the middle of having
sex with Miranda and we messed it all up
and some people must be bored out there
I mean imagine I guess you're just
looking for things though - I kind of
remember back in the day when I was on
the computer just skyping strangers like
hey I was so excited to get Skype I
would just go through the Skype
directory and I would just hit people up
and I I heard some pretty incredible
conversation and then it turned into
every single time someone hit me up it
was ASL and I just turned it off and
stopped with that that must have been
like 15 years ago I don't even know but
pretty funny hey Sal I was like oh my
god yeah I'm a full [ __ ] blocker it's
cuz I've been with my wife for 29 years
yes we shall puff one
I am the gas pump let's do this
eight sex language or location yeah
location age sex location stupid
it's basically what trolls that are
trolling for like desperate people
usually dudes fishing at best I just
avoided it at all coughs never looked on
the internet for that it was more
interested in finding educational
information and cannabis wow look at all
the cannabis information we put on the
computer over the course of the last 20
years it's really been massively
affecting the populace people are
learning about this for sure don't get
me wrong a ton of people learn about it
from Sanjay Gupta and other very very
mainstream straight people that mention
it just in a little blurb or maybe even
do a whole show on it but those people
then go on to the Internet and they
start doing research and that's where
our information comes in handy oh yeah
damn cannon brah why were you expecting
that you might be on the wrong on the
wrong chap
well the Cuevas are great obviously
qwave bangers are like that look top DC
makes them pretty damn decent bangers -
oh these are from method sevens the
glasses that I wear all the time it's a
great logo it says don't grow blind
maybe I'll hit these guys up and see if
they want to give away a few shirts or
maybe even a pair of method sevens I
think they were they're really generous
they always have been
yeah the claves are nice all right so
where do the DC's don't get me wrong I
mean I'm using one no I know but you
know what it's they might like it it's
kind of like it might be nice for method
7 to get the exposure as well so I'm
kind of like thinking they've been so
generous to me I don't feel like I'm
going out of my way as much as maybe
giving them an opportunity where if they
want to donate some shirts or whatever
we would gladly give them away on the
show there you go yes plenty people
what's the CN n I think that's how a lot
of people got mainstreamed information
on cannabis was when Sanjay Gupta
admitted that he was wrong and
apologized and then went on this whole I
was pretty incredible not sure how that
came to be but very very cool that it
happened and yeah yeah I was smoking
some Justin Trudeau Kush from the
glacial melts good old glacial melts
guys and then I was puffing a little of
the of the bubble hash Congo apologies
for my nails I went camping and after
two three showers they're still dirty
I'm all like dirty nail guy what when
sweet I'm almost ready for another puff
but I think I'm gonna call it a day it's
a 35-minute er that was a good drop we
did a lot of talking we talked about
some good stuff so I don't know how much
oil I took I don't weigh my oil it was
just a bunch a lot enough to get
everyone high like 50 times a day
but they didn't want to all of them so
it was much easier all right yes Kel oh
thank you for the sesh hope everyone has
gotten their packages and I guess I'm
going to be giving away the next batch
hopefully if you send me your email
you'll bottle will go out as well and
I'm if I'm getting backed up I feel bad
but one guy wrote me and said he didn't
want the gift he just wanted me to
answer all his questions and he never
gave me an address but it still feels
like I'm one short hopefully not but I'm
gonna mail them all out today and we'll
see if you're one of those people that
one and I didn't send you something
definitely don't feel bad to hit me up I
don't want to be the kind of guy that
says I'm gonna give you something and
then totally spaced on it so have a
great day everyone made the full mount
bless your bowl sooner than later peace