we did it we did it everyone I'm always
so nervous I'm not gonna lie it's tough
making this [ __ ] work
welcome everybody to bubble man's world
and the oh the wake-and-bake
episode 84 hope we're all doing well
today got a few little things from the
karma cup that I'm gonna be giving away
a pin and some Terp proof and a little
karma Cup silicon pad not sure how I'm
gonna go about giving that away but I am
gonna be giving it away and we'll see it
happening in the near future hopefully
we're going live here make sure
everything is on the up and up oh yeah
yeah that looks good that looks good
kind of uh all right here we go I'll sit
over a little bit over here I hope
everyone's having a great effing day
I've got a few dabs here gonna do a
little turf dips wanted to announce
right away to the Canadians in the room
that blue river Canada has another
discount on it got turned off for June
yes I did shave thanks for noticing and
the new discount is all lower case
letters blue river one word be lue RI ve
R 2017 and the Blue River 2017 code is
gonna get you 30% off your order so
about 50 bucks off each vial definitely
worth wild got my karma cup shirt on
today figured I'd wear one it's actually
pretty comfortable and I've got people
dab in on the back so you gotta love
that oh I would recommend the piece for
any type of light that you have they
have special LED ones they have special
MHS ones metal halides they have HPS
ones that are right here they have ones
for the Sun and this company is called
method seven and their logo their motto
if you will is don't grow blind and I
love that motto so I guess we're gonna
do a Terp dip here start off this day
parappa got a little sweet skunk got a
little Congo oh yeah this ship is like
glass sometimes you almost have to heat
up the the dabber to be able to get a
hit like this proper I'm gonna have to
melt it so I can get the turf dip there
we go
that'll do it I think we're gonna go in
for some Colville
our diesel oh yeah she was loving loving
the blue drew the green dragon oh gee
bran she was loving and her name is
Sarah Sarah Sunday and we are gonna talk
a little bit about the karma Cup today I
talked to her the other day and she
asked if I could you know maybe share a
little bit of pertinent information I am
going to be a celebrity judge for
solvent list for the hashish and so if
you want to have me testing your hash
smoking your hash you're going to want
to get in touch with the Karma Cup calm
and you're gonna want to do it before
July 28th because at July 28th is the
cutoff date that you need to have the
product in Sarah's hand so that's pretty
important July 28th and yeah she's got
all sorts of categories she's got
[ __ ] pen categories and solvent list
categories and solvent categories but
categories so much so much well Kayne I
think wholesale it's worth about fifty
thousand plus US dollars I think retail
considering they did a piece with
mothership that was very similar that
retailed for a hundred and twenty five
thousand US dollars I think that cups
worth at least a hundred thousand US
dollars so it is a little bit insane to
think that I was balancing it in the
palm of my hand 30 stories above the
ground when I turned around and the
owner of the pipe was inside the
apartment he was clutching the Pelican
case and clenching his teeth and he just
he was like dude I have never been so
nervous I'm like hey man you know I'm
good for it I'm not gonna break your
glass and if I did I'd pay for it
I mean don't [ __ ] around with people's
glass if you can't pay for it you know
what I'm saying
cuz geez Louise that's uh yeah that's
it's well it's not quite a Lambo a Lambo
here is about 300 plus K depending most
people are buying the Gallardo z-- and
the the upper levels of Lambos at least
here in Vancouver I think for 150 or 125
you might get like a nice Audie or a
decent not a not a great Mercedes but a
decent one crazy how much people pay up
for [ __ ] cars crazy for how much
people are paying for [ __ ] pipes but
hey
you've got the money you've got the
ability don't get down on people who are
doing that [ __ ] I personally would love
to see people who were buying $125,000
pipes also take care of people in their
life I hope that they're helping feed
people and helping clothe and house
people but hey to each their own man
we're all allowed to buy the things that
we want I just sometimes think that
there should be a humility involved that
when you get yourself something on that
level that you might want to be taking
care of some of the rest of the world
you got a pay-to-play there DB Cooper
let's do this up shall we
well that was a cheap Mercedes for 6k Oh
is it only 120 km Canada that surprises
me that really surprises me because we
have a local club here and you can't get
into it without a $250,000 car and
there's quite a few Lambos in there so
I'm gonna go out on a bait a limb and
say you guys are talking bass models and
these kids that are buying these Lambos
and these Ferraris and these Bugattis
they're they're paying high dollars they
like they're not paying 125,000 dollars
for a Lambo I can promise you just
saying I'm not too sure I don't go to
the dispensaries too often I think
they're kind of on par I think be a
butane oil sells a little bit there you
go an f-150 there you go and that's a
good deal I know a guy that just paid 75
grand for one yeah you're talking 1995
okay there you go that's a little bit
more accurate because there's no way
people are getting Lambos for 150 grand
not here
[Music]
alright let's clean this minor Chaz out
sometimes I'd like to hit it a little
warmer in the morning that wasn't too
warm the Terp dip listen when you hit it
with the Terps the taste is so [ __ ]
OnPoint it's ridiculous whoo and there
burned my fingers I put so much in there
sometimes when it comes out it steams
hot burn your [ __ ] if you do that we'll
see what happens here
I'll get this Chaz off I always do
sometimes I got to go in a little harder
especially if I hit it a tiny little bit
warmer than usual I'll go in with my
little dabber and I'll just sort of
remove the majority of you know the part
that's just not coming off nice and then
I'll just heat it up a little bit more
and go in with the DC glass cleaner now
remember I've given this tip a few times
even though you might want to try not to
move the q-tip around too much let it
just sit on the Chazz and what it'll do
is if you just let it sit there it'll
pick it up even easier than it would if
you know you try to do this intuitive
sort of scrapey scrapey scrapey thing I
mean obviously at one point you're gonna
have to scrape a little bit but for the
most part you shouldn't have to do too
much oh yeah getting her off feels good
feels good to clean the banger feels
good to clean the banger a little bit
harder on this one and then last but
nonetheless I do believe it's ready for
another rip that DC glass cleaner is
made from this sort of oil not-not-not
Ranjha karanji karanji oil process
coconut extract process kelp extract and
process extract of sugarcane for those
of you that want to ask the question in
the future you can go to DC glass
cleaners website I don't know it but if
you punch it into Google just the same
way you would ask a person where what is
DC glass cleaner made of or where can i
buy it and whatnot Google will give you
the proper answer each and every time
q-tips saving lives saving DC glass
quarts anyway wanted to give a shout out
to my bro head stache whose local here
in Vancouver makes these medicated
lollipops these are artisan lollipops
and this one's like got some root bur
it's the root bur and it is a hundred
milligrams not too bad not too bad
probably get into that a little bit
later
random lollipop just had it sitting on
here on the desk I went and bought all
this stash recently from the heavenly
days guys and the gentleman who brokers
for them he has his own company and he
sells these so how about that yeah those
fly hats you know what I'll do I'll get
in touch with Adam and I'll see if he
can't send me a couple of these hats for
giveaway I have been a loyal wearer of
this
hats since well since the day he sent me
the two so big squirrel nuts don't [ __ ]
with me I'm just joking dude I'm so
funny like it's like I I tried I
apologize if I'm reactive sometimes and
I don't mean to come across I'm intense
I don't know if you guys have noticed
this yet but I am a fairly intense
person if you spend any amount of time
with me sure we could get bubbled up and
I'd be pretty relaxed and pretty baked
but after a couple hours you'd be like
this [ __ ] is intense and I'm not
talking about intense camping I'm
talking about like intense energy
flowing outward off of me in all
directions at all times people are kind
of enamored with it at first but it's
sort of gets annoying after a while
I'm just being honest tell us a new joke
no joke I think I told the horrible
horrible horrible rabbi joke already did
I tell the rabbi
and the priest joke I must have it's
like one of the only jokes I know it's a
terrible joke it's definitely not a good
joke but I'll say it anyway it's
derogatory it insults Jews it insults
Christians and I'm friends with
Christians and Jews and I have nothing
against either of them but I will tell
the joke the joke goes like this a rabbi
and a priest are walking down the street
they walk by a park and see some boys
playing soccer the priest says hey let's
go [ __ ] those little boys and the rabbi
says out of what is that funny all my
[ __ ] Christian friends and Jewish
friends are gonna be like what's up dude
that was really [ __ ] mean I didn't
what the [ __ ] I don't believe it it's
funny it's a joke but it certainly
doesn't have any malicious intent and
for all of my Hebrew brethren and
sistren apologies for my Christian
brethren and cisterns apologies I know
it's just a few bad apples in the bunch
creating stereotypes but hey it is what
it is if it made you laugh then [ __ ]
a now if you laughed because it was
funny good on you if you laugh because
you are a hateful mean vengeful person
who dis
like certain groups of people and shame
on you so there it is you know I'm kind
of like with Dave Chappelle on this
Chappelle said years ago look bro I will
say anything for a laugh you know and I
and orge Carlin has a couple of things
that are just really intense his comedy
talking about certain things that can be
funny that at the time and even in this
time still to this day people like
there's nothing funny about that a
comedian can make something funny about
anything as long as you take the hate
the anger the derogatory the you know
and make it a positive sort of like
perspective where you're looking at it
and kind of like hahaha yeah absolutely
George Carlin one of my favorites one of
my favorite well I don't even hate
everybody I think I love everybody the
same it's good there's no reason not to
any any tips for starting a terpene
business I mean dude honestly just do
what everyone does copy blue river find
the same containers find the same
stickers find the same lids create a web
page but figure out a method to extract
your terpenes with I mean it's it's a
whole and then try to innovate you know
once you've kind of copied the base I'm
not even being joking here so what
everyone does anyway
and once you've got the base then your
responsibility is to be like okay I
totally like [ __ ] copied everything
about these these guys companies what
can I do to make it something different
for the customer because in the end
that's all that competition is really
about it's about making the product
better for the end user and it doesn't
matter if I don't like that you want to
start a company or vice versa
the end user is the person who's gonna
benefit and if you do a great job and
you copy blue river but then you come up
with your own method and you innovate
and you create something different well
you're gonna you're gonna you're gonna
be the next step in the ladder and trust
me it will be someone who comes along
and kind of copies the base cuz listen
there's a half a dozen companies and
they've all pretty much done the exact
same thing they've copied Blue River
whether they want to say it or not it's
what they've done there were they
weren't even thinking about it before we
started having this
they heard the conversation they watched
what started happening and then they
then they jumped in it's not I don't
know why we [ __ ] on people so much for
that I mean do you think that [ __ ]
Eminem just made up all like he was
inspired by rap he was inspired so then
he had to go and show his stuff and this
is how it is we all we all kind of are
inspired by the Giants whose shoulders
we get to stand on and those are the
people that we're going to you know copy
a little bit I don't know why we're so
afraid to say it when it's like if
you're inspired by someone imitate
emulate innovate there you go Tyler
however you want to say then fancy
beautiful words that's a very nice way
to say it it's like you're basically
gonna fake it till you make it you're
gonna copy it you're gonna innovate it
you're gonna change it bubble bags were
the exact same thing and I took mad
[ __ ] slack for a decade plus over
something that I really shouldn't have
because let's be honest
bubble bags are [ __ ] awesome they
blow isolator bags right under the water
and they were for North America when a
European woman who was promoting this
process was not doing any promotions in
North America
I came to up in North America and I
promoted this when it was very illegal
and shared it and showed it and that's
what bubble bags did they weren't the
first but they have been the best and so
it shows you that the first isn't always
the best and so I'm not even being like
joking at all when I say copy I'm really
not I'd say James get in touch with
Peter there's no one that knows more
about it in my circle you can reach him
at Peter at soil balance procom you can
also google soil balance pro just in
case to make sure that's the right email
and it should be good I didn't watch the
M&amp;M thing that was trending recently
about the story of how much Dre put
himself out there and how many people I
guess what Dre was saying was like
racist people in his life that he didn't
even know where that racist you know
talkin about em because he was white and
had blue eyes who gives a [ __ ] what
color you are if you can do the job then
I could care less if you're purple you
got the job you know
that's it did you miss everyone's missed
everything
every Wow I mean that's been a lot of
work too but back in the day isolator
bags were known better I've done a lot
of work sharing this information and if
you guys haven't noticed I try to share
it in a very like I don't want to
shamelessly plug my company if that's if
that makes sense I don't want to
shamelessly promote my company over and
over and over again you very rarely see
my logo or me wearing one of my own
shirts or my own hat for that matter I
try to like stay away from that
shameless plugging but I figured my way
that I could market my product is a
coming out and having conversations with
you guys sharing bowls with you guys
answering your questions and always
being there to support and give tips and
answer in regards to the curing and the
processing and the preparing and all
these things I've been doing it for
almost twenty years so I don't think I'm
gonna stop anytime I'm actually getting
pretty excited I'm planning my trip for
Jamaica I'm gonna be flying there in the
next like week we've got a whole bunch
of cool [ __ ] happening in Jamaica right
now and it just kind of blew up with
these products that we've had registered
with the Ministry of Health and these
permits now that we have to grow and
process and cultivate which is growing
actually research and developments
produce products basically and and and
sell those products so we're pretty
[ __ ] excited we're gonna be getting
lots of videos we're gonna be rolling in
Tony and I are rolling in a week after
Ernie and Amy from the United cannabis
who are going to be going in and doing a
little doctor training going to a
conference in Kingston Tony and I are
gonna be heading to a conference in
Montego Bay so that'll be kind of
different we're gonna fly into Kingston
but eventually end up in mo Bay quick
trip hopefully I'll have a couple of
days in Toronto afterwards some of my
friends want me to come there and teach
them how to make water hash
and well if I can't facilitate helping
my friends make water hash then I'm
failing miserably so well potency you
know we used to be really impressed with
THC like if you're up in the 70 Plus THC
and the oils guys would come in and say
we have 80 plus percent THC slowly but
surely we learned about the importance
of the modulating effect or the
entourage or the ensemble effect of
terpenes and how it creates more of the
Spacey full kind of like what I would
call high vs THC and cannabinoids which
I would call stoned very one-dimensional
II just kind of like this the terpenes
they're much more of an ensemble and
that just changes the game completely so
we're more impressed with 40 50 maybe 60
percent THC and in that a large
percentage of terpene profile I don't
like to micro plane bubble too much but
if I do
I absolutely freeze abso 100% lutely oh
yeah it's 20 it's Blue River 2017 is the
new Canadian discount code please share
that with everyone you guys know I'll
put it up on my blue river accounts all
lowercase B lue RI ve are two zero one
seven blue river 2017 that is the code
that's gonna get you 30% off your order
that's a lot it's 100 bucks off a
jamaican mil that's 50 bucks off each
Californian vial it's a good deal people
were loving it I sold a schwack last
month when I did that and yeah blue
river 2017 thank you DK trades you have
to live in Canada that's true from my
company you have to live in Canada
karmak up is the next cannabis culture
event in this that is true that is true
that is true have I ever sent you
anything well water have you ever won
anything on my channel are you meeting
up with your reggae bredrin when in
Jamaica ah yeah they're like our family
so we will absolutely be meeting up with
our reggae bredrin when we're in Jamaica
what do you think of it any other way it
would be like them coming here and not
calling me up I'd be tripped out thanks
Trey all right well well well
alright well water today you won this
this is your package I got the are you
elite pin from the karma cup I got the
PTFE sheet that you can put your rosin
on or squish rosin and tur proof I guess
and then you get this little uh this
little silicone daba daba Doo de lo here
you get your look your oil on here and
it's kind of nice anyway send me an
address send me an address now if you
don't mind I like to kind of go to the
post office how do you guys aren't
sending me the addresses right away I'm
not pitching but I'm saying can you
please send it to me before the show is
over bc bubbleman at icloud.com
and yes there is a new vape pen coming
up for bubbleman and so yeah if you send
that right away I'll get this off I have
the last couple of pins I did just send
a big there was like seven people
including melty heads who I hadn't sent
the large PTF oil slick tube to all of
that stuff's been sent just the other
day cost me $115 to send like I had like
eight or nine things saved up vape pen
we had designed by Gary from Omicron we
didn't want to pump out disposable pens
I don't like the California has this
huge marketplace for distillate mixed
with terpenes gold drop and blue river
are crushing it I don't do distillate
but we figured out a way to do rosin and
create a distillate like product without
the use of chemical solvents and adding
the terpenes back so what I wanted was a
pen I could put my name on you know a
pen that I could feel good about that
people weren't throwing away each time
they smoked a half gram and so we had
Gary design as a pen he also designed
the Hercules which is a beefcake like
last you forever type [ __ ] cartridge we
had him design our cartridge so it's
renewable it's not disposable and we've
got applicators that you can buy the
product a little cheaper afterwards and
you'll be able to fill your own pen
cartridge so it's going to be the
Trinity cartridge the bubbleman Trinity
cartridge and yeah from Omicron and blue
river is gonna have a little sticker on
there they will be available in the US
in fact they're going to be filled
refillable and they'll be sold through
I'm sure
Harborside and BPG and maybe you know la
cush or the real green dragon i know
they've got some shops haven't figured
out exactly who's gonna carry it yet
once we have five or ten thousand in
hand all filled up I'm sure someone will
be very excited I'll take a bone room in
fact I will puff the Cline kind of small
the client is compared to the egg it's
quite a difference isn't it this one is
about seven point seven inches and this
one's just under nine or just at nine
all right we got it we got a little dab
there perfect perfect
got a big dab now yeah we got a big one
here we go yeah we're having a nice time
here we're doing it up soon we're gonna
be doing waken bakes in Toronto we're
gonna be doing waken bakes in Jamaica
that's the best part about going to
Jamaica I don't stop my shows I maintain
and continue consistently just remember
it's gonna be three hours later once I
get over there so you won't be seeing me
at 9:00 or 10:00 but it'll be more along
the 12 to 1 p.m.
time line karmak up is September 9th and
10th and you can go check them out at
www.thekingofrandom.com
[Music]
that was a stinger
yeah please come to the karma cup if you
think you have something worthy of entry
enter whether it's a solvent or a non
solvent I'd prefer to hit your non
solvent as I am a celebrity judge and I
would love to try your guys's hash I've
asked the West Coast boys to enter and
the Glacial melts boys and I've asked
Dee for 20k and a few other friends I
know the great Gardner enters all these
things so there should be some nice hash
to try and to taste but if you guys are
out there in the world and you want to
[ __ ] see how you stand amongst these
guys dude why not what a great way to
become the next Conor McGregor come
knock it out of the park I'm not sure if
I'm planning on coming to Washington
anytime soon I'm sure he'll be there he
enters all these events he's you know
he's one of those guys that loves to
enter and take place in the competition
I'm gonna have to pour a little bit in
here this time we chaste good
oh yeah that's so good it pulls it off
and puts it in the middle in a way that
I can't even explain it is awesome so
what are we gonna talk about here guys
you talk about hash making we talk about
Karma Cup we talk about Jamaica a lot of
[ __ ] going on right now what are we
gonna talk about well listen don't be
nervous at all like off a lot because I
take rips that would crush your soul
there Terp rich okay it's not about the
size of the RIP it's how much terpene
there are present in the RIP I'm not
even joking like it's Eickhoff Verret
not a lot to be honest and keep in mind
one of the
things that I'm doing that maybe a lot
of people aren't doing is sitting and
talking and using my vocal cords and
vibrating my vocal cords without the use
of water or taking sips
I'm also puffing extremely strong
concentrates with terpenes added to them
most people's mouths would dry up and
their heads would shrink and they'd just
be here not talking in the way that I'm
able to actually articulate my
conversation I don't have a cold right
now I very rarely get colds and my
throat feels pretty good other than the
fact that I took you know probably ten
rips before I went live and then a
couple of no I've got a little bit of
water in there even these pipes even oh
don't worry Raymond dude we're still
[ __ ] doing this [ __ ] we're out we're
not leaving anytime soon we're just
getting into it while we could talk
about the reason why people complain
about expensive art when you don't have
that kind of money it's hard to imagine
people do that not just with art but any
type of valuable thing that someone
chooses to have that actually has the
means to get it I think it's somewhat
petty I would never go on a plane this
is the analogy I use often I would never
go on a plane and complain if I'm in
coach and there are people in
first-class I'm happy for them you know
I'm like right on like that sweet
first-class go I don't sit there going
why is first-class tickets so expensive
it's ridiculous why should they get to
set up there when we have to sit back
it's like oh my god dude listen just
take your place whatever wherever you
fit whatever you're you know wherever
you can afford and don't be too upset
about it you know sure there are
experiences where it might come in handy
to be upset that you know monetary
situations keep us out of certain areas
but really who [ __ ] cares
people are buying forty thousand dollar
rigs $50,000 rigs hundred thousand
dollar rigs of course they are crunk
sell for mad dough 100k plus to each
their own chilling like a villain
exactly you know someone wants to spend
400 K on a [ __ ] Lambo so be it for
them and someone wants to give away a
little 5 or $10 thing every day on their
wake-and-bake show well good for them to
do what you want don't be too upset
about other people I don't think I'm
very I don't know when someone asks me
if I'm
I think it comes with being humble it's
weird people like all your elite dude
your elite and I'm like I don't know man
I got a whole bunch of aspects of my
life baby I'm elite in the ability to
isolate glandular trichomes heads but
there are whole other parts of life that
that maybe I'm not so elite whatsoever
so I'm working on those parts and always
trying to maintain you know the the hash
knowledge as well but how you doing Rob
more I'm still waiting for those
cannabis cartoons of hashed Church you
know not necessarily funny joke ones but
like actual our voices and our faces put
in too much the way they've been doing
I've seen this guy do with the Joe Rogan
videos have Joey Diaz or Joe Rogan and
they're just sitting around the table
it's their real voices it's kind of cool
I think if some certain little knowledge
bombs little 30-second knowledge bombs
minute-long knowledge bombs I think it
would be a cool thing to animate and I
did see your one the other day don't
feel weird brother
we support Todd yeah well I don't know
30 minutes I think it did it 10 o'clock
I'm gonna have to have a call here I
actually do have a call so you sent me
that email bro well water and I will get
you these three little things off three
little things yeah they're all right
here
I put the pipe over here and I guess in
the meantime we will see all of you guys
tomorrow on Friday it's Friday tomorrow
we got a couple more wake-and-bake
episodes before we have a hash Church
it's gonna be a [ __ ] stellar hash
Church I can promise you it'll be a hash
Church unlike any hash Church you have
ever seen so please help promote it let
people know that it's going to be one
worth catching and I'm real excited it's
it's got the the makings of being maybe
one of the best hash churches ever and I
don't say that lightly and yeah may the
full Mel bless you your bowls
sooner than later peace out everybody