all right we did it we made it hey
what's up everyone welcome to the
wake-and-bake episode 79 and welcome to
bubble man's world you know these apps
they're kind of funny it's not like
going on live and doing it through
Google Chat it is definitely giving me a
hard time each and every time I do this
I'm live but no one is in the room oops
all right hey there we go there's some
peeps I'll I guess I got to go into my
channel here go into my live events and
well try to delete the one that I
already I think I started three this
morning so let me go into live streaming
and see how many they are there and read
on everybody you found me good to see
you everybody
alright well there we go wakey Bakey
looked like a funny funny face on that
particular photo hope everyone's doing
well and yes have a wonderful Challis
weekend I believe chalice is this
weekend down in San Bernardino always a
big event I've never been myself would
be cool to be able to get down there one
time although I hear it's very hot down
there at this time of year 35 to 40
degrees Celsius which is who in the
hundred plus degrees might be a little
bit hot for me but yeah I'm glad it
worked out the kind buds as well I just
wanted to have a couple of words with
you guys have a couple of puffs with you
guys and then call it a day of course
yesterday I went over to the Sunshine
Coast and met with the team Japanese
guys Yoshi and June and O dice dico dico
can't remember the third guys name and
then John Green was there and dosa was
there and of course I interviewed glass
art was there got some really great
photos got a little bit of video of
those guys making their magic I'm gonna
try and go back in about a week when
they finish up doses super chill dude
dosa we met like we didn't eat like
we've known each other for 10 years we
weren't even introduced he was just like
hey dude what's up I was like hey bro
what's up so it was it was kind of the
weirdness of Instagram
and social media where you just feel
like you know someone meeting dosa truly
was like meeting a friend that you've
known for years it wasn't you know we it
was I don't think I've ever met anyone
like that in fact that it was just so
hey what's up dude what's up not like oh
hey this is dosa dosa this is bubble man
we just knew so very cool on that on
that angle super nice guy great
glassblower gave me I wish I had it on
me actually I left it upstairs gave me a
really beautiful little Marini I
photographed some of them and put it up
on the post yesterday on Facebook let us
wake the bake I think that's a good idea
oh why wasn't it working for me just a
moment ago grandma call him well why not
it why not go through this a third time
what happens is I guess when you run
your computer and you do live chats
through the computer through Google
right it's through Google Chat and then
it forces itself through YouTube when
you do it on the phone it actually works
a little bit differently and so the
phone is a little bit jacked if you will
and so when I go to go live okay often
it'll just it'll go it'll like three two
one and then my phone goes black now
when this happens oh don't worry about
it dude it's you missed out and I want
you to hear what the answer so and it's
not your bad at all don't worry about it
so when that happens I have to start it
over well what's been happening is a
glitch lately that when I started over
and I go to resume the chat its vertical
and I'm OCD I can't have a wake-and-bake
video where it's where it's like that so
what I have to do is I have to stop that
one go in and restart a whole new one
and sometimes I have to do two three
four per per day per morning and so
usually it's easier if I go back and I
find the ones that were already there
and delete those ones but just making it
easier for people to find the actual
chat that we're in because if I start
three or four sometimes people are in
one that aren't that are not actually
moving so that is the answer the answer
is is that the there's a bit of a glitch
and that's because there
streaming and encoders that are needed
when you go through google it does
everything for you but when you go
through your phone
I guess it's using just the YouTube app
and the encoder for the YouTube app is a
little bit glitchy you know what I tried
putting a little tussin on it rubbing a
little tussin on my phone there but you
know so far it hasn't worked might have
to get that super tussin we'll see what
happens all the this the the crystal
should have been tied to taped to the
Hat yeah I would have taped it like
right here so not sure a few people said
they didn't get their crystal that's
weird I want everyone to get their
crystal I also want to have a big bong
rips oh oh this bomb this is a nate
dizzle swiss perc love me a swiss perc
let's do it up
yeah I met in the tussin I don't know
this bong could almost be 10 years old I
don't it's very likely actually I'm
hitting sipped maybe that's why the ribs
look bigger I did gram I did see the
weird guy rollin drip in my videos I
sent a little thing in today saying hey
these are my videos doing good human
nature doing good what temperature am i
hitting at I am hitting at 590 this one
was Darren's if the one that I just hit
the next one I hit is going to be Sun
rises a little bit of a different color
on the two Darren's is a little bit
darker quite a bit darker actually so
awesome plans for today well I have a
good call that I have to make in regards
to Jamaica and we get to find out what's
going on there and get an update for
everyone and then I'm also going to try
and edit the video that I filmed
yesterday I got a hope that I filmed all
the parts and get to fit it in I don't
know if it's gonna be a 15-minute video
or a 30-minute video I did film a lot
but I didn't really interview the the
glassblowers them being Japanese and not
speaking the best of English Yoshi I
probably could have done an interview
with but I didn't want to bother them
and they were in crush mode and I didn't
want to pull them out I felt actually
bad just standing behind them trying to
film because the work that they're doing
is so intricate in so detailed that the
last thing I want to do is be
responsible for causing any
sets in the in the process so I filmed
all three of the Japanese glass blowers
I filmed dosa I interviewed John Green
and I guess I took a couple of puffs out
of the Kevin nail so that video will go
up I'm hoping today yeah exactly Tyler
that's kind of what I was hoping for I
mean of course we'd love to see them all
yeah Ron said yes to the greenhouse
project we're just in the middle of
waiting to hear from the greenhouse
companies yeah Japanese glass for the
wind these guys are unbelievable
watching them do their thing was really
impressive I look forward to going back
in the next five days when they're
finishing they're making a cup and you
know it's gonna be the entire two weeks
that they're at the house that this is
gonna happen yesterday they crushed a
dual sided pendant just absolutely
unbelievable in how much detail these
guys are able to put into their glass
and the process of watching them do it
absolutely blew me blew my mind you know
there was a big cannabis culture in
Japan John was telling me who lives
there and helps facilitate the Japanese
glass blowers here in Canada bring them
here he speaks Japanese and he can sort
of you know get them what they need and
keep them comfortable he says that there
is he says that they were selling glass
and they're selling one-hitters and
there's head shops and this that the
other thing at the same time he says the
cops can stop you anytime they want and
they can search you it's very harsh the
the government is definitely against JA
herbs that are not using cannabis
medically to promote you know the
endocannabinoids system
herb is illegal and expensive like maybe
30 40 dollars a gram and so yeah he was
saying the other days I call I miss my
wakin bakes cuz he's just loves waking
up and getting high and he can't do that
in Japan so yeah of course Ron said yes
we're working it out there's logistics
we got to find a place you know we got
to get rid of Ron's house we got to get
him moved over here we got to find Ron a
new house we got to buy a green house we
got to build a green house we got a it's
gonna take us some time give us a couple
of months to get this project going
because let's be honest it's just one of
it is not the main project yeah I bet
Chuck Liddell said the same thing most
anyone that's traveled to Japan will say
the same thing beautiful country and
beautiful people and culture and love
the food and but the anti herb sentiment
when I got my record my lawyer basically
told me the two countries you shouldn't
go to our America and oh glad you
received the bubble bags illegal
cannabis Farmers of Canada and Japan he
said those two places will be your
biggest problems with the felony record
of cannabis possession so best to just
avoid those two countries which sucks
you know I don't want to avoid any no he
does not want to live in the Cootes he
lives in the coots and he's leaving the
coots but thank you I don't think so you
know he's gonna figure out his own thing
it's probably gonna be personal what he
figures out so I might not be sharing
exactly what he's done with his house
but he's gonna figure something out with
it and you know get it taken care of
sell it I don't know but he's gonna get
up here we're gonna find him another
house and then we're gonna start this
greenhouse project so I pray that it
starts sooner than later I would have
loved to have been starting it in you
know March to get it all going by April
May but instead it'll be the way it is
we'll see what happens
exactly Jan I live in one of the most
beautiful places I've ever seen as well
and I've traveled all over the world - I
don't know 25 or 26 countries not that
that's that many considering there's 218
or 220 oh I won't be telling you exactly
where Ron lives but you're welcome to
keep guessing oh that's okay stoner
Smurf listen always ask questions never
feel bad the worst thing is is it might
not be answered or you might hear a
reply that you're not expecting that
doesn't mean you shouldn't have asked
your question when you hear a reply that
you're kind of oh that's not what I
wanted to hear in return sometimes
people get a little uh-oh sorry don't be
sorry you asked a question that's cool
we should all be allowed to answer
questions just like we should all be
allowed to answer questions in the way
that we see fit
so would you live in Jamaica or Spain
yeah yeah I could do Barcelona I could
do the countryside I will do Jamaica
I've spent a lot of time in Jamaica you
know like really a lot of time over the
course of the last 20 years I may have
spent a year of my life in Jamaica so I
used to go there for six seven weeks at
a time and that was really nice getting
those trips in mr. melts you know
there's so many things going on in
Jamaica right now that I love the idea
of I have no idea if that's true you'd
have to look it up and regards to a
Spanish person that might know the
Spanish laws the product in Jamaica is
like anywhere it's hard to find but it's
great if you can find it the majority of
the stuff is not great and it's not
exciting and it's not you know just like
anywhere to go into a dispensary or if
you go into you know buy herbs anywhere
it's - always the same like most is not
that exciting and a little bit is super
exciting and it's uh that's the way it
always is I'm not sure if I'll be trying
to get into the USA anytime I thought
about it I won't lie I thought about it
oh geez who was I supposed to shout out
today Andrew and Katie Harrison SSS
that's who I'm shouting out I had a nice
email from a woman yesterday who said
her husband was kind of bummed out and a
little down and out and if I could just
give him a call it would cheer him up
and I thought wow what and I just said
that morning you know if you can make
someone's day better by giving them a
smile or helping them in some small way
wouldn't it be a good thing to do and so
I got the email later that day saying
hey I was actually a with the team Japan
guys and so she sent me this email and
she said her husband was down and out he
was having some problems some health
problems and lost his job and sent me
his phone number and man I had such a
great conversation with this guy I
called him up I was like hey bro what's
up and he's like he answered he answered
just like this hello and I was like hey
dude what's up and he's like who's this
and I'm like it's bubble man bro what's
going on
he's just like what what do you mean
what are you talking about I was like
dude it's [ __ ] bubble man dude I'm
calling you up it's waking banks it's
bubble man attached churches bubble bags
it's like I don't know don't you know
and yeah SSS man he was so he was such a
nice guy and it was so amazing to be
able to help inspire someone because you
have to understand I don't feel in any
way shape or form that I that I that I'm
special I just felt like in that moment
like I was doing the right thing and if
I if somehow I was making this guy's day
by by talking to him I mean what the
[ __ ] is this world come to that we can't
share our time with one another that
people have to feel like it's a special
occasion if someone who has a bunch of
followers on Instagram gives them time
it's just [ __ ] up so yeah it made me
feel as good as it made him feel I won't
lie really did and I felt like I was
able to give him some inspirational
words you know he felt like he was in
this obstacle zone and losing his job
and being sick and I was just like bro
those are your opportunities that's the
energy that is feeling so intense that
if you go down into it you're gonna be
super bummed out but if you can kind of
flip it around you're gonna have this
incredible rocket launcher boost of
power that can set you off on the next
vision that clearly you manifested in
the first place because you didn't want
to work as a construction worker anymore
and you couldn't quit so you ended up
manifesting subconsciously this other
experience that took you away from your
career so I want to give a big shout-out
to Katie and SSS what a nice person what
great people I didn't talk to her for
very long I just heard her voice in the
background but I'll tell you the guy was
the real deal just a nice person and
maybe having a little bit of problem
problems in his life and feeling a
little down man it made me feel good to
be able to lift him up a little bit and
I hope you listen to SSS I hope you got
you're having
better day today and I'll tell you that
you made my day a better day yesterday
by being a part of it so thank you
brother in the meantime I think it's
time for feeding our endocannabinoid
systems have you fed your
endocannabinoids system today I know I
have alright actually we're gonna go for
the other stuff well it's the right
thing to do and it's nice and it just
feels good and in the end well okay
here's another cool story survivor who
came in the other day and I decided to
give him the the bottle of DC glass
cleaner he sent me a really cool email
says he's super good friends with vital
garden supply guys and says if you want
I'll help get them on hash Church and in
like three emails back and forth and
he's got buddy from vital garden supply
who Tony has talked about and supported
in the past and who I've only heard
great things about he's gonna come talk
about soil on hash Church you know all
because of that experience of that just
sort of stepping outside of the box if
we're looking for things to be different
in our lives why don't we change them
step outside of the box do something you
might not have done do something that's
a little bit you know not the everyday
step out of your norm and so for me
stepping out of my norm the other day
and deciding that the guy who said hey
did I miss the giveaway am i late you
know I got to give him that thing and in
turn he gave back this beautiful energy
and and because of it you are all gonna
benefit because now Brian from vital
garden supply is gonna come and he's
gonna school us on soil and he's gonna
we're gonna have a great conversation so
and then you know sss was the same thing
he just he just made me the everyone in
this world has something to offer and
you it more importantly have something
to offer them and i think that i often
think that fame is how they hijack it
they try to make certain people famous
so that everyone's focused on those
people while missing the true people
that they've manifest
into their life through whatever form of
energy or what-have-you
those are the people you're supposed to
be meeting and they might not look like
you know the movie star or the rock star
they might just be an everyday person
and don't miss that opportunity because
you yourself manifested that person into
your life what a horrible hell to be
trapped in to subconsciously manifesting
the energies and the people that you
need in your life and constantly blowing
them off and missing them missing the
mark how [ __ ] up is that
I'll tell ya hey thanks Christian much
appreciated with the kind words
much appreciated yeah you know you know
I mean don't get me wrong some people
rub me the wrong way and I have I have
this crazy energy with and but for the
most part I try to understand that all
the people that come across my path I
myself have manifested them into my life
and you know I learned that through
getting busted in thinking getting
busted was the worst thing ever and then
sort of transferring that energy into
starting bubble bags which was like the
best thing ever for me and my family
it's just been a wonderful great thing
and it all came through this all through
this obstacle that everyone I can assure
you was all on the same page saying this
was bad very very bad and that's how we
feel you know we feel that and I'll tell
you when I told SSS yesterday listen bro
you probably manifested losing your job
but because you were so stubborn in your
life you would have just held on to that
job for the next 50 years
I said now you're going to be able to
create a reality for yourself where
you're not just doing something that you
have to do or that you're good at but
something that you want to do and that's
you know the law of attraction there it
is the first time I ever saw that Law of
Attraction my wife and I we were
laughing about it because my wife is
like that's what you've been doing since
I've known you
I'm like hell yeah oh yeah I fully
believe in manifesting your reality well
there's no doubt about it it's all done
through the choices that you make but
more importantly through the thoughts
that you think through the words that
you project and through the
actions that you display through those
three combinations and they are like a
ladder one step comes before the other
they lead into these manifestations and
I just you know it's it's hard to
understand sometimes but even you know I
guess what it is is it's kind of like
outside of good and bad
do we need trustworthy what's that
what's that Pharmacy bro do we need
trustworthy hands and 21 years
experience in Cali yeah quite possibly
dude hit me up bro I'd love to have a
talk with you there's things that I
would love to have done in California
one of the things is I would love to
find the quality material obviously we
have access to some but this is an
opportunity for everyone to be a part of
this in the sense that whoever has the
the top the the the 10 out of 10 we want
to wash your material we want to turf
your material we want to process your
material we want to promote your brand
because that's what bubble bags is all
enough is all about we're not about
there's nothing without the grower so
we're looking for great growers and if
you can help facilitate some of that
that might be a great way for us to you
know start a relationship and it's
really easy the great grower
relationship we just need a little
sample we run it we see the quality of
it and from there we move forward and
it's Tony's got simple contracts down
there they're all licensed they do
everything by the book and the drivers
and all this that and the other things
so hit me up farm CBC bubble man at
icloud.com and anyone that thinks they
have the quality down in California if
you want to get washed with bubble man
and that's the best way to start right
there and as you can see from the bubble
man brand Instagram account we are not
messing around
so check it out that's it Pharmacy
that's it it comes with a thought it
turns into words it turns into action
boom boom oh I'm sorry to hear the
source while it's nice that you did that
form good job good job on you
no Damien gareki actually the giveaway
is not done you won the giveaway one
bottle of DC glass cleaner send me an
email to BC bubble man at iCloud calm
and enjoy your bottle of DC cleaner
brother Damien gareki I'm not joking
[Laughter]
apologies for a little bit of the
coughing there but you know what I found
about these giveaways is I love doing
them I'm gonna do them as long as I have
product that people have sent me to give
away and I just like kind of doing it
like that you know once people catch on
to that it'll be something different you
know it's just uh you know Tim there
kind of has been a giveaway almost every
episode of the wakin bakes I started I
don't know 40 or 50 episodes ago maybe
more I really can't remember do I have
any suggestions on music well I love
reggae so I love cabaco pyramid is
wonderful chronics of course with two
x's I love all old-school as well but
the new-school like Chewbacca and
chronics John nine protégé jesse royal
and then the old schools like kid acai
in the inna de yard band
Winston Rodney Burning Spear the Israel
vibrations love Israel vibrations of
course obviously Bob Marley which leads
you to Peter Tosh everything Peter Tosh
has you should check out that's all
reggae I could go on for hours about
reggae I also love jam bands I'm a big
fan of fish and I traveled around and
followed them which of course means I
love the Grateful Dead
I love the Allman Brothers I'm down with
government mule and the Tedeschi trucks
band and some other you know sort of
inspirational jam tunes also love all
the old-school Beatles and stones and
Led Zeppelin and cream and Clapton and
you know Jimi Hendrix and you know many
many a Frank Zappa who's not for
everyone but I do love me some Frank
Zappa son raw who's kind of also Frank
Zappa ask and very very intense going
into these jazz orientations that are
next level I love the blues I love jazz
so you know think of the top 10 from
Howlin wolf you know into BB king Stevie
Ray Vaughan on and on and on it goes for
that but jazz as well I'm a big
fan of jazz I used to go to the Montreal
Jazz Festival I love Pink Floyd I love
David Gilmore and I love Roger Waters
both together and apart so I just love
good music in general Muddy Waters
absolutely not a huge Rick Ashley fan
never gonna give you up but I've been
Rick Rolled on a number of occasions I'm
not gonna lie love the Traveling
Wilburys as well as every one of the
members of the band yes dub side of the
Moon is a wonderful album super super
proper I love Bill as well check out
bill as well he's got some really good
stuff he does he did a Miles Davis remix
and he did a Bob Marley remix both of
which are exceptional I also listen to
punk rock when I was younger from Black
Flag to the Dead Milkmen to you know a
whole variety of misfits and SNF you and
you know I've listened to a lot of music
over my life and I really enjoy a lot of
music so I'm not too like Michael Franti
like Primus I like what the hell are
they Blues Traveler you know so much
yeah grunge you know back in the 90s I
was there for all of that so Pearl Jam
and Blind Melon and Nirvana I was there
it was I love the Ramones back in the
day that was one of the first first
bands I ever got turned on to like way
back in the day yeah yeah you know Sonic
Youth Leon Russell you know what I'm not
a big rush fan even though I am Canadian
I've never been a big rush fan I can't
lie you know probably like Violent
Femmes more Soundgarden for sure
guar seen him in concert avoided getting
spewed on by the giant fish caught that
he wears some days yeah yeah lots of
good stuff Motorhead of course come on
I seen Motorhead Lemmy was the man the
ace of spades the ace of spades yeah I
might have put my head through a wall to
that song at one point in time in my
it's hard to say it's hard to say let's
just say I've covered the gamut in
experiences ok I'm not making this [ __ ]
up I'm from Winnipeg
Santana absolutely bro
love me some Santana saw a good
interview with him talking about how
much acid he took before he went on
stage at Woodstock and how crazy in his
head everything was spinning and he's
just trying to stay on time but if you
watch the video he is absolutely
crushing it he became famous after that
they knew who he was after that oh yeah
one last one last bubble rip we are
making make it get to 30 minutes let's
do it let's do it
yeah the giveaway happened cartwheel
should have you should have been on that
[ __ ] bro hey what's going on
squish there's my most awesome employee
I don't even like to call her an
employee you know my employees of fresh
Hattie seem more like partners they're
more like my team you know so squish
Rochelle who's in the room right there
is has been working for fresh headies
for a long time doing customer service
and help him do the creating these
beautiful ads and answering the phone
and doing you know a lot of stuff she is
a woman of many hats so please give her
a shout out and give you know Stu is out
out and Max's shout out as well because
they do the good work down at fresh head
ease they make it so you guys get your
product when you want it you don't need
a hundred subs trust me the last thing
you need is a hundred subs go have one
sub and don't go to Subway go to like
mr. submarine so you can actually kind
of get it toasted that's the sub you
need a hundred subs that's absurd
her name's Rochelle squish color squish
and we called her that even before rosin
became popular so there what kind of
nail do you prefer well you know what I
prefer the one that's around and the one
that's available but if I have all of
the options I love my sapphire and I
love my quartz they both work great I
like quartz bangers I love sapphire
dishes and I'll even hit off of titanium
if it comes down to it I'm not so so
picky if that's the only thing that's
around but if I have my choice I'm going
to go with my sapphire or my quartz
there it is
welcome IQ of 420 if we can't have fun
at these wake-and-bake sai mean to me
that's what these shows are all about
they're just about us having a few
laughs and you know just maybe givin
away some a thing here and there and no
I don't perfect to prefer smoke ash on
titanium Amelia I prefer to smoke it off
of quartz or sapphire however if Sat if
titanium is all there is I will smoke
off of it however if you want to see how
much I don't smoke cannabis if I have no
hash and there's only cannabis and I
don't have a vaporizer I won't smoke the
cannabis so that's uh
I will hit titanium it's not like I
dislike it I just I can't
I don't enjoy smoking cannabis any more
the burning it just doesn't bring me
enjoyment so I don't do it ooh that
sounds like a good toke one of those
bowel emptying tokes be right back I
hear that turn to change my photo but I
can't seem to see a change here I see
just an R you might have to re you know
leave and then come back or maybe next
time you come back the photo will be
changed that's how it works sometimes I
have PK Brewer I have
solutely have ghost train well I think
we're good guys we rocked 30 minutes I
had fun I had good times as always I'm
not sure I dropped the best information
today
it's kind of a big responsibility to
always drop this intense information
sometimes it's facilitated out of me by
the particular conversations we're
having and other times it just doesn't
come but I am glad I got to tell you
about SSS and KT and you know we're
gonna be doing another wake-and-bake
tomorrow so I will see you around 9
o'clock or so for that and I'll leave
you as I always leave you may the full
melt bless your bowl sooner than later
peace out everybody