all right welcome back everyone we've
tried this again
technical difficulties it does occur
welcome to a bubble man's world
welcome to the wake-and-bake episode 86
and glad to have you all here a little
bit of problems with my phone I'm
finding that the encoder with the phone
no longer works properly I go to go live
it goes black I turn it on I go to go
live again and then it's flipped the
phone
vertical which is not something I want
personally so I'm back I'm back and
we're making it work for those of you
that were wondering what I was holding
up in the last photo that was of course
some heavenly days I did show it earlier
I've got the green God's green crack
I've got some sweet skunk rosin and I've
got some Congolese rosin so all made
from some lovely hashes although maybe
God's green crack was made from herb I
don't have that information but I
figured we'd open up a little and have
some pop puffs
we'd have some puffs puffs ah yes
Jamaica I am going to be bringing the
drone to Jamaica absolutely you know I
went through some pictures earlier today
I had a man I posted it on Facebook
actually some of my friends from from
the years of going to Jamaica and
there's some great people out there that
I've been visiting with and yeah I
thought it would be a cool post today so
if you're on my Facebook page go check
that out give thanks to harass the far I
the energy that brought many of the
people into my life through Jamaica
definitely was the Rastafarian vibes
that I've always seemed to vibe out on
oh this shirt was a gift from say
Beauchene from vape exhale we talked
about vape exhale the other day keep it
I suppose I'm gonna have to have a big
fame exhale session here in the near
future and what we'll do is we'll invite
Sabo in because he's just a very
articulate speaker and he's very
intelligent when it comes to the message
that he's sharing and that's who gave
you the shirt so thank you same oh thank
you thank you yes in the meantime why
don't we have a
little pop we've opened up the sweet
skunk I'm gonna hit it up we're gonna
hit it up we need to wake the bake
alright here we go little shards of
goodness here in the wake and bake
episode well 86 hey morning pharmacy
Bros from endo hope life is good up
there I don't know who Jason s is bingo
Lombardi I really don't know sounds come
on
anyone else have sound what are we doing
it wasn't you make a why would I be
wearing this hat tell us about your
shirt well I just told you about my
shirt a little bit right but can't
athlete I just want to make sure you can
okay good that's what I like to hear
that's what I needed to know is that you
guys all had sound and that we weren't
just you know talking with no sound so
much love I don't know what to tell you
about my shirt other than what I just
told you about and it's best if sable
comes in and shares that information I'm
not sure where he's act today let's hit
the show it a little bit more of a
weight get that low temp happening tell
us a story uncle beau man
I was a wicked rip loved it when I damn
near take the whole rip in one shot
that's what I'm looking forward to some
time on the low low low low temp tabs
you end up we end up getting like 50
rips out of the thing
who was the pump
I am the pump I should get some [ __ ]
away today shouldn't I because let's be
honest the pump isn't the pump if he's
not giving [ __ ] away not pump what can
we talk about no New Age utopia the
giveaway has not happened yet we're
still on it we're gonna get something
given away here in the near future
oh nice counter concentrates good stuff
brother good stuff hitting that Green
Dragon the real green dragon we've got
some great great great results with
working with those guys so far very
happy I know Tony was happy as well even
while we wouldn't even consider grabbing
trim from just anyone as we really
mostly deal with with buzz but they had
some really really nice trim trim that I
haven't seen in a while you know like
that we haven't seen in a long time
when you get people you know focused on
taking care being OCD really making sure
you're paying attention I mean back in
the day I used to make the top top
quality with trim but the trim was
basically like Nugget it was the tiny
little leaves just chopped off the buds
nothing else so that trim produced
incredible quality as well as yield
there was a large surface area on such
such materials that you would get a lot
of resin you would get yields comparable
to bud for that matter while green
dragons been doing work for a long time
they're 20-plus years around so they're
growers for certain I don't know if
they're breeding but they're definitely
grow
I just don't want to bother Carsten
honestly every little bit that I've
broken my rule and been like oh I'll
send some and then it gets lost and then
it's a nightmare or the VAT is 18% and
everyone cries like a baby or they say
oh don't put the real value because the
VAT is so high and then we send it
without the real value and it gets lost
and it's uninsured and they want me to
pay for it these are some of the reasons
why I'm not saving terpenes to Europe
from Canada I wish it was easier I wish
this wasn't the case but this is exactly
the case it's exactly what happens and
it's just not worth the energy the the
stress of getting all choked and pissed
off but it is what it is this beggar
will David for kur you are getting me
live right now bro and so there we go
I know woody woody I know but trust me
the UK was the same way people sending
it to the UK complaining about the VAT
or when it gets lost and the right and
the real amount isn't on there and they
spent a thousand bucks you don't owe me
an apology Kyle I'm not even sure why
you would say that but you would ever do
if you feel like you've done me wrong
just do me right don't do me wrong
anymore and we're good to go you don't
even have to know ya salt and ice oh
isn't this good it's true
there's a rig on my end chalice chugger
that's exactly what I was looking for
today what size t-shirt are you so I can
get this damn giveaway over with chalice
chugger with the wind with the
thoughtful unique funny inspiring
what is your yeah just do me right man I
did say that I certainly didn't mean it
in the way I think you are thinking
Challenge chugger medium alright brother
I think I do have a medium with your
name on it right here there's your shirt
there it is here's your shirt bro so if
you wouldn't mind this is a medium
sending me an email at BC bubbleman bc
bubbleman
at icloud.com with your address and I
will send out all the other things I
still haven't sent out I think there's
four or five of them sitting on the
table now I try I try I try yes I have
seen that just and good stuff I put it
together when you told me I put it
together once you told me I'm going to
be filming at the karma cup you know
last year I got very busy and here's the
thing I'll try to film at the karmic up
the best that I can I think I'm speaking
so I'll probably film that just put a
camera up on a tripod but I'm not sure
how much else I'll get to film maybe
some sessions maybe a quick walk around
and some interviews with the with the
people that are around or at least Sarah
who's throwing it and I am going to
Jamaica prior to the karma cup so I will
be in Jamaica this month and I'll be
visiting the acreage I'll be visiting a
process facility of bottling plants and
a packaging facility we'll be visiting
the doctors conference so we'll get to
talk to a lot of the different doctors
about how they view cannabis as a
medicine in Jamaica and what the future
is going to bring and hey do you still
do videos with Dan I'm not sure who Dan
is Austin lafrenze
I might still do videos with Dan but
right off the top of my head I don't
know who that is
yeah Jamaica waken bakes the island hey
is they are gonna be Ballmer Johnny B
he's coming with me Johnny B he's gonna
be telling his patient story to the
doctors and bringing his crazy crazy
information with his x-rays and all the
doctors I think he's got like a 21 page
thing that explains exactly everything
that he's gone through right now and of
course Tony V is going to be in the
house our partners will be there prior
to that in Kingston of a different
doctors conference training then a
couple of representatives from United
cannabis and so we're really just
all-in-all super excited about how this
is going to be coming together here
slowly but surely it's true Adam smokes
a lot it is hard to do videos well out
one of those have been
it's very hard I'll be there kak it'll
be hard for you not to meet me I'll have
a booth and you just come right up to it
and introduce yourself and we'll have
met will probably puff a Terp dip dab
and we'll go from there
could you repeat your email one more
time I know I must oh no problem child's
checker my email is BC bubbleman at
icloud.com that is my email what's going
on weed nerd when you need organic help
in Jamaica well we have a pretty
incredible organic gardener Ernie who is
our Master Gardener he is Hebrew for
river rock I guess he you know I guess
like Scott from rare dankness Dredd
smokes weed and a couple other growers
would have been under Ernie
it was Ernie sort of grow that he was
over looking and those guys were helping
and operating it back in the day and so
he's an exceptional grower and then we
might be getting the skunk man Sam to
come out and do some you know some some
breathing for us so yeah Ernie is very
good put it this way all the herb that
you know jibs and can the melts the
trichome have the extracts guys a lot of
that herb back in the day was was being
produced by Ernie and his knowledge so
he knows how to grow big monster plants
he knows how to do micro teas and brews
and he's he's [ __ ] he's good to go
man Ernie is a good a great [ __ ]
grower
I'm like as a hash maker those are the
kind of growers that I want to make hash
for I don't want to have to go through a
hundred people that think they're good
and need me to explain through the bags
and the hash that I make that that in
fact that they're not people don't want
to hear that [ __ ] if they get aggressive
about it and the reality is the bags are
the Word of God when it comes to the
quality of what you've created because
it's producing a purity that
is the only way you could tell that
quality of product by purifying it I
don't know what I see the evolution of
weed in North America in the next 20
years I mean I have you know I'd love to
see it available everywhere I'd love to
see it available everywhere and if
that's the case a lot will happen to it
it might get pigeonholed down to three
different things but it might expand
even more than it is today and be you
know be hemp was always about being
about fifty thousand commercial products
we always bragged about hemp because it
had 50,000 commercial products well
cannabis will easily have 50,000
cultivars 50,000 terpene profiles I mean
the amounts that the ratios exist in and
how they change and how many terpenes
there are and rare ones that barely
exist anymore and in the ratios with the
cannabinoids there are endless
possibilities
way more than 50,000 so it really
becomes about who wants to go into that
mystery and find something unique and
amazing because there's a lot to be
found you know let's be honest not that
many people have focused their
attentions on breeding cannabis it's
true man the pump the hammer translating
over big squirrel nuts you always put a
smile on my face first because I read
your name and then that makes me laugh
then I see your avatar I don't even know
if that's you but you look like a
character definitely like someone I
would hang out with on the regular and
so appreciate it appreciate your humor I
do appreciate most of your humors and
all of your energy so thanks for coming
in guys I hope you man why do some
Jamaicans grow males with the females is
it for seeds well some are doing it for
seeds obviously some are doing it
because they don't know how to how to
get rid of the males how to call the
male's quick enough some just sneak up
on them so some are very good it's just
like anything the people who are hyper
aware the people who are paying more
attention they do a better job and
that's just like obviously even if it's
something as simple as cleaning a window
if you don't pay that much attention and
you don't go tie it into the corners
you'll leave water droplets in the
corners maybe if you
using not a rag but an actual window
cleaner and you leave too much of a
space between cleans you'll actually
leave a strip of water people do that
but then there's other people that can't
do that because all they see are the
imperfections they're looking so hard
and they're so focused that they would
never leave an imperfection like that
imperfections are screaming to them and
the cleaner they get it the louder the
imperfection screams under screams you
understand screams is kind of like a
little Freudian slip there as I'm doing
a metaphor for cleaning resin but
talking about cleaning on window anyway
squeegee there you go
the squeege imperfections they should
use DC glass cleaner right and that's
what's happened in Samuel bench if you
check every plant it depends on how OCD
you are it depends on how much attention
your pain - to do this just another day
getting better here my friend welcome to
the party
yeah I wish I could get my boss to
understand that I'm not even sure how to
test how to figure out how to convince
people to understand anything I think
you can just repeat things and then live
things and then eventually it'll be
written in the in the newspaper and then
those people will come to you and be
like hey did you hear about this and
you'll be like yeah I've been telling
you that and living that for twenty
years and they're like oh [ __ ] well I
just saw it in the paper so it's real
now it's kind of how some people are
living it is what it is probably not the
best idea anyone have a good strain for
bipolar - it's a tough one tough one you
know any type of those as anxiety or
mental you know where they're where it's
a feeling where it's in your head where
you're like I'm sure cannabis could be
good for bipolar or manic depression all
those things but I would definitely be
like be careful and be wary and of
course don't particularly with bipolar
because one of the things bipolar does
is you want to have a really good
support system and you want to have
people that you trust and believe so
that when you go
no potentially if you go manic if you go
really this high-end energy it's good to
have some people that you can trust and
believe who are saying hey you got to
come down that's not the right and so if
you have those people in your life and I
think it's safe to try all sorts of
forms of cannabis and find the one
that's right for you but make sure that
you don't get lost in it and that you
know I'm sure you know yourself better
than anyone that's just it's a tough one
mental illnesses are always a tough one
because they're there so in the head
I need another rape let's have another
rib I mean [ __ ] I won't say no to
another rib maybe a rip in a Turk dip
why not yeah yeah for sure Chris tank so
you want to make sure that you have good
people around you that you're able to do
that in and definitely we know one thing
and I would not normally say this but
you know my father-in-law
was was sick with mental illness most of
his life and a lot of those pills that
were prescribed to him I don't really
feel you know it and I would never
really tell anyone to not take
pharmaceutical pills because to each
their own we have to look at all the
options that we have but make sure that
you do your research and look at all the
options and make sure that that it's
good for you and it's good for the
people around you because it is some
scary [ __ ]
father mother lovers
as dean 420k would say we've got 236
people that's pretty good I'll send a
little message out we'll see what
happens I need you to peens on your
plant well I mean one of the easiest
ways for sure is to extract them that
really shows you what you've got just
like anything just like the hash making
its gonna let oh yeah POV and how did
that go
what would I like to know do I like Star
Wars and F yeah fes who was my favorite
character I swear to god I must have
been like five or six years old the
first time I saw Star Wars and now that
has gotten so complex and there's so
many different levels to it to me first
of all Star Wars was the four five and
six Star Wars Empire Strikes Back Return
of the Jedi that is Star Wars to me all
this other stuff I don't know it trips
me out I'm old and who my favorite
character is well come on it's got to be
Han Solo man he was smuggling [ __ ] he
was getting people ship the ship they
needed that you know the the rule makers
had decided that they they couldn't have
so you gotta like of course he was
classic but Han Solo was smuggling [ __ ]
in the Millenium folk I thought the
Millennium Falcon what was the wasn't
what's the name of his ship
yeah well it's true ramen kaolin I mean
it's a it might sounds funny by saying
that mental illness that's tough there
so in the head but it's what I meant by
that is that because it's in your head
and people can't see it and it's not
quite diagnoseable like a tumor right or
something visual on your skin or in your
body holding yourself a certain way
skeletal whatever it's it's tough
because people don't have the same level
of compassion and empathy for people who
are sick with bipolar or manic or other
mental illnesses so that's what I'm
saying about that it might sound like
funny the way you wrote it but really I
wasn't meaning it to sound funny at all
I was meaning it to sound very sort of
serious in the sense that if maybe we
had a little more empathy and compassion
for those suffering with mental illness
the way we would if someone had a giant
tumor growing out of their neck I think
it might be easier on people who are
suffering with mental illness so that's
what I think I don't think that I think
people are afraid of mental illness and
because they're afraid of it they tend
to sometimes be angry instead of
compassionate but I don't I mean that's
just my opinion I'm not too sure Bowman
even if I have to pay can I set up Skype
to talk to you well I mean I'm sure we
could probably do a Skype talk it really
depends look I don't like to try and be
like the guy who tries to charge people
to talk to them but I have an enormous
amount of people writing me messages and
stuff and one-to-one it's fine and
people who are wanting to learn and
educate I feel like that's always going
to be something I spend my time on
however when I realize that it's a
company a commercial enterprise
something that they're doing for a
living well then it seems like it's fair
that it's a consulting gig in that we
that there's there's pay being involved
so do you make most your decisions out
of intuition or gut feeling well
intuition and gut feeling are definitely
there i watch for the coincidences i
watch for these experiences that I
myself have for sure
manifested that in my brain are like
well that's weird I just had this happen
you know like things that align in a
weird sort of coincidental manner
I see great value in and I never ignore
meeting anyone so you know that's
another kind of key thing that if you're
only trying to meet people who you think
can help your agenda and you look at
them as a certain level of person and
the people who are below that you're
ignoring you're gonna miss a great deal
of stuff because personally I find the
majority of the the really magic that
happens in my life happens from random
people that are not known or with wood
you could never think of them at a
certain level they're just a neutral
person you've never met when you give
these people the time you'll see that
there are actually people you manifest
it into the ten to your life and now
it's up to you to recognize that it's
kind of hard to put into words but well
that's it I pet Maddy and I want to
share my truths with people that's why I
do this all the time but then people
have specific questions that they want
to ask me for their time and it's like I
said if it's like oh I'm helping my dad
try to beat his cancer or something I'll
spend hours with that person but if it's
for a commercial enterprise it just
seems fair that I'm pretty comfortable
talking about guarding gardening big
squirrel nuts you remind me of my best
friend that died wow that's crazy and
ruber be sorry to hear about your best
friend that died but I'm glad I remind
you of him a little bit who's to know
maybe he's in here a little bit giving
me inspirations because I definitely
feel like wherever I'm getting my
inspirations from it's like from another
place other than me like it comes to me
and so give thanks for cannabis being
one of the most incredible facilitators
of reality manifestation you know a
facilitator of positivity and a
facilitator of just great vibes IRA
vibes as they say in Jamaica
share some of my Jamaica photos with you
guys man because I was taking some today
and to let me see where I put them on I
put them in the CR D that's where I put
them
so these are some pictures I've taken
who so many years ago now this is these
are the first two dudes that ever made
bubble that I ever made bubble with in
Jamaica now I made a batch that I didn't
photograph and then I then they made
this batch after watching me so here
check this out
boom I think of em apples how cool is
that
those are the og bubble makers right
there James and his helper James is on
the right
really incredible Rastafarian man like
totally inspirational dude bump above
let me get another one open for you here
red is another inspirational dude
chill this picture of red they see where
you're at red all right here we go boom
there's red not sure why I'm showing all
this other [ __ ] I'm kind of failing at
this but old-school red making me feel
Allah there we go let's see if I can get
the rest to you guys when did I even do
with you guys I had the chat and now oh
there we go there we go let me try one
more Ziggy Ziggy one the Cannabis Cup
last year two years ago in Jamaica here
we go that's what I want to show you
right there so there's Ziggy and I this
is an orange he'll you can see the soil
in the background is orange with good
reason and those are 20 gallon set of
bubble bags that I'm passing his way it
would be 15 years later that I would see
him on stage at the Cannabis Cup me
winning best product first place with
bubble bags him winning first place for
best bubble hash almost twenty years
later really really great guy right
there let me tell you that's not Ziggy
Marley
that is Ziggy me bredrin from orange
hill so let me give you one more then we
go who else we go we got bongo roach
bongo roach where are you at bongo
chillin with bongo let's see if we can't
get the screenshare happenin here so
this is also about 15 or 16 years ago
chillin with bongo roach and also given
him set of bubble bags he was a medicine
man so he was making all sorts of
different medicines from different from
different plants and coconut oils and
yeah well that's almost 20 years ago
that is damn near almost 20 years ago
what else we got oh we got the doctor
got to give give thanks to the doctor
these were some of my original videos
with this gentleman he has the
dreadlocks that go down all the way to
the ground like way to the floor there
like seven I smoked with all these guys
of course are you kidding me man come on
the whole reason they were spending time
with me and not thinking I was just some
whacked-out tourist is because I was
there making hash I was a medicine man
you understand I'm teaching this bongo
Roach guy who's like a revered medicine
man in Jamaica I'm teaching him how to
make bubble hash and giving them bags
and not asking for anything in return
this is my brother Mikey we call him the
doctor we're at his grow that's on top
of a mountain everything in the picture
he carried up on his head including
55-gallon drums
I brought Remo here I brought Pete Brady
from cannabis culture here I brought all
sorts of people to meet with Mikey he
was just an absolute beautiful person
grew absolute fire and even skunk man
Sam smoked the resin and met these guys
as well and he loved it too so it was
the real deal how about the sativa days
back in Jamaica where he could actually
go into a field and see a sativa
or a narrow leaf drug cultivar how about
that oh yeah there we go
so yeah just sharing a little bit of
pictures with you guys you know figured
it was kind of a short little wake and
bake today I don't know how long we've
been on for already but it's probably
been close to half an hour maybe we'll
do one more dab and call it a day
I hope you guys are gonna have a good
day Saturday tomorrow is hashed Church
and I do would like to tell you but you
should be there for it it's gonna be a
good one like a really really good one
so come to hash Church tomorrow I'm
gonna start the link right after we end
this so I would appreciate it if you
take that youtube link and you share it
throughout your social medias let's see
how many people we can get watching live
on hash Church tomorrow it's gonna be
it's gonna be a top 10 maybe top 5 maybe
top 3 I don't know that's saying a lot
there's been 146 episodes but it's gonna
be a good one and I'd hate for any of
you to miss it
not that it would matter because it will
be recorded and you'll be able to watch
it on YouTube anytime afterwards what
what do you mean I am giving you a hint
dokdo Tom I'm telling you it's gonna be
a super awesome episode that should be a
hint right there and after to tell you
that you should be there now in the
meantime let's do this
[Applause]
we got 234 people watching right now
thank you everyone for coming and
hanging out puffing bowls with me on
this beautiful Saturday afternoon well
it's not afternoon yet but they are the
East Coast then it is then it's
afternoon I'll be there well this should
just cracked into into shards I'm doing
well Marcus thank you what you smoking
on I'm smoking on some Congolese rasen
little Congo Bongo and I think it's
about to go down here very soon let's do
it I don't remember the last email I
thought you sent me chase was asking if
you could send me your book and sign it
and I just was like I don't want to have
the responsibility if you don't mind
like I said if you meet me anywhere I
think I went through this and if this
was the email you were referring to I'll
gladly sign something at karmic up or at
one of the events that I'm working I
just don't want the responsibility of
like my kid destroying it or me losing
it or spacing resending it so thank you
brother Louie's in there there we go
well I can't wait to be waking baking
from Jamaica here soon try to do some
good ones get some good friends will get
prophecy to do maybe a little wake and
bake sing sing song maybe even Richie
spice would do it I know he's sure
talented this [ __ ] it would be great to
have either one of those guys come on
the wake-and-bake show and play a little
song for you guys I'll have to ask them
I don't think it'll be too hard it's
such good vibes such good vibes on him
there I truly love Jamaica sure they
truly truly love it
oh yeah unlimited amount sticks
unlimited amounts wait until that green
house is rocking anyway everybody thanks
for coming in today and sharing your
time with us I did receive your email
he who won the prize so why don't I
leave you with maybe the full Mel bless
your bowl sooner than later and we'll
talk to you then peace everybody hey
what's up you got meal