hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world and the wake-and-bake
episode Oh 83 I guess we're on here
right now doing it a little bit
differently today I guess something's
wrong with YouTube live having a bit of
difficulties going live on my phone so I
actually went live on my computer and
doing it the hash Church way so who
knows we could end up getting a guest or
two if I decided to invite someone and
it's much more doable this way what's
going on island haze drunk Ethan coot 16
octo
in masks vapor Co Sam Allen Seth Johnson
Brian Wilhite sticks with Terps
and a good morning to you as well Alex
clay I hope everyone's doing well today
and yeah I'm excited excited to have a
little bit of a rip with you guys
excited to possibly give these two
things away today these are basically
PTFE sheets four by fours I guess
they're using it to press rosin it's
just a kick down these are not for sale
sent to me by the good people at the
caramel cup there are Sunday so there's
that pin again as well and yes indeed
we're going to be giving those away
today because why shouldn't we and let
me see I think we've already let me see
where we're at here do we need to
refresh the feed says mind puff buzz
well I hope you guys are letting
everyone know to refresh the feet if
that's something that they need to do
because that is something that we need
to do what's everybody smoking on says
diggity dang the chat room has been
going on for a while I'm just actually
running through the chat because I saw
something in there earlier that I liked
and it did it did it let me see I'm
almost there I'm almost there the answer
to today's question pizza from the kiln
for the win yes mind puff buzz it's true
you win my buddy you win and it's not
really even that you win it's just that
I choose you
I choose you choose you and this is if
you remember that
does anyone remember that reference I
choo-choo choose you let's see how many
references we get for that one anyway
this is going to you mind puff send me
an email at BC bubble man at icloud.com
and I will get back to you by mailing
you this when you send me your address
hopefully that's really cool yes the
Simpsons dank runner but what from The
Simpsons yes doner Smurf yes but what is
the actual what is it from okay we're
getting a little closer Ralph okay Ralph
what what okay The Simpsons Valentine's
Day yeah yup that's it Simpsons Ralph it
was the way I would answer that question
this is it was ralph getting a
Valentine's Day card that said I teach
you choose you I can't remember if it
was one he gave away if it's one he
received no it's the one he received
from Lisa it's the one he received from
Lisa because she never he never got a
Valentine's Day card poor [ __ ] Ralph
you know how nice of Lisa to sort of see
that Ralph was hurting and to send him a
card because even the local cops kid
needs some love and there's a lot to be
cited some of these Simpsons episodes
obviously you know all taken from the
social context that is life yes she
broke his heart but first she tried to
save his heart and that was the lesson
she put herself out there she tried to
offer him some sort of you know and it
came back to be but he was a little bit
more annoying than previously thought of
let's have a damn shall we
it was a condo today she's a good [ __ ]
right it's been a while I watch an
episode every once in a while with my
son my 14 year old son likes the
Simpsons oh yeah that is a fab AG behind
me look at that
here let's see if we can get this off
might be a little bit stuck and I did
just heat it up so we might have to do a
little bit uh there we go
gotta love the heat transference
courts allowing us to do such things
let's hit the fab egg shall we I think
it's great Tara I think it's great
Tara is called talking about Whitney
harmonies new glass banger unbelievable
concept he's put frit inside the bottom
of the banger
he's encased another banger into the
bottom of the banger so it's like a cup
within a cup and basically the frit acts
as a timer and you can it changes color
as it gets hot and then it changes color
back again as it loses its temperature
so what it can do is and this is a very
cool concept it can train you to hit
your dab instead of from a timer from
color from a color sequence so I thought
it was [ __ ] coolest [ __ ] its
innovative
I love the innovation of these glass
blowers and the stuff that they're
bringing to us I'm an end-user so even
more happy will I have one in the very
near future
absolutely I got on the second list the
first list was was hammered out actually
I'm not using my phone for this first
time so I can actually show you guys if
the phone actually wanted to work
sometimes I just hate iPhones but not
always let me see if I can find Whitney
Whitney harmony glass all right so here
is the unit right here and that's he's
doing a giveaway go check him out on
Instagram you can see his account is if
I can get it to focus Whitney Harmon
Whitney Harmon glass Whitney Harmon
glass go check him out it's a super cool
concept really really cool concept
I thought about the torch with the laser
thermometer all in one that's kind of a
good idea still I thought about it but
honestly like I don't know I think this
is cooler I think this is way cooler
it's sealed in its quartz I wouldn't be
too worried about it
it's not like the quartz can breathe and
things can get through I'm not a big
future round the fan no big wave today
and Topanga all right all right you know
with what bong rip tasted like it tasted
like another one drew I know exactly
what that bong rip tasted like because
I'm constantly taking that bong rub
let's get a little bit more cleaner on
the banger a little bit of areas that
get missed sometimes when you have a
really big banger it's easy to sort of
missile a section here in there and we
do not want to let the Chas hang out for
any amount of time I am one that thinks
that that is not such a good idea
Oh Kris you don't even know bro you
don't even know I have a video of the
final piece and now it's a short video
like two minutes but I am going to be
releasing it in the very near future
because let me tell you it is awesome
just the piece the quality of it I put
some pictures up on my Instagram you can
check them out at BC bubble man but the
video going close up and looking at the
absolute insane quality of the glass and
how much it pops in the Sun I was a
little disappointed the this apartment
that I went to photograph in was very
not sunny the Sun in order to go I'm
behind
yeah you totally missed everything you
[ __ ] it all up dude damn Adam smokes a
lot just joking you didn't [ __ ] anything
up did you miss anything I don't think
so
did you miss me giving something away
yes I did give something away but I gave
that away before it was even that before
anything went down in here so it was an
impossible one to let to win unless you
said that it was the pizza from the kiln
how cool was the pizza from the
was that not a funny experience I see
him pulling this [ __ ] out and I'm like
oh [ __ ] yo she yo she's pulling some
stuff out over there I I'm sneaking up
on him kinda and then I look over his
shoulder is opening the tinfoil I'm
expecting some some cool glass something
something I've never seen some new
technique that involves tinfoil but he
opens it up and it's pizza he's cooking
his [ __ ] pizza and Miquelon course
quarter C is perfect
very cool mr. Kondo very cool oh yeah
dude it was unbelievable that whole
video I am happy that everyone's
enjoying it as much as they are and let
me tell you there is some good enjoyment
happening on that particular video
Woodruff uh boom just in case I'll send
that out you never know it happened I
end up meeting yesterday as well with
dr. Natasha and her husband David that
was a nice little hangout session we sat
by the boats and puffed some bowls out
of this really cool little piste he had
he basically had maybe I put it way over
there if you know the baby exhale dog
actually I have a big exhale right here
I can show you so if you know the vape
exhale bond the bond that has the base
with the hole in it this unit right here
he has a couple of different models but
basically it feeds the unit feeds right
in through here well the other day these
guys had a handheld battery unit with a
ceramic bowl that fit right into here so
it was a battery unit that fit into here
and I'll tell you the rip that I got off
those hot thing was was actually very
impressive for you that don't know the
vape exhale that's the unit right there
this is a cool little unit maybe one day
Sabo will give us one of these to give
away it kind of a cool unit to share
with the audience but you can go and
purchase on your own from vape exhale
and save those an awesome dude even if
you just want to learn about the unit
it's definitely worth
the money I'm not gonna lie they don't
all come in Pelican cases you can get
them fairly cheaper than that but oh
good job seventies moment that's a lot
of work getting those tents up if I'm
guessing what kind of tents you put
yourself up I took a few down just the
other day and it was it was work that's
for sure
no no ants on my rig today but keep an
eye out keep an eye out anytime you can
of course recognize any type of bugs I'm
going to reward you with great with a
great gift of some sort so if you see
one climbing on my hat if you see one
climbing on my shirt if you see one
inside my bong if one goes in the bowl
while I'm dabbing I mean that's
potentially worth like a million bucks
you could literally get a million bucks
transferred into your account
he transferred I'm sure they do eat
transfers up to a million bucks these
days so just being silly down to this
nine pound tastes like grapes all right
Amelia lavender look down to that
getting great rips from a bowling bag
vapes feeding the bottle thanks again
you're welcome Peter s I'm happy to be a
part of your journey you will not
probably see any tins of eagle 20 behind
me there are no Eagle 20 tins in my home
but boy what would that be worth the
portable electric nail I don't know of a
port oh the one that I had wasn't really
a nail I'll have to find out from David
if he's maybe he's in the chat or dr.
Anna Tosh I don't know if they're in the
chat right now but I was a really cool
little unit and seeing as I already have
a couple of the pipes I wouldn't mind
getting one of those little pieces to
modulate my battery with because it was
good my dogs barking in the background
not sure what up but I definitely am NOT
going to be yelling at him to shut up
you can just bark all he wants bark bark
bark bark bark that's what dogs do it's
kind of their version of being like hey
what's up what's up are we hanging are
we chilling what's going on probably
there's a stranger in my house right now
because he doesn't really bark like that
for any particular reason but what am I
going to do he's barking I think I'm
gonna have another puff actually we'll
get the torch going
there we go on a pop yes oh [ __ ]
yeah really sorry to hear all these
people all of these people going through
these spires right now probably not just
in British Columbia but all over but
definitely British Columbia has a lot of
fires right now it's kind of over the
top all right here we go little bubble
hit it's hitting some God's green crack
this time around a little bit oh it is
someone is here absolutely someone is
here that's why my dog won't shut up
there are people in the other room while
I'm viewing this episode maybe they'll
come in they'll hang out do a dad with
us they'll be in for a surprise if they
do let me tell you people love the
avenue car I forbid an eagle for that so
yeah that's that's some [ __ ] up [ __ ]
dude people gotta stay away from that
stuff on commercial printing your
pictures I've done it in the past Savage
I've G clayed them you know people they
just die I don't see a huge market for
it
I have people contact me and they want
photos I sell photos at least photos if
I print them they cost more obviously
because a giclee at south big enough can
cost you know I've spent upwards of 500
bucks on a nice G clay like a 4 foot by
5 foot or whatever Oh mine's inclined
he's like a little like toy poodle
crossed with a shih tzu
he's a ship who in fact I don't promise
on any signatures if you bump into me
one day in life and and I have a pen and
you have something you want me to sign
my god I will sign anything like a
hundred things but I find when I make
people to promise something simple like
that it ends up becoming more difficult
than it should be and like the product
it should just be shipped doesn't get
shipped and then it just doesn't all
work out and it fails so in regards to
will I send you anything signed no I
don't want the responsibility
don't mean to sound like a dick and be
disagreeable but come to an event that
I'm at come to the karma cup or one of
the cannabis cups or one of the lift
events or come to Jamaica I'm all over
the [ __ ] map just come meet me I'll
sign anything you want no problem except
over like control of my business and
house and whatnot and I will hey what's
going on from Russia welcome back I will
I just you know what I Fitz yeah get
exactly India that's what I that's what
I like to do promise nothing give all
when I make a simple promise like okay
I'll sign your thing I end up forgetting
I end up not doing it or you know for
the instance of the gentleman who asked
recently who wanted me to sign the book
the book that I gave away of Dana
Larson's was the only thing I have not
personally shipped I've shipped
everything myself
Dana shipped the book Dana lives in the
city 40 minutes away from me I don't see
Dana very often at all maybe two or
three times in a two to three month
period I might see Dana so when he asked
me could you sign it I just was like you
know what I'll try but it's unlikely you
know and then Dana hit me up the next
day saying I shipped the book I knew
that it wasn't gonna happen and in that
experience it taught me that I shouldn't
be promising anyone any type of
signatures hey if you win one of these
morning's Adam you'll get yourself a hat
if it happens to be a hat and you have
to give the right response or happen to
share this the right energy or happen to
you know say something that is funny and
grabs me in a certain way
absolutely but otherwise nada
yeah drew it is sold in California
dispensaries and I'm not sure when we're
going to do Colorado because that intro
involves building an entire facility in
Colorado of course you can't ship things
over state lines we need to have the
facility in Colorado a processing resin
that's grown in Colorado and we have
partners there and we have the ability
to do it but we're really just trying to
get our feet up let's release California
let's show everyone what we're about and
then we'll recreate the
oh sure I can do that tinychat comm
backslash French huh DS pretty easy
there we go
you can plug that into your Google and
it'll come up well there you go Eliot
it's always nice to play with dry
squares screamed dry set screens that is
a mothership sticker on this Pelican
behind me this is a stack of Pelley's
behind me one two three four there's a
couple over there
I have nothing like flab dofollow flat
four two one you got to see his Pelican
collection it's completely insane insane
your partners in Oregon already - no not
really John we've had conversations with
a few people we're always down for
working with good people who are doing
things we usually just pick that small
percentage of people people that are
focused on you know biodynamic farming
and the symbiosis of the root bacteria
like soil balance is talking about and
living soils with rhizomes and all of
these sorts of things that allow for the
plant to express itself at a higher at a
higher level of terpenes and
cannabinoids and whatnot these are the
people we want to align ourselves with
the people that are understanding that
you know growing biodynamically and
organically and you know really allowing
the plant to express itself that's where
we want to come in and process that
resin we don't want to be the mass
processor we want to be the processor
for the people who are producing the
highest quality product and those are
the people we want to promote even more
so than our brand we will promote the
people who grow the cannabis that we
process because they there are
everything they're doing everything
let's be honest the processor is a very
short percentage of time over the course
of that plant's life from seed to finish
oh well you know lots of people grow
with salts it's uh I I don't I think
that you can grow some decent herb using
these salts growths I just believe that
the Sun and organics and the symbiosis
of living organisms feeding for and on
the plants will produce a higher quality
expression that's unparalleled this just
can't be compared now that doesn't
that's not on the market
right now you know so that's not
available to people so things like
mostly salt grown newts are the ones
that are are popularizing right now so
trust me I'm sure you can
Willie you'll have to check out with the
company though oh thanks kiwicare Carrie
Thanks
just trying to keep it real just try and
keep it truthful you know I kind of was
having a conversation with a guy today
who we were talking about Tokyo smoke
and he said you know they're really not
bad guys and they'll probably end up
getting some good traction out of this
this nightmare Fiasco that they had with
mice these are of course the guys that
said there's no original bombs and in
the pipe making industry and their metal
3d printed space metal by pipe for
$13,000 is going to be the new future
obviously these guys are somewhat
disconnected from the scene but they're
reconnecting to a new scene that isn't
the scene and I understand that but you
know you can do it without completely
insulting an entire industry we were
just sort of talking about that that
concept of like coming out and like you
know trying to represent an industry
while insulting the entire industry it
was really it was really a crazy [ __ ]
crazy [ __ ] thing yeah sweet dragon
that was a sweet dragon this is a sweet
dragon and this is a pretty nice dragon
and I get it it's hard not to make fun
now but you know I haven't met Alan on a
few occasions he's actually a really
nice guy and it was unfortunate that
them that it got that it came out like
that that they just said the things that
they said and the editing and the way it
came out was just like oh that's just
terrible you can't be you can't do such
a thing yeah they're not bad guys trust
me they're not bad guys at all they're
actually pretty good dudes but they just
came across really do sheet in that in
the particular video and they did kind
of insult the entire industry in there
coming across as douchey so Adam smokes
a lot if you want to get in touch with
me get in touch with me at BC bubble man
at iCloud
komm if you need me to I'll put it in
here see bubbleman icloud comics my
email can hit me up I will reply yeah
here we go pretty chill chill today we
got 250 people I don't feel like I've
gotten too deep it feels a little
different now that I'm on the computer
than when it did on the phone but maybe
another dab will loosen the gift of debt
of gab I need to just do a quick little
cleanup because my last step is still
actually sitting in there somewhat dirty
it's always the good sign of a pretty
strong gab when you go to take your next
hit and your bowl still has the oil
floating around in it from the last one
it's not a bad sign love cleaning the
Banger love not having it Chazz out on
me it's my favorite I'm not gonna lie oh
yeah I have a feeling this tab may again
taste like another you know they
constantly do Cheers
Kelo you're enjoying your Hercules
that's great to hear I'm guessing it's
the one that I sent you
that's pretty cool that's pretty cool
wow it's cool that that the more stuff
we give away the more it makes itself
out to all these different places around
the world and eventually you know
hopefully we'll cover we'll cover all
the four corners with cool little gifts
that we pass out damn love the Dark
Crystal yeah me too T Minor
oh yeah Benny Sheets those guys are
next-level dosa as well all four of
those glassblowers I can't pronounce
that I see Dyson's named Daisuke Saito I
think Yoshinori condo and junichi Kojima
who is aka Rhodes Rhodes really really
really talented individuals I love what
I love about it is what I love about
everything that I do in the fact that
the things that I'm good at hash making
isolating resin heads I'm good at it
because I pay careful careful attention
okay I go in and I was paying more
attention
ahead of a lot of people and then
teaching other people how to pay
attention and how to become aware has
been a learning lesson for me because as
I teach I realize all the things I don't
know and I go out and I seek that
knowledge and I want to learn more and
more and there's so much that I don't
know about these components in these
plenty of this plant and the resin that
it produces I'm sure eventually one day
the stuff I don't know about cannabis
will fill a small library maybe even a
big library so I'm definitely looking at
it as I'm still the student even as I
try to fit the shoes sometimes as I
don't like to say teacher but share
facilitator of knowledge you know let's
all learn this knowledge because
eventually some really [ __ ] smart
people are going to gain it and when
they do the next step of the next
knowledge the deeper level that we need
to go into may be unveiled so what do I
think of Jerome Baker I like Jerome
Baker you know originally I met Chris oh
geez like it must be 20 years maybe more
than 20 to 22 years ago is when I first
met the main blower I'm spacing right
now actually a little bit because I
called him Chris and now I'm like
doubting that that's his name and
everyone used to call him Jerome Baker
and anyway one of you guys will put up
his name and then I'll feel terrible
I've known him for a long time so it's
kind of crazy that I'm spacing on his
name but I like him I like his you know
it's different it's a different level
and style of glass people used to love
that [ __ ] back in the day he was you
know when I first met him it was in 1995
and he was in the back of Adam Dunn's
place which was I want to say it was the
KGB Jason exactly don't know why I
called him Chris but yes Jason was there
he had his long hair and I got some
video footage of him use bone a glass
pipe and it was the KGB Adam had just
closed the CIA which was cannabis in
Amsterdam and the KGB which was his new
incarnation was called no KN o W good
buds and it was [ __ ] awesome yeah he's
been on Church absolutely Jay Harris
exactly
I call them crisps but yeah a couple of
good dabs of some sativa some narrow
leaf drug cultivars and that'll occur
although you know actually the last one
I took was that God's green crack and it
is definitely not a narrow leaf drug
cultivar it is very strong and narcotic
and that could seriously put people to
bed excellent a pot smoker yeah I've
been sharing it for almost twenty years
so if you've been paying attention if
you've been out there listening the
information has been what I would
consider fairly widespread even though
tons of people still don't know exactly
about what water hash is how the concept
works you know the things to sort of
stay away from yeah I still not sure why
I called him Chris he's kind of funny
he's gonna be like do this are you on
your way can big call me Chris just I
get a better actually contact them you
know cuz that's a good when you know
you're getting old and you haven't
talked to some of your friends in too
long when you start mistaking their
names uh yeah hit the thumbs up for me
man people Thank You Adam did you get my
email by the way that I said to send me
cuz I totally missed yours and it's
easier for me if you can send me the
email bc bubbleman at icloud.com
try to get it off i don't know what you
wanted to talk about but oh what's going
on Michael stay hater it yet it can
Michael &amp; Michael M is of course one of
the wonderful helpers over at n visa you
know kind of a personal assistant
manager style dude to Tony but maybe
even more started out with Blue River
extracts and still helping those guys
and Etienne needs no introduction at
Tanza [ __ ] pioneer and so much of all
of this activism and dispensary world
that yeah it's pretty cool to have you
guys in here man wakin and bacon with us
all have a hit for that let's let's hit
the let's hit the climb
let's hit the climb well heat it up oh
nice say hello to the BPG
I'll tell you I found a rolodex recently
I don't know where the hell I think I
put it up there I found my old rolodex
from like I don't know it's I got to be
close to 20 years old and it opened up
on the BPG and Debbie's personal number
and it was like like she seriously must
have written that in there like a year
after they opened that place just kind
of cool all right let's hit this little
dab we're going back in for some Congo I
just hit something special no wonder I
saved it that's the way dude I love that
want to hear one of my most amazing and
it's kind of funny because it goes back
to joints and I haven't smoked joints in
a long time before I started the bubble
bag company the night that I got busted
and arrested was 16 and a half pounds at
a roadblock I ended up staying the night
in the West Vancouver jail and they
impounded my car and the next morning I
released myself on my own cognizance in
the end it was a very very chill
experience other than having to spend
time in jail and this is the price you
pay for practicing civil disobedience
prior to these great legal platforms and
systems mechanisms being put into effect
how we get those into effect as we
practice civil disobedience that's what
I was practicing I got caught I got in
trouble I spent the night in jail I lost
all my pounds but I'm not away home I
noticed that they had left my ashtray in
the car and back then I used to smoke a
lot of joints and leave the roaches in
the ashtray well there was this big fat
roach in the ashtray and I was driving
home and I was kind of choked and pissed
off but having all my pounds taken and
having the letting down the compassion
club and getting busted and having to go
to court and losing money and all this
crazy [ __ ] you know being pretty
stressed out about it actually and I
opened the ashtray as I'm getting out of
West Vancouver driving up towards
Horseshoe Bay and I see this big Roach
there's a whole bunch of little ones in
there too but I see the big one and I'm
like
I know what that is and I I just put it
in my mouth and I push the cigarette
lighter in and I like that joint and if
it wasn't the [ __ ] haze it was like a
pure haze joint I just I inhale and as I
exhaled I realized everything is going
to be fine stop reacting to this
experience do not give them any more
power than they have already taken from
you and from that moving from that
moment on I started looking at it as a
valuable lesson instead of a costly
mistake and that's led me to start with
the bubble bag company start fresh
headies start promoting isolation of
glandular trichomes heads start
educating people do macrophotography
start my youtube channel hash Church all
of that comes from being arrested one
night at a roadblock with cannabis so
you know sometimes if you're really
looking forward to change you know and
you manifest this rock bottom that's
kind of some of the best change you can
ever manifest not saying that I was
really rock bottom but it was a bummer
for me it was my lowest of my low it was
a little scary low lower than I like to
go and there's real comfort in that
experience I was talking about it today
actually in how you have these two sort
of worlds whether you have this money
world this world of people who want to
become involved with cannabis that have
never become involved with cannabis and
then you have this kind of as community
people who have been very very much
involved and are very connected and feel
very somewhat possessive about their
connection with cannabis that they you
know some people feel like they kind of
own it and I get that and so the real
value in those two groups in the future
will be what in mathematics is called
the semi VESA kiss which is when the two
circles intersect there's a third little
area right here and that little area is
going to be a very valuable area if you
can communicate with both sides of that
group and if you can create the buffer
zone that's going to be needed for this
industry to expand beyond the simple
division that we've been suffering from
thanks to prohibition and we haven't
done much better it's almost like a
colonial mindset as prohibition mindset
is so ingrained in us that even now as
we get legalization we fight against it
we fight against the mainstream being
involved we fight against it being
allowed on a larger level and we want to
somehow protect our little baby from
getting out of the nest and spreading
her wings and you know touching the rest
of the world and so it's uh it's pretty
it's pretty trippy I think that we're in
for a neat surprise in the upcoming in
the upcoming years of cannabis
prohibition crumbling and falling and
what's going to replace it they're not
going to fall easy they're going to
constantly try to replace it with a more
corrupt version of itself but we've
already crumbled the most corrupt
version of itself so I think that the
foundation will soon follow we have a
very incredible group that is now
willing to say I use cannabis and some
of them are children and some of them
are elderly and some are female and some
are male and all races and all genders
and belief systems and it's incredible
before there were only a certain group
of people who were willing to stand up
and promote the use of cannabis and
those people were looked at it was easy
to make those people look like
degenerates
because we were willing to be arrested
for what we believed in and in society
it's like the laws are supposed to keep
you in the corral so having this group
of individuals who think they can just
do something and not face the
consequences sort of freaks society out
quite a bit however in any sane society
when a law makes no sense whatsoever
it's up to the good people of the
society to stand up to practice civil
disobedience and to not allow them to
you know direct what is right what is
the truth
you know because lies are lies and
that's the [ __ ] that I can see
whatever your truth is if it changes
then change your truth and let people
know but you don't have to lie there's a
lot of line there's a lot of [ __ ] so
I think it's why people I hope it's why
people enjoy these wake and bakes
because I try to be genuine I try to be
myself and I try to be as truthful as I
absolutely can I want to call it for a
very short amount of time we called it
University same-same I took some things
I didn't last very long my college was
psychedelics my college was reading on
my own and between my own psychedelic
use and between my own reading and
absorbing of knowledge and of course
interactions with smart individuals you
know hanging out what is in my life find
out the things you want to get good at
and then hang out with people who are
much better than you at those things so
those are the things that I've practiced
whether it's playing pool whether it's
trying to learn guitar whether it's
isolating resin heads whatever the
things that you're passionate about
driving a dirt bike or a snowmobile or a
snowboard hang out with the best of the
best of that group and you will quickly
learn at an exponential rate of things
that you want to learn about and so
that's kind of even for photography
you know same thing and anyone can do
this it doesn't take anyone special now
the more you pay attention and the more
you focus to what's going on the more
aware you are the faster and quicker
you'll be able to absorb the information
accurately to what it is you're trying
to learn if you're spacing out and
you're not paying attention and you're
the text guy and you're the MTV flash
flash generation you might have a harder
time in focusing and being hyper aware
and being you know notice listening to
what you're learning and then applying
it the way you learned it certain people
are exceptional at it and other people
can't do it to save their lives
it's crazy but for me
it's what it's my thing I try to just
hang out with people who are much better
try to find people that are doing things
that you're inspired by but doing it at
a higher level and you too will climb
quickly
the last run I did of bubble hash jeez
it probably would have been maybe within
the last six months I did a couple of
batches here and there I've done some
batches in the tropics in Jamaica and
I've done a few local batches just
little small batches bigger ones in
Jamaica but soon we'll have some batches
coming soon will have we'll do some some
good video of Jamaica
I don't know if you guys saw that we
made an announcement in Jamaica today
maybe I should read it the announcement
is United cannabis corporation and
cannabinoid research and development
receives approval to begin manufacturing
and distributions of products in Jamaica
and so yeah we've got a prawn a hemp
aromatherapy roll-on capsules and some
bling you'll drop so the first products
registered with Jamaica's ministry of
health so we have the first products
registered with Jamaica's Ministry of
Health I'm going to Jamaica next week
with Tony and we're going to train
doctors on how to use prana and to
prescribe the prana and what it can be
sort of used for so this is very
exciting very huge we're [ __ ] super
excited we have an acre right now that's
looking fairly good in Jamaica and soon
we'll be able to process this into
medicine and plant many many more acres
so we're pretty pretty excited I'm not
gonna lie
we're pretty excited it's gonna be
[ __ ] sweet and so yeah we'll have
some videos from Jamaica hopefully
myself and Tony and I believe Ernie is
going to be there as well one of the
founders of United cannabis and the
current CEO so we're really excited to
be able to show you whatever we can and
show you the vape pens come and Thomas
it should be here at the end of July
we've got less than two weeks left for
that all the packaging they've been
ordered they're currently being
manufactured all the oil and the
terpenes have been produced and ratioed
out and are just waiting for these
applicators and
pens to come in so we can fill them up
and also be available through the
bubbleman brand through Harborside I'm
hoping Berkeley patients group is going
to jump on with an order and I'm sure
some other spots that I'll let you know
as well as weed maps is going to be
getting photographs and links to all the
accurate places like la cush and the
real green dragon to places in LA that
we're processing for right now so we
want to let people know the legitimate
places that our work is going to be
found and we'll be very vigilant in
exposing people who are claiming to sell
stuff from us that is not from us
toaster grow I gave away the karma cup
in today and I gave away the Turk proof
which is basically rosin and PTFE like
sheets probably safer than parchment and
we gave it to mind something nuts I
think he said he came in and said and
the answer is it's the pizza from the
kiln it's definitely made me laugh and I
figured what is a better answer than
that I hate having a contest I hate
making it like seem like we're winning
I'd rather feel like you were chosen and
that you didn't really have to do
anything for it except be you and have
your sense of humor and so that's what
we did how about this for a beautiful
story to finish it off with and I hope
that it's not too personal I don't think
that it is do gee oh gee remember his
father I think it was David pop Pasir
poster his father was on his deathbed
he's passing away now he remembered I
didn't know much about him but I gave
his dad a shout-out well he wrote me
this really beautiful email and he said
hey there bubble man I first want to say
thanks for your kind words I want to
give you a little story to go with my
father's name my father was born in 1947
and got to experience some really neat
times and always loved plants and
flowers he raised me and my brother by
himself and helped me learn and grow
teaching us that honesty respect and
love were the base of our being he did
this by living his life this way every
day cannabis was and will always be one
of his greatest passions more than
cultivation the idea of sharing some
really good herb with the friends that
you kept was the reward
felt that this idea of sharing parallels
to what you talked about with the idea
of plentiful not scarcity he first saw
the Grateful Dead in 67 and at the age
of 8 took me to my first dead show that
was 1992 at Star Lake amphitheater I was
fortunate enough to see them again in
1995 which I'll never forget the Gloria
Encore so we got to experience a lot
together he was diagnosed with chronic
lymphatic leukemia and when I was 12 he
was given three months to a year two
weeks from that day we got a call from a
different doctor who informed him he was
a candidate for a stem-cell transplant
this gave us the last 15 years together
and allowed me and my brother to grow up
having an excellent example of how we
should live aloud and and be and treat
one another everybody is every day is
blessing my name is Jason and I take
value out of your waking baek's and
enjoy the first changing hashed Church
the ever-changing hash Church first
weekend bakes I wasn't working and glad
I got through and hearing you talk about
my father brought me much joy I
appreciate the pin and will wear it with
the cool story of holes I also thank you
for the hash knowledge that in turn will
help me become a better grower the
learning never ends
so how [ __ ] cool is that you know you
step out you do things for a reason and
there are doors that open up because of
it this is the real [ __ ] in life it
seems to be hijacked by you know the
fakeness of creating a person and making
that person famous so that when people
are supposed to be opening doors with
one another the ones they've actually
manifested into their life they get
hijacked by John Travolta or whoever
thinking that that's a person they need
to engage with the people you need to
engage with you would never [ __ ]
guess so Jason I want to thank you bro
for sending me that email it was very
touching teared me up the first time I
read it I'm not gonna lie and it's even
kind of Tears me up when I took when I
read it to you guys it's just a good way
to connect a lot of this Internet a lot
of this you know way of connecting
that's different than in real life and
true face-to-face person this connection
through the internet a lot of it has
been made to be less than and if we can
make it more than by May
sort of a more special connection
connecting with each other a little bit
more than just through a quick little
buzz on a wake and bake video then man
that's [ __ ] awesome puts a smile on
my face inspires me and I know that it
inspires you guys as well that's it
lines incline starts with the pita is
with the beat starts with the breath
ends with the breath probably with the
first beat it's pretty heavy
yeah gently I did I'm not gonna lie
Jah bless you just come in on your
business money of beeswax you just
making it come on cannabis Oregon thanks
for coming in and heading back to work
peace brother like to find a way to
connect this community more than this
also yes Larry Dunnington well the first
way is to be simple don't look at the
huge picture like it you know like start
or locally start within yourself connect
within yourself with the plant learn as
much as you can and then you know
naturally as you start talking about
cannabis you'll connect with people that
you pull into your life and you'll find
the direction that you're supposed to go
in through these coincidences that are
really coincidences and Robert Anton
Wilson has a book he calling the phrase
the coincidence so I don't want to take
any credit for that but it is the
coincidence and you have these
coincidences you will see these
experiences replicating themselves into
your life in different ways where it's
like okay I'm supposed to experience
this this is what's supposed to be
happening it's a great way to lead your
direction if you're really lost and you
don't know what direction you're going
really nice way is to follow the
coincidence you've seen the same person
a stranger in your life three times in
one day okay they're either the DEA
investigating you or more likely they're
a very important person that you've
manifested into your life and vice versa
and you guys are supposed to connect
this is another valuable thing that the
DEA loved to [ __ ] with by taking away
that trust and by creating paranoia
people would manifest people into their
lives and then they would suffer
paranoid delusions that that person was
out there to hurt them and not actually
help them so all sorts of different ways
that they can affect us in negative ways
I'm gonna leave you guys on that note
230 people hanging out in the room I do
appreciate it I think
pretty good one I'm not sure how long it
went but I guess we'll find out when it
stops thank you guys all for coming in
May the full melt bless your Bowls
sooner than later peace out everybody