hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to the
wake-and-bake and as you can see I'm
still clearing the sleep out of my eyes
not really I've been up for hours but
how's everybody doing we got Tara Lee in
the room melty heads and octobe Tom we
got lustre burn and jord eye and master
Olli and hanky boy and big truck driver
I hope everyone's doing well today we're
gonna have a couple of bong rips we're
gonna give away a bottle of Dark Crystal
and maybe we'll have some conversations
some good old conversations as we always
do welcome there Martin Gillis and Kappa
and Julius Corwin and Alex from Quebec
oh good good glad you got your cleaner I
sent out a bunch of stuff yesterday but
I forgot all my bottles of cleaner so if
you're waiting for a bottle cleaner and
hasn't come up yet I still haven't sent
it but I'm going to send it today along
with this new bottle so why don't we get
right to it the video that you're going
to be checking out today is myself and
my sorry about that that was my mentor
Ron Hickey calling me I had to give him
a deny as we are having a wake and bake
here right now so the video was with my
good friend Sara Sunday who does the
karmic up out in Ontario and the video
is called the Karma Cup 2016 it's just
the two of us sitting on my deck on a
beautiful sunny day and we're hitting
some roll some bowls there are a few
different temperatures that you will see
okay that come across the d nail but
what I'm looking for is one of them so
I'm looking for a particular temperature
that's going to come across the D nail
screen you can go through the video and
and just guess and yeah it's so there
you go you guys are already there it is
bingo Lombardi was 645 bingo Lombardi
for the win bingo buddy be ing o be ing
o be ing Oh dark crystal glass cleaner
was its name oh don't forget that I got
a lot of people asking me what is the
name of this the name is Dark Crystal
glass all right so good job bingo let's
get on to it shall we
that's enough of that really now how do
I feel
how does it feel just being next to
elites well it's nerve-racking I mean if
you're sitting next to a pike that cost
someone 50 or 60 racks you have a real
serious level of responsibility if you
will you want to be very careful with
that I remember the last video where we
saw a buddy go pink with the torch on
his seventy thousand US dollar uh yeah
Keegan you know it just came man it just
came
no no issues bringing glass to Jamaica
I've never had an issue bringing glass
to Jamaica ever once Jamaica is pretty
cool when it really comes down to it
let's be honest I don't want to be in
the same room as a 50k pipe my friend
Hilary used to just say no thanks that
she'd be like no no thank you
I'd go to Pastor the big crazy piece and
she'd just be like I am okay don't need
it
yeah that was a tank wasn't it hey there
was another tank I'll do next time we'll
do another one now
there's one with flap four two one where
he does a really good one he puts the he
puts the mothership
Debbie Marcel piece right down on top of
a glass jar like bag like it is crazy so
cool and calm doesn't even look I'm like
after the video shot I'm like looking at
the piece like trying to make sure that
there's no breaks he was just so chill I
guess that's how it is sometimes when
you just don't have any [ __ ] to give if
you have no [ __ ] to give there are no
[ __ ] to giveth that's just how it goes
alright so let's do this shall we
a little bit of a rippy dip in the
morning
ah no I don't think so at all Sean I
don't remember where anyone said you
were useless if you useless if you keep
worthless if you can't do it a fifty
thousand dollar pipe yeah that was a big
one even the secondary hip from that was
wonderful oh right
spilt that again did I I keep spilling
my my little jar full of cleaner there
we go god I love the way this [ __ ]
cleans it's just so nice it's ridiculous
such a nice way to clean the pipe it
really is a bonus
excellent drew and you should be
perfectly happy with your $75 rig
absolutely you know have someone having
a nice rig should certainly not take
away anything from someone's you know
plain and simple rig I mean I Drive a
pretty plain truck and when I'm driving
in Vancouver and I see all these kids
literally kids they're in their 20s
driving around in supercars like
McClaren's and Gallardo z-- and all the
craziest cars you can ever imagine
I feel great for them I'm stoked for
them I never feel bad about myself I
never feel bad about my own vehicle and
that it's not up to par I think to
myself man those kick those guys are in
their 20s and they get to drive a car
like that good for them that's for sure
I try not to do the whole keeping up
with the Joneses thing in life you know
just acquire the things that you want
acquire and don't feel too bad about
other people's acquirements it's like
when I fly I get I fly coach 99% of the
time I don't fly first-class very often
and would be interested in printed
articles on how
HT panelists and Bowman's world
knowledge I'm not too sure grant you
sent me the email I got the email it was
a very nice offer I'm trying to figure
out what I can I can get printed at your
company I'm really not too sure we'll
have to talk about it in in person but
at this point in time I did get your
email and trying to get it returned to
you and I just haven't really been able
to think other than maybe some pamphlets
or flyers I'm not too sure who knows I
like the idea there's a guy well we've
got our own Rob Moore who's been doing
funny cartoons but what I really liked
is these cartoons that I saw that a guy
was doing for Joe Rogan and it's
basically really simple it's the three
or four or two of them sitting around
the table and he's just created a
cartoon of the actual voices so he's
taking they're real voices and he's
putting it into the cartoon I'm gonna
see if Rob Moore can do a little of that
even just some of the most magical
powerful you know 1/2 minute
three-minute things that happen on hash
Church if we could get a cartoon of that
made up and a collection of those
cartoons made up and I'm not looking for
the funny sounds and the like the comedy
aspect of it I think that's great but
I'm talking about something very
different something like that's us in
caricature form talking in the hash
Church panels and sort of you know with
with this breakdown of whatever we
happen to be saying cuz you guys know
the knowledge drops aren't consistent
they happen there are little gems that
get dropped here and there so hopefully
we can ask Rob about that I like the
idea of of getting something like that I
saw these Joe Rogan ones and I thought
this is a great way to share information
it's hard to share a four-hour house
church but imagine like Jessica Hawkins
telling the story about naya first
trying cannabis oil I mean that is yeah
you know it alpha beta you know where
I'm at so I think that would be a cool
idea
I know Rob's not in the room right now
otherwise he would always already be
replying but we'll hit him up and we'll
see what's going on and we'll see if we
can't get some of those
more serious cartoons don't know because
I think it's a great way to share first
of all the knowledge that is being
shared sometimes is very let's say not a
joke it's it's not a joke it's very
serious but it would be nice to sort of
you know paint it up in a way that puts
it into a cartoon so you can get these
serious knowledge drops but at the same
time kind of be watching a little
cartoon I don't know if you guys saw the
one recently where Vice put it up and it
was ninja from die Antwoord word and I
guess he's telling the story of going
over to Kanye West's house and playing
basketball with Drake it's a funny story
they do it all in this cartoon form and
I liked it I thought it was really good
I'd seen a similar thing prior and
someone had even mocked that they had
jacked it from someone else so I'm not
trying to get vice the credit I'm sure
it was someone else's before vice did
this concept an idea but it was pretty
funny it was good it made me think man I
loved the idea of having I would love to
be able to tell a story like that and
then having a cartoonist be able to
produce a cartoon out of it because we
got some hilarious stories I mean the
hashed Church series alone from Sam and
in Juris stories those two guys have
some pretty incredible stories
Todd McCormick has some pretty
incredible stories as does a TA I mean
most of them really just have incredible
stories they're all incredible people so
why wouldn't they have incredible
stories even Dee 420k who's been quiet
lately I can promise you has some really
crazy crazy stories oh yes Charlie
Murphy there you go well Charlie
Murphy's dead r.i.p rest in peace
Charlie Murphy I was happy to puff a
bowl with Charlie and sit one evening
just lucky enough you know it was
through Mark low-keyed he was having his
event the cush cup and he always hired
these guys to come and be there I was
never one to try and meet you know these
guys I would not try to get my way in I
always felt the energy was awkward so I
told mark that I would come with my wife
and we would watch the show and so we
showed up a little bit late we saw the
end of the show of Charlie show and then
Mark was like oh here I'll you know sit
back here it's a little more private and
he had the
little table in a corner and so my wife
and I sat there and it ended up being
Charlie Murphy and his bodyguard who
traveled with him all the time big guy
can't remember his name
sat down with us and it was pretty
[ __ ] cool to have Charlie Murphy at a
table with just my wife and his
bodyguard telling stories you know
telling we kind of got into the true
Hollywood stories and the Chappelle's
Show and and what it was like being
Eddie Murphy's brother in the 80s like
holy [ __ ] Eddie Murphy was our rock star
in the eighties man I'm telling you
maybe late seventies whenever whenever
that stand-up that he did came out I
can't believe I'm brain farting the name
but yeah Eddie Murphy's stand-up I'm
sure someone's gonna put it up right
away but very cool I love it I think
comedy should stay alive I think if
Charlie Murphy came up with that he
should absolutely Eddie Murphy raw there
you go thank you it was kind of paused
out uh you know I'm smoking on a variety
of things I'm just finishing up that
Justin Trudeau Kush actually I think
that's what's gonna go down in the next
ball it's kind of amazing how much was
stuck in this little jar myself one more
little dab there probably gonna go in
for a Terp dip because well I can it's
hard not to when you got the Flav's give
thanks to Tony V for this beautiful
little gift not the terpenes themselves
although thank him for that as well
but this little case with the carabiner
I'm telling you he gave me this one year
in Amsterdam and I kind of remember
maybe it was Barcelona I don't remember
I was watching some of the videos from
2014 and we were talking about you know
we were hitting some of the first Terp
melts some of the first terpenes added
to hashish that I had never known about
anyway you know from that we're going
you know soon to be available I never
tried cannabis profiled terpenes it was
always just single terpenes that were
you know the food-grade ones that I now
really don't suggest to people that they
inhale those into their lungs are you
independently wealthy how do you support
all this how do i sum
all that well that's a very personal
question I guess I am independently
wealthy in the sense that I came to
British Columbia with $6,000 to my name
that's how much money I had when I moved
here and so now I have about $7,000 but
I have a whole bunch of other stuff too
so I worked hard bubble bags was very
good good to me over the years it's been
almost 20 years that we've been selling
bubble bags and yeah man I don't know I
guess it's all what people's versions of
wealthiest when I hear wealthy I always
I mean I obviously feel that if you're
living in North America generally
because I do have you know friends that
have grown up in ghettos if you're
living in North America generally even
the way I grew up which would have been
in
with a lot less cash you still are
wealthy to a degree let's just say you
know if you can afford shoes you know to
some that's wealthy I feel like I did
and still have and em and I do
appreciate you guys for the support
purchasing bubble bags and dry set
screens and all those little tools that
we sell it's definitely been very
helpful
live on SD s SD there we go
work is good do it every day as long as
you can yeah yeah but GABA doe I feel
the same way I'm not very um you know
adverse to working I'm happy to work I
work a lot I'm kind of working right now
alright hey send me that email right
away he who one long bingo
bc bubbleman at icloud.com tricep 270
you for my screens hundred and ten lines
bridge get your screens out who did that
tastes good oh I forgot I dipped it in
Karma's [ __ ] oh my god hey there
Kayleigh mmm I know hanky boy you know
the only reason I kind of haven't or
don't is because it's a pain in the ass
every morning I go live I think of
solvent less mind
we've talked but he said he would come
on but he's probably sleeping in I'm up
early it just doesn't always line up and
so I definitely thought about it this
morning I thought how cool also I've
been doing all of these on my phone
that's really giving me the freedom to
do them as wat as almost anywhere as I
have been doing them because I don't
even need the internet to do them that
being said if I invite a guest on I have
to do it through my computer because
there's no way for me to
and the live link when I go through my
phone it actually is going live through
YouTube and when I go live through the
computer it goes live through Google
live Google chats so I don't know that's
just so firming delicious it's so
delicious it's like a very delicious all
right I'm getting texts from mr. t while
this is going on I think I am going to
be at the Karma Cup this year yes I've
talked to Sarah I have to yet to give
her a solid yes but I'm wanting to go
there I always have a good time at the
karma Cup Sarah does a good job it's a
nice event and I guess you know the
bottom line is she really brings people
out like a lot of people came by a lot
of people checked out my booth it's a
worthwhile experience for you know small
companies like Blue River and the many
others to go there and show their wares
and you know do a decent amount of
business because these trips cost money
you're gonna end up spending close to a
grand on a hotel and maybe close to a
grand on a on a flight so and if you
have to pay for two or three grand for a
booth now you have to do about seven to
eight thousand dollars in business to
make that all pay off now keep in mind
if you did a little bit less even if it
cost you a couple grand there's the
advertising aspect of it the same way
you might do an ad in a magazine going
there if it costs you money at least you
were there you were seen you know you
got people to see what you were all
about so ooh quality hash I'm not too
sure
good morning Abraham all right on to a
cannabis yeah dude well hopefully it'll
be there again and we'll be able to my
booth was super simple it's funny that
you would say it's awesome because
really all my booth was was a table a
little sort of sheet laid down and
and some turps on top with us hidden
bowls so I guess that's just all you got
to do to have an awesome booth I do
appreciate your kindness but we sure
didn't go out of the way and spend too
much money on it did we
well the properly made full mouth hash
will have a dry consistency like sand
even it has a bunch of turkeys Wow full
mouth hash can be made into a sand like
consistency but if it's allowed to yes
I've been to why us Falls if it's a lot
been allowed to get warm it will congeal
and melt into a solid puck for sure
every chance that it can get jaha
freedom in says Allen schanberg it's
nice that Bingle Lombardi won today that
was great to recognize his name um I'm
not too sure no I have not nunya Oh
although I would check out a seeds
they've got the exotics you know like
the Tiger's milk and the what is it
called the the Roja something Roja it's
like the red
oh the Angola Angola Roja as well as
Congolese they've got a whole bunch of
pretty nice exotic cultivars going on
over at a seeds yeah China why I got
some China white right here boom going
in in yeah a seeds I always give those
guys the Angola red yeah I traded some
Angola red I believe it was something
like the bangy haze crossed with the the
Angola Roja the Angola red that produced
the Congo I could be wrong I don't want
to say anything that's wrong but back in
the day quite a while ago when I
originally traded my son bubble bags for
some seeds from Rana Ganga Rana Ganga
was of course married to lamanno negra
and lamanno
who was Alex was the one who collected
the original Congo seeds in Africa that
ended up here in in Vancouver as well as
all the way down the coast in San
Francisco as well I'm not too sure je
cannabis I like a lot of cultivars it's
really hard to say yeah it's a horrible
name for sure Nicholas although you know
I don't have really a big connection to
heroin so it's not quite as bad but yeah
I'm always opposed to sort of like the
chemos and sort of like just the you
know the MKULTRA all sorts of names that
are like man those are like some [ __ ]
up things to be named in that after but
and what are you gonna do hey listen the
wait chimera put it but and I believe it
and I think it's the future as well is
that that the future of cannabis is not
these names that we know them by those
might be secondary
you know tags but really what they are
going to be named is the constituents of
which they are so what is the
cannabinoid profile and what is the
terpene profile those are the two things
that I really want to know now do I need
to know every single one maybe not maybe
initially it'll be just you know the
dominance you know these are the three
dominant terpenes so the cultivar could
be called you know like chimera had here
the other day the pine the lime and the
terpene alene say his didn't have it but
say it had it you could have the top
three or the top two or the top one you
could have dominant terpenes and
dominant cannabinoid profiles and I'm
sure those things now specifically
terpenes especially will show that they
are different in the afghan grown in the
arid dry mountain range compared to the
tropical exotic narrow leaf drug
cultivar that is grown in an extremely
humid area I'm convinced that the
terpene profile will be specific for
each of those areas and that those
terpenes will be specific to say things
like resisting powdery mildew but my
be a specific terpene that allows
cannabis to resist powdery mildew when
it's grown in the tropics versus Afghan
ease that just don't have that terpene
profile and because of it get these
mildews this is just a theory but it's
one that fits in my brain and I could
see it coming true we're going to find
the truth to all of these questions in
the very near future as more and more
people are getting out of school young
people going into university
specifically for jobs in the cannabis
sector
yeah milled out I love when he says that
that's awesome
what a trip life is a hash is so
different - yeah but man's world would
you ever spray terpenes on the plant
um no I would not spray our beans on a
plant you spelled episode oh yeah my
phone actually doesn't weird
autocorrect it does this thing and it
makes it Ella sewed so it's not a big
deal I can I can change it pretty quick
in fact it is already changed Sam's the
man absolutely love the old schoolers
love their stories you know absolutely
till they tell us we're wrong our
theories are perfect this is my favorite
Ella soda yeah this is my favorite Ella
sewed - well no it's not my favorite
Ella so do you remember that Ella sewed
like back about 23 Ellis Oates that one
was a kick-ass Alice ode to real I mean
[ __ ] yeah as far as Ellis ODEs go that
was as solid as an Ellis ode as as I had
ever experienced in an Ellis ode just
saying there's a shock any tips for
starting older seeds yeah you know DJ
short gave me this tip you know I do it
just like ever regular do whatever
you're gonna do your soma method in the
water and your until it sinks or your
your your wet paper towel I like a
couple of plates I put some moist towel
it in i put the seeds down and then i
put it on like my stereo receiver and it
just keeps it this perfect temperature
like not so warm that it dries the paper
towel oh but warm enough
that in it creates that warmth of like
yeah let's crack I cracked 20 year old
seeds that way now if they don't crack
what DJ short said to me is that he's
actually helped them crack with his
fingers he's actually and he's imagine
how gentle you have to be to be able to
do this this kind of goes to show the
level of passion that the man had but
yeah he would just give it a gentle
gentle pinch until the tip popped open
or until he saw a slight crack and yeah
he's just cracking seeds with his hands
I never was forced to do it but it's a
great tip from a guy who had a lot of
old seeds back before I really knew
anyone who had a lot a lot of old seeds
well Jay Henrik's short DJ short has you
know saved some nice genetics doing it
so it's a last resort but if you have to
do it if it's not going to crack
normally because what I said was if you
listen to me try it all normal first and
if that doesn't work then you can give
it a little help that's it
DJ short he told me that while we were
spinning a batch of bubble hash in a
school bus that Marc Emery had rented
and was driving around the city of
Vancouver not really it was leaving MPC
or whatever CC HQ or the other million
names it's had ever since and it was
going to a restaurant for the tokers
Bowl but it seemed like it was driving
around downtown Vancouver for a while
and me and DJ were mixing up the
medicine I had the five gallon bucket
started it actually in Marc's store in
the basement at Pot TV but then we're
like everyone we gotta go and I'm like
alright well this is the beauty of water
hash it's portable so I picked up the
bucket with the water in the bud and the
ice and I just carried it on to the bus
and we sat in the two front seats and we
just gave it a spin 'man min and I
remember we let it settle on the ride
from there to getting to the restaurant
and when we got to the restaurant we
pulled the bags and collected the hash
so Wow very cool I don't know if there's
there has to be footage of that
absolutely now I don't know who would
have it I was making hash so I didn't
have my cash
and we were it was definitely a little
bit before the time where we were like
always had someone filming us so I would
suspect someone who was at the tokers
Bowl either the O 3 or the O 4 tokers
Bowl might have footage of that um was
Mark Emma and I friends I'm not too sure
about that I've known mark a long time I
guess I could innocent you know we've
never really gone to dinners he's always
invited I think it was been a more
professional relationship you know I
mean I would call him a friend in the
sense that you know I I appreciated what
he was doing in the community back in
the day for all the money he was
donating to people that were getting in
trouble for growing his seeds and his
store was really cool he was donating
all the money wasn't keeping it he was
just putting it back putting it into the
activist hands and promoting events and
he was just kind of doing cool [ __ ] so I
liked him in that sense but he was
always more business you know I wrote
for the magazine four years so he was my
editor as well as Jodie was my editor
after that yeah dot see a is canada.com
is America for blue river extracts so
yeah we still got a great sale going on
over at blue river extracts dot CA it is
lyft 2017 is the code and you will get
$50 off each vial yeah that me and Dee
420k are good broast absolutely I love
that that love that guy [ __ ] hanging
out with Dee is awesome
we've just been pushed in the opposite
directions for the last little bit but
I'll get him on here again soon that is
blue river us opening into order I don't
know sticks I don't believe so check the
website yeah check the website and I
moved to Canada dude I don't know Sam
you got to contact them I don't know
Anthony you got a card listen this is a
I see that there's there's some customer
service that
has that is not getting done because
blue river extract CA gets a lot of
calls a lot of emails and a lot of
people in my social media asking me
about blue river extracts us I think
blue river extracts us has made it
pretty clear but you guys might want to
put a phone number up if you're still
watching Michael so people can contact
you and ask you these questions because
you might not see it but what they're
doing is they're asking me these
questions and I can promise you it's
taking up like time in my life I get a
lot of phone calls actually from from my
website about it and yeah I don't know
just figure it out guys very clear they
are only bit in only
business-to-business now okay well great
so that's it I mean if that's it that's
it it's as simple as that still I would
put up a phone number with someone just
saying that or even an answering machine
because people look they can't get it
from just that they look at the website
they look what do you mean not selling
anymore does that mean they're not
selling they want to ask the question so
I don't know for me for my company I
would have like a phone number up with a
recording if I didn't want to answer it
so people could also hear it we're no
longer selling you know person-to-person
we're only doing business-to-business
so any tips on pressing the eater out of
the puck of hash before I sieve it the
eater would that be the moisture what
are my views on psychedelics well I like
them a lot I think they're great I think
that it's nice that people can go inward
instead of outward I guess it's a
business as someone that would be
purchasing wholesale probably but once
again if they had a phone number these
are things that although they have a
website I'm sure you can email them info
at and ask them that very question or
you guys could just continue to hit me
up on my social media while we're doing
a wake and bake I guess it's up to you I
guess it's what depends on what you want
to hear most of how much would you
typically process in a one-gallon versus
a five-gallon bag
well 56 grams is the maximum dry that I
would put in a one gallon 200 grams dry
as the maximum I put it in a 5-gallon 56
DRI is close to 200 grams wet and 200
grams dry is around a thousand grams wet
but I like to do it around 800 fresh
frozen 800 grams into a five-gallon
bucket
200 grams fresh frozen into a one gallon
bucket so it's pretty simple about four
times the the weight of dry will be
fresh do you tip at a restaurant in
Canada yes chase 20% always and every
time servers work hard unless the
service is absolutely horrible and the
food is [ __ ] even then I still have a
hard time not doing it yep that's right
melty heads what's your fave dabbler at
the moment my fave dabbler I'm not sure
what that even means hey how's it going
from Korea what's the difference between
the effects of low temp dabs and a vape
like a volcano well they're very
different they're just very different
ones like light ones very light you know
like a one course and ones very heavy
like a seven-course does fresh frozen
get dry at all when it's in the freezer
it can it can especially if it's allowed
like you know the freezer sometimes can
act as a desiccant and pull moisture out
of things
Nate sizzle good name good name sticks
that would be up to you they're
certainly not illegal at the border but
I just sell them here in Canada I'm not
have you seen that guy Alex free-climb
I'll cut Mountain in four hours yeah I
saw Alex Honnold free-climb El Cap it
was unbelievable
pretty insane really insane actually
it's kind of like wow dude no safety no
ropes no nothing just going for it it's
like I'm glad people like that exist
though I gotta say it's amazing it's
it's inspirational really right I mean
who doesn't watch that and think
I'm a human I should be able to do human
[ __ ] like that although I'm pretty sure
that's not human [ __ ] even if you've
ever looked at his fingers they're just
like these huge sausages I think they
can probably hold an insane amount of
weight compared to most people's fingers
no we're still far away from it we're
still far away from legalizing cannabis
axel monster hey what's going on from
the Kootenay z-- what's going on Nikola
gamer so you think Puff Wednesday's are
done for now well I mean for now you
know maybe let's say we're not it's not
like we've retired it forever it's just
not happening if it's just started
happening you know if John's got his
life on track right now he's super busy
as businesses growing he's got his
girlfriend they moved in together plus
he's got all his channel and all the
other you know clean stuff that he's
constantly doing that's new and then I
myself am at least that busy and more
because I have three children etc etc so
between the two of us we got so busy I
think when I first met John he had the
most time out of anyone he was retired
he just he got his pension from getting
hurt and he didn't have to do anything
he had literally seven days a week to do
whatever he wanted to do and so that's
when he started hanging out with me four
or five days a week he would come we
would film all the time he just had
nothing else to do but since we started
doing that filming he has become an
incredibly busy gentleman so good for
him is right fucking-a I'm not too sure
no I do not suggest dry ice dry ice is
the worst thing you could do stay away
from dry eyes dry ice is not your friend
it's going to make it look like you get
a lot but that lot that you get is less
head and more contaminant it's
counterintuitive it's convincing you one
thing while the reality is saying
another and it's going to make cleaning
that material even harder when you try
to get out just the heads and even if
you just press it it still ends up
getting this weird funky darkness to it
from the contaminant that you're
pressing along with the
heads I'm not a huge fan of live resin
myself I think that I've always
appreciated bud that was properly cured
and that bud that's popularly cured is
not just the plant matter releasing
moisture but it's the resin glands
releasing extremely caustic terpenes
that evaporate and volatize first prior
to any of the other ones they're the
ones that are we are burping out of the
weed in the curing process and i like
them to be out of my hash as well so i
prefer a nice strong hash that smooth on
the throat but still gonna grab me by
the nuts and yeah that's that's what i
like good luck with your event korean oh
I didn't hear about what event the
Korean dude was talking about but yes
good luck if we're giving good luck good
luck I like to inhale agree Wow poke at
a tanks tanks THC exams blowing hash
clouds towards everyone what about 194
shark shock was tasty - thumbs up for to
tears down yeah that's true grabs you by
the booboo yes Ryan Portugal it can and
will sometimes grab you by the booboo a
full screen hash reg I'm not even sure
what that means a full screen hash rig
you can go to bubble bag calm if you're
looking for hash tools dude how about
I'm still waiting for scale down and
indre to test the terpenes how long has
it been since those guys said they were
gonna test those terpenes that is a test
that I wanted to see because I think it
would be interesting yeah [ __ ] rights
Jordan G we give discounts for medical
users but I'm going to try and come up
with a discount in the very near future
so maybe like a 10 or 15% to offer
something something to give away to the
chatroom because hey it'd be cool to see
they still haven't all right yeah yeah
peace out for the wakin Baker's someone
said world bong rep motherlover
D for 20k voice yes grant welding come
say hi and given high if you come on do
you like the one years with John are
what hasn't work sent it through the NMR
I'm not too sure I'm sure they're gonna
figure it out for sure they have to I
mean they have to you can't come in and
tell us you've extracted terpenes that
have never before been extracted and
then not get them tested just get them
tested we just want to see what they are
I'm like super excited to see what they
are I don't doubt him at all
but I want to see the test you know yes
it does J cannabis yeah
sasquatch Terps yeah I should have Remo
unawakened baked maybe I can go over to
his house one of these days he's usually
up pretty early what's the discount for
medical patients well alpha-beta you
contact
oh the met that discounts like 25
percent off but you have to contact just
phone 186 six melting and or info at
bubble bag calm and just ask them I
think they require a card or some sort
of thing but they'll let you know
they're friendly I have been on Ramos
channel a few times that's for sure is
good good people over there very good
people absolutely Sean it is now if you
want to be a real youtuber you need
drone footage that's funny well I've got
drone footage I haven't pulled my drone
out for a while because I didn't feel
like people wanted to see the same old
drone footage over and over again which
is really you know what a lot of my
drone footage would be at this point you
really need to take a trip and go
driving and spend a day with a bunch of
different batteries and chargers so you
could go out and you know get some
really epic drone footage some b-roll if
you will that you could take later
and cut into your videos I myself am an
idiot and I just do it all the same day
I get all the footage that day I do all
the editing that day I film everything
it's it's completely insane and it
becomes difficult as you can see these
live videos are much easier
the filmed edited videos are much harder
I think some of its pretty cool
absolutely
yeah but Chrisman or you could become a
business and buy wholesale fill a niche
because you see all these people want to
buy these turps but can't buy them why
don't you go buy a huge wholesale batch
from them and then start selling them
through your own portals you know rather
than you know don't let an obstacle
remain an obstacle turning into a
opportunity I am not sure about that you
look extra medicated in your eyes well
maybe I am maybe you talked [ __ ] you
stupid [ __ ] really I don't even know if
you know what you're talking about how
about we just do this it's called be LOC
k BL OC k if you say it really fast
block it comes out block you're gone
you're out zero tolerance on the bubble
man channel we have zero tolerance for
negativity you must remain positive hey
what's going on from Japan it's nice to
see some people coming in from other
places posting some other languages
that's pretty cool I wish that I could
speak your language so I could reply to
you or at least if YouTube would
translate it to me
yeah block the negatives that's what we
got to do you know what I wouldn't even
say call her that because I always think
of them as just like not know sex
they're just they're just trolls you
know what I mean if they could be they
could be a man
a hermaphrodite anything else in between
they're just trolling it has nothing to
do with their sex that's for sure I
built log homes in Japan on hash that's
nice can you do the troll stump the
troll stump hecklers yeah well hey we
must be getting popular if we get if
we're getting our our our hecklers in
the house yeah there you go another
troll slain yes well listen this was fun
it was great but I think I should
probably call it a day here alpha beta I
would always go with the originals
they're their warrantied for life
5-gallon is the basic midsize one is
very small 20s fairly big five is a nice
middle zone eight bags obviously all the
bags always never not all the bags and
blow some bubbles eh well I will I will
be blowing some bubbles on my way out of
here while I say hasta LaVista or I
guess I'll finish it off the way I
always do not with the bowl but with
maybe the full melt bless your bowl
sooner than later peace out everyone