hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to the
wake-and-bake episode number 72 we are
one away one show away from giving out
some bubble bags that is gonna be pretty
cool let's see if we got this thing
going on oh there we go
there we go Jordy and bingo Lombardi
Mitchell O'Brien and Kayleigh Cal two
jeroni sorry about that guys I had to
reset not sure if the chat is going to
actually open up trying to get it
opening up on my page here let me just
go back wake-and-bake
episode 72 bubble man's world I'm gonna
have to go and find there we go oh
there's two of them I see there we go I
was on the old one there I am look at
that now I can see the chat and
everything's moving beautifully and
hello everybody I hope you're all doing
really good today I'm sorry that it
didn't notify you Scott I hear a lot of
people complaining about that and I
really don't know what to do about it I
am a little bit later today about an
hour what's up getting peel Julius Chad
blind country boy celestial gardener
George Malone full mouth bingo bill a
Jani cycle Berta Fetty Rose Scott
Mackley stinky bomb try to say hello to
everyone but there's a lot of you in the
room at any given time alright so we're
gonna do a quick little wake and bake
today I'm probably just a little puff or
two gonna give away a bottle of the DC
Dark Crystal cleaner it's gonna be a
real easy one real easy one so get ready
you're not gonna have to go to a video
okay I want to know for the first person
that can answer this correctly okay yeah
what's good sticks with Terps I'm the
pumpy oh I don't need to remind you guys
that I'm the pump and you all are on the
inside okay remember who's correct in
all of this the pump is correct look at
these guys answering ready what I want
to know about oh thank you being a
little Barbie I know whoever won the
other day it was his second time winning
testicle is the answer actually cannabis
with the wind just joking the answer is
okay
jeopardy style what country is dark
crystal glass cleaner made in what
country I'm looking for the country if
you can tell me the country Oh
melty heads melty heads with the win
melty heads with the win that's Canada I
have a feeling next melty heads one
already but hey you know what if I ask
you guys not to guess and you continue
to guess I'll just keep sending your
[ __ ] and the people in the room can can
can either let you know hey please stop
guessing or hey that's awesome that
you've won nine times but today melty
heads is the winner Canada Canada is
where that [ __ ] is made so send me an
email melty heads with your contact info
bc bubbleman at icloud.com and yeah I
said jeopardy style but I haven't
watched jeopardy in like 18 years I
don't have cable TV and I don't watch
game shows so you'll have to deal with
it the way it came out and in the mean
time maybe we will have a little rip
just because she's better at winning
than you I'll be more than happy to send
it that's awesome
yes congratulations to all those who
have won over the course of the last 40
or 50 days I was going to be giving away
one of Dana Larson's books I guess I'll
probably do that for Canada Day July 1st
he's got the cannabis in Canada history
it's cartoon I'm in it myself with my
old partners but he's offered to give
away a bunch of those books the only
problem is the reason I didn't give one
away today is because I went to my
bookshelf and I couldn't find my copy
he's going to be shipping it he's going
to be signing it but I want it to still
be able to hold one up and show it to
you so I'm probably gonna have to go see
Dana in the next couple of days and get
get a couple of his copies of his books
so I can show them what do you say to
that Ella sewed 73 yes Ella sewed 73
will be coming
up in the very near future it's gonna be
a really kick-ass Ellis ode I'm telling
you they'll be nothing like it well
that's some pretty greasy greasy right
there it's color on that stuff - Jesus
Christ
borderline orange gang gang bubble
what's up there Kelly thank you thank
you YouTube has been acting weird
where's the syrup I don't know Michael M
I'm waiting for the syrup I'm waiting
for the xylitol sugars I'm waiting for
the Terps I'm waiting to support blue
river in any way shape or form that I
can and that's been a while since Blue
River has Canada has it as ordered
anything new we still of course have of
our absolutely fire sale on for those of
you $50 off each vial so if you buy
three vials you get a hundred and fifty
dollars off your your price and that's
over at Blue River extracts dot CA if
you want to do some wholesale if you're
a company that wants to you know add you
know create your own pens or do a
distillate mix or whatever there's
really no better company than Blue River
down in the US and you can hit them up
at Blue River extracts calm and I think
they have an email up there you can get
in touch with Michael who's in the chat
room right now and they'll uh they'll
hook you up with some wholesale action
all right so let's do a little rip here
shall we
let's do a little rip maybe we'll have a
guest would you guys like to have a
guest would you like to have someone
just show up here at my house and just
get guest on the show could happen it
could happen better turn the other bomb
on just in case I've heard my dog bark
and that's usually the sign of a guest
making their way towards the studio now
who could it be who could my guest be
could it be my mother
could it be my wife is it Johnny B I
don't know I don't know is it D 420k I
don't know is it my mom should my mom
come and be on one of these shows anyway
let's hit this like paronto roll oh it's
Batman
it is Batman Tony Tony Tony just flew up
I'd be awesome y'all seem to have any of
those guys show up I'd love to have Ron
show up yeah all right let's do this
everyone hope you got your your rigs
ready we're ready to wake the bake to
bake the wake actually
I like to get the giveaway out of the
way I like to not be puffing 10 bowls
and then have to see who won I kind of
like to get it given away prior but I'm
not saying that I wouldn't consider it
Tommy chunk is amazing I just don't have
a relationship with him that way
I'm not quite sure that I would have the
ability to get him going that same way
yummy
do you like bubble caps you'll have to
be a little bit more what kind of bubble
cap are you referring to what is this
bubble cap you are Bon Apetit we have an
episode of hashed Church about the
annual cannabinoid system yeah I'd
probably have to invite some people that
are a lot more knowledgeable on me
perhaps at the doctor Bob or a David
Allen I'm always wanting to link with
these guys by the way it's not easy I
invite David Allen on to hash Church
weekly
he doesn't have the connections he
doesn't have the proper computer to come
on and actually be a part of it dr. Bob
himself even comes in on a phone which
is always a little bit rough oh did we
lose the video did we lose the video I
think we did lose the video ah okay
we're back not sure why we lost the
video the connection says it's solid on
my part hope everyone's doing well okay
good good good yes I always want to make
sure that I'm not wasting my time and
talking to nobody what screen should I
but should I press - umm stick with
Terps I would say get some screens that
would allow you to clean the kief I
think the real valuable lesson is in
learning how to clean that sift and not
taking the lazy man's way out and
pressing it into Ross and now don't get
I love rosin and it's wonderful and it's
fun but don't you think you should have
some of that sift cleaned to a 99.9%
degree so you can actually understand
what the quality of that is oh the
bubble cap for the thermal Bangor I
don't personally have one but I've hit
it I like it I think thermal bangers are
pretty cool I could see myself getting
one in the near future but I'm not gonna
run out and try to get to get one any
time soon we'll see if it comes to me
we'll see what happens I don't think
that's bad Geordi your system you know
keep in mind the endocannabinoid system
regulates biological functions and
taking a [ __ ] and eating are both
biological functions so the fact that
you're regulating them with cannabis
isn't overly surprising I wouldn't feel
too bad about it the real worry would be
potentially being away from cannabis and
affecting your day by not being able to
stimulate your appetite and your bowels
I would suggest taking orally cannabis
extract in a coconut oil or something
that is easier on your system but you
can take daily and micro doses building
up to larger doses not necessarily for
the effects but for this system
regulation that's going to be a little
bit more above and beyond maybe what you
get from a DAB or a puff so always good
to cover both bases puffing is great it
got us where we are today but I think
that it's very important to know thank
you melty heads just got your your shot
of course we'll give you a shout out
Scott Dunlop is in the room I want
everyone to say what's up to Scott give
him some love show them that we're good
people in these wake and bakes we're
happy to give people shout outs we're
not here to bust on people's balls we
might have a little bit of comedy here
and there and sometimes my sarcastic dry
humor might offend you but you know what
shout out to Scott Dunlop and I hope
you're having a great day dude I hope
you're having a great day you got a
hundred and forty-three people all
thinking about you all giving you the
what's up Scott dizzle what's up what it
is
Scott wish it is that's just nice you
know this is all we want this is the
connection that people are looking for
they want to be seen they want to be
heard and they want to be loved we all
have that in common
it's interesting that the guy who would
connect us through this interweb of
connectivity Steve Jobs just happens to
be the person who is the most
disconnected or was the most
disconnected from his actual family from
his parents giving him up for adoption
right up to him you know in his own
words in his books not really
recognizing the importance of spending
time with his children towards the end
of his life and just making some bad
decisions it's so strange that he would
be the person that would set up this
link that everyone would connect through
on these computers and phones and in the
meantime he was unable to create true
meaningful relationships outside of
outside of work hey what's going on big
squirrel nuts I love to say hi to big
squirrel nuts mostly just for his name
alone but the avatar also shows a dude
that I think I would get along with I
picture me in big squirrel nuts having a
blast sitting by a fire doing some dabs
and beheading off on some bikes
afterwards motorized ones of course yeah
yeah that's true Sal hello from San
Diego California mines inclined
saludos saludos Scott that's deep job
was the only one link in the chain of
thousands who made the things and did
the work yeah I'll tell ya squirrel
testicles KTM footage there's a little
bit of KTM footage on my website here
YouTube you can go check it out I think
one of the videos is called I don't know
if I named it Broome Ridge I'll have to
go back and if you punch in KTM
dirtbiking bubble man into Google you
should come up with the videos that I
have up there okay this may be kind of a
dumb question but if bubble doesn't turn
out as clean as I want it what is the
best way to go about cleaning it can you
use screens or just press it to rosin
okay so I'm not sure if what you're
talking about is actually cleanliness or
quality because sometimes the quality is
not there and so even when you purify it
to 99.9% heads it might come across as
dirty or not clean when really it's as
clean as clean can be but the quality is
not there now there's the other side of
the coin where the actual cleanliness
has not been achieved but that's rare
especially if its water hash because
water makes this almost
like a no-brainer everything syncs
everything floats heads syncing
everything else floating creating a
transfer chamber of sorts that really
allows for almost even a monkey to be
able to mix up a batch I could come
along and pull the bags and they would
be isolated down near to 99.9% now of
course there are mistakes that you could
make you could use too little of ice you
could over mix you could beat dry
material into powder and have the little
pieces not have the proper amount of
surface area that would allow for it to
float in water and it'll be affected by
gravity and sink and contaminate your
final product but those are two very
different things
Oh is Jordan not being being a good dude
or what for a million dollars would you
do a porno yeah we'll put him in a put
him in a timeout there for a second all
right so yeah that's kind of the
difference right there bubble hash water
hash is almost a no-brainer it's going
to make a very clean product for you
purity is what you're looking for with
bubble hash dirtiness can be cleaned
over screens you could rerun it through
the bags and float it in water there
must have been a reason that you I have
tried CBD crystals
do you like crystalline I like the idea
that crystalline in masoom purity when I
see a crystalline structure I'm not sure
why the people who are growing the
really beautiful crystals of CBD and THC
are smashing them into powder because
once it's into the powder of course
we've seen a variety of different colors
some are almost yellow some is like
white white white I'd like to see it in
the in the crystals just because it
implies purity hello good morning Sun
grown trichome hope you're having a
great day blended in first set of bubble
bags in high school oh my god sir smokes
a lot oh I had a few of those let me
tell you just blending and then pouring
the soup through and they're wondering
what did I do wrong and then also maybe
not the best material to you know it's
because I'll tell you the people who
have the best material their
consciousness is already at a level
where they know not to throw that into a
blender
and zip it all up you know what I mean
that's more like the fear and scarcity
mentality of I don't want to lose any
and in the beginning when people were
first putting their material into water
and I second I can assure you they were
tripping out they didn't think it was
real and they thought I'm gonna lose a
lot so they would over mix you know some
guys actually got an outboard motor like
an electric trolling motor to mix their
material up with just turned it into
soup definitely not the good idea I
could do it with a spoon and a lot of
ice and get just as beautiful of an
extraction from both my yields and of
course my purity dabbing on reclaim that
sounds wonderful
I bet you were luster bird imagine how I
felt the first time I threw eight ounces
of dry sift into into one any tips
running 20 gallon bags well you know 20
gallon bags that's a lot of water I
usually when I run 20 gallon bags I run
multiple sets of 20 gallon bags I love
having all the bags inside of one
another I mix in the machines but I also
use an all screen 220 bubble now bag I
put a lot of ice to make sure that the
temperature has been achieved that's one
of the most important factors ice ice
ice and more ice
it usually melts in the mixture and as
long as you're hearing that crushing of
ice you know that the that it's
happening proper mixing trim versus
mixing bud is very different as you get
larger amounts of bud or plant matter
into larger amounts of water you have to
really be careful that you're achieving
your sweet spot in your threshing ratios
you want the threshing to be perfection
so the amount of water versus the amount
of plant matter and the plant matter
variables are going to matter whether
they're thick strong buds whether
they're loose tiny little sugar leaves
or a mixture of the two those these are
more things that are very difficult to
teach and to put into words because they
change much the same way you know when
we drive the resin and depending on
where you are if you're in Arizona or if
you're in Washington those are two very
different places once dry and arid and
ones wet and humid and so drying the
hash is going to be different and then
in between those two differences are
also very little bits and changes so you
can see there's certain things in the
water hashing process that it's kind of
like you have to learn by making little
mistakes and how you do it as you either
go past or go under and then get closer
and closer and closer you hone in on
that sweet spot that is going to be
sitting in between your two points but
I'm not exactly sure where it will be
sitting in between your two points so
there's that I think that was some
pretty good information right there
definitely you know that's the problem
with people trying to give advice on
this hash making thing there are a few
points where you can take the basics but
once you get to the few points you you
have to really go and make your own
mistakes right on Mitchell O'Brien glad
you're using those bags what's your
weight for 20 gallons I usually run nine
hundred to a thousand grams after the
machine seems to be slowing yeah nine
hundred grams
dry through four thousand plus grams
fresh frozen and it's just all about
your thrashing how long you thrash for
you know we don't Thresh trim as long as
we try Thresh bud four trim is very
quick and I can wash trim in one to
three minutes one to three minute wash
is on really tightly grown oh geez or
cookies is not going to give you your
yield you might get a really small
percentage of something awesome but I'm
more inclined to get the majority of my
yield in the highest purity that I can
in my first batch I don't want to be you
know going back and forth and having to
run the material three or four times
that's not efficient that's why you
don't over stack your bags if you over
stack your bags the heads aren't able to
fall they get captured in the material
that's plugging up the hole and then you
have to re wash multiple times to get
all the resin out you can use a couple
of like a half pound dry in that
5-gallon bubble washing machine paint
stirrer is too aggressive yeah area if
you really have to do something like
that even a little cake mixer with the
two little pieces I made fire bubble
with those four years nowadays I use the
spoon because I can really get around
everything and then of course the bubble
now once I saw the washing machines and
how well they spin I loved the fact that
they spin everything to the left and
then they spin everything to the right
and they just continue to do that and
that's a really good process of having
it go one way stop and go the other way
I'm certain that there's an enormous
amount of resin loss and falling
happening in that process of where it
turns and stops and then starts going
the other way
there's going to be some sort of force
that has felt in there and of course the
ice
smashing back and forth and the
glandular trichomes head's being
extremely brittle and cold it's pretty
sweet pretty sweet
well we gave a bottle away of dc-8
cleaner as it was made in Canada thought
that would be a real easy question today
so I will get that off to you melty
heads thank you for sending me your
address I now have like four or five
packages once again that I need to go
send up so I'm probably gonna go deal
with this now maybe gonna put the boat
in the water today I got it all off a
little bit of interior work needs to be
done hopefully my son can get down there
and clean it but otherwise everyone have
a great day if I go live from the boat
later I will see you then otherwise can
you talk about the difference between
all the bad companies bum bags bolt ice
track well bolt and ice strap extract
came after bubble bags I don't believe
they have paid for reinhardt's patent so
they would both be in the breach of
patents and then I don't really know how
much they've been teaching everyone how
to make bubble hash for the last
eighteen years I feel that I'm a little
bit higher on the podium but the
beautiful thing about being a customers
you yourselves get to choose who you
want to support if you do support me I
do appreciate it and if you don't I'll
still be here for you
when those companies are unable to offer
the same level of customer service that
I do and if you need a question answered
whether you got bolt bags or ice extract
bags or whoever's bags I'm happy to help
you out I just want people making more
water hash and up until the point that
it actually starts to affect my business
I'm not going to be too worried about it
so thank you everybody for the support
and we'll talk to you guys soon may the
full melt bless your bowl sooner than
later peace out everybody