oh yeah right on there we go welcome
everybody welcome to bubble man's world
welcome to the wake-and-bake episode 68
in the house and today we're going to
give away something a little different
we're gonna give away an MTG hat it's uh
grow big or grow home I kind of left
this hat I had one myself that fit
perfect I lost it in Jamaica in Kingston
I remember driving in this guy's car and
we had all the windows open at one point
my hat blew off inside his car and it
went right to the back of the car not
the back seat but the back and I was all
excited getting dropped off at a buddy's
house in Uptown Kingston we were gonna
go dirtbike riding which I made a video
of and it's on bubble man's world anyway
I never went back and got the Hat so I
lost it so I'm gonna give this one away
today it doesn't fit me it's a 7 and 3/8
all right 7 and 3/8 this means don't
guess the answer if your head is way
bigger or way smaller I mean unless you
just really kind of want to have but I'd
love to see this hat go to someone that
actually fits their head Keegan
someone like Keegan or someone else
whatever I'm good to go with whoever
wants to win it and the question is
gonna be simple I want you to understand
that the question I'm looking for a
specific meaning that if you abbreviate
if you use a different term if you don't
say exactly what I said in the video
that I'm about to link you with it's not
gonna be a win so those of you whose
size hat this is alright alright alright
I know it's gonna be impossible to get
everyone else to stop guessing as well
but I really would be disappointed if
someone wins this hat and it's it's you
know under a in a box under a desk
somewhere much like this one's been
sitting for probably over a year now so
I'm about to tell you what the video was
off threat the video that we are looking
for today is called Marcel X Debbie fab
egg Debbie is spelt with 2-piece you
should be able to find that on bubble
man's world it has thirteen thousand
four hundred and
the six views and within the first
minute of the video in the first minute
of the video I pull out a white little
tub with some something-something in it
I want to know what's in it
I want to know the name and I want to
know the micron so anyone that is going
to put up that will win this hat and
then we'll get ourselves wake-and-bake
tear what do you say all right let's do
this
he's got the poutine on the J rolled I'm
firing it up I'm firing it up
yes David T with congolese 90 micron
bingo you were close but you said Congo
and I wanted the specific name that I
said Congolese ninety micron that's
that's what it is it's the Congolese
mighty Niekro ninety micron dave is the
winner
yeah Dave if you want to give me an
email at BC bubble man at icloud.com I
will send you this beautiful hat yes I
will send you this beautiful hat so
there's that we've given away something
why don't we get now to the puffing had
the West Coast guys well the East Coast
guys I guess they're the East Coast guys
now they got their new packaging here if
he goes around Toronto they brought some
Larry lemon Larry og flower rosin which
was okay pretty pretty nice you know a
little bit dark for my likes but that's
okay they also brought me their
distillate I'm not a distillate guy but
they wanted me to check it out and I was
probably gonna do a little experimenting
with adding some turps to this I won't
be puffing on it but we'll see what my
friends think and so that is their
distillate right there quite clear
almost no color to the west coast East
Coast distillate and there is that oh
yeah they also sent me this little bit
of butter rosin which is also very nice
it's very barely sitting on there so it
could slip off so we have all sorts of
lovely options for puffing this morning
yeah west coast of good guys I met with
Jim Ian and Brett from West Coast
yesterday and we had a nice little
conversation and it was good to see
those guys because they've been out on
the East Coast for the longest time oh I
don't really smoke chemical solvent
extracts myself
I'm not a big distillates BHO hexane
propane guy okay Josh Warner see you
later have a good one but at the same
time I would sure fight for someone's
right - presumably there is no solvent
list distillate well that's correct in a
sense most so all distillates that I
know of are washed with solvents like
ethanol or something and then run
through short paths molecular
distillation units the problem is is if
it's been sprayed with pesticides you
can't get them out what's going on Brad
kay oh look at that I got some torch
torch action here
here's your best dry sniff tip
I don't know man get great material I
mean it couldn't be better than that
use exceptional material I couldn't give
you a better dry sip tip than that
honestly like that is as accurate as it
gets
don't bother [ __ ] around the garbage
it's just a waste of time energy and not
worth it really
most distillate is made from complete
garbage Wow let's just be honest a lot
of distillate is made from complete
garbage not all of it but a lot of it is
I've known a lot of people that you know
trying to get that prohibition dollar
back out of cannabis as cannabis was
lowering the price and as we were
getting these great prices you know the
oil game stepped right up and said hey
guess what we'll still take those
prohibition prices and it's still pretty
high up there but luckily you know once
people start making this on a larger
agricultural level we'll have the price
go down obviously it's not going to be
this expensive forever I'm sure some
people would love it to be but um it's
just not gonna be the case there's too
many options all right what am I looking
for I'm looking for one of my glass
there we go give thanks to nish give
thanks to the space walk
think I'll rock the space walk right now
all right
silicone gel filters sharks for real
good morning Samuel good morning I'm
about to make some sausage gravy and
biscuits as chaser figgins all right
well we won't keep you we shan't keep
you wake and bake guys
yeah Tyler he's a cutie
it was really amazing that he let me do
it I I spent 12 hours with him yesterday
at the beach and all over the place and
we had a great time nothing better than
you know spending time with the youth
such amazing inspirations all right four
completely white heads one gram dad one
gram Deb oh my god I couldn't think of
something more waste worthy than taking
one grab dab right now but I will take a
nice little rip of this who is it master
kosher Paula Piera Paul piera is the
strain on that one and the other
cultivar was oh yeah the lemon Larry the
lemon laude all right hey it's not a
waste if you love it and it's for you
and you want it I just I'm not I have
zero interest in taking one gram Debs
like zero maybe when I was 17 I'd have
been all over that [ __ ]
lemon Larry for the win
let's get our dabs up shall we everybody
to talk a little bit about what's going
on in there in the community these days
you know as they want to legalize
decriminalize whatever you want to call
it yes 800 grams Keegan
that's not dry no why don't you go on
the website because you're gonna [ __ ]
that up the website says everything the
dry weights are very simple 56 grams for
if 1 gallon 200 grams for a 5-gallon
1,000 grams for a 20 gallon so those are
dry weights now you multiply by 4 or 5
those dry weights to get the weight of
fresh frozen that you would run in the
same size kit so you're confusing the 5
gallon wet fresh frozen with dry so it's
very important not to confuse those
numbers because Wow can that ever [ __ ]
you up and I don't want you to have have
a [ __ ] up there like that yeah chat does
move pretty quick well that's right you
heard it backwards but I for sure
probably did not say it backwards cuz
well this is just one of those things
that are I don't really I just know it
it's like ingrained in me I know it like
I know anything oh yeah I've been
watching that as well track home city
if you don't have anything positive to
say sometimes it's best not to say
anything at all
Mark's very opinionated he's got strong
opinions and I guess he said some
negative things about the LGBTQ
community which obviously is you know
you don't wanna be saying anything
negative about any community regardless
of whether you see their way or not
whether you agree with it or not you
just have to let people live their life
I mean honestly I'm down with whatever
people want to identify as you know if
they want to identify as a man as a
woman as a [ __ ] lion I support it
it doesn't affect me it's you know just
support people let people do what they
want to do you know you know people so
are so worried about the world changing
in the world is changing the world is
not gonna be recognizable in the next 20
to 30 years for a lot of people that
live in it so you know just do you just
do you and don't worry about about
anyone else that's right Roger Cobb
live-and-let-live I think it's a fairly
simple method a fairly simple rule to
follow I do plan to make another pure
hash joint video stoner Smurf you know I
think the next one will be out on a boat
and maybe we'll smoke like five or six
of them we are indeed the pioneers of
change yes yes exactly Jay plot and we
don't want to be affecting anyone
survival health well-being or freedom
happiness whatever those things are and
we don't really you know like it's
sometimes it's unnecessary I mean often
it's unnecessary to say something that's
just hurtful and mean for no good reason
I mean why would you do it why would you
do it you know I guess because we're
insecure and when we get insecure we
lash out we say negative thing
we become well we become the fallible
human beings that we are are the hash
joint six star oh gosh no bingo you
could never smoke a six star hashed past
joint it would melt right off the tip
the hash joints are specifically mixed
with a lower grade of hash like a 1 60
or 120 DRI sift mixed in with some nice
bubble and he's got the ratio right down
for producing the perfect paper that he
then rolls into which becomes the hash
spliff the paper of course is made out
of hash he flattens it out and I'm not
sure if he's rolling it over a toothpick
or what exactly he's doing I've asked
him on a few occasions if he wanted to
share the the technique and the method
and he was kind of a little bit leery
but maybe one day we'll get him in the
least I will be ordering some more of
those joints in the near future and
doing a video I still can't believe
there's over a million views on that
video just from sitting at my desk one
day and smoking a hash joy you never
know through social media how many
people you can touch I mean I'm happy to
touch 100 to 200 of you each well I
guess it ends up being a couple of
thousand to three thousand each
wake-and-bake video but that's I'm happy
with that so you can imagine when you
get suddenly get something like 1.3 1.4
million people that is an enormous
amount of people much larger than the
thought of like a stadium that the
Rolling Stones would sell out or even
like one of those Russian concerts that
Metallica would sell out four or five
hundred thousand people 1.3 1.2 million
people it's just well Shawn Zoe I think
we know enough I think we know each
other well enough now that you can just
let me have a little touch but don't you
think just a little touch come on man
don't be so so uh prude are you prude
so another bond rip I think and we'll
finish it off it's a short one 14
minutes gave a little something away
dropped a little bit of knowledge not
too much today the hash knowledge will
come I'm still writing the blog if you
can imagine Hoffa add a bonsai breeder
half a
yeah still writing this blog so this
should hopefully go up I'm down to the
45 micron bag so once I get all the bags
emptied I'll now start going through the
process of how to break it up properly
and then how to dry it properly it's
gonna be pretty good
and what else what else what else oh
[ __ ] you know I should say r.i.p to
Micky Martin I never really knew Mickey
Martin to me he seemed like this real
kind of troll II internet character that
was just like trolling everyone at epic
levels but apparently it was a really
amazing guy a family man a proponent of
medical cannabis and after seeing so
many of my friends in the community say
nice things about him in his passing of
course which was crazy cuz you just it's
wild to sort of see like here you got
marc emery saying a bunch of ignorant
[ __ ] to fuel the whole community to hate
him and he's got lots of people jumping
on him right now for the some of the
comments that he made there even jumping
on Jodie it's kind of harsh actually cuz
she never made the comments but yeah
they're jumping all over Marc and in the
meantime this guy Mickey who was very
much a troll like character like he was
a troll on the internet he had the [ __ ]
Mickey Awards if you can imagine which
mark of course won many years in a row
it was just interesting to see I guess
when we passed we just everyone's gonna
say the nicest things about us and so
Mickey had some really incredible things
to say they had some incredible things
to say about Mickey so our IP and I
raised my bong to you Mickey I never
really knew you didn't have the
connection with you thought you were an
internet troll but it turns out that you
were a real cannabis activists and we
thank you for the work you did and
really you know our thoughts go out to
your family and friends that you left
behind
never good passing away and leaving
people behind that's kind of sad but it
is the sort of circle of life as we say
so let's load it up for Mickey
r.i.p Mickey I was kind of scared of him
I'm not gonna lie I was kind of like I
hope I don't get on this guy's radar and
have him start trolling me incessantly
but
I've attracted a few good ones over the
year yes rest well Mickey Abraham
Espinoza it would change something in
the matrix yeah we're gonna do a bong
rip from Nicky that's right and I guess
you know while we do a bong rip for
Mickey we will also use his hashtag [ __ ]
Mickey which yeah there you go Daniel
Walsh I heard a ton of amazing stories
like that that Mickey really went out of
his way to help people like that and
that's to me the sort of foundation of a
great cannabis activists particularly in
this world of you know it's for the
patients it's for medical it's nice to
see people like that regardless of how
they're coming across on the internet
you know being a real solid human being
off the internet and helping people
that's I mean come on what more can you
ask for in a person are you Terps
available wholesale in Canada give me a
call absolutely give me a call or hit me
up info at blue river extract CA there
is still a [ __ ] excellent sale on the
Terps at blue river extract CA which is
lift to zero one seven twenty seventeen
that's $50 off each vial
that was very yummy let's do it again
yeah all right
yeah I didn't plug in my um I didn't
plug in my microphone today it's plugged
into the computer but not the phone that
I'm actually doing the chat on so my bad
see if we can't get a little cleaning
solution in here love me some DC cleaner
love me some DC cleaner we can't help it
sound like a commercial when you promote
something you love
congratulations met Mitch that's great
to hear really really really nice to
hear always happy when people are
getting their federal licenses to grow
possess and process cannabis what an
amazing [ __ ] opportunity we have here
in Canada on a federal level Mitch and I
can both grab our cannabis our cuts our
seeds our hash whatever we have and fly
to the center of Canada meet in Winnipeg
and legally federally have our product
with us flying through the airport
security the whole nine yards that's
really really awesome I hope to see it
happen in the rest of the world the rest
of the world visit our own it yeah I'd
love to come to Vancouver Island
trichome city always always
oh listen Lyndsey listen Lyndsey I got
some exciting news I am trying to
manifest a reality where I get Ron to
move from the Kootenays come out to the
west coast and possibly do a little
project together in a greenhouse still
the same greenhouse I've wanted to
for a while from forever flowering
greenhouses although we're going to be
contacting a bunch of different
greenhouse companies because it's
basically going to be the show the show
will be us building the greenhouse the
show will be wrong planting the
greenhouse talking about all of his
growing tips wakin bakes every morning
with Ron in the greenhouse massive
quantities of social media content for
me processing all of the resins
afterwards into you know dry sift bubble
hash and rosin macro photographing the
whole crop from seed to extracted resin
heads massive quantities of tips listen
Ron is very very knowledgeable in the
cannabis world very very knowledgeable
in growing and he will be able to have
tips like you won't believe and so and
yes trichome City we are looking for
that kind of help I'll probably grab a
couple of interns through interviews
gonna have to be able to trust them but
to be able to have them also come and do
work under Ron and myself you know
whether it's helping with editing
helping with filming helping with
growing helping with hash making helping
with a whole bunch of different things
like that obviously people who are local
are ideal because it's an intern
position we're not looking to you know
right away be paying out of the gate
we're definitely not looking to tell
people to move from other countries and
far away to come here with the hopes
that this will be a job that opens up
their future and we don't want that
responsibility but a couple of ships
will be there for sure for people who
are local for people who live here who
have their support system here and for
people we know aren't gonna have to
bugger off back to home after three or
four weeks if things don't go proper
bubbly University yeah with Ron and
myself I'm pretty excited about I'm not
gonna lie I'm I'm really excited at the
idea of just having Ron back in my life
he lived so far away ten ten hours away
and I know we could be a great
grandfather figure to my kid
he is a great father figure to me as
well as a mentor and a friend so very
excited at the whole idea of Ron coming
out here so thought I would share that
guy with you guys not too sure when
we're gonna try and make it happen maybe
in the next six months we're gonna start
doing research if you guys know
greenhouse companies that might want to
you know forever flowering greenhouses
came on hash Church and I fell in love
with that greenhouse if they can give us
a good deal
we will definitely you know grab that
greenhouse but this is you know we won't
be growing cannabis for profit or for
sale will really be growing cannabis for
the content and for the education value
and we're going to be promoting the
company who sells us the greenhouse so
we really want to be able to get the
most extremely awesome deal that we can
possibly get you know so if any of you
out there know any company's greenhouse
companies definitely let me know hit me
up and we'll send out the email to them
because we're basically gonna send out a
nice cover email explaining bubble man's
world
the wake-and-bake shows all of these
different things and how we can start
doing it out of the greenhouse
supplemental lighting you know obviously
a blackout you know the forever flower
in greenhouse one of the main things was
that you could control the flowering the
photo period by simply making it dark or
keeping it light so all of that has
really cool got me super excited and
yeah hail the trichomes that's it
fin ah it's going on fin ah 23 minutes
49 seconds yeah
time-lapse cameras in the greenhouse
there you go exactly LEDs and and you
know Gavita xand like the whole nine
yards we'll we'll have a whole variety
of things going on in there and I'll
definitely promise you this much it will
be heaven on earth Yeah right on coup
sorry that it's freezing up I'm gonna
probably blaze off right now feeling
pretty good beautiful day found out the
place where my boat is is actually open
today so I could probably get in my
truck
drive down there so why don't you guys
have a great day enjoy your weekend and
well we'll see you tomorrow for hash
Church episode 143 or 144 can't even
keep up with it anymore but I do know
that the wake-and-bake SAR slowly
catching up to that number
alright everybody may the full mount
bless your bowl sooner than later we
will talk next time peace out