hey what's up everybody welcome to the
wake and bake episode 77 that's seven
and seven it's a palindrome actually
forwards and backwards and anyway I hope
everyone's doing great today we're just
in the chatroom talking with sticks with
turps Scott ray Detroit Bubble Boy we're
talking about the cost of hash we're
talking about you know trying to get
bubbleman Brad really wants to get the
price of hash down in California it's
hard because the shops you sell to
obviously are doubling the prices on the
hash and you see these extravagant over
a hundred dollars sometimes over two
hundred dollar prices which that's a
little bit of a kick in the a little bit
of a kick in the newts for someone
especially if this is your your your
medicine that you're purchasing I agree
demand amide the rent is too damn high
and the hash is too damn high hope
everyone's good I can't seem to get this
working but it seems like we're on live
here my YouTube video won't go live on
my computer but I see you guys so
obviously you can see me yeah rocking a
little DNA always happy to support Erin
and Dawn and of course Crockett good
people good people haven't seen him for
a while I gotta say last time I saw Erin
was probably when he was out here for
New Year's came out for New Year's with
his family and we hung out with him and
as well as flat 41 and his family and
even the great gardener was up with his
girlfriend Sarah that was Whistler
there's videos you guys could go check
it out I just don't get why it won't
show me not that I really need to as
long as I can see the the chat then
we're good to go
right now it's 9:30 I don't stream at
any particular time Gavin I go when I
want to go I like to build up the room a
little bit have you guys sitting in here
and chatting and creating a conversation
that always seems to be a great way
let's hope for 2017 to be the year that
we see the prices of hash go down a
little bit it would be really really
nice to see I'm gonna turn on the dab
inator and scw live east coast what's
going on Jedi surfer good morning good
morning keiki meow and
or Smurf and intrepid chronics and the
Kanak guide got a whole crew in there
you were slowly converting me to solvent
less bro well you know what Nick it's
all up to you to do your own decisions
I'm not trying to direct you any one way
but I have my own directions and I'm
passionate about them and hey what's
going on Aaron mr. heavy ice is in the
room I've been seeing you in here for a
while buddy nice - nice to see you
I hope life is treating you well I'm
probably gonna rip into some of this dry
sift or some of this dry sift I'm not
too sure this one's D for 20k it's a
little bit darker oh gee cush this one
is from the guys that sunrise wellness
and I can't remember the name of it
right now it's it's definitely not the
petróleo head stache cross with the
malawi that was just the jar that he
gave it to me
all right i will go for the light one I
will go for the light when it's funny
because you know Tony said something the
other day when he was talking to someone
about rosin and there is sort of this
minor negative attention that gets put
on the darker resins and I'm not sure
why that is I as well love clear golden
as light colored as possible it just
seems to have something that is more and
I when it's when it comes out darker I
just feel like it's not quite as good
and I'm not sure why that is it's
definitely a weird thing I'm not trying
to be hash racist that's for sure but I
do prefer a golden a golden color all
right let's grab a little dabble here
it's aesthetically pleasing it's an I
don't think it's Oh 9 cookies for some
reason but maybe it is I really kind of
forgot maybe it is the oh 9 cookies I
forget
oh nice heavy ice what I would love to
see that and I've had some delicious
dark rosin don't get me wrong but for
the most part I'm usually a little bit
happier when it comes out well you know
what I mean we're talking about color
we're talking about you know when it's
it's it's a strange thing because the
dark resin the dark bubble for sure can
be absolute fire I find particularly in
tropical countries the bubble will often
go dark
just from the oxidization and the heat I
saw it in Spain the last time I was
there really really beautiful dark
Amber's almost reds all you know deeply
twisted oranges just beautiful hash read
on Kaylee don't be late don't be sorry
don't be sorry
right on Kaylee's mom I hope you guys
are all having a good good day puffs and
bowls over there yeah for sure me too
Cuban me too I do remember when the West
Coast boys Rose in that 10-year old
bubble I brought that 10 year old bubble
to them so they could rosin it that was
a very nice thing for them to have done
for Steve because those guys are
connoisseurs and let me tell you they
were not too stoked on the quality of
that end product you know I'm not too
sure David it might be the oh nine
cookies I can't remember the last sift I
clean this is so old at this point in
time I wasn't puffing it for the longest
time but it is full melt it drips and
bubbles into a liquid and is definitely
on point for that sweet from a Dean ale
to heat up a little bit and we'll have a
rip with you guys that's a good price 35
euros you know I'd love to even see it
cheaper but it's tough paying these
insane prices when you can do that swai
a lot of people are happy to grow their
own you know what sticks with Terps I
have no idea I talked to the cookie fan
guys and they were just like Oh nein
cookies what the [ __ ] that doesn't even
make any sense so I suspect it's one of
these situations where a name got named
something and I kind of feel bad every
time I say the name because I know [ __ ]
in flux or cringing in their in their
surroundings of true cookies but it is
what it is how much is decent hash in
Jamaica decent hash is very hard to find
in Jamaica but you could probably pay
about 20 plus dollars for a gram I've
heard that some of the co2 oil and such
is going for 50 and 60 dollars a gram on
in the nicer in the nicer hotels should
we get this going on now yeah I think
it's fire but I'm just not sure if it's
actually cookies so this is the thing
right we really need to get people like
to name things
things and it's like you're right let's
just rip it
that was nice
well that was really nice you know what
I love about properly cured rice EFT
it's so smooth
this isn't dry sip that was taken fresh
and put in a vac freezer and had
moisture this is properly dried and
cured and processed dry cept
and because of it it's just absolutely
smooth I'm gonna take one twice as big
as that because that one tasted just
like another yes you can can a guide but
it depends on what your definition of
trim if you want to produce full mount
from trim it better be proper trim I'm
talking about the tiny little pieces of
from the bud that you cut clip away not
the large fan leaves maybe small fan
leaves like that if they have resin all
over them but all the first bubble I
made back in the day was absolute
absolutely made from trim and once I got
the growers trained to producing the
trim that I required which was really
generally simply put when the resin when
the leaf has no resin put it on this
pile when it has sugar exactly sugar
leaves over to the right and you know
everything else over to the left and I
don't know whoredom at four or five I've
sold a couple here and there maybe four
so you can absolutely get incredible
quality from trim it's it's you know
there are some trims that still will
have this minorly
like I'll sometimes I'll be like oh did
you make this from trim like I'll taste
that hey that really really a lot of
people won't taste it but I'll sometimes
taste it and I think it has a lot to do
with the terpene profile of the plant
Renae for instance the trim made bubble
that was as nice as tasty as quality as
the bud and so that was a very confusing
thing now other cultivars did not do
yes the grass tastes I can really taste
the grass taste in dry sipped made from
trim if you use trim and make dry sift
unless you clean it to 99.999 I'm gonna
taste that hay in there just a little
bit let's have another big rip shall we
it actually had really nice effects like
it got me really really stoned not gonna
lie
let's have another shall we trying to
get a big one it's not that easy oh
that's a pretty big one if it will let
me oh there we go
I wouldn't say it's twice the size but
it's big it's big it'll be good
yella well hey that's a good idea thank
you for smoking pot that's a very good
idea
you that one was really nice on top of
my second when it really finally grabbed
me I was like I'm going in again this
was made from bud well as it should
I'm hitting beautiful dry cept this
often sends people reeling a lot of
people aren't really used to the puffs
that a full mount dry sip will give you
it's not going to be the same as pretty
much any other concentrate
unless you're smoking really unique
cultivars that produce you know the
alcohol soluble terpenes that don't wash
away in the water I've seen some really
what's the key to dry sifting buds well
I don't think there is any one key I
think that's why it's a difficult and
complex thing and most people are unable
to do it carding allowed a very few
people to get on board
one sneeze discovered that he could wrap
his card with parchment that created the
static addition Darrin added the deep
that the the DVD and then other people
went with books and wider things to
create a wider edge along the bottom and
now you have you know people producing
99% dry sift that was otherwise you know
they weren't they weren't pulling it off
quite with carding I was able to get to
99.999% with carding only because I was
so obsessed and I would card for hours
sometimes first time we carted just a
couple of rips Johnny B and I the first
time he I did it with him to show him I
had been doing it for a while at that
point in time maybe 10 years it took 40
minutes just to produce one really
yeah one you know beautiful rip each and
that's also on YouTube but it's the 2012
video of rip and dry sips with Johnny B
and I love the video because at the end
of the video actually I'm gonna show you
the video because it's so [ __ ]
awesome dry sip dry that's weird
I'm not sure dry sipped ribs YouTube I
don't know the exact name of it so Oh
full mouth dry sift no oh here it is dry
sift after 40 minutes of cleaning all
right let's get you guys a little show
here so this is me and Johnny be smoking
his hash that I cleaned up got it all
melty oh yeah little B line rippin
little B Line rippin not too shabby
the best part is the laughs at the end
so yeah we're just showing the purity
here you know this is really high
quality now when Johnny B came over with
this stuff it was like 20% heads I
remember him being excited about it we
had just met and I said listen this is
farmers grade and he kind of was a
little insulted and that I just we just
cleaned it and Johnny B never looked
back from that day forward he was a full
melt hasher yeah and this is dry set
that I cleaned right here in my office
right here in my office I cleaned it so
it's starting to char up finally and
we're just trying to finish it this was
this rip took like 20 rips listen to the
laughs when I exhale this is so awesome
it's coming I'm about to exhale and blow
up
[Laughter]
the Charlie the wax membranes the
fibrous mat the the you know the
material that's left over from the gland
that isn't oil so pretty fun good laugh
yeah giggling like a schoolgirl well you
know that's funny that you should ask is
there any way to make a distillate
without a solvent because that's
something that we're working on right
now trying to create a distillate from
rosin without using a solvent so let us
get back to you on that one
yeah indra who made me laugh to you see
that rip we had set it up and what you
don't see off-camera is that no one
person smoked that whole bowl John and I
were both going like crazy we'd hit it
he'd hit it I'd hit it he'd hit it I did
it he hit it it got so ridiculous that
at the end we were almost unable to
finish the bowl and I was I kept trying
to and right at the end when I finish it
I just I give it all blows out and I I
just had to bust into laughter it was it
was quite a rip even for the two of us
it was a rip and I will say that we both
felt quite wonderful it also obviously
made us feel really good for John it was
a profound revelation cuz he was in a
lot of pain at that point in time and he
was using cannabis for his pain but he
had never acquired that clean or pure of
a product and it was his own resin and
the thing about John is he grows great
resin he just didn't know how to process
it when I met him and so when I took his
resin and cleaned it and saw that it
melted like that I was like alright okay
you know this next thing you know I
basically said to him you know what
about bubble why don't you try bubbles
oh god I've never really been impressed
with bubble and so you know what I did
was basically go over to his place and
whip up a batch of his material make a
make a batch for him and it was
unbelievable quality once again whoo
what are we going on here
why why is this guy like there we go
I don't even know what that dudes deal
is but he's gotta go yeah bubble
ambassadors so going there and making
bubble at his house he was kind of like
I've made bubble I'm not really that
impressed that I'm like well maybe you
were doing it the way you were dry
sifting so he was like oh yeah maybe I
was I don't know so we ran eight bags we
produced some absolutely stellar product
and once again you know that those are
the things that he identifies himself by
now his dry sifting in his bubble
hashing so hats off to Johnny B for you
know growing the good resin and making
the good making the good isolates yeah
grape God is really nice I've had the
hash I've had the rosin very nice I love
using your saying whenever someone has
poop soup I hope I say bah no yeah
whoredom at well that's a good good way
to go about it if it's poop soup you
know difference between solvent free and
solvent list there is no difference Nick
Lutz because there's no such thing even
though I myself have fallen victim to it
there's no such thing as solvent list
when it comes to cannabis because all
the hydrocarbons that are the terpenes
are solvents so how do you call it
solvent list it's more like if you want
to say it's it's you know it's not made
using petrochemical based solvents you
could say something like that
petrochemical based solvents or whatnot
but it's definitely they are still
solvents the the terpenes are solvents
they are hydrocarbons that's why Horatio
could take the terpene dilemma Neen and
make oil with it instead of you know
running butane through the tube
he runs delimiting through the tube and
he gets his extract well it means that
the the solvent they used has all been
cleaned out that's what they that's what
they mean but for me the solvent is
never really the big worry it's whatever
heavy metal contaminant can be
potentially laying in the solvent that
is you know or pesticide worse say the
solvent is clean as clean can be but you
end up getting material that is late
ladened with
besides those pesticides will have very
similar molecular weights as the
cannabinoids and even if you run it
through a short path molecular
distillation unit you're still going to
have concentrated with that oil all
those pesticides so yeah petrochemical
free extracts you know that that's
that's probably a little bit more
accurate bubble hash turns dark
depending on the oils inside sometimes
it stays very bright I've had stuff
bubble hash be very blonde be very red
generally it's oxidization you know if I
keep it I've got some here that looks
almost black it really depends on how I
let it get exposed but if I make a very
and then also the life cycle of the
trichome like people now love the light
golden color so will end up and also
people love cutting their herb down
early so they can get it sold and they
can get paid faster a combination of
those two things really does create a
very light colored resin if you take
that light colored resin and keep it in
a fridge or a freezer it's pretty much
going to stay preserved it's not going
to get very dark to a degree Conor but
it depends on how cold you keep the
water and how fast you can wash it
because a lot like for me I wash fast
I'm not about mixing and then taking my
sweet time pulling the bags in a perfect
world you'd have four or five friends
and you'd all pull those bags all
simultaneously get the water out right
away you know you don't want it to be
there any longer than it needs to be so
no I mean like I said you know I love
properly cured resin and often properly
cured resin is not light in color when I
you know some of the best present I've
ever smoked in my life was fairly dark
in color reddish dark but much darker
than blond or you know this sort of
beige color that I've got
here oh it smells good though when I
leave the lids off of these dry sift
it's like Terk heaven it fills up the
entire room with this beautiful terpene
latent smell very good so yeah how do I
feel about storing flour in a fridge or
freezer well it'll it'll it'll it'll
suck out moisture unless you can really
seal it properly it'll just it'll remove
the moisture that's what it'll do the
moisture will try to leave the bud go on
the inside of the bag and then the
process of the moisture leaving the bud
and then getting reabsorbed to me
turns bud into hay and so I'm not an
overly big fan of it especially in that
process I'm sure terpenes are being
affected even though it's cold there's
still an evaporation happening put in a
chest freezer for long-term storage
alright well there it is if you want a
vacuum that's definitely the better idea
you don't want any room between that
herb and that who knows what the ideal
curing temp is that's something you're
gonna want to find out from you know for
you
I like colder I like to preserve you
know you know terpenes but I also like
to evaporate out the most caustic ones
that are a little bit harsher on the
throat when you don't when you cut it
fresh frozen and you wash it right away
and you keep the fresh cold the whole
time you get a very more of a harsh sort
of grab you by the nuts rip a lot of
people like that I myself prefer a
little bit more of a smooth rip
especially if I'm going to take 40 or 50
of them in a day
nitrogen storage would be for a long
term if you wanted to remove the oxygen
and replace it with nitrogen for sure
that's going to preserve much longer
than oxygen would yeah alright grab me
by the short and curlies well head here
if I used to do fresh froze and I was
all about it but what I found was it was
like a cheat it was like a way that
could this is the importance of bubble
bags I wish I could learn how to say
this is gonna be really good drop if I
can figure this out bubble bags are a
guide they guide you in growing and so
if you listen to them they will take you
to a place where you can give that plant
what it means to express itself to the
maximum of its potential okay now what I
mean by that is how to really explain it
how to really explain it it's it this is
this is so I I don't want to get lost in
my thoughts but this is this is a this
is an important factor properly drawing
the resin okay
would we ever smoke fresh herb no it's
harsh it hurts our throats because those
caustic terpenes the ones that are
evaporating out at room temperature I'm
not sure we're supposed to be inhaling
those ones and those are the ones that
people are trying to save to get a
higher terpene production that's fine I
used to make bubble with trim that was
bone dry and that bubble came out six
star it was called Renee so I know that
it can be done I know that the nicest
bubble can be made from from dried cured
bud and to this day I still prefer it
and I see that you know if your bud is
grown to the maximum of its potential
and you you and you dry and cure it and
you take that dry and cured material and
you make bubble hash with it it will
melt into a liquid now the problem is
most people's material most people that
make fresh frozen if you dry their
material and you make bubble with it it
doesn't melt anymore
so the melting factor has more to do
with the wax membrane and the moisture
content of that membrane boiling out
when you hit the hash then an actual
melt factor so it's kind of a cheat it's
kind of a little bit like oh I didn't
listen to the bags I'm just cutting it
fresh frozen now I'm just yeah Yahweh
trust me dude people are how do you use
dry material and still get it to melt
it's like it's called growing great pot
look into it it's what the bags have
been trying to tell you but you're
ignoring them and unfortunately when I
started releasing the bags the BHO
method came out
immediately like a month later and a lot
of people would try the bags and then be
like oh that shit's not that good which
really was telling them your shit's not
that good and they would just instead of
growing better herb they would go make
oil and the same things happening with
rosin people are making a meltable
product out of something that's not
mountable well of course it mounts it's
oil you melted the glans off the head
it's not going to be as impressive as
hash melting hash melting is impressive
that means you grew that plant to
absolute perfection and then you
purified those glands to perfection if
you can do both those things trust me
that is the Holy Grail
nobody loves anything more than that and
just very few people have it it's a it's
a rarity to have full melt dry sift I
have some for instance but the problem
is both of these were not grown to
perfection this was not grown to
perfection I would say it's a seven out
of ten and this one has not grown to
perfection it might be a seven point
five out of ten now keep in mind for the
most part because so many people now are
used to just blasting they're so used to
not seeing quality but a7 is the new 10
which is really [ __ ] unfortunate when
we're in an era where we know the
importance of this medicine and we would
think that the highest quality would be
the most important for us whether we are
sick or whether we are healthy and
trying to prevent so that's what I
wanted to say about that the bubble bags
are about if you run your material
through bubble bags and it does not come
out melty and beautiful and tasty and
wonderful then you're not doing
something right and the bags have told
you so please listen to them listen to
them and go back and learn from it learn
about maybe creating a living soil maybe
look into those strains of bacteria for
the roots that can produce healthier
happier plants all of these different
things
Allen Malta the best thing you can do if
you can get material from someone else
run their material for them and give it
to them in this and show them look at
this do you know what this is it's a
c-plus at best you just passed maybe
it's even a d'
some might be adi some are c plus some
are B's some are B pluses but very very
very few are a pluses because the a
pluses they just find they get gobbled
up so fast let me tell you that much how
crucial is the drying process if you're
using grain a flours well fairly
important you could [ __ ] it up to a
degree although the highest quality
flowers I can tell you the product
always melts you know but hearing is
going to be important you've grown this
thing to perfection you purified it to
perfection you're done everything right
why [ __ ] it up at the end one way to
[ __ ] it up at the end and a lot of
people would do is they would put it all
together I would say use it put it on a
desiccant and sieve it so it breaks into
powder they would still powder it all
into a pile like this I don't want to
see it piled into a pile I want to see
little specks spread very thin over the
desiccant over the cardboard because
that is what's going to pull the
moisture out properly another thing I
see is when people start to feel the
hash and they say oh it's kind of I
think it's dry now it's it's it's really
dry my trust me it isn't it's it's it's
a it's a trick the outside is dry but
the inside is not and they'll go and
they'll rub it all together and make a
ball and of course you know you're gonna
end up with this buttered out kind of
you know falling apart hash that ends up
smelling of that sort of funky moisture
this is what we saw in the early days
mostly my fault
I showed a lot of people incorrectly how
to make how to how to you know put
bubble together afterwards and I spent
years trying to explain the importance
of removing all of the moisture content
so keep in mind when I started showing
this to people no one was really making
medical isolates for patients it was a
very new thing and I think most people
were producing it for personal use it
was a personal use thing and now we've
gotten to a point where it's turning
commercial and
now we've got to change up the tools a
little bit so you know I dried out for
10 to 15 but I'm in the Pacific
Northwest so you know generally you
could probably hit that same range in
about 3 to 4 days you know in a in a dry
place like Arizona or something well you
know what drew I'm not fussy I don't
grow all my cannabis and I I don't
pretend to think that one way is better
than the other as I get older I realize
that a quiver is an important thing
because it gives us options and I know
that I feel different on different days
and I have different months and weeks of
my life so why would I want to have only
one thing to take me to take care of me
when it comes to cannabis there are so
many beautiful options and that's why I
always say I don't fight against
anything that already exists I just
fight for more that's the way to do it
yeah possible for a hash mate with like
4 to 5% terpene content to make a house
that doesn't butter out I'd be hard to
say dan Richards I couldn't really say
it's possible the terpene content might
very well just be too high and when you
concentrate that much hash it very well
may butter itself out
we know that terpenes can butter out
hash we know that moisture content can
butter out hash at the same time I've
had very chirpy hash that I've managed
to dry properly and I'm keeping in mind
drying properly is I think it could take
a couple of months sometimes to hang a
plant and get it prepared for dry
sifting so those those little heads
shrink like little resins and you just
know that all that's really in there is
that resin head sure you're gonna lose
some of your terpenes and your weight
but the smoothness of that smoke and the
watching it melted I'll tell you any one
I ever put that in their bowl the
impressive they can't believe they can
get that high without coughing and
turning red you know and don't get me
wrong you can turn a coffin turn red
you're gonna get maybe one or two rips
of that smooth and by the time you take
your second or third you're gonna be
like oh because it's just unbelievably
pure
if it's properly grown then that's even
better that's for sure well excellent
Akio Tom I'm glad you are I always want
it to be a good one we're gonna have
another one tomorrow another one Friday
and hopefully another one on Saturday
morning so we will see you guys all
sooner than later
and as I always like to finish it as a
already said the end of it but may the
full melt bless your bowl sooner than
later peace out everybody