is it gonna where it's working hey right
on everybody my q-tips welcome everybody
to wake in big episode Oh number 80 here
we are hopefully you guys find it
because I think I made three or four of
them before we finally got into this one
sorry about taking so long today yes
welcome for Ellis ode number 80 my
classic misspelling of episode it's
funny that we you know what if you can't
laugh about your jokes or your mistakes
then GZ can't laugh about much I think
we're gonna start it off with a bake of
wakes right away to that yes bless up as
well to you Dominique and Steven Simmons
is in the room and Ryan Axton and Cody
Wilson and octo Tom and the AL f farms
New Age utopia ancient cannabis Jeffrey
ALL to cush dr. Colin KP and woody
Cooper
bingo Lombardi and all the rest of you
wonderful people are we gonna have a
good show today I think so I won't keep
it too long as I know that there are
some other live shows happening this
morning that I'm sure you guys are eager
to get over to I figured we could pump
out a quick wake-and-bake here tried to
get it started by 9:30 but had a little
bit of technical difficulties not too
sure why I'm having these technical
difficulties but it is what it is and I
hope you guys are all doing well today
shout out to Sabo for the can athlete
t-shirt that I'm wearing today for those
of you that wonder in Sabo's Shen from
the oh geez what the heck why can't I
remember the name of his company now his
cool little vaporizer with the glass
rods the vape exhale [ __ ] great
little unit great I should pull mine out
and have a big sesh maybe the vape
exhale yeah
maybe have a session with that tomorrow
morning and we'll get we'll get busy
with it yes I do for sure
trust me I try to get one going but then
[ __ ] happens and I need to get another
one going and then more [ __ ] happens and
a third one gets going but I do
appreciate you letting me know lettin me
know all right there we go cheers cheers
Cheers chillin like a villain is
everyone doing well today I hope we're
doing good
what are we gonna talk about we're gonna
talk about the Karma Cup yeah we're
gonna talk about the karma Cup that's my
next big event while my next big event
will be a event in Jamaica that's mostly
for doctors it's not really a an open to
the public cannabis event but I will
talk about that a little bit in the
future
Oh Congo 120 bubble hash squished into
rosin boo yeah [ __ ] Brian I'm sorry
to hear that I don't know who grow boss
is but shout out to grow boss for doing
this thing to try it for trying to build
an audience for trying to do a show
sorry that he was boring you but at
least he's out there trying right oh god
this is so nice
gonna have to give it just one more
little shot one more little shot to get
that last little bit I love the nish cap
super stoked Thank You nish that she can
I skip I got another one given to me
from space walk and I really loved it as
well well it looks like the top of his
jars if you ever look at Nicias glass
his little his little cap is the top all
of his pipes have this mouthpiece on
them so it's a pretty cool little thing
I think that oh my net my egg is about
like just under 9 inches I think yeah it
is pretty short little fat little stout
little egg Monday I'll sell it one day
I'll sell it can you imagine I'll do it
I'm not connected to these things I love
the idea of sharing them and passing
them on letting him get to the next
place they're just clear they're
beautiful they're you know it's not like
it was given to me or that I have some
special connection to it you know what
Adam Sinclair that's a pretty good one
but I'm not going out of respect for my
wife I will not answer that I love to
make jokes but not with my wife at the
butt end of them
no pun intended
I would love to own a bubbleman
mothership well there you doing Nicholas
cross they come up for sale every once
in a while I sold my Taurus I sold my
straight fab and what do I have I have a
Klein I have a mini frosted mini and I
have this egg as well as another one
that I've been waiting for this deadbeat
to pay me back I've been so good and not
blasting this guy because I know how
many people follow me and it's not
really sometimes a good idea to make
your own personal gripes public so I
always sort of would say to people
listen if you have a problem with
someone and you feel like the best thing
to do is call them out in public it's
it's probably not the best thing to do
they might be going through some other
things in their life and it's best if
you just have some cash compassion and
some empathy for them even though you're
in the situation where you're feeling
wronged and not to do that not to call
those people out because I just don't
think it brings any positivity to anyone
I don't think we all need to what's the
purpose in waking up in the morning and
trying to build and get your followers
to be against someone or to feel
negative in any way so for me what I'm
trying to do with this thing is and I've
already failed miserably a bunch of
times I've gotten a little upset and
I've gotten pissed off here and there
and I am human no no no no one broke my
egg I broke my egg long time ago broke
the neck right here perfect snapped it
off sent it back they sent me back with
this now it's got a little R right on
the bottom it's not gonna affect the
sale of this pipe I assure you I think I
like it better with the new neck
actually well that's what it that's what
it's all about right I'm trying to what
a my thoughts on Frenchie cannoli
well Frenchie cannoli has very different
belief systems than me in regards to
hash but at the same time my thoughts on
Frenchy and cannoli are that he's like a
kindred soul a kindred brother a brother
in hashish and hashish aficionado he
loves hashish and so my thoughts are
good I think Frenchie cannoli is good
and he's good for hashish and he's good
for the people and if he says things
that are completely different and
sometimes even the opposite of what I
say Who am I to say otherwise I mean
someone's got to cover the opposite of
what I'm saying and I think that just
because it's the opposite of what I
saying it certainly doesn't mean that
it's wrong it's just different and as I
learn about the quiver I have an
appreciation for all things different
for all things unique so I think Fran
she's a good person and my thoughts are
that I like him he's a kind person and
all-around lover of hashish that's what
I could say about Frenchy cannoli
now 5-10 years ago I might have gone on
and on and on about how I thought he was
wrong about this and wrong about that
and he should this is how I do it and
this is what I would do and bla bla bla
bla bla but really you know get over
yourself
that's not what people need they just
need everything they don't need just
what you have they need everything so
please don't try to stunt or quiet or
muffle anyone else's voice because
exactly octave Tom we all have our own
way and we all have our own voice so it
does come with maturity you know it's uh
I was immature for a long time I have my
own insecurities about things in life
but as I am a humbled father of three
and the humble husband of a beautiful
wife for close to 30 years now I've
learned to be a little bit more patient
and look at things from a little bit
more of a wider perspective and so that
is the perspective that I'm looking at
things these days in the meantime when
can we hang out well we can hang out
September 9th and 10th in Toronto at the
Karma cup and although I was going to do
an unboxing video I kind of feel like I
still possibly could but I'm gonna do it
right here today Sarah sent me this box
it's really heavy too and so we're gonna
open it up I already cut the tape this
looks like we got some t-shirts so let's
just pull some of these out yeah yes oh
yeah oh yeah I'd say that there are
probably six or seven karma Cup t-shirts
here so that's good
fun for a giveaway and then she's put a
couple of cannabis extracts I wouldn't
be able to give these away because I
don't want to be you know doing that
I'll keep those maybe pass them on I
won't give away all these pins karma cup
pins and are you elite are you elite
there you go and then some some cards
and such for her event
you know what I'll say about Sarah she's
an extremely capable person and so she's
going to make it happen even when
everything blew up last year she pulled
it off and it was a great event my
company did very well a lot of people
come from the outside area of Toronto
there's millions of people in and around
those suburbs and in those cities really
and then of course the US is right there
is 2 you have New York State you have a
lot of people coming up from the the US
for the event she puts some dab maps in
here as well she puts some Terp proof
packaging squares in here
karmak up silicon pads and yeah you said
that yes thank you melty heads melty
heads how does one become a karma cup
judge mister melt
well first you begin by sending me an
email at BC bubble man at iCloud and
then telling me which one of these pins
you want me to send you that's that's
the start right there so you wanted to
know how to become a cannabis cup judge
mister melt I don't know but you won a
pin so an urn wolf3d won a pin as well
so you guys both send me an e-mail at bc
bubbleman at icloud.com and tell me
which pin you want and if it's the same
one don't worry I got a shitload
all right so those are the two giveaways
for today mr. melt and Arne and I thank
Sara from the karma cop I'm looking
forward to being there honestly last
year it was outside in a parking lot she
had all the booths set up it was sweet
the weather was a little bit cold but I
was a little bit later as well this year
it's it's quite a bit earlier so I'm
pretty stoked to be there if you're in
and around the neighborhood September
9th and 10th I think I'm speaking as
well so I'll be there why are you dying
natural alternatives I missed it
getting some pasties in the mouth and I
don't have my water you guys are gonna
have to listen to it ah sorry
Christopher Reece I just can't make them
all you know we're in Toronto I'm not
sure why don't I find out and it might
be a thing that they announce closer to
the time let's see September 9th and
10th competition live music speakers
downtown Toronto so I guess that's
that's about as close as you're getting
now this is sort of the what's going on
here at the karmak up we have but indica
hybrid sativa edibles made with extracts
cannabutter edibles concentrates so
shatter indica shatter hybrid shatter
sativa butter wax butter crumbles sugar
Terp enhanced extracts all types
non-solvent extracts all types no co2
CBD extracts functional glass water
pipes pipes tab rates and more pen
cartridges all types 510 threading and
topicals bones lotion bath products and
more so I'm not sure if she's doing it
where they're all separate categories
and when you judge you apply to judge
for certain things I'm not sure if she
has crazy VIP judges that you can just
judge everything but it's pretty wild
awesome I pet meze that's good to hear
man very good to hear [ __ ] love in
that oh there you go yes in the Karma
Cup website very good the Karma cup calm
general admission tickets now on sale
vikarma Capcom I guess they're also on
like Instagram and Twitter at the karma
cup so Sara's done a great job she's
passed us on this box and goodies and I
don't need any of it so I'm going to
pass it on to all of you now what was
that question do I know anything about
paralysis and psoriasis and topicals
well
I know cannabinoids work on almost
anything so without knowing much about
much you could easily start
experimenting through bioassay if you
have psoriasis with creating your own
bombs which is you know simply enough
find out what's not irritating to your
skin maybe some shade nut butter maybe
some coconut oil maybe even some nail be
coconut oil extract the the further
distill that if you will it's quite the
singing voice oh I don't know about that
uh hello from Bavaria here in Bavaria it
is partly impossible to get good oil I
pressed myself with a hair straightener
that's the way to do it bro I love to
hear that oh yeah we've been smoking
hard and killed too one fresh but we can
smoke more it is a wake and bake why not
right let me turn on the D nail cuz
that's always nice I don't always like
to torch like three four times in a row
it's kind of loud I don't like the way
it sounds when were filming John BIRT
fellow in regards to what might he have
more info he could John has much info
he's a man of many hats from processing
and growing and running a business I got
some fire flower ozma hey you guys want
to see some fire fire rosin go check out
my instagram @bhl
or the new one at bubble man brand just
all one word go check that out give us a
follow over there we only have like
three thousand followers so far but look
at the last picture of the tur-bros in
that that the video that Tony took that
is in
I assure you dry sifting rub the real
dragon yeah we knew that was fire the
second we saw it so very excited for
that to be able to I guess people at
rosin or at rosin people at chalice if
you see Tony V walking around or if you
guys know the guys at the Green Dragon
the real green dragon go see them go see
if they've got any left cuz yeah
might be worth checking out might be
worth checking out and then I guess Tony
was entered a whole schwack at times I
think he entered one bubble man brand
into chalice but I know he entered like
three or four with gold drop brand PAH
Ketchum in Vancouver definitely you're
gonna want to go check out sunrise
wellness they probably have some fire
Ross and maybe some fire melts from West
Coast concentrate the best rosin I've
had has probably just been stuff that
I've made I love I love a whole bunch of
different stuff when you surround
yourself with exceptional quality and
people who really push themselves to
have exceptional quality I find that the
best is reappearing often and shows up
in different places and shows up in
different cultivars and even different
processes so I just love perfectly grown
cannabis resins that have expressed
themselves to full potential and I love
of course a whole host and variety of
terpenes and terpenoids well that makes
sense
what's that weed makes you lazy people
try to say weed makes you lazy want to
talk about it as a tool and how I lost
150 pound redeem pounds yeah I don't
find that it makes me lazy at all um I
feel that certain people who are
overworked and just in this mentality of
being a zombie there might be a level of
being baked and on a couch that they
need to go through to on brainwash
themselves from the current reality that
they've been in and I went through that
as a younger person I remember being
super not motivated and just hanging out
being baked and that was just as my
brain was adjusting to cannabis and my
body was adjusting to having it back and
I lost that very quickly and very early
on it became extremely active and in
fact when I used cannabis I want to go
do something that's active I don't want
to just sit around and be you know I'd
rather go for a hike or a bike ride or a
snowboard or you know a wake skate or
whatever yeah they're not puffing on 73
bubbles melt 73 knows he knows yep oh
yeah love me some 73 you know and then
there's the real 73 which is if you use
the 8 bag kit but you remove the 90
micron and let that all fall into the 73
we used to call that everyone needs the
Hayes Christopher Rees we used to call
that well I just called it the 73 but
once I got the 90 and we'd make batches
without the 90 we call it the real 73
that's what we call it oh yeah that's
the real 73 or the true 73 that works
too yeah
Hayes gets you motivated oh you're most
welcome one time I love hanging out with
you guys you know we got a couple
hundred people in the room I think it's
a pretty good core group of people that
we've had probably for the last maybe
four or five or six weeks I'm not too
sure you know hard to say job blasts
once again the favorite thing you know
everything's a favorite I'm not sure
that my mind works that way anymore I
mean it might in certain aspects of
things when there's very when there's no
second place but with the motherships
what they all have is their place so
certain times I love the blasting chug
of a ball rig or
the Faberge egg they chug these are chug
motherships
then you have the more almost like a
silencer on your gun that would be the
klein and the Taurus both of those hit
in this real sorta they don't have this
long crazy chugging feeling they're more
relaxed and then you have your mini and
the mini or and the straight fab for
that matter as well which are much more
open and hit more like a swiss perk the
the straight fab hits more like a swiss
perk the mini it just hits really nice
it's open but it's a very short space
that it's traveling so it's still quite
tight and it's very small and I just
like them all I really do like them on
then there's the the FTK also the FK t I
never went with that I always called it
the FT K which is like a fab egg a
Taurus and decline all stacked on top of
one another that one to me felt you know
there was a hype because that was the
most expensive the most sought-after one
because it's all of them it's pretty
unique and it definitely hits really
cool but it hits very very like you're
really pulling on the ftk some of them
hit more open than others but generally
if you're used to hitting any of the
other single pieces you'll find that the
ftk hits a little a little tighter it's
going on FATA mike Chooch Zac Willie and
black Starliner talk about what it means
to only have resin in the 25u bag well
you don't see it very often if you're
talking about making bubble hash all
only having resin in the 25 micron bag
I'd almost right away think that your
bag kid if it wasn't bubble bags and
even if it was for that matter not that
we've ever seen it but I would wonder if
the screens were mistaken and maybe
bigger screens got put on for the other
seven bags accidentally or some screens
were mixed up but 25 microns very small
heads even in places like Australia
where the Sun is extremely hot and
really cooks those heads down into
little heads we're full full full melt
resin comes out of the 25 and the 45
micron I still see resin in the other
bags so I'm not too sure that's you
might have just cut it down like I don't
know that's even like so early to get
all premature like all small little
heads like that unless you're growing
like in the extreme heat of like the
Australian Sun that's gonna produce
smaller heads otherwise if you're
growing indoor or almost anywhere in the
world that's not tropical outdoor then
it's likely that those heads were never
really fully allowed to mature possible
early early harvest yeah yeah fat on me
too man I like hanging out and talking
with you guys I always try to just make
it like a not too long but not too short
it's always nice when the information
flows naturally and we can just have
great conversations without too much
awkwardness like I said I'm excited for
any of you that are gonna be in the
neighbourhood of the karma cup come see
me I'm gonna be speaking I'm gonna be
out of booth I'll have Blue River
terpenes and I'm sure I'll have dabs
that I'll be dabbing everyone out with
as always just won't be selling the dabs
but if you're a chalice you can go check
out the real green dragon I believe they
might be selling the dabs although
probably not it'll probably be one of
those things where they just keep it and
say no this is just personal head stash
for the crew but we'll see let me know
if you guys run into the real green
dragon say hello from the bubble man and
yeah go follow those guys on Instagram
if you get a chance give this video a
like if you get a chance or don't
whatever I mean honestly I don't want to
ask you to do anything that you don't
want to do seems ridiculous as I came in
like my video [ __ ] your video I don't
give a [ __ ] about your video pardon my
french to buddy's two-year-old but hey
my three-year-old probably heard as well
in the meantime we should have another
day I shall we not I think so hey
already did stoner Smurfs way ahead of
the
aim it's good it's good it's good good
that you like it John Fidel yeah right
on man right on I'm just trying to have
fun and hang out with a couple hundred
people 214 people we got that's pretty
good I'm happy with that
all right that's probably enough of that
wouldn't you say
I am puffing on a tiny little bit left
of some 120 micron bubble hash pressed
into rosin Congo zigong goalies Aza
Congolese is so good yeah
we will not be Chaz Aronian you know if
you guys want to really see something
funny I'm gonna shut this guy up cuz
it's just ridiculous
this guy started an account called jazzy
bangers Google you go find him on
Instagram he is all about his chassis
bangers he doesn't call them Chaz
bangers he calls them chassis bangers
and he's basically like post your
chassis bangers he's got a hashtag it's
so ridiculous
hey what's going on from Russia man
welcome
I've never been to Russia but I would
really like to go need to have a really
good crew to receive me but I'd love to
go to Russia and trip around in Russia
check it out jazz life yeah go check out
chassis banger it is ridiculous
much like that Congo rip was YUM oh yeah
that's delicious that's tasty and we
won't be producing any chassis bangers
here uh no actually quite the opposite
uh no Malaya when I switched to
concentrates I was at a point where I
was smoking so much cannabis that my I
had hit a ceiling there was no more
getting past where I constantly was and
it was kind of a little bit of a bummer
and then I got into excuse me a little
bit of coffee err then I got into the
concentrates and yeah it was basically
every time I hit the I do not get a lot
of phlegm no I do not I woke up a little
bit
feeling like a tiny bit of a cold today
from my little son but I think it's
already most almost blown out I might
sound a little more nasally than usual
hello effect Anatole welcome I don't
speak Russian but I'm gonna think that
you might have said something like hello
from Russia or how's it going hash
family and either way it's wicked to
have some people in here from Russia I
just think the world is such a cool
place and we've been so tricked with
trying to be divided by our borders and
our languages and our cultural
differences and they are great dividers
don't get me wrong when we can elevate
ourselves beyond and above those things
we really start to respect those things
instead of resent them you know like for
me anytime I go to any country
I feel like honored to be in the
presence of another cultural group to
eat their food to listen to their music
to dance to be with the people it's just
a good thing really right on we're happy
to have you here chef at Anatole and I
hope you're dabbing wherever you are in
the motherland because wow Russia that's
big country that's like Canada you know
like when you're from Russia two people
say hey hey you must know so-and-so they
live near coz it's like you'll see that
in Canada like I have a friend from
Halifax do you know him it's like well
no I live like 7,000 miles away and
fairly far from your friend respect from
Germany John 4:20 absolutely glad to
have you mmm yeah of course Chuck that
is the attitude to have while traveling
and that's usually when you're a
traveler you know you're probably
traveling because those are the things
you're seeking out you're seeking out
these cultural differences you want to
experience other human beings living on
planet Earth in a different way with a
different vibe and how cool is that
sooner than later bingo Lombardi let's
drop another dab Sam will be is going to
be on Church absolutely yeah I know Bob
Bob's a good friend of mine he's you
know of course we do well there you go
I'll tell you the Russians and the Dutch
have a good relationship or they did
back in the day when the Dutch showed
the Russians how to sail and Wow to
Russia ever do a lot with that there's a
museum in Amsterdam that you can go to
and it is kind of treasures of the Tsar
in from Russia and it's the only place
in the world these treasures ever leave
Russia to go and it's because of this
relationship with Amsterdam Holland the
Netherlands teaching the Russians about
sailing and building boats and whatnot
so yeah this I went with skunkman Sam
and
his wife one time maybe I even just went
with skunk Mountain Sam's wife I don't
think he even came and another friend of
ours wife I wanted to go and it was all
like crazy play setting silverware and
dishes and stuff like a peck ridiculous
treasure pretty neat
we got all blasted and went in there at
least I got all blasted and went in
there
yeah Chinese what's going on man welcome
welcome welcome cool that we got some
different languages happening today we
got 229 people in the room right now
which is really cool I that's sort of
one of the higher numbers for the waking
wake-and-bake Oh going to harbor side in
a few what should I get I'm not sure
what's happening at harbor side right
now I might have to ask I might have to
find out what's fresh on the menu
because you know for for the bubble man
brand we're really really just getting
things going right now and the places
that we've worked with that have
produced property a product for us so
far hasn't been Harper's side but I know
Harbor side has some material coming
down in the near future and we will
absolutely be working with some of that
well very nice man visiting the
Netherlands I miss visiting the
Netherlands I used to go at least once a
year sometimes two three times a year
any time I would fly into Europe I would
fly into Amsterdam first and then of
course every year the cannabis cup damn
near 20 years of that it's I do miss it
I'm not gonna lie I did give away two
pins I hope you guys send me those
emails and in the email I want to see
episode 80 I want to see the pin that
you won and that you want and then I
just want in one real nice separated
spot your name and your full address so
I can just copy and paste it
that would be super helpful and I do
appreciate it and I'm sure Sara
appreciates it and I'm sure you guys
appreciate it so always happy to be
given away some things here and there
what do I think of hash out in
Washington State well Jimmy I've heard
good things about hash
Washington State it's you know I was
actually just hanging out over at the
what is it the hub studio is it the hub
studio I'll have to link them on my
Instagram but you must have seen some of
the glass that I've posted recently I
was lucky enough to go and visit Team
Japan play busting out some absolutely
ridiculous glass they're all building a
cup right now and dosa is also up from
Washington State and he was just saying
that it's quite quite wonderful in
Washington State right now with the
quality and the access that they have so
good for Washington State share all
sorts of people have complaints about it
I'm sure it's not the best that I'm sure
it's overtaxed and I'm sure it's
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah but let's just
be happy with what we have not fight
against it and fight instead instead
we're going to fight for more for what
you want you can get what you want
without fighting against what already
exists when we have our foot in the door
you know fighting against this foot in
the door mentality approach is a very
dangerous thing to fight against because
it's how the cannabis movement has moved
us forward to where we are today
nothing's ever happened major it's been
these tiny little foot in the doors and
all the way through you've had these
people saying no that's not good enough
we won't accept that we can't have it
like that if we can't have it the way we
want it we don't want it it's like who
the [ __ ] is that guy talking for because
I want whatever I can get and then I
want more and more and more and yeah of
course we'd love to have it
instantaneous but holy [ __ ] man like
people fighting against access that
already exists is completely insane we
need to get our foot in the door each
and every time and if we can get more
than our foot in the door great but
don't cut out one step at a time because
you want to jump 20 steps you know the
movement itself is not an Olympic long
jumper it's just not so baby steps right
baby steps as Richard Dreyfuss says in
the classic Bill Murray movie they call
me Bob or sorry what about Bob you'll
memory you know what about Bob classic
what about Bob Nikolas knows what about
Bob Chris Flores knows awesome that's it
look I'm say like tell us a pirate joke
I told you a pirate joke I told you all
my pirate jokes how many pirate jokes do
you think I have I mean honestly
BC bubbleman at icloud.com what is the
pirate say on his 80th birthday I'm 80
get it it's what he says I know it's
terrible it's terrible it's one of those
ones that you're not really laughing
you're just kind of like not a good way
to finish it bubble man not a good way
to finish it but you know what someone
might have gotten some enjoyment out of
that and if one person got enjoyment out
of it maybe everyone else can you know
sit on their annoyance right I'll be
your rep for bubble man brand Michigan
wow that's not and it's easier said than
done you can't cross state lines so
anywhere we set that up we have to have
our lab processing everything has to be
done in that state so I think that'll be
the horse before the cart you can be the
cart but we got to get the horse in
there first and I would love to do that
I would love to get into more states
give people access that's what it's
about right there well it was it was
better than the firetruck I was thinking
of well I told another one a while ago
Peter S which was kind of like my
funniest pirate joke which is the
classic you know the guy walks into the
bar he's got a steering wheel coming out
of his nuts it's out of his crotch and
he and he's a pirate and he the
bartender says oh my god does that hurt
and he says are it's driving me nuts so
like that's kind of a funny pirate joke
but I've told it before it is what it is
yeah you have any on the East Coast boat
man not as of yet not as of yet New
Jersey
oh I've got my finger kind of pinched
about a few weeks ago and now there's a
little bit of a sensitive nerve in the
outside part right here and I just kind
of pinched it and it's whoo I think we
better fix that with a rib should I do
the Swiss perk possibly well let's do
it's so nice I looked at my sapphire
just wasn't clean enough
yeah soil King brand don't know about
that but all right
favorite rig someone already asked me
that I like them all the one that I'm
using currently ie that can change the
one that I have
certain ones I prefer to travel with
more than other ones
if that makes any sense so there's
different times you know if I'm going
out on the boat there's certain time
there's certain ones that I like to have
with me oh that sucks chilling like a
villain I hope I didn't like do some
crazy nerve damage that'll never be
fixed it didn't even make a mark on my
pinkie but it's right in there and I
definitely pinched it between the boat
and the dock was a good one right at the
start of boating I was like it's gonna
hurt all day but it didn't I was kind of
surprised
Cannabis actually is quite amazing for
pain management and it's almost more
like it just takes the attention from
the pain receptors away and puts them on
cannabinoid receptors and it's like hey
look over here it just feels better it's
weird
mm how big of a part is taste and smell
when it comes to your relationship with
cannabis and hashish I would love to
come to st. birders Petersburg and swim
on channel rivers and see beautiful
architecture are you kidding me
I was just talking about that FET I
would always stay in the krasnopolskiy
hotel in Amsterdam and it always made me
want to go to Russia little wheeze in
the in the COFF there little wheezy I've
got some reason going on all right taste
is everything smells not that important
to you though hey Brian literal I think
smell and taste are definitely important
they're not always the same ie sometimes
it won't smell as good as it tastes
sometimes it doesn't taste as good as it
smells it's always nice when it tastes
as good as it smells like really nice I
have a sanger as well at the V 230 the
Saenger yes my boat is a singer you
can't taste without your nose well there
you go
smell dictates buzz to a degree Eliot
but it's yeah it's almost like if you
really like it and you get excited you
almost know your your consciousness
knows oh this is gonna be a good
collaboration you know because it's like
those those receptors are really
receiving some of those components when
they're smelling them into your
olfactory the Terps absolutely those
terpenes and terpenoids mine's a
[Music]
what is mine at 2007 I purchased weed
last night that smells amazing but gives
almost nothing when squished that's a
bummer maybe you're not squishing
properly or though maybe you know how to
squish properly and its really just
maybe not enough moisture you could try
Boveda packs get that moisture content
back up there moisture is a huge huge
helping factor in this in when you
squish as squishing really is a steam
distillation process you're steaming the
moisture out of the bud and that's
melting the rezident and pushing and
carrying it outward as the moisture
evaporates and disappears you don't want
too much in there otherwise it tends to
stay in the rosin and then you get that
poppy crackling rosin oh don't feel that
way Tony D all those people are
incredible in their own right and why
would you want to cut yourself off from
good information if it's out there go
support it I urge everyone when we turn
this off to go support the show it's not
a bad thing I don't feel wronged you
know what I mean Todd and I had been
talking about doing another show for a
long time so it's natural that he would
want to do a show after making the
decision after kind of putting me in a
position where I had to choose him or
someone else and I just said look I'm
not choosing anyone I'm just saying
anyone can come at any time and if the
conversation is is is proper and it's
like I need to invite this person in
right now I can't feel that someone's
gonna feel blindsided by that so I'm
gonna say don't feel bad in supporting
that show and it's all good it's yeah
come on it's gunk man Sam and Tom
Alexander and Kay and all those guys are
good dudes you should I don't want to
create any division in any way shape or
form those got a lot of those guys are
mentors and so yeah let's let's not
create the division you know and if you
do go in there be respectful if you're
going to be trying to represent me don't
be upset for me be happy for me and be
positive and be
you know share the way you would want
your children to represent your family
type of thing you know just represent
well be be be good
awesome been Willie grows the other show
is called talking with cannabis and it's
actually on right now so I should
probably let you guys all go we've gone
over longer than we needed to and so go
check it out go check out talking with
cannabis say hi to all those guys from
the bubble man and yeah made the foam L
bless your bowl sooner than later
everybody peace out