hey everybody welcome to the wake and
bake episode 85 welcome to bubble man's
world and welcome to YouTube I can see
quite a few of you have been hanging out
in the chat since I created the show we
got Darryl Cornell and Peter S and
Bingle Lombardi and Banzai breeder and
octo Tom a whole crew already chillin
and waitin for the bakes of the wakes
got my HQ shirt on today with a message
never stop growing now that could mean
never stop growing cannabis but it could
also mean never stop growing in regards
to your maturity into regards to the
evolution and the innovation of your
life never stop growing
in the meantime shall we bake the wake
good morning Martin Gillis hope you're
doing well my friend my friend thank you
yes this was from HQ I don't even know
if they put there oh yeah right on the
bottom there HQ look at that I love
their little logo there it looks like a
smiley face guy puffing on a joint
please do rinse the bong for the
occasion my bong is a little bit dirty
not gonna lie but I can hit it oh yeah
and we're gonna be Terp dippin this
morning as well I was turf dip in the
Jack Frost the other day and oh it is so
absolutely delicious reminds me that I
want to let you guys know Canadians only
apologies for those that aren't
Canadians but those of you that are
Canadians that want to try the terpenes
you can check out blue river extract CA
and I have a new code for 30% off your
order and it is blue river all lowercase
B lue
RI ve are two zero one seven Blue River
2017 that is for Canadians for the Blue
River Canada extract site you can get
yourself 30% off it's about 50 bucks of
per vial that the discount is so a good
discount well worth the time to go check
it out if you're you know looking to
looking to get turkey
yeah thanks e CJ Diego I I well I'm
trying to be awesome it's always a
difficult position in life it's not
always the easiest thing to do well
let's get this I still have a discount
code coot of course smoking leave me
hanging
there's a lot of people that spaced on
the last discount code they were a
little surprised when it ended at the
end of June and so I figured it was time
to make another one couldn't give a
shirt away today but I don't know if I
should give a small a medium a large an
extra large double XL or a triple XL oh
we're going Jack Frost we're going
congolese bubble hash rosin dipped into
Jack Frost look at that three largest
four larges in a row I don't know
yeah just give them all away right
[Music]
I say it's gonna be a large I say it's
gonna be a large I saw a lot of largest
popping up the screen and I think that's
what it's gonna be it's gonna be a large
I'm not sure exactly how I'm gonna go
about doing this because I'm just
[ __ ] playing it by ear everyone I'm
playing it by ear make sure we got our
carb cap from nish so stoked on this
nish carb cap make sure we're ready to
go I hope everyone has their dab or
their joint or their bowl or their sub
link you will drop patch you know
capsule whatever it is whatever it is I
hope you're out there and join it let's
let's let's wake the Bakke shall we on
the three two one I can't even explain
to you guys how amazing that is the
terpenes are so incredibly tasty from a
taste point from a from a from its taste
standpoint without anything else if it
wasn't even modulating and creating a
stronger effect for me I would still hit
that what is so tasty it's just [ __ ]
insane Jack Frost man holy Christ you
are the real deal Jackie Frost I'm just
cleaning up the the mild dirt and the
banger whoo I just cannot believe how
delicious that really Mike atomic skier
that's that's old-school for sure that's
only uh well the company had only really
existed for about three years at that
point in time so that is very [ __ ]
cool that you've been on it since then
you're an OG my man you're an OG all
right let's get this bowl clean such a
big big banger that it's really a job to
get all around and clean it out you can
see we got some pretty decent
cleanliness going on there what do I
think of kif Rosen well kif is dry sift
and what I think about it depends on two
things the quality of the dry sift head
ie how well was it groaned and how well
was it able to express itself both on
the cannabinoid and terpene profile and
then the purity of said head is the
purity of the Dreyse if 20% heads 40%
heads 99.9% heads these are the two
factors even when pressing rosin taking
rosin our dry sift that has been
contaminated or not sorry decontaminated
so it's just maybe 20 or 30 percent
heads you're going to have some effect
come in from the non glandular material
I don't know exactly what it is but it
will affect the quality of the resin you
will not get as nice of a resin as if I
were to clean it out and then squish it
but if you clean dry sift - 99.9 percent
heads and you get your purity and the
quality is unveiled to be a nine very
few people are gonna consider squishing
that don't get me wrong there are people
who will there's always going to be
people who will but for the most part
you really don't have to that's true
Jay Hendricks eighty-six percent of
statistics are false and that's only in
43 percent of the statistical analysis
that they've set up and done in 21
percent no I'm just joking let's have a
bolo shall we
what's 3-star sift I don't know I
honestly don't know what 3-star sift is
I I know that I would try to stay away
from it whatever it is can I make this
can I make a tiny request if I may can
you do a wake and bake making a batch of
bubble hash you know one day possibly or
in the very near future hopefully we'll
be making some bubble hash here in
Jamaica and I'll be able to do some
videos it's just that I haven't had
real material that I want to run to show
if I get the greenhouse going with Ron
in the backyard here of course we'll be
doing many many batches of bubble hash
imagine every morning doing a different
show from like the building of the
greenhouse over the course of a week
from foundation to structure to
everything lights and light depth the
whole nine yards
then the cloning then the the planting
and the soil making and the bacteria so
like all the whole nine yards just to
show on every single aspect now remember
we're we would just be sharing and kind
of learning as we go along we're not
trying to pretend that we're greenhouse
experts ron has a lot of growing history
he knows a lot about growing but by no
means would we it would be a learning
experience you guys would get to be
there with us for the entire learning
experience get to see our mistakes get
to see our successes and sort of that's
kind of the vision that I have I just
want to do that right from the start of
the grow right down to the end of the
grow where we're processing it after
hanging and drying it I think it'd be a
pretty cool show I think it would you
know for this greenhouse we would be
creating living soils we would be using
the soil balance Pro the bacterias on
the roots and we would go for as an
organic option as we can you know
potentially using biodynamic gardening
methods and tips yeah exactly Pharmacy
and Ron and I are no strangers to
mistakes ie learning people often say oh
geez you shot your sound fairly
intelligence did you go to university
and I'll say or college and I'll say no
I just made a lot of mistakes what I'm
like yeah yeah I ate a lot of mushrooms
I smoked a lot of herb made a lot of
mistakes and between those three things
right there brilliance can and will be
attained let me tell you ganja
University the school of hard knocks it
would be awesome everyone wants a
forever flowering greenhouse in their
backyard well that's for sure not gonna
be a forever flowering greenhouse mash I
hope that it is I've talked to Eric
but I've talked to some other companies
and some other people who represent
green house including Brian from vital
garden supplies so we'll see what
happens we'll see what green house we're
kind of like listen should we just go
blow 50 G's on a green house or should
we see the value that this particular
show could have how much advertising
that it'll be for this particular green
house depending on which one we buy and
we just figured there could be some
reciprocity there we're not trying to
say that we deserve a free green house
although you never know there might be a
company out there that feels that
fingers crossed we'd like to take the
money that we have for investment put it
into the surrounding area well you know
what we're gonna give a lot if this if
this green house is the one and it's
really really you know amazing and
useful I would say that they will be
making a lot of sales through green
house sales through these videos and I
would think these videos over the course
of time would probably gather up
millions of hits you know even if each
one was only getting ten or fifteen
thousand like a hash Church if you go
through the hundred and forty six hash
churches there's well over a million
views there already so well no we're not
haggling at all can of stones and it's
uh it's I was very ready to go and just
do that and someone had mentioned why
would you do that you have so much to
offer in return maybe you could work out
a deal and so that's what we're doing
work and ideal we're just trying to get
a good price we certainly haven't asked
for a free one three one would be
amazing but I'm not one to ask for free
ones at the same time I do have people
contact me on the regular and when it
works out and when I see the value of
their social media or so or or you know
where they're sharing I've been known to
give away free free bags and stuff oh
yeah sorry I didn't know what canna
stones was talking about I'm trying to
read everyone's stuff and but thank you
for letting me know and keeping me on
the right track I'm trying to talk to
Eric and what Eric actually said was
that he would try to match the best deal
that we found I wish he would have just
said here this is the deal we can offer
we could have decided whether
something for us and then I could have
already ordered the greenhouse and have
it on its way here I know that Ron has
already taken the cuts from the Congo
plants so the greenhouse cuts are
already vegging and you know while
rooting as we speak
so I would like to get on it sooner than
later probably hit him up in the near
future I want to have him back on hash
Church maybe in the next two weeks I'd
like to have Eric I'd like to have Brian
from vital garden supply I'd like to
have Peter from soil balance Pro come
back and then you know some of the
regular panelists and maybe even a few
new ones yeah now you know Jordan I'm
not interested in ending the market that
way entering the market now I could help
with my distribution to help sell
greenhouses if I found one that I really
loved I generally do that with all
things if I love something I'll try to
promote it and let people know about it
I mean the the glass cleaner I don't get
paid from the glass cleaner there's no
you know I've gotten a few free bottles
really and I guess I could have kept the
14 that he sent for giveaway if I really
wanted to but of course I I was giving
those away and I have I think I have
maybe one left today I'm definitely
given a t-shirt away but I haven't
figured out how it's going to come to be
just yet yeah Peter's very good Cuban he
impressed me I like his vibes and yeah
we'll see if we do greenhouses in
Jamaica natural alternatives Jamaica can
just do fields and they're so good it'll
really be dependent upon where we did
where our grows are and what kind of
weather and insect variables happen so
we'll learn those things as we have been
learning them over the course of the
last few years with the small research
and development projects but yeah we'll
see we'll see what happens what do you
need my help for Richard Campbell
is the greenhouse going to be just
Congolese I'm thinking it might be
sticks we haven't decided that yet oh
yeah yeah exactly
now you're talking pharmacy that's
exactly what we'll be doing oh goodness
gracious
a nice early wake-and-bake only 904 I'm
yawning I've had what if I had one rip I
have only had one rip we need to have
another rip I think we're gonna go into
the Bruce Banner this time little Bruce
Banner Terps left in there why congolese
cuz i love it why do you grow what you
grow I mean honestly I hope the answer
is not because that's what the market
dictates not that that's the worst
answer don't get me wrong the markets
important I think it's good that people
have an interest in cultivars but I also
think that the markets been so
controlled by the monopoly that is
prohibition ie only people really
willing to break the law play the game
that doesn't really bring you know the
best of the best of the best of the best
of the best
all the people who could listen I some
people are worried about these new fresh
people that are coming into the scene
and getting on cannabis because they
weren't involved for the last 20 plus
years I'm welcoming it personally I
can't wait to see the excitement from
the new group of young people that come
up and get degrees and go and study
agriculture and botany and Sciences and
go and travel around the world to you
know countries that are now legally
producing cannabis that to me is awesome
I am very much so looking forward to
just all of that how that's going to
play out in the next 10 to 20 years it's
gonna be very interesting trust me some
exceptional people are going to come
into this with exceptional minds and the
ability to execute their ideas and I
think it's all going to benefit us a
great deal obviously we don't have to
deny the fact that prohibition did not
benefit all of us it was quite the
opposite
so removing prohibition should benefit
the the scene in a very very good way
it's the way I see it Bruce Banner
oh [ __ ] and a pussy's in the house you
know
that seems like I might have to
banhammer that I don't know I don't know
we'll see we'll see
I look like Adam West's stuntman all
right cool
I don't even Adam West like Batman like
Adam West or is this like a new Adam
West I'm old I'm thinking Batman from
the 1960s boof bap Kapow Oh your bubble
hash won't bobble well that's easy
and teach you bro you just need to grow
better weed it's on I'm not even being a
dick like you have to grow better weed
that's it you called fresh head ease
left an email because your bubble hash
won't melt
dude all bubble hash does all bubble
bags does it isolates the glandular
trichomes heads from the rest of the
plant matter your quality is up to you
that happens in the grow room that
happens with the genetics and with how
well you've offered those genetics what
they require
yes collars are narrow leaf but somewhat
not the super super narrowest that's it
that's it I tried to say so many people
ask that question well you know do some
googling on micro planing there's micro
planing is simple freezing the bubble
freezing your tools breaking the pieces
into small little squares so when your
micro plane in the warmth of your hands
don't melt the paddy and kind of become
a nightmare you are gonna be shredding
heads generally when you do that which
will give the effect of a more melty
hash even when the hash is not melty I
see it as a cheat
I see fresh frozen microplaned hash as a
cheat and I see that if I take that hash
and I leave it out at room temperature
it's gonna butter out it's probably not
gonna melt as nice towards the end
I just like to sieve really is that the
truth but half of you [ __ ] are only
here for the giveaways sometimes when
you read someone's like just even like
cuz you might not have said it like in a
kind of hateful way but when you read it
it's like oh my goodness like he just
called half the people in the room [ __ ]
it's funny right hey you know what
whatever you're here for bottom line is
no judgments you're here and that's
awesome and if you're here because you
want to get some winsome [ __ ] well
that's fine too you know what I mean
you're still hearing what said you have
to be because at any point in time the
question could come that could lead to
the carrot I mean the t-shirts that I'm
giving away did you catch that reference
I'm not really trying to lead you guys
at all I'm just giving [ __ ] away I I'm
sure that it'll end one day but it seems
like a fun thing now people keep sending
me little boxes of stuff I'm gonna give
it away I love carrots do there's
nothing wrong with a carrot I want to
care it I want a carrot alright alright
uh herb Gardner have you won something
herb Gardner have I sent anything to you
herb Gardner let me tell ya
well what size carrot would you be herb
Gardner if I were to send say a carrot
what size carrot would you be would it
be like a small carrot or like a medium
carrot or would it be like a double XL
carrot what kind of like what kind of
range of carrot would you happen to be
in if you were in the market for a
carrot winner winner chicken dinner
XL will work you know I don't know if I
have an Excel bro honestly I really
don't know
I can check real quick but I think
that's the one I don't
I think it's the one I took in fact she
sent me one of almost every size so I
have a large I have an SP I have a SP
two smalls
a medium a three x XL another large and
a 2 XL so if you want to pass and go
with another contest another day I
wouldn't want to Excel it is perfect to
excel it is all right let's pull out the
two XL right here all right here's your
t-shirt bro
here's your t-shirt so karmic up
September 9th and 10th I'm gonna be
there come check me out and there's your
carrot I'll roll it up like a carrot
there you go
carrot right there for herb gardener
send me an email bc bubbleman at
icloud.com
do it soon maybe like right away EC
bubbleman at icloud.com I have already
three of the last pendants I gave away
sitting on my table in line to be
shipped this now is the fourth one which
means I really got to go today down to
the post office and send this [ __ ] off I
sound Russian well I do often do a
Russian accent it could have come out
when you do enough accents over the
course of your life sometimes they just
become you know little voices that will
come out whenever they need to come out
and so it's done with love it's not done
with any mocking whatsoever and yeah too
much borscht I would like to be here
there to be a real winner I'm not sure
what that means but all right Igor the
pump that's me
thanks for the giveaway it's an awesome
touch well you know why not why not
yeah it'll shrink it was a 2 XL tricked
me right out oh [ __ ] Mike Quinn I
remember your buddies were all around
and they were like oh our buddy was
supposed to come here and he's like your
biggest fan and I was like well I can't
remember if they said can we call him or
vice
let's call him up I think they said can
we call him would you talk to him I was
like [ __ ] sure man I'll talk to him no
problem right mm-hmm
I'm just a dude after all people are
always like wow that's amazing
I'm a dude it's not amazing I am NOT a
famous person I'm not like above anyone
I'm just a person and it's like if it's
and I love good vibes I love like
happiness and smiles and everyone goes
what oh [ __ ] and if I can be a part of
that let me tell you I'm pretty stoked
about that
it's fun it's enjoyable I mean FSS the
other day was so happy just called him
up hey what's up dude it's bubble man
he's like what ah [ __ ] it was cool I
could tell he he changed his whole vibe
yeah didn't you end up coming down Mike
when didn't I end up meeting you after
that I thought I can't remember exactly
I'll be there again though at the Karma
cup come down check it out gonna have
blue river terpenes and should be fun
yes yes Fatih Mike I am the pub man hash
dude well that is important you know
what more than being a hero I will take
that compliment which is you helped me
not [ __ ] up my hash perfect that's
exactly what I'm here for to help people
not [ __ ] up their hash and really maybe
it's for a personal agenda I might be
greedy and selfish in the sense that
when I bump into you I want your hash to
be the best hash possible so that when
you share it with me the enjoyable
experience is that much the bar is that
much higher set and so perhaps it's a
little bit greedy of me but I feel like
give that information away it's gonna
come back not just to me but to anyone
to anyone it can come back I mean [ __ ]
when someone makes great hash and then
they smoke it with you
the only thing let's talk about the
responsibility factor of growing great
weed and making great hash I'm talking
about that next-level [ __ ] above a nine
it's so next-level that it could cause
anxiety
caused discomfort in people and when you
have hash or oil of that quality I think
it's very important to when turning
someone on new when it's you know
showing them concentrate for the first
time not to try and destroy them not to
be like a childís immature high school
kid and I apologize if you're in high
school right now watching this not all
high school kids are immature but I was
a bit immature and you know we you know
we thought it was funny like Oh give him
a big glob give him a you know like we
don't want to hurt people we don't want
to turn people off and these are
powerful substances in the sense that
when taking a concentrate for the first
time in a larger dose than is necessary
you can get really really really stoned
and that's not our intention when we're
trying to turn the mainstream on to
cannabis we could show them that listen
yes this is very strong if you ate
enough I can probably do a surgery on
you if you smoked enough you could
potentially create an uncomfortable or a
level of discomfort that is maybe more
than you have experienced in the past
and so with that said it's also a
powerful medicine and when using like
micro micro micro amounts especially for
newbies for people who have never done
this before you know for people that we
want to be able to enjoy cannabis but if
we come at them and destroy them with
something so powerful and I see it
happen all the time to me you're doing
the work of prohibition you are not on
the right side of things it's not cool
destroy yourself destroy your friends
that request it but don't destroy people
who are who are have never had a rip
ever in their life really try to turn
turn them on in a proper way which is in
my opinion a micro dose something so
small that first of all when they see it
versus the the ones they've seen you
give all the other people in the room
including yourself it's like a tenth or
twentieth of what you took maybe even a
fiftieth if you're taking really big
dabs I don't take overly huge dabs I
mean even this right here would probably
be a little bit bigger than
what I would take now don't get me wrong
I could take a huge dab I just find it
wasteful and I don't enjoy it quite as
much as I enjoy you know a really nice
proper sized dab that I can finish in
one rep yes you did Rick fondle er but
do not worry we will be giving more
things away in the near future right now
we're talking about etiquette we're
talking about when someone is going to
smoke their concentrator hashish with
someone for the first time someone that
has maybe never been exposed to it maybe
they have a bit of experience with
joints maybe they have no experience
with joints so we're talking about
really showing people how to micro dab
and and get them the smallest amount so
that if they request another one they
can have another one no problem but if
you give them too much it's hard to now
say can you get rid of this feeling I'm
having an anxiety attack and I was just
kind of saying that we don't really want
to be turning people on that way that's
not that's not the way to show someone
into the wonderful world of cannabis by
producing a really uncomfortable
experience exactly cartwheel that as
well super low temp micro dose not like
super huge rip hot as [ __ ] like man so
many people putting that so many people
putting that on the nail it's not even
funny like unbelievable like rippling
hot ribs this creates an effect of
burning and harshness and coughing that
in itself is an experience that is not
really enjoyable now combine that with
extremely high someone for the first
time just taking a huge dab like that
it's just not a good combination I think
that cannabis deserves better
representation and I hope that you all
can respect that when turning new people
on to cannabinoids and terpenoids aren't
too bad for sure
you know there's that's a kind of a
great way but you know what I like to
show them dabbing I like to wood you
know why oil would taste like sulfur yes
I would absolutely know why your oil
would taste like sulfur you're not going
to like it it's a product called
defender
has a couple of other names it's a
smoker and they spray it kind of fog or
they spray it kind of for powdery mildew
it's when you have massive amounts of
powdery mildew and I say that because
when you can see powdery mildew
generally you'll have a lot so a good
way to find out this and I do it before
I run anything because of back in the
day in the 90s oh it's nasty pharmacy I
made 28 grams of Renee bubble hash like
full melt the most beautiful blonde it
would have turned to an Amber golden
amazingness smelt like pounds of weed
like just the most beautiful hash and
it's it had sulfur I hadn't checked I
was learning about this so I hooked it
right off my deck and just said goodbye
to it no need for that it's contaminant
it's not good it needs to go there's no
way to get it out and yeah powdery
mildew powdery mildew is a nightmare
from hell this is a problem when you
have people grilling cultivars that have
never had to fight mildews because they
grew up in dry arid mountain ranges not
in the jungle or in the in the
rainforests of the Pacific Northwest
you know the temperate rainforest we
have a lot of humidity and a lot of rain
here so these are the wrong cultivars to
be growing and because of it you get a
lot of powdery mildew that grows on
these plants congolese for instance is
resilient to powdery mildew because it
grew in a jungle it's used to moisture
in humidity and so over the course of
time that that plant was was bred and
selected by humans it chose to build
itself resilience ease now whether
that's the terpene profile I don't know
it's likely which is one of the reasons
we grow it right because we want that
unique terpene profile I don't want to
plant a bunch of coaches in a greenhouse
behind my house and have powdery mildew
come in and take out the whole the whole
crop yeah exactly Pharmacy that's why
people do breed their own cultivars the
sulfur comes from the product it's a
powdery mildew it's like I think what it
really does is it
is the pH of the leaf it attacks powdery
mildew in some way but it's not in any
way Anna you're still going down today
you know what I'm just gonna go poopoo I
don't know maybe it's a little bit harsh
but you've got to keep that banhammer on
the fresh fresh hammer route still can't
get the image of those mites and webs on
those plants oh my god are you kidding
me dude don't even listen for real I'll
tell you something that gave me like an
anxiety attack when I saw that like I
got dizzy and my heart started beating
and I could feel blood pumping much the
way you would if you were getting say
pulled over with a trunk full of herb
very much like that feeling just looking
at that whoo-hoo those mites all over
that plant like what a bummer there's
just nothing good about that I would
never go in that room I wouldn't even
film his phone I would be worried about
cross-contamination even over the
Internet oof gross is right thanks for
bringing it up my god whoo well 32
minutes and 47 seconds I think we did
pretty good
I see herb the herb gardener has sent me
his email so I'll probably head down to
the post office and get this stuff off
to all of you and in the meantime I hope
everyone has a great day I hope they all
have oh it's not a pic Matthew it's
located on hash Church when Tony showed
his phone with a video of mites it was
the video that made it so much worse it
really was it has been 33 minutes
actually did I ever get my email from
episode 81 I believe I did I don't know
what your email was about or what but if
it was an email that said your address
and you won something that I would
suspect it's been shipped off just
recently I shipped off like eight or
nine things that I had saved up so sure
Alex do you see why not have a bond
right before before we leave why not do
a little Ripper put that right there
get this party
if this party started boom long ripped
and trim jail
you know I was never a fan
yeah
I seem to recall you saying don't be
nervous I take rips it with purchase I
was just being funny I'm not like ego
competitive in my dabbing at all I don't
claim to take the biggest drips I just
felt like that was kind of a comedic
thing to say didn't you didn't you kind
of enjoy it on a comedian level on a
comic level comical level that would
crush your soul all right violator
yeah never stop being funny it's all
about being funny I was a class clown if
you can imagine it was like making
people laugh I thought it was like a
noble pursuit to put a smile on
someone's face just seemed like the good
thing to do let's do this
[Music]
can still taste the Terps from the last
dip
I didn't even dip that how the hell is
that possible like the ball is just
fully chirped quite delicious when are
they just gonna leave us alone hey when
are they just gonna leave us alone let
us have this point one thing after
another it would seem fully turbed dee
jazzed a little bit dark here where it's
reclaiming but that'll clean out real
nice as long as the banger itself the
dish is clean have I ever had my rig
turn blue from Terps no no I have not
what is that - Celine or Hugh I can't
remember the name of it Jim frere posted
it a few times Bobby man ribs would
[ __ ] me only I only baked flowers
well you know what that's why we all get
this is the beautiful thing about
cannabis that the bioassay and that's
why I say be respectful for people
because when they don't know what level
they sit out when they're coming in
fresh it's best for you to bring them in
smooth and nice not to like yank them in
in a way that that is discomforting for
them so cannabis can be powerful is the
oil that tastes like sulfur dangerous to
consume well you know what I'm not gonna
say that it's deuteride I wouldn't say I
trust inhaling it like what was the
sulfur sprayed for is it was a mildew
obviously so you have mildew and Pat and
sulfur that you're inhaling least to me
don't seem to be like I don't think
people have been inhaling them for
thousands of years safely the way they
have
cannabis I have faith in cannabis
cannabis produces terpene profiles and
cannabinoid profiles that seem to have
been over the course of this last
several thousands of years safe for
human consumption so sulfur it's bad man
it's bad you know and if I know it's a
hard thing because but it's education
right I know I know
so what you got to do is you got to
educate the people around you to stop
purchasing herb from this guy who's
selling sulfur aidid herb you also have
to educate him first and foremost so you
give him the chance to stop on his own
if he doesn't stop then you just have to
sort of convince the people around you
that are your friends at least that that
is no bueno
and to try and seek out a better source
because you know it's supply and demand
it's your your the demand so he produces
it the grower if this guy continues to
sell it we'll keep spraying his [ __ ]
with powdery with sulfur powdery mildew
is horrible it's like spores so if his
grow has it he's gonna have to [ __ ]
strip everything down and clean that
[ __ ] with a nuclear bomb in order to rid
himself of those spores they really are
hard to kill Spore we talked about it on
hash Church a couple of weeks ago or
maybe even last week I think it was
Peter from soil balance probe talking
about the powdery mildew Spore and how
intense it is like a bowling ball
actually is what he referrin stit - so
yeah troubles troubles hate - it makes
me feel a little dirty talking about it
I'm not gonna lie a little bit dirty oh
wow that's insane wow that's crazy isn't
that the power of cannabis you know
laughed for the first time since the
Holocaust that's a pretty serious
statement when you think about it
ideally I picture that the woman has
been through hell during the Holocaust
has not laughed for the rest of her
entire life and then 78 tries cannabis
Wow
thank you for bringing Kent laughter
back into my life that's not too bad one
of the many beaut
of cannabis you know another biological
function laughter and happiness have you
ever had to throw a crop away bubbleman
um I have thrown a crop away yes Andrew
Driscoll I did right before Johnny bee
went through his house that's why I
actually stopped growing for quite a
while Johnny bee gave me some clones and
I had been to his Grove before and
everything was fine but he gave me some
clones and it had some mildew on it and
the minute I saw it like and I saw just
one little kind of leaf had a circle on
it I just killed everything now it
wasn't a huge crop but I just got rid of
it and I cleaned all the tents and I
stopped growing it's been over a year
since I grew anything so I'm just kind
of safe like that I'll be very very
confident when we bring the greenhouse
in that there's no powdery mildew here
and that you know people who have
gardens will also kind of go through a
specific sop before they're allowed
anywhere it's not gonna be like an open
like hey you know come on over to the
greenhouse I'm gonna have to do a little
bit stronger on the SOP than that but
we'll see how it plays out you know Ron
and I are learning and it's gonna be a
fun experience I just want to have Ron
back in my life that's one of the things
I'm most excited about having him back
in my life and back in my family's life
super super excited about it so I can't
let this one fall to the wayside it has
to happen and I'm gonna keep talking
about it until it does so with that said
may the full-mouth bless your bowls
sooner than later bubble man is out
peace