hey we did it we made it we're here
welcome everyone to the wake and bake
episode 65 somehow we've managed to rock
65 of these waken bakes and that's
pretty effing cool I hope everyone's
having a great day today just gonna get
my D nail turned on and of course I
think why don't we start it off with a
bottle of Dark Crystal glass cleaner the
DC glass cleaner why not let's do it
let's get it over with I like to do it
before there's a hundred people in the
room there is 38 okay now there's 90
that was a quick jump not gonna lie
let's try and do this oh we're at 100
already I blew it next time I'll be
quicker okay so the video that we're
going to be sending you guys to in
regards to this giveaway cuz I got a
question and it's always I like you know
the numbered questions were good and
quick and easy for the camping trip but
now that I'm at home we're gonna go back
to the video so the video is called boat
session with my homie Lincoln you got
that boat session with my homie
Lincoln alright so what I'm looking for
is a simple time I'm not looking for the
seconds I'm only looking for the minutes
so you only have to give me the minute
number and I want to know at what point
in the video does Lincoln show us his
hairy crack in his ass it was one of
those moments in time I forgot to delete
I forgot to edit and unfortunately it
came through the way it came through I
totally spaced it and you know grant
Wendling you took it buddy grant
Wendling took it let me just make sure
that's a hundred percent yep grant grant
Wendling is the winner with 11 so grant
no no we're gonna go with 11 11 is the
number I was looking for I'm the pump so
grant gets this bottle for knowing at
what point in time Lincoln showed us his
air hairy ass crack so there you go dude
if you don't mind sending me an email
right this second with your full name
the the thing that you want
the episode that you won on all of that
is helpful for me when I'm going back
and looking at them and I'll send it off
today I'll put a little crystal on there
for you as I have all the other bottles
and all the other gifts that I've been
sending away for the last 28 gifts and
in the meantime uh yeah yeah Tyler don't
even go there
youyou were right here in fact here
Tyler here look at Tyler let's see was
Tyler before Grant or after I'm gonna
say he was after looks like grant is the
winner yeah you know I had to have that
[ __ ] on lockdown because I knew someone
was gonna [ __ ] like a little baby
that's okay now calling you a little
baby but you kind of are anyway let's
get it on let's have a nice wake and
bake we gave a bottle away let's all
congratulate Tyler oops I mean grant
Tyler lost grant won I am the pump and
not only that but I have it on my screen
because I knew the second you can't give
anything away without someone being a
little kind of but that's okay hey let's
have a puff and this puff is going to be
for Tyler so we're not completely
heartless here at the bubble man's world
we're gonna have a puff and this puff is
gonna be for Tyler so close close but no
cigar due next time maybe you'll get it
who's to know it's just a fun game it's
not a big deal let's let's all
congratulate grant actually oh we're
waiting sir globs we're waiting we're
waiting yes the bong rip is for Tyler
the DC glass cleaner is for grant that's
how it's gonna go this morning
pretty good huh wake and bake yesterday
we had some nice information getting
passed of course I went back and wrote
more on the hash blog which is at
bubbleman brand calm still not live but
that's where it's going to be oh yes
there's always tomorrow I've got so many
more bottles of this stuff and so many
more dab mats and other things yeah
exactly yeah exactly bingo Lombardi
knows that's good all right we ready to
rock here guys a little bit of a wake
and bake I've got my Swiss
I want to give a shout out to the dizzle
mr. Nate dizzle always taking care of me
with this beautiful beautiful last of
the hand bopped the hands spun he got a
lathe after this so I did see the Leafly
article about hash Church sub cool in
the grow to brown tooth table very very
cool very nice to see glad that some
people are receptive if you need some
cleaner I would say that the price is
reasonable the guy's good the cleaner is
great it's worth purchasing honestly go
support the guy's company go spend 10
bucks it's worth it I'm hitting a little
bit of a mix of rosin here
sixteen there you go well within your
reach yum yummy oops
you droppin torches droppin torches you
know I lost the bottom on this thing and
it just constantly fall so it's probably
best to just leave on its side luckily
all it fell on was one of my old bangers
hey PA
we're still waiting unfortunately our
license never came in in the first
twelve that was received I guess some
pretty big players were we're involved
but we're still hoping on getting our
second application and we're gonna
reapply for the first one as well in the
sense we it's a grief group that I'll be
a part of if they acquire their license
to do processing for so the unique thing
about the processing aspect is is we
ourselves are not actually applying for
licenses the groups that we've created
partnerships with are so in the end even
if our groups didn't get licensing I
suspect what we would do as processors
is we would approach those who did
receive licensing and we would suggest
to them that potentially we create a
partnership so it used to be 25 on
Amazon the first time bubbly I mentioned
it wow it's going down in price that's
great to hear
[Music]
cat no bat day you've been trying to buy
some DC DC's from Canada bro try
checking their internet either their
Instagram or go to Amazon Canada wow
that was a good one a good one
excuse me sorry for coughing nobody
likes to hear someone call that much
what to talk about today I guess we
could talk about dry sifting a little
bit I've been asked to do a one-gallon
video of many at times it's really all a
matter of it falling together having us
that uncomfortable enough within running
and cleaning and and shooting the whole
thing because when you do these videos
they really need to be done properly and
simply I think what's going to happen is
I've been writing the blogs for the dry
sifting and the wet washing our top lab
is obviously in California with Tony
right now so I think the photography and
the video will be done there so I'll
have him run the one gallon the five
gallon and the 20 gallon I'll be on the
Skype explaining exactly how I want it
to be done and then that SOP that
information will go on to the website
and then of course people who want to we
kind of want to have it as such that you
can purchase from the brand but if you
have your own abilities you're a home
grower and you want to buy the kit and
you want to be able to make the best
possible hash possible we want that to
be a reality as well and I'm sure Blue
River will probably even be you know
doing a variety of things like maybe
potentially selling the the phils
which we make for our pens that are
going to be released if you've looked at
bubbleman brand
recently on Instagram it said bubbleman
Trinity coming soon and those are the
Trinity carts that were designed by Gary
from Omicron and the good people who
designed the Hercules pen cartridge
reusable non you know not something that
you just toss and throw away and so
that's coming here in the new in the
near future pretty excited about it
actually pretty stoked to get one and
fill it up with Terps and try it out
myself
can't believe Lindsey Snyder did not
pull a license in PA that's what I'm
saying drew it's pretty crazy a lot of
people applied all sorts of people
supplies
yeah the Hercules is great the Hercules
is what inspired us to want to create
this other cartridge that we're going to
be creating that's why I got in touch
with Gary the team was myself Gary and
Tony and we created this this trinity if
you will a trilogy the three of us and
thus the Trinity cart was born and so
yeah we're pretty excited about it it's
gonna be good it's safe it's it's
inexpensive but it's not disposable we
want to we'd rather sell you reusable
syringes where you can just plug into
the cartridge and fill it back up rather
than puff a half gram and toss it and I
think we're gonna make our cartridges a
little bit bigger than a half gram as
well yeah I think it's gonna be just
under a gram Nicholas I think it's gonna
be about three-quarters of a gram 20.8 I
think point eight is what we decided on
all right yes MD 73 in the house PK
brewer John Maddox sir globs a la luster
burn chillin like a villain octo Tom and
melty heads and Lois Lane kind of feel
like I'm getting to know you guys like
here we go we got a hundred and fifty
people in the room on a Wednesday at
9:21 and the bake is on and did you say
that that will be available in the US
yeah it's gonna be sold out of
California Tony will be moving those
down I'm sure through places like
Harborside places like Berkeley patients
group and hopefully a whole bunch of
other places as well and then it would
be cool to be able to sell them here in
Canada if I can get you know I'm gonna
continue to do the terpenes if I can
sell them you know thirty percent
already filled with the terpene Pro
file then you know all you really need
to do is dump that you know emulsify it
into your whatever your product is and
then you can do your own refills with
them as well not just be forced to
purchase from someone else
yeah me too Nikolas I'm not sure what's
going on there I'll have to figure it
out I guess really in reality the state
thing is difficult right because you
can't really cross lines so it's all got
to be produced in each state and that's
yeah the shirt the Terp sugar is going
to be available for Canadians for sure
I'm getting it and putting it up for
retail for sure I want people to be able
to have it and try it and say they've
been able to you know experience it I
myself want to experience it and so
absolutely I'm gonna be making that
available sounds good David for Kerr
thanks for coming in yes sir globs lot
you know I used to have an emoji years
ago when a chat room called true stoners
and it was my fingers holding up a
little piece of hash up to the Sun so it
looked like it was blowing yellow
instead of the closer to reddish amber
color that it was anyway somehow my
friend Steppenwolf who owned the site he
cut it into a tiny little picture and he
turned it into a little he actually did
it for all of us there was was Towe who
had a big tow truck emoji and we all
kind of had our own emojis but let me
tell you I was pretty stoked on that
emoji that was a long time ago like I
want to say that was potentially in like
1999 or 2000 it's going back for sure
mmm I don't know when dr. Bob is gonna
come on hash Church next to be honest I
thought what I might do with dr. Bob is
do a private seating with him maybe with
one or two other people but different
than hashed Church I found that whenever
he comes on hash Church he's so out
there that the panelists can't just not
criticize and critique what he's saying
before he even says it and it's made me
fairly uncomfortable I'm not interested
in having people argue his perspective I
want to hear his perspective
afterwards I don't
having a discussion but with dr. Bob you
really need to hear what he has to say
and that can take up to two hours before
it's done so if you spend the first hour
arguing with what he's saying and he can
never just get it all out then you don't
really hear it as the way it should be
heard at least in my opinion the way I
want to hear it and the way I want to
offer it up to my audience yeah there
you go
dr. Bob was next level yeah I think dr.
Bob is amazing I really really enjoy it
really enjoy it
yeah indras pictures for sure I always
liked indras stories in the beginning
when he first came on hashed Church he
always told some pretty awesome I love
hearing about old Indian stories India
and traveling and generally you know I
love that from Sam as well when he talks
about his trips to Afghanistan and other
hash producing countries of the world
both super awesome for sure but I just
you know and all the hashed Church guys
are amazing but I just I think dr. Bob
requires his own you know two-hour to
three-hour block of just maybe just an
interview maybe myself and him or maybe
one or two other people maybe Todd wants
to sit in on it he's always got good
questions but dr. Bob's a tough one
because you gotta really let him finish
his thoughts before you jump all over
them and so when I saw him recently
speak he said listen please don't try to
attack right away just listen to what
I'm saying and then we can have the
discussion so yeah yeah I will I will I
will yeah I don't know if it'll be a
morning wake and bake I'm not sure but
definitely some type of a show exactly
Andrew you said it dude and you know how
we all are we're all [ __ ]
interrupting each other on hash Church
like mother [ __ ] it's just our
passion we're into it but you know both
times I had dr. Bob on I can't it was
kind of Mara one time and I can't
remember
was the second time but it was basically
like just constantly all over him like
what about this what about that no no
this is that was just like oh [ __ ] you
need to just be we need to just let this
man talk I for one feel of a true like I
feel truth when dr. Bob talks I feel
like it's a valid discussion well you
know what Spock durometer it's hard we
don't we try not to begin to become a
pissing contest but we're all very kind
of alpha personalities we've all been
involved for a long time and you're
absolutely right in the sense that we
all absolutely have our own insecurities
and those insecurities come up through
the show when we feel the urge to tell
people that you know that we're
responsible for this or that or that we
are though you know when we when we get
into the pissing contest and I'm I've
been responsible for it for sure I'm not
gonna lie I have insecurities and I've
jumped into the pissing contests for
sure what hashed Church is teaching me
slowly but surely is that the profit for
MS bigger than me and that I sometimes
just need to sit down shut up and look
inward at myself as I expect all of my
panelists to as well that this has
become bigger than any of us that if we
replace the whole panel me included hash
search could continue it could it could
continue on because there's great people
in the cannabis industry have I picked
and chosen some amazing ones absolutely
oh my goodness we have some incredible
panelists each and every one of them
were special in their own right at the
same time you know if we all went down
tomorrow in a plane we would be replaced
quickly and wonderful incredible
information would continue to flow and I
think that's the magic of the platform
and yeah it's interesting it is one big
trip I see you know sometimes I realize
how much of an inspiration it's had on
so many people all over the world how
much it's helped educate people how much
it's helping people educate the people
in their lives because they know the
information but after watching all of
this dialogue back
fourth and listening to it you've become
extremely educated in these
conversations and it's okay that
sometimes we'll repeat things and that
we'll go into things that we've already
said before because it's an ongoing
conversation and certain people are
tuning in that weren't tuned turn tuned
in before so it's what's that what would
be sad oh yeah yeah of course us all
dying in a plane would be ridiculous it
was more just like a metaphor of the
importance of showing that life would go
on without all of us the platform itself
is the most important factor and yes us
feeding our passion into it is very very
very important but I see a lot of great
people doing it now I see sub pools got
his channel going I see the gentleman
with the round table the Diago daegil
all sorts of great things are happening
and it makes me happy I actually got an
email and recently I wish I could check
my phone because he invited me on his
show the round table and absolutely I'm
gonna reply and go on his show he even
wrote in it that he thought maybe there
was some animosity and that he had heard
I was upset about him and his showed a
go yes of course not
of course not and when he told me that
he he was inspired by hashed Church to
start his show and it made me super
happy that's awesome you can never
listen if what we we're a part we're
like a step in the ladder hash stretch
is a step in the ladder and if we get to
be a couple of more steps that's amazing
and great but I'm not connected to it if
someone else comes out with the next
amazing show that everyone's focused on
and paying attention to wonderful that's
just great
I mean honestly I can't I can't support
it anymore and you will see me on that
show because I just got an invitation
and I don't know when the show is but I
will be emailing him back today and
letting him know that absolutely I'll
come on the show it sounds like a plan
what's the shirt today well this is a
Jesse royal shirt and the small acts if
you are a small
max right small acts so Jessie royal one
of my favorites in comes the small acts
check them out on YouTube got some great
songs off the top of my head the Jesse
Royal what is it modern-day Judas I
think was the one that really grabbed me
it was up there with Kibaki
free from chains those two were my
anthems for a while while I was in
Kingston I would just wake up and listen
to them constantly Jessie's got a whole
bunch of great songs never been lucky
enough to chill with him or see him live
as of yet but that is for sure coming
nice Mitch that's awesome love to see
Jesse might have to consider July 14th I
don't know if I can get out there when's
that cannabis thing again is that in
June
yeah Damian Marley is wonderful great so
love them all yeah finally is a great
song give me likkle give me little is
his new herb song which is also a great
song what else do we got here we got
Kwanzaa warning to all is good hotter
the battle raindrops
yeah modern-day Judas is my all-time
favorite this morning quite different
from the rest of his stuff if you punch
in this morning it's a little bit more
mainstream you can almost see what they
were going for but it's got a great beat
and it's uplifting and I mean [ __ ] maybe
we could listen to it should we listen
to it don't want to get in trouble
yeah dub syndicate is dopes Big Ups
James Smith from the UK for to the UK
from Canada we got her on our money too
for sure for sure for sure she's on our
money there she is
yeah can't get away from it maybe in
Canada but that Queen is all over our
cash let me tell you let me tell you
so what else what else can we say yes
the shape-shifting reptilian absolutely
there you go I guess I heard recently
that the guy
the the MIAA gentoos on his deathbed
announced that he killed all sorts of
people for the crown for national
security whatever their version is
pretty crazy story you never know what's
real and what's not real anymore so I
take everything with a grain of salt you
know kind of just listening to it as
information I kind of like the way David
David Icke who's a completely not Vulcan
conspiracist for most perspectives but
one of the first things he said in his
book was not to listen or or believe
necessarily anything that he was writing
about but see if it rings true to you
see if any of it throughout your daily
life rings true and unveil certain
things and there definitely was levels
of that I would say hey what's going on
silly Simon sly
yeah double-oh-seven stuff for real am i
planning to visit the island sooner than
later well which island are you talking
about trichomes City because I'm not
gonna lie there's a few of them out
there well I never sold CBD that was
Tony down in California I am not
convinced that CBD is legal to sell I'm
not really willing to practice that
level of civil disobedience I don't sell
any cannabinoids up here in Canada I do
sell cannabinoids or at least my brand
is branded down in California selling
cannabinoids and terpenoids oligo
mechanism for me to do so so I have been
unable to do so I'm waiting for for you
know Canada to allow extracts I can
create extracts for myself I have mines
inclined from from so long ago the first
one was actually catalytically altered
water now thanks to Mitch we've been
doing and he's the one that would have
to explain this better than me but some
type of molecular manipulation
something's going on you're activating
the waters of more living water I
believe was the was the quotation but
yeah we have it on one of our hoses in
Jamaica right now Mitch would be the one
to break that down hey welcome from
Rainey Scotland it's usually rainy here
- but today it's sunny actually might go
get my boat thinking of driving out to
the WAC and get in my boat it's a long
drive I'm not gonna lie but would be
nice to have the boat all of a sudden
it's that responsibility of course you
know a hundred days or so of it sitting
out on the front lawn
etc being responsible do have a video
taking you through the tert making
process no that's Tony's information and
he doesn't share that openly and I I
don't really doubt him you know it's a
pretty major thing the way he's doing it
it's of a high value at the same time
you know I was all I show I've always
showed everything that I've learned over
the years I've never kept anything to
myself as a secret
other than skunk man Sam secret which is
you know not my secret to share so it's
it's easy not to share your own secrets
to just to not share your mentor secrets
but for myself I don't have any I share
everything I just share everything it
seems to be the good way it's how my
business was built you know it made
sense to just tell everyone how they
could do it the best way they could do
it and then people would hit me up and
go yeah but can you uh can you tell me
you know some tips that you don't share
with anyone else
and I'd be like I don't have tips that I
don't share with anyone else I just
share everything that's the way it's
always been
dab time I don't have a dab went on
let's have a go it's a wake and bake
Wednesday afternoon I've got some
friends coming in from out east today so
that'll be nice to see those guys see
what they're up to
my dads are shattering didn't want to
cross that line that's right I don't
think well there you go it might be
legal in some states but we can all
agree especially that the federal law is
for sure
because the federal law for all
cannabinoids is this is illegal so it
just gets dangerous it's one thing if
you're protected in a state it's another
if you're shipping over state lines and
in particular international
Alliance now you also have people who
are selling pure isolate and feeling
comfortable about it because they go on
Amazon and see people selling an oil
that they call CBD oil and they're
shipping it over the border but that CBD
might be point zero one percent which is
the legal limit of hemp seed oil to have
as a natural contaminant not as
something that they're actually it's
snake oil salesmen there's not it's not
really medicine they're selling it as
basically like they're legally allowed
to have a little bit so they can put it
on the on the on the container and right
CBD oil and ship it and that's a pretty
shitty thing to do if you ask me
nobody's testing that accustoms that's
what I'm saying but the guys who are
selling isolate are getting confident
because of these guys who are selling
hemp seed oil that has tiny bits of CBD
contaminant in it and they're snake oil
salesmen selling it as CBD I'm saying
don't let that make you comfortable to
think that you should be able to sell
isolate over borders over state lines
and over international borders I would
be wary I would be careful of that
especially with Jeff Sessions trying to
be nasty
oh yeah we'll be doing boat dabs maybe
old goat wake and makes in the very near
future very near future I suspect I
suspect Oh Diane 73 yes you absolutely
can happy birthday we are the same age
you and I birthday shout out to Diane
born in 73 much like the bubble man who
is also 44 years old not today but some
days ago yeah that's pretty much the way
to do it MD some of the best I've ever
made was her best I've ever had was
myself as well but probably the best I
ever had was skunk man Sam's I'd have a
hard time beating that that [ __ ] was
from another planet seriously
sift Kotik its sift Kotik we just feel a
pump
yes I twelve ah there you go
well Indra I grew up with a French
family and french grandparents they
spoke fluent French around me and I went
to French immersion school it quoted SEK
Tycho in Winnipeg Manitoba and I'll tell
you I'm glad that I did it's very
helpful when I go to Europe and I'm
speaking with people whether in
Switzerland or Germany or Amsterdam or
wherever where they don't speak English
but they will speak a little bit of
French and so when you speak a little
bit of French I mean at least one other
language I wish I spoke seven or eight
languages just never really had the
energy to put into it maybe something
I'll do as I get older I'm not sure but
I think it's a huge bonus a huge
advantage to be able to speak French in
Spanish Italian you know other languages
a multitude of languages over your
mother tongue so for me I think that's a
huge advantage to ever let pump no I
think that is a false a very cool silly
Simon that's awesome props to you very
cool I once met a sadhu in India who
spoke over 50 over 50 languages and
self-taught you know he'd sit on the
Ganges we were at the Maha khumba mela
and he would just pull people out that
he saw walking by and he would call them
over and then he would speak to them in
their language if they were Korean or if
they were Chinese and it was pretty
impressive to say the least
at one point he said he had probably a
dozen of us sitting around him all from
a different place you know place
speaking different languages to all of
us and how
us communicate with one another because
we didn't all speak each other's
languages and it was just a pretty
amazing experience the main I guess
connector if you will was hashish we
were smoking Chilam so that's why we
were sitting with him the Chilam was
really the main thing that was going
around and then the conversation the
dialogue much like these waking baek's
where we get together we have a little
bit of cannabis and cannabis seems to
sometimes really create a wonderful
dialogue amongst people yeah very cool
very cool Indra you ever had Frenchie
cannolis hash I do believe I have had
Frenchie cannolis hash I absolutely yep
all right something that guy that was
some chars to the UN teach him he said
the Chilam is cashed in Chinese right
he said one more Chilam we are making
one more Chilam we are making yeah
what's the combo flow exactly I'm not
sure what that supposed to mean
theme-park nerd but I guess you gotta go
bro I guess you gotta go sorry I
deducted I love chars hate the tobacco
yeah for real chills um I had a little
Frenchie cannoli hash there you go
thanks beer and yeah I gotta get rid of
people that are being you know I won't
even give them a platform the thing
about social media is is that you build
your platform so that's why that's why
there's this certain thing that you
don't go and do on other people's
platforms you don't go use other
people's platforms to spew hatred
vitriol and and and negativity you don't
promote your self promote yourself too
much with posters and website links and
links to your groups and pages that's
another thing I'm always choked at in
hash Church where people will post like
hey you know this is my event or
whatever I'm like man come and start a
conversation don't just post your thing
I want to start conversations so there
are etiquette that we don't do we don't
go and [ __ ] do weird porno links on
on people's social media platforms I for
one love
the fact that we've moved away from you
know large-scale websites where you
could make a post and then anyone could
write anything they wanted to because
those things really take direction and
they they redirect the energy of which
you've built this incredible platform
whatever your social media attraction is
you build this great audience and then
you don't want people to abuse it you
know particularly like the last guy who
was spewing racist comments that I just
had to block out of the room it's like
what the heck are you doing man your
order has already been fulfilled Felix
your order got sent out the other day
I'll send you your tracking number I
have to go into the website for whatever
reason there's a disconnect there and we
send them out long usually when I go in
I have to click that it's been shipped
and that's why you're seeing that it is
not shipped as of yet but don't worry
boss it's coming to you we got it and
yeah 200 people there you go ok Bubba
man did you notice any difference
between regular THC strain and high CBD
strain water extracts well other than
the fact that you tend to get a lower
amount of the CBD at least from the
cultivars that I've run in the past not
too much you got to hit that bubble when
it needs to be bubbled yeah that was
classic I can hear him saying and it
makes me smile actually vets do need
free weed I'm surprised that the US
government isn't producing it for them
oh absolutely mines Inc inclined I will
absolutely go back to India potentially
the Himachal you know valley I know I
don't dank nug lists I actually don't
there you go that's a good name for it
in draft Avenue coughs up and obviously
the day I want to job in the cannabis
industry you hired dude create your own
job in the cannabis industry that's the
beauty of the cannabis industry you just
create your own job you just do what you
need to do Parvati mallanna
Himachal Pradesh all those areas it's
all like one beside the other you can
roll in there and go hang out with the
chief of each little area and make some
rub and make some water hash
I've had some friends that I've sold
bags to that have gone up there and
shown the Chiefs they know about water
hash and bubble bags they're no stranger
to it that's for sure
and I'm glad that it never took away
from that you know it was a sort of it I
didn't I was being a little wary in the
sense of like I'd hate to just change
the way someone's been doing something
do I have any Milla screens I'm not even
sure what that means no why would I have
Milla screens screens that Miele sold I
have a bubble man bubble bag screens all
my screens are of my own have you ever
heard of Graham Hancock and his theory
of an ancient lost civilization I was
hanging out with Graham Hancock just a
month ago talking about his theory of
ancient lost civilization with him
personally chase we both spoke at the
cannabis and hemp conference that Salome
put on here in Vancouver at the
University of British Columbia and yeah
he was a keynote speaker and I have
heard of him I've read his books from
many years past and would you believe
cannabis was a huge inspiration for him
to go and do all that research big
inspiration to Graham so very cool had
not known that when Psalm and it was
enjoyable it was funny because I was
sitting next to Chris Bennett and Chris
Bennett and him kind of like bump heads
a little bit so hey that's good to hear
Mitch get on those bubble bags let me
know what happens it's better hash rosin
or dry sift well that depends you know
for me the highest resolution the
highest possibility the best expression
of both bubble hash and dry sift are my
favorite now if you took both of those
and squished a little rosin well that
would be lovely too you could put all
three of them on the plate I'm always
yeah Rupert Sheldrake more for genetic
resonance theory I first read Rupert
when I got turned on to him via Terence
Mckenna I also was lucky enough to meet
Rupert once in my life now Rupert
Sheldrake and Ralph Abraham never
Terence Mckenna though unfortunately
which is really a bummer but I did get
to meet his son Finn at a psychedelic
conference where I had a booth where I
actually a very cool look Louis yeah
Rupert's cool I I loved his books really
kind of opened my mind
that was interesting theory and it made
it rang true you know it was one of
those things that just rang true and
then of course fractal chaos mathematics
interesting Ralph Abraham fractal
mathematician great in a book with all
three of them try logs at the edge of
the West both with Rupert and Ralph as
well as Terrence and it was maybe one of
the most inspiring books to me as a
young person I was only maybe 20 years
old or 22 years old when I read that
book and it really really really blew my
mind
yeah yeah Finn I met Finn and another
really cool dude the psychedelic
gatherings that travel around and have
these little events where the different
people that have written books speaking
etcetera are really small small
communities and you can really meet some
amazing people at those events I'd say
if one is coming to your city absolutely
go hit it much smaller community than
than the cannabis community for sure
yeah
any thoughts on introducing regenerative
land techniques to your farm in Jamaica
maybe a stable and providing for
Jamaican economy Freddie oh yeah Ian
holla absolutely the whole nine yards
I'm personally not going to be the
grower but you can bet your ass for the
project in Jamaica that everything we do
we're going to want to have some form of
philanthropy that goes towards the
island and the people that just has been
from day one whether it's producing and
helping clean and recycle fill potholes
pay taxes build schools build hospitals
build other types of things I I would
suspect that in the success of the
company that you will see many things
like that it seems like it's the only
way that it could be really almost
hitting an hour long wake-and-bake that
is true probably gonna cut it short I
actually have a few things to do today
especially if I'm going to be doing this
a long drive to go get the boat but
thanks everybody for tuning in I really
do appreciate it and
Mich have a great time at the event I
guess that you're gonna be going to next
week or even closer or sooner it might
might be right around the right around
the corner do you have any do you have
do you I don't even know what that
question said I think it's best to write
the whole question with no abbreviations
sometimes if you want me to answer it
how often does it to make a flood jeez I
don't know I'm not always there but we
definitely had a good one recently thank
God we were able to pump the water out
of our fields nicely because we have
such a huge area to put water there it
is ancient cannabis a channel there it
is they hate us cuz they anus anyway
everybody thanks so much for tuning in
to this wake-and-bake we'll have another
one tomorrow as we do will the next day
and may the foe melt
bless your bowl sooner than later peace
out everybody