hey it worked I'm so glad it worked
happy Canada everybody happy wakin bacon
soda 74 I'm going to be giving away one
of my good buddy Dana Larson's books
today green buds and hash this is a
[ __ ] awesome little book when I first
saw it it threw me off a little bit I
was kind of like wow oh he's doing these
kids books but he's making a cannabis
like I wasn't I was a little like Oh
what and then as I read the book and I
learned more about what what Dana was
doing with Harry pothead and with green
buds and hash and a few other different
books I really saw that the parody was
really educational and there was a whole
bunch of information that he was passing
on that would be good for parents to
read to their kids particularly if maybe
they're using cannabis as a medicine and
they want to kind of break into the ice
the book I wanted to give away today was
a copy of cannabis in Canada another
book by Daniel Larson he had wonderful
artwork done throughout the whole book I
myself have a page in there with my
Manitoba hemp guys and yeah this is a
dana Larson parody green buds and hash
it's it's [ __ ] hilarious I mean just
to give you a little uh you know this
guy's trying to get him to to take and
to have a puff you know would you like
them in a joint anyway I won't read the
whole book to you there are some pretty
funny things in here the video that
we're going to be getting the question
and the answer from okay is going to be
called Dana Larson green buds and hash
and I did a video with him Oh back in
May of 2015 just on his couch in his
living room there we talked a little bit
about it in the first 20 minutes it's
between 15 and 20 minutes there is some
cream on his desk and I want to know the
name of the cream and I also want to
know which category it is so you're
gonna give me the name and then you're
going to give me the category of that
cream and you will win this book so go
check out that video it's called Dana
Larson greed bugs green buds and hash
and
Daniel unit you gave half the name you
gave half the name
that's good does anyone want to finish
Daniels answer off with the whole thing
I want to know the name of the yes
there's bud rich with half of it so bud
rich has had half of the answer and
Daniel had half of the answer what I'm
looking for are there two answers
together so if anyone wants that that's
kind of the easiest way I can give it to
you
you know MJ cream comb lavender calomel
MJ cream calm JC Figgins I'm gonna give
it to you you seem to be the first one
that actually put the two answers
together and so chase eat Figgins you
have a nice new book coming to you from
Dana Larsen's and if you want I will get
Dana Larson to sign it like he did for
me to bubbleman
thanks for all you do for green buds and
hash gotta love it so chase you win the
book I hope that you get much enjoyment
out of that and hey Anthony if there's
no point on trying then [ __ ] it don't
try I mean [ __ ] don't even write that
you're not gonna try there's not even
any point in writing that you're not
gonna try because nobody [ __ ] cares
I personally don't anyway but I do care
that JC Figgins tried and that he won
the book I think it's fun I'm always
excited for people when they win the
book I'm not gonna lie but I'm more
excited to be able to bake my wake of
course what's my email again BC Bubble
mana icloud.com is the email and thank
you for reminding me JC Figgins I try to
give it out every time fresh but clearly
I spaced it this morning so let's have a
bud let's have a little little dab dab
dab around you'll never win if you don't
try you know Peter s that is so true
Betty sheets with the half answer a
little bit late morning there Brian
Steve chillin like a villain is in the
house DK trades Alan Mota bud rich
Norwegian frog Tara Lee and John keel
Bay wakey baekje vape so thank you for
everyone I'm down with that
I am down with that I'm gonna hit a
little bit of this Kongo last tiny
little piece of it actually pretty
excited
rip it up got a long day ahead of us on
we're gonna go out on the boat today do
some wake skating and some wakeboarding
and some wake surfing all the wake funds
obviously and some Canada Day experience
I'm not too sure what exactly will
happen but it should be fun tomorrow we
got a pretty good show poppin together
for hashed Church still trying to get
alyc from from SC labs and going to be
getting this gentleman Peter from soil
balance Pro come and talk to us about
different strains of probiotics of
bacterias beneficial bacteria that can
help cannabis express itself to higher
degrees of what it what other was I have
a couple of weeks gates lip but I'd
honestly like I bought so many of these
things I'd have to literally look at the
name of it because I don't even remember
I bought a really really new one
recently that I like my old ones pretty
much just a board you know with a little
bit of rubber on top the new one has
like a super thick coating you can go on
there and bare feet and stuff hydrofoil
no I don't have any hydrofoil on order
just yet but here let's get the bacon on
guys got the Klein 7.7 sub-8 cleaned up
for the day and we're gonna dip into the
D nail sapphire let's do it
excellent getting peeled sent out your
package the other day I'm not sure the
release of crisp annex new book but I
could have him come out on a
wake-and-bake maybe offer one up for a
gift and come talk about it how about a
few pages from green buds and hash it's
Canada Day would you like them in a bomb
would you like them all day long no I
would not in a bomb no I would not all
day long I do not like green buds in
hash I do not want them mr. stache would
you like them wrapped in paper will you
try them now or later I do not want them
wrapped in paper I do not want them now
or later I do not want them in a bong I
do not want them all day long I do not
like green buds in hash I do not want
them mr. stache good old mr. stache a
[ __ ] guy so this goes on for a while
you know he's talking about glaucoma and
a mass he's really breaking it down
would you like it in a tincture I could
show you how to make it I offer buds and
hash for free there is no benefit for me
someone said that you were sick green
buds and hash might do the trick
hahaha exactly spoiler alert alert hey
do you find you're getting thinner with
no appetite for dinner do you suffer
from sclerosis epilepsy or neuroses for
almost all the ills that a Leo buds and
hash will never fail you have glaucoma
PMS green buds and hash have much
success for protection against strokes
it's best to have some potent oaks if
your muscles are not dandy try some
green bud infused candy for migraine
spasms even cancer green buds and hash
provide the answer if you're not feeling
right then have green buds and hash
tonight it's true I am not feeling great
my house been rather poor of late my
doctor says that I have ills he told me
I should take these pills I cannot even
sleep at night I never do feel quite all
right well no [ __ ] bro don't listen to
that doctor
he'll [ __ ] you all up I will try green
buds in house I will try them mr. stache
alright we're getting through to this
[ __ ] and
his first puff his first puff oh look
how happy he is look at that guy right
there hey now I am feeling good they
work just like you said they would I
have never felt this fine green buds and
hash are quite divine I will bake a
green bud brownie whenever I am feeling
frowny I will try them vaporize that tea
technique seems very wise I will take
them in a texture and in every other
mixture look at this guy he loves herb
he learned the secret perhaps I would
prefer to puff and stop when I have had
enough I will roll some juicy joints and
smoke them down into little points I
will toke upon the bong I will do it all
day long I really like green buds and
hash I do enjoy them mister stache
thanks for being so insistent and for
being so persistent my mind and body are
improved my spirit also has been moved
though I was told they are a sin green
buds and hash are medicine I'm sorry
that I was so hateful now I know I
should be grateful thank you thank you
mister stache thank you for green buds
and hash yeah dude Thank You Dana Larson
for putting together such a cool little
book I think that that is a real fun
little story I didn't read the whole
thing there was quite a bit of him kind
of trying to turn the dude on and get
him to try some cannabis of course you
know it's a classic story really done
and a parody of a dr. Seuss but we all
know the story we all have our
grandparents and some of us have our
parents that are very endocannabinoid
deficiency and it's one thing to have a
negative against cannabinoids and and
you know feel people that use them are
negative and have this sort of prejudice
towards it but it's another to cut
yourself off from the actual benefits
that it could be giving you so I think
that that book is a real neat little way
to educate through the parody of dr.
Seuss which we all love dr. Seuss I mean
my goodness couldn't have picked a
better one really and I think we should
have one more little dab what do you
think The Grinch grinning the rasen
pressed has squeezed out its last drop
Tina Larsson is great I want to give a
mad shout out to Dana Larson he has done
so much good for the cannabis seen here
in van
Coover really from the beginning days
when I first met him Dana was the editor
for cannabis culture magazine that was a
long time ago like over 20 years I want
to say and he's done a lot since you
know when Mark went to jail Dana really
picked up the slack he started opening
dispensaries teaching people how to open
dispensaries he's got his MJ cream
company he was doing sensible BC he's
running for the NDP he's like the guy is
really busy and I just think that all
the work that he does is really good and
you couldn't really support a better
person in the cannabis industry if you
put money towards Dana or his companies
you know the majority of it goes right
back into the industry the community you
know activism so yeah yeah he's got some
great pot TV I remember him doing like a
what was he doing like smoking DMT and
smoke and herb and then driving his car
yeah I got it he got into a bit of
trouble for that one but hey let's have
a quick dab here and gonna get another
one done here another one done if you
could change one thing who you have done
your cannabis travels what would you
change and why
well a lot of people might say that they
would change getting busted at the
roadblock was 16 pounds in six and a
half grand cash but for me that was an
obstacle turned into an opportunity and
I don't think bubble bags would have
ever been created had I not had that
happen so I don't think I would change
anything I think that when you go back
and you try to change things in your
life and inadvertently you will change a
lot more than you think and I'm not
really a big on regrets guy I look at a
lot of my obstacles my mistakes if you
will as obstacles and I wouldn't regret
any of them in fact maybe my only regret
is not making more mistakes
they were very submit my mistakes were
very successful for me that's what I'll
say my mistakes were very successful for
me so the more mistakes for me the
better exactly exactly
I [ __ ] up rather well that's right
sometimes anyway a bunch of know what
else but if you'd only find purple candy
strain and shatter well I feel your pain
buddy I feel your pain I think mine is
not trying cannabis before age 42 that's
okay Tara Leigh that's ok you found it
now it's your friend and it will be with
you you know throughout the rest of your
life if you just if you so choose and if
not it'll always be there when you
choose to come back that's the beautiful
thing about cannabis it's always there I
know that today on Canada Day they'll
have the police out on the boats and
they'll be looking at all the boats and
they'll be coming around to everyone and
the reason that is is not because people
enjoy cannabis but because people abuse
alcohol and alcohol is dangerous
particularly in almost any situation
actually it can become dangerous so out
on a boat definitely can become
dangerous things like being out on a
boat especially on the ocean you want to
be humble you want to be respectful you
want to pay attention you definitely
don't want to turn your back on the boat
Oh what do we go we got Lilian Morgan
let me just pull out my hammer I think
that's what she wants I think dad's when
she wants there she is
there she is boom wouldn't be a big make
without a Bott experience you know I
kind of feel like that as well that was
one of the a sports people die for
drinking and boating near the lake near
me every summer of course they do of
course they do so you know today they'll
be out there they'll be in their
militarized vests and guns and radios
and pepper sprays and they'll be driving
around searching from boat to boat and
you know when they get to mind boat
they're not gonna find any alcohol
whatsoever they might see a bomb they
might see some hashish but they're
definitely not going to be seeing any
alcohol so we'll see how it goes with
that maybe we'll end up having a
conversation definitely gonna be
bringing my federal license with me out
on the water that is for sure yeah there
you go when was the last time you ran
out of hash bubble man I don't think
I've ever run out of hashes bubble man
to be honest that sounds like an alien
experience I've gotten low but not
running out I mean for instance my okay
for instance let me show you this little
situation here this is a jar of about 10
or 15 grams of full melt dry sift and
this is another jar of about 10 or 15
grams of full melt dry sift and they are
used from for my phone I put my phone on
them I bounced my phone on these two
jars I guess that you guys didn't even
know that but every day I do these wake
and bake videos my phone is sitting on
about 25 grams of full melt dry sift
it's funny because each time I kind of
want to smoke it and I'm like all the
phones on it I don't want to really move
it and buhbuh buhbuh blah but yeah I
mean I can open almost any jar any any
spot on my desk and there's just there's
just stuff you know there's some other
ratios distillate boom you know there's
some leftover dry sift it's just
everywhere this stuff this stuff is
everywhere I think we've been through
this already it's stuck everywhere it is
everywhere I have some 10 year old stuff
stuck right here next to my computer
desk
I love hashish I like to keep it around
don't run out show the aircon temp
control I'm not sure what that is that
you're requesting how about the floor oh
god did the floor yeah the floors the
floors got some hash on it I'm not gonna
lie I spent about 20 minutes yesterday
cleaning my desk and it's the first time
in a long time like I cleaned down here
and you can barely see there's some of
the some of the hard drives on the other
side there but ya cleaned her up a
little bit
a little bit scrape scrape scrape I
remember I had my desk in my office at
the melting point and there was a
homeless guy that used to come and ask
for any type of jobs and we would of
course you know try to give him as many
jobs as possible and one of the things
that he would do is tidy up the gallery
and do the floors we had like a mop and
pail and whatnot and he used to come in
and when he was around my desk I came in
one time I felt so bad
he's like down with his hands and knees
and he's trying to use the soap and he's
like I don't know what this is it's some
kind of some kind of a resin and it was
just like there was probably like seven
to ten grams of it around my chair on my
desk like an absurd amount for really I
said Oh try some alcohol I gave him some
isopropanol I'm sick Oh what's coming
off really good now just felt bad you
know it's like a lot a lot of hash on
the ground there probably could have
like a trailer-park but yeah I'm serious
I'm not even [ __ ] joking like a no
joke it was that much because when he
finally scraped it all up it might have
even been more it was ridiculous
but back then it was the days of
abundance and youth and stupidity and
lots maybe more we're getting dropped
and needed to be oh yeah chest out your
desk hm that's good floor hash well they
were hardwood floors in that sense so
that was good but I had a roller chair
and I'd end up rolling over all of it so
actually the wheels on the chair I also
were pretty gummed up not as impressive
as skunk man Sam sealing a pipe okay
with cleaning his bong I think it took
him about 15 to 20 years but he sealed a
pipe like when they came and they cut
that pipe out and they cut it open it
was like solid resin on the inside of
like a pipe bro like do you know tough
you have to puff to be able to do that
yeah hardwood floors are not a good
desiccant at all ooh cat hairs man I'd
be picking my cat out of my house if it
was doing that sort of thing
mess around shave that cat one man
gather wood another man spills do you
know would have been like hey bud I
scraped that out makes it
alcohol strain it through a filter don't
be that don't be like that set your bar
higher my friend you can do it you can
do it you know it's a weird kind of
thing with cannabis where we want to
save every last bit and I feel it and
I've always felt like the edible
industry really started by people trying
to save what they were throwing away
from after extracting or you know lower
quality materials trims whatever and you
know it turned into oh let's just you
know we'll make some butter we'll make
some product with the leftovers and
that's the edible quality that they're
giving to people I would love to see the
day where edibles are made with the
utmost I mean I guess there's a huge
distillate edible market now so that's
good that they're taking high-quality
cannabinoids or at least high percentage
maybe not quality of hopefully purity
when you're using monomolecular
medicines because generally if you're
not coming up pure probably it's going
to be some of the solvents that are left
over in there but yeah very interesting
I saw the Vegas drop yesterday
I saw that good for Vegas yeah high
quality medicine why not make the best
hash that you could make like take your
90 micron and make your edibles with
that now that's a level of medicine that
fur for myself that's what I want I
would want that's what I would want what
was that question oh I miss let me just
get caught up here what your thoughts
are making dries up with bubble bags
well what are my thoughts are making dry
sapote bubble bags what are my thoughts
on filming a movie on a still camera or
taking pictures with a video camera what
do you guys notice when you take
pictures with a video camera do you
notice that the pictures kind of suck
and you notice when you make video with
a camera even a beautiful camera like a
5d Mark 3 beautiful camera they they
filmed some Hollywood scenes of movies
with that camera however there are
limitations to it and it's not properly
designed for that job so for instance
with the 5d Mark 3 it's fine if you want
to set up the camera set your focus and
your lighting and have a shot move
through the camera but if the camera
itself has to move with the shot and
focus has to stay and
and an interchange then you're gonna be
[ __ ] and you would want to use a
camera that was designed to film in that
way so for me the bubble bags were
designed to use water I'm not saying you
can't make a sift with bubble bags but
I'm saying they weren't designed for it
they're not ideal for that job and if
you're taking it seriously it's not
really a ton of cash to get some dry
sift screens you can make them yourself
for probably a hundred maybe a little
more I sell them for a couple hundred
obviously minor great quality warrantied
and come with the customer service that
is asking me a question about it at any
time so those are the value differences
you can do what you need to do if you
want to support fresh headies bubble
bags we got your screens we can show you
a couple of different ways to make some
really great dry sift screens that are
designed specifically to do that well
the best heating unit is going to be the
one that you like the best you know you
can't ask someone else what the best is
because we all have different opinions
and we all have different abilities I
guess you would you know if someone who
has a very low olfactory and very low
taste compared to someone who has a high
olfactory and a high level of taste
they're not going to be experiencing
things the same ok one's going to
experience much more of the terpene
profile that is present than the other
and so that's a level of enjoyment that
maybe the one doesn't even know exists
you've also got people that are so
sensitive that they notice the
differences between resin and terpenes
evaporating off of different heat
sources so titanium versus sapphire
glass versus silicon carbide ceramic all
of these different compounds are going
to disperse the heat differently and
that is how we vaporize like when you
hit your torch
you torch up your nail whatever your
nail is made of and then you decide how
long you allow that temperature to leave
that nail each one of these surface
areas is are different so there's really
no real answer for that and this
that that it's gonna be different for
all of us it's gonna be different for
each of us and it's interesting because
once you know that you can grab these
different surface areas and you can
start doing some experimenting and see
if you can't notice the difference
really a perfect example is you know
with with the count with how people are
in the their lot their the horrible
distaste that is left in their mouth for
thinking of wasting a cannabis product
especially something that's been illegal
for so long and even through its
legalities it's still expensive like
platinum it's so expensive people don't
want to waste it so what people tend to
do is they tend to heat things too much
they hit things too hot they Chazz they
get this really hot hit but they feel
that they got it all you did get it all
in a sense but you destroyed so much of
the terpene profile that you didn't
really experience the other side of that
rip you got that hardcore blue like THC
buzz but you didn't really experience
the the velvety smoothness of the
bouquet that profile that is the
underlining you know connection it's the
language if you will and we're going to
be getting into this into hash church
tomorrow terpenes are the most widely
ranged language on the planet it's hell
it's how we communicate its plants
communicate to us and to one another
smells pheromones all of these different
things are languages that create
dialogue between different you know from
people to animals to plants to etc so
we're gonna have a really cool
conversation about this we're gonna get
in some great guys from soil Balance Pro
to come in and talk about their love of
soil and probiotics and the importance
of these bacterias to produce these
symbiotic relationships where the plants
can be pushed to express greater and
further terpene and cannabinoid
expressions so it's gonna be good for
sure in the meantime I feel like I
should have one more rip with you guys
before we send you off I have been
yammering a little bit but when I get on
it you know I want to stay on it so that
was something I wanted to share with you
guys in regards to is there ever just a
simple answer no there isn't and it's
taken me 20 years
learn this I will have a big rip for the
Aussies love the Aussies yeah man
yeah Oscar it's gonna be good well blue
river above the man brand be a chalice
this year I'm not too sure Tony said no
and then I saw the other day like oh
maybe I will go so maybe he'll just roll
through I'm not sure I'm not sure we'll
see what happens we'll see what happens
and then more hashed Church dramas
coming out in the near future that you
guys will hear about you'll notice a
little bit of change in hashed Church
over the course of the next two or three
weeks and yeah it's gonna be exciting
I'll see what happens all right here we
go lemon Larry oh gee
well yeah yeah drama we got to keep it
we got to keep it dramatic so people are
interested that's how it goes right
there you go deej right hey you know
what drama doesn't have to be a negative
thing it really doesn't sometimes drama
is really exciting and awesome I think
so many people are focused that drama is
like this negative thing that people are
creating and it's all harsh and it's
that's one form of drama but there are
really no enjoyable forms of drama as
well bingo well water bingo analogues to
change once again people are afraid of
change people are afraid of mistakes
people are afraid don't be afraid jump
in with both feet because that is the
best way you could have put that drama
is often the analogues to change can be
no need to fear me dude I'm like the
least worrisome person ever not gonna
cause you nah problems you know but I
will wake and bake with you every day
I will use my channel to help spread the
word of cannabis normalization as best
as I can and I'll keep supporting my
friends like Dana Larson who do cool
[ __ ] things like write books about
green buds and hash I will also be
getting some more books from Dana and
giving him away to you guys I'm gonna
try and get some of those cannabis in
Canada's he's very generous so I'm sure
he's gonna give us a big pile of books
to give away so you will probably see me
holding up one of these books for the
next week or so I'll try to interchange
with the other hats and little things
that I have still have a few bottles of
the dark crystal and happy Canada Day a
Rob awesome nice to see in the room
there
bow-bow what's up aj PK brewer
yeah well you can buy it actually thank
you for saying
because you can buy Dana's book at do to
do to do where are you Dana where did
you go I know he's got a little oh here
this
he takes PayPal so he can send him a
PayPal at book at Harry pothead dotnet
and so I'm not sure if he still got that
PayPal going but you can also google
Dana Larson Google Harry pothead Google
into the name of any one of his books
and you'll come up with his accounts and
how to get in touch with him and if you
do want to support him like I said he is
not the worst person that you could
choose to support the guy does really
good things and yeah I just have a heart
I can't say enough I can't say enough
good about it to be honest anyway I'm
glad we got that done that was
definitely wasn't sure if it was gonna
happen
getting under my skin making me agitated
but that's okay I persevered you guys
persevered thank you for that couple
hundred people in the room we got 30
minutes on the clock and I don't know go
have a great Canada day have a great
weekend
have a wonderful 4th of July if you're
down in America be safe be well be re
and may the full Mel bless your bowl
sooner than later all of you peace out
everybody