hey we didn't I'm sitting here like come
on come on let it work come on welcome
everybody welcome to bubble man's world
welcome to the wake-and-bake
episode what is it 81 is it episode 81
did we somehow have we somehow waken
banked 81 times together in the last 81
or so days I know we've been missing
Sunday's but we don't really miss
Sunday's because let's be honest
Sunday's are all about one thing hash
Church and last week two days ago or one
day ago actually holy [ __ ] that was only
yesterday that was a powerful Church for
those of you that didn't watch it I
would definitely suggest going and
checking it out we had Peter from soil
balance we had Brian from vital garden
supply we had Wade from the house of
Harlequin we had forest from the khalad
rias Network and then of course all the
old regulars we had mark Sheldon dr.
mark was in the house Etienne made it
back after his computer died stuntman
Sam was in the house to share his
knowledge with us as always it was one
of my favorite panels in a long time I'm
not gonna lie it was nice to see it full
almost all the way right up to the end
of church that shows that there was some
mixing up that was necessary there was a
little bit of stirring of the pot that
was necessary because it's been a while
since we've actually had a full panel
like that and I'll tell you it felt good
in the meantime I'm puffing on some
heavenly days resins here we got three
different flavours from the green crack
sweet skunk and congolese yeah it was
great to see yea well jhonny bee wasn't
there Johnny bee was doing his thing but
you know what it's nice to see some d
420k wasn't in the house either and as
much as I love Johnny B &amp; D 40 for 20k
it was nice to have some new people in
the room as well and that's you know
it's a hard thing when you start hashed
Church when I first started hashed
Church all my friends after inviting
them 3 or 4 times in a row kind of
became quite comfortable with the fact
that they had a spot on hash Church and
that they would always be there so
yesterday D 420k was too busy and Johnny
bee was too busy and it opened up the
opportunity
for us to invite some other people into
the room and some of those other people
were sharing a great deal so I guess
it's kind of the the hard difficult
choice to invite new people tell your
friends they have to wait I'll get them
back in next week obviously or the week
after it's definitely not like a trading
in the good folks but it's hard to give
other people opportunities if you don't
you know ask your other friends or have
the opportunity come up that your
friends aren't able to make it in so
John and Dee are awesome in the sense
that anytime someone wants to come into
the room they're willing to move out for
so I've always appreciated them for that
as well it can be a little bit of a hard
decision you know sometimes when I don't
invite someone they'll text me the next
day hey are you mad are you mad at me or
they'll text me during church hey why
did I not get a link what's going on
it's like well hash Church is its
ever-changing experience and I think
you're going to see it change more and
more and more
yeah when Tony showed those mice I'm
telling you I felt like I was getting
pulled over by the police my heart
started beating um I don't know
stink Bob you know we all get impressed
by different things and so I don't know
it was a person at all I don't know it
was a smoker and it would be hard for me
to answer you why you're not excited
about DC cleaner that being said I'm
pretty excited about about the goods no
Matt Butler you did not miss the
giveaway you won the giveaway in fact I
think I'm gonna send you a t-shirt so
yeah they are large small large and
small she sent me Laura a medium so what
size are you Matt what size are you Matt
what size are you Matt tell me what size
you are small medium or large and I will
send you out a shirt if you're an
extra-large I'll have to show us I'll
have to look to see if I actually have
that
yeah if you could reply what size you
are Matt that would be super cool NamUs
T is not Matt I'm still waiting large
there it is okay I need you to send me
an email I want you to say that it's
episode 81 I want to say that you won
the karma cup shirt and then I want to
see your address so I can just copy and
paste it that makes it the easiest for
me there have been a few people who said
they didn't get their materials that I
sent that's a bummer I'd rather have it
get lost in the mail than not send it
and be a sketch bag so please make sure
you send me that email the other day
when I gave away the two pins only Arne
sent me the email for the pin I can't
remember who won the other pin but they
never sent me an email so obviously in a
couple of weeks when they text me and
say hey I never got my pin I'm gonna be
like well you never sent me a message
you never sent me your your your address
and stuff so it's hard for me hard for
me to send that [ __ ] out without an
address not impossible I'm sure I could
probably track it down but I think it's
time for a wake and bake before grinding
up the herb before making bubble hash I
wouldn't do it you know I would maybe
try that way at the end anything that is
going to be about you trying to get the
most out of it which is very much so why
you would want to grind the herb up
anything that's really going to make it
so you focus on getting the most don't
do it it's counterintuitive and it's
tricking you and it's going to [ __ ] up
your quality I can promise well not so
much equality but your purity which will
[ __ ] up your quality if you break up the
herb too small and you don't have
surface area for the herb to float no
survivor it won't shred the heads
surprisingly the only thing that I've
seen that shreds the heads is micro
planing well I mean if you're planning
on running it into rosin anyway then it
sounds like you just have swag I mean if
you are grinding your bud and then
running it
the hash that hash is obviously no good
because you want to make it into rosin
uh don't get me wrong
rosin isn't like this horrible thing and
happy 7/10 to all of you out there I'm
gonna have my rosin dab here in a second
but I prefer hash all day long today's
7/10 we're gonna smoke some oil but hash
doesn't hold oil doesn't hold a candle
to hashish so when I hear people that
are like I'm just gonna you know make a
bunch of hash and press it I can tell
that the hash they're making is not five
or six star but it's more along the
lines of a two or a three star maybe a
four star but when you're getting into
that high of a level of equality who the
hell wants to press it in the first
place not me that's who all right let's
have a melty day and indeed yeah it's
the holy grail dude I can't get enough
of it that's all just that's all I can
say about that all right so let's get a
little a little Congolese on the 710 for
our 710 rip oh yeah let's blaze I'm
telling you we haven't even had nothing
really gets the conversation going like
having a little
say no to growing schwag say no to just
growing swag well that's cool you know
some people do make it out of five and
six star although it's funny because
when you actually get to their house and
you see their five or six star you're
like I think that might have been a four
star I think we're a little bit more
picky when it comes to saying what a 5
or a 6 star is particularly because
we're grading not to sell but just to
tell people the melt factor of the
actual hash there we go Congo tastes
amazing
[Music]
you got terpene alene you got piney I'd
love to actually see a full terpene
profile down on it because there is some
definite magic going on there yummy now
it's time to get rid of this mild mild
Chaz that's on my bowl
what's the genetics of schwag I don't
know just ask anyone they're all smoking
it and I don't actually mean that that's
not the truth
really but holy [ __ ] let's be honest a
lot of people are smoking schwag it's
not something that I'm proud of to see
out there in the world let me say that
much I just wish people were smoking
better I wish people took it more
seriously and really tried to acquire
the quality that they're seeking rather
than just give up and decide you know
what this super swaggy garbage weed is
fine good enough for me and I'm just
gonna blast it into some some shitty oil
and that'll be that for me no that's no
good that's that's not the high road I
mean if you watch the church last week
it was or yesterday I keep saying that
like it was a week ago I really loved
the episode the whole conversation about
quality the conversation about
pesticides you know on one side you got
mark Michele Doan talking about how
people could potentially clean it up
using different things but then you have
like conscious individuals like skunk
man Sam saying no we don't want to let
people know that they can clean up
anything we want people to grow better
we don't want people to grow utter and
complete [ __ ] full of powdery mildew and
and full of bugs and you know all these
different things we want like Wade was
saying like to grow resilient cultivars
you know people like Sam I would say
that it would balance it well for your
Tomatoes Peter uses that product on
everything now I haven't used soil
balance Pro but I like what Peter has to
say and I like his knowledge
and I feel that he's a pretty honest
fellow from the conversations that I've
had from him so I'm very much looking
forward to trying his product on on the
roots of our plants Oh what do we got
pesticide free do you think that gave it
ever back for the fire to make it legal
against stating that it'll never be safe
for consumption
well Daniel Cruz that's you know a bit
of a tricky situation because keep in
mind cannabis seems to be the only
industry where people have a
consciousness whatsoever because if you
look at any under industry even the food
industry the majority of foods that are
sprayed with deadly chemicals and GM
owed with deadly chemicals are not safe
for human consumption but somehow
through that system they have managed to
pay the bribes to get it so it is so in
reality many many many things are not
fit for human consumption
cannabis just seems to bring to the
forefront we were talking about it how
some people will you know they it's the
most important thing to clean their oil
and make it as clean as possible and
they will spend a day or a week or a
month trolling someone on Instagram
because they have dirty beaut poop soup
butane oil but in the meantime they will
eat fast food they will be a hundred and
fifty pounds overweight they will have
no personal hygiene and these are the
things that sort of like are the
dichotomies most of the things in life
don't teach us about raising our bar
about like becoming more conscious but
cannabis does and I'm quite certain that
it's because of the relationship we have
with smoking it I don't think it would
teach us that the same thing if if it
were not being ingested into our bodies
the way it is so you have this amazing
plant that can feed us and clothe us and
get us medicated and it teaches us
consciousness it teaches us to be more
conscious whether you're eating a meat
eating diet or a vegetarian diet perhaps
you want to eat non tortured flesh
perhaps you want to eat you know non-gmo
vegetables you know there's levels to
this [ __ ] and you learn about it in
cannabis by starting as a kid smoking
seeds and stocks and thick paper and
glue and eventually getting rid of the
seeds in the stock and eventually
getting thinner paper and eventually
getting no glue
and eventually starting to take the butt
away from the paper and put it in a pipe
and then eventually taking the bud and
breaking it up and collecting the resin
and eventually taking the resin and
separating it out from the non resin to
the resin and then eventually taking the
resin and separating that out into
micron diameter increments and that's
how far we have come in this beautiful
thing of you know the cannabis industry
hey let's get sila I hope it's not too
crazy we got a lot of people in here
there's 234 people and what I find about
the group of people that like to come in
here is that I try to make it
comfortable for you to ask questions no
matter what they are you're not gonna be
ridiculed you're not gonna be laughed
out we might make jokes and laugh with
you but we're not going to laugh at you
so whatever I like the idea of everyone
who's watching really being a part of it
and really asking their questions
sometimes you might have to ask your
question a couple of times because it is
going fast and if you notice I'm talking
while reading as well as thinking about
the next thing that I'm going to say I
agree well water really good people in
here I saw that you came into hash
Church late yesterday I hope you did get
a chance to rewatch it you came in quite
late if I'm correct I remember seeing
something about you at around the
three-hour mark Oh Matt my email address
is BC bubbleman at icloud.com the
history of the 710 I don't know it kind
of happened with the oil community it
certainly didn't exist 20 plus years ago
but maybe 10 or 15 I can't even remember
now as you get older you sort of lose
track of years and how you remember like
what oh that was just a year ago it's
like no it was like seven years ago oh
[ __ ] crazy ah they're nice to hear Cuban
chronic nice to hear Cuban chronic
somehow got blocked out of our chat for
a while so welcome back to him you did
miss the giveaway someone got a t-shirt
a karma cup t-shirt in fact got a cool
t-shirt right there in fact I should
pull it out right now he's set a large
and there is his t-shirt oh I didn't
even see the front that's pretty nice
hey
tshirt that good that good let's thank
Sara Sunday for that you know Sara I've
said it before and I'll say it again
she's an extremely capable person so you
know for me my whole worry is when I go
to an event that my money that I spend
is going to be made worthwhile but the
person putting on the event is going to
make a point on touching enough people
that they bring to the event and that
the venues and everything you're gonna
be good and like I said Sara can do it
Sara can pull it off so I hope to see
some of you guys out there at the Karma
Cup September 9th and 10th I'll be out
there should be fun should be good do
you have any UK retailers to get your
bags from well so atlas UK yes you can
get my bags from pure sativa that is my
distributor for over 10 years now emit
from pure sativa great guy great company
he has good products as well like if you
get his catalogue you'll see that it's
good stuff I'm not sure if he actually
does retail as well as wholesale
although I suspect he would just Google
pure sativa UK and you'll get that in
touch with them hey what's going on Ken
Sharky Carribean trichomes I'm sure I
mean if you buy yourself a karma cup I'm
pretty sure you just get like a big I
don't even know how it works to be
honest I would get in touch with them at
the Karma cup calm and ask any of your
more detailed questions that require
answers like about the contest and I
don't think you'll need a card but yeah
if you have your Michigan card you
should be fine Canada is pretty chill
it's kind of an interesting thing
because you know from the way I look at
it is this it's a double standard in the
sense that showing a card for a medical
for something medical seems to be a
breach of our Charter of Rights here in
Canada like why would I have to tell you
that I have something that I need to
take a medicine for that would be
ridiculous that would be like giving
diabetics a card so if they got caught
with syringes they could say oh no no no
this is just a diabetic syringe I have a
diabetes card and I'm allowed to have
these syringes it's completely [ __ ]
ridiculous and so when I opened my vapor
bar in 2003
I would never card anyone because it was
not in my position I'm not the police
I'm not the government
I have no reason why I would want to
know if someone has a card and so I
allowed in a sense everyone who wanted
to vaporize with their own material at
my vapor bar because it was not my right
to ask people about their private
medical records are confidential you
understand even your dental records are
confidential so come on medical records
and then people are just gonna be like
hey I want to know if you use cannabis
medically I never claimed that the
sessile heads are not that good actually
Mike Michaels the sessile capitate
sessile and the capitate stocked are two
of the heads that you those are the ones
that you're mostly getting when you do
extractions with screens whether bubble
bags or dry sifting that's just a fact
the bulbous heads tend to stick to the
leaves on their singular cellular stocks
it's almost looks like they have no
stock at all they just look like a head
and they're stuck on the leaf and
because of that they don't have quite
that motion and snapping you can get
some of them don't get me wrong and I'm
sure the 25 micron bag is ripe with them
but oil gets the majority of them and
that's why you see bubble hash never
gets the same yield as oil and for the
longest time people were convinced that
they were acquiring oils that were
inside the plant I am still not on that
page from what I know about science all
of the glandular trichomes and
cannabinoids and terpenoids
not inside anywhere else of the plant
I've separated the plant all out and bio
assayed it and I found with my own mind
when I smoked all the components of the
plant that only the glandular trichomes
gave me actual effect of cannabinoids
and terpenoids
they come from and so you it's very easy
to run a batch of something with through
bubble bags and then run it through run
the same stuff but that hasn't been run
you know separate two piles run one
through water hash and one run through
run one through oil and you'll see
clearly that one is going to yield
higher and that's going to yield higher
because of those bulbous heads not
because there's resin hiding inside the
plant or though hey science could tell
me that that is the case tomorrow and
trust me I would learn about it and I
would accept it I'm mostly accepting
like stuntman Sam of the truth whatever
the truth may be the first strain of
real bubble I ever made was shish kebab
I had made a couple of batches prior to
that and I don't even remember and then
really the real real bubble the real
first bubble that kind of beyond blew me
away was yeah 15 times that's well if
you put enough material in there you
could wash it 15 times absolutely for me
here's the thing there's only a certain
yield to be had on these materials it's
very easy to find that yield you can
squish it with your hair straightener or
your rosin press and that will give you
your glandular trichomes full-spectrum
yield it'll tell you whether you have
17% or 21% or 13% and through that
number you can then go and run it
through bubble and really get an idea
bubble hash is extremely efficient I can
get 90 plus percent of the medicine off
of the plant the medicine that I'm
looking for the medicine that I want to
inhale the micro encapsulated trichome
heads that I'm looking for and you know
so I've always found people that are
washing it many many many many many many
times or they're trying to make their
freezer colder or their washer colder I
just asked them are what is the deal
with that like what are you improving on
because water hash is so simple and so
perfect that it's like you use water and
ice and you break the glands and they
sink if you're getting your yield you
know what is the purpose you know what I
mean is are there claims that oh I
watched it 15 times so instead of giving
12% I got 29%
I guarantee you not
tu you can get the majority of your
yield in a very very short period of
time so these people they're coming up
with all sorts of unique things and I
get it I think personally it's more
connected to the way we all are and how
we want to do things through our own
lenses and it's it's kind of like it
makes it ours as well I saw that from
day one of starting the bubble bags
because I would just put the directions
out I never felt like I owned the
directions I felt like I was sharing
them and as I was sharing them people
would say oh I do it different I do it
different I do it different they were
all coming up with their own tax which
coincidentally enough created their own
companies that's fine for me I never
felt like I owned it I felt like I was
sharing information that people needed
to know and so the only reason I even
came up with the name bubble and bubble
hash and bubble man was because I didn't
want to bite anything that the isolator
company had already done I wanted to
stay away from any type of that energy
so I could just do my own thing
and since I did that it's turned in much
more to a just everyone kind of creating
it like oh well I make ice oil I make
ice wax I make solvent list I make and
people would contact me and say what's
the difference and I'd be like well to
be honest they're all guys using my bags
making water hash so I would call bubble
hash I started calling it water hash
because it was more accurate in the
sense that you know all the bags will
make water hash it's just about
isolating glandular trichomes heads to
the to the best of your abilities and
then there are simple sort of little
truths little tips that if you follow
the simple tips like keeping it cold
keep lots of ice present don't overmix
don't overstuff simple things that you
realize when you do those things the
sweet spot of your extraction and by
that I don't mean quality that's another
thing people got all wrong its purity
bubble hash is about purity we're
isolating glands to 99.9% gland head
ratios it had nothing it has nothing to
do with quality it may unveil quality
but trust me when you're using bags to
make hash you are not making or
responsible for the quality of said hash
now if you grew that material then you
are somewhat responsible you and the
genetics did a great job and the resin
is melty and the bubble bags have spoken
they are the Word of God when it comes
to purity and quality because generally
if you purified a 99.9 percent heads and
it's not mounting everyone always says
the same thing what's wrong with my
material and I'll start with it could be
your genetics it could be you it could
be you and your genetics like those are
the three main combinations that are
going to be responsible for why your
bubble is not melting if you're the
grower of your material I wash a couple
hundred grams dry you know maybe six to
seven hundred wet in a five gallon batch
and I make sure there's a ton of yeah
lack of and you can call it lack of love
you can call it lack of focus lack of
attention but that's what it is people
are just being loose with things and the
bags the bags were always meant to be a
very simple tool that you could you know
test materials with you could learn
about how well you grew you could you
could check your your efficacy your
efficiency I should say how well you
grew that resin will be shown in the
resin that you extract from the bags
they are bags of truth I've always
called them the word of god when it
comes to the quality of your product
because they're gonna get everything
else away and then all these different
methods started popping up of people
because people if you ever do yoga you
will learn that what people love to do
is compensate and they love to lean and
they love to kind of take the easiest
path whatever it is they'll compensate
to get there and so those compensations
happened in water hash with fresh frozen
and with micro planing when you use
fresh frozen you are using a wax
membrane latent crystal head that is
filled with moisture okay there's a lot
of moisture in there and you can see it
in the photos when you photograph fresh
herb if you've seen mine it looks
beautiful like a like a full blown water
balloon I just happen to have a
beautiful picture here in a frame
on my desktop so you see the quality
there there you have sessile trichomes
and capitate stocks capitate stock being
the tall one and the low ones the small
ones being the sessile now if you look
closely on the tall one
you see these tiny tiny two little dots
right here you might not be able to make
them out but what those are and they're
actually all over here I can tell
because they just it every little dot of
shining shimmery circle is one of them
and these are male pollen this is one of
dr. Atomics breeding projects that he
did this was a DJ short blue berry and I
believe he smacked it up with I want to
say one of his powerful powerful strong
Northern Light men so I'm not sure
whatever became of that but yeah these
fresh frozen methods leaving the
moisture content in the membrane a lot
of people nowadays just don't believe
you can even make full melt with dry
material because people are so far from
the tens the perfectly grown perfectly
you know terpene rich cultivars and I'm
not saying everyone don't get me wrong I
see some beautiful bubble hash being
posted on Instagram so shout out to all
of you guys and girls that are making it
happen it's great to see but I think
that the majority of people still aren't
really learning that one of the aspects
of bubble bags is is that they can teach
you how to get better and if you ignore
that lesson and you just start blasting
your [ __ ] and going down the oil path I
think that you won't be as well off for
it you know not to say you can't do the
oil path as long as you're also still
learning the best weed that I've ever
seen that's a hard one I see a lot of
best weed if you can imagine you know
I've seen some pretty crazy la you know
just like the [ __ ] gnarly crazy
beautiful fall colors cookies and just
[ __ ] that you can see the the the the
texture from across the room when it's
sitting on your table I remember one
Gold Coast came out one time with some
really nice cookies they had on my
table in Amsterdam but also all sorts of
exotic Hayes's the moment bimba madness
was a beautiful plant I wish I had more
pictures of it I really have an affinity
for cannabis so I appreciate all aspects
of it and I appreciate much more than
just one particular style if you can
imagine be exon oh yeah you need to meet
my hammer here it is and see you later
buddy
peace out sorry to say but B xn and W
yeah bump we bumped them don't they know
about the hammer I mean you'd think at
this point in time word would have
gotten around we slay the trolls here
much like we slayed the bowls they rhyme
so it's easy that's how it goes bad
hammer Enya knows that's how it goes in
your nose nice I see what you did there
I see what you did there I like that I
like that it's good to be chillin with
all of you you know 267 people in the
room we're picking up you know it's it's
starting to get a little bit more more
people in the room not quite to the
level of hashed Church at this point in
time but hey it's a small group and I
like it yeah we try to run a tight ship
here you know we're not gonna yeah maybe
a bowl for the troll how about that you
ever do cocaine you know I did cocaine
only a handful of times maybe even only
no no I did it twice I remember I did it
twice and both times I absolutely
[ __ ] hated it I was quite young
definitely you know for my style of
personality someone who's already going
very fast and who processes information
quite quickly
cocaine is no bueno for the bubble man
and of course I was very young the one
time I did it was also the same way as
trying coffee which also didn't agree
with me and [ __ ] me up and put me in
the [ __ ] for an hour I just wanted to
stay awake I was traveling across Canada
all the way from Manitoba to BC and you
know these [ __ ] degenerate i was with
were like oh yeah try try a bumpin s
well let me tell you a bumper that was
like the worst experience I ever had
so not good not a fun experience and
yeah I just can't do it
Oh surely your SIL you need to meet the
banhammer you want me to suck your balls
how about I slam your balls into this
[ __ ] how about that
all right did you could do no I don't
consume caffeine like I said the same
trip after having that horrible
experience which lasted way longer than
I wanted it to I ended up trying
caffeine to stay awake I was really
exhausted and I just I didn't want to
sleep and wake up dead in this vehicle
cuz the guy driving was like maybe he
shouldn't have been driving either way I
tried the coffee and then that was even
worse it was just you know I never did
try math I'm kind of glad because of the
cocaine experience I was like I was good
with psychedelics and cannabis from a
young age never tried heroin no need to
try some of these more extreme drugs but
I did I have to admit I did try cocaine
I'm not proud of it I'm not proud of it
I think that if more if most people were
honest when you're younger that's the
thing about raising kids is kind of
scary that when you're younger and
you're becoming who you're gonna become
you try things and so that as a parent
is of course the scariest thing I tried
opium one time as well and it was no
good no good for me as well I thought
that that was bad I said I did I did try
opium it was it made me feel much like
alcohol to be honest real Spinney in my
head and I don't like alcohol either I
tried it a handful of times and just
never liked it at all so I felt pretty
lucky to not have it in my life all
these years yeah shrooms for the wind
probably one of my most how does harmala
affect a mushroom trip well its Harmelin
and harmine they're two components that
sort of potentiate the tert the trick to
mean hi Terence Mckenna talks about it a
little bit in I think it was archaic
revival now may be true that no archaic
revival it was about his brother they
did this crazy to
it's basically like you know tryptamine
can be a very short trip
you can intensify it with the harming
and the Harmelin you got to Google these
companies and you probably find out a
lot more information than what I
currently know but it's definitely
interesting oh really I will smoke you
sweets gun thank you for that quite the
surprise ginger tea will soothe the
stomach yeah no [ __ ] all right are we
hitting again hey Bubba man I have to
ask you what's your opinion about
extraterrestrials and if you ever minute
unacknowledged unacknowledged what does
that mean by dr. Steven Greer the name
sounds so familiar I don't think I have
been unacknowledged by Steven Greer my
and what do I think about
extraterrestrials that's a good one you
know that's a pretty good one because I
will say that I was I read all the crazy
conspiracy books back in the day from
Robert Anton Wilson led me into Terrence
and all the psychedelic visionaries but
then I kind of got into David Icke who
was just out there completely and I read
like Graham Hancock and I read what's
the other guy draw all all of it like
from all the little walks from like
about you know Enki and Enlil and oh oh
zecharia sitchin the 12th planet series
which I felt was just a really enjoyable
book whether it was true or not the
stories were incredible and they sort of
resonated with me that there was this
potential of a planet on an elliptical
orbit with our planet that you know came
here to mine gold for their planet
because they [ __ ] their [ __ ] up with
their technology pretty interesting
story written on Sumerian you know multi
thousand ten and fifteen and twenty
thousand year old stone tablets found
all over the world and I found it
interesting I try not to really grasp
and believe anything fervently these
days other than cannabis truths and
knowledge otherwise I just I'm always
afraid of people like that that just
that they believe what they
so fervently that's why it's so easy to
laugh at the flat earthers and not just
the flat earthers but also the people
who argue with them and say no no no the
world is round
I have no card in the game but it just
sounds so ridiculous that it's allowed
me to be a little more open with my
belief system but yeah sakuradite
Sitchin had some pretty good information
about you know and it sort of kind of
combines and resonates with me in the
sense that you know we seem like we're
these different versions of the apes
that are naturally here and in the story
of course they took the ape DNA and put
it into their DNA and created they're
their servants which were humans and
then the story goes that the Apple of
knowledge the Adam and Eve story which
this predates by like 8,000 years which
it predates all the religious textures
by many many thousands of years which is
unique because all of the religious
stories repeat themselves and when you
know that these stories were even older
and they're slightly different it's
pretty cool but you know does it change
my day to day life do I go around trying
to convince people yeah possibly I see
that there's a dichotomy in the human
beings on this planet that some of us
want to just hang out by the bonfire and
live in a teepee and smoke the peace
pipe and then others want to build metal
spaceships and fly to other planets it
seems like we have a little bit of both
going on there so who thinks satellites
and dinosaurs are fake yeah I try open
morning FATA mike korean natural farming
can repair the world and grow our full
melt hash for pennies on the ground well
that's my [ __ ] gig I want to grow
hash for pennies on the ground you know
who thinks dams are real I agree bubble
man yeah you know go with it on your own
try not to believe blindly in anything
you know particularly the opposite of
what you believe yeah John Dover I have
a few of them on my on my Facebook but
you know what I have to say I laughs
equally at the people who argue with
them because the funny thing is they
start talking about math oh I know math
that
prove it it's like the bottom line is
this have you been outside of the earth
and looked at it the answer is no so
then that's why I laugh at everyone you
know using using other people's
information that could easily be
manipulated as proof to the other person
why you're right and they're wrong it's
just seriously the most ridiculous thing
ever so I think it's time for another
dab what do we say anyone in here use
ativan no Mike Michael's out stay the
[ __ ] away from that stuff it turned my
friend into a zombie really and you know
for those people that say it works okay
I'm sorry but I worry about using
pharmaceutical drugs to regulate your
anxiety or how you feel that's a very
dangerous dangerous game what friend you
wouldn't know him it was a long time ago
now but he was the most normal of people
and I'm telling you that ativan
completely changed his personality he
became really aggressive really really
aggressive don't do it that's what I say
good for you Larry what do you think
about alchemy and hermetics bubbleman
well what little I know about it I think
it's quite interesting I love the
concept of alchemy and often tell people
that's what bubble hash was maybe like
this is science I'd be like it's
actually a little bit more alchemy yeah
there's just got to be better ways to
deal with these anxieties I think it's
very important that we find them because
these pills that mimic you know and and
try to regulate these feelings and then
coincidentally have side effects that
are suicidal thoughts these these that's
not good to go from a little bit anxious
or even a lot anxious right to suicidal
thoughts that's something that I think
we should be looking at in our society
you know we're not allowed to smoke
cannabis and drive a vehicle but
potentially the person who's driving the
school bus that your kid sits on is able
to take an extra a divan if he or she so
chooses it's kind of freaky I'm not
saying they shouldn't be allowed I'm
just saying maybe I'd like to know so I
could make the decision you know rather
than just I'm not all about trying to
make everyone not be able to do anything
that's not my intention here the jazz
dissolving off yeah just cleaning the
Chas Chas and Chas and cleaning the Chas
and it's good to get it clean yeah I
wish we could share photos on here too
that would be kind of a nice thing yeah
yeah I can I can that I don't have to be
for tomorrow though
let's see what we got Chaz prevention is
the best medicine yes the d Chaz in it
or did you guys go check out chazzy
Bangor or chazzy bangers on Instagram
it's almost too hard to believe it's
almost like looking at a car accident
you just can't stop watching as you
drive by it's it's Chaz bangers and
they're quite proud of them go check it
out yes this is no bueno
Oh FSS how you doing FSS since our
conversation you know I thought you said
SSS I knew your name was an SSS I don't
remember an SSS and I have a pretty good
memory when it comes to that [ __ ] so
when I saw the other day and hashed
heard someone say FSS I was like ah
there it is I get it
hope you're doing well anyway brother it
was nice talking with you the other day
and talking to you right now
say hi to your wife Katie for me Katie's
a sweetie
doing the good job loving her husband
it's nice when our partners can take
care of us like that and just step out a
little bit to do something special those
are the important things those are the
signs of true love but you know someone
loves you when they go out of their way
to just shoot an arrow out Griffin will
someone explain to me what is this I
guess that depends on what this you're
referring to are you holding something
in your hand that we can't see are you
referring to this live chat that
currently were all-in what what what
yeah cuz this is just a chat this is
kind of a like trying to get you going
on the day maybe a little bit of
inspiration while we puff a few bowls
you know we're all cannabis aficionados
here so we're promoting the
endocannabinoid system which is of
course a system that uses cannabinoids
which cannabis is ripe with to regulate
our biological functions from the first
breath to the last breath that we take
basically our entire lives all of our
biological functions so this is kind of
what we talked about it used to it
started out as oh we're all smoking weed
and it's illegal and then we learned
that it actually regulates our
biological functions and can keep a lot
of disease
sickness out of our lives if we just
prevent it by staying in homeostasis and
what homeostasis is think of the
endocannabinoids system as the crank on
your bicycle and each pedal one is the
immune system and one is the central
nervous system when all the ball
bearings and the grease is all working
perfectly
you have homeostasis and what that does
in the body obviously is it feels good
you feel good when you're in homeostasis
and you're healthy you go to the
bathroom regularly you sleep well you
have a good memory your appetite is
healthy all of these things stay
regulated when you are preventing
endocannabinoid deficiency by consuming
cannabinoids now if cannabis isn't your
bag don't worry you can produce these
endogenously in your body which also
tells us how important they are not only
endogenously through the consumption of
essential amino acids which you can get
through hemp seed once again thank you
cannabis or different things like salmon
and different fish that have fatty acids
in them gl na s and GLA s they're all
there for our consumption and our
enjoyment and then one more thing to lay
on you when we start our life if you can
imagine that the the negative
stereotypes against cannabis like oh
look at that guy's got puffy red eyes
he's all stoned or look at them they got
the munchies well those actually flip in
the medical world puffy red eyes he's
stoned equals granny's not going to lose
her sight because she's able to reduce
her ocular pressure with cannabinoids
stimulating one's appetite may look
funny to the stoner stereotype looking
out at it but in reality stimulating an
appetite of one suffering from wasting
syndrome from some of the AIDS
medications or when one is starting
one's life and suckling on the nipple of
your mother the breast milk is ripe with
cannabinoids these cannabinoids are
inducing appetite and the the initial
latching of the baby to the breast is
the is the absolute stereotype of the
munchies that's how all life on Earth is
sustained cannabinoids produce and
regulate biological functions so there
it is from me to you that's what this is
I think that was a pretty good little
drop I'm gonna let you guys go because
I've been babbling on for probably a lot
longer Oh Thank You Griffin right on
brother
we will appreciate having you here dude
this has good information that you can
share with people that might still be
locked away into the propaganda based
prohibition based mentality of cannabis
that is showing them that they still see
the negative stereotypes and you might
need to flip the coin for a few of those
people and I think it'll be easier for
you to flip that coin if you have some
of this knowledge that I just shared I
do this six days a week and then on the
seventh day it's kind of a steroid
version where I invite a panel of
amazing cannabis aficionados to come and
share their information with all of you
so yeah be men very locked away so many
don't care it's true trichome City
wasn't gonna do Thank You Chawla chugger
much appreciation I loved seeing all the
familiar faces in here every day have a
great day everybody and made the full
Mel bless your bowl sooner than later
peace out