what's going on everybody welcome
welcome to the wake-and-bake with bubble
man I've been awake for a long time I'm
not gonna lie I just finished a very
long conference call with one of the
companies that I sit on a board and it
was awesome very interesting stuff as
always but sorry it took so long to get
out here guys that was that was a couple
hours that the chat was up and holy
smokes 43 63 people hanging out in the
chat and waving that's pretty cool well
we're gonna give away what did I hold up
today I think I held up one of the
little yeah it was one of these guys it
was this guy I was holding up so I
didn't really have a question I kind of
had a question but now it's gonna be
real hard because the picture is not
there anymore I'll ask it anyway and
we'll see I am NOT the bubble bag dude
no I'm not I am the pump that's that's
who I am anyway I was gonna ask a
question on the front page of my picture
okay
I was holding up that little thing and
there's the nature in the back there was
there was something behind me on the
ground it was yellow and if you can tell
me what that was I would send you this
little dab map if anyone can remember
what it was I wasn't a cooler it wasn't
a cooler wasn't a bubble bag I don't
think anyone's gonna be able to answer
this to be honest it was yellow it was
yellow and it was no there's no way
anyone's gonna remember this one this is
a real hard one I could just do a number
two I almost should have given a little
bit of a tip someone should have done a
little screen shot
should I give some more clues all right
it was yellow and it was a child's toy
you know what I'm gonna give it to 420
wild dragon because he said a truck and
that's what it is
it was a Tonka dump truck and that's 420
you win you win dude I might even be
your second one I can't remember but
either way you win it's yours you got
one coming to you it's a toy truck it
was a dump truck yeah absolutely it was
my son's little Tonka truck very hard to
see very tough question but hey 420 wild
dragon
got one coming at you a really cool one
too I picked this one up today because I
love the face on it the squish and good
thanks to the people at Sasquatch my
brothers and sisters for always hooking
it up and being so kind with that
in the meantime shall we get our bake on
here shall we yeah I think we should
let's get medicated so we're set for
having such a long conference call once
again I know you guys were waiting and I
was thinking about you but hey we can
have a great conversation didn't we have
a great conversation yesterday you know
yesterday I got into a lot of the
discussion about bubble hash and it
really helped me because right now Tony
and I are designing my new website which
is bubble man brand calm if you go there
now it's just a password page but
eventually it's gonna go live it's gonna
have beautiful photos you know education
from the macro of the seed all the way
through to the resin of the plant
you know Tony and bubble man style where
we're gonna go hard on it and really put
major major information into this so I
started writing a blog yesterday in
regards to bubble hash and how Tony just
said hey how would you write a blog on
teaching someone how to make water hash
it's pretty complex I'm not gonna lie
because there's so many different sizes
of kits there's fresh frozen there's
properly dried and cured material
there's threshing ratios that we spoke
about the other day and how
felt it is to learn about those ratios
and how you really need to learn the
state make mistakes to learn key things
about those ratios ice water to versus
whether it's trim or bud those are going
to wash differently
temperatures environments outside of the
bags as well if it's too warm when you
pull the resin out this is going to make
it very hard to not remove too much
moisture so that the high quality resin
self presses in the pressing screen etc
etc I went through all of this stuff in
the blog and I'm pretty stoked it's
really being able to talk to you guys
has helped me write an even better blog
so that'll be all up there for you guys
Tony's gonna go through my words and
photograph in the lab that process that
I've explained so you'll have a really
high-quality photo essay with deeply
deeply informative words and that's
gonna be a bubble bubble man brand.com
is where that will be so why don't we
get ourselves oh I gotta turn my timer
on for starters Oh
Siri wants to know what I'm doing well I
don't want to do anything with you Siri
I wanted to go to my launch bit there we
go
Thank You Siri thank you for nothing all
right let's do this
oh they'll always be more of tawny vids
coming dude he's gonna be putting more
stuff up for sure
hey coot keep trying bro you're not fit
you're gonna win one of these times I
promise you we won't stop until you do
and then if you just never win and
everyone's won three times I'll just
[ __ ] send you something straight up I
will just send you something that'll be
it we won't wait any longer we'll make
it happen
all right so we're gonna grab this
little unit Dubai oh I say yes I've got
a double here a little double probably
can't see but there is my double right
there boom and a boom yeah those will be
bubble man branded absolutely John but
the we're gonna hold off I think that
was a little ahead of its time I need to
have the infrastructure set up so that I
don't have to basically rely on other
people for the infrastructure which
won't really be a bubble man branded
thing it would just be like a leased out
to other people so once we have the
infrastructure we're gonna get it done
all right 1 &amp; 2 1 &amp; 2 here we go 1 &amp; 2
yes I've heard of the ketogenic diet
absolutely you can google that [ __ ] I'll
tell you get and peeled oh this is like
my sixth or seventh I had a lot of puffs
on my conversation my conference call
excuse me miss Bangor came to me for
Mick from DC glass still milking it my
goodness damn near perfect temp - wow I
hear you Geoff not everyone wants to
watch hashed Church be a hard thing it's
one of those things you really have to
be wanting to hear that information to
be able to sit through it otherwise I
suspect it could be like a Phish show
walking in half way through the middle
of an intense tweezer reprise to the
hardcores they're going to enjoy it to
other people they're gonna be a little
thrown off by it so hey I love fish
do you love fish sticks well little
self-park drop there now let's take a
couple days to watch it soak up church
Church is heavy duty I mean it's a
serious thing you know that the
conversation that sometimes gets created
through the dialog of the information of
the massive amounts of years that it's
taken for the panelists to compile that
information skunkman Sam alone skunkman
Sam alone is worth having hashed Church
on Todd McCormick alone is worth having
hashed church on you know Tony vers Ora
all of these guys Marsh aldohn Oh
chillin like a villain you went there
can't believe it so yes I am going to
definitely be
writing a dry sipped blog as well where
I break down as much information about
glandular trichomes heads and isolating
them without water but Mack mechanical
screen separation and I'm excited to get
those up in the very near future I can't
believe it's taking this long to have
really great versions of those things up
and running it's it's unfortunate but
here it comes
what happened to Horatio I'm not sure
Horatio and I just kind of went our
different ways
we were just getting along less and less
I guess you would say not like you know
in a negative way but just more like our
egos were colliding and we would talk
and we would get into arguments and
finally on our last argument it was just
like hey you know what this is silly why
don't we just you be you I'll be me I
have nothing against Horatio I think
he's brilliant I love what he did I love
to have him on hash Church I just could
no longer deal my ego you know I'm just
as responsible could no longer deal with
his ego our egos were no longer able to
interact as we grew together so I wish
him the best of course I would never
want him to be down and out I want him
to have all the successes that he wants
to manifest for himself and his family
but it ran out for us and so maybe that
is my own
maybe it's more my fault than his I
don't know maybe my ego was the bigger
problem I don't know I have a biased
perspective because my ego is the
perspective I look through so either way
there'll be more Horatio's in the future
what I look forward to hash Church and
Todd is also sharing the same vision is
that we try to bring as many amazing
panelists I mean the more people we
bring on the more likely we are to find
the forests I don't know if you guys
remember Samantha LV you know the Wendy
Turner's you know all of these great
people that have come on over the years
the Jessica Hawkins remember Jessica
talking about her daughter niya how
heart-wrenching that was how we were all
tearing up my goodness
very very very
intense stories I'm I for one find that
hash Church is bigger than any of the
panelists anymore and it's it's now its
own entity that is a responsibility to
feed each Sunday to make sure that hey
let's get some people put in there you
know it was great to have Tim Blake on
last week it would have been nice to see
Alec or from SC Labs those guys are
always hard to nail down I talked to
Brad from guild extracts he said he had
an interest in coming on I even spoke
with the jungle boys briefly and they
said they might if they had time come on
and do a little do a little hash search
as well so we got some good
possibilities yeah the real Rick Ross
exactly you know how we roll on hash
Church we're not gonna bring the the
faux Rick Ross on Todd right
always with the amazing guests I miss
having Kenny from trichome heavy hunts
not Trek I'm heavy from geez how am i
spacing on K that's crazy that is crazy
that I'm spacing on trichome
technology's trichome technologies I
almost called it trichome heavy extracts
which was jibs and Ken's company but yes
trichome technologies which is crazy
because that company is like 25 plus
years old and so I used to have posters
of them on my wall behind me but I don't
know what happened to them I must have
given them away how much do you consume
these days do you produce yourself well
I do produce myself in certain countries
not in every country Canada I have a
license to produce so I can produce
right now I don't have any plants per se
in the ground but I'm getting extremely
close now as I'm going to put my refre
man Otto flowers let me grab those
actually just because we're talking
about him and it sucks to talk about
things when you can't show the things
that you're talking about so we have
here a little bit of motion there all
right so we've got these four Otto
flowers from reefer man he sent me these
as a nice little gift
nice-looking seeds I have you know with
refre man I'll say this he kind of
reminds me of breeder Stephen
very much a character very unique
individual but always has the flame
always has the super rare exotic like
low yielding super rare terpene
expressing cultivar and to me that is
kind of what a breeder is all about
chimeras the same way he shows up he's
got the lime and the pine he's got this
unique terpene profile that I haven't
hit in a long time that took me straight
up and just left me completely focused
while I was there thanks to those
particular terpenes when we see the
value in producing cultivars that
contain all hundred and forty plus
terpenes instead of the twelve that we
seem to recreate over and over again and
we understand the limitless endless
possibilities of profile mixes that can
occur which should and will end up
creating medicinal and recreational
effects unique and different so we
really kind of shot ourselves in the
foot when we fell for the prohibition
based how much can I get and how fast
can I get it I always appreciated the
longer flowering cultivars even in the
90s in the mid early 90s I can remember
growing cultivars that took 16 to 18 to
20 weeks to bloom so you know you would
also want to veg that plant for a little
while as well the Haze's absolutely
alright
Pablo you are welcome for the wind thank
you for the win you nailed it I'm not
too sure kou I will try to be at the
great canadian glass gathering I don't
have a booth I haven't talked to Patrick
I haven't bought a ticket I'm not very
organized in that sense I do you know
what I mean if I could just roll up and
be like hey what's up pay at the door
maybe I'll do that but we'll see I'm not
sure about exactly the dates on that and
whether or not I'll be in the country or
not so I've got a little bit of
traveling coming up here in the near
future
out what do you call them sasquatch Pat
you're holding in today's post I call
them dab mass
you know there's a bunch of different
ones I have a mothership one here as
well
little mothership dad Matt this one
silicon comes from an oil slick folks
so yeah I'm mostly looking forward to
this haze they're all autoflowering
which should be interesting but this
haze and this lemon tie from reefer man
he has suggested that both of these are
going to be right up my alley
and I wouldn't be surprised if he's
right so probably put these in the
ground in the very near future it really
depends on how much traveling I have to
do if I can take care of them if I can
get them all sorted out and per when I
go on some cool show or roundtable to
respect you and your contributors yeah
of course I would Louis Garcia it's just
a matter of if I have time to do it
yeah lemon ties so sweet autos don't
they have more CBD I'm not sure if
that's the case with reefer man's autos
I don't know how he's been you know
producing these what his selections have
been what his work has been whatsoever
really but I have a feeling that I will
go and see him in the near future if I'm
able to once I get these into the ground
so it was a big responsibility when
someone sends you seeds that you make
sure you plant them it's kind of like
bubble bags if you've got them don't put
them under your bed make sure there's
trim or bud or some sort of cannabis
product going into them for that matter
non cannabis product you can use any
plant that secretes essential oils and
glandular trichomes can be used for
water extraction so many things from the
mint family as well as urban mate' or
Besant a and even roses I've extracted
resin from so it's pretty cool it's a
pretty cool thing autos have come along
pretty good just like LED lights how do
I get invited to legends legends is
pretty easy to get invited to you just
have great hash
so usually Legends is around a cannabis
event where people are coming to I'll
usually have a booth there and usually
it would come up to that
and be like oh man this is my hash I
would like to come to Legends I would
look at it maybe puffs a bowl of it and
it would be very easy for me to decide
right then and there whether or not you
were going to be getting the ability to
purchase a ticket because that's really
what that is that doesn't get you a
ticket it just gives you the ability to
purchase a ticket now that way that with
the ticket purchase we are able to rent
venues get caterers have service and
give everyone a nice t-shirt that says
legends of hash I do not have any tips
on autos gold I was gonna ask you the
same thing oh yes that's right you're
right sorry I did have one tip that you
don't want to replant them that you want
to plant them right into there he told
me to plant them right into their bucket
right okay there you go good tips good
tips so the tip was from DANC runner
don't top autos and don't stress them in
any way
Oh injuries in the room how's it going
Indra what is legends Wow
dude that's amazing legends of hash is a
party that we myself skunk man and Sam
and myself started a very long time ago
like I want to say 14 or 15 years ago
now I'm going to see if I can get some
of these edits found because if I have
the legends it would be so good yes I do
here we go so let me show you guys a
couple of these here we go
so there's my computer I'll just close
this off these are legends of hash
tickets from past years so this is the
legends of hash there's Tuesday November
25th this was during the Amsterdam
cannabis cup you notice the no cameras
we did not allow cell phones we still
don't to this day you're not allowed to
bring any phone or any camera of any
sort the messenger resin is the message
that was a legends of hash that I did in
Vancouver
here's another legends of hash in amps
there's the ticket this is the back of
the ticket dinner and belly dancing so
we had a belly dancer this year this was
our friends Lebanese restaurant and we
really were just allowed to puff the
[ __ ] out of this restaurant
another legends of hash ticket you know
these could all be really cool t-shirt
so I have to say like these are all
invitation only the legends of hashish 5
a gathering of Chara C Illuminati
connoisseurs legends of hash six you
know real good [ __ ] I think a gathering
of Chara C Illuminati connoisseurs bring
your own resin and some to share you
know legends of hash legends of hash
legends of hash it's a gathering how
about this one
boom the legends of hash the legends of
hash the legends of hash the legends of
hash the legends of hash boom love
Shambhala or land are legends of hash
here's one from Barcelona from two years
ago our first and only one in Barcelona
so far there's the back legends of hash
city city this was the celebration of
city city I remember that wonder if he
sent me all the other things now all
right
I thought that would be cool so those
are kind of some of the tickets the real
world the real purpose of Legends and
I'll tell you right now I was sitting
with skunkman Sam we were puffing his
shirac his 99.9% heads and we were
getting really I read and we
kind of talking about the cup and what
was great about it and we were like I
love the people I think it's amazing all
these different people and some of them
are real hash smokers it would be cool
if we had an event where just passed
part mockers went and we're like yeah
but an event also where you didn't have
to rent a booth he didn't promote your
company you didn't bring flyers or
business cards and in fact we didn't
even talk business
we just milked the fact that we loved
hash and we were all kind of good Chara
see people and so that was the birth of
the legends of hash and that turned more
into let's keep cameras out because some
people that are coming may have done
illegal things in the world of hashish
in the past they're also true Chara see
people and so charas is hand-rubbed
can't cannabinoids
it's hashish from India or Nepal I'm
sure other countries do it as well but
that's where it was most famous from the
charas so hashish that is what the
legends of Haris party was about we
wanted to make it not about people
coming and self promoting themselves and
more importantly about trying to capture
parts of it and share it on their social
media afterwards so we made that's why
most of you won't know what legends of
hashes other than if you heard about it
through like an Instagram post of say
one of those tickets because that's
about the only picture you'll ever see
at a legends of hash party we don't
really do the the cameras and that was
for a specific reason but it really
created a very special event
particularly during big large events
like spannabis or High Times or whatever
which are so you know massively marketed
and sponsored and it's very much about
companies and money and products and and
that's not a bad thing but this event
was one day for all of us when we were
together those special people that were
lived their lives in this and were
working for a living in the cannabis
industry where we could step back and we
could have a little bit of a night just
to smoke charas to eat good food to
drink good drink to eat good fruit and
of course to smoke great hash and so it
was kind of funny we just thought
at first they thought I wouldn't be able
to sell 50 tickets you know and I was
like oh I think I'll be able to sell 50
tickets and it was pretty close you know
towards the end there I had like five
left and finally I sold them all on the
last day but it became a thing within a
couple of years that that everyone
wanted to get a ticket too which was of
course hilarious right when you try not
to make it any big deal you just pull
the people that you feel are the most
hardcore hash smokers out of the group
to have a night of enjoying hash smoke
you know like it's been illegal for so
long that people feel they have to feel
bad about enjoying hashish well guess
what I smoked hashish all night at the
legends of hash parties I go home safely
in a cab or on a bicycle and I end up
waking up the next morning early around
7 or 8 a.m. and I'm ready to go a quick
shower brush my teeth a little a little
breakfast and out the door feeling good
it's like you can't really get that if
you abused like say alcohol for a night
like that the way and I wouldn't say we
abuse it we really like it's almost
spiritual it's like a therapeutic
spiritual night of hashish do I do those
yearly I tried to coup I try to it's not
easy to do them but I try to yeah I do
indeed try to we were supposed to do one
in Barcelona this year and it was going
to be great if I had my place here in
Vancouver I would absolutely I when I
had my gallery the melting point I would
have a legends of hashish every year I
threw three in a row in Vancouver and
it's been a while since I threw one in
Vancouver over a decade in fact so
that's crazy
I think it would be a fun one I'm kind
of thinking hello Amelia I'm thinking
maybe Jamaica would be a fun legends if
I could get a hundred people to come to
a legends in Jamaica and maybe even just
make it a like a legends weekend almost
where you know people come it's the the
logistics are tricky because people
really need to have the
sheesh so ideally people would come to
Jamaica they would go find material that
they felt was the best that they could
find they would potentially concentrate
or extract it with whatever process they
had because trust me a lot of it is
there in Jamaica now it would be fun to
come back and meet each other all for a
celebration
you know for me it's not about a
competition it never really was you know
the the the simple competition is is
that you put everything out on a table
and this is how I did it in Vancouver I
put everything out on small plates on a
table small amounts of each unique
cultivar and you know the one that was
gone first was the one that silently won
the one that was given the respects was
oh who brought that one you know in
Vancouver I brought them all so if there
were twelve or fifteen different kinds
of melt on the table I had put them all
there from saving them over the course
of the last year I'll put like five or
six grams of each nice melted part aside
until I have 12 or 15 different ones and
then I would do a big buffet exactly
like what Rob just said I had a nice
picture of Shiva in the background and
all these beautiful ornate bowls and I
gave everyone paper plates where they
could write then the names of all the
cultivars down and then take a little
scoop out of the bowl and put it next to
the name on the plate and you can go
back to your table which was inside my
gallery the melting point and there were
beautiful rulers and glass on all the
tables brand-new stainless steel screens
and wicks and anything you needed to
vaporize we had half a dozen different
vaporizers from the aeromed from Germany
to the volcano to volatize er to the rip
tech it was quite lavish I'm not gonna
lie it was quite lavish that is the
truth so yeah I guess I can't I think
that's it I think I think I'm gonna call
it a day thank you guys all for coming
out and I still haven't heard from
yesterday's winner who won I guess it
was the Dark Crystal glass cleaner so
whoever won yesterday please send me
that email and of course I'll go back
listen to the video make sure it's the
right one
and right person because it's getting a
little confusing I have like five or six
I need to send I haven't sent anything
since the book so I have the book I have
the the dab mat from the volcano kid I
have like three or four sasquatch
one so I need to go today and send these
out so hopefully I can get these emails
and in the meantime as always made the
film L bless your bowl sooner than later
peace out everybody