hey good morning guys still here at the
rock house just have a few drinks at the
bar and met with a Russian friend that
we met at the show last night sold him
some bubble bags so he's one happy
camper but another gentleman from Italy
today that I'm going to be selling bags
to and then we've got a drive to
Kingston we're gonna follow the nomads
in their car make our way to Kingston so
yeah pretty sweet
you own over this way
I'm just gonna go for a little swim here
just waking up in the grill on the
cliffs at the rock house you guys a
little show
good morning
so
it always helps
camera
haha
hi guys
bubble man's world going in
one more great reason to come to Jamaica
the Caribbean Sea
[Music]
[Applause]
nothing me intervene and I gotcha
something would I really love in our how
cause I wanna leave this Reformation
when so many Chaves treat my peoples
will take my god man and
[Music]