[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world I am
over here at the West Coast concentrate
uh one of the spots yeah with Brett and
Adam and today we're going to do a
little review on some West Coast
concentrate products uh we were going to
film our melt videos first we we did get
one melt video done in uh what was that
like an hour yeah close to almost broke
the pipe twice y dropped the light bulb
on the table for additional light uh
let's see we dropped the silicone or the
uh the ceramic as well as the sapphire
burnt the table um we decided we're
going to do the Melt videos
later and we're just going to film The
Talking aspect uh we're hitting through
a silicon carbide uh nail and uh yeah
why don't you uh pull out one of those
jars tell us a little bit about the
strain you guys can maybe talk a little
bit about what it's like to wash this
particular strain where the Melt is
found definitely and uh then we'll all
hit it sure or we'll hit it while you
guys are talking yeah so just the one
from the top there uh this is the purple
candy uh which is a pretty big Staple in
our flavor Department anyways we run a
lot of purple candy um it's it's a
pleasure to run honestly uh I've never
really had added until I moved out to BC
a few years ago so for me it's it's it's
something similarly new anyways uh but
the 120 um this is one of the first
times where we got a big batch of 120
off of it uh so we were like got to
share this uh I personally like the
bigger heads um full spec is great 73 is
great 90 is great but I don't know I
find the bigger heads just have a bit
more flavor uh they they seem to look a
little nicer too on the nail uh in my
opinion anyways but this stuff is still
pretty glandular um when 120's on smells
good flavor is usually where it holds
the best out of all the microns it's
proper for sure it's definitely if
you're doing a full spectrum and the 120
has that flavor don't be leaving it out
no for sure and we're still
experimenting with different uh bags and
what's our favorite and you know just
what what seems to give more what's
cleaner um so yeah it's all it's fun for
us like we we love it it's a it's a
dream come true really looks pretty
melty there for
sure yeah the purple candy is definitely
something we definitely get to run a lot
which is really a blessing it's a it's
it's a great hash strain uh at least
from from plants that we're what what is
the cultivars uh lineage what is purple
candy uh I've heard so many different
things uh we didn't grow this personally
uh this this exact like I don't grow
cannabis personally but uh so I I don't
want to you know overstep I've Heard
lots of different things I've heard that
there's purple cushion there I've heard
there's um uh candy cushion there I've
heard that there's the the perss are in
there so it really depends on who you
got the cut from basically what we've
heard from from from our friends and
from where we've got it from is that
it's uh Purple Kush and Candy Kush is
basically what we've heard from the
closest source to where it comes from
anyway you know from my um oil factory
and the taste of this rip that I just
did that seems pretty on point
definitely Purple Kush um I wouldn't say
the perss just it doesn't mean it
couldn't be in there but I don't
somebody's has the pers in it that's
what they've called it that's a thing
it's so hard these days where everyone's
calling things what they're called and
it's like un you get the seeds from the
guy who created The Strain that's really
the only way to do it and uh yeah I mean
I personally uh purple cand is one of my
favorites for sure uh from from our ume
our batch of flavors anyways yep
definitely get out there that last
little bit of the little scoop it's hard
to get that little glass little food
full well you have to be quick on the on
the uh how you drop it uh into the nail
that's for sure here ninja dab that's
you too it's like when people leave a
little bit of drink on the can take your
friends yeah take your friends right
yeah that was really nice flavor I love
the potency of the purple candy it
always looks great it's a joy to
photograph uh it's a pleasure whether
it's in rosin or bubble has the microns
the full spectrum it's hard for me to
say if I have a favorite of the microns
or the full spectrum I really just like
it all when I grab my jars and I see the
name on it I'm usually pretty happy to
know that I'm going to be able to get a
great dab out of this uh out of this
hash
definitely yeah the PC's PC's a good
returner we've talked about it
before something something we get to
watch all the time that was so quiet it
didn't land because it landed on the
Q-tip but it seemed like it landed on
this even it may have yeah cuz I know it
was nice I was expecting it to go it's a
very old jar this is a marble Slinger
classic probably 2002 maybe 2003 little
wiggity nice don't want to be losing
that fella so yeah there we go we got
one flavor down um purple candy 1 to 120
Micron from the West Coast concentrate
crew let's move on shall we next I got
it I got this
og73 um it was really one of the first
drains we've come across where we pulled
it right out of the bag and knew
instantly there was no way we could see
it with the the room and temperature
that we had
um so we instantly had to freeze it go
to micro uh go to micro planting and it
turned out really nice micr planting was
always sort of like a a safety net for
me you know when people asked me what I
liked to do more I was like well they're
both in my quiver and seing is what I
prefer and microplaning can get me out
of a jam when my hash is just Tre
greased right out yeah yeah know it
turned out really nice it's gassy um I
look forward to running more it for sure
yeah we're hoping to get some more and
it's a true 73 as well so we've kept the
90 in there as well as the 120 um so I
don't know I I definitely uh it's it's a
new flavor for us to be running and
we're definitely um stoked on just any
new flavors really but this one seemed
to be a really great hash drain hard to
go bad hard to go wrong with with great
flavors for sure OG is a staple right
you know it's hard to it's hard to deny
the OG yeah it's absolutely beautiful
hand press full full like five to six
star quality for certain so uh oh I
think actually you started us off last
time didn't you sure I can definitely go
this time or maybe you ended us off
sorry that's what I meant you ended us
off two in a row so why don't we just
get you bubbling right up big clear
domes real nice color on it and uh you
know that
classic o flavor and taste the
O the o
from like what I know in my head of OG
that's exactly
that beautiful want to give it a little
Zamboni there BR I
Canam on it Adam's cough bit of a bigger
rip than I usually take yeah it was a
little bit bigger than I usually give
you actually it's all good you know why
cuz it was my rip and then it was like I
need to give this to Adam I'm going to
push this onto this guy B I'm going to
push this onto this guy just the hash
Pusher yep
I'm not going to lie I'm a bit of a
pusher so here we go OG Kush 73 Micron
true 73 that means the 90 Micron bag was
not used and everything from below the
120 bag fell into the 73 bag the true
the real deal Shaquille O'Neal the
rdso yeah I was uh I was super surprised
at
uh just how nice it came out not that it
was you know ugly plant or anything like
that but it
definitely definitely a new thing for us
to do and we're stoked on it I took a
deep yeah I know I seen that held her in
there then I was like yeah he's going
to very lovely very just you
know
classic OG Kush grabs you by the nuts
yeah isn't making me tear up right now
but I can it's so close and that's
that's kind of what you look for in the
efficient connoisseur world when you're
building your quiver of course you want
something like OG Kush in there that's
going to really give you a punch tastes
great melt like a five or six star and
just kind of not ever really
disappointed yeah presses out beautiful
um looks nice and blonde all the way
through right to dry yep careful how you
dip in there I know it's hard phph it
already broke stay nice and I can dip it
for you if you want are you looking to
do an
O that's cuz you you dipped the wrong
and that's okay we can get you another
photography one there's it's NeverEnding
paper
tow good call good call even though I'm
already q-tipping it this is my new
Q-tip tack of cleaning the uh see how
good it works I know yeah it works
perfect we've got one for later you nice
little a nice big nice one please yeah
here just take it all no jeez too late
that's a nice hit we're just going to
give him a good one this giv me a good
one BR always asks for a good one so
let's give him a good one it's going to
me about six
hits It's a quarter of the
gram but it's the O who doesn't love the
OE I mean my God it's just beautiful
somebody in church was telling the
story about that the OG the somebody
called it the AUG at the the trial oh
yeah yeah yeah exactly the the and then
he had
the AUG cush or something that was a
good one I love stories like that oh
yeah this is a good
rip that's what you get if you dip your
Dabber in my jar and you break a big
chunk of hash off smoke it all you get
to smoke
it which is not a bad thing not if you
want that I definitely don't mind your
that no it's uh it would have been a
nice melt video this one cuz it was you
know generally we don't want to waste
hash when we're making a a melt video a
lot of people think I waste my hash I'm
smoking that hash while I'm making the
Melt video it's not an easy thing to do
it's not especially once you do two or
three in a row and you know a size hit
like that you smoke a gram in 15 minutes
and you're destroyed yeah then you got
to try and edit it or something and
forget about it tomorrow we'll do
Champion hit from Brett right there that
was uh that was great Top Notch action
there and now we get to move on what's
the last one here the last one is from
our good friend Phil yeah true genetics
true genetics He's Got The Sweat Band
This Is The Sweat Band true 73 as well
uh Phil process and grew this
photographed it looks beautiful it's
definitely really nice super unique
smell all of these hashes really look
beautiful I'll have to make a picture
where they're all right next to one
another to show their subtle differences
this seems to be potentially it's a
little cheesier funky smelling than the
OG is like a strong cushy kind of it's
got a nice blondish yellow look to it as
wellar nicely as well too that one did
not get microplane so it's got all the
heads still attacked nicely well we got
some photos so you guys are probably
looking at them right now overlaid on
the video beautiful beautiful stuff yeah
Phil did a great job on that stuff I
definitely got to give him M props for
that who is Right BR just did a great
job on that rip got
14 smacky [ __ ] he'll be getting a few
slices of pizza oh my God we are
definitely going to Nat's Pizza okay
here's something that we got to ask the
people is Nat's original like from
Brooklyn or Manhattan because this whole
place is done up like it's a a New York
Pizzeria what I'm asking people is is
there Nat's Pizza in Manhattan or in New
York City let us know we'll bring you
there after we do this review maybe
we'll show you kns real quick and
smiling brat eating a big piece of pizza
they definitely have the full milk Pizza
some margarita pizza oh yes my favorite
my favorite so what do we got we got OG
we're finished with uh you guys are due
for sweat Bandits sweat back and you too
I hit one you hit this already yeah the
first time how did you get it out I
think so maybe I didn't it's not touched
yet maybe I didn't hit it no you will
know you will know I will know too
cuzen if he hit it it was the most
impressive hit I've ever taken out of a
jar from a photographer standpoint I
couldn't tell where he hit it from you
tell where I hit it from of course I was
like how did he do that I'm just this is
my this is my wake and bake here so I
don't know what's going on really yeah
this is a that's all right to not know
what's going on even further there you
go you've already had two hits haven't
you yeah
exactly third one more than two hits cuz
we were doing the the trying to get the
Melt hits I know what was happening with
the Melt hits to give you the Side Story
is my flash ring that sits on the front
of the camera it's broken on the inside
it has three clips and one of the clips
on the inside no longer pushes out to
hold it on the lens so it falls off and
it falls on top of delicate things like
bongs and hash you know powdered out
hashes it's not a good look it's not a
good look let's just be honest so I know
we're getting stoned
but this is a fun part tell us about the
headband or the sweatband it definitely
is true to its name first of all he took
the headband and he crossed it with what
to make the sweat band that's what we
got to know we'll get him to we'll get
him to put it in the yes in the comment
section Phil will tell us what he gave
this to me and I should know and it was
a nice should know told me the other day
but too high right now to to think that
far back you just see what I just hit so
it was a big rip it was definitely one
of those rips that everyone at the
Cannabis Cup wants to give me yeah hey
bu man you want to rip I guess let's end
this day right here yeah I don't care if
it's a big rip as long as it's clean
yeah true you know what I mean if you
give me something that's not clean and I
have to take too much of it then it's
like wao yeah the SWAT B is is pretty
cheesy though like cheesier than it's
not like cheese but it's it's funky it's
funky
I like it sometimes the Hindu comes out
a little bit cheese ask as well and I
would say that it's not a bad I prefer
that flavor honestly over a lot of the
fruity ones myself but to each their own
cheese it's a little bit cheesy it's not
like the cheese but it's definitely got
some some funk to it I'll tell you for
the size of the rip I
took that's a lot of of smoke that It
produced got to get a good couple hits
there like it actually hit really nice
beautiful resin yeah props to fill for
that one y let's get uh I got one oh you
oh perfect look at that no D you're
Champion CH are a champion man I just
didn't really want to hit half the jar
again yeah I was like yeah well you
wouldn't have to not when you pull it
out like that and you didn't even really
have to hit that I just thought I know
you love big rips oh I wasn't that and
it's definitely not like I was being a
dick it was like uh he loves big rips
true
he on the other hand did I give you a
big rift uh the first the first one was
a big day but it's all good I didn't die
we're still here he likes the puss RPS
that's the puss trips we talk about
those in hash church for those of you
that watch hash church every Sunday
morning on Bubble man's world this gets
so awesome stay tuned it's getting good
I think 73 we're going to have a hash
episode we'll have these guys on
hopefully going to invite a bunch of
other different people that are actively
making hash on the regular and just have
a great episode episode about talking
about hash and talking about Little T
tips and tricks and different subtleties
and nuances that we all find and see
when we're making hash we look forward
to it absolutely it's going to be
definitely share some knowledge get some
get some tips so that was three bubble
hashes we did want to finish it off with
a rosin rip um tell us about the rosin
that we're hitting today uh this is some
master Scout uh rosin which is another
one of my favorite flavors uh at least
in our quiver um it's super super lemony
go hold it up to the camera that one you
can do just hold your hand in the back
there and it'll clear right up you can
go close close close and it'll grab once
everything else disappears probably
right around
there yeah so it's definitely uh very
nice looking rosin pretty lemony uh on
this on the flavor but it's like a lemon
soap it might be my favorite type of
rosin that you guys make it's just that
Jack Frost Master Scout combo it goes so
well with almost any of the turfs I've
tried done lemon cush
tur I like it better with the the Hindu
honestly really the purple Hindu it's
phenomenal it's nuts wow it's a
different thing shout out to Blue River
for that very good very good I like it I
like it yeah I think I think you'll like
it and this one actually is one of the
sometimes the um the hash rosin can get
a little bit buttered out or something
if the hash hasn't been like fully fully
dried or you know just little things
like that can can change the the way
that the hash comes out but this one
stayed really stable man this one's nice
yeah I
know super L yeah it's like Lemon Pledge
or something yeah it's like a cleaning
supply for sure oh yeah it's nice it is
very pledgie
pedy it's got a great I mean I took a
very small one but it's just got a great
kind of feel to the high too yeah it's
very
upy I was saying thoughting I don't even
mind smoking that before bed like I I
just like the master it just gets me
into a nice place I can go to bed I can
go do stuff it's just one of those
strains I can use it all the time yeah
it's a good
functioning it'll be nice it'll be very
nice after this OG
rip it was the shadow of the tip I was
like did I give him that with dirt on it
and then when he looked at it it kind of
made me doubt myself like I think I
might have given it to him a little bit
alas I did not good on you so yeah real
nice flavor real nice high love the
master Scout
rosin West Coast
concentrate uh where can they get these
products um most of these products are
available either at Eden medicinal
Society they have multiple locations uh
or you can also find some of our
products at um TC they're on Main Street
Main Street in Vancouver perfect and uh
then they check you guys out as well on
Instagram you guys have accounts on
there what West Coast melts and west
coast and you can also follow the West
Coast Collective uh with no e on the end
of collective and uh true genetics 604
for some of the genetics and uh pictures
of hash and plants and everything
else excellent well I mean aside from uh
giving The J Man a shout out for
starting a great company and seeing uh
having the wisdom to create a branch of
Sol
solventless crew that are actively
making water hash it's a it's a tough
gig in our city right now butane is all
over the place uh unflushed chig grown
weed is all over the place it's very
hard to find top quality properly grown
cultivars that have been then been
processed into property properly
processed and dried and cured resins so
uh hats off to both of you guys for uh
doing the good work
as well you you know all of the the big
guys out there that are just doing it
right doing it all the time that's where
we came you know we saw it we were like
how do we do that you know so well
that's why we're doing it literally for
the very reason that we want to I mean
it's win-win win when you see the
younger generation coming up and they
have beautiful hash and rosins and
you're like this is I've been waiting
for this to happen for years why I
always wondered when I when it was me 15
to 17 years ago in Vancouver and no one
was doing it I was like I wonder how
long this will take to get everyone
doing it and it's like 20 years later
and it's still you guys are like man
it's us and it's like we're waiting for
yeah you know it's a tough gig yeah it's
a tough gig for sure 2016 is the year of
the full melt I'm not sure if we're
going to see what Johnny Be coined as
the death of BHO but she surely has been
wounded
boys thanks for watching Bubble man's
[Music]
world why the timber Ro feel real good
give me
[Music]
a one man home man
realp the purpose after the weed that's
to the
m purpose after the weed gave by
this the purpose after the we l i VI the
time
we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
ding well I've been traveling to
Kingston 20 mil hour sleeping on like
the clock fresh vegetation with trees
and with flowers off stop
and give me a big
Z don't give me give
me give me one Bigg and if
[Music]
bigger I make pass pass pass and
now