[Music]
[Applause]
you guys are great thanks thanks
watermelon let's give watermelon a big
round of applause
we try to keep it fresh and funky always
um speaking of fresh and funky our next
battle um is uh you know in every in
every respective area where cannabis
legalization is going on whether it's
under medical or recreational offices uh
you have these U uh these Gatekeepers
these oracles these these certain uh
individuals that have uh been there for
a long long time in this battle for a
long long time because before this
became an issue of Economics it was an
issue of just pure Justice okay and uh
uh I
mean it's so important to understand
that that when when we're the there's
there's how do I say this I'm sry I
never prepare any notes by the way um
but obviously you can tell uh there's
oracles there's Gaye and these
Gatekeepers are are what we go to as the
foundation from what everything Springs
from and there's a certain amount of uh
lawyers can be real shyers
okay but in every but in every that's
what I was trying
to but in every in every in every
respective area where there is the
legalization and Recreation recreational
things going on there's always a few
lawyers that are Hardy activists there's
always a few lawyers that actually Lobby
against their own interests in terms of
making money and that is by reducing and
ending criminal penalties uh towards
cannabis you know no nobody likes to see
injustices if they make money out the
only person likes to see that are Das I
don't know what you call those in Canada
Crown prosecutor Crown counsel and I'm
sure they're dicks okay
they're wonderful people I've said that
that's those are my words
not um and with that uh I I'm going to
uh give it up to Mr KK Tusa uh we have a
extremely powerful panel of uh three of
the top uh advocates in Canada uh I'm
going to introduce Kurt Tusa here he is
the man if it wasn't for Kurt Tua uh
none of us would be even in this room
right now so give it up for
[Applause]
Kirk thanks Alex very much and and
thanks to the ICBC for putting on this
incredible conference it's been a great
two days I hope everybody's enjoying
themselves as much as we are um yeah I'm
going to just give you the format of
what we're going to do here uh today I'm
going to give a little bit of an
introduction of these two fine gentlemen
in my
give an overview of Canada's current
medical cannabis regulatory policies I'm
going to pose a couple of questions to
to these very smart individuals and
they're hopefully to make me look good
with their answers and then we're going
to kind of turn it into just a
discussion we're hoping to have a lot of
participation from the audience uh I
think you know if you've got a question
about the medical regime the transition
towards legalization it's probably
shared by everyone in the room uh and
we'll do our best to sort of dust off
our our the balls and and prognosticate
a bit and and try to talk about how
things are right now and and where
things might be going as we move this uh
this policy this industry this culture
forward here in Canada so to my right uh
joined uh on the panel here is Rob Lori
uh he's the principal of AD lome law
corporation B based in Vancouver uh he
attended UBC uh in Oxford University was
called the bar in the United Kingdom in
2006 in province of British Columbia in
2011 uh Rob's doing a ton of work right
now working with dispensaries and and
others in the Canabis industry here in
Vancouver and really across the province
uh and it's a real pleasure to have him
on the stage with us right
now immediately to Rob's right is a man
who probably needs no introduction he's
the The Godfather of ganja litigation
[Applause]
of
our I think it's fair to say without
John Conway Rob and I would be uh not
doing what we're doing uh and certainly
not doing it anywhere near as
successfully it's John Conroy QC Conroy
law uh and and really his list of
accomplishments in prison law reform and
fighting for human rights and fighting
for people's rights and being founder of
normal Canada back in
1971 uh there's not much you can say my
mentor one of best lawyers I've ever
known one of the best people I've ever
known that's John
C thank
you thank
you so let's kick this off with a sort
of where we are right now um as a result
of uh litigation uh brought by U John
and and a team of lawyers um back in
2013 2014 uh when the government of
Canada moved away from the medical
marijuana access regulations a medical
Canabis exemption scheme that had its
primary focus personal and caregiver
designated production for a limited
number of patients um a lawsuit was
filed called Allard versus candada
because the government candidate chose
to transition away from that system
towards a commercially oriented system
called the mmpr or Marland for medical
purposes regulations that system took
away home and and personal and caregiver
production rights uh entirely from all
patients uh and it forced you instead to
access your cannabis from uh a group of
then non-existing but now existing
licensed producers who have managed to
navigate a very top heavy bureaucracy
and obtain licenses to produce and self
cations I think it's fair to say that
that system has not worked very well uh
up to this point I don't think we
necessarily need to be labor that right
now um but that lawsuit triggered uh
success uh earlier this year uh the mmpr
was struck down in their entirety as
being unconstitutional in February of
this year uh the court in a very I
thought well thought out and strong
opinion eviscerated the crown Witnesses
uh who suggested that there was some
sort of intrinsic danger in producing
cannabis and need destroy your homes and
burn your neighborhoods down and do all
these terrible things that was
because it's not true uh not believed by
the court and so uh the court gave the
government six months to fix the access
problems existing with the mmpr and so
what the government did is brought in
this new acronym this new regulatory
scheme in August of this year called the
acmpr so we're really in the infancy of
this new program and the acmpr the
access to cannabis for medical purposes
uh regulations prolongated under the
control drugs and Substances Act
essentially did did a couple of things
they breathed new life into the
commercial production aspects of the
mmpr that was sort of brought back but
the licensed producer system remains in
place it is not been significantly
streamlined as of yet there continue to
be hundreds of applications in the
pipeline that aren't really moving at
the pace that are necessary becomes it's
also very difficult to navigate and they
sort of mushed that together um um with
the old MMA uh and and in effect the
acmpr and the old mm are pretty much the
same they feature pretty much the same
process we're getting uh it's no longer
called the license now it's called the
registration I'll probably call it a
license at time during the course of
this talk but it it's basically the same
alpath ACC physician signs a medical
documents sets out your dosage you
submit that to the to the government you
can then register yourself as a personal
producer of a number of plants that are
calculated based on that dosage at
roughly five plans per gram per day for
indoor production or two plans per gram
per day for outdoor production
um or you can designate someone to
produce for you on your behalf they
become the grower uh and they can then
for and they can charge you uh they can
provide the medicine to you designated
producers can service at most a maximum
of two patients that's a feature the old
system that was preserved in the new
system I think a constitutional we can
maybe get into that later and you can
have a total of four uh production
licenses or registrations at any one
physical site again that's a whole over
from the old system um there are a
number of tweaks and features uh to the
acmpr but sort of broad brush Strokes
that that's what we have we have the
mmpr and the F muchh together and you
have one system for commercial producers
and one system for home and or
designated producers uh the injunction
that was granted that preserved mm
rights for about 28,000 patients
continues to have Vitality today if you
were protected then you're still
protected now government's going to have
to go back to to try to undo that
injunction and they may do that at some
point in the future if however anything
needed to change from that status quo as
of at the end of 20 uh 13 early 2014 you
need to now go through the acmpr to
moove your licenses to to grow at a
different location to increase your
dosages to change your designated
producer any any changes to the status
quo at the time of the injunction
requiring you to be the new participant
in the new system so that's the broad
brush Strokes overview I'm going to kick
this off by uh asking rob a
question uh and that's uh if in his
review of the new acmpr are there
pressure points and issues that he's
identified that could be problematic in
that regime as we move forward all right
Thank you Kirk and let me just start off
by saying it's a real honor to be up on
a panel with these two and to be part of
this great conference so give yourself a
round of applause for coming
here all right
so limitations and problems with the
acmpr now to start out with this acmpr
was really you know it's designed to
salvage two medical programs that have
been in place for a while the difficulty
is is as Kirk mentioned in the panel
this morning doctors have been forced
with the role of Gatekeepers and so
under the acmpr you still have to go to
a doctor to get a what would be known as
a prescription usually and uh the
problem still is doctors are not signing
those uh as readily as we would like to
see so that's one issue um even though
if you do get a permit under the acmpr
to grow cannabis well it's not like you
can pop down to crop King seeds or you
know Mark Amor's or wherever you have to
buy your seeds from limited Supply and
limited sources so in my opinion that
doesn't really seem like a free and fair
market um again Limited strains the
licensed producers uh in many respects
are limited with what they can supply
the patient Market with respect to what
health Canada says they can so really if
unless you fit within that very those
very limited exceptions you have a
problem even if you do get your
prescription or
recommendation to grow well what do you
do for the six three to six months of
your first cycle right so again that's
why we're seeing dispensaries
unfortunately or fortunately however you
want to see it are really going to
remain the the reasonable dignified
patient
access and um let me just see the other
Pitfall
um I'll give you a story my dad was
recently diagnosed with cancer and had
followed the law and waited for him to
get a doctor's prescription and so on
and so forth his stage one uh can
reptile cancer would have spread in fact
I gave him a an address of a farm and
Mission and he's been on the suppository
so I guess it illustrates the the
problem of do I follow the law or do I
help my dad and I can assure you I'm
going to help my dad and I know the
majority of the folks out there that are
requiring access to cannabis can't get
it without feeling like they're in a
position where they're breaking the law
and and I think that's the biggest issue
that this legalization question has to
address so those are my my thoughts on
the limitation and
pitfalls what do you think her I you
know I think Rob identified six points
uh one was the doctor's gatekeeper the
second one was The Limited sources for
starting genetics third is limited
strains available in the lp system
fourth is access home producers or
designated producers during increase
Cycles or downtimes or get crop failures
the fifth is that dispensaries are not
part of the legal regime and yet they're
the primary access point for most
patients in Canada and then six is is
related to that and that's there's a
limited range of products available in
the lawful regime so John hearing
hearing these problems identified uh
with the
acmpr um what are your thoughts on as we
transition towards legalization
um how some of these different uh points
can be
addressed well my hope is that uh many
people will apply under the acmpr
whether they like it or not if for no
other reason than to tell us what
problems they're having with because
remember Allard uh the injunction
continues until the court orders
otherwise or until further order of the
court so those people who were fortunate
to be grandfathered by the injunction
are protected by the injunction but they
they don't lose that status if they
applied under the acmpr and you've got
all of the people who weren't uh who
were called the left outs or who who
weren't covered by the the out
injunction who now can finally uh apply
to get their licenses again and at the
locations that they want to because one
of the biggest problems was trying to
change your your
location and so you have to remember
remember that this was a temporary
solution that was forced on the
government by the order in Allard they
had 6 months to come up with something
to fix the defects in the
mmpr and also remember that the evidence
uh in allardt pointed to the defects in
the mmpr which led to the patients
voting with their feet and going to the
dispensaries which led to the surge in
dispensaries which leads the argument
that really the dispensaries are lawful
in that they're simply filling the void
that was created by the
mmpr um so it's still a temporary
solution we need to know what the
problems are that people are having with
it because there are going to be more
changes the task force on
legalization uh there's a whole part of
their mandate that deals with medical
and so U my view is as we move towards
legalization uh hopefully uh it seems
very difficult to get some people to
overcome this attitude that they have to
to cannabis at marijuana but hopefully
they'll realize that uh they no longer
need all this security they no longer
need all of these limitations and
restrictions that they've imposed simply
because of this somewhat ridiculous fear
that uh it's all going to go into the
illicit market and there's you know the
the idea in my view is to flood the
market so that uh there's lots of
cannabis around and there's no longer
any interest or profit to be made as far
as organized crime which they always
throw up as being the the people who are
out there trying to make a profit out of
it so you hopefully we will transition
into a situation where as is apparently
happening now in California they're
trying to to ensure that the small
producers are protected and are able to
participate in the market not just big
producers so that all of the people who
have leared how to do it well and
produce uh good strains will be able to
continue and and to to participate on a
fair basis with others that the
dispensaries will continue to exist in
terms of the medical but as a distinct
perhaps group compared to stores that
will be able to
provide uh legal access to people for
social purposes and so my hope and it is
a hope but I'm not um i' I've been
around and been involved in this for so
long that I am somewhat cynical as to
what will happen once the task force
hands this over to the politicians even
though the politicians are saying they
will
legalize how what form that takes is of
significant concern but
hopefully uh they will come to their
senses and realize that there's an
existing Market with existing suppliers
with existing Distributors with existing
stores and they will try to Simply
regulate them in a fair way as opposed
to trying to change it uh by squeezing
this or squeezing that they're just
going to create more problems and and
more litigation so as I say they they've
created the as perck points out part one
of the acmpr is the old mmpr part two is
the old mm with a few tweaks it's
essentially the same but uh because of
the abuses by doctors in
particular the colleges across the
country and the Canadian Medical
Association and provincial associations
have clamped down on the doctors and
this has created a problem for those
doctors that did have a positive
attitude or new something about Canabis
and they're all fearful that they're
going to be hauled up in front of the
colleges and stuff when really it's the
doctors who were charging huge fees uh
and who were you know having people just
line up and signing for them without
bothering to do anything as far as their
medical situation is concerned or I
heard even charging on a per plant basis
was the last one that I heard so so you
can understand why the colleges have
come in because they see some of their
members clearly just you know in a total
conflict of interest just doing it in
order to make money nothing to do with
with uh the medical situation and
so the doctor gatekeeper thing I see as
as the looming problem which is not a
problem necessarily with the acmpr it is
to the extent that we've always said uh
doctors of traditional Chinese medicine
naturopaths people who know something
about real cold plant medicine uh should
be involved not just Al apathic medicine
types who are used to prescribing a pill
and take two of these and mail in the $5
type of thing so you know that certainly
is a tweak that could be I think part of
a a criticism of the acmpr but the
bigger problem is how to get these
colleges to come to their senses and uh
to you know get up to date in terms of
the the information that's out there
about cannabis and its uses for medical
purposes in in in particular and so you
know we had the M case some years ago
which
unfortunately didn't get through due to
a lack of evidence on some of the areas
so we really need to to document the
problems people are having because
Allard is until further order of the
court and so at some point in time
whether it's us or whether it's the
government we'll be back in court
and we need to know and have evidence to
show the court what the problems
continue to be so that the court will
hopefully not just say okay the acmpr is
the solution what are you complaining
about it's all over so that's why I've
been
saying fine if you're protected great
but if you're not protected both
protected and unprotected should apply
so we can see what the problems are and
document them and then we can at least
have that body of evidence to produce
the Justice feeling when we do have to
get back into court I certainly hope
that the government legalization model
will uh undo huge numbers of these
restrictions but I'm troubled when I
hear the chairperson the other day was
quoted as saying that young people
shouldn't smoke anything because it
causes cancer which then I said to
myself well you obviously haven't kept
up to date in terms of uh what the
smoking of cannabis and the difference
between smoking cannabis and cigarettes
and that there is no evidence of cancer
in fact the opposite that there isn't
empyema that it is a bronco dilate or
these sorts of things and that patients
some patients need to smoke it because
they need rapid onset eating it and
waiting an hour isn't going to work for
them so you know getting them to
understand exactly how it works I mean I
I shake my head because I've been
involved in it since the early 70s
people were being sent to jail for
simple possession in those days and uh
you know so from where I sit things look
way better than they used to but we
still have these ongoing issues and
problems which uh Astound me that they
continue to some people to have this
sort of attitude but uh the fight isn't
over we still have obviously some
looming issues to come and uh
again I I think you know our experience
with the task force those of us who
appeared in front of it was very good in
terms of being able to provide them with
information and the information seemed
to be very well received in terms of all
sorts of areas but again you know even
if they come up with a good model we
have seen even this
government uh have committees not follow
the recommendations of the Committees
not follow the recommendations of their
independent Senate
so uh I have to say it's a wait and see
a a as to what they recommend and B then
what the politicians do with it
afterwards all right so I think we're
going to turn it over to the audience
and see if we can get some questions if
anybody has anything they want to talk
about we'll take this guy here first
thank you guys for coming here and
talking today um I just wanted to know
uh what kind of legal consequences could
you expect for an unlicensed grower uh
arrested for cultivation if that grower
can prove the Cannabis was being sold
for medical purposes in a license
dispensary oh wow yeah so that's a
sensing law question I could throw
something out there and John will tell
me where I get it wrong perhaps um but
where are you the numberal question is
where are you uh because sentencing
tends to be different in different
provinces all right so you're in British
Columbia so there's there's a fairly
long line of sentencing Authority in
British Columbia imposing very lenient
sentences for producing canvas for
medical purposes even if contrary to
existing licensing are outside the
licensing scheme now a lot of that case
law imposed what's called a discharge
which is a finding of guilt and no entry
of criminal conviction that's that's
obviously a pretty good result if you
get to that point the difficulty is that
the conservative government's changes to
the control drugs and Substances Act
increasing the maximum penalty for
production from 7 years to 14 years and
imposing mandatory sentencing in some
cases uh means that production as an
offense is no longer discharge eligible
so you you cannot receive that outcome
of guilt but no entry in criminal
conviction if you're if you're found
guilty you will be convicted you will
have a criminal conviction entered
against you and the penalty is going to
range from at the low end perhaps a
suspended sentence
or a fine or some kind of probationary
disposition uh to at the higher end
potential mandatory minimum sensing
legislation based on the number of
plants and the presence or the absence
of any aggravating factors um those laws
those sensing laws have been from time
to time found to be uh
unconstitutional and so it remains to be
seen whether they would have any
continued Vitality uh going forward but
they they still are on the books
and I don't believe the litigations
progress to the point where you could
say with confidence that they would not
necessarily apply to you and those tend
to kick in after six plants between 6
and 200 grown for the purpose of
trafficking between 200 and 500 there's
another range of penalties and over 500
there's yet another range of potential
man during minimum
sentences it used to be that uh what
prejudiced you in life was getting a
conviction uh and I've written a paper
on the prejudicial consequences of a
non-conviction in Canada where people
get stays of proceedings because the
crown suddenly drops the charge
everybody's happy thinking oh the charge
has been dropped but you'll still have
problems at the border with a stay
you'll have problems in other places
with the stay another thing they do is
withdraw the charge and but this digital
age I'm afraid has created a situation
where whatever is in the digital
database some where oh you were seen in
a car with somebody who had a joint in
your passenger had a joint 10 years ago
and a guy like corpal homequest who was
the main witness in in uh Allard who I
just spent the last week arguing about
again and another case he's going he's
the guy who goes to these databases and
digs it up and causes these problems so
we've got convictions and sentences and
referred to the discharges it was uh
prime minister's father Pierre Trudeau
who introduced absolute and conditional
discharges because of cannabis offenses
so to try and reduce the consequences
for people of of having a record and you
should know that even if you get an
absolute discharge the record remains
for a year before they have to take it
off and a conditional discharge it
remains for three years and then in more
recent times uh because we've always
complained about the over incarceration
of people in the country the government
brought in in conditional sentence
orders and a conditional sentence is
quite distinct from a conditional
discharge is sort of the last step
before actually being sent to prison and
so you could have a conditional sentence
where you served your sentence at home
or at least in the community subject to
various conditions before conditional
sentence orders existed we used to be
able to get people probation and period
of maybe a couple of months of house
arrest so they could still work support
their families and so on and so for even
though was a sanction so I just argued a
case of maybe 6 months ago now called
nearer in Catan where we argued that now
with the government having said it's
going to
legalize so what is the crown supposed
to do what is the defense supposed to do
what's the judge supposed to do in
sentencing the principles of sentencing
that one looks at a major one is to deny
the conduct and so we said to the judge
in saskatch well uh the government here
is on one hand saying give this guy 15
to 19 months it was a trafficking
possession for the purpose of
trafficking case about
30 and on the other hand the government
saying we're going to legalize so uh you
know denounce denounce conduct that you
say you're going to legalize another
sentencing principle is to deter others
who are likeminded again
you know you're going to legalize so
people are going to do it so you know
what what's going on here I mean the
other ones are are you reformed and
rehabilitated well usually it's a year
later and the person has usually managed
to do all sorts of things to appear at
least to be reformed
rehabilitated and the other one is
specific dets so so we said look you
know J the crown here wants 15 to 19
months uh and they've taken away the
conservatives took away the ability to
impose conditional sentence orders and
here was a classic fellow who would have
got a conditional sentence order if they
still existed and didn't need to be sent
actually into prison and to my surprise
the judge accepted that argument and he
said we are in an interregnum period
between Kings between
C and he gave him probation with a
couple of months of house arrest and uh
some other ancillary orders you know
Firearms etc etc and the government has
appealed that uh so they run the risk of
the Saskatchewan court of appeal
hopefully accepting the position I just
heard the other day they want us to be
there November 10th but I think it's
more likely to be at the end of November
but I also heard U other Council have
succeeded in a dial of dope uh case to
get a conditional discharge for somebody
based on was it J yeah maybe it
was no no that's this is a recent
sentencing in British Columbia so we're
encouraging other lawyers and then
certainly people who are facing these
sorts of issues to get their lawyers to
make that same argument and rely on Neri
to point out this problem and I you know
you you criticize some of the crown
counsil I've known some of the people in
the federal department of justice for a
long period of time and they're quite
candid some of them with me not all of
them but some of them uh about how
they're in this awkward position you
know what are we supposed to do we're s
of getting conflicting positions here in
terms of what we're we're supposed to do
and of course as Kirk mentioned
mandatory minimums it's ridiculous that
they've brought in these mandatory
minimums and and it's ridiculous that
this government hasn't moved to get rid
of them you know that should have
happened by now and yet we're still
forced into situations
where we have to make these arguments
I've got a a guy next week who he he was
a guy who went and watered plants to
make a little extra money he wasn't
involved in any other aspects of this
grow operation uh he wasn't he wasn't
benefiting in any other way from it
other than being paid and he's the only
one charged because they screwed up in
relation to the main people and all the
rest of it and they're running three
years mandatory minimum for this fellow
and so you say you know okay so we're
going to have another challenge to the
mandatory minimum we're going to have
another challenge to the fact that they
took away the conditional sentence
orders and it's going to wind its way
these cases are going to wind their way
up through the courts and come the
spring they're supposed to legalize or
start the process so what are the judges
supposed to do you know they're sitting
there saying wait a minute you know this
doesn't make sense so there's a real
problem and we really need to somehow
get the current federal liberal
government to move quicker or move
faster and get this sorted out so that
we can put this behind us and uh move
forward better take some more questions
let's hear
from okay um hold close your okay first
of all I'd like to agree with your point
that um doctors are an issue um doctors
are not available in a lot of the
province I mean people don't have doctor
you can't get access to a doctor I mean
many people can so it's really an issue
I mean in Vancouver there's lots of
doctors but out in the country it's hard
okay they're just simply not available
so that's a real barrier okay and um
secondly you know the license producers
in in the old mm regime they're getting
forced out because they can't afford the
the access barriers now that are in
place okay so we're changing the whole
base of the industry into these great
big players that are squishing out
little guys that actually formed the
industry and have been on the front
lines fighting all the way okay so it's
it's really not right and secondly um I
just like to point I finally did get
access to a temporary doctor I managed
to get I applied for and got my U
medical grow okay and um you were
mentioning and I also saw on the website
that it's supposed to be um two plants
per
gram an outdoor license is approximately
two plants per gram per day right well
they're issuing under the old uh amount
still so I got issued one plant program
outside and 3.7 for inside so oh you
went with a with a split license indoor
outdoor so there is a different formula
for there is an indoor outdoor license
you can only grow indoors or Outdoors at
any one time but the formula is
different if you apply for that
licensing uh because the assumption is
that you're going to grow indoors during
the indoor cycle and Outdoors during the
outdoor cycle and they sort of think
you'll you'll produce x amount of
cannabis as a result of those two three
Cycles a year that's one of the things
that's carried forward in the acmpr you
can only grow indoors or outdoors and
does that make sense I mean I would
think people would start indoors try to
get them Outdoors when you get some good
weather to reduce your hydro cost and
bring them back in before the Bold sets
in you know
[Applause]
so you know there continue to be these
issues there's no doubt the ACM and and
you know to be fair you can't reg no
regulatory scheme is going to capture
every potential factual situation but
but that's why the scheme ought to have
some more flexibility than that and at
the end of the day any plant number is
pretty arbitrary isn't it what does it
what does it matter I mean why why
should you have to grow four big plants
instead of 40 really small plants maybe
that's your preferred growing method at
the end of the day the question ought to
be are you uh growing that for
commercial purposes in which case
there's a different system for you to be
part of or are you growing it for your
yourself or permision to caregiver um
then then it's a different ball game
entirely what most people Overlook is
because it's been a criminal issue but
now we're looking at product liability
when I hear for the old mm Growers that
say but I had a right to grow in like
solid people under M it's like no you
didn't you had the ability to grow for
yourself and grow for someone else and
that's it but when you then give that
product or sell that product in a
commercial retail like setting there's a
whole bunch of other rules I mean for
any of the lawyers in the room you only
have to look at Don ATU and Stevenson
which was a case of a snail in a bottle
of ginger beer in England about 100
years ago which essentially means that
you have a duty of care that is owed to
the ultimate consumer so if you're
selling or producing a prod a product
and then that goes to the dispensary and
then the dispensary sells it on to
somebody well you then have to ensure
that that that product and you meet the
duty of care to the ultimate consumer
and so really until we figure out
definitively how are we going to get can
cannabis by the mail dispensary liquor
store um that's really going to
determine a lot on that do we have
another question
yeah I think we need a few good lawyers
by the sounds of it who are these people
are we not free I mean who gets to tell
you how many plants you can have and you
know why why is cannabis treated hard
more harshly than tomatoes or potatoes
and all that stuff um we've actually
known for a long time that they're full
of that they lied their through
their teeth about this that the Cannabis
was never a dangerous strug it was only
ever a threat to corporations and people
that wanted to sell you their stuff and
so the whole thing is is a huge scam and
it's a huge crime against us and it's
continuing and there should be some
repercussions for these people they
shouldn't be able to just get into the
business of now selling us weed after
they spent their lives penalizing people
for it uh we need some lawyers to go
after these people they should be held
to the fire it's a huge huge time
[Applause]
that's you're obviously preaching the
choir at this
conference we can't keep up with
I would say on the on the question of
you know should lawyers go after people
that are legislators that then get into
the Cannabis industry I mean you know in
law you have to have causes of action
you have to have base seats for lawsuits
you can't just sue people because you
think they're bad people or did bad
things they've hurt a lot of people and
they've known for a long time in law you
need a cause of action to sue someone
and it is not to my knowledge a cause of
action to be wrong in legislative policy
change your mind vote for something new
and then later become part of that
industry there's that's not a cause of
action that's just what happens I'm not
saying prosecutive for the ones getting
into the Cannabis industry I'm saying
the ones that maintained these
prohibitions knowing that they were
wrong and in violation of free people
and hurting people they that's a huge
huge
crime agree that it's politically UNR
morally reprehensible but I don't see a
legal cause of action how do you stop
people supporting Donald Trump
[Applause]
you elective that'll teach him well I
mean your power comes in BX that's where
you exercise power over political
officials at the B they get away with it
yeah have another question next question
my quick answer to you is I think
education um how we help Donald Trump
supporters their education I think will
make some better decisions but um I have
two questions completely unrelated but
maybe sort of related um my first
question is um just wasting more of what
jod was asking yesterday what is going
to happen to the people who have already
been wrongfully incarcerated for using
cannabis simple possession once
legalization comes about are those
people are going to be remaining in jail
what's going to happen with their
process um my second question as
actually just more to what you were
mentioning a lot of people in rural
communities don't have access to doctors
that are on board that um choose not to
educate themselves and I know that
that's very frustrating um
wondering isn't that doing harm by
choosing to remain ignorant to something
that has a lot of theil right on the
head well really but it's philosophical
but it's also legal like I so those are
my two questions sure why don't we uh
John you've had many more clients
wrongfully incarcerated than I have
um John is actually an expert on Prison
reforms that's a great question is he's
he's an expert on Prison policy been
fighting for the rights of prisoners
just as long as the rights of canis
consumers so so what does
happen what can and does happen uh when
we legalize candidates all the victims
well you know my hope and expectation
would be that we will have a government
commuting providing amnesty or you know
these remission these sorts of things we
do have a process for getting Royal
prerogatives of mercy and pardons and
these sorts of things so I would expect
that there will be some movement to try
and and decarcerate people who are in in
that situation I mean my uh position is
broader than just cannabis I don't think
that drug use of any kind should be
subjected to the criminal law it's a
health
issue with trying to control people's
use and providing a black market for
organized crime essentially uh it's just
absolutely stupid yeah um but in terms
of your other question I mean I think
again the digital age hopefully will
enable people by Skype and other sorts
of ways to be able to access doctors
remotely uh in order to deal with that
problem I know that some doctors are
doing that again the college sometimes
raises issues with them doing that if
they're in different provinces and
things like that but surely that's the
obvious solution is if you're in a
remote community and you don't have a
doctor and you're entitled to reasonable
access uh the doctors who understand the
issue and who are supportive should be
able you should be able to access them
online
and you legal action those doctors who
choose not to educate themselves or the
college well I was going to throw that
to Rob is there in your view a cause of
action against against an individual
doctor or a college for its prescribing
or or prescription type policies or
refusals to do assist patients well
there's definitely a cause of action the
question is finding a cause of action
that the courts will take serious now
one of the big difficulties is when you
go up against a
regulator which has
had um what it Authority delegated or
power delegated to them by um the
government and there's an expectation
that well the government entrusted the
college with power to essentially make
mistakes I mean their job is to try to
regulate policy the best as they can and
although look I'll be Devil's Advocate
they may not get it right all the time
they get it right
sometime and unfortunately that's really
how things evolve and get better I think
the answer that you need to be looking
at is instead of like well I need to
deal with the college I need to you know
fight all these battles I think the
better way to look at it is you know did
women wait around to get the vote no
they engaged in Civil Disobedience until
the laws and the rules change what's so
fascinating about you know we saw an
Allard they didn't really address the
issue of dispensaries but despite the uh
intense enforcement in Ontario and the
lack of enforcement in British Columbia
creates this patch quilt scenario where
the difficulty I see it I mean we had
brandan Kennedy this morning and it's
all very impressive but this is a race
to the bottom ladies and gentlemen folks
have been growing and engaging in
cannabis and some of our clients been
doing this for 40 years and I'm
confident tomorrow they're going to wake
up and continue to do what they're doing
regardless right and so really these are
who the corporate and I work I have a
Wall Street background I worked in L
London city of London
and New York with the cia's law firm on
Wall Street and all of this really is
ladies and gentlemen is designed to be a
most trap to essentially work for the
people that Lobby and uh you know put
policy for the system so every day that
you go to a dispensary and make that
decision to shop there or to inform
yourself and educate yourself and make
the decision that if cannabis is right
for you that's a decision that you need
to make and so
thank you you can wait for the
government to get it right and actually
I'll use an analogy as they say in Texas
you can wish in one hand in the
other and see what fills up first so I
think the question is is the government
may or may not get it right well show
them how they should do it and so that's
where I think the future really is civil
disobedience and social engagement
because it's the communities that are
making the changes and the monies are
flowing up the Grassroots back into the
community not to Ottawa let me just
speak to the issue you you said in terms
of the doctors and the colleges I me
again the colleges are doing the right
thing in my view and trying to clamp
down on the doctors that are abusing the
system but it's having this impact in
affecting reasonable access and so I
think in the short term we need to get
the doctors there is a group The
practitioners for uh cannabis medicine I
think it's if I'm getting the name right
but there a a group of doctors across
Canada who are fully supportive and
knowledgeable about cannabis these folks
have to be the ones going after the
heads of their colleges and and and
being the ones to try and bring them you
know educate them and so on just like we
lawyers if it's the Law Society or the
Canadian bar we need to be the ones who
go there to do it rather than just
thinking you can start a court case and
somehow that will uh will uh sort the
problem up let me just for a quick story
for you though because Rob mentioned
women on the right to vote uh you got to
remember that uh it was uh uh one of the
famous five who wrote the Black Candle
and uh it was the Black Candle that was
serialized in uh in McLean's magazine
across Canada that was based on all the
stories in the US that uh led to uh 1923
cannabis being put in the schedule to
then opum narcotic act following on what
we did here in Vancouver when we had uh
all the Chinese who came and built the
railroads and were our best workers and
many of them were killed doing so and we
had opium dens they brought the Opium
with them from China after the Opium
Wars and so on we had opium dens all
over Vancouver Victoria and New
Westminster more than the
dispensaries and uh it was a Labor uh
situ situation that led to them uh
kicking shutting them down and kicking
them out if you go to the Dominion
annual statistics you'll see China and
deported possession of opium product and
so when you look into the history of
drug prohibition it all goes back to
that the Chinese in terms of opium the
black people in terms of cocaine it was
the Mexicans in terms of cannabis
starting in I think Utah with the
Mormons and then spreading across the
United States so you know these sorts of
things still happen where this people
say we're losing our jobs they blame
people of color and these sorts of
situations develop so we have to try and
All Rise Above these sorts of things and
try to educate people reason if I can
make an observation before we get to
another question a lot of people say
well what's going to happen what's going
to happen and well let's look at another
simple example in Vancouver so history
repeats itself uh the pentos nightclub
and the Commodore Ballroom got their
licenses 1969 and 1971 respectively so
what was happening during the 40s the
50s the 60s and then you know early 70s
well they remained open and uh they you
know I think really the key is is if you
survive and stay open you will in 20 30
years get a history um commemoration CLA
from theal government so I think really
just think of the words of Fel
Castro condemn me it's not important
history will absolve me and I think
that's what's going to happen in this
market so I think we have time
for might about it but I'm sure they'd
love to talk to you the hallway I got a
a question here I wanted to ask you
people keep telling us oh it's going to
be legal in the spring you're just
impatient once it's legalized in the
spring I don't feel it's going to be
legal in the spring and and I would
expect people to still be charged for
possession all through
2017 I'm curious as to what you feel
about the timeline for the federal and
provincial and Municipal legalization if
I if you think I'm right there will
still be possession arrest and
enforcement all of next year and what
what you should anticipate as the
timeline over the next year or two and
when we're actually going to be able to
buy some kind of government approved
cannabis with Justin Trudeau's stamp on
it in a store at some point or going to
have
so so I think we may have different
views on this I I uh gave my view
earlier today in an earlier panel I'll
just repeat that briefly and then I'll
I'll flip it over to these other
gentlemen to sort of look into their
murky crystal balls but you know the
timeline that we know is that next month
the task force going to make its
recommendation to Bill Blair Bill Blair
will then regurgitate and and that up to
uh his bosses Ministers of Justice
health and Public Safety uh with his own
commentary added into it uh they they've
told us that that's the timeline the
government has promised to introduce
legislation in the spring of 2017 spring
session of parliament lasted about mid
June
2017 uh I would expect if legislation is
introduced at first reading in the
spring 2017 it we don't get through
third reading uh in that spring session
so I expect the whole thing's over till
the fall session of 2017 I expect there
will be extensive committee hearings uh
because despite the fact that the
government has said it's not about
whether we're going to do it it's how
we're going to do it they they know the
eyes of the world are abond Canada
they've said that repeatedly everybody's
going to want to have their piece of the
action and piece of the publicity in
Ottawa so you know I think that that
could drag on through the remainder of
2017 then the bill goes to the um senate
for review they do committee hearings
they look at it some more and then it
goes back to the house and if it goes
back change the house has to start of
then either adopt those changes or try
to override them you know my own guess
is that we we we don't have legislative
change until early 2018 that legislative
change is also going to require each
province and territory in this country
to participate and to have a
distribution plan ready because the feds
have signal they're going to retain
jurisdiction over manufacturing
production the provinces are going to
deal and territories are going to deal
with uh the distribution piece so you
know I I think we're a long ways out
from buying legal cannabis in a store uh
whatever that store might look like uh
and and you're right I mean the tragedy
of this all is that people continue to
be arrested for violating these laws and
I got to tell you it it doesn't have to
be that way the the public prosecution
service of Canada before filing charges
against individuals in British Columbia
have to determine whether filing those
charges is in the public interest and
whether there's a substantial likelihood
of conviction not discharge conviction
if you file the charges you could stop
Prosecuting simple possession offenses
in this country as a matter of policy
and prosecutorial discretion today and
the reason it hasn't happened is because
the political pressure has not yet been
applied sufficient to make them liberals
believe that this is a vote loser in the
next election and they're they're
probably right about that um at the
current calculation but I you know I
think pressure will continue to build
because the Jud you know judges as Johns
recounted to you when you put in front
of a judge the idea that you got to
sentence somebody for simple possession
or even for growing or trafficking
cannabis when when we're making it legal
you know the judges are scratching their
heads and saying what are we doing here
uh and and at some point it may get
taken out of the hands of the government
uh you know by the courts and there's
there's a I don't disagree with KK in
terms of the timeline I think you know
the spring they're supposed to introduce
leg legislation and we'll see what
happens we have a similar problem to the
us where the US you can have a
government that takes a position but you
got a congress that's stacked with still
Republicans here we have a senate that
still has more conservatives so you know
that needs to be fixed in order to make
sure everything goes through my
experience with u you know as I say when
I started people busted for very small
amounts were're getting 30 days in jail
and things like that and throughout the
70s and 80s and so on I've seen that
reduce and reduce and reduce and to you
know it used to be a $100 fine was veryy
common and then discharges I do not get
people charged with possession anymore I
haven't had a possession case for ages
other than sometimes a large amount that
in the past they would always charge
possession with the purpose of traffic
now is a simple possession so I think
and I'm talking abord police who aren't
known for necessarily them being very
Progressive in in this at least in the
past uh and and even RCMP who are who
are known to be or less were thought to
be less Progressive although I I see
them coming around quite a bit as well
so that's pretty key but we still are
always going to run into that problem of
they'll use the smell in order to get
into your car to find out what else
you've got or to arrest you simply to
then you know hassle you a bit before
they then drop the charge and again my
concern is is that you're in a database
the minute that happens you're in the
database and there's some further
information that can Prejudice you in
the future so you know hopefully uh we
will at least see a big movement in in
the simple possession area uh but what
really needs to be addressed is as as
Kirk said the the distribution and so on
you need to remember that at the moment
it's the federal government has the
Constitutional power under its criminal
law power and control drugs and
Substances Act is a criminal law statute
okay and so if they take it out of the
control drugs and Substances Act out of
the schedule then they're no longer
using the criminal law power so what is
the power it's health and that's a
divided field between the provinces and
the federal government as Kirk said uh
so you need the provinces to get
involved as well and they've been not
jumping in at all I in uh in Seattle
Washington the district attorney there
made it a part of his uh platform when
he ran that he was not going to
prosecute simple marijuana possession
cases he told the cops at and arrest
droughts this is before the initiative
passed to
legalize and then uh to the other point
about the two-part Point that's what
Oregon did they legalized possession
first and then came up with regulations
in order to get the ball rolling I think
we have time for two more
I know you had your hand up the got to
be quick I think it's 3:30 so long we
got to make way for Ed Rosen here
folks I've got a question for the panel
um the M individuals were allowed to
grow for themselves friends and family
the mmpr allowed these joggernauts to
grow for multiple patients um thanks to
two Smiths and one two saw the uh the
the derivatives um were allowed to be
made by these joggernauts it seems that
they are limited to 3% potency which
seems like a form of insanity to me
under the mm or sorry the
acmpr um I'm told that individuals that
used to be mm holders are now allowed to
make derivatives the legislation still
states that you're allowed to collect
four licenses to one property for
growing I've been told that you're
allowed to collect the outdoor storage
facility under multiple licenses and
perhaps that would be a good place for
individuals to do extractions is there
limit on how many licenses can be in one
storage facility and is there a limit on
the percentage value of the extraction
made in those facilities yeah so uh in
terms of uh patient uh making
extractions or derivatives uh they don't
have any pocy limits in place uh you're
not subject to the restrictions that the
LIC producers are what you are
restricted to is that you're unable to
make any extractions using the acmpr
defines as organic solvents organic
solvents is then defined as butane
couple other chemicals and and the
katchall is basically anything that can
blow up now you
know let's be clear I think Smith
overrides that restriction I think that
derivative makers that are doing it
safely have very good defenses under the
charter that that restriction supposed
in the acmv is unconstitutional on its
face uh I I've had I've got a couple of
cases currently of Prett big extract
facilities uh that the Crown's making me
off as you can't refuse on um you know I
don't think they want to litigate that
issue in the medical Arena right now so
but but the answer to the question of
extracting is no organic solvents uh
otherwise no potency limits you cannot
act your storage location under the
acmpr for a production license has to
either be at the production site or at
your ordinary place of residence yeah so
production site is artificially limited
to four because you can only have four
licenses at production site I suppose if
you had like 20 people all living
together in the same house there's no
restriction that that those 20 people
could have their storage site at that
one location I
mean you know but but then doing
extraction there uh you know the
question would be is the extraction is
the derivative making part of production
or is it part of possession right and
that's not defined by the acmpr so the
locus of your derivative making hasn't
been mandated so you know I suppose
theoretically you could aggregate a
whole ton of people living Under One
Roof and tons of storage there and that
would give you protection for a great
deal of cannabis to be stored there to
process um but you know creative
compliance is sort of my manager right
the government makes rules lots of them
are arbitrary and
creatively comply with them you know as
long as you're not breaking the rules
you're not engaged in unlawful conduct
and I think that you know we're creative
people so we can do it but remember this
is
politics and so every time you have an
explosion and a fire and somebody gets
hurt it sets back the cause okay every
time you have people stinking out the
neighborhood because they're not
controlling the smell of their
production you set back the cause I get
constant complaints from inspectors at
various
municipalities Conroy there's a grow
there and they're stinking out the
neighborhood and we got all the
neighbors complaining so I have to get
somebody in there to teach them how to
do it without stinking out the
neighborhood we want the neighborhoods
on our side come the spring we don't
want them against
us give it up one time
than
youw thank you we saw you on stage last
night you
look wow wow wow you know that's that's
pretty much the bang for the buck right
there you know if you want to know
what's going on uh in Canada these guys
you three gentlemen if I could ask you
just to go outside because you will be
mobbed at this current time so
appreciate it thank you so much uh thank
you guys so much yo Make Some Noise if
you're having a good time
y'all this has just been Splendid you're
wonderful we have an amazing special
guest for you right now he is he is the