[Music]
so here we go bubble man and John B we
are in the truck we have everything from
Bubble Nows plants hash pounds of weed
fresh frozen fresh frozen ready to run
Bubble Bags bubble boxes dry sip screens
medtainers basically we're going up to
Whistler and we're going to film our our
puff Wednesdays up in Whistler we
thought what let's go make some hash on
the side of the mountain so we're going
to like fresh frozen yeah dude I'm a
Whistler and it's and it's dumping up
there right now oh man we've talked
about this for so long so this is what
we're doing this is what we're doing
Sleds on the back of the truck just in
case we might go do a Backcountry
Adventure we'll keep you guys posted
we'll keep you guys posted 2014 is
looking awesome yeah dude right on see
you guys soon see we're off to
whis all right here we are entering the
C2
sky highway this is the road that will
take us up to Whistler we'll keep giv
all right driving on the SE to sky
highway personally I'm not allowed to
consume cannabis while I'm
driving but John's not driving is he no
John's not driving and God we've been on
the road for what like 3 minutes now I
would say two yeah so it's just
obviously we've gone 2 minutes longer
than we need to and and and right now
honestly it's like [ __ ] feeling PUK not
doing that all lifting all that heavy
ice that we put in the car in yeah
you've been working hard for sure John
I'm definitely just going to do
this doing some uh full melt here on Med
Haze full melt hay medy Haze car rip
oh
yeah
beautiful how's that what a beautiful
smells really nice oh we've got the
Pacific Ocean just on our left for those
of you that have driven up to Whistler
before you may know the highway the SE
to sky highway the number
99 got about a $900 million overhaul on
this highway when the Olympics came here
in
2010 and basically made it so only a
small section of the highway is single
Lane like what we're finding right here
yeah he was going pretty good wasn't he
that GoPro is really
cool Johnny's up for ripo number
two we're going to try and do 99 rips on
the way up to the uh Whistler here on
the 99
highway I'll be the designated driver
happy to do
it this is a new section of the SE to
sky highway actually right up here and
you can see how they've dynamited
through this mountain to extend the
highway into a four lane this is cool
I've never haven't been up here in yeah
Shannon archers Memorial is just on the
other side where that young girl died in
the car accident she's got a little
Memorial where the highway used to
be across the way we have Anvil island
in the clouds there kind of looks like
an anvil and to the left of that further
back we have
gambir the defense Islands out front
there and Bone Island back back behind
us so to see this oh we saw it all right
just driving through by Shannon Falls oh
that's a
nice the chief barely picking out let's
see if we can see the Falls yes we can
oh yeah there it is Gondola just for
tourists
pretty
fun that's really
fun all right driving through
Squamish and it's a
PMW squ Venture
Center all right coming up here if you
look to the right you'll see white heads
in the trees those are bald
eagles and there's usually quite a few
of them I can see two right there right
by the river nice look out yeah just
hanging out all right we've got into a
little snow just a little
bit right next to the chamus
creek this
River
yeah I'd like to be talking to some of
these places but it seems like I'm still
down the road a little
bit you know what I mean it's a little
early for for my where I come in yet I
wish it wasn't
but hey everyone welcome to Bubble man's
world I'm here with John B welcome to
Whistler the basically 5 minutes out
function Junction we're going to go whip
up a batch of some beautiful bubble has
up on the mountain we're going to do
some dry sifting joh brought some
beautiful colas fresh off the plant
we'll see you in
Whistler coming into chica Miss Crossing
function
Junction this is Creek Side this is old
Whistler you know there's still some
newer condos over by the gondola which
is right over there yeah see the
mountain that's what I remember right
there this
place
wow does it ever look like it's uh
busy all right heading over to the
room what have we here the
tools
sweet so this is where we're going to be
spending the next 24 or so hours here at
the hotel Interwest pretty nice little
facility little
one-bedroom nice little one-bedroom
suite at the
table we'll have the denail set up on
that ASAP our material sitting out
here A Mountain View even though it's
kind of being covered right now by the
fog and and of course we have this and
of course we have this ice we know what
that's for ice we know what that is for
and and the good ice oh yeah nice ice
nice ice
excellent all
right I guess uh it's time to make some
plans shall we set up the mother ship
and get the Dil going I think we should
do that all right we'll be right
back welcome to Bubble man's world here
we are John B Mark R the bubble man
hanging out with you in Whistler we're
up in Whistler we just got here it's a
beautiful day this this you can kind of
see the the runs are coming out now all
the Mist is lifting oh yeah on both
sides just beautiful and we thought we
would do a little puff Wednesdays I
think it's a great thing you know why
not we've got fresh frozen buds that
John has cut down just a couple of days
ago they've been frozen since he cut
them down what uh what strains oh we're
doing the My Little Pony My Little Pony
what a funny name I know we're going to
get a lot of great comments on yoube
YouTube for this but John has a string
called the My Little Pony it is very
unique in its flavor and its and its
taste and when you close your eyes
someone say it smells like My Little
Pony and hence that's how the name came
about that is kind of how the name came
about was that not in uh in Toronto in
main or was that even pre it was pre-
Toronto and then I laughed with it in
Toronto and it stuck everybody just
loved it so here we go yeah it's funny
you know it's fun so of course we
brought the Dil Mothership combo we got
the puking bee
um quartz Bowl I hope I pronounced that
right I don't know how to pronounce that
guy's name cooking bee beagle the this
is my little master of quarts oh you got
some My Little Pony fresh frozen this is
what I made on Christmas Day actually
maybe we'll do a video upload someday oh
excellent film it oh that looks nice
I've got my macro lens so I'll be able
to shoot this and and put it into the
video so you can kind of see what we're
what we're hitting I'm about to drop
this fresh frozen onto the quartz nail
that's going at 7 50° f it is a little
bit cold outside so we'll see how the
Dil
performs TR know how bubbly that is and
you can hear it
just such a nice Mothership of course
wow that is a lovely
taste
[Music]
smooth W very
nice excellent so yeah it's exciting to
be up in Whistler you know I've been
coming up here since 1991 but it's
something I've never actually
shared on my channels or with my
followers this year you probably heard
me talk a few times how I want to make
it out to the glacier I want to do a
batch of bubble uh with my crew my back
country crew sledding access only get up
to the pton ice caps into the one of the
ice caves and do a nice little batch of
uh fresh frozen or even some dry sifting
as well while also showing you the
adventures that we go through just to
get to these areas and then of course
you know to show you some of the footage
of the Epic riding that goes on as well
from ski flying to uh you know cliff
jumping and features off of off of Epic
Back Country Cliffs and rocks and and
and whatnot so definitely looking
forward to to doing all that I'm I'm
just really excited to be up in Whistler
man this is the first time we've been up
here filming you know it makes me want
to hit another Bowl would you like to
try some of them Med haes fresh frozen I
will not say no you will not say no John
is the fresh frozen King well you showed
me something that just utterly totally
helps me so much for with all my
conditions and one thing I've realized
is actually the fresh frozen is what
helps me the most for sure well you know
what it's not just the showing John uh
it's your humility in the way you accept
being shown and that that I'll tell you
guys something it goes a long way to
have someone tell you something show you
something and for you to listen to them
to a point where you benefit from it and
I'll tell you John from the get-go from
the dry sift cleaning 11 months ago and
then to the fresh frozen wet washing
yeah you hey that's a nice hit by the
way thank you that's a Golden Delicious
that's the golden ticket right there
that's like 5 just
beautiful not even not the
[Music]
just I didn't know how much he's going
to appreciate that cuz that's by far
that was day
84 and of course Stu feeding on day 35
so once again your 40-day PL flush oh my
gosh that is divine it that back end
tastes but the beginning flavor of the
hazy cooky
it's definitely
um wow I can't believe how um how
flavorful that was is that amazing yeah
it really is it tasted almost like like
fresh
material scooper SC got to give it up to
Skillet tool oh yeah I love my gold
Skillet
tool I'm hang on to this CU I God is
that beautiful the color of that is
absolutely I mean that's just
it's it's the infamous white lady and of
course what he's done is he's gotten I'd
say 90% of it into pure perfect powder
and then the tiny little chunks that
aren't pure perfect
powder they have a different color
they're a little more caramelly a little
deeper and you can tell that they have
the tiniest bit of moisture in them the
the the the dry parts are bone
dry but the little other part and I'll
show you that while I'm talking about it
you'll see these photos appear and um
yeah this one piece in particular really
nice little kind of almost a little hot
dog yeah I kind of left that in there
for a reason I keep watching and looking
at it and yeah it's nice we'll take a
photo of that uh and did you this is
microp PL definitely microp plane and of
course Dy it on cardboard great well I'm
looking forward to photographing it
there's been rumors of people discussing
um oh people always assume that certain
things damage Tricom heads squeezing
them um grinding them um all these sort
of variations of things that could
potentially damage a tricol the macro
camera lens really shows what's going on
so I like the idea I'm going to
photograph all John's microplaned bubble
we'll get in really close and we'll see
if we can see any heads that have been
you know damaged or or broken du from
the color which it's pretty much white I
would guess that there's no damage
because if you breach those heads in any
way and you let oxygen in uh the color
turns really fast
yeah faster than say leaving it out to
be exposed to oxygen and or uh just
light you know what I mean those two
things exposing it to those two things
will darken it as well over time but if
you breach the head and let oxygen
actually get and touch those oils they
go red faster or
darker definitely um great things to we
learn yeah I can't believe how beautiful
it is there's I can just see the peak to
Peak Gondola going from Whistler to
Black ho home um would you like to hit
the med A's with My Little Pony um what
would you like them you they were both
so nice I'll go back to My Little Pony
would you like the 70 90 or 120 let's go
73 73 yeah let's go 73 one of my you
like the
sir I tell you too if any of you guys uh
are coming out to Whistler and you ride
fairly well and you want to link up um
I'm definitely in a position where I'm
always looking for good people to ride
with always looking for people to link
up with definitely I'm not the guy to
find you um your
smoke so please don't ask but I am the
guy that'll take you around the mountain
and show you amazing places and maybe
you
know have a have a good afternoon
together so I'll put that out there and
uh I'll put this in there that yes yeah
it's always nice meeting new peeps new
peeps new things and and Andy this is
kind of cool we got this uh new Med
tannas that were coming up with these uh
oh yes yes kind of some new things going
on in our world and how did they do that
now what is it it's just a kind of a
it's just we just playing we're just
playing people ask for different things
and so there's like a couple prototypes
trying to get some opinions on it and
stuff like that so having fun you know
new colors new
things bubble B lights something else
new that's coming
in yeah they've been doing
well I mean people have been waiting for
them for them for years people had been
waiting for those for years yes so now
they have them and that's
good I think I could let this dry out a
little bit quicker but I was eager to uh
smoke
it tastes nice it's a very um subtle
thing to learn as a hash SM smoker the
difference between a cured hash and and
a properly dried and cured hash as
opposed to wet hash I mean really wet
hash is pretty easy for most people to
decipher depending on how they're
smoking it as well cuz it's one thing to
use a beine it's another to drop
something into a onto a d nail well this
has changed everything it definitely has
this is this is a whole new level now
yeah these electric nails are game
changers for sure I'm really uh for for
f Mill bubble is just really is the only
way I don't even have lighters anymore I
haven't lit well we we looked for one
this afternoon we couldn't find a
lighter like I've been hit the Dil since
my first Dil arrived I basically have
not even at the Cannabis Cup this year I
smoked very few BTS mostly everything
was through the denail through the
electric nail thank you
denail and thank you Mothership what a
beautiful combination
just love it all thank you w
absolutely yeah it's like you packed one
that was fairly
big I like
that why not got three out of that one
oh it's still burning smoking
off it is still burning
yes
well I think we have to um go make some
plans don't we yeah we're going to go
make some plans we're going to figure
out where we're going to go next I kind
of want to take you guys up the mountain
show you guys around a little bit I'm
not sure how much I'm going to be able
to do that I of course have a seasons
pass and have a snowboard but I'm
hanging out with John for the day and
he's not going to be going snowboarding
and whatnot so we'll probably if
anything make it up to one of the free
parking lots of on black home at base 2
you know drive around somewhere and find
uh find a little place that we can just
walk out of the parking lot onto the
mountain give you a little visual of
what's going on up there I even get a
lift pass and jump on the ground like we
yeah yeah we could potentially do that
too get get you a lift pass either way
if we do go up there we'll bring the
camera with us and we'll show you what's
going on up there and most importantly I
hope to be making some bubble if not
today we're going we do it tomorrow
morning uh potentially right here on the
on the deck so with the beautiful view
with the beautiful view so why don't we
finish off with showing you that view
and we'll talk to you guys real
soon hey good morning guys buban and
John B here just waking up here in
Whistler we raged it pretty good last
night we um ate pizza and we puffed hard
yeah ate pizza and puffed hard had some
friends over uh Pro photographer Mike
calr was here our friend Johnny they
brought a couple of friends I saw my
friend Ari from Texa Island that I
haven't seen in like a decade so that
was pretty incredible and uh we turned
them all on
to the
denail so this morning John and I are
trying to figure out where we going to
make bubble with you guys we got this
beautiful fresh Frozen nugget that John
cut down just beautiful
plants um we've got our bags and our
buckets we've even got a bubble now if
we have power but we're kind of trying
to give you something a little bit more
than just a hotel session so we're
thinking we're going to go out on the
mountain somewhere either near the
chamus river or up on Whistler uh
Creekside we're not sure exactly where
but we figured we'd do a couple of dabos
before
we before we
start
so a little dabble do you D do
you maybe we'll do the uh the little
GoPro
uh the GoPro dab cam go GoPro dab Camp I
like
that that's dabin fresh
Frozen not that shatter or butter we're
talking about we're talking about real
medicine here actually wouldn't say it's
all medicine let's just say clean
organic
medicine let me rephrase
that it's quite important you get your
canabo up in the morning to uh have a
better
day here we are oh it sounds like uh
coffee is ready in the
background coffee and Bong ribs no
coffee for me more of a tea kind of
guy
[Music]
beautiful this fresh frozen is
absolutely white it's
uh smells like candy I just can't
believe the nice smell on
this yeah the one thing you got to do is
[Music]
you don't want to be wasting that
goodness super stoked on hitting your
fresh
frozen
[Music]
was
it's a good rip in the
morning more sativa with the cush in it
so it's got the really Zing LIF but that
nice pushy taste in the back that I
really like it's an interesting flavor
definitely um a
[Music]
winner he just wants to smoke
okay let smoke it
[Music]
then one of those never ending
hits the taste on this I cannot even
describe it fru overtones
with just things I never
taste stick the
throat it reminded me of one of my
viewers just now when I looked at your
face one of my viewers said I love how
the grower is so
proud John is proud well I do enjoy
growing good medicine and I enjoy
smoking good medicine and I enjoy people
who grow good medicine I enjoy teaching
people how to go good medicine
absolutely like you enjoy teaching
people how to make great medicine
from what they
grow hence that's why I have this
marvelous fresh frozen
here little bit of education and uh we
got uh full melt dry sift and uh Ste it
up and not to
um fresh frozen which is
uh wow all right definitely uh turn the
music down a little bit so it can be
heard I'm not sure how loud that was in
the background but I figured I'd turn it
down a little
bit
yeah pretty excited to make bubble up
here in Whistler I've made it in a house
before a good friend of mine used to
well he might still have the house he
used to just back in the day when herb
was quite expensive he would buy half
lbs of um Renee and just run it right in
the bags that was pretty expensive back
then close to 1,500 for a half PB So
today we're going to do it with the
fresh froze and what is it that you cut
down again I know we've mentioned it's
the My Little Pony My Little Pony so
tell them a little bit about My Little
Pony like what are the strains that were
used to create My Little Pony My Little
Pony was um some genetics that that was
um grandfather me through uh a friend of
mine and uh he gave me some nice Elite
beans and um I took those to a prair
medicinal cup of 2012 and W third place
for Baba km so he took he gave you seeds
that you cracked and it was Baba km yes
okay and then so perfect so we then you
took that Bubba km and we hit I hit it
with a a skunk Haze skunk Haze skunk hay
nice and that skunk ha came from um
unknown um Mark
9293 sh and I have a lot of different
beans over the years I've been um
playing and pumping seeds since the mid
80s so um it's really unknown sh it's it
didn't even say skunk it said well I can
tell what it was growing right away
remember the beans I the mid it was just
that time year and they went into a bag
and actually have video of me popping
these beans and them taped the inside of
my box Barney this diesel skunk okay so
it came from Barney I don't know no
there's this other stuff I had I had po
so many different seeds and this one you
can see the bag and it's right it's just
a little bag it says sh h n black 92
nice I love to find the history of of
things so um
while smoking it for the first time the
gentleman there is where I got the beans
from were laughing and like it smells
like My Little Pony and we joked about
it and there's three of us in the room
and when we went to Ty we uh well I
actually started saying that to people
like well we called it My Little Pony
and people love the name and they close
their eyes and smell it like yeah it
smells like my it's such a fruity tasty
it definitely is it's um we're talking
about it where is where is it right
right here we should maybe smoke some I
think we should I was just about to load
up a dab of the OG but um here we go
right on top right want take a little
this what I made on Christmas Day
actually the
dab going to get a half H there's
definitely some smoke in there for him
so that's
uh always pay attention to your tool you
never know what you're leaving behind
right it's all good
medicine
just enough to heat this up and give it
a
wipe all right so that's
clean that's um also fine with the real
real mouy stuff especially dry sift if
you've got your hit on the pan on the
little scooper and you hold it above the
denail for too long the resin melts
almost immediately onto the spoon and
now you've actually got to like press it
against the center piece rather than
drop it I prefer dropping
it if I can you know oh yeah no the
dropping that's why I like to roll it up
a little bit too
sometimes so that was um Christmas Eve I
made my cut myself down a Christmas
present and I put this into the
freezer and uh did a run of uh My Little
Pony cush for Christmas
and because I Haven had a chance to see
Mark over the holidays I went up almost
smoking it all so we're going to make
another batch that way we can really
puff it down hard because there's not
that much left kind felt bad hey it's
great I'm smoking it right
now
excellent
tasty oh yeah it's good to be in
Whistler we're going to try and find a
good place today I'm not sure where it's
going be we're going to find this
amazing place today and you guys are
going to love it it's going to be really
cool yeah I suspect so as
well this will be the first of many as
long as I can procure um
material the next batch we'll do will be
up in Whistler somewhere on the back
country we'll build a little
eagloo and we'll do everything up there
and then after that we'll go to Pon ice
caps excellent well I see John and I are
going to finish our breakfast rips here
and uh we'll get back to you really soon
with uh some bubble
making all right little bit rainy we're
going to go look for a water source my
we're not going to make it here hey John
nah N I got it all packed up here it's
all light up ready to go so we're out of
here we're out of here all right got all
our [ __ ] packed
up
just
uh grab uh grab the Marlin Asher don't
forget the
CV I got
[Applause]
[Music]
it
all
right we are
Udi what happened
there I just spilled the
cooler it was the first thing I did when
we came in like and this Falls open the
LD opens all right okay let's move on
here we are out of here quick breakfast
quick breakfast Southside Diner outside
down let's do
thiso good for
three looks like you got
room want peti
John good that's a
I'm having to
scramble filming our little session here
that we've uh stopped in at uh with
Phil and uh it's pre we haven't gone to
make the bubble yet we're thinking of
going up the Camus we just went up
kadenwood it was snowing at about 1,000
ft and uh yeah we figured we'd stop and
have a quick session
here hit the
denail oh yeah I should introduce uh
Devon Devon's a friend of mine that I do
a lot of snowboarding with and back
country sledding with and then Phil
who's kind of out of camera he can lean
in another local
Whistler uh ganja fish andado canabo
intake
lover and of course John B and Oreo Oreo
Oreo's in the video today say we can get
him video to Spotlight all right so yeah
here perfect you know what it is I know
what it is it's my little p
that's how you that's that's flirting
that's what you call
that check my nuts
out [ __ ] ra Che them
no so it's ring right now in
Whistler down in the valley
anyway we're not sure where we're going
to make this
bubble I have a feeling it's going to be
cheze Miss
though which is for for you that don't
know that's a function Junction
function it's
function
Instagram Pony yeah yeah you get what
every else Pony one sec one sec doing
that just I caught that on
my carb cap there we
go the carb cap
AI couple of quick rips before we go do
a little adventuring I'm going to drive
up the Camus River and find a nice spot
where the snow is falling where the
rains turn to snow freezing
level and uh hopefully we'll be able to
get a quick batch done up there I think
with four of us we should be able to you
know have a couple of guys pull two bags
each you could pull two bags he can pull
two bags he could pull two bags I can
pull a bag and we'll just each literally
have enough spoons and enough pressing
screens that the bubble can I've never
actually done a batch where you could
almost pull all the bubble out at once
rather than one guy pulling a bag at a
time I've never thought seven guys each
we each just pull the bag right away
scoop it's like out in one shot it would
be uh it's kind of like an assembly
preserving those flavor noids preserving
the turs exactly keeping them Less in
the water for those water talking about
yep a little
more
there you want to give a carve
cap well it's taken a couple of days to
try and make this bubble but I think
we're going to get it done I cut it down
New Year's Eve New Year's Eve New Year's
Eve is one this came down I was going to
make fresh Bubble New Year's Day wow but
um I kind of wanted to make it with you
so here we are we're stoked all right
now we'll move
on why always put back on on oh yeah
what what do you mean oh no when that
got moved over just explaining to the
people you always put your lid back
always put so par just right there you
put your
back you got to smell this that's dude
that's lovely oh yeah
[ __ ] F dude that's smells like candy
[ __ ] rights it does I'm going to take
the first rip you know what look at that
I guess I it looks way bigger than it is
cuz it's so that's she that's what
she's this is a new strin that
sick it' be nice to watch this melt but
that it smells
crazy oh what you look hang
there so the best thing about the medy
haze is that in the beginning giv you
that zing and the flavor in the end is
just so like wow it's well we're trying
to name the flavor
and it's it's it's like a I would say
more like a like a a fruit Lo but there
is that small Haze on the it is it is a
little bring your tongue a little bit
it's kind of there you can kind of tell
it's
there as you were saying last night
there's a little bit of little bit of
that Haze that's actually present
there [ __ ]
lovely lovely
like yeah the salivation factor is kind
of imminent the 120 is I always say is
the most flavorful it's the most more
poent oh my goodness is that ever just
the most candyrific and then smells like
a fresh nug that's the closer to smell
the fresh the fresh but itself Oreo
wants to smell it yep because it's just
one of those gulp
ready just because his valuable heads
just on the lid that's
why it's definitely a reasonable request
John to keep the lid on your full melt
hash particularly when people are
looking at it put the lid back on it
that way when you knock it over a couple
minutes later when you're too
high it's just a mild second of
uncomfortableness instead of oh my God I
just dropped oh my God three months
worth the work and everything that I've
been doing for the last three months all
over the floor and because it's so
sticky it's now full of fibers and
you're just G to do what with it well
maybe rewash it maybe maybe throw it
back into a bag try to get that out not
going to work I'd probably go tweezers
tweezers with this amount I'd probably
get a couple of tools one like this one
like tweezer and my little you know eye
Loop thing and it's not like it's a
pound of it that you wouldn't be able to
do but was that hitting you Phil
steamroll it it's really tasty it's
beautiful man dude we have to make My
Little Pony bubble hash today up on the
chap Miss wow it's funny how this name
is
actually that this will be step one of
getting into making bu Whistler next
we'll do it on the mountain I like the
idea of with a group barbecue you know
people
doing a little fire whatever exactly
yeah you know it's getting dark out so
we can put a nice bright light in the
eago and make it Glow epic I like it you
know I like it come on yeah and I think
the really cool cool way to get it done
would be that the whole reason to do it
would be for that you know if everyone
was on side okay where are we going to
do it we've got a couple of good spots
that we can go and build you know good
people
that'll help out best even smell smells
great smells like freaking candy yeah
man it's awesome
always a good time to be had and
Whistler oh that smells just
lovely that's cuz of this D now the way
it just releases out it's so tasty the
perfect
temperature every time you put something
on this thing it's just like where's
that where's your that o or whatever
that purple that you have those so tasty
last thing um my
has oh yeah I like the nice
CES oh actually you know what I get some
nice nice stuff in here
too so there's that tasty from last
night I was tasty but then
this this one right here Poss this one
this
one we did one Med did one My Little
Pony right one
each oh my we got to go make some hash
guys
goodness
all this we're smoking it all we smoking
it we're talking to these guys over
here got the boxes we got the boxes
we've got the pressing
screens so this is watermelon is that
the Mellie that's we're going to stay
for one more yeah that stuff is just
that's candy man that smells like all
right candy we have Cy man yeah this is
how I roll everyone wants to do I'm like
in the treasure box man you like that oh
yeah full flavors everything's packed up
everyone's got something good in it he's
got aov piece of paper that one check
that that's that's the number
four the number four the number
four what's that now it's
a is that the one we gave buddy the P
it's just caked
man no that was a cream 398 oh it was a
pre98 pre98 yeah no that's that's
another speci so look at that I just
played with that a little bit wo that's
quite what um what screen is that oh
that'll be 90 M oh here before I put
this in my container I like to have it
back thank you sir thank you that looks
like [ __ ] candy dude like smoking
yeah yeah let's get rid of it yeah
exactly so here John if you want
to really
John you want the dab for that one
let's just make
it that was pretty tasty e yeah this
needs to be seen I'll have to take a
picture my camera doesn't self focus oh
that's [ __ ] let's see oh oh yeah
it's beautiful I think you have a qu
pound of that stick
somewhere your house remember I left
that qu pound at your house oh I think
it's down in the
truck I keep leaving weed line but
that's what I left line where it Mar CU
I forgot about it and that was about a
month and a half ago
we're going to we're going to do a video
dry sifting probably next puff wday that
that qu found we found some buds there
we go you know make some medic and some
real buds yeah get some nice macro
phot
[ __ ] nominees are the nominees are
right
now in there cuz I was just doing the
small HS in the whole time not those
other ones you were hitting huge rips
you were just packing giant I took one
that I thought was big and then you
loaded him one even bigger and dumped it
in the middle I know then you loaded him
another one I was like damn we're
puffing tough here but puff
tough it's always nice when the rips are
plenty i' say puffing top oh at this
point in time you probably noticed from
the start of the video that John and I
have shorter hair it is true that we got
all stoned and ended up going and
cutting our hair seemed like the good
thing to do with the time anyway now
that that's been said and how was
that tasty that's probably like oh I
don't know about a year old
now is that is that what you had at Ty
last year age to year I don't know you
had some really really nice
M take it around I'm coming around watch
the you know the best that never
came
753 we're talking about that temperature
yesterday wor about this I can kind of
just even bring it closer there's no
reason to even have it back
there there's really nothing too
breakable on there no and with the wood
box I feel even safer with it but I
haven't dropped it the rubber um feet
make it so it doesn't slide in any way
shape or form like it's like even like
when it's on glass or a surface I'd
actually have to lift it up I would
never even be able to pull it towards me
cuz it's just stuck
it's like that on my desk as
well how's
that oh do you even need ask that was
lovely that was
beautiful yourself one up I'll take the
last one what' you say I said load your
cell one up I'll take the last the last
hit we give you
that got a decent size
as it should be I'd say that your cure
is doing a pretty good job of that yeah
really um changes yeah it's much more um
seditary say sedative mhm much heavier
for sure I'm sure some of the TCS turn
to CBD CVN sorry
yeah pretty
medicinal yeah I like it it's definitely
uh it's enjoyable you know from smoking
you know fresh FR Frozen it was cut down
very recently and now we're even smoking
still quite recently within a month
anyway pretty and then to something
that's uh you know this stuff was also
um the material was dry and dried for
almost uh 6
months
wow thank
sir I love that extra one from behind
for you cuz I think that big first one
you got Rob somewhere along the lines so
we're going to do that last one I'm
feeling bad it's my
fault see that we were talking about
this y oh he wants the bonus round he's
like the car
out double snap cuz I was already in the
midst of getting the the next hit
ready thank
you yeah that's
so deep
different so completely different
yeah it's almost like one was a meal and
one was a dessert one lighter heavier
this one was a dessert it was so just
delicious and candy and like oh my God
it was exciting really this one was
definitely more
like serious a little more
serious got the sativ in it that's more
uplifting settle right in well the
watermelon is usually a racy High that's
what I was very this gives people
anxiety it does it does truly normally
but now it's a year old and it's acting
different yeah I like that and I I'm
cons convinced it has to do with
the the modulating effects of the T of
the tpes being affected by their
volatility the fact that they're
evaporating and
changing more so than the canabo
are I think you know from my own I think
we need to go extract some canabo some
fresh Bud that sit cool yeah let's go do
that let's do that all right okay guys
all right we're
[Music]
going