so check
Miss left it function
here this is where I used to go dirt
bike
riding Che W late for
Service East
Side I guess
so okay Mom here we go icy and little
slipper all right so we are in the trees
here on the ice and
snow
and slowly making our
way I
suppose looks like it's getting pretty
fresh
yep
let's start that over
again all right Phil is this where we're
going to do it yes sir all right we got
the fresh Frozen and the ice the Bubble
Bags over
there we're going to be mixing up a
batch here in the beautiful Czech Miss
River we're right next to it we just out
a Whistler we're about to whip up a
fresh batch of My Little Pony with John
B so stay
tuned
water all right we're going to go get
water over there yep going throw a
bainer in there and you grab yeah I go
that way dude is a
machine
just half full is even good so it's not
too heavy for
you beautiful cold chilly Glacier fed
water Phil's got it
I'll come grab one with you just going
to show them the creek real quick the
river
well here we go got that 25 bag all
right what's up guys welcome back to
Bubble man's world we're standing here
on the side of the chabus river the Phil
and John B we've got an eight bag
original uh bubble bag kit 5 gallon
about to go in the bucket Phil's just
collected a bunch of water from the
Checker Miss river which is extremely
cold I can assure you we brought up a
cooler of our own ice and John was kind
enough to cut My Little Pony down My
Little Pony yeah My Little Pony Here
Comes My Little Pony right now what's
upo all right so we're making bubble
Oreo's helping we're on this all right
so we're going to start with the 25
micron bag let's get it in
there you know what I'm not even going
to worry about flipping the bags over
the edge right now we'll leave them open
like that 25 45 they're always in a row
number white number white 45 yes once
again number white color 45 Micron
73 it's uh nice to have
both all
right my hook of Jack is so thick that
when I put my arms in the bucket I push
all the bags into the bucket so we'll
see what kind of success rate I actually
have doing this might have to do a
little outside bucket
trick nice I like that
little way to speed up putting your
bags into one another uh let's get the
orange one first let's do the order
proper you want your 120 you don't want
to mess that hash up 120 is a nice
grade we have the 160 bag the orange bag
specifically to secure the quality well
the
purity
of that bag the
120 all right green bag getting these
bags in here
nice know a lot of you are looking at me
like I'm an alien right now cuz you've
fiddled with your bubble bags for half
an hour at a time trying to get them all
fit inside one another
nicely oh this way is a little
quicker which is uh we're going to run
out of time again as always light so not
like we're in a huge rush but we wanted
to make sure we did some bubble making
today somewhere cool like we mentioned
we
would and we
go yes there we go and if you really
want to you can one by one them down do
your yeah you know you really want to
get
those all down and tight does secure
them
nicely it's never a terrible idea to
do we have all the tools here for doing
our extraction and stuff like that got
our spoon for uh mixing everything
up we got our trusty little
uh bag over
here in this bag you got some bigger
spoons yeah I figured we could all give
it a shot hand stirring it we're
obviously not going to be bubble knowing
up here in the electrical free zone yeah
electrical free
zone no Outlet we got our spoons pull in
our bags fingger
spoon just going to make sure the P by
here all right so I'm going to pour a
bucket of water in
here
that is some nice cold water Wow Let's
get some ice in there good ice great ice
let's use about half that bag actually
let's put some fresh frozen down
first here I'll hold that for you here
we
go hold that for a second got our whis
in there too but uh yeah show them
that
oh fresh frozen fresh frozen look at
that guys what do we have about 400 R
there done
roughly all right so normally I would uh
actually use a medtainer to grind all
this stuff up in here but because it's
so fresh we're just going to freeze it
directly in that ice yes then we going
put half in up we
go not going to break just a little
there you go yeah there half of it f
away a little early but that's okay ear
get all that niess off of there look
that actually let's go for this one oh
we brought the good
ice yes we
did there we go all right hold that go
the
rest
right it
nice
I think this one's pretty low to the
cost and this is how we wash our
butts yes we're getting it all nice and
filled up use a ton of ice
and a wooden spoon the old school method
I haven't done this way in quite a while
uh I usually use the bubble now I think
we use the paddle we did use the paddle
on we use the paddle now we don't want
to leave this in the water for too long
so I'm just trying to reconstitued get
the buds like really worked in there so
they're not all floating up to the top
we have tons of ice in so what we'll do
is we'll probably work with two or three
spoons for there approximately 10
minutes 5 to 10 minutes and uh we'll
eventually once it gets a little more
mixed we'll be able to do a nice mix and
once again the ice is doing two jobs
keeping the water cold and knocking off
the glandular Tricom heads from their
citate
stocks so you can smell it it's just
absolutely aromatherapy yeah
aromatherapy is Right nice and
strong let's see what we got here the
best part about this is actually
uh watching my resin being stirred in
ice and water and knowing that great
medicine that I'm going to get from the
end of the prodct is quite amazing which
of course you'll be seeing pictures with
Mar
do but uh we're getting that color
change in the ice already starting to
see the color change in the
water getting a little excit we got some
ice falling all over the flge as long as
it's not fun
oh the butts will be falling up and
ground get thrown back in at the blink
of an eye so if you blink you might miss
something
here all right we get a little bit more
melty so now there's more room to
actually
mix the material out we really want to
hear that ice bashing back and forth cuz
it's going to
be working those triom heads off there
and that River in the background is
actually giving us that incentive to
keep working wow is that it yeah let
bring it all
back what do you think H lovely lovely
out here on the side of a river and
Whistler perfect trying some lovely uh
give one of
those yeah so really beautiful Zone to
be making bubble in once again keep this
River coming
down I guess from Black
Tusk is that where
it's
tus really sweet it's a little bit
different from the bubble now of course
with the bubble now we get a better mix
I always noticed that with some of the
other runs that I've ran in the past and
stuff like that but uh I mean this is
old school method and uh this is the way
it all started right yeah absolutely the
old hand stirring you know first first
time I ever made it was with an actual
cake mixer and we used the use a little
cake mixer and then halfway down the way
we just sort of figured out you know
maybe gentler is better we took a
dashing it up too much and then we got
the spoon and I found the spoon was like
if you mixed it too little you didn't do
a good enough job if you mixed it too
hard you did too much of the job and it
was actually a little bit of a trick to
get the spoon mix perfect and that's
when I came out with the bubble now
where a friend of mine called me and
said you know to check these units out I
looked into them I used it a couple
times and I found that it basically made
like a perfect
hster batch every time a perfect hamster
batch every time but we got a perfect
hamster batch going on right here my
friend I'll take over whenever you're
ready
go best to uh just do like a minute or
two you know when you stay nice and
fresh of course the material after I
want to keep and I'm going to do the
second run with it we got a great amount
of ice in here I'll tell you that much
and me being at 0° right now it's almost
s in between guarantee everything's
staying nice and cold here which is
great we don't get that opportunity
to but actually you did uh up in uh
Delon there yeah I did a little bit of
this out in the snow this is obviously
more like my own backyard so it feels
pretty good I've I've played around in
here for 20 plus years on my dirt bike
you know just up the mountain on my
snowboard and sled just across these
streets so it's pretty neat to be off BL
whipping up a batch in the
playground are we still on record there
little flon in the top right cool good
to make sure good to make
sure it it's a little oh wow the smell
from na right now is just amazing I just
got the nicest whip give it a little
whip time
man himself he grew the resin he
isolated the heads and he loaded the
bowl nice
wow pass it over when you've got a good
amount I've got this R going minute or
two is good it's medicinal making your
own he who makes his own hash heals
himself
twice
take Dr that
res oh yeah that's the best part about
it love the golden color you got in
there okay I'm going to pass off the
steing stick here yeah
perfect why I like to use the bubble M
machine because my back and stuff like
that so it's actually a little bit more
convenient for me personally takes uh
takes the heavy work out of it because
this is really the only work that you're
doing is just mixing with the ice so if
you're having problems mixing get
yourself a bubble now and uh really
that's all the work that's needed in
making the fres fros than actually
growing the res but yeah and then of
course the drawing is really the tricky
part that's the part you want to watch
the videos over and over
again we talk about that a lot on the
water extraction and team dry shift on
Facebook yeah both of
those team dry shft obviously more for
Dr but uh drawing uh techniques water
extraction drawing techniques page on
Facebook we definitely talk a lot about
that so yeah water extractions and
drying techniques on Facebook is uh a
great place to learn and um also uh
understand your
medicine well I'm really glad we stopped
and did the batch oh yeah we we've been
trying to do this let me
see good
I'm going to have a seat here and
uh to stir the medicine up when you're
doing a hand stir generally I'll always
do it for more than 2 or 3 minutes you
know I'll do like 5 to 8 even 10 minutes
because you notice when we're hand
stirring the stirring happens for a bit
and we stop and pass the spoon that that
that time doesn't count the way it does
in a washing machine when it's
constantly mixing it back and forth
looks great break his butt up here sof
and wet fresh PES look at that just came
off the stock like a nice cooked salmon
just nice but you know taking that nice
nug and
smoker with the
smoker such a beautiful day here in
British
Columbia man the Roar of the river
behind us which is why why we're trying
to pretty much yell so the camera can
pick our voices
up gra It champion I go je bring up that
nice present I want to grab this bu
up yeah see
big it's already get broken up that's
what
we
everything oh we're getting
there oh yeah how see how sticky that is
it's
water water stick it's water we're
losing all the sticky ice
too well we definitely have a great cold
temperature I'll tell you that much oh
the ice is barely
melting right
yep give to make a hash on the boat here
boys yeah I love it I love making hash
everywhere chalk up one more cool spot
I've made hash on the side of a river
and
whistling very
cool for
me
epic and for us until March 31st all
three of us we're legally allowed to do
this we've got our licenses we're
federally exempt we don't go rubbing
into people spaces we go to quiet remote
places but we're allowed to isolate our
medicine here in uh British Columbia
thanks to Owen Smith uh in the uh vagina
versus Smith case of Edibles in Victoria
where they won the right to
use THC in any of its in any of its
forms concentrat or otherwise just like
the Constitution
says oh wild man here where is
it
all right we're going to pull these bags
real quick and see what we
got all right so we're back after mixing
John's still mixing for whatever reason
I'm not too sure it's my
red so we're going to pull this blue oh
my God does that smell good holy Christ
that's a lot of ice here
um I'm going to put it in my yeah know I
just figured to carry it over there just
in case we collect any
residence we're going to put this in
here just carry it over there dump your
bag now we've got you want to hold this
one we've got the 160 190
sorry it is very very small which is
okay looks pretty good throw this in
there wow look at the water in here yes
I'm going to let this sit here
first so I'm putting this in here cuz
I'm going to have to do a check and run
of this later all this nice and Frozen
and be
P how's
that all right so try to scoop that up
with your
spoon I'll be taking this cuz that was
just so darn
convenient I'm going to walk all like
this over
here no no no no no Jesus John holy
Moses that was the scariest thing he
just took the dirty Leaf covered bag and
I didn't touch it oh no you did okay wow
Moses hey try to walk try to stay on
either side of the camera there we go
all right that was a bit scary not going
to lie mild heart attack there thank God
it's only the 160 bag there's a lot of
leaf in it from the bag that you dropped
in it I don't think it oh well then what
what do you think oh yeah that's it's
full holy but it's just your 160 so it's
not the end of the world but wow you
want to pay attention when you're making
bubble I the F the first thing I said
funny enough was let's not look like
yahoos while we do this and he flips the
220 bag inside out and goes to dump it
into our Bubble Bag clean it
like yeah that would clean it all right
look at the resin it's covered in leaf
you want to do
that all right you you're putting it in
the sep pressing screen each fun let's
try to do this John hey John let's keep
you right now you're blocking the camera
let's keep you right here and we'll keep
Phil right here if say he you can pass
me that and I'll put exactly we'll kind
of do it that way and we'll keep the
camera open okay
so Phil's going to clean the 160 bag it
got a little bit of leaf in it which
won't be the end of the world I'm going
to pull the 120 and possibly uh pass it
over to John do we have another bucket
that has to be hung that b and that
bucket has to be taken out cuz we need
it ideally for future references we
don't want to put the bucket on the
dirty
ground because it may
contaminate the bag bag could you open
the box wait be to do with passing it
that here get it on the
spoon perfect pass it over to John I get
you to hang that one over by the blue
bag that's good yeah that's
great that one I'll take this
one oh yeah we're working together we've
never actually the three of us made
bubble together but it's not a super
overly complex process the important
part is that you rinse a bag in water
after you've made bubble with it and
then you hang it so each of these bags
will be cleaned in water there's a
little water right here we might be able
to pour some of that on there you might
be able to dip it right there in the
puddle this one yeah right on the top of
that puddle kind of give it a little dip
it's very important to clean the bags
immediately after using them we are in a
colder environment so we've got that
working in our favor there's not going
to be uh if it was really warm the
bubble would melt fast on the bags when
you took it out this 120 looks amazing
like unbelievable
beautifulness
wow look at that
you take that with your SP joh that's
ridiculous
beautiful very nice #
wiay # wi spray taint you heard it from
Phil you want to get the rest of them I
got that buddy this up there yeah hang
that up over there and then come back
and we'll do this
guy one of my funnest places I've ever
made bubble hands
down
there I'm excited about the
90 you should be it's slow
draining I just want to keep it open
there we
go
all right all right 90 coming up nice
and slow draining looks white like the
color of the
screen look at
that always nice to have a little bucket
like this to be able to flip your
product Inside Out
wow the color look at the color on
that nice color you want to pull that
off hean it up like this scoop
it he's real
nice some real nice fresh
hes we still
recording man I'll tell you bubble hash
making is inspiring it's so something
that you don't have to do inside a
shitty basement or or down in inside
your house anywhere you can get out and
actually do this in nature you know this
is something that's kind of nature
friendly I'm sure if people drove by
right now not that there's really many
places to drive by they might be
concerned as to what we were doing but
upon quick examination of the situation
and the safety of of it all
youin we're going to rinse this one in
the 73 just a little bit quick collect
any of those lost resin heads and then
we'll get them to rinse it in the we're
actually using Glacier puddle water just
here on the side of the uh on the side
of the mountain 73
time you know how to make that
water yes many many hundreds of
batches we'll do
that wow I love the size of these
buckets these these are real great
buckets I'm going to going to start
promoting these for sure these are
working great how's ice cream and
Whistler yeah perfect Cow's Ice Cream
little bit of foam no problem there we
go
there nice I'll tell you quality resin
cleans up like you can still get the
last little bits guaranteed and one
more perfect and it's already hard on
the two more bags we got the 45 and the
25 these are slow draining bags unless
you know the technique then they're
quick draining
bags always inspired to make some lovely
bubble oh s right as always the 45 has
painted the entire screen covered
it how's that for a
yield All Right Scoop It Up From The
Bottom yeah
[Music]
exactly lastes
here wow beautiful smelling raspber for
sir one more bag the 25 micron over
we're not going to be drying it here
we're going to take it freeze Our
Patties that we get and we'll be taking
them back uh either to John's or to
Phils and uh powderize them into boxes
and getting them ready for the dry the
desicant wicking out the hash uh the
moisture from the outside of the hash
allowing the glandular triome head to be
dry in which case now you can cure the
head let it shrivel up like a raisin and
let that wax membrane dehydrate all
right keep that in
there those go perfect that'll be a
quick rinse 25
micron and I'll tell you make a bubble
with three guys is nice and quick whip
this batch off and no time
flat quick technique with the 25 micron
I lift it up real quick lifting the
resin off the screen and allowing the
water to rush
through that uh makes for a much quicker
drain than what some of you guys have
done in the past I've heard some funny
stories of people telling me how long
their 25 micron bag took to dry or drain
yeah I heard 36 hours
yeah yeah that'll happen with quality
resin like
this 25 micron still a little bit of
water but with this technique of lifting
the bucket seems to suck the water out
as
well we
go got another screen to put that on
baby screen
here and that's pass me a
spoon just a stainless steel spoon and
once again if you could get
out John's having a hard time getting
that one today today we're wearing these
big jackets and if we turn our backs to
the camera the whole screen already
taken there's really no that right now
just working it it'll be fine I know
look at that that's a that's a dirty
little looking see your chest oh no
problem we'll get a spot for no I don't
want that contaminating all that Beau
this isn't contaminating and it won't
touch any of that if you have trust in
the guy that showed you how to do this
it's guide knows how to do it I'm going
to do it right now I'm just working the
resin over top of the screen and getting
it a little thi ther because right now
it's quite quite a bit of it as foam
it's not actual bubble it's taking up
more space than it needs
to so hands running into my perfect
7390 we won't have it it's not going to
happen we will not have it and we're
actually getting a natural rain spray
that's falling down on top of this a
little bit of snow got a little bit of
snow very nice very nice okay here we go
let's see so here here no no no no not
putting it anywhere over
there I have a second pressing screen
we're going to push down on top of this
stren therefore there will be zero
contamination see this is why we got to
listen to the guy all right no
contamination
spoon pass them over my jacket beautiful
passy water
into the
creek what a color that was awesome that
was beautiful I hope you guys saw
that look at all this ice we got going
on
here oh my God that's all I can smell I
can still like that's hope all I can
smell right now all right putting those
bags away I'm put them away that's what
we like to
see I'm just going to put my back to the
CER right
now and uh yeah we'll give you a quick
little peek of what we've been doing
here
we've got our bubbles here beautiful
colors oh my goodness we'll get back
with you when we're inside we're out of
the rain we' got all our gear put away
and uh yeah thanks for coming out and
watching us here in beautiful British
Columbia John once again hope good time
always Phill thanks for joining us man
ni have good
friends joh pleasure always a pleasure
all right we'll catch up with you guys
soon
[Music]