[Music]
hey how's it going guys bubble man here
driving up to Whistler with my good
buddy Dave who's on the camera and uh
yeah we're just heading up there it
finally dumped we got some uh oh we got
some traffic up ahead we better pay a
little bit of attention
[Music]
a
pap
[Music]
right heading in to see the
boys
sorry wrong
door all right
Dark As
[Music]
[ __ ] wake up it's time to
party wake
up all right right so we're at the party
Zone here Ryan's sleeping on the
couch and uh yeah we're going to get
this [ __ ] party
started can my buddy W uh clear the wax
off his board on your
deck can you
Ry waxing that board
yeah [ __ ] ton of wax in here
[Music]
can't really get to do
leverage they probably have a better way
of doing it
no buddy in right
yeah we missed it but here's the after
effects Deon just took the biggest hit
he ever took happy birthday Birthday to
Me birthday rippers happy birthday to me
happy birthday to him happy birthday n
HD puffing ballls
with Deon Begley Deon Begley
[Music]
awesome
sweet oh [ __ ] yeah oh what are we doing
today birthday man we going to oh shred
theard shred thear do we have a name for
birthday
man a queen
gaming part oh my god
dude oh here pick one ah sweet you're
hero [ __ ] awesome yeah dude one's
white one's the color of the green or
whatever and one's like a funky like
insane that's just some trippy [ __ ] huh
yeah like some trippy trippy 2.0's too
which means they come with two was it
slide out oh there you
go comes with uh the original one that
you have to fill in here and then it
comes with a 2.0 that cracks right in
half and you can put the you know the
material right in y gotta all right
there we go shout out to Trippy sticks
yeah trippy sticks for Life yeah [ __ ]
rights smoke all right
here we go
sweet well we got to film
this those are
sandwiches ours is a
burrito awesome
sweet thank you so much and no
sausage thank you
hey we could be twins yeah I know yeah
[Music]
a
pap
[Music]
oh
you're yeah right on guys welcome to the
Whistler Gondola this is the uh I don't
think it's actually the original
original Creek Side Gondola I think they
replaced it once since the 70s or twice
maybe but we're in the Creekside Gondola
and uh the gundula as some of us like to
call it locally here and we're going to
have a little puff come when puffing in
the gondola I always implore you that
it's might look cool to blow your head
out in your friend's face but just blow
it out the window and that way when you
know kids or moms or whoever wants to
get on they don't have to smell it and
you still get to enjoy the uh the
goodness of uh a small
rib so that's why I'm one more reason
not to smoke joints you smoke one joint
in here and it just reeks for the next
100 people which it seems funny but it
it might not be to certain people
[Music]
don't see me hit every day with a
lighter but when you do I'm shredding
Whistler
Mountain see at the
top Graham in the goddamn pipe it was
like a bubble like I know it was funny
so tell the story we saw a guy it was
his birthday
he's celebrating a birthday just like
mine today yes and so I gave him some
hash and yeah as as a generous man he is
and sure enough he puts the whole gram
in one hit where the the bubble
literally was like a
volcano right just waiting to with good
aroma awesome so awesome so this is
where we're
heading heading up the
monang this the creek
side down that way
where we just came
from looks like we got some snow out
there boys I for one him stoked to be
here on Whistler Mountain on my buddy's
birthday these guys always do it up good
I'm sure we'll be having a good day get
stoked or die trying get stoked or die
trying holy [ __ ] dude we
[Music]
what
what not a
[Music]
d
a
[Music]
pap w
pap
[Music]
a
w
[Music]
a
m
[Music]
a
he
[Music]
he hey w
he a
[Music]
w
he
[Music]
a
yeah
buddy I'm a happy
camper coming around your side Dave
[Music]
CH we know that of
heroin alcohol can produce long lasting
changes in the neurochemistry of the
brain this is
really
exp it is because it has been
high THC content which is boosted by
being grown under lights how many young
smers actually use SC is
another it is expensive the best
estimate suggest that scope these
account for just 15% of the UK Market
15% of the UK Market
[Music]
strong
you
[Music]
I
back
way alcohol produced longting changes in
the newer chemistry of the bra so this
is really rather un have expected but
thank
goodness is strong because it has been
cross high THC content which is boosted
by being grown under light
how many young smokers actually use scum
is another matter it is expensive and
the best estimate suggest that SC
varities account for just 15% of the UK
Market 15% of the UK
[Music]
Market how many young smokers actually
strong because CR
[Music]
you
strong
[Music]
back
alcohol longting CH in the
[Music]
new is it filming what's up guys yes bub
man here just on the [ __ ] what chair are
we on we're on crystal chair man we're
on the crystal chair Crystal chair we're
on the new Crystal chair heading over
what Fraggle Rock right now yeah coming
up on fragle yesh anyway we're we're uh
going to try to do a Trippy Stick hit
but snow and [ __ ] up here right now we
in a blizzard man we in a blizzard you
know we're going to test the Trippy
Stick put it to the test what we have
here you know so we've got a battery
going to pull up my Ras the battery r on
and then we'll pull out some new
elements that I just got Trippy Stick
elements see what we got let's go gold
gold or silver gold we're going gold top
the podium we go gold man
taking a whole Canada taking a patriotic
in
at all right so we got our Rasta Trippy
Stick one and we're on we are heating up
is she giving us love let's see if we
batter's giving us the love I might not
have charge this one or enough we'll see
if not what we do is we use the other
one that I
charged sometimes I [ __ ] up on my
charging ability anyway
let's see what we got going to give us
love we'll get this going guys there is
no doubt in my
mind cuz these are the things you do the
clock when you're on the mountain
clocking in you're on the clock
definitely on the
[Music]
clock come on baby give me that Trippy
Stick love that I know you have for
me oh yeah that's what I'm talking about
little Trippy Stick
love oh yeah give us orange orange
temperature that's what we want there so
we're going to put a little of this
there watermelon hashes we got some
watermelon little Trippy
Stick and uh yeah I think I'm just going
to pour a whack load in there [ __ ] it
[ __ ] it is filling that [ __ ] everywhere
going to pass it over to the birthday
boy
woohoo we're going to hit this yeah go
ahead birthday boy oh yeah I can see
this The Vapor hitting it
nice oh yeah dude that is working well
that is working very very
well
trippy you getting trippy boy oh let me
see there the button flipped on it's
down here now there you
go it's so nice to see it coming out of
there with SE that little birthday
puffing on the mount Tang we're just in
the burn trees here as you can possibly
see as
ah ask how you get lifted on the
chair tasty
bub awesome you want to hit that yeah
you do
yeah right on Whistler riding actually
we're on black home but kind of
everything's Whistler up
here fresh
turns oh yeah and this is what we call
Fraggle Rock back in the
day all right how you doing on that
thing not getting a hit we'll get you
one all
right you need to okay Dave I'm good all
right I'll just prepack it
again
prepacking we'll wait for deine up here
anyways too so yeah exactly might as
well keep this thing fresh and around
want to hold it thank you you can give
it to him and have a hit she raced down
and we'll catch you guys in a little bit
when we're shredding more pow peace
[Music]
a
let's go let's go
[Music]
w
I
[Music]
he
first G RI
[Music]
woo
[Applause]
let's go let's go
[Music]
this is a r and Beach production
w
[Music]
n
a
[Music]
is
your
your your
[Music]
hand your
hand
your your oh
[Music]
oh
la
[Music]
w
[Applause]
no
[Music]
he
oh
[Music]
that one got me
tired that was awesome
[Music]
[Applause]
w
[Music]
n
ah
[Music]
I
yeah
buddy yeah
[Music]
we're up on the
null awesome buddy yeah we'll get that
shot on this with the rest of the Mask
for sure this h
[Music]
[Applause]
he he
[Music]
[Applause]
last call let's go
go all right there Budd O Boys I think
any time you're ready there oh wait one
sec little bit of fog on the lens
[Music]
I got you I got you well this tree will
block you but I'll get a little bit of
your
jump yeah 1 2
[Music]
3ooo yeah there's the slide we wanted to
see nice
Crown ah that a boy good drop you hopped
in good dude you da
[Music]
like you know what that's nice that's
nice sequence of shots yeah you'll be
happy are both of us in it at the same
oh well Ethan cracks out at the tree
right but yeah your guys are in it for
the start it's a good sequence of shots
no doubt you know what I mean you got
some good bro shots like right here yeah
these are nice that's nice um L to turn
and this is nice right there when I that
looks sick bud when I zoom in on you
there you're going to be like that's the
shot your birthday in the white room
yeah
buddy out B
you holy
[ __ ] we set off that nice fracture I
know I just felt it behind me it was
just like boom the wave on to I'm just
like all the snow comes down and takes
me again off the [ __ ] with my camera
I I literally was just talking about it
all fracturing remember that time when
Mark almost died camera a little idea of
the depth here how deep is it Ethan oh
[ __ ] deep enough actually not deep
enough but here wait wait we get n party
this is the crew that made it here
deon's birthday deon's up
[Music]
there up [ __ ]
you're
not no I'm operating video cameras
[Music]
cameras
up this is so that's a mountain puffing
right there you want to chop
oh there you go hell yeah man puffing at
5,000
ft hey what are you doing oh
[Music]
hey uh don't go that way don't go that
way all right I got to go my front F I
got there now that I got a Bo
[Music]
all right Dusty's bound guys Dusty's
bound birthday boy
up good
[Music]
good right here how about this table
that
[Applause]
[Music]
me
thank you
that Jack is a stoner and always forgets
my gloves so
[Music]
[Applause]
Le here or what and we out
yeah we out we out thanks
dusties let's do
this hey where'd you get the Fancy Pants
Mr Fancy Pants you want to do a disco
[Music]
jig hey man if you're going to sing that
song you got to sing it with a
voice and that's myboard
I'll [ __ ] dig dig dig dig dig and
then you can do all the snow skating cuz
I can't do
it long as you kill yourself I'll be
happy sounds legit stand alive stand
alive ah the vill you feeling e oh he's
fantastic fan [ __ ] tastic amazing day
riding fan [ __ ] tastic over
thereo fan
Fantastic [ __ ] yeah bud just suffering
from Great Depression right so I drive a
Mini Cooper but I think we'll all
fit I got a smart car but I think we'll
make well I I am a clown the clown shoes
are on if I usually roll with like 18 of
my friends in my mini
Austin MINI Coupe
Austina I mean I'll admit 12 of them are
anorexic talk about some heated [ __ ]
Bridges huh yeah that's Tada that's a
heated
Bridge it's very
pretty M smells awesome smells like
canabus smells beautiful smells like
margi Wana
Flipboard I think more people should
smoke marijuana yeah it's good for you
it stops cancer and
[ __ ] it's so fun
fun it makes doing absolutely nothing
amazing it will turn your bordedom
upside
down
upst did you say you had a mat up there
I'm pretty good no everyone boots
there's a for us to walk then I'm
heading up you Dro to place
dude make
sense I'm like what is this he's like I
don't know something Ryan pulled out of
the dumpster he pulled tons of [ __ ] out
of the dumpsters he's got a backpack and
I'm like stop stop what the [ __ ] is you
doing
dump them right off sent them back to BT
and they sent me $500 boots for free it
Wasing I was doing this on my sled like
just it's time to smoke it's time to
smoke some hes you guys want to smoke
some
H
yeah we're going to have another bong RI
we got some
watermelon let's do this one it's a
little bit smaller but darn it that's
beautiful you ready for bong I sure am
all right
well let's see what we got here we got
the
bong all right you're good to
go good to
go puff a b we usually have beline we
usually have a d nail but I forgot
everything today what can I say
sometimes you got to be in Rome and when
we're in Rome when we got nothing else
suck on the
[Music]
lighter how about a bong rip with your
mask on I kind of am
[Music]