[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world back again
this is part three of The Whistler
Excursion it was quite an Excursion my
little my little Whistler we're going to
call it my Whistler we took the My
Little Pony fresh frozen fresh frozen it
was good I like beautiful beautiful
quality um I saw it quite a bit when
John was dumping it all over the hotel
entrance and at the elevator when he was
dumping the cooler over accident it was
just bringing him some nice flavors to
the hotel room some nice flavors to the
hotel room so anyway what we are at Now
with uh where we're at now is we've got
a nice big piece of cardboard is usually
attached to my screen so mostly the only
thing that is on this cardboard is a
little bit of dry sift but I've managed
to get most of it off I've got the two
micro micr planers here John has the
Frozen material he just pulled it out of
a Pelican case which we have stuffed
with frozen juices and ice packs it's
our little mini cooler that way we don't
have to uh continue to bring the
material in and out of the freezer so
I've got my pen we've already done the
190 Micron here
and here is the 160 we're going to do
the 160 now it's really just and then
once we're done the 160 we'll write on
her yeah this 160 of course is going to
be a little bit dirty um oh I would
suggest getting some type of a rub
rubber glove um I'm I usually SE when I
se I use a spoon I don't touch the
bubble whatsoever um I'm going to have
to I've cleaned my fingers made sure
there's no skin particles and uh I'll be
very careful when I grind down like I
said because John made a little bit of a
mistake when we first made this batch
he's he went to clean the 220 bag I try
to pull as much fiber out inside of the
um 160 bag so that it is a little bit
there's a little bit of leaf in
it but it'll be very easily to
distinguish once it's broken into a
powder all right so nice and sticky yeah
but and you know what still maintaining
its coolness yeah oh was awesome I think
the freezing of the uh of
the microplane helped as
well keeping them nice and
cold there we go we're going to have a
few little
chunks which will be identified by The
Rolling
up those will probably be the chunks
make great for um actually throwing into
your
cookies I love the cleaning of the micro
plane it always seems like it's going to
be
impossible and then you just give it one
good whack
and it's clean see keep everything nice
and cold
here excellent excellent Mak it much
easier all right so that
is the
160 all right next next is this here
this is the 120 wow this is a lot of it
dude yeah it's really Frozen isn't it
yeah Frozen let's see the bottom of the
screen for a second perfect perfect okay
uh just look at that probably break that
great thirds at least here's a really
good tip for you guys you don't want to
be using um too large of a piece when
you're microplaning uh it starts melting
in your fingers particularly of this
quality this is going to melt very fast
right going to move over to the next
planer here that I
have look at the
color oh wow is that white that is white
for 120 that is amazing it's not white
for 120 it's white for
snow I've don't that's just so white
that's amazing I'm I'm super so we need
more
CLE yeah I think we
will really careful when we get down to
these last pieces kind of gently rubbing
it over
the this micr planer another piece right
there for you excellent it's always nice
having someone to health you you doing
this oh so nice so much easier it's a
huge or just to to to do it all on your
own it's always nice to have a good
buddy especially oh yeah who grows
killer resin it's always ni to have a
good buddy that makes killer
bubble yes it's a a symbiotic
relationship it looks up quite nicely
actually sh that that is that that looks
like we just threw some white IC and
sugar I can't believe the color I can't
wait to see the
90 yeah this is the 120 yeah oh my
gosh excellent
excellent that that I might break that
one in it too just
give and this Pelican case here full of
um ice and some frozen packs is keeping
this just perfect and in the pizza box
that marvelous Pizza we had in Whistler
and I'm trying to keep my fingers nice
and clean so as to not let it build up
it can be a very tricky thing uh getting
ooey gooey resin on your fingers you can
get yourself in a position where you
make a very big mess in a very short
period of time so it's good to keep
those fingers clean as you're as you're
going like I said if you wear the gloves
you can freeze the gloves and the resin
just pops right off you're going to
manage you're going to keep any type of
uh particulate from your fingers out of
here so I would love to have gloves on
right now however I do not have have
them so in the world of bubbles we do
what we must do we Trot on we continue
give this a little whack to release
what's in
there how many more 120 pieces do we
have one more after that one more after
this okay so we'll go in a little
deeper I was going to maybe oh so we too
small no
problem I mean that's just coming apart
so perfect and it'll be really nice to
take some nice shots of that and show
that the heads aren't all mangled or
chopped up that we were talking about
actually what you mentioned and what we
yeah we we'll definitely take a shot of
this with the macro lens of each variety
oh so small and now the smell is just
hitting me so
much yeah it's really nice isn't
it and there's your next piece of 120
one more after that next piece of 120
coming through
I find that when you do it flat you'll
get a nicer plane a more surface area of
bubble that's touching the plane gives
her a nice um almost not not too thick
but just a nice even spread yeah comes
out nice I still prefer um a strainer
that is I have to
admit a strainer is nice for me cuz I
don't touch the
product I can just imagine how high
you're going to be getting as you're
doing
this it's pretty much uh this all gets
absorb through your skin so when
touching really killer resin understand
that that is also going into your blood
system that's why he's happy right now
you'll see the smiles get bigger and
bigger nonactive though nonactive but
I'm still going to
smile
right okay so
Okay so we've
got our
120 all right that 120 is basically uh
the majority well next okay we're going
to get another piece of cardboard
because we're getting some bigger pieces
out here so I will be right
back we're going to do the 73 cuz there
just not enough room for the 120 okay
yeah we're uh we're going to place the
here I'll run it through my little guy
my nice micr plane coming out beautiful
color keep everything cold as you're
planing if you can keep the bubble cold
keep the planer cold keep your fingers
cold anything you can keep cold is going
to be helpful if you can do it in a cold
environment that's not going to
hurt he just had his hands in the
freezer so I literally
did I washed them from the last that's
cor apart really nicely right there just
crumbling yeah it is really too bad it's
staying on my fingers
but not that much this time not much not
much we'll give it a
little yeah it's because there's
moisture present I can feel it it's
making it easier that moisture
definitely makes makes it
easier all right so we've got our 73
we're going to mark that down you know
you think you can
remember just write it down
73 120 160 and 190 we're going to
replace this cardboard with a clean one
put this one up in our stack so it's out
of the way and protected and uh yeah
we'll be back in a second
Okay so we've got our nice fresh piece
of cardboard there's a couple of rips in
it that I don't really like cuz it's
actually exposing fibers we're going to
avoid that and
uh yeah here we go next up 120 I thought
we did all the 120 the 90 okay we got to
keep that straight we're in the 90 he's
he's playing games with me tricking me
well I'm just keeping you on keeping me
on my toes keep me on your toes all
right so so this is U one of the
favorites in
the that's just
crumbling but it's making for easy
crumbling so whoever says it has to be
completely
Frozen I after doing
that must disagree with you we have
quite a bit more 90 or oh yeah yeah
excellent yeah this is real nice the way
it's crumbling
up ni see the more more you experiment
the more you realize what's everything's
can change with your environment and the
humidity and the temperature
and way less sticking to my fingers this
time because it isn't Frozen I don't
have to push as as hard on it and we got
another piece after
that yeah just washing it it's just
coming apart
perfectly yeah nice and gentle
and our last nice thick piece of 90
excellent save the best for
last
woohoo look at
that not too shabby hey yeah very happy
with that for sure the smell is just
awesome
all right so the 90 is
plained do my little roll the hash off
your
fingers you'll end up usually seeing
these pieces in the end they'll have a
little bit of a different texture to
them and they they really are just going
to have a tiny bit of moisture trapped
in them so I usually just puff those
early on
here's a
45 all right we're going into 45 now are
we right into
45 so
[Music]
45 what do we have left after that just
20 yeah five getting right down to the
last ivly by the looks of everything
here it's uh upwards of over over 10 10
rounds at least I
say yeah you know it's I'm sure we'll
get our 10% return at least oh yeah
that's what I'm saying we're definitely
getting that 10%
return good piece
out fiber there that
off 45 has that very strong tonation
tpine smell you just I can always know
when it's the 45 yeah truly yeah it's
also so the first bubble that is usually
the one to light a flame when you're
smoking
it not that I've been smoking much
lately since I got the
Dil one more piece of 45 oh only got lot
45 pass it pass them up there go
excellent shaving them
down one little Tri head of B yes one
little tricomb head at a
time sometimes 50,000 heads 50,000 right
there I raise you 50,000 heads to uh
there's an
extra 5,000 there yeah the moisture
content is good in this it's got enough
moisture that it's not um really
sticking to my fingers uh the moisture
allows for it to that little bit of
water makes for a good PL l in and it's
easy to go through and pick up the tiny
little chunks that are too big and just
run them gently through the micr planer
I've got a two size planer here so the
one size the smaller size is pretty easy
to
uh to touch directly it's got smaller
little blades I guess you would say and
because of that it's not it's gentle on
my fingers I'm not peeling my fingers
off on it and last but not least is just
one big chunk of 25
25 you know truly the one that you can
honestly get away with sometimes drawing
in a
Patty um we're just going to microplan
it
up crumbles right up
perfectly never have a problem drying
the 25 micron I think it has a lot to do
with the fact that the heads are so much
smaller um less water actually fits
between the heads on the outside of the
heads if you if you think of it like a
bowl of grapes um the larger the grapes
the more surface area between Those
Grapes uh the smaller they are the less
space between the more can fit in a bowl
there's less room for moisture and I
think that's why the 25 micron has never
really been a problem drying it even in
a Patty and it's definitely the one that
can confuse people when you tell them
you can't dry bubble in a Patty they
might have done it 5 Micron and and
think yes you can so there's a quick
little uh microplaning job I'll tell you
uh having somewhere safe to put this
away from dust and debris pet hair kids
whatever is very important we've got it
in the gorilla tent here on top of the
4X 2T screens we've got them stacked
they're going to be safe and beautiful
and put away and not even dust is going
to fall on it you really want to make
sure you can kind of create something
like that before you get yourself into
this situation of having the bubble all
powdered out on the on the cardboard
board or parchment paper and uh yeah I
guess we're going to put this over there
John and I are going to hit some bowls
so we'll be right back thanks for
watching
[Music]
sh