now we're going to put the baffles in
the tank the baffles help the water move
properly and the Cannabis to the tank as
it
mixes so once it's nice thought it comes
in really
easy for different sizes of Tanks
now I'm going to put the impeller into
the motor so you have the quick release
coupling you let it fall
down and then you have to make sure it's
in the centered position once it's there
you push up on the spring rotate it Let
It Drop into position now the tank is
ready to mix now once you have the water
level filled up to the top of the baffle
all the Cannabis is thawed it's time to
start it up so we're going to turn on
the impeller
as the tank first starts to mix it might
need a just a little boost to start
fluidizing the material so get it up to
your speed and then just start to loosen
material from the edges