I didn't want to do it in the lab
because it just everybody has to stop
working when they're filming and I can't
afford it yeah and they and they
complain of course
is it is it why is there so much
interest well uh because there is is
being used so widely in the U.S and so
many
states have approved it and the same is
happening in Europe
so uh when something which is not well
known is being so widely used
people come out and start asking
questions how where what are the type of
diseases it can do what is the
scientific background what are the
side effects and so on and so forth so
quite a lot of people come around and
start asking questions can I ask you
both something do you feel like a weight
do you feel a weight and a sort of a
pressure to keep discovering things or
to live up to your discoveries in a way
I'm not sure that I
think along those Pathways we've been
doing
yeah
in the lab in Jerusalem we've been
working since 1964. uh Lumia Dr hanus
worked in the Czech State a little bit
later and these are two in individual
separate researchers then Lumi joineda
lab about 20 years ago and no I don't
think that we have to find new things
all the time that's part of
of what we do all the time I mean we do
things some of them succeed and some of
them don't sometimes we find new things
and sometimes we don't so it depends on
what we're doing you see
most people are interested in the plants
canopy dial THC in the plant and so on
this is something that we didn't Lumia
and the Czech researchers did it
separately
I don't know 30 40 years ago we did it
about 50 years ago
work on the plant
identification of the active compound
see the active compound THC was only
partially known when we started working
it the structure was unknown it couldn't
it it was not available for research and
of course that's a major problem this is
contrary to
uh morphine which had been isolated from
opium 150 years previously or cocaine
which had been isolated from coca leaves
100 years previously and of course they
had been investigated thoroughly here we
had a strange situation that is a plant
that's being widely used in various
forms marijuana Ashish
etc etc but the science behind it was
rather weak because the active compound
or compounds had never been isolated in
pure form and they could not be
investigated
so in the 60s we went first into that
direction isolating the THC and many
other compounds and we I re-isolated
cannabi dial and quite a lot of other
compounds quite many of them new
compounds that had never been isolated
previously we identified their
structures and then we started looking
at the metabolism the activity and so on
and this went for quite a long time this
is essentially the first stage of
cannabinoid research work on the plant
chemistry biology clinical effects and
we did some clinical trials just as well
now this is something that we did in the
uh
60s early 70s we did some clinical work
and I can tell you about it later
but that was the first stage one thing
that was not known
at that point how how does it work
what's the mechanism of cannabinoid work
and
uh
it turned out that they are receptors
proteins in the brain and in the body
that THC binds to them
and these receptors that two of them won
when activated causes the well-known
effects of marijuana the high the other
one does not binding of THC to that
particular receptor causes only
protective actions and no it doesn't
cause the high
so THC bind to both these receptors now
we don't have receptors in our body
because there is a plant out there we
have receptors in our body because we
produce compounds that activate these
receptors when needed so we went ahead
looking for these compounds at that time
a fellow who had worked on The receptors
a joint is a postdoctoral fellow and
Lumiere hanus came from the Czech State
as a visiting
a scientist and then he's he has been
here with us now for the law he came for
six months 20 years ago and he's still
here and he just retired so um uh we
retired I think he's he's completely an
entrepreneur now yeah that's something
else you see retired from the university
the university one has to retire the age
of 68 or something like that so um we
went ahead looking for the compounds
that our body produces that activates
these receptors so we believe I see it
as the second stage of cannabinoid
research the second stage meaning
another compounds from the plant the
compounds that we produce that activate
these receptors and cause a lot of
effects and indeed we worked and at that
time as I said Dr hannus had joined us
and Dr Devane had joined us in quite a
few others when this was in
collaboration with several groups abroad
these the compounds that we were just
covering were also tested in the UK and
tested in the U.S and we found
eventually two compounds that our body
produces chemically they are completely
different
from the compound that the plant
produces but they have the same activity
more or less
so we called one of them anandamide and
the other one 2ag Ananda in Sanskrit of
course you know Sanskrit I speak it
every day yes so we found that
Ananda is supreme Joy anyway we call the
compound the nandamide and we elucidated
its structure and synthesized it and the
same with the second compound 2ag and
these two compounds are present in the
body made by the body when and where
needed
and they act when and where needed for
example if somebody
has been injured and there is pain
the body will produce anandamide and 2ag
in that area in order to lower the pain
but they are involved in a huge number
of additional actions in the brain as a
matter of fact the researchers at NIH
National Institute of Health in the U.S
I had a review and they said these two
compounds as a matter of fact the whole
system of endocannabinoid system The
receptors the compounds and so on are
involved in essentially all human
diseases
and this is a very strong statement
but they are because they do several
things they regulate some of the other
neurotransmitters in the body and they
have actions of their own so they are
extremely important and therefore there
has been a huge amount of work on them
thousands of papers have been published
on an antibyte in 2ag and we know quite
a lot about their activity within the
body
so we see that as the second stage of
cannabinoid research showing how this
endogenous cannabinoid system works in
the mammalian body in our body and how
it is associated with
everyday life mood happiness sorrow and
so on and with disease states is it sort
of like like a part of the immune system
well it is uh
uh parallel to the immune system
the immune system guards us against all
kinds of things happening to us without
the immune system will be dead within 24
hours the activation of the one of the
receptors it's called the CB2 receptor
activation of one of the receptors helps
basically activation
of the endocannabinoid system of the CB2
receptor is a apparently extremely
important in guarding us against all
kinds of
things that are happening in the body
and we want to prevent them we don't
know enough about it but we know quite a
bit and we have seen that in many
diseases activation of CB2 is important
it does not completely parallel the
immune system maybe it adds to the
immune system and at some point we shall
know I hope much better how these two
systems work together for someone who
twice a week about this you seem very
very energetic well I have to be at my
age but I'm
but now we have moved to the third stage
of the cannabinoid research and there
are very few people interested in that
stage at the moment and I can tell you
in a few words what's going on the
endogenous cannabinoids we have in the
body
formed a not very complicated compounds
they are
conformed from fatty acids like oleic
acids which is present in olive oil and
amino acids which form the proteins in
the body
so here we have a simple relatively
simple compound but the body has
prepared almost 100 of these maybe more
of compounds of the same type fatty
acids Mountain amino acids and it
doesn't make a hundred compounds because
it has nothing to do it makes them
because of it knows how to make them and
it needs them and we have found that
these compounds about 100 of them those
that we have investigated are of major
importance in our body
so this is the third stage of
cannabinoid research we found that one
of the compounds acts in osteoporosis
the breaking down of Bones
the background of that women after the
age of 50 with all the changes are
happening in the hormone levels then
they should have a lot of
bone damage
osteoporosis it's not all not all women
have that and the reason is women as
well as men but women in this case
produce a compound which is closely
related to the endocannabinoids closely
related to anandamide which blocks
osteoporosis
in another field with Professor shohami
we found the compounds of this type
affect brain damage
and if somebody has brain damage the
brain starts producing them and lowers
the brain damage wait but if someone
with osteoporosis creates these
compounds then how come they still have
osteoporosis well uh
they do not block completely they act
against those operas they say the body
starts
breaking down the bone see
our bones are not stable to this in the
sense that
the same bones that you had when you
were six years old will be when you're
six years old and the body changes them
I mean brace them down and build them
again breaks them down and build them
again they are cells
that build the bones and cells they
break the bones so these compounds
endogenous compounds limit the action of
the cells that break the bones and
enhance the action of the cells that
uh buildabouts so it's a regulator in
this case the same is true for brain
damage we recently found something else
which is also of major importance I
believe we have to find out
our body makes one compound of that type
that tries to block certain addictions
in this case we've worked only in uh
nicotine addiction we found that our
body makes a compound
that tries to block nicotine addiction
and tries to block the
the effects
that are caused by addiction the effect
that caused after one stops taking an
addictive drug
now it doesn't succeed almost but
sometimes apparently it does succeed
most of the research and addiction has
been done on the addicted people or
addicted animals very little work has
been done on those that are not addicted
we have with
a different addictive drugs only partial
addiction
only depends on the drug it may be
twenty percent sixty percent seventy
percent get addicted why don't the other
get addicted why don't we have because
the body produces a compound and maybe
compounds we so far identified one
compound and published it
showing that it blocks nicotine
addiction and it can block the
withdrawal effects both of
nicotine and of opiates in animals we
haven't tested in that in humans that's
complete that's uh the next phase so if
we if the body does that
it's a major
advance
towards using such compounds is
anti-addictive compounds so here we are
at the third stage of cannabinoid
research working on compounds that are
somewhat related to the endogenous
cannabinoids but have a huge uh
effects in many many other medical
situations
um
um so if I want to ask you a few
things about different things do you
feel is if you haven't discovered THC
and if Lumiere hadn't discovered
nonetheless
would would someone else have discovered
it oh yes
I mean
it's nice to think that we are the only
Geniuses in the world but no it doesn't
work that way
science advances
people are happy to make an important
step but chances are that if we hadn't
done it somebody else would have done it
even with cannabis that's so it's it's
it's rare it was rare for many years for
anyone to study it do you think we would
be very far behind if you guys didn't
well we have contributed yes definitely
but uh
uh
science moves ahead it's based on
individuals but science moves ahead and
chances are that if we had not
discovered or identified the structure
of THC of cannaby diode somebody else
would have done it maybe a few days
later maybe
the things we did pushed the whole field
ahead but China's aside would have been
by done by somebody else the discovery
of anandamide and 2ag
again chances are that it could have
been discovered later as regards the
third stage who knows
the guy I can't remember his name Gill I
think I can't remember the guy who runs
Debbie mealy's lab with him told me that
when they first opened the lab the
technion was against it and they they
said okay we'll let you open it but they
were embarrassed by it or something and
I'm not so sure about it the they got a
lot of money they got millions in order
to set up the lamp yeah
they wouldn't they wouldn't come to show
them yeah and what what I'm getting at
is do you think is is there a sense of
is there a fear of the establishment in
studying not that the Hebrew University
as a matter of fact when I moved here
1965 they asked me to move over after I
was at the Weitzman Institute and uh
here they offered they suggested they
should set up a independent unit which I
did and the university never had any
objections to what we were doing as a
matter of fact uh
the professors at the University didn't
look at it it's something that well
maybe should not be done and the fact is
that I was well accepted personally and
my research was well accepted and many
years ago I was elected by the
professors by the Senate of the
university to head the University's
academic head of the University as
Rector they thought it were working on
something that is
well objectionable they wouldn't have
done that so
it's a
positive sign why why did they not think
that you were working on something
objectionable it was illegal in Israel
just like everywhere else so why why was
it acceptable do you think why was it
okay
well uh it's illegal to use it's not
illegal to do research I mean people do
research on on illegal things most of
the
investigations in law have to do with uh
breaking the law who knows what no uh
there are two different things we were
not doing anything illegal as a matter
of fact our work was supported
originally not by a financially by
giving us without having to pay anything
and we got cannabis from the police the
original work was done by
quite a lot of cannabis that I got from
the police I never had any problems with
the Ministry of Health as a matter of
fact they consulted me I never had any
problems with the National Institute of
Health in the U.S as a matter of fact I
was given an award
by the National Institute of Health for
our work on cannabis and it's very
different in America well no but I got
the award in America no I mean for our
research
well
the laws are complicated there more
complicated than here I mean people have
to get all kinds of approvals the same
is here but here it's just we're a small
country and I have no problems getting
the approvals uh
the Ministry of Health actually
sometimes have some of my students there
we've never had any problems getting
approvals as long as we did our work
legally and we always did our work
completely legally we never had any
um legal problems
why
why worth studying
well we bother because it's a something
of importance but in a in a university
this is
a little bit strange to ask why uh
you see something exists we know that
cannabis it has been known for thousands
of years that cannabis has two types of
effects it causes what we call the high
today but it also has medicinal effects
we should study that we should know why
cannabis does that are there different
compounds that cause the recreational
effect versus the medicinal effect we
should learn about all kinds of things
academics
try to work on things that are in there
are is important not necessarily
important to the community in general
they have to decide and sometimes
it turns out that academics find things
that later on turn out to be of major
importance I can give you numerous
examples of that
breaking the atom who cared about
the atom being broken down it's a nice
thing well it did matter because it it
is the basis of
atomic energy and unfortunately atomic
bombs and so on there are many other
things who cares about a certain place
in the brain who cares well we do care
so we try I mean individually we're not
told from above that's the major
difference uh
academic a professor at the University
decides on his own what he wants to do
research on he's not being told from the
top do research on this one he has to
decide on his own and this is the best
way of doing it and this is why
universities in the West in Europe in
the U.S obviously in England Germany
France and so on uh has has advanced
much more than in many other countries
because they're the individual decides
what he has to do not somebody who is on
the Trap and decides for everybody else
working in front of a microscope do you
think about greater context about
societal context at all or or do you
just look for what you're looking for
well
Louis Pasteur in the 19th century said
that chance helps the prepared mind
so you look for something you have a
plan you look for something but if you
know
a little bit more you know what's going
on and you see something happening then
chances are you can explain something
new so new things happen sometimes these
new things are of major importance but
in most cases these new things can be
observed by people that
have the background to understand what's
happening what I mean is he meant
something different
when you're when you're doing
about the connection between This
research and just and all of society
using this research later or do you not
think that way well this is exactly what
I told you Society is something very
large I mean
a scientist is not thinking of society
every minute maybe in a large in a
in the evening when he looks at his
results as well maybe Society will be
interested and so on but he has a plan
he has to work maybe his work will
prevent
some kind of disease maybe the work we
are doing an addiction will prevent or
slow down Addiction in many cases in the
U.S last year there were that's what I
read 65
000 people died of
opiate addiction mostly opiate addiction
in the states well maybe by helping with
the withdrawal symptoms we can help that
if we can block
the withdrawal symptoms then many people
will be able
to get out of the other addiction at the
moment many of them are afraid of the
withdrawal symptom so they continue
taking the opiates in order not to get
with those symptoms it's a simplified
way of telling it but it's it has
something to do with it when we looked
at the cannabis
well we knew we know we knew that the
large number of people are using
cannabis maybe we can learn something
about it and we have learned not only
about the recreational effects we have
learned something about them medical
effects and I believe that within the
next decade or so we shall have quite a
few cannabinoid based drugs on the
market in in various fields
let me give you a few examples yeah uh
we work on the and cannabi dial a major
compound found in cannabis which is not
psychoactive it doesn't cause the high
and people would have thought okay so if
it's not of major interest it is a major
interest because cannaby dial is a major
possible drug
we have seen that in epilepsy it blocks
epileptic attacks we published that 35
years ago
cannabidiol blocked epileptic attacks in
patients that nothing else was helping
them
what happened
nothing for 30 years
just the neurologists were not very
interested nobody was very interested
until parents found out that Canada
plants that contain a lot of cannabidiol
maybe they saw our work or maybe they
just learned it from other sources they
found that cannabidiol helps children
with epilepsy there are children that
have 20 30 attacks a day
well Canada helps them so uh
our work on a prevention of
epileptic attacks by cannabidium
is a as an important medical step
forward now uh
about 150 children in Israel are getting
extracts with a huge amount huge amount
of cannaby diode at the blocks their
epileptic attacks so these children
would not normally uh
will not be able to develop with 20
attacks a day now they are more or less
normal
in the U.S
a major study was done based on what we
did 35 years ago yes they showed that
it's a major importance in epilepsy so
here we have a medical Advance based on
the basic science on identifying
cannabidiol looking at cannabidiolin
animals finding out that it's
anti-epileptic then going into humans it
doesn't always work that way we show
that in Diabetes Type 1 which is an
autoimmune disease cannaby dialysis of
major health well nobody has done that
in the humans which is a shame because
it helps
inanimous exactly the same mechanism it
helps with diabetes type 1.
why it has not been tested in humans
it's beyond meat costs a lot of money to
do clinical trials but I have no doubt
that when tested in humans it will show
the same effect
cannabi Dio has been shown to be an
excellent
empty schizophrenic drug
in schizophrenic patients now
schizophrenia is not a minor disease one
percent of the population in every
country has schizophrenia so we're
dealing with Millions
and this there are drugs against
schizophrenia but they call side effects
cannabidiol does not cause side effects
and once it is pushed forward chances
are that it will become a major anti
schizophrenic drugs so uh
we see a lot about autoimmune diseases
namely diseases in which the body
attached itself white about the attacks
itself is a complicated question we most
cases don't know much about it but in
essentially on
autoimmune diseases that have been
tested in animals
we see that cannabidiol helps so the
basic work that was done in canopy down
may turn out to be a major importance in
medicine
what can you tell me about the original
science about the anti-epileptic stuff
was that done here
well it was known
uh that cannabis is an
anti-epileptic agent as a matter of fact
there are all kinds of in the individual
reports over hundreds of years on and
off and I'd like to quote somebody in
the Muslim World a major person in the
Muslim world in the 15th century he had
uh
epilepsy and somebody brought him
cannabis and he didn't have a epileptic
attacks but he had to continue taking
the drug this was actually
written and described by in the 15th
century and the document was found about
20 years ago in a
in Paris by
a friend of mine Dr Rosendale
this is here we're doing some we are we
have
information of the 15th century and most
probably it was also used for the same
purpose in India to a certain extent
India Chinatown so when we started work
we had some individual information but
this is today individual information is
not enough when it's information on
humans will need a scientific medical
way of doing it we need
people that take Placebo namely
take the same
solvent or the same drug without the
active compound and those that take the
active compound and who is doing the
research should not know who is taking
the placebo and who is taking the active
compound and the end of the research one
should do that so we started working on
that we also we always work in
collaboration
we collaborate with friends and
colleagues all over the world in this
case it was with a group in Sao Paulo in
Brazil and they we first tested cannabi
dial we isolated huge amounts of
cannabidio from Cannabis given to us by
the police and we send them
almost half a kilo of cannaby diode they
first tested it in animals
uh Apple animus with epilepsy it worked
very well they test them then they went
into human patients and they looked at
the human patients for several months so
here is how it is done it has to be done
in collaboration between Chemists in
this case our group biologists in that
case the work in Sao Paulo and the
police
and the police that gave us the the
material
so uh it has to be done in collaboration
it has to be obviously completely legal
and it has to be well planned ahead and
we've been doing that in collaboration
with many other groups The Addictive the
uh research and addiction is done
jointly in collaboration by four groups
uh for independent groups I mean it
every one of them can say I don't want
to do it well they do because it's
interesting uh the addiction is done by
in collaboration by our group a group in
Richmond Virginia a group in Canada and
group in Italy so we work together we
correspond we tell each other what's
going on and each one of us has his own
specialty and it can help the others who
have some other specialty so we do the
chemistry and the general background the
general idea of cannabinoids the people
at Richmond work on nicotine addiction
and and so on the people in uh uh in
Canada worked on opiate addiction and
the people in in Italy work on uh
addiction to food actually overeating
and so on Obesity things of that sort
um some I've had heard very interesting
things about clinical trials
some doctors have told me and
researchers told me that they think
clinical trials might need to be
adjusted or even reinvented re-thought
of because for cannabis based medicine
because it's because it's effect it
seems to be so individual
uh dead email and someone else said they
completely disagree with that that it
has to stay exactly the same I think
also didn't say exactly the same and
that they have to uh do um just isolates
you know and and build up a pharmacology
of of which which cannabinoids that work
together for what what do you think
about that
well you have good research and you have
bad research
if you don't do it the right way it's
bad research and the results are not
worthwhile but good reason today
uh uh advancing in the chemical medical
side has to be done by good research
I've originally in animals and then in
humans the clinical trials have to be
done according to rules that are well
accepted by
clinicians now if somebody does a lousy
research well it's a lousy research but
the good research is good research one
has to look at the research as it is
done without clinical trials today a
compound cannot become a drug but
through clinical can for cannabis
medicine can we do clinical trials the
exact same way we do it for other
medicines same methods yes one can take
compound
canopy dial and give it to
schizophrenics
take the same solution that contains the
cannaby dial but also but does not
contain the cannaby diode itself only
the solvents and all the
formulation there and give it to other
patients at the placebo these are basic
rules and for example the German group
that published on
cannabidiolins schizophrenia did an
excellent job so the work that was just
completed in the U.S and epilepsy a
large number of epileptic children it
was an outstanding research proposal it
had to be approved by
many other clinicians it costs
unfortunately Millions to do it but once
it's well done it should be well
accepted clinicians have to base their
work the day-to-day work on clinical
trials and these clinical trials have to
be outstanding can you do clinical
trials with with
um
stuff that's not just isolated compounds
like with full spectrum plants
well it is more difficult because it's
uh doing it with a single compound one
can
say what are the amounts of the single
compounds how often how it has to be
given and so on when a clinical trial is
done with an extract then what has a
problem because the extracts can differ
so I assume that the people you talk to
and were negative
thought about
extracts and not about the well-defined
compounds this is true with working with
extracts may be very complicated and
this is because of something that we
discovered many years ago which is
called the Entourage effect the
Entourage effect means that there are
compounds in cannabis that change modify
the the activity of THC
they by themselves have no activity but
they modify the activity of THC so if
you have different compounds every time
you do a clinical trial or an animal
trial as a matter of fact with an
extract which is not exactly the extract
you had previously or somebody else had
previously then obviously you cannot
compare because of the Entourage effect
so so is that a is that a barrier for
for research how how do you overcome
that well you work with well-defined
material
so okay so about isolate and full
spectrum there are people who have told
me very very confidently and adamantly
that isolates are not helpful but I
definitely heard the opposite I've heard
isolates can be very helpful some people
are saying only full spectrum is helpful
and you have to have THC to make the CBD
become you know useful
um what do you think about that these
are very general statements you have to
go into very specific cases uh
pure cannabidiol is outstanding in
many diseases
there
a lot of people that claim that
a
one has to use
extracts in order to get better effects
maybe in some cases this is correct but
in order to to do a clinical trial one
has to do it with
well-defined extracts so uh
this is where we stand
think so is so is pure cannabidiol
useful in many many indications that
you've seen so far yes as I said in we
did work on epilepsy with 100
cannabidiol pure crystalline the people
in Germany need a
uh work on schizophrenia with 100 pure
cannabidiol the work in
epilepsy in the state the clinical trial
was done with
compound which was
a almost pure CBD extracted from the
plant
and the reason they did it is because
an extract from a plant falls under
different legal definition in the states
a pure compound has that's what I
understand I'm not a legal person
a compound
that dispute has falls under the
jurisdiction of the FDA
extract of a plant
is something else so it's easier to do
yeah
yeah well the extra you see plant
extracts in the states
uh
uh seen legally in a different way so
you have a 50 billion dollar business of
extracts various plant extracts in the
state and the FD has essentially it
cannot say anything about them
uh uh this is not the same as pure drugs
pure compounds the FDA has a lot to say
about them so legally the two different
uh
legal situations what do we know about
um about cannabis in pregnancy and in
birth and in women's health in general
is that and and its effect on the mother
and the fetus well generally
most
women that
still take cannabis
uh say they're nothing major has
happened but sometimes he sort of
thought that the children that are born
maybe smaller and
develop more or less
normally but basically I would strongly
recommend not to use anything during
pregnancy not cannabis not any any drug
if possible
because it's extremely difficult to
to know exactly what's going on if you
have a drug which causes damage to the
fetus in 50 percent of the cases this
will be seen immediately but what
happens if the damage is seen only in
one fetus out of 1000
it is not seen in any clinical trial
but the one damage is one damage that
particular damaged baby is damaged and
we don't know it's extremely difficult
to prove anything of that sort I mean
we need statistical proofs
it is very difficult to work with
effects that with things that affect
I don't know half a percent of the
population or half percent of the
fetuses and uh
what I would normally suggest
if a pregnant woman asked me may I take
cannabis because it lowers the vomiting
I have during the pregnancy I say well
too bad just suffer the vomiting and
don't take anything any drug
but isn't that true for for any disease
that anyone has because you can say well
we haven't
we haven't checked it on on 10 000
people yet so maybe it will do damage
even though it helps many people well
this is probably true for all kinds of
minor effects but there we know that in
a disease it helps the disease pregnancy
is not a disease pregnancy is a normal
thing
so are there are there any things that
you would have done
just since 1964 was this THC isolation
right so so since since then is there is
there anything you would have done
differently that you think would have
changed in any way the way that it's the
in this the industry I'm calling it has
gone
well scientifically probably not
probably I could have got more money to
do more research but basically we went
the right way what I should have done
better is try to get industrial interest
and still although we know that these
compounds have activity cannaby dial
derivatives cannabi dial
they're still not
sold as defined drugs and possibly I
could have pushed more for that for
example Tema the biggest company in this
in Israel the biggest pharmaceutical
company is not really interested was not
interested chances are that we could
have pushed more for that well we did
so so but scientifically you feel like
everything was done the right way well
maybe it could have been done faster
maybe the group could have been larger
we always had my group was always a
small group of three or four people
working in different aspects
um no I can't say most of the work we do
is collaboration
we do a lot of collaboration with many
other groups I mean
research that is done between chemistry
and biology one needs good collaboration
between the chemists and the biologists
and over the last 30 40 years we have
always had collaborators in various
fields
and
every
a aspect anything that we do now is
always in collaboration with people that
are well informed know how to do the
biology or the clinical work and so on
do you think there's a
over the years with cannabis research
I see the biggest problem
in cannabis research cooperation between
different nations scientists from
different countries because karabis is
stigmatized and it's illegal drug just
to exchange of samples is a big problem
so some sometimes analyzed locally and
we cannot compare these samples in
abroad so we can do locally
even different studies but it's problem
to do it in the other country because
when I ask when my friend in United
States for some
cannabis standards he told me you know
this permits export import it's such
complicated better come to here and do
it here it will be without any problems
so I see this is a certain break you
know
yeah but do you feel do you feel like
you if people rolled their eyes at you
over the years and and do you feel
did you feel stigmatized over the years
from people did people look down at any
of you for the research that you're
doing other scientists they ever say oh
those are the guys that do marijuana you
know not in my case I can't I can't
complain I've uh the fact the fact is
that I've been uh uh
given prices all over the world in by uh
in many countries I have a honorary
doctorates from the U.S and Canada
yeah and so on the day-to-day level you
know from people that you meet is it
always is it always like a joke to other
people or people who don't understand no
as a matter of fact most people think
that it's important to do
if somebody thinks uh otherwise
we're a Open Country let him think
otherwise
I think that's
Israel I never have problems we
cooperate it also with criminalists
was no problem on medicinal level on
matter as a drug of abuse
so I don't compl I cannot complain just
only this
relations International you know this is
a little bit problem because of
ricardity
yes let me give you an example of what
lumir is saying I collaborate with a
group in in the UK a well-established
group in the UK the person that has that
group has a Knighthood he's sir
and so on but I cannot send him the
derivatives of cannabi dial because of
legal problems in the UK they don't he
he heads was head of a major group at
Oxford
he's not somebody
who does who is on the side he's at the
center of
British research highly regarded and yet
I cannot send him the compounds because
of legal problems pity
ridiculous yes it is ridiculous
because they're not giving them to
humans then going to test these
compounds in the test tube and they're
going to test these compounds in animals
and if they are
and good drugs then they have to go
through the official legal things in
order to get into the humans but nobody
says it
he's doing anything illegal in the
country wasn't it frustrating to work
for years with this stuff that's just
that's completely illegal outside I
understand you have to study things that
are illegal but is it frustrating
because you're discovering hey it's it
works for epilepsy but we can't give it
to anyone because it's illegal
Celebi
were you ever ready to give up because
of that
no no why should I
did you ever feel frustrated
you know concerning the research I was
every time very satisfied it was every
time Vander for
we can share any our ideas on paper on
emails it's no problem only what's
mentioned professor meshugram
[Music]
it's complicated what I told you that my
friend told me just come it's no problem
so as you can see he he wrote me come
it's no problem it's no problem but send
it
it's a complicated
even I think if I want to bring some
samples from the other lip here you know
I need certain pyramid because I cannot
take it and go by car and have the
sample
I I need to have sample this permit
because it stopped me some police that
they say that I have some sample from
cannabis and I don't have permitism it
can be problem yeah never happened to me
but theoretically I'm talking about it
so okay so so what where do you see this
going in terms of how do you see this
getting uh can I have noid medicine
getting
um into the Pharma into into
pharmaceutical drugs how do you see the
process happening well things are
changing
uh
Israel is a matter of fact it's uh
pretty well ahead of many other
countries
medical cannabis it can be administered
here one needs an approval
by the ministry or by physicians that
have uh that are associated with the
ministry they're about 35
000 patients that have approval which is
a huge number for a certain for
well-defined diseases
particularly uh
in a diseases that are not associated
with the
Psychiatry every almost everything else
in order to work with cannabis a group
has to get approval by the ministry and
there is a committee a major committee
that sits every three months and it so
happens the time chairman of the
committee
so I collaborate with the ministry and
we are very
liberal in allowing people to do
research in cannabis somebody wants to
do research in his background in his
backyard well we'll say no because
that's a way just to use to make legal
cannabis into illegal cannabis but if
it's done in a university or a
well-established unit
governmental company then they have no
problem doing research and that today
they are
no I don't know probably 50 60 labs in
this country they do research in
cannabis in various aspects of cannabis
did you ever expect that when you were
starting out that cannabis and marijuana
will become your your life's work
well yeah this is one of the topics
we've worked on I am a natural products
chemist I work on the chemistry of
natural products on the chemistry plants
produce a lot of compounds contrary to
humans so
mammalians we produce all of us produce
the same type of compounds we produce
the same type of compounds more or less
like a cow or a
duck or a pig
not with the plants because we have a
immune system plants don't have a
specific immune system their immune
system is based to a large extent and
compound they produce and every plant
family has more or less the same type of
compounds but there are many families
and therefore there are thousands of
compounds in the plants so this is a
well-established field of chemistry
chemistry of natural products if you
look at a plant of one type plant if
another type we find many different
types of compounds and most of these
compounds their structures are unknown
or their activities are known so my
group has worked for the last 50 years
on the chemistry of and biology of
natural products
and and are you optimistic about where
it's all going
well
I don't think about optimistic or
pessimistic we want to establish things
uh hopefully they will turn out to be
positive in the sense that they can be
used further on but uh that doesn't uh
depend on any academic lab we are
we can't do much about it we could
investigate something
you can show that something is happening
we can talk to the people that are
involved in promoting a compound but we
can't go further on the clinical trials
today contrary to what was in the past
cost a lot a lot of money give you an
example
when a hundred years ago insulin was
discovered and insulin is the compound
that our body makes in order to regulate
the sugars in our body it was used
immediately as a drug it's an excellent
drug still being used in one way or
another the insulin anandamide which we
discovered 25 years ago has never been
given to a human never
insulin was given within six months and
then the bite probably is a pretty good
drug but it has never been given to a
human because a company has to be
interested and has to spend many
millions of uh downloads to develop so
are you are you surprised when you look
around and see just how big this is
becoming and how accepted this is
becoming and how much research there is
relative to when you were just well I'm
I'm delighted
uh uh I'm delighted that the medical uh
part of it is developing slowly but it
is developing one should
separate the medical use from the
recreational use the medical use has to
go according to
well-established medical routes
it has to go through
toxicity and animals and then into the
humans it has in order to be accepted by
The Physicians
it has to follow the well-established
medical rules recreational use is a
social issue
a recreational use has to be decided by
the population whether it's toxic or not
uh that's something else uh obviously
populations all over the world have
decided or decided a 100 to 200 years
ago that smoking tobacco is fine the
fact that people die out of uh smoking
tobacco doesn't matter it has been
socially accepted the same is true for
let's say whiskey 50 alcohol definitely
not very healthy but it is approved but
this is a social issue one cannot come
over and say we should be allowed to use
cannabis recreationally because it helps
with epilepsy what's the logic there
there is no logic these two things
should be completely separated one is
the medical issue the other is a social
issue
I was going to ask you before about
anandamide it's really interesting
of we think of cannabis medicine as
cannabinoid based but we don't ever
think about it as endocannabinoid based
it will be 10 years from now should it
be of course why
because these are compounds that we make
if we make if our body makes a compound
it makes it for a certain reason and
we more or less know what the reasons
are and there is no doubt that at some
point people will start using it let me
give you an example from a different
field there is a compound in our body
called dopamine
and there is a major dopaminergic system
well it was known but it slowly it was
slowly discovered that the lack of
dopamine causes one disease and too much
dopamine causes another disease uh too
much is causes schizophrenia so in order
to block
if there isn't enough in Parkinson's
disease for example one gives
dopaminergic type compounds of the body
if there is a lot of if there is
schizophrenia one tries to lower that so
the body has to have a
certain amount of dopamine not too much
and not too little the same is probably
true for an antibyte people have come
out and claiming without any major proof
that migraine for example
is due to
maybe
a lack of anandabite maybe but of course
it's very difficult to do work and a
migraine because if you ask a mouse do
you have migraine he doesn't want to
answer you but basically it seems to be
maybe it's true so it has to be
investigated if in many of these
diseases we find that anandamite or 2ag
the two endogenous cannabinoids uh there
is too much of them or too little of
them maybe we can do something about it
we thought of as
a nourishment issue like in other words
that
that if we we're not having enough not
making enough endocannabinoids we need
cannabinoid nourishment for some reason
well possibly
I mean this is still being investigated
but the fact that the endocannabinoid
system is involved in a huge huge number
of diseases then obviously we have to
think along those lines
you're most welcome in that case
thank you
um I just I was hoping to have you guys
talk about something or other about
research but I don't I don't really know
about what because this was an idea well
if you wanted for second or two we can
talk I would love it yeah
do you see any difference between the
attitude in in the check state which you
know very well before previously
a communist
time or a bit later and the attitude
today
of course in communistic regime
everything was prohibited it was not
such easy and we work on cannabis
interface I started to work at 1970 by
the way the first day when I came to
Professor Karachi the first name which I
was familiar with was Professor Rafael
dashura this was even at that time
leading Authority and this was the main
brain concern in
canabinoid research so this was what I
met but in
Czechoslovakia Professor Karachi history
1950 when he discovered
antibiotical principle so we start to
use it in medicine and it was used up to
1990 when I left for one year to Israel
what is 25 28 years ago
so it became illegal even then from 1961
it was
illegal drug we use it without any
problem
for treatment of patients in hospital I
I prepared extracts 20 years to the
drugstore and they prepared medicine for
hospital without any problem we
cultivated cannabis without fence I
never lost one leaf if we cultivated on
the same spot today overnight there will
be no cannabis and before patients were
retreated without any problem
today cannabis is legal in Czech
Republic five years
and they use only five kilogram in five
years in the fact it's not accessible
for patients and something like sativas
which is allowed it's not accessible
because it's more expensive than its
tension of old ill person so I see
certain problem here because illegality
became like a harder harder pressure on
that than than before and today
situation is worse but you are
associated I know that you travel to a
lot of East European countries you have
been in uh
almost all the small countries in
Eastern Europe and what's the situation
there the best situation is today we had
several seminars in Macedonia
cannabis
for treatment is illegal since last year
the most
medicinal compound is considered THC
it's strange that CBD is not considered
like medicine like this is concept like
supportive compound Maine is THC so
there can be extracts without any limit
of
THC contents in the sample
I was many times in Slovenia even we had
seminar in Parliament
it's still illegal the same in Serbia in
Croatia where we had seminars several
times it's still illegal just only
Macedonia
better situation maybe is in Austria
because there are they sell CBD
extracts
like five pair Center ten percent CBD
you can buy it without any problem it's
legal
in Czechoslovakia I said it was used for
treatment today in Slovakia what is
separate country today everything is
illegal
cannabis CBD everything is illegal like
in the United States so situation
between Czech Republic and Slovak
Republic it's quite a different and in
Czechoslovakia mainly cannabis was
cultivated in Slovakia
today
well in the U.S of course things are
different because you have one stated
cannaby diode can be freely sold and so
on another one when it's illegal so if
you have one gram of cannaby dial in
your pocket on this side of the border
state border not yes country border
state border you're fine you you just
walk at 10 meters so past the frontier
then you can go to prison for five years
so the same that doesn't make much sense
but that's the situation the same is
this alcohol when I was in the United
States there was County
but I was it was prohibited to buy
alcohol
but one meter after the border of this
County
was liquor store and you can buy it so
so chances are that things will change
within the next couple of years we shall
have most probably
plant material
basically cannabi dial and derivatives
which come from the plant but companies
will develop derivatives and derivatives
will be sold you see
the natural products are not always sold
because of various reasons
let's look at penicillin you cannot buy
penicillin in the drugstore penicillin
is not available as a drug
you have derivatives of penicillin
chances are that we shall have the same
with cannabis but because of the wide
use of plant cannabis you will have
plant cannabis sold for many years and
you will also have derivatives of mostly
cannabidiol and there you are so you
have two different types of drugs in
fact we need a lot of experimental
studies and trials clinical trials
because up to now whenever I prepared
the derivatives of cannabis
it was like successful but at the end it
was not successful yes only I think
nabilon is used but not the other one
except of that I use just cannabis
extracts like dronabino Marino this is
THC or epideolx what is CBD but others
like was one derivative for obesity
and then patients were depressed even
commit suicide so it's not such easy to
prepare derivative it's very
we cannot do it at the University this
can do only Rich pharmaceutical
companies and chances about five percent
and they must
use spent tens of millions of dollars
for yeah so it's not also such easy for
pharmaceutical companies well I hope it
will change we as you well know we work
now with three or four companies in
different aspects
they are spending their money in order
to advance cannabinoid research and to
advance cannabinoid drugs ultimately
hopefully they will succeed
I hope also because you had from the
time when I came to the university and I
I heard of your name for the first time
you had so many wonderful ideas and some
of them up to now were not fulfilled
because of illegality yeah well there we
are I hope that uh
you did you didn't tell us the last word
still I am sure that your continual
contributions will be wonderful and that
uh thank you it will help your patience
wait what kind of ideas that have not
been fulfilled
well uh
the development of many of the synthetic
compounds which are known to to be
pretty good
in animals they have not Advanced to
clinical trials as a matter of fact the
schizophrenia trial which was then
obviously in human patients and so on
has not Advanced cannabi dial to be
accepted as an
anti-schizophrenic drug which is very
strange but that's what's going on
chances are the derivatives will will be
better accepted we have made derivatives
of cannabidiol which are
better than cannabis itself so chances
are that sometime within the next decade
who knows uh
cannabinoid drugs will be on the market
and will be widely used what's a
derivative
well we have published for example
cannot be done with the fluorine
atom on on the cannabidiol molecule so
it's a fluoro cannaby dial we have
published that in collaboration with the
group in South America we have shown
that it is uh pretty good in anxiety
lowering anxiety pretty good in acting
on
other psychiatric diseases
we have shown that cannabidiol itself is
pretty good in these things we have
recently shown that another derivative
which is a derivative of the acid of
cannabidiol uh helps with the depression
so chances are that at some point some
of these compounds will
will become
major drugs you see depression and
anxiety for example a major diseases in
Western Society
a huge number huge
percentages of the population have
anxiety or depression on and off
and we need compounds that do not cause
side effects we need simple compounds or
compound data we well one doesn't have
to be
anxious taking the compounds against
anxiety what is what is the role of
anecdotal
um evidence in in this research
well anecdotal is
according to the work anecdotal I mean
you have a person in uh in Paraguay who
knows where saying that it helps against
a certain disease that he has which is
well uh
academic person will say that's an
interesting observation but until we
have a clinical trial it's just
anecdotal I mean well maybe this person
by chance was getting a better anyway
and he took the drug and well maybe
the the drug has nothing to do with is
getting better we are we have to have
well-established clinical trials but is
there a moment where anecdotal stuff
becomes more than just one one story
that's not useful is it well we can base
our work
an anecdotal data but it will never in a
modern society never make a drug make a
compound become a drug
just on the basis of anecdotal evidence
one needs clinical trials without the
clinical trials a new drug will not be
accepted not but in the FDA it will
still be an extract an anecdotal cases
is also a problem
that even if it was successful this
patient don't know which type of
cannabis they use if it was high THC or
high CBD and so on and I won't return to
this what was not fulfilled professor
michelam already mentioned it that 35
years ago they did legal research this
group from Brazil and they found that
epilepsy can be treated with CBD nothing
happened it was supposed to be a regular
case or officially by the law illegal
case that parents treated child
rich
color piece
and they found that it can create this
drawer syndrome for this heart type of
epilepsy and then it was fulfilled what
was ideal already 35 years ago and this
was legal idea and was supposed to be
illegal
practice just to fulfill
I'll give you and this is the last
example
we have about a hundred
autoimmune diseases about 10 of them are
very Central autoimmune diseases
Diabetes Type 1 rheumatoid arthritis
many other diseases are
autoimmune diseases our body attacks
itself
and most definitely cannabidiol has been
found to act
very positively in autoimmune diseases
as a matter of fact uh
group here at the Berlin Hospital looked
at something that is more or less like
an outer immune disease in many cancer
patients
uh
one has to exchange
part of the body the bone marrow with
bone marrow from outside but the body
doesn't like bone marrow from the
outside and he attacks the bone marrow
the new bone marrow and the new bone
marrow attacks the body and the patient
is sick it has to be done because there
is nothing else that can be done with
these cancer patients but many of them
are sick and this is called graft versus
cold disease which is an autoimmune
disease more or less well a group with
batism thought I was a little bit
involved with them I'll group it
Bailey's in hospital thought that maybe
as cannabidiolis and autoimmune disease
drug let's give them cannabidiol they
gave them cannabidiol and the results
were outstanding it definitely helps in
graft versus host disease so a company
has taken up now this particular
information by the Bellington hospital
and their developing canopy dial as a
drug in the case of graft versus host
disease so chances are that we'll have a
canopy dial as a drug
hopefully again within the next three
four five years in this particular case
cancer being treated
after bone marrow
with canopy dial
okay that was great thank you you're
most welcome okay