first of all I'd like to thank the can
Med
advisory panel to give me this
opportunity to share our study
so first of all I'd like to to share
what was the purpose of this study
to understand the status of cannabis
microbial testing regulations in all U.S
states and territories then second
to identify Trends in microbial testing
rules since 2019 and to identify a
consensus set of required microbial
testing rules to lower public health
risks
now everyone knows what the federal
perspective of cannabis is but there are
individuals from other countries first
the use sale and possessions is illegal
under federal law
is considered a schedule one drug under
the federal controlled substance Act
and also and schedule one drugs are
considered to have no accepted Medical
use a high potential for abuse and
physical and or psychological dependence
so where is cannabis legal in the United
States and this is as of January 2023 so
highlighted in Gold 21 states and two
territories have both
legal adult use and medical cannabis
programs highlighted in green There are
16 states that have medical cannabis
only that also that would be two
additional territories so the total
number of jurisdictions the United
States is 42.
this slide shows the methods of our
study first we reviewed all the current
Cannabis Testing rules
then we updated our microbial testing
regulations for each jurisdiction
[Music]
and the two full size we had was
required microbial tests for each
jurisdiction and the corresponding
Action level for each test for each
product type and there's four product
types flower
concentrates Edibles and non-edibles and
the web link where you can find all this
information updated to the present is
shown in the slide
so from this data set we determine for
each test the number of jurisdiction
requiring each test
the number of each Action level for each
test and the number of unique microbial
test combinations for flour and edibles
but this afternoon I'll only be showing
you the data for the flower testing
then we perform two sets of comparative
analysis first within the 2023 data sets
for testing flour and edibles
and also what or on a comparative
analysis between a 2019 database and in
our present 2023 database to see the
direction of where microbial testing is
occurring in the United States
so here are some general observations
concerning the required microbial
testing regulations in the U.S
the bottom line is it's a mess
there's 22 different microbial tests
that are required by at least one
jurisdiction
and they fall into three categories the
first category is
is total count tests there's six of them
and I have four examples total aerobic
bacteria total yeast and molds total
coliforms and total biotolerant
gram-negative bacteria
and then there are four
tests where specific genuses any species
so these first two types of tests I'm
not a proponent of requiring this
testing because an enumeration of these
two kinds of tests provides me with no
information
whether there's any pathogenic
microorganisms in my sample and I might
get a fail a failure in my sample then
the last type are these there's 12
specific genus species tests
in
in the literature in the clinical
literature
I have
five five examples here we have the four
pathogenic aspergillus species that's
aspergillus flavus fumigatus Niger
antarius
and sugar toxin producing E coli one of
six pathotypes where this one is the
most pathogenic
now interestingly of all the
jurisdictions the number of microbial
tests required was a wide range
Winter's fiction has just one test
required
in a few States as many as 10 tests
so an example of the sole state in the
United States that only requires one
state is total I mean is Arkansas is the
absence of total coliforms but anyone
can Google this and not all colon forms
of pathogenic so you might
get a film but are there any pathogenic
coliforms in the sample I don't know and
then Connecticut is over the top where
they have the six specific pathogens
that have described including also
salmonella species but also four total
count tests
now the action there's no consensus is
even in the action thresholds and the
widest range for the total count tests
is the total Eastern mold
on the low end is it's three orders of
magnitude and the low ends the thousand
colony forming units
program of sample and on the high end is
10 to the fifth
and for all the genus and the genus
species test it's always non-detect
now this slide describes the status of
the microbial testing rules for flowers
in the start of this year so if you
focus on the second row I've already
mentioned the 42 jurisdictions have
legal programs but three of the
jurisdictions being three of the
territories have no testing rules to
date
now there's actually 41 sets of
microbial testing rules because two
states Arizona and New York have
separate testing rules
for adults and medical use
so what we have is 13 of these states
share three common testing rule sets we
have what's commonly known as the
California model which are the six
pathogens that salmonella species sugar
toxin producing E coli and the four
pathogenic aspergillus species
three states have tacked on tourist and
mold
and then Six States still utilize the
archaic American herbal pharmacopoeia
model that came out in 2014
which are four total count tests a total
aerobic
touriston Mall total coliforms
biotolerant gremnig the bacteria and one
nonsensical rule
pathogenic E coli
please correct me if I'm wrong but I
have not ever found a single test
utilizing any technology that can detect
all six pathotypes of E coli
and so I've asked lab directors what do
you do oh we test for sugar toxin
producing E coli that's what they do
um
so what we have the bottom line is shown
in the lower right
is that there's some chaos here still
there's 29 unique test combinations in
the United States and so there's still
quite a bit of Chaos
now what we have is I'd like to share
with you the trends over the last three
years in terms of the total count tests
and the specific human pathogens and
this slide is the total count test and
the bottom line is that there's a trend
towards decrease in the fraction of the
jurisdictions asking for this test so
the top line is the total aerobic
bacteria and total microbial count
whereby
over the three-year period it has the
fraction of jurisdictions has decreased
from 67 percent to 44 percent and that
being a change of 23 percent the total
Eastern mold they're hanging on for dear
life
whereby it's decreased from 74 to 63 a
decrease in 11 and then the third line
total coliforms they're hanging on to
that one too but it's a lower percentage
of the fraction as of 2023 and it's 37
percent a decrease in four percent and
the ball tolerant gram-negative bacteria
have decreased the most down to 32
percent of the jurisdictions was a
decrease of almost 40 percent
now what we have now is the specific
pathogen test and where this shows
a trending in in my mind the correct
direction towards consensus as a
beginning point so we have salmonella
species so it's already 85 percent but
additional states have seen the light
and now all jurisdictions except two
require salmonella testing
and then for the pathogenic E coli that
nonsensical rule
has now decreased to 27 percent of the
jurisdictions a decrease in 17 percent
and this is the indication that
Regulators are being educated that this
is the rule that can't be met
and so until a method developer develops
a test
that can detect all six pathotypes
I feel that the most pathogenic one
should be tested for that being sugar
toxin producing E coli and there has
been a dramatic increase to 44 percent
of the jurisdictions which was an
increase in 29 percent and sorry for the
typo on the aspergillus pathogens have
increased also dramatically
uh to over half 56 percent of the
jurisdictions an increase of 26 percent
and I have collected 23 clinical case
publications of individuals uh acquiring
or becoming sick with aspergillosis
affiliated with cannabis use
so yeah I have a very short talk
so where might we go from here
the six specific pathogens that are
required in the California model are not
all the human pathogens in cannabis
flowers I'll be the first to admit that
so how do we identify these additional
human pathogens
which would lead to a possible creation
of a consensus set of microbial testing
rules
to be considered by the by the federal
government
and so This research study is a massive
study it's more in my brain
so this would be a national cannabis
flower microbiome study so every legal
jurisdiction
that has legal cannabis one would
determine a statistically significant
number of cannabis flowers which is a
minimum of 400
then they would be sampled in the
different regions of the jurisdiction
noting
what type of cultivation was used
outdoor indoor Hydroponics or forth and
so on and the actual technology has
already been developed so one does a
direct DNA extraction from the flower
the second step
is the amplification of that DNA for
both the bacteria the yeast and the
fungi
so the sequences that you amplify for
the bacteria are the 16s ribosomal genes
and for the yeast and molds it's called
the its sequences
so one has all this DNA now that you've
Amplified and then you do sequencing of
this DNA and there's now nanopore
technology developed by Oxford uh the
Oxford technology company where the
sequencer is a little bit bigger than a
than a flash drive and the computer is
quite little and you can buy one and
play with it for six thousand dollars
and then you have to contract or have
in-house about informatics expert and
believe it or not we've already done
this at mgc
is that you can identify every genus and
species in that cannabis flower
and also you can
determine the relative amount so now you
have all this massive information
it's a lot
so what do you do with it and I don't
have the full answer of the composition
of the stakeholders group
I don't
but I know that we need infectious
disease doctors they know we need to
have clinical microbiologists
and also a clinical I mean risk
assessment experts just because you have
a human pathogen and cannabis flowers if
it's at a super low amount
does not necessarily mean that you have
to add it to the list but if you find or
identify
human pathogens at high levels in this
in a number of flowers throughout the
country then you want to keep it in the
list
and then literature search experts are
very very important because they can do
massive literature searches to see what
are the
microbial species that are
human pathogens which ones are
opportunistic pathogens and so forth and
so on and then through just dialogue
they identify identification of
additional subject matter experts that
could be included in this dialogue and
from all this big data set one can then
determine a consensus set for microbial
testing rules for a state for a region
of the United States or the whole
country I don't know how this is going
to come out
um and I hope to see I'm sharing this
slide simply to plant the seed for
people to consider from now into the
future and hopefully the study will be
conducted in a stepwise manner until we
covered the entire country
and I'd like to acknowledge the
individuals who helped me in this
massive project Donna Street Nair Donna
Street pawar and sravine
who updated the database and created all
the data sets and summer Hall helped me
visualize some of the data in this last
slide
I have my email up there if you want to
ask me any questions I mean email me to
continue this dialogue and at this time
I'd like to entertain any questions
thank you
and I kept my talk short
hi Sherman
um Hey Joe I I never dreamed anyone can
make a talk about regulations so
exciting it was really great
um I wanted to ask you
um I've talked to a couple of people
with history working in the USDA
and they have told me about a lot of
you know uh I guess uh institutional
knowledge about agricultural pathogens
um our
is there still information that's kind
of
um known from other crops that we're
missing here that we could use to kind
of have a better guess of what what to
look for
well the thing is that you mentioned the
USDA and
you know I I worked in public health and
in environmental chemistry and in our
laboratory in New Jersey we had some
interaction
uh with the Department of Agriculture
um and again that's thank you very much
for pointing that out to me I really
have not had the opportunity to ask them
in terms of I know that they focus on
the on the plant pathogens but with all
the information and all the experience
they've had I'm sure they've identified
some human pathogens so I think it would
be a good source
of information yeah like you should look
into like Berry sorter's lung and Rose
Grower's thumb there are a bunch of them
that are known especially from
agricultural occupation
um and uh there is quite a lot of
information out there right okay we'll
talk about that thank you
so any other questions
thank you very much for listening thank
you