[Music]
um welcome to
the canmed coffee talk podcast where we
talk with the leading minds in cannabis
science medicine cultivation
and safety testing i am your host ben
ameralt
the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canned med conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now to learn all about
our canmed 2021 event that will take
place
april 12th through 14th at the pasadena
convention center
in pasadena california and get your
tickets today
at our special early bird rate while
you're at canned events dot com
be sure to sign up for email alerts to
stay up to date with all the news
surrounding
this industry-leading event
the best place to sign up for those
alerts is on our podcast page
which you can find in the main menu
under the media tab
you can also go there directly via
kments.com
coffeetalk there's a sign up form on
that page and if you complete it you
will be entered into a drawing to win
two cammed 2021 vip dinner tickets
on this episode i got to speak with dr
marion mcnabb
who is the president of the cannabis
center of excellence
and ceo of cannabis community care and
research network
marion is a public health doctor by
training
and has nearly 20 years of global and
domestic public health experience
her team recently completed a veterans
health and medical cannabis research
study
with the goal of gathering information
from u.s military veterans
regarding their current health
conditions conventional medical
treatments
medical cannabis use and its
effectiveness with self-reported health
conditions and symptoms
we talked a lot about the veteran study
as well as other public health topics
related to medical cannabis
including how military veterans use
cannabis to treat a variety of
conditions to reduce dependence on other
medications
what barriers veterans face when trying
to access medical cannabis
what programs have been established to
assist veterans with the cost of
cannabis medicine
how does veterans use of medical
cannabis compared to the general
population
how has the coven 19 pandemic changed
cannabis
use in terms of frequency purchasing
habits and conditions
how implementing proper testing led to
the eventual lift of the vape ban
in massachusetts and how the vote to
legalize adult use cannabis in new
jersey
affects the issues of public health
social justice
and advocacy in that state
but before we get to that conversation i
do want to thank this episode's sponsor
cannabis science and technology cannabis
science and technology
is proud to present a special supplement
and free
virtual veterans day e-symposium focused
on medical cannabis treatment for
veterans with ptsd
the supplement and symposium will
feature dr marian mcnabb
and the data she uncovered in her 2019
veterans health
and medical cannabis study in addition
the supplement will include
articles with dr stacy gruber veteran
patient stephen
mandeel a va caregiver a nurse
and medical cannabis advocates all
heavily involved with this topic
the e-symposium will also feature a
special panel discussion
organized by stephen mandiel with the
group of veterans from across the
country
go to cannabissciencetech.com
to learn more
and finally it wouldn't be the canmed
coffee talk podcast
without the hemp in coffee exchange if
you don't know hemp coffee
is a healthy delicious natural product
rich in trace minerals
and nutrients providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee
for more information check out hemp
coffee exchange dot com
and use the promo code drink hemp to get
off your purchase okay as promised
here is my conversation with dr marion
[Music]
mcnabb
good afternoon marion thanks for joining
us good afternoon ben thanks for having
me
of course uh and i'm really interested
to talk with you today because
many of our guests on the podcast we've
had so far and really a lot of the
presenters
that we have in canmed in sort of the
medical area
really speak from a clinician's
perspective you know sharing their
experiences and their successes
but the work that you're planning to
share at canmed is really
more focused on the patient's
perspective which i'll admit
unfortunately isn't a perspective we
near
we hear nearly enough at canmed so
that's why i'm really interested to talk
with you
about that um so i guess
instead of me telling you what you're
presenting on
i want to give you the opportunity to
kind of tell us and the audience
about the data you've collected and what
you'll be sharing at cam at
yeah thank you and i'm really excited
and honored to
be presenting next year at canmed um so
what the work that we did last year i'm
a
public health doctor by training so more
of a population level
um researcher um so
last year i partnered with stephen
mandile uh
and anne brum of joint venture and co to
to launch the 2019 veterans health and
medical cannabis study
so this study was designed to
understand from a veteran's perspective
using through an anonymous survey
how veterans what are the current health
conditions that they face
what are the current treatments that
they
are you know using to address their
health conditions and symptoms
and then ask further about their medical
cannabis use
and uh how biomedical cannabis use has
impacted their life from a variety of
perspectives
um so we uh partnered also together with
umass dartmouth the study was approved
by
by their irb and we had about
an eight month uh data collection period
and captured data from 565 veterans
nationally but majority of the focus of
our
outreach and work was in massachusetts
so around half of our sample size is
from massachusetts
excellent and what data from this survey
really stood out to you or perhaps what
information is really sort of the the
take-home message
that the folks should know about it yeah
so
uh great question um well one of the
most
uh interesting things was to learn uh
what
health conditions veterans were using
medical cannabis most commonly for
and those out of the reported sample uh
38 of veterans report uh using medical
cannabis to address chronic pain
as their top health condition followed
by 25
uh reporting medical cannabis is helpful
for ptsd
and nine percent uh reporting uh their
top condition using medical cannabis for
is anxiety
um and so if we look at chronic pain
ptsd and anxiety is
as some of the top conditions uh we do
and i will present at canmed some
further data about
each of those conditions and their
medical cannabis consumption
but one of the most striking data points
that we found in this study is
the amount of veterans that are using
medical cannabis to reduce
unwanted over-the-counter medications or
prescription medications related to
their health conditions
so in fact out of our entire sample of
78 report using medical cannabis to
actively reduce the use of
over-the-counter or prescription
medications so
from a public health perspective when
you step back
and look at this um you know there's
never been a documented
death or lethal overdose with cannabis
but there has been documented um you
know
really unwanted side effects and the
possibility of overdose with a lot of
the medications that veterans are
commonly
um which i think i recently read a study
that
uh reviewed i don't know over 10 000
uh veterans uh records and found that
often they're prescribed
you know somewhere between 40 and 50
medications um
so the understanding the medical
cannabis is being reported by veterans
as a
alternative and actively trying to
reduce the use of
unwanted medications is pretty striking
wow and now are there sort of
barriers to veterans getting access
to this cannabis medicine absolutely um
so we ask
uh what are some of the major barriers
um
for accessing and actually 51 report
money to purchase products that they
want
41 percent lack access to the actual
right
products for their conditions uh 32
report uh they don't have the money
required to get a medical card
um followed by stigma at 30 owning a
firearm
at 29 and then workplace testing
um at 24 so um we also
asked you know about how much money that
veterans are spending right so
our top barriers are money to purchase
products access to the right products
which is market related
and then money to get a medical card um
when we ask how much money are you
spending per month
on your over-the-counter or prescription
medications
and then how much money are you spending
per month on medical cannabis
and uh nationally on average veterans
spend
98 dollars a month on out-of-pocket
expenses for prescription
over-the-counter meds
but they spend 343 a month on medical
cannabis
wow so without having you know
understanding that it's being used as an
alternative medical cannabis is not
covered by insurance
yet you know also the majority of our
veterans in our sample
are getting their prescriptions mailed
directly to them from the va
so you know the you know you could just
really tease out
um you know cost is a major a major
barrier
um however you know um
so there's you know examples of um i
believe in canada
um they're starting to provide um you
know free or low cost access
to medical cannabis for veterans and you
know in massachusetts stephen mandela
who i've worked with on the study
um and events last year he partners with
dispensaries to
um you know share this information and
to offer uh
40 off discount for 100 disabled
veterans
so you know the use of this information
um i think is really important that's
one of the
areas of of research that i'm most
engaged with is not only conducting
studies and collecting
data but then how do you actually use
that data for policy change or to
implement programs
or um you know
yeah provide access so
um yeah and i think the the other
barrier um that i
i think is quite interesting um
is the owning a firearm right
and because that's a federal uh
regulation i think
you know that's that's also something
that you know is unique to this
population
yeah that one sort of jumped out to me
as well because
i mean one would assume that veterans
are probably more likely to own a
firearm than maybe your average citizen
but
so what is it about um
about owning a firearm that makes access
to cannabis difficult
um and massachusetts i am not entirely
sure about other states but
um you know i mean you know i'm not sure
how enforced this is but you um
cannot have a firearm if you are trying
to get a medical card
yeah so
one of the um one of the other really
interesting findings
uh from the study was actually so we now
see that you know veterans are using
medical cannabis for variety of their
health conditions they're wanting to use
it as an alternative treatment
but one of the challenges specifically
for veterans is that you know they
um can access private care but they also
access care through the va
and because the va is federally funded
um you know va clinicians are restricted
um from either becoming recommenders of
medical cannabis
um you know and uh
you know basically don't have access to
a lot of high quality education around
where the state of the science is for
medical cannabis
um so and the reason i think this is
really important
is because these veterans are working to
you know get access to an alternative
treatment and
you know it's important for them to
discuss this with their healthcare
providers
um and so right now policy at the va is
that
um you know the clinicians and the
veterans are allowed to
um you know discuss about their medical
cannabis use they won't lose benefits
and that will be recorded in their
medical record but the clinician
isn't allowed to advise on you know
types dosages and et cetera et cetera um
or even really
you know engage with it so we ask um the
veterans in our study
you know how how many i mean uh is your
va doctor
or clinical care provider aware about
your medical cannabis use
and 60 said yes and then we ask
is your va doctor or health care
provider
uh supportive of your cannabis use and
said they don't know indicating it's not
this clinical
discussion happening right um they've
maybe informed the doctor
um but you know they're not discussing
you know they don't know if
their clinician approves its use um
so that's i think also another barrier
to really finding what the right dose
what the right
um you know products
um dosages etc for for veterans
uh for medical cannabis
yeah that's unfortunate and
unfortunately in
my other conversations with other health
care providers that
that's not an issue that's really
exclusive to veterans unfortunately
there's a lot of
there's a lot of citizens out there who
who feel they could benefit from medical
cannabis but
there's just so few clinicians who are
who are well-educated and can really
provide that guidance
um so that is certainly a challenge but
it was
encouraging to to hear you say that um
sort of in the absence
of the va giving benefits or
or giving access to medical cannabis
that
some of the dispensaries were stepping
up and providing discounted products
to them i think that's really
encouraging and i wonder
and this is probably something you've
already looked into but is there any
chance that
you know private doctors or one or
cannabis doctors
specifically would be willing to sort of
provide guidance to
this population at a discounted rate or
even perhaps for free
yeah that's uh that's a very um
interesting question and i think some
some providers out there
are giving us sometimes free discounts
for a special but you know for a short
period of time
or definitely discounted discounts for
medical cards
um we actually used the study under the
leadership of steve last year
we used the data from the study to
advocate for a bill in the massachusetts
state house
to mimic a program similar to what's in
illinois where
you know the veteran has already been
diagnosed with conditions by the va
and to have that paperwork used as an
evidence
that would be required to get a medical
card so reducing the
need to purchase so
we did introduce that use this data to
support that the bill did not go through
um this year but changes will be made
and
um you know going to try in the next
session um
but i think it's a really you know
important
aspect to have that medical cannabis
specialist
sort of guidance and help for
veterans um i don't know anybody that
is providing absolutely free ongoing
services um but that would be great if
they were
absolutely and i guess another thing
that that sort of stood out was
you're saying that so many of these
veterans are trying to use cannabis
to sort of um either replace
or help reduce the amount of other
medications that they're using but
the cost is being is sort of the uh
the barrier there so that's it just
seems so unfortunate that
um that that has to be that has to be
the case because i think we all could
agree that
um they would definitely benefit from uh
from reducing that
yeah um and actually i i led another
study prior to this one in 2018 that
looked at over
two thousand we had over two thousand
respondents it was uh open cannabis
consumer and patient study
um so general population and we found
very similar findings over seventy
percent
of people in that study of over two
thousand sample we're also using
cannabis to
reduce prescription over-the-counter
medications um and i think this is just
an extremely important
uh public health you know reality that
we have to look at
um you know if you're you have a legal
safe
alternative um treatment that's
available
i i think it's a public health right to
make sure that that's accessible
um but the other interesting parts in
the veterans study and in the consumer
study that
that we ran is that
they also report reducing the use of
alcohol and tobacco
much less now with the use of cannabis
so if you think about this it's like
almost a
harm reduction method for a variety of
substances that
you know are uh more lethal
um so you know it's not only medications
it's medications tobacco alcohol
um in addition to both physical and
psychological
relief so yeah and i'm glad you brought
up that
that survey because i was looking at
that data as well and really one of the
things that jumped out to me and it
seemed to be
almost the same percentage on the
veterans study too was that
80 of the respondents said that using
cannabis
just generally helps their quality of
life which
um and that was sort of the top response
for
you know sort of how cannabis impacts
their daily lives and
it seems to um to ring true with what
you just said you know if you're using
cannabis and you're just generally
feeling better that you're probably less
likely to
to be resorting to some of those
destructive behaviors
yep yep yeah or finding you know it's a
it's a better alternative
definitely definitely um
and so i wondered were there any other
kind of interesting
correlations or maybe even some
interesting differences sort of
comparing the the
data from the veteran survey to the sort
of more open study
yeah so the consumer and patient study
um
uh and the veterans study i think one of
the differences
is in the top conditions um so in the
veterans study
more veterans express you know report
having ptsd
um and uh so i think you know that's one
major difference we see similarities
in you know like we just talked about um
in the medication reduction um
you know and there's and i think you
know differences a little bit
and smoke and preferred methods and
preferred time of day
um interestingly we have you know i
think these populations also
in the veterans study we had about
half or over half of the respondents
were
over the age of 65. um
if i've got that right let me just check
on myself um
so uh you know that's a pretty
um like a substantially older population
versus what we had in our other studies
so
um but you know you give me the idea i
want to dig in further
and really try and um tease out those
differences maybe i'll write a blog and
i'll make sure
to send it to everybody who's listening
yeah that'd be great and be
happy to share it with the audience and
um if you do publish it before this
uh this episode goes live i'd be happy
to put it in the show notes so people
have a
quick way to get to it um one of the
things that stood out to me
and you sort of touched on it there um
was that i think this was at least
in the um the more open study that 54
of respondents said that smoking flour
was their primary method of consuming
cannabis
and then there was another question that
sort of asked for their preferred method
where they could select
multiple different ones and still
smoking flour was
um was the top choice at 79 percent
and maybe it's just because i'm more
in the industry and aware of all the
different types of cannabis products
that are out there whether it be vapes
or edibles or tinctures or patches
um that it's it's interesting to see
that you know smoking flour
is still so such a dominant um
preferred method and i was wondering if
you had any thoughts on that is that
sort of just because
it's sort of the easiest one to access
or the most
widely known one i didn't know if you
had any thoughts on that yeah it's a
really good question
um so in both of these studies
um they you know we focused heavily on
the massachusetts market although they
were national
it was convenient sampling approach and
anybody nationally could take the study
but we did targeted outreach in
massachusetts and i think it might be
because of the nature of
um the industry at that time
and you know the availability of
products um
and not having as many now you know uh
that we do have now or could have in the
future or even the diversity of products
and other markets outside of
massachusetts i think is much greater
than
than what's available here so maybe it's
a factor of that
product availability um because we see
that you know access to the right
products was one of the barriers for the
veterans study
um so maybe they want vapes and edibles
and you know
it's too far away or only one um you
know
dispensary offers it or that kind of
stuff um
i also think it's probably also you know
it's just a very common you know people
are traditionally very used to smoking
flour
and if people are new
into cannabis now um i think it can be
intimidating to do some of the other
methods of administration you know um
maybe they're unfamiliar maybe needs to
be more patient education around that so
people gravitate towards you know
simple flower you know i know that you
know when i walked into the dispensary
the first time
i you know i'm a consumer i'm a patient
and
but i was intimidated to ask questions
and this and that you know
um so i think you know it's uh
probably accent you know availability in
the market
um awareness about how to consume those
other methods
uh comfortability and consuming those
other types
you know etc yeah and
maybe one thing that sort of struck me
as as you were answering there is
could there perhaps be a correlation
between the method of administration and
sort of the
um the symptoms that they're looking to
elimi alleviate
exactly i think that's a great point you
know um
like whether or not you're using a
tincture or an rso
or a flower i mean you know all of those
by by condition
i think people definitely probably if
they're you know very committed to
learning how to dial in their dosage and
everything that they need you know
um what's interesting too is so um
you know we've run these two studies the
open consumer and then the veterans
health and earlier this year
together with umass dartmouth launched
the coven 19
medical cannabis and consumer study that
i'm running right now
and so we launched that study and we
have several partners in
massachusetts and
really looking at the impact of coven 19
on
uh patients and consumers so again you
know what are they consuming for what
health condition or symptom
how much and how has this changed during
coven um
and i'm just trying to pull up the data
now but um
you know speaking of you know cannabis
consumption methods
um let's see let me
let me find it here um we did ask has
you know because of covid have you um
you know switched has your cannabis use
changed basically
uh interestingly uh that 14
said that they switched their preferred
method for consuming cannabis
um which i think is really really
interesting um and
47 percent stated that they consume
cannabis more now since cova 19 started
uh and only 11 say they consume cannabis
less now
so yeah people are consuming more
cannabis um they're also reporting
you know uh using cannabis uh for top
health conditions differently than the
other studies
um i think now we're living in an
environment of covid which is
heightened anxiety um also just
heightened
um risk for people who have underlying
health conditions
like medical cannabis patients um you
know so i think
you know medical cannabis patients are i
think should be considered a vulnerable
population right now
um within the epidemic um or the
pandemic
so um yeah i uh and they're also still
reporting
in our copa 19 study uh replacing
the use of alcohol or prescription
medications
uh with the use of cannabis
wow so that's interesting um what other
questions
are you are you asking as part of this
this survey
so uh we asked how has covered 19
impacted your purchasing
habits um and
about 40 um report that it has
um one couldn't access legal
recreational cannabis
now a 14 reported now since covet they
purchased cannabis in the
illicit market our unregulated market
uh 12 now only order for a curbside
pickup
10 reported they got a they registered
to get a medical cannabis card
um and that's you know quite interesting
um the other uh questions that we ask
are you know the top health conditions
etc but what are the barriers
again to purchasing uh to accessing
cannabis
uh both pre and postcovid and
access to the right products is the top
barrier and that's increased since covet
started
and then money to obtain cannabis
products has also increased
since covet started um very interesting
uh stigma has decreased as a barrier
place consumed cannabis has decreased as
a bear
money required to get a medical card
decreased as a barrier
um and so did a lack of health care
provider involvement
um yeah yeah uh really interesting
yeah and so what does that compare to um
is that compared to the the study that
you did in
2018 or uh we asked in the survey
pre-covered what were your barriers and
what are your barriers
interesting yeah yeah and to rate their
top barriers
um very interesting um we also asked
about
covid infection um eight percent
of the respondents reported they were
infected with covet and received the
results
11 uh respondents i think they have
covid but they can't access a test
and 13 report they have current symptoms
of coping
so all of this is very interesting um
because of the
emerging evidence around cannabis cbd
terpenes cannabinoid profiles that are
coming out right now
um from a variety of research
institutions related to the impact of
cannabis on covent right by interrupting
the cytokine storm at the
end stage or you know different
researchers are looking at
uh either thc or cbd or a combination of
different
again cannabinoids and terpenes and how
they may actually
be a possible prevention measure
um so it's quite interesting uh
data that's coming out of you know
israel and canada
and south carolina and georgia
and other other universities um
university of miami
um so as part of this study we've
actually
i'm organizing an event to be held
in december around covet and cannabis
and where is the research
and standing at that point and then also
from a clinical perspective
to really lead an engaging virtual event
that will i've invited several several
of these researchers to present some of
their preliminary findings
uh some clinicians and then we'll have a
nice uh discussion at the end about
the state of the evidence around this
and and kind of what's what's the latest
that sounds excellent and i don't want
to invite ourselves but
i know that some of the uh the folks on
our team
here have uh been looking into
to covet and cannabis more on the
testing side to to make sure that we
have sort of a
testing assay to
measure if there's any any covid on
cannabis products
to sort of protect consumer safety
i will i will say we've seen no evidence
of that in the marketplace that that's
out there
um and the main reason that our cso
kevin mckernan felt it
important to uh to create this test was
more so because um one of one of the
encouraging signs
of the pandemic was that in many states
um they deemed cannabis to be
essential which i think we can all agree
was the right move to make but
one of the concerns that we had here was
that if
for whatever reason there ever was covet
found
on cannabis that would completely shut
down the supply chain
and you know so many of these patients
wouldn't have access to their medicine
so in order to prevent that we wanted to
make sure that there was a test
available that
should should that become an issue that
the testing labs could run
to make sure that you know medical
cannabis is still
is still functioning so thankfully we
had
thankfully there really hasn't been a
need for that but it's something that we
felt very strongly about
and um like i said i know that
if you gave him the chance that kevin
would be more than happy to
uh to take part in your event yeah i
would love it i think that's really
interesting
um and i you know thank you all for that
because that would have been a disaster
to say you know i could have really shut
down uh
oh yeah and put you know patience at
risk so
thank you guys for leading that work and
definitely i would love kevin to be part
of this event
yeah and speaking of sort of um
maybe there being a band that that took
medicine away from patients i know that
when i was doing my research on
on the many things that you're involved
in that you were involved in sort of
advocating
here in massachusetts to lift the vape
ban that had been uh that had been
implemented after
um there was that the vape scare where a
lot of people were getting sick there
so i was wondering if if you'd like to
speak a bit about that since
it seems like a nice segue yeah yeah so
um last year uh there was sweeping cases
of a valley um going across the united
states um
so the you know sort of uh issues around
um potentially contaminated products or
really just a lack of understanding
about what was causing
a valley um and governor baker took very
swift action
to ban vapes in massachusetts
um i had looked at this issue
in terms of i just scientifically
started look from an epidemiological
perspective
where were the cases where they be
reporting you know is this coming from
tobacco vapes versus coming from
uh thc vapes um and just trying to
start to dig into whatever i could find
online
um and really you know uh at that time
also very quickly uh mcr labs put
together the vitamin e acetate test
um to start testing products so we
actually work together on the
um you know trying to figure out the
science of this um from the different
perspectives
um so they they put together um that
i started to look into you know like i
said what be my potential causes
i actually reached out to my father as
well he's an international infectious
disease epidemiologist
um and you know i thought it was
uh a little premature for to have such
swift
action uh without a little bit more
further testing which only took a little
bit of time to do
but it really hurt the industry and
really hurt medical patients that
rely on vapes um so
um yeah we put together a press
conference
um around this uh invited dr peter
grinspoon
commissioner title different experts to
give their opinions on
on the vape ban um and so that we've got
that recording
um and then um yeah did advocacy around
that they eventually lifted it
um and then you know now since we
understand that um
massachusetts um you know i think it was
a premature
uh intervention um some studies that
have come out later have have documented
that it had
really no impact on valley cases
so i think i was yeah that was a that
was an interesting time and an
interesting time for the industry and i
think it took a really big hit
for patient access um and just for the
industry at large
yeah and again just another example of
how
sort of the knee-jerk reaction can be
just to ban
and um how you know that
unfortunately is sort of a blunt
instrument that's not always the best
one to use and as you demonstrated
having good testing techniques
to ensure patient safety um is really
the way to go rather than just kind of
do a wholesale ban
so thank you for your your work on that
yeah absolutely um we
ran a quick survey of that as well
because you know me and studies
um and you know we did find that i mean
people
when they're when they don't have access
to things you know they're and you can't
just cut them off with a ban
you know what i mean um so people did
they'll start searching
products on the unregulated market that
are not tested and that are not
necessarily
fully safe uh driving across borders to
get things you know
um saw that also probably when when
adult use was deemed non-essential in
massachusetts
um with coving um right you know
so i mean in our study you know people
like we said
i said that you know some people now
since code had to
seek their products on the unregulated
market i'm gonna look at that over time
since i'm gonna look at the timestamp of
when adult use was banned in
massachusetts and that data versus now
when it's
uh back open and see if those numbers
change but
yeah that'll be interesting to see yeah
yeah
so i know we're getting towards the end
here and i did want to give you an
opportunity that i know
in addition to the work that you're
doing in terms of
doing surveys and sort of larger scale
studies
that you also do a lot of work in terms
of advocacy and social justice so i
wanted to
kind of get an update and see if there's
any any new things that you're working
on that you like to share with the
audience
awesome yeah thank you yeah long-running
advocate for
social justice and um and uh
addressing the failed drug war uh
through
effective programming education access
et cetera last year we
were a state approved social equity
training vendor for the massachusetts
cannabis control commission
so taught nine courses in massachusetts
and this year i'm quite excited to
partner
with writer university and my colleague
dr sarah trocchio
who's a professor in criminal justice at
writer
she's leading a course and i'm one of
three mentors in the course that's
focused
on new jersey and focused on new jersey
legalization and the vote that's coming
up
and social equity in new jersey um so
we are the students are grouped into
three
consulting groups one focused on public
health one focused on social justice and
one focused on advocacy
and the students are actually running
their own research study
that's approved with the writer irb as
part of their learning methods um and so
it's open right now so if you know
anybody in new jersey
um please take the survey uh it'll help
the students
um basically asking opinions about
legalization
and uh social justice in the in the
state
and the students will be analyzing this
data and producing a report
um that would provide recommendations
for
future commissions or advocates or
others in the state
around those topics of legalization and
social justice
uh so we're trying to make this a very
actionable
uh study uh it's very quick data
collection so before november third
if anybody is a new jersey resident we
encourage you to take
take the survey and um we'll be having a
virtual event
um on december 2 at 3 p.m where the
students will present the findings
and we'll have various um advocates and
experts from new jersey also
participating in the virtual event
wow that's great um and if you send over
the links i'd be happy to put that in
the show notes so people can quickly get
to that
um if they're able to take the survey or
definitely
sign up for that event and i think
that's
a very appropriate you looking into new
jersey because i know that a lot of
folks
in the industry here especially us on
the east coast are very interested
to see what happens in new jersey it
would be
only the second state in the northeast
to really go
full adult use and i think the general
consensus is
if if new jersey goes legal pretty much
everyone else is going to follow so that
is
definitely going to be a big vote that
we're all paying attention to in
november as a
in addition to another pretty big one
that's going to be happening in november
um so i guess just finishing up here i
did want to give you a chance to
let everyone know about the different
organizations that you're involved in um
and plug those websites social media
anything like that
uh now's your now's your opportunity
awesome yeah and thank you all for
listening
um so i'm the president of cannabis
center of excellence
uh it's a 501c3 nonprofit aimed at
improving access to research education
social justice in the cannabis industry
uh you can find us at
www.cannacenterofexcellence.org
and we're on uh facebook twitter
instagram
um and linkedin um so you can find
me at marion at
canadacenterofexcellence.org
i'm always open to collaborations ideas
uh innovations um trying to bring the
best foot forward
in the cannabis industry so thank you
ben for the time and
and for having me on the podcast today
thank you marion uh we look forward to
seeing you out in pasadena
and um i think that'll be a great
opportunity for you to connect with
those innovators and
collaborators so we're looking forward
to it me as well
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr mcnabb
marion was kind enough to send along all
the links we mentioned in the interview
which i've added to the show description
on our blog so please do check those out
and thanks again to cannabis science and
technology for sponsoring this week's
episode
i hope you will sign up for their
veterans day e-symposium to learn more
about how cannabis is being used to care
for our military veterans
again you can go to
cannabissciencetech.com
to learn more about that event
coincidentally enough our next episode
of the canmed coffee talk podcast will
drop on veterans day
november 11th in the meantime please go
to cammanevents.com
copy talk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you into that drawing to
win two tickets to our can med
2021 vip dinner and keep you up to date
on all things canmed 2021
give us a follow on social media too we
are on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for can med events
and lastly if you're listening via a
podcast app
you can subscribe to our feed so that
new episodes automatically download to
your device
and if you do like what you hear please
leave us a five star review
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of canmed coffee talk
you