[Music]
uh welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing i am your host ben
ameralt
the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now
to learn all about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place april 12th through
14th
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and get your tickets today at our
special early bird rate
and right now through december 18th you
can register to win
a free ticket to our canmed medical
practicum
which will take place on april 12th
it's all part of our canmed giving back
campaign
and it's very simple to enter all you
have to do is go to canmedevents.com
click on the can med giving back banner
fill out the form
and you'll be entered to win and
actually if you follow us on social
media you will earn some additional
entries so please do go to
canmedevents.com
check out the giving back campaign and
good luck
in other news we've started a facebook
group each year we are consistently
blown away by the amazing presentations
inspiring conversations
and important connections that are made
at the annual canmed conference
so we decided to keep the conversations
flowing online
with our canmed community group the
canmed community
is our virtual forum allowing you to
interact directly
with many of the canmed conference
speakers past attendees
and other group members to discuss all
things cannabis from bench to the
bedside
use the link in the show description to
visit that group today
and join our guest this episode is dr
stacy gruber
she is the director of cognitive and
clinical neuro-imaging care
at mclean hospital's brain imaging
center
and an associate professor of psychiatry
at harvard
medical school dr gruber has spent
decades
investigating how both recreational and
medical cannabis use
affects the brain in 2014 dr gruber
launched
mind which stands for marijuana
investigations
for neuroscientific discovery the first
ever program of its kind designed
to clarify the specific effects of
medical cannabis use
what she and her team have found is that
not only do medical cannabis patients
tend to perform better on cognitive
tests
when compared to recreational users but
medical cannabis patients tend to
outperform themselves
when compared to tests administered
before they started treatment
stacy and i explore why this may be the
case in our conversation
and we also discuss some results from
mind's double-blind placebo-controlled
cbd clinical trial for anxiety which
uses a high cbd
whole plant extract spoiler alert
the cognitive performance data is pretty
consistent with the team's earlier work
other interesting observations from the
study include
patients using whole plant extract tend
to use smaller doses
than single compound therapeutics as you
would expect
this led us to discuss the entourage
effect and the benefits
of using full spectrum products however
it was interesting that some patients in
the trial
still tested positive for thc despite
the fact that the hemp derived extract
contained
less than 0.3 milligrams per ml
of thc lots of good stuff in this
conversation
but first i'd like to thank this
episode's sponsor
healer healer is a trusted
physician-developed medical cannabis
brand
founded to address the challenges of
helping patients
and health providers get the best
results with safe
reliably dosable products and education
on how to use them best healers
distinctive product formulations
and educational material are based on
the work of leading cannabis clinician
dr dustin sulak dr sulak's healer hemp
cbd and cbda products are available
nationwide
and are accompanied with a step-by-step
usage guide and response tracker
visit healercbd.com and use the coupon
code
canmed for 20 off your order
again that's healercbd.com
coupon code canmed
and it wouldn't be the canmed coffeetalk
podcast without some good coffee
and for that we always turn to the hemp
and coffee exchange
if you don't know hemp coffee is a
healthy delicious natural
product rich in trace minerals and
nutrients providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com and use the promo
code drinkhemp to get 10
off your purchase
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation
with dr stacy gruber
good afternoon stacey thanks for joining
us sure thanks for having me
first of all i want to thank you not
only for joining us on the podcast but
for being a
two-time canmed presenter
i know that in 2019 we were thrilled to
have you as a keynote presenter where
you shared the data that you
and your team have collected about how
cannabis affects cognitive function
which
is quite extensive but for lister
listeners who
might not be too familiar with you or
the work that your team is doing
i was thinking that a great place to
start would be for you to
fill them in on the work that you've
been doing sure well first of all i'm a
huge fan of canned med let's start with
that and um i actually think i've been
three times
extraordinary conference and it really
is
um probably the the very best of its
kind that's out there and i
am very fond of telling people that so
there you have it um
but just by way of i think a little bit
of background
i've spent decades actually looking at
the impact of
recreational cannabis use on things like
cognitive performance clinical state
measures of brain structure and function
etc
with a particular focus on what we call
the vulnerable brain
so what happens to individuals who may
begin using cannabis very regularly
while their brain is still developing or
as i like to call it half-baked
those studies from our lab and from
colleagues across the country and really
in fact the globe
demonstrate that there appear to be some
differences in those who begin using
cannabis
regularly especially with regard to
again some of these cognitive
measures especially those mediated by
the frontal part of the brain
now that's the recreational story and it
seems to hold
for again early onset regular cannabis
users and there's a relationship between
earlier onset higher magnitude that is
higher amount of views and higher
frequency of use
and maybe not doing quite as well on
some of these measures as other folks
who use
uh regularly starting later when their
brains are more fully developed
or who start you know when they're when
they're you know in their 40s or later
that's the recreational story uh that we
that we've spent a lot of time looking
at
but i was very surprised when i looked
in the literature since medical cannabis
was first legalized in the states in
i couldn't find much with regard to the
impact of
medical cannabis use and the potential
impact of that
type of of cannabis use on measures of
again cognitive performance clinical
state quality of life sleep
conventional medication use again
despite the fact that it's been around
uh for a long time so we started a
program called mind
marijuana investigations for
neuroscientific discovery it really
should have cannabis in the name
but states have medical marijuana laws
so we stuck with mind and that program
is really
dedicated specifically to looking at the
potential impact of medical cannabis use
on all of those domains i mentioned
and others using lots of different
approaches so longitudinal observational
data which was the first
set of studies that we launched
survey-based data
and finally clinical trial data which
i'm very very excited about
excellent and in doing my research for
this conversation it seemed like in
you touched on it in your in your great
summary that
the the studies that you've done can be
sort of broken into a few different
broad groups
one first as you mentioned depending on
user type the recreational
versus the medical and then age
adolescent versus adult
and then i'm curious too um
does some of those findings have to do
with the type of product being used
whether it be
kind of high cbd versus high thc
yeah those are those are great um great
points and you know the very first thing
i always like to remind people of
because you know
first of all cannabis is a highly
polarizing topic right
i've never actually dealt with anything
in psychiatry or neuroscience that's
quite as
um as much of a hot topic as
cannabis and maybe a hot potato people
have very strong feelings on both sides
you know
either it's you know the the devil's
weed the devil's lattice and and it
should be outlawed immediately if not
sooner or
cannabis later al the plant that is the
you know the the plant
from which everything comes and then we
have things that are single extracted
constituents of the plant right the main
players delta nine thc the my
main psychoactive or intoxicating
constituent and as you appropriately
note cannabidiol or cbd
a primary non-intoxicating constituent
but there are lots and lots of other
cannabinoids
phytocannabinoids things from the plant
that interact with our own system of
um chemicals and receptors the
endocannabinoid system
there are terpenoids the essential oils
that give cannabis its characteristic
scent and flavor profile that have their
own
biobehavioral effects flavonoids waxy
fields you name it
lots of different things cannabis is not
one thing whole plant full spectrum
products
very different from single extracted
purified compounds
something like an epidiolex purified cbd
likely very different from a non-plant
derived that is
i made it in the lab synthetic thc
something like
um marinol all of these things are
likely to convert different effects but
i thought one thing that you mentioned
was incredibly important and i spent a
lot of time reminding people
recreational or adult cannabis use is
very different
from medical cannabis use when you look
at the
cohorts that is the population and
that's because their goals are different
the recreational consumers typically
looking to change their current state of
being or to get high
and thus they look for products high in
thc that primary psychoactive
constituent
our medical patients almost always say
dr gruber i don't
want to get high i just want to be able
to drive my car
i just want to be able to sleep through
the night and as a result
our medical patients often choose
products with a broader cannabinoid
constituent profile
that is often dominated by
non-intoxicating constituents like cbt
so when we look at the data
that come from our studies of
recreational consumers or adult
consumers of cannabis
versus medical consumers or medical
patients
the data does look different and very
likely because
the goals of use tend to drive product
selection
yeah and that is as you said a very
important distinction but
and i'm curious is there sort of a
third type of user in there that maybe
isn't
interested in the recreational high and
maybe doesn't have
a you know a severe condition that
really needs
medical use but maybe is interested in
using cannabis just for a
general wellness supplement sure
that's a great point and actually i'm a
firm believer in
exactly that kind of approach i think a
lot of people when they begin to
understand
the potential of exploiting the
non-intoxicating constituents from the
plant
given the potential health benefits they
may confer they look to use it as
prophylaxis or health and wellness as
opposed to
treating a symptom or condition or
looking to get high to your point i
think
a lot of products that are currently on
the market that are classified as hemp
derived meaning they come from a
cultivar with less than 0.3
thc by weight that's exactly what people
are using it for
um and they've they've decided that this
is a uh
likely a very helpful and not likely
very harmful
thing to add to their daily regimen and
so i'm curious in terms of
looking at cognitive effects is there a
difference there have you been able to
look into that
i know that you you've mentioned that
folks who use cannabis for a medicinal
purpose
actually perform better on a lot of the
the measures that you've been looking at
is there any and you look into those who
are kind of using it
as a supplement or general wellness do
they perform worse better stay the same
it's a great question you know so far we
really have data from what i would call
the two primary cohorts but again your
point is a good one
that that third cohort um is an
important one to think about
recreational consumers we know with
earlier onset and higher frequency
and magnitude of use we tend to see some
difficulties with tasks
that are controlled or mediated by that
frontal part of the brain which
not coincidentally is the last uh part
of the brain to become
fully developed or to come online so
that's not surprising right so if you
begin to use anything
whether it's cannabis or other
substances alcohol
or if you're injured or you're ill very
possibly you may sustain
uh some damage or or have some issues
completing tasks
required or which require the part of
the brain that's not yet fully developed
the medical cannabis patient story is
very different and we have published
some really interesting data on rather
small samples but compelling
samples of well-characterized medical
patients demonstrating
that at baseline where they have no
cannabis on board
and then you know after being tested at
3 months 6 12 18 and 24
we generally not only don't see
decrements in performance specifically
on those same types of tasks
that the recreational consumers show
some difficulty with if they're early
onset users
they actually do show some improvement
which is really quite stunning i don't
think people
necessarily expected that
so those negative effects that that
affect the
recreational users is that sort of an
acute
sort of effect is that something that
can be overcome if you
stop use or is that sort of a lasting
effect that can
continue great question um you know
there have been studies
um longitudinal studies that actually
follow folks over time
and they try to identify individuals who
begin using it early
versus those who began using later and
then you see how things sort of quote
turn out
long term and what happens after a
protracted period of absence
lots of studies look at absence periods
that are um
several days to several weeks but the
bigger question is really what happens
if you stop using
and how do you look compared to where
you where you were when you
when you were using you know i think
that there is a fair amount of evidence
suggesting that for individuals who are
using
um with great frequency and at high
amounts who happen to be young
when they take a break or cut down they
do tend to look a little bit different
so it's not as if there's this quote
long-term damage and again damage is a
relative term
it's not as if we're seeing you know
data that suggests these people can't do
anything
and i want to make that very clear it's
uh you know in our studies
when we look at people who are using
very very high amounts of cannabis
very frequently it's not as if these
people can't perform or can't function
it's that on specific tests we really
did see some differences in those folks
versus those
who began using much later on who didn't
use at all
i think a number of studies have
demonstrated that performance does
improve
with protracted periods of abstinence or
reduction in the amount of use
again primarily in those folks who are
using early on
so you mentioned when we were sort of
talking about the difference between
adolescents and adults i'm curious
in adolescents who are looking to use
cannabis to treat
conditions like anxiety or depression or
anything
like that are there considerations that
need to be taken for
for them i think absolutely i think for
anybody but especially for those who
i consider our most vulnerable consumers
those are the folks who are
in their their adolescent or emerging
adults again the brain is quote
um again under construction half baked
whatever euphemism you want to use
um not quite done and we always tell
people we're not saying
just say no we're saying just not yet
and for those folks it's especially
important to remember that
delta 9 thc again the primary
constituent appears to be
appears to be what confers the greatest
um potential declarant later on so we
don't have much
in the way of data suggesting that
exposure to other
cannabinoid constituents like cbd cause
problems later so for folks with anxiety
or difficulty with with things related
to anxiety or perhaps
some other conditions products high in
cbd with very low or perhaps even
no thc may be may be a consideration
versus products with discernible and uh
sometimes not so insignificant amounts
of thc
for people with anxiety it's also
important to remember we have a whole
set of studies dedicated
to looking at patients with moderate to
severe anxiety it's important to
remember that thc appears to have
um a very interesting impact on
symptoms related to anxiety at low doses
thc
may be anxiolytic that is it may relieve
anxiety ah it took the edge off
i'm chilling i said okay at low doses at
high doses
thc can exacerbate or increase
anxiety or be what we call anxiogenic
that is make anxiety significantly worse
or create anxiety
so it's a very important thing to be
mindful of especially in a day
where we are i mean bombarded with
products
but you know the concentrate market
starts life at about 35 40
thc and goes from there and for some
folks that's absolutely okay
i'm sure for people and patients with
anxiety that can be a real problem so
it's important to know quote what's in
your weed
which is why we conduct laboratory
analyses of all of our patients
um most commonly used products
interesting and so what are
what compounds are you looking for when
you when you test it are you looking at
uh terpenes and flavonoids and
stillbinoids the more i talk to people
about all the different compounds that
are in the plant it's
staggering amazing yeah it's an
extremely complex plant and so
incredibly fascinating as far as i'm i'm
concerned no um
you know for our study subjects given
the extraordinary cost of these
analyses but the absolute need for us to
know because
the observational longitudinal study
which again follows
real world folks using real world
products i'm not actually creating a
product in those studies
we're just following patients um and
allowing them to use
whatever products they choose but then
we want to know what's in the product
because
as you have probably also heard very
often what's on the label does not
reflect what's actually in the product
and that's a problem so we're really um
having uh cannabinoid constituent
profiling done so
13 cannabinoids are quantified for our
clinical trial data
um you know before we ever get to the
state where we're administering anything
everything is profiled and analyzed
including
you know the terpenoid profile because
if we're aiming for a specific profile
we want to make sure
we've hit it but you know i think the
patients find it incredibly helpful
especially those who are spending lots
of money on products that purport to
have let's say
30 mins per ml of cbd right an online
product
hemp derived so it's legal they buy it
it can be shipped to them at home
um and they wonder why they don't notice
anything and then we
we tested for them and they find out
they don't feel anything because it's
got less than one meg per ml or
something like that
that's that's terrible yeah that's going
to be
incredibly frustrating for patients and
probably even equally
frustrating for you as a researcher to
not have a consistent
product to be able to kind of limit
those variables
absolutely i mean there are some
products that continue
and can they continue and consistently
test
exactly where they should and that's
great in terms of some of these
manufacturers that's terrific
unfortunately not all are created
equally
um and for these studies where we are
relying on patients to use the products
that they select
we want them to be getting you know what
they are supposed to be getting for the
clinical trials of course we have
a lot more control over it but by and
large i think it's a really helpful
piece of information and a very valuable
tool for
our patients to to be able to see oh
this is not exactly what i'm arguing for
okay let's talk let's talk about the
clinical trial
we're fortunate enough to have received
several inds or investigational new drug
approvals for a number of indications
including um anxiety and pain but
starting first with anxiety
we actually had the very first ever
study of whole plant
full spectrum high cbd low thc but not
no thc
sublingual solution that was formulated
for patients
with moderate to severe anxiety and
that's an open labeled double-blind
placebo-controlled trial we intended the
open label phase to also be a little bit
of a dose-finding study because look
this has never been done
and we know in studies that use
single-extracted compounds
like epidiolex um you know the doses
that are being used are incredibly high
that's also true of non-plant derived
cannabidiol sources that have been used
in studies of
for example things like social anxiety
disorder so the question is you know
using the whole platform spectrum
product would we need the same
kind of dose and anecdotally we hear
that people
experience tremendous relief using some
products that they get online
at significantly lower doses so we
pitched it that way
and the open label phase was designed to
look at 15
folks who received the study product
that i formulated
and they take it three times a day it's
a sublingual solution so they take one
mil
three times a day hold it under their
tongue for as long as they can
and we basically see them every week
and we actually also look at thc
positive status over time because the
other question for lots of folks across
the country is
hey if i'm using something that's
derived from hemp i'm never going to be
positive for thc
and i don't have to worry about it if
you know my workplace is testing or if
i'm worried about
any other kind of um surveillance i
shouldn't worry because it's from him
i can never be positive and we were very
interested in figuring out whether that
was true or not because i don't think
i didn't think it was true now we know
it's not true um
but so far we've completed the open
label phase
and we have not published the clinical
or the cognitive data
yet but i can tell you that the data is
really rather extraordinary
and quite compelling and it looks as if
relative to baseline after a four week
trial with this
custom formulated high cbd low thc but
full spectrum product symptoms symptoms
related to anxiety
are significantly decreased over time we
also see some improvements in symptoms
related to depression
and we see improvements on measures of
cognitive performance so these
these findings actually mirror what
we're seeing in the larger
longitudinal but observational studies
so that's that's pretty interesting
absolutely and a lot of things to unpack
here the first being
lower doses of the whole plant extract
actually being
as effective as the higher dose of the
single compound um
is that the entourage effect well it's a
great question and that's exactly why
we added an arm to this particular study
so this study was designed
as i mentioned open label to double
blind the double blind is
you know patients either get placebo or
they get the whole plant full spectrum
product but what if we could
make a a product that used the same
base that i created the study product
from from but stripped away
the other cannabinoid constituents the
terpenoids and flavonoids everything
except for the cbd what would that
yield i don't know the answer to that
but that would be a perfectly matched
arm
right and that would tell us
definitively uh my my hunch is that
we're going to see
some differences but i don't know and
yes to your point i am a firm believer
that
whether it's the synergy between
cannabinoid constituents terpenoids
flavonoids etc
or just a few of the constitu the
cannabinoids themselves there is clearly
something that is an additive
property or effect at using a whole
plant full or even broad spectrum
type product versus a single extracted
compound
yeah and that i mean it makes sense and
conversations i've had with folks who
are
studying the endocannabinoid system it
seems to be a very
complex system with a lot of different
compounds interacting in enzymes and
receptors and it seems
unlikely that it's just one compound
that's producing this
great effect absolutely and if you look
at the ways in which each of the sort of
well-known cannabinoid constituents
exert or modulate effects for example
thc at cb1
or even cb2 receptors versus cbd which
does not appear
to modulate its effects um through that
system at all
but uses 5ht1a trip there's
all sorts of other things happening here
um again i think you get a bigger bang
for the buck so to speak
when you're using something that's a
phone or broad spectrum product
and it will be really something to be
able to
actually have data empirically sound
data to support that theory which is
a theory that you know some of us have
had for a long time but i can understand
on the other side people say look a
molecule is a molecule and you know it's
probably just this well
i'm not so sure and
another thing about um that stood out to
me when you were talking about the
clinical trial is
again you're seeing the improvement and
cognitive function um for folks that are
using cannabis
so do you have any idea of what's sort
of causing this
improvement in cognitive function is it
you know actually that it's
making the brain work better is it that
they're using less
of other medications or some combination
of all of these factors
another really good question um so you
know
for a four-week clinical trial here's
what i can say when you see improvements
in cognitive performance and you also
see clinical improvements
so a reduction in anxiety or let's say
depressive symptoms
the question is are they doing better on
cognitive tests because
they're less anxious and then they can
actually focus more effectively
is it that they are no longer leaning
into or leaning on
concomitant medications like
benzodiazepines or other anxiolytics
that can
compromise cognitive performance we're
not necessarily empowered to see that
from the open label phase
we will look more closely at that in the
double-blind phase but
um you know i think there's a lot of
things at play again
the longitudinal observational study
that we've been doing for several years
at this point again it looks at folks
using their own regimen over time with a
really comprehensive set of assessments
and so far what we're seeing is
improvements in cognitive performance
and clinical state quality of life sleep
etc
and a reduction in conventional
medications so the question becomes is
it that these folks
are older than uh you know our
recreational consumers who
showed some decrements on some of these
cognitive measures is it that they're
clinical
symptoms that have led them to wanting
to use cannabis in the first place
whether it's chronic pain or
you know in our clinical trial anxiety
etc so those symptoms are better so they
can focus more effectively and think
more clearly or is it a reduction in
medication use are they sleeping better
and therefore they can process more
effectively
what i call the direct versus indirect
impact
of using a cannabinoid-based product on
cognitive vision
and you sort of already answered this
question but i guess i'll direct i'll
ask it anyway
is there is there any research into
cognitive performance with other
anti-anxiety
medications do they also improve it or
or not you know it's a an
important area to look at by and large
most folks who are on
different types of conventional
medications don't typically report
improvements secondary to the medication
specifically right um
so i would have to look at that um
actually and that's
that's an interesting thought in terms
of a very nice comp sort of comparison
typically what you hear from patients
who are on anxiolytics or things to help
them relax
or sleep is you know i have this
fuzziness
bit of a hangover i can't think clearly
we've all heard stories of people
using different medications who you know
had a little bit
of difficulty let's say the next thing
is like oh you know it's this it's this
little cloud
i can't shake this cloud i used to call
it the cognitive cloud
and that was very common in folks with
anxiety but you know i don't know of
studies that have done
acute challenges these are more
sort of observational studies of folks
who are using these types of products
who
who then you know report these types of
of cognitive difficulties but that's
that's an interesting question from an
acute
administration perspective
so i'm curious what are sort of the more
traditional or conventional medications
doing that cannabis is doing differently
so i think it depends on the class of
medication you're talking about and i
think you know
you sort of hit on it earlier when you
said is that the is that the
entrepreneurship effect with regard to
canvas
you know one of the things that i think
is so extraordinary and still
so relatively so it's understudied
is what do we expect when we involve
different quote players who exert or
modulate effects using different
mechanisms versus a medication
let's say a conventional medication that
we know is a selective serotonin
inhibitor right an ssri common treatment
for depression
or anxiolytics or even you know opioids
what is it that's different about
cannabis in my mind one of the things
that's
one of the things that's different is
that you have multiple
players addressing multiple systems
and so you're much more likely to have
an effect that does not necessarily
confer
some of the same downsides right this as
something that
is not as as broad i guess i would say
um to me that's that's incredibly
important
and again using the philosophy i think
of most
conventional medication approaches you
always want to use the lowest effective
dose
right the lowest effective dose required
to get let's say symptom relief
i think that in our studies what we're
finding is patients often begin using a
certain regimen and then they wind up
reducing the amount that they're using
it's interesting we haven't seen
people necessarily using higher and
higher and higher doses of certain
things
we actually see a little bit of a
reduction over time i don't know that
that will hold
but that's interesting because the
question i would then have is what
does their endocannabinoid profile
look like over time which is something
that we'll also be looking at so
you know what do endogenous or inherent
levels of let's say anandamide or 2ag
our own endocannabinoids what do those
levels look like at the beginning of the
study
versus midpoint when they're using you
know a product with
this amount of thc or cbd versus the end
but it might be a different
story that would be very interesting to
look at so that is very interesting so
you're actually
testing for endocatabates
well we haven't begun that part of our
studies yet but we have this set up now
so we're very very excited to be able to
do that because i think that's one piece
you know that's that's an incredibly
important part of the puzzle you know
it's one thing again in the literature
to look at you know studies that have
used either non-plant derived products
or
thc exclusively on acute symptoms like
pain
or muscle spasticity as a function of ms
or nausea and vomiting
as a function of chemotherapy you know
it's one thing to look at at
again that type of administration but
the big question is
when when we really want to know what's
the impact of cannabinoid-based
treatment we want to look
at clinical and cognitive and
conventional medication
use all the you know the sort of outcome
variables that we can think of sleep
quality of life and some of the
neurobiologic variables that we can
look at even from imaging whether it's
in vivo brain metabolite ratios or how
much
of a certain brain metabolite you have
let's say at the beginning of a study
versus at the end of the study or what
your brain structural function would
look like all of these things will help
us
to build a much more comprehensive
picture of what is possible
and so i think getting a profile the
endocannabinoid system
before during and perhaps after clinical
trials or even longitudinal studies will
be very helpful
absolutely and you know it's a question
i've asked a few other guests who've
been talking about the endocannabinoid
system
is there a a test a panel that you can
run and sort of
get a profile of what your
endocannabinoids look like
and it didn't seem like there there was
at least not
widely available so it's really exciting
that that you are going to be testing
for that that's
that's really interesting it's certainly
not um
what i would call you know a simple
straightforward thing where you go and
buy this thing off the shelf right
and in 20 minutes you have a panel nope
if only
um and it is not trivial with regard to
the expense or amount of
uh effort required to do this but
frankly you know
having the very first neuroimaging study
of medical cannabis patients wasn't so
easy either but you have to do it
and it's really important especially if
you can control
what patients are taking in a clinical
trial and really look at this
data again before and after
you can really begin to make some um
important discoveries i think about what
is and perhaps is not happening
great and now i guess i have to ask
we've heard all of the the great
benefits that cannabis
can can give especially in this this
clinical trial for anxiety are there any
downsides
sure you know i think with um with
anything with any compound that actually
can yield any effect you always have to
be mindful right of what
what we call the good the bad and the
truth right
with regard to cannabis or cannabinoids
you know so many constituents have been
touted for so many things
and i'm the first to tell you that the
open label data is incredibly compelling
but it's open label data
and these patients know that they're
getting quote the sauce
so there is potential for you know
expectancy effects to creep in we
actually have
begun looking at that and it's a really
interesting story i will tell you i
don't think the study findings are
related to that um but to your point
whether you're talking about cbd
thc or whole plant products full
spectrum products broad spectrum
products
it's important for people to remember
that cannabis
is complex and some of these
constituents including
cbd especially cbd and thc interact with
things like
the primary enzyme system of the liver
this
cytochrome p450 enzyme system which
means that inadvertently
consumers could increase or decrease
amounts of other
medications or products that's important
so
it's something to be mindful of i think
that products that are particularly high
in thc
could be problematic for some folks for
example who are
perhaps with all great intentions some
some folks get information
from cannabis devotees who say look
i use this concentrate and it was
fantastic for me and i felt so chill
they may not know that the person that
they're recommending this to has
you know more than let's just say minor
symptoms of anxiety
or they have a genetic predisposition
and a very strong family history for
perhaps psychotic disorder we don't know
enough about this just yet
um it could exacerbate some
let's say less desirable the facts we
don't want that to happen so i think
it's always
important to be mindful of the potential
downside
and not go into these things assuming
that it's
absolutely been on they can do nothing
but be helpful
yeah i think that's good advice and i
think it's always good to
seek out the the council of experienced
medical professionals who who are used
to
administering cannabis that can help
kind of guide you in your journey for
sure
it's hard because everybody's also we're
not all created equally right so from
the genetic perspective that's a
that's a tough one and you know people
say oh you know
we know that cannabis causes psychosis
well i'm not really
sure that we have the data to say that
but could it certainly make things worse
for people
with latent psychotic you know with
either prodromal symptoms or
very strong family or genetic histories
um this is something to be mindful of
um doesn't mean you can never use it
means you need to it's sort of like
not buyer beware but buyer be aware
right be mindful
um know what's what's uh what's in your
weed so to speak i think it's incredibly
important
absolutely and i think that might be a
great place to stop i definitely want to
be respectful of your time and
very much appreciate you taking the time
to to be
on the podcast with us but before i let
you go i do want to give you the
opportunity to
uh tell folks where they can find more
information about mind about you
there's a website or social media or
anything that you want to
plug please sure well thank you
um i think most of the updates about
the mine program has a number of
different studies from the longitude
observational studies to the a number of
survey-based studies
to the clinical trials we have a a
program dedicated to veterans
uh serving those who have served we have
a program dedicated
it's called whim or the women's health
initiative that might be lots of
specialized initiatives
and you can learn more about that at
www.stacydoctorstacygruber.com or just
dr staceygruber.com
and that's actually the same for social
media for twitter and
instagram i think so that's a great
place to find some of
some of the latest greatest stuff that's
coming out the lab including the
the very newest study looking at him the
the clinical trial product and the thc
positive status was really
quite an interesting discovery so it's
important i would check it out
if you're using a hemp based product and
think nah i could never turn positive on
a urine test
well oh that's not the case huh
not the case fifty percent of our sample
was positive after four weeks
despite zero reports zero reports of
intoxication are feeling high
and there was no relationship to the
actual amount of study product used
we weigh the bottles on the way out and
on the way in
or body mass so didn't matter how big
the folks were
or how much product they were taking we
saw a relationship only with urinary
creatinine which is a measure of you
know kidney function and hydration
so really really important especially
for
people who think you know these urine
tests you know the lower limit of
detection is
very often 50 nanograms per ml or in the
workplace sometimes
15 our data also suggests that for some
of those
assays um they are more sensitive than
they are
supposed to be we see positive results
at far lower levels than 50 nanograms
per ml
so we do the in-house test and then we
send it out for quantification using
gcms and we were
rather surprised wow so are you doing
are you performing potency testing on
the product
itself as well so is there just a lot
more thc than folks think is in there
oh no no not this isn't potency testing
this is just um thc positive status for
the the clinical trial patients
um see so would you be positive if you
used a hemp derived product that's high
in cbd
and very low in thc and i'll tell you
our study product has between 0.27 to
0.29 migs per mil
that's not by weight that's migs per ml
okay and
um a whole lot more cbd than that
somewhere around 10 minutes per ml which
doesn't sound like a lot
but three times a day you know it's
about 30 is the targeted dose for this
study
and after such a low level so that's
less than one milligram of thc
per day after four weeks would you be
positive and the answer is
half of the sample was positive that's
important
especially since products that you can
buy commercially online
you can have point three percent by
weight which
uh again ours is point zero two since
more than ten times
the amount of thc as in our study
product
is legal and our study folks half of the
sample was positive after four weeks
but despite never feeling high or
intoxicated at all nothing like that
interesting were you only testing after
four weeks or was it every week and
it um kind of accumulates in the body or
how is that
we didn't test after every week actually
no i'm sorry
we have in lab testing we can actually
look at that data the big question
really was after four weeks
um but we did we sent uh laboratory
um we had laboratory analyses confirmed
after uh week three and week five so
it's after two weeks of product and four
weeks of product
i don't think we published the two-week
data but we did um weekly assays
in lab so really interesting stuff
very much so so much so much to learn
about this plan
absolutely right never boring that's for
sure
well it'll keep us employed for a while
hopefully
let's hope so certainly couldn't be more
interesting and i'll tell you
with the the sheer numbers of consumers
and patients
using cannabis for lots of different
things especially our older population
it's never been more important for us to
understand you know
again i always like to say the good the
bad and the truth it's up to us to try
to help people make the best decisions
they can
about a really complex but rather
extraordinary plant
excellent that's just what we're trying
to do at canmed absolutely
and i look forward to seeing you out in
pasadena thanks so much it'll be great
to see you there
all right take care
[Music]
i hope you enjoy my conversation with dr
stacy gruber
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to healer for
sponsoring this episode
go to healercbd.com and use the promo
code
canmed to get 20 off your order
our next episode will be on december 8th
in the meantime go to canmedevents.com
and sign up for our giving back campaign
for your chance to win a free ticket to
our medical practicum
if you're a medical practitioner this
really is a great opportunity and at no
cost to you
i really hope you take advantage of it
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast
app you can subscribe to our feed so
that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and if you like what you hear
please leave us a 5 star review alright
that's it from us as always stay
safe stay healthy happy thanksgiving
and we'll see you on the next episode of
canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you