[Music]
uh welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing i am your host ben
ameralt
the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now
to learn all about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place april 12th through
14th
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and get your tickets today at our
special early bird rate
and right now through december 18th you
can register to win
a free ticket to our canmed medical
practicum
which will take place on april 12th
it's all part of our canmed giving back
campaign
and it's very simple to enter all you
have to do is go to canmedevents.com
click on the can med giving back banner
fill out the form
and you'll be entered to win and
actually if you follow us on social
media you will earn some additional
entries so please do go to
canmedevents.com
check out the giving back campaign and
good luck
in other news we've started a facebook
group each year we are consistently
blown away by the amazing presentations
inspiring conversations
and important connections that are made
at the annual canmed conference
so we decided to keep the conversations
flowing online
with our canmed community group the
canmed community
is our virtual forum allowing you to
interact directly
with many of the canmed conference
speakers past attendees
and other group members to discuss all
things cannabis from bench to the
bedside
use the link in the show description to
visit that group today
and join our guest this episode
is dr maro macaron maro
is a pioneer in endocannabinoid research
in 1997 his team identified the receptor
targets
for the first two endocannabinoids that
were discovered by professor raphael
matchulum
earlier in the decade anandamide and 2ag
since then the endocannabinoid system
has been the focus
of his research at kmed 2021
maro will present the complex
endocannabinoid system
and the challenge of developing
selective drugs towards its distinct
elements dr michael macaron's
understanding of the endocannabinoid
system is exceptional
and i really enjoyed picking his brain
on some of the topics that have come up
in conversations with other podcast
guests
we discuss the technical challenges that
prevented researchers from understanding
the endocannabinoid system
until the early 90s how the discovery of
the endocannabinoid system changed
medical research and drug development
the difference between endocannabinoids
and phytocannabinoids
the large number of enzymes involved in
synthesizing
and cleaving each endocannabinoid and
how blocking or enhancing those enzymes
can affect the concentration
of endocannabinoids in a person's body
how when do cannabinoids work together
to create an entourage effect
how an increased level of
endocannabinoids can help you forget
a painful experience like childbirth or
a difficult run
and why researchers need to agree on a
standardized formulation of cannabinoids
to use for research before we get to
that conversation
i'd like to thank this episode's sponsor
cannabis science and technology and
their newest brand
cannabis patient care cannabis science
and technology focuses
on educating the legal cannabis industry
about the science and technology
of analytical testing quality control
insurance extraction cultivation
and processing slash manufacturing
in october cannabis science and
technology launched a new brand
cannabis patient care which is an
educational research
for patients doctors nurses pharmacists
and caregivers on the latest research
benefits
and treatment options cannabis provides
for a variety of illnesses
go to cannabis sciencetech.com to learn
more
and it wouldn't be the canmed coffee
talk podcast without some good coffee
and for that we always turn to the hemp
and coffee exchange
if you don't know hemp coffee is a
healthy delicious
natural product rich in trace minerals
and nutrients providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com and use the promo
code drinkhemp
to get 10 percent off your purchase
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr maro
macaron
[Music]
good afternoon maro thanks so much for
joining us thank you for inviting me ben
absolutely and we're very excited to
have you as a presenter at canmed2021
i'm really interested to see what you
have to present on
and for people who maybe aren't familiar
with you or familiar with your work
i was hoping we could start if you would
give sort of a brief bio
of who you are and the research that
you've done into the endocannabinoid
system yeah well i'm a biochemist
and i work as a full professor at
university of
rome and recently i moved to university
of
la cula that is nearby i was
involved for almost three decades
in lipid signaling so how
certain fat molecules fatty molecules
can bring
information in our body and i
was there when endocannabinoids
were discovered and since then i made of
that a major
subject of my research activity so my
group
works actively on the endogenous
components that we call
endocannabinoids
so that's fascinating so you were
actually there when the endocannabinoid
system was first discovered uh
yeah you know we issued our first paper
in
1997 and you know that the first
endocannabinoid anandamite was
discovered by rafael meshulam
group um shulam's group in 1992
and then the second major
endocannabinoid to arachidonil glycerol
was discovered in 1995
again by mishulam and independently
sugura so two years after the discovery
of these compounds we were able to
show some properties of the
receptor targets
and so i know we're going to get pretty
deep
into the endocannabinoid system and all
the different body systems and organs
that it touches but
maybe it'd be good to start for again
people who maybe aren't as familiar
if you could kind of give a broad broad
brush summary
of what is the endocannabinoid system
and what function does it serve in the
body
well you know uh this is a this
is a system because it is composed of
many molecules some uh
are able to activate targets
and these are called agonists
of receptors and are the true
endocannabinoids
and endocannabinoids come from fatty
acids that we
eat and we know for a long time
like arachidonic acid and then
we have all the targets of these
endocannabinoids
again receptors on the surface of our
cells
enzymes little machines that break down
or synthesize the endocannabinoids
other proteins on the membranes that can
transport endocannabinoids in and out
the cells
and therefore it is quite an ensemble of
molecules we should say
basically distributed everywhere in our
body
you can find them in virtually in all
tissues where they play different roles
so given that the endocannabinoid system
seems to be
so ubiquitous as you mentioned it's
pretty much
present in almost all the body tissues
and all the body organs
why do you think it took so long for
researchers to really discover
the endocannabinoid system in the role
that it plays in the body
uh this is a this is a really a good
question ben but
you know lipids and endocannabinoids
again
are lipids are fatty molecules
are quite difficult to handle and
the research on these molecules is never
easy
uh is it is not yet possible to
buy something from a company that all at
once
allow you allows you to measure uh
the amount of these components and to
understand
if they are present and if they are what
they do
so it is maybe a real is a purely
technical question or scientific
problem if you want that lipids are
difficult to handle
and it was then after many years of
research on proteins
and then on nucleic acids the
information material of ours
of our cells that we were able to look
more carefully into lipidic substances
and therefore in the 80s
for arachidonic acid derivatives and
then in the 90s for endocannabinoids
research focused on these molecules and
was able to make a kind of quantum leap
since then
interesting interesting and now since
the discovery of this system
and as we mentioned it is involved in so
many different
organs and tissues how has that
knowledge
sort of changed how you know medical
research is done
into different disorders that may affect
these systems
uh well it is true that the discovery of
endocannabinoids
immediately attracted also
pharmaceutical companies
because the uh
[Music]
endocannabinoids themselves and the
targets that they
hit in the cells can
represent novel targets for novel
therapeutics
in a time where we did not have
so many new totally innovative targets
to look at
therefore in a few years basically uh
one and a half decade we could say
enzymes that break down endocannabinoids
became targets for intense
research efforts by
all major pharmaceutical companies all
over the world
and so were the receptors so in a way
these compounds have
filled the gap and in this
in this gap therapeutic perspectives
seem to be very very strong
great and as i was doing the research
for this conversation i did come across
your paper entitled endocannabinoid
signaling at the periphery 50 years
after thc
um it's quite extensive look at the
endocannabinoid system
and as i've mentioned several times all
the different organs and body systems
that it interacts with
um and i will put a link to that paper
in the show notes
in the description so everyone can take
a look at that and very much encourage
people to read it
um and a lot of heavy hitters in in the
co-authors
of that paper including our dear friend
here at kamet dr
raphael machulam i was hoping we could
kind of use maybe that
paper as a framework to explore the
endocannabinoid system a bit more so
maybe let's let's start with covering
some of the different systems that the
endocannabinoid system
interacts with in that really show that
promise
for therapeutics that you mentioned yeah
but first
well thanks for the quotation and i like
to say that that was a
community paper that i happened to put
together and coordinate
the colleagues that have contributed the
most to the field
in the la since the discovery of
thc tetra hydro delta nine
tetrahydrocannabinol
and this gives me the chance to make a
clear point
plant extracts so the phytocannabinoids
like thc
were discovered approximately 30 years
before the endogenous cannabinoids
so we have to clearly make a distinction
between
the endogenous compounds that all of us
we
do have and the those compounds that
some of us decide to take
in different ways by the plants
and these are very different so
cannabinoids were discovered uh
almo now uh more than 50 years ago in 64
again by rafael michelan and only
after that will we understood that there
are endogenous compounds
that are activate the targets
accidentally activated also by the plant
extract
and therefore cannabinoids
are something different from the
endocannabinoids
the endocannabinoids in the
endocannabinoid system
certainly uh holds a lot of hold a lot
of promise
for uh central the central nervous
system
where it can control can contribute to
mood there are um
some indications whereby depression
can take advantage of an inhibition of
the
cleavage of the endogenous cannabinoids
for instance
but also at the periphery bone
homeostasis
rather than reproductive functions
rather than energy homeostasis
which means food intake the pleasure of
eating food
the uh the search for
palatable food and the way
we take energy out of food
making more fats like
lipogenesis or breaking fats
in the lipolysis all these aspects
are in a way or another under control
over the
endocannabinoids
so that's interesting when you're sort
of making that distinction between the
endocannabinoids and the
phytocannabinoids and
i think at least i understand that you
know
folks who benefit from cannabinoid
therapies
typically may have
a deficiency in their endocannabinoids
that the body is
is creating endogenously and
from what i understand in talking with
you that the endocannabinoid system is a
very
complex system with a lot of different
things at play so
how many different ways could someone
develop
a deficiency in their endogenous
cannabinoids
or there are actually many which makes
the the field
complex but also challenging and
promising
uh just to give you a general guideline
each endocannabinoid is synthesis
biosynthesized by one or more enzymes
and then it is cleaved by one or more
additional enzymes if you are able to
block or enhance any of these enzymes
you can modify the final content of
endocannabinoids what is called in
general
the endocannabinoid tone and this
in our body apparently the way we
use we take advantage of
endocannabinoids
as a very
[Music]
special signals is
through metabolism so there is a
metabolic control
in other words the way our body decides
how much endocannabinoid must be in a
certain cell at a certain
point can make a really difference
between
health and disease
so you mentioned that there are a lot of
different endocannabinoids
roughly how many different
endocannabinoids
do we know of and are there more
uh so far we can say that we know uh a
dozen
of which again still the very first two
to be discovered anandamide and 2ag
those that i mentioned before were found
already in 1992 and 1995
those two remain uh the most interesting
because apparently they hold
they they are uh the
the main signals that our cells uh use
yet we have to admit that of the quite
many others we don't know yet much
so maybe we have not learned enough
about anandamide in 2eg that we decided
to investigate
thoroughly the others and therefore we
cannot
really predict if another of these
endocannabinoids
can can be more relevant for a certain
specific condition
maybe a specific disease one of the
the topics that always comes up in
talking about
cannabis medicine is this whole idea of
the entourage effect
and i'm curious to get your thoughts on
that um from an endocannabinoid
perspective and you know we were just
talking about there are
many different endocannabinoids so is
there sort of an
entourage effect that's happening
endogenously as well
this is also very interesting question
then because we have learned
and it is clear that there are compounds
that do not act directly on the receptor
targets of the endocannabinoids
but can potentiate the activity of other
endocannabinoids on that
on those receptors why because they
interfere with the metabolism of those
endocannabinoids
for instance by blocking the
hydrolytic enzymes and this entourage
effect
seems to be relevant under many many
circumstances
and again also the endogenous compounds
not to mention the plant extracts that
we might
ingest for whatever reason also the
endogenous compounds
can play this entourage effect
and you mentioned earlier when we were
talking about how
it took so long for researchers to
really fully understand the
endocannabinoid system you mentioned
that
it's hard to test someone for the levels
of endocannabinoids that are in their
system or at least it was
earlier is there a better system for
doing that now
can someone you know go and get tested
and get lab results in terms of
figuring out if they have an
endocannabinoid deficiency
[Music]
basically the techniques remain uh
sort of highly specialized you have to
use
what is called liquid chromatography
mass
spectrometry maybe
it is true that now you can find these
techniques
much easier than it was just few years
ago
however you need a high level of
specialization
and high level of expertise to do these
essays
it is not like for others substances in
our blood
that with the drop of blood in 20
minutes
you have your uh your data
it is still quite challenging there are
investigations looking for alternatives
and this might change
the scenario in the coming years but so
far
you still need high and high level of
specialization
and quite sophisticated machinery
to do these essays
and i would imagine too would the level
of endocannabinoids in a person's system
sort of depend
on different stresses or as you said you
know
it can be part of metabolism so could do
the levels sort of
fluctuate throughout the day
this is this cannot be really said
uh conclusively from a scientific point
of view because
to my knowledge it has never been tested
in a very solid scientific manner
but what we know is that there are
changes there are
during the day rather than during
different conditions for instance the
estrous
cycle in women and certainly there are
changes from
individual to individuals so
interpersonal changes
we cannot yet assign a certain
a meaning to a certain value we are not
at the stage of
defining threshold values uh
below which everything is okay for the
world population and above which there
might be
a problem uh you we are we are
let's say starting to learn how
these differences could be meaningful
for our health
yeah that's interesting and i mean i
personally
i'm a runner so i am familiar that
as i believe and you can you can
certainly correct me if i'm wrong that
anandamide
is sort of what's credited with the
runner's high do i have that correct uh
yeah but it depends on the way you uh
what you mean with high
what i can tell you is that there could
be an
increase in anandamide but
maybe to cope with the pain
that can be associated with an extensive
physical exercise
because endocannabinoids like anandamide
are certainly the analgesic
so there is a the hypothesis that
when you practice a lot but also in
other circumstances like
in the delivery phase
when you you are delivering a baby an
increase of endocannabinoids
help you to cope with the pain
there is also something extra and
something more that seems very
interesting and the fact that an
increased
level of endocannabinoids might help you
to forget
abusive memories uh so
to forget something that you don't did
not really like
but that in terms of evolution uh
must be done again for instance once
more once again
in a partition so the
the pain that the the mother
can feel in the in delivery is uh
forgotten better with an increase or
with an increase of anandamide so
is not that you feel better as if you
were smoking
a joke but you might feel
less pain and forget something which is
negative
[Music]
due to this increased level of
endocannabinoids
so that's interesting so you're telling
me that my body is helping me forget the
pain from that run so that i'll
i'll get up and do it all over again the
next day exactly
and you like to do it again and you
don't associate
the negative memory or the pain feeling
uh that you had that is certainly a
clever trick
because uh oh yeah i do get out there
and do it again
um i did want to talk to you a bit more
about um
you know cannabis therapeutics or maybe
just you know phytocannabinoids in
so yeah one of the the newer aspects
that we've been seeing
research on in at canmed
is looking into sort of these different
types of cannabinoids whether it be
in acid form or even in cannabinoid
varins
so i was wondering if you could speak a
bit to sort of how these
different forms of the cannabinoids
how does their effect differ on on the
body
well as for the acids
you know that we also have
endocannabinoids that are
acidic like an arachidonyl glycine it is
a natural substance
an endogenous substance with an
acid tail so it is an endocannabinoid
acid actually
and we know that it mimics some of the
properties of an
andamide uh for instance with the law of
with affinity for
type 1 cannabinoid receptors uh
with in anti-inflammatory activity and
again
analgesic properties the same can be
uh said for the main
cannabinoid acid that is a
phytocannabinoid this time
a derivative of thc er
in 11 or oe case it but besides
the chemistry behind is a an acid form
of thc but this one is a form
of excretion is a metabolite that has to
be
wasted by the body so
if you add acidic tails to endogenous or
plant-derived cannabinoids you certainly
have different effects
[Music]
maybe what is more complex is to
understand
how these molecules along with the
variants like for instance
the the thcb the tetrahydrocannabine
they play together with the others
components of the plant extracts or the
endocannabinoid system
and this complexity of molecules
working together is a real challenge to
be understood
adding thc having a cbd cannabidiol
having both together or adding them
along with other less investigated
compounds can make really a huge
difference
in the biological activity that they
have
that's got to be the biggest challenge
of all is that there seems to be so many
different compounds
at play here and and it seems to be very
individualistic too in terms of what's
what the need is in the individual body
so i imagine that must be a
very big challenge for anyone who's
trying to develop a therapeutic
yeah and you know what i like to
to say as much as i can is that it is a
pity
that we did not yet uh decide
which are the standardized formulations
to be tested also in therapeutic terms
because because if we keep on using
different formulations of which
maybe you only know the amount of thc
and cbd
but you do not really i i don't want to
to see my i'm polite but you don't seem
to
to care at all about the others you
actually miss
the opportunity of learning from what
you are doing
because using different things will not
give you
a solid knowledge
that will finally help you to advance
your understanding
we have to clearly say that cannabis is
not
one you can have as many cannabis
as many formulations are going around
are being used or can be used
so the composition of each formulation
and also the amount of the different
components of each formulation
can make really a difference and we
should now
decide how to standardize
these things with the hope of learning
maybe from mistakes but in a 5-year time
10-year time we will really know better
what is good what is less good for our
our health
that's a really interesting point and it
it really touches on
you know a lot of the different
conversations i've had on the podcast
and in presentations that we've had in
previous canmeds
is first of all from a testing
perspective
it's difficult for them to have assays
that are going to detect all the
different cannabinoids or
and we haven't even gotten into terpenes
and flavonoids and stillborn
i am interested to get your thoughts on
that but from a testing perspective it's
hard for them to really get a full
profile of what the product is from a
cultivation side it's very hard for them
to produce a consistent product
and then it's interesting to hear you
say from a research perspective that
it's difficult for you to have a real
standard medicine to work off of so
it seems to be a problem that really
touches all the different aspects
of the industry yeah
and is a problem that finally has to be
faced
and i'm perfectly aware that it is not a
trivial problem if you
consider that we know that from a
cannabis
extract from cannabis sativa or cannabis
indica
both used to make
formulations used in therapy
you can expect at least 110
different phytocannabinoids and
on top of them at least 440
non-cannabinoid components like
terpenoids flavonoids
and and so many others so it is a
challenge
but it is just because
this challenge can lead to real good
drugs therapeutic drugs that we have
to take it in the proper way
there are no shortcuts to reach in an
easy way
a good drug at the end you have to
study properly the the composition
and the effects of
these combinations and maybe if we did
that 20 years ago
now we would really know so much
more then we could have more
therapeutics
that are active effective and are based
on these
cannabinoids yeah it certainly would
have been nice to get a jump start 20
years ago
but i i know at least here in the united
states that
that was not possible given the the laws
but thankfully
those seem to be loosening and research
has really come a long way so we're
excited in a lot of different ways
and if i may add ben another clear
distinction that we should make
is between recreational cannabis
and medicinal cannabis because
a therapeutic use of cannabis under the
responsibility and the control of a
physician that
continuously looks uh a
desire he looks after his patient is
something and to my understanding that
could be
made as free as possible
on the other hand a recreational use of
cannabis can be
uh dangerous it's not not at all true
that these compounds
are harmless especially if you think of
the what is going on is available also
through
internet and other means to young people
you can really find formulations where
thc itself is 10 more 10 times
more concentrated than in others and
other formulations where you also have
unexpected compounds so
a a free recreational cannabis can be
more dangerous than usual and certainly
it i have the feeling that certainly
these
mixing up the two recreational and the
therapeutic
did not help the the medicinal cannabis
yeah i think i think you're right um at
least for a long time here in the united
states and actually it is still the case
today
it's been classified as a schedule one
drug which
which states that there is no known
therapeutic
use which i think we've pretty much
disproven um and certainly your work and
in the work of many others have done
that so hopefully
um and sooner than later we can remove
that tag
um and before i let you go because i
know i'm coming up on the end of the
time that i i promise to keep you
um i did want to talk a bit more about
terpenoids flavonoids stillbinoids so
sort of these
these compounds that are present on the
plant that aren't necessarily
cannabinoids so
therefore they're not really interacting
as endocannabinoids at least i wouldn't
think so
so but are they sort of mimicking other
endogenous
compounds within the body to kind of
help those cannabinoids do what they
need to do
well you know for for some of them there
are
activities known for decades
like anti-inflammatory antioxidant
and some may also have specific targets
that
are certainly different from the targets
of the endocannabinoids so again the
concept of the
entourage effect could come out
here in the sense that the combination
of these
compounds non-phytocannabinoid compounds
together with some phytocannabinoids
that are present in a formulation
can change the react reaction of the
endogenous system to them
and we do not know much about these
interactions and these interference
among
components and once again this is why
we must standardize formulations
and investigate the effects in a
systematic
very sound manner
you know some people might find it maybe
discouraging to
to hear how little we still know or how
much work we still have to do but um
i find it fascinating and exciting that
there's still so much more to know and
so much more potential
within this plant and within this system
as well so i guess with that that's a
good place to stop
first i want to thank you for joining us
here on the podcast
and before i let you go i want to give
you an opportunity if there's
a website that you'd like to point
people to or if i don't know if you're
involved on social media or anything
like that
any sort of plug you want to give to the
work that you're doing so people who are
interested can learn more
it'd be great to share that ah thank you
so much ben i
actually i suggest people to look
through pubmed which is an official
uh site open public
where scientific studies are reported
rather than uncontrolled or less
scientific not to say gossip
that you can find easily elsewhere so
please
when you want to know more try to have a
good uh
source of information where it is clear
that things that are claimed
are claimed because there is a
scientific
background well recognized by the
scientific community
so once again you can go to pubmed
an nih site
and under my name you might find the
papers and whatever you want to know
more i'll be glad
to keep in contact and
exchange information that is excellent
and that is excellent advice
um and things beyond cannabis too always
make sure that you're
you're trusting your sources so exactly
so tomorrow thanks again for joining us
and i look forward to seeing you out in
pasadena for canmed
thank you so much ben for the
opportunity and i look forward to
meeting you and
many other colleagues and friends to
discuss this
fascinating topic
[Music]
i hope you enjoy my conversation with dr
maro macarons
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor cannabis
science and technology
some sad news to report but this will be
our last episode for the year
that's right no new episode on december
23rd
as we take a little break to enjoy the
holiday season
don't worry we will be back with a brand
new episode
january 6th i hope you'll take this
opportunity to get caught up on
one or more of our past episodes and if
you have a request or suggestion for a
future guest
we'd love to hear from you email us at
info
canmedevents.com or hit us up on one of
our social media properties
we're on facebook twitter instagram and
linkedin
just search for cam ed events and
finally if you enjoyed this episode
or any of our previous shows we'd
appreciate it if you hit that subscribe
button on your podcast player
and give us a five star review alright
that's it happy holidays happy new year
stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to come back
for the next episode
of the canmed coffee talk podcast
[Music]
you