[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing i am your host ben
ameralt
the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now
to learn all about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place april 12th through
14th
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and get your tickets today at our
special early bird rate
in other news we've started a facebook
group each year we are consistently
blown away by the amazing presentations
inspiring conversations and important
connections that are made
at the annual canmed conference so we
decided to keep the conversations
flowing
online with our canmed community group
the canmed community is our virtual
forum allowing you to interact directly
with many of the kanmed conference
speakers
past attendees and other group members
to discuss
all things cannabis from bench to the
bedside
use the link in the show description to
visit that group today
and join this episode's guest
is hope jones she is the ceo of superior
finos
llc a hemp young plant production
company in arizona
she's also ceo of emergent cannabis
sciences
an international cannabis and
micropropagation consulting company
with clients in colombia australia
germany
and canada hope has deep expertise in
both hemp and cannabis
often serving as an expert consultant on
forming policy at the state and federal
levels
nasa also tapped her micro propagation
expertise
to develop programs for growing plants
on deep space
missions in our conversation
we talked a lot about tissue culture as
hope will be leading a panel
on the topic at canmed 2021 we covered
how cultivators use tissue culture to
remediate plants that are infected with
pathogens such as powdery mildew and
hoplate and viroid
how the covid19 pandemic has actually
made hope's conversations with
cultivators about plant viruses
and pathogens much easier how tissue
culture can produce
changes to the plant's dna why alcohol
is not an effective antiviral solution
for plants
how cryogenic storage of tissue cultured
mother plants
can be used as an insurance policy
against pathogen infection
or other disasters and much more
before we get to that conversation i
want to thank this episode's sponsor
medicinal genomics medicinal genomics
uses its unmatched
knowledge into the cannabis genome and
the microbes that impact
cannabis plants to create a diverse set
of testing solutions
that improve crop yield accelerate
breeding
and ensure product safety many of the
top cannabis testing labs trust
mgc's pathoseek microbial safety testing
platform
to test for state mandated microbial
targets making it the industry's
preferred microbial testing method
now labs and cultivators can use the new
pathoseq
cannabis virus multiplex assay
to test plants for hoplite and viroid
lettuce chlorosis virus
and cannabis cryptic virus in a single
pcr reaction
learn more at medicinalgenomics.com
and it wouldn't be the canned med coffee
talk podcast without some good coffee
and for that we always turn to the hemp
and coffee exchange
if you don't know hemp coffee is a
healthy delicious natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information check out
hemp coffee exchange dot com and use the
promo code drink hemp
to get 10 percent off your purchase
okay without any further ado i give you
my conversation
with hope jones
[Music]
good afternoon hope thank you so much
for joining us
hi ben all right so
tissue culture very excited to talk with
you about this
and um our audience may already be
familiar with tissue culture because i
did speak with
mark jordan in a previous episode and we
discussed tissue culture and mostly
around
sort of how it's performed and the
different stages of tissue culture and
how the whole
process works but for this conversation
i'd really like to talk with you about
how
tissue culture can actually be applied
um in cannabis and hemp cultivation so
maybe a good place to start is can you
tell me how widely used
is tissue culture in cannabis and hemp
so tissue culture is widely used in
in practice when it comes to regular i
say regular
quotes um regular agriculture
horticulture
when i started doing cannabis tissue
culture i
i realized nobody's doing this and if
we're doing a lot of cloning it makes
sense and then i
will i'm sure get into all the other
advantages
um to tissue culture but it it was
actually pretty shocking um
but then not surprising once i thought
about it that nobody
in the cannabis or hemp industry had had
had been
um approaching that at least not at any
kind of real
commercial scale that i had seen and so
it makes sense uh given the nature of
the cannabis
industry having to be underground for so
long how how are you
to actually even think about doing
something along those lines so
it made sense to me when i thought about
it of course and i thought well
i have an opportunity to contribute uh
to this industry
um so i just oh i park myself i feel at
home and
and i'm happy to to help the industry
understand
what it can do what its potential
benefits are
and you know really there are cons that
come along with it as well
so i'm sure we'll get to all that
excellent all right well let's start
with the pros what are some reasons that
cultivators
should be using tissue culture
so i think probably the most common
commonly understood would be the idea
that you can
produce a lot of clones in a very small
amount of space and that is true
um and and that's exciting so the fact
that you can
take one cut um the hat
that in that cut should have a node
obviously and we can
either culture that node or we can
culture the very tip
of that node we call the meristematic um
cells up there um but either way you can
just take a part of a plant and you can
plate it
onto tissue cultured tissue culture
media
and the media has everything a
growing plant needs for growth
development
vitamins the obvious elements and and
hormones
and we can do that in a small think of a
baby food jar
or deli cups um about that size
you can have multiple plants in each one
of those vessels are each one of
our cuttings in in in one of those
vessels
and if you have good healthy stock in
those vessels then you're off to the
races
and so it really comes down to the um
the ip of the nutrient that's within
that media on
what your actual multiplication rate can
be but on average let's just
let's say at least two to four x so one
cut gives you
two or four additional plants um after
about four weeks is the way we think
about it so i think that's probably
the the most um popularized
understanding of
of of tissue culture for any plant um
in cannabis in particular to me the
reason why i do it
is because we are dealing with a plant
that was grown
underground first for obviously
decades and decades and decades um
and bred for one thing only
and that was not disease resistance it
was bred for
obviously cannabinoid um production and
and
and high thc in particular so we have
plants that are
pretty weak to environmental stresses
and
and diseases that come along with it and
so tissue culture
allows us to try to eradicate those
diseases
and generate stock and a lot of it as
i was explaining and and when done right
and um using testing to to verify
we we should be able to produce a lot of
clones that
don't have known diseases and
that's really why why i do it because
we're dealing with
i think an epidemic when it comes to
diseases because we do have some
you know a very a focused
um breeding for so long that it's gonna
take a while for these breeders
um and there's a lot of great ones out
there uh busy working
and and and doing this to generate more
strains that are that are
um resistant to various environmental
stresses and diseases
so that's really interesting that you
mention
pathogens and diseases that are
affecting the plant
coincidentally here in medicinal
genomics
we're developing an assay actually we
just released an assay
um to test for viruses within the plant
mostly poplatine thyroid lettuce
chlorosis virus and
cannabis cryptic virus and i'll i'll say
the response that we've gotten
from the cultivator community around
those
assays has been very strong
which seems to jive with what you were
just saying that
there seems to be a bit of an epidemic
when it comes to
um diseases among the cannabis plants so
it's very interesting that you say
uh that you say that just because um
we've been experiencing
that ourselves too so so maybe that's a
good
place good um topic to get into as far
as how can tissue culture be used to
remediate plants that maybe are showing
some signs of infection
so um yeah i love your guys's company i
love companies like
yours because um we need the ability to
be able to test and there's not enough
companies out there doing it and so the
cost of it is still really high
because of that and many people are
still becoming educated about the
process of testing and how frequently to
do it so i think uh the more that
companies like yourself
others um consultants and nurseries like
myself who are um
out there you know helping these
uh cultivators be able to produce
um and and and produce on margins that
are getting smaller and smaller
we must have the ability to be able to
test and then we must be able to do
something about it once we
find out let's just get to one of the
big ones the hot blatant viroid for
example right um so once you get that
sucker
what the hell are we going to do and so
um
with plant tissue cultures so so the
strawberry industry is a really good
example strawberries are very
susceptible to various um
pathogens and and viruses and viroids
and i'm just going to use disease
as a generic term that is every kind of
a fungal bacterial virus viroid as a
generic and then
probably just use hot plate and viroid
for the sake of our conversation for
something
as a specific example when it comes to
one of those um
but strawberry is really susceptible to
disease and so what they
have done is they have generated clean
stock
and this is because uh using uh plant
tissue culture
and since um uh mark had previously
discussed
how you know the various stages to go
through that well once you go through
those stages so i'm not going to
go back over it but once you go through
those various stages well we can keep
testing and it doesn't take a big
sample size to do that we don't need to
flower the plant out we don't even need
to take it out of its vessel we can
continue to test
throughout the process so um
the the the what do we do once we know
that we have it so i
here's here's a common uh day in the
life of hope jones
um i get a call from a particular
company who's really struggling with
yields
and let's let's just say they used to
have their favorite
strain um and it used to produce yields
and uh
that and and percentages and and now
this strain is no longer doing that
well because just like with covid
out for us and our pandemic well plants
also get um
viruses and viroids and so with like the
hoplite and viroid
you have to know what the symptoms are
to be able to identify it
well we have a problem because obviously
there's not enough understanding out
there within these companies to
to a know what the symptoms necessarily
are
until um oftentimes it's too late and so
when i show up at somebody's facility
i've seen these symptoms now for so long
that i'm just
ah you know i put my hands in my pockets
i'm not touching anything i don't want
to tour anymore i know exactly what i'm
dealing with and the reason why i do
that is because
these diseases almost every single time
are very easily transmitted by us right
so
uh we call that um you know mechanical
or
yeah mechanical transmission and so i
can take
a plant from their facility and um
my r d lab in arizona is is hemp and so
i'm taking a plant from somebody's
facility back to my lab
and i'm working with taking cuts from
this plant i'm sending it to a third
party lab for testing and identification
of these diseases so i always know what
i'm
looking at but now i'm going to start
the process of trying to dissect the
smallest parts
of that plant that i can that will
survive in tissue culture and oftentimes
that's that's that meristematic cells
well why do i why do we do that well we
know from
decades and decades of research and
other plants that have
these various diseases and the reason
why this is this particular disease is
hoplite and thyroid is it was originally
identified in hops
closely related um plant to us makes a
lot of secondary metabolites just like
our plants do
has resin glands just like ours so
that's a pretty good place to
to study and so just like we see
reduction in yields will so
do the hop growers they were seeing you
know um
in papers back into the early 80s when
it was
really identified and characterized you
know reductions in and
oil production by up to 40 percent uh
fewer
lateral branching and which you know
that's going to give you less biomass
all of these problems right and so very
similar to what we're seeing
plus we've had companies out there
identify
um and characterize the hoplaton viroids
so if i can take the smallest piece
possible and if i can learn from these
other plants um species where the
highest density of
of these particular particles are in the
plant
i'm going to try to avoid taking
cuttings from that part of the plants
and i'm going to try to go
and and and you know it's theorized
anyway that
hot blatant virus seems to really
populate
in the roots in the base of the plants
and so
is that true in cannabis it's it's yet
to be wholly characterized and
determined so but i'm gonna
actually say i'm gonna go for the tips
anyway
and i'm going to take as the healthiest
tips that i can
and i'm going to take those meristematic
cells and why the meristem instead of
the node
i'm going to do that is because a lot of
these diseases have a tendency to
localize and travel through the plant in
the vascular system
conveniently the meristematic cells are
not connected to the vascular system so
if we carefully excise that those
meristematic cells from
the rest of the plant we may be able to
um rescue tissue that does not harbor
any of that
disease or those viroid particles
so that's the idea and that's how it's
been done and and so many other plant
species
strawberries turn this into a very um
feasible
process and it's still commercially
viable right and so
i'm going to use a model out there that
and approach that
with cannabis in the same way because
that's a
industry that's focused on um providing
in their industries in any industry but
cannabis certified stock
that is disease free or at least free
of the disease that they're um
specifically testing for
so we can't do that and and we don't we
should be able to do that but there's
just not a system set up to do that but
if you are working with plant tissue
culture companies
um those would be the things that i
would ask what are you testing for
how are you going about that process how
can you be sure
um that when i get it that it doesn't
have that particular virus or viroid or
whatever your problem is but
that's our approach that's why we do it
and
financially if we get to a point where
we're constantly dealing with this like
they have with a hot blatant viroid and
and other viruses in the hop industry
just to
you know continue with that example
they've been dealing with this for 30
years of research
and they've yet to eradicate it and
they're seeing they and the reason why
they spent
all of that time and put in you know
decades and decades of research
is because it affects the bottom line
yes it affects the
taste and the bitterness and all of that
that comes about those secondary
metabolites that are produced like those
alpha acids that
that's being used but we're seeing those
reductions too
right and so that hurts and we cannot
continue
down that road so we've got to try to
attack um
this problem from multiple approaches
and tissue cultures but one
now it sounds like tissue culture is
really used when
you know a problem has been identified
and you're trying to kind of salvage the
plant but can it be used sort of
proactively as your propagation
technique and will that always produce
something that's
that's clean it should if it's done
right
if if the individuals that are doing the
the plant tissue culture are are
tracking their
their rounds of multiplication if
there's more um you know
if the ability to use molecular markers
allows us to make sure we're not getting
dna variants which can happen
um that would be wonderful but at least
we know the chemical profiles and if the
plants that are being produced are
still producing the expected chemical
profiles because
again the goal is to produce a clone not
to produce a variant
and so yeah we should be able to produce
that's why that you see more nurseries
tissue culture nurseries coming about
because there's no reason in the world
why we should not be able to produce
clones
at a commercial scale there's a cost
that comes with it but anything in our
industry comes with certain costs and
it's not for everybody but
you don't necessarily have to be good at
everything if there's nurseries and
there's options for um you know being
able to purchase that from
from neighboring companies absolutely
so you mentioned dna variants which
stuck out to me because
again here at medicinal genomics we do
we do a little sequencing work on
cannabis as well so
i'm curious um so what sort of
variations can you see
as a result from tissue culture so
you know what we can see in in cannabis
we're going to have to just compare to
other plant species that that's been
very well
characterized in the literature um even
those companies
you know like myself and other good
companies around the country
and canada other places in the world are
doing amazing research
but they don't always publish that and
so
it's going to be a long time before we
know all the types of dna variants
but in in many other plant species it's
known that you can get
um if it's not if you're if you're not
approaching
your tissue culture correctly if if you
want to maintain clones but you're
you're doing something and your media is
not right or you end up getting what's
called a lot of callous cells
those are undifferentiated cells that
develop what happens when a plant
forms a bunch of undifferentiated cells
is that
well they're not actually
signaled to do anything yet so they
they're not signaled to be a stem
they're not necessarily signaled to be
a root they're not necessarily signaled
to be uh
you know uh a leaf or another node
they're just
there which means if any kind of signal
or
or or change happens well it's going to
go with it and so i'm being
over simple kind of oversimplifying the
idea but
you can get a lot of what's called dna
off types or dna variants that happen
from that where each cell
out of that puddle or a pile of callous
cells can
can have a different expression is it
because of an actual
genetic change something that happened
to the chromosome
well it depends on what the stressor was
if there was something to cause dna
damage
that can absolutely happen just during
normal rounds of replica
dna replication as the cell divides you
can get
dna replication errors so that
definitely happens and if you
then propagate those cells up
into new um shoot material and then
you're
putting it on a different media to get
roots well then now you're going to see
different expressions
potentially depending on what those
genetic changes were
not everything's always um visual but
often times they can be
and so that's just one example and when
you have a pile of cells and cow cells
that are all
undifferentiated you can have millions
of cells depending on
on how many cells are there right so
they're very small and so you can
imagine that you
now have just in the size of like a dime
potentially cells that could have a
bunch of different genotypes and
it's not dna actual something that's
modifying the dna you might see
epigenetic changes
so epigenetic changes can are things
that
happen over time due to some sort of
environmental cue
that causes the cell that
it might have a localized response or it
might have a systemic response right and
if if a plant is constantly getting
some sort of um
signal because they can't move right so
they have to adapt to their environment
and so they're going to these these
signals can then all of a sudden
induce a regulatory pathway
up regulation down regulation what have
you and and those when
can can also happen in a bunch of
callous cells
and so you're going to see different
epigenetic effects
and i think one way i like to think
about it um
where i where my labs at i don't know
what the hell but
this parking lot every that there's one
way to
you know drive down and park your car
but for some reason people like to drive
the other way right and so that now
causes me
every single time i'm leaving my you
know getting in my truck to
you know not you you don't assume
anymore and you're constantly
looking on both directions and going
slow because it's a busy parking lot
whereas if you were in a different
environment you would have never had
that
signal so you would never be really
hyper sensitive to having to do that
you know i i think um you can imagine
how if you had a bunch of cells that
all of a sudden had some sort of signal
changes in chromosome structure
different dna or rna methylation
patterns are happening and now you can
check out a library book that you never
had access to and now you're getting a
different expression so
it can also be used for good it doesn't
it just means
why are we doing it how are we
approaching it do we want clonal
production or actually do we want to
kind of
get into that r d side of stuff it
depends
yeah that's really interesting i mean i
understand the epigenetic
part of it and i know that that can even
happen
um with clones like in traditional
cloning but um
are you saying though that with tissue
culture there can actually be
actual changes to the dna sequence or is
it more of an epigenetic sort of
response both both
wow that's interesting you know again
are there papers out there
and cannabis um that have done canvas
tissue culture that have looked at
molecular markers actually thankfully
there are a few papers out there and
there's
um only going to be more and more coming
so we do
have molecular markers like like like
your company is actually a great
resource to be able to
to to start um utilizing
the power of what a molecular marker can
do for us right so we can not only
um the ability to sequence something so
we can see if there's been major
genetic changes we can also look at
molecular markers to see
if we're having amplification of
something or if it's completely
disappeared
and it is known in other plant species
yes both
actual changes to dna can happen and
epigenetic changes
if and and because of all that you know
decades and decades of research
most of us in the cannabis tissue
culture industry know that
and we are cognitive of
if even if we don't have molecular
markers or sequencing
everything is is there are there logical
approaches that we can take to
mitigate that or you know try to
mitigate that risk
there are because of all those decades
of research and
other plant species and so um it's
careful selection of your medias it's
it's it's looking for those that callous
those callus formations um you know at
the base of of your nodal plants
as you're doing your tissue culture for
example not not doing callus unless you
really want to so there are approaches
that are
you know well described and
at least we have a logical way to
approach it and then
ideally after uh plants gone through
culture that you
even if you're not sequencing it you
should be flat you know we obviously
want to flower it out make sure it still
has the same chemical profile because
clonal tissue culture should not change
what its dna potential what its genetic
potential should be it shouldn't
be introducing you know genes for
limonene for example to create new
terpenes unless
but unless that plant actually already
had the genetic code to be able to
produce that
um particular um compound
so you do the um flowering out you look
for the chemical profile but you also
look for
the architecture and the group the habit
of this particular
strain so if it's a strain that you know
very well
you know likely what its growth habit is
and you know what its chemical profile
should be and it should
be performing um
pretty damn well compared to what what
what you started with
before you gave it um a a tissue culture
bath shall we say
no that's really fascinating and at the
risk of
the risk of plugging medicinal genomics
yet again
we recently came out with a snip chip
which is sort of a more cost effective
way to
to get some sequencing information on
the plant without having to do you know
full-on sequencing it's more of a snip
panel and i wonder if a tool like that
would be useful
for tissue culture um just to you know
screen against
the original plant to just make sure
that there's no
differentiation between the the snips
that are being called
my god man yes the simple answer is just
yes um you know i think
any of us doing plant tissue culture
would love to be able to
to utilize tools like that whether
with a third party and sending it off or
in-house but
just yes absolutely and
my my favorite
my favorite r d and thing to do
in this industry is to be working with
breeders and and other growers
on on on a a breeder spending a lot of
time the good breeders um
to generate these new genetics right and
so
they should be rewarded for that i want
to be able to
to get their genetics out in the
marketplace and they should be able to
feel confident when their genetics are
in the marketplace that
their genetics are in fact true to type
that they are optimal so then that way
there's
um there's there's accountability
on on all ends that a the we get
we get to choose we're you know we are
the consumers right we get to choose
what we buy
who we do business with and and and all
of that
comes down to why would we want to do
that and and and to me
i would want to do business with
somebody who was in fact utilizing tools
like you were just describing
and then working with readers to be able
to protect the integrity of their
genetics but also be able to
protect their genetics right so if they
wanted to validate or if they want if
there was a dispute about genetics you
know um
it's it's been a long time for these
breeders to be able to say okay
i i spent years you know generating this
particular strain
my god you know the fact that it can
just get out there should be a choice
for them to make
not just because somebody can just take
it and
in horticulture and agriculture if you
see you know the hot new
um you know rose that's out on the
market
and there's a always a tag that goes
along with it the reason why there's a
tag is because those companies that
generated those particular
um cultivars are those
are getting paid right there's a royalty
that goes with that and if
some company ends up selling that
particular rose
without the proper licensing rights well
then
a obviously um you have the ability to
use
markers or snips and sequencing to be
able to
um you know to enforce your trademark
patent or whatever it might be
but then if somebody is actually growing
something of yours as well
you want to make sure that whoever is
selling that product or representing
that product on your behalf
is doing it in the right way and using
markers for example or just
understanding the genome
is a good way to actually have the best
understanding of in this environment
the plant when grown under these
conditions with these substrates with
this nutrient solution
so when you buy something again from a
nursery it typically comes with
those climate light and other
requirements because
if somebody's growing something of yours
and they're just excuse my language but
they're just
a shitty grower well that represents
that i mean it's a reflection of their
brand potentially
right and so all of these tools can be
used
for all aspects of our industry it's
just pretty complicated right now
as our industry is still very young
absolutely and that's a common common
refrain in a lot of these conversations
i'm having with folks is that you know
the industry has a lot of learning to do
has a lot of growing up to do we have a
lot to learn
um which is exciting i mean
bring it we get to be at that point and
it's
such a you know this is a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to be a
part of a
brand new industry and something that's
so huge
awesome definitely and that's why we
love doing
doing canmed as well to bring all these
people together from the different
facets of the
the industry whether it be cultivation
or safety testing or even the
healthcare professionals who are using
the medicine uh to treat patients too
um to really learn from each other and
kind of
see where we can help each other and
move this whole thing forward so that's
what's exciting
and you guys are really great at doing
that and for the education of everybody
because we all do want to learn right we
we don't want to stay small shitty
growers forever or
or struggling with a lot of this stuff
this is not why we do this so it's
awesome i mean you guys are really
really um important
uh avenues for this and so
we talked about how to use maybe tissue
culture to remediate plants that are
infected with pathogens but
i do know that your company um emerging
cannabis sciences you also
work with integrated pest management
systems to sort of maybe
prevent things like this from happening
um i was wondering if you could speak a
bit to that and kind of how that can be
used in cannabis
in hemp cultivation most important
acronym of my life
ipm um integrated pest management um
it is the most important um thing in
any cannabis company and i don't care if
you're a company that only does retail
because
you can't have a retail operation if you
don't have any
product to put in the shelves and if you
don't
actually care about the product on your
shelf
you know people are going to get wise
and they're going to shop elsewhere
right i mean we want
good quality predictable
product and the only way to do that is
actually to be aware
of all your cultural practices and it
the the ipm
um is absolutely critical it's it's
about
first of all the genetics as soon as
they are coming into your your facility
i think one of the biggest mistakes that
i see um and i
love seeing like the easy light bulb
moment it's like everything must go into
quarantine
right so that's not a pesticide so
integrated pest management isn't
only about pesticides or scouting and
looking for
actual insects it is about how to
mitigate that risk in general you'll
always have problems as a grower
what can we do to mitigate our risk and
so it starts with
as soon as you have genetics coming into
your facility as clones
or if you're popping seeds you've got to
have some sort of place to be able to
isolate those plants
until you have an understanding of their
health status before you
introduce them into your you know mother
population
and to me that's probably the number one
thing that most companies
don't they may think about it or maybe
they're not
i'm sure how to go about it and it does
take space out of your growing and you
know um
square footage and and so a lot of times
nobody necessarily wants to do that and
so but it has to be done
because almost well everything that i
see in cannabis when it comes to any
disease
happens through mechanical transmission
and if you are bringing in
i take in people's problems for a living
so i'll i'll you know get
um hemp genetics and i'm opening up
literally a mite bomb right because i'm
getting these
these cuts and then i'm we're checking
them in
which is another thing that is really
critical um for
uh ipm uh strategy what i mean by
checking them in while
physically looking at the damn thing
before i you know just throw it in a
population i
have a uh it doesn't you don't have to
have something crazy expensive just a
microscope that allows you to be able to
see
things like russet mites and small eggs
um
but yeah so you're i'm opening up and
it's just like oh
russet mites right so what am i going to
do am i going to just throw that into my
population no i
i now then have to have the next step
what do i do
for all incoming plants i need to be
able to isolate it i need to have a
strategy
for any what pesticides i can use in my
state what i
should be using what i what i shouldn't
be using and then
immediately make sure that my staff is
appropriately trained to be able to
handle and and do all of that and then
follow it up with a specific regime so
this is again
all independent of tissue culture but i
do the same thing
in my own lab so i'll have um
grow tents and i actually you know those
disposable gowns in hospitals the yellow
ones that you see everybody wearing all
the time
so i'll actually take that and i on the
inside i'll duct tape that around
any orifice of the tent right so
because i don't want anything to get in
and i don't want anything to get out
if that's all we can do then that's all
we can do but at least we're doing
something
and then only certain people can go in
and out
and then i'm only putting something into
my
um general population once i know
i'm not introducing a white bomb to the
rest of the other moms because
guess what's going to happen and and the
mothers
are the most important most valuable
thing in any company
because if something happens to your
mothers if we don't
quickly quickly identify which means
you have to train your staff on what to
look for and then immediately
get rid of it yes it might be the last
one of that strain but if it
has a virus or a viroid unless you're
going to immediately remove it and put
it in your tissue culture facility or to
another tissue culture company
you will spread that disease you
absolutely will
so why around let's get rid of it
let's move it out
and yes you're gonna have to source
another genetic if that's your last one
but
it's either that or it's going to be you
know
within probably the you know six months
to the next two years
you know you can expect to see a
significant decrease in your yields over
time so
paying staff to to be vigilant about
identifying it
um purchasing clean stock from companies
that actually can provide a different
type of coa is another thing
um that i think is really critical for
us all to become educated and get
in a habit of asking about we know how
to ask for coas when it comes to
chemical profiles
or compliance for state but there are
agriculture laboratories and
companies like you that do this testing
and work with companies like mine that
say okay i'm doing this process when it
leaves my hands
here's the test report that shows at
least when i tested it for
these particular diseases it was
negative
so you know at that point can we say
disease free or virus free well
at least when it's leaving my hands
according to the coa
um it appears that it's it's testing
negative
i think we all need to understand that
we should start asking for that
because i don't want to bring anything
into my house
unless i know that at least that bare
minimum
um has been done um especially since i'm
oftentimes spending a hell of a lot of
money for these genetics right
um so so i think um and then just
it's you've got to have a sanitation
process in and and
there's so many good resources about how
to do ipm scouting why you would want to
do that
and then consultants like myself and
many other consultants around the
country this is what we do we help train
your teams we help bring that
method in um and then it's
just a learn curve it's just like yeah
nobody likes to wear a mask but
you know i don't think about it anymore
but i can't tell you at the beginning
how many times i'd have to turn around
right before i get to the the door of
the damn store because i left the mask
in my car right
but i don't do that anymore so it will
take some time
and it has to be accepted and practiced
and prioritized from the top down
because
if somebody doesn't want to pay for
testing are you going to throw that plan
away if somebody you know if if the boss
is like oh my god that's my strain blah
blah what
okay but what do you want me to do with
it as the grower right and if your boss
is telling you to keep it and you have
no place to put it
this is how these companies are getting
themselves into trouble and so i think
there's a few things to learn and then
there's just the cultural practices that
there's so many great resources out
there companies and consultants to help
you
if just get you over the hump
yeah and you and you mentioned masks and
sort of this whole
shared pandemic experience that we're
all going through and
i wonder if if cultivators and growers
will be
more aware of potential
infestations whether it be from viruses
or pests or anything like that
sort of because we're all going through
this experience and it's
it's been so top of mind and maybe
you're already seeing that are you
seeing that cultivators are being much
more cognizant of
you know potential infections you know
it's a really good question i will tell
you
um the immediate thing that i have
noticed is
i don't have to explain as much people
it's get it now
it can get virus because when i started
giving these um talks it really actually
took like a year
before people would believe truly
believe that
plants can get a virus or a viroid and
so i was like oh my god yes it can
and again that was just because why
would they need to know that before
um so anyway so and then the idea of
like okay these cultural practices of
wearing gloves
so when i started the industry a little
over five years ago
i was working for a company and they
still when they were doing the pinching
they were still doing that
with their thumbnail with no gloves
and i was like why would you do that
um because you know having had the
experience working with
with plant diseases i mean it's just i
would never
in a million years think to do that but
that's because i've gone through it and
this company hadn't gone through that
yet
so yeah everybody we put ppe stations
and and the first thing i do for most my
consultants is
where are your ppe stations so the uh
protective
um uh supplies that we need like gloves
and and and and the refills for your
your bleach or your vircon for your
shears and stuff that it's actually
killing the virus because you can't use
alcohol
um little thing for everybody out there
so where is all of those supplies
i call those the ppe stations well guess
what
i know how i am and if i have to get up
to go get a new pair of gloves
my god i'm not going to do it right make
it easy for me make it easy for
everybody just to be able to do it you
don't want to have a box of gloves just
at one door on the entry you want to
have
gloves and gloves of every size and have
stations throughout your facility
and then it becomes people will do it
it's not like they don't want to do it
it's just if you if it's not you know
you know planned and actually done in a
way that's going to be successful for
people then
you know it gets to be up to a point
where it's like ah forget it you know
i'm not gonna
if i can't find anything i'm gonna use
alcohol at least i'm using alcohol
um well that's the worst thing we want
to do for
uh virus because unlike with people and
we can use
you know hand sanitizer and alcohol and
you saw all that happen with
the the data in the literature is that
alcohol is not
really the most effective thing for for
plant uh viruses and viroids and
that's why you've got to use the bleach
and other products that have been tested
and shown out there like virkon that
will work
you've got to leave that stuff out you
have to have it prepped up i mean just
make it easy for everybody and so
since the pandemic it has been very easy
for
these companies to get it they get it
quickly
um and they understand mechanical
transmission
more now than i think anybody would ever
want to
unless you do what i do well that's an
interesting point about alcohol not
being an effective
sanitation method maybe for lack of a
better term when it comes to plants
that's interesting i didn't know that
it will work with a lot of other like
fungal
and bacterial um um
microbial contaminants um and and i
think a lot more needs to be done
to see what products out there are in
fact effective against
specific or particular plant viruses or
viroids
the reason why there's going to be a
different mode of action is because
we're talking about
different kinds of things so a dna or
rna
molecule versus you know a single cell
organism
right so there you can ima you can
understand
thinking about it from that approach
that different chemicals are going to
have
different effects on on those on those
things so
yeah the the much of the literature out
there uh looking and at least studying
things like uh tobacco mosaic viruses
which is one of the worst things um to
get because it's
damn near impossible to eradicate even
with plant tissue culture
and it just is persistent it i mean it
will stay
in you know soil or water or or i mean
it'll just stay
there as as a kind of a latent particle
until it gets into
a favorable environment and then off it
goes again
um same with the hop latent viroid right
um we don't
quite understand the mechanism of of
a its duration how long it you know is
it viable for what
environmental parameters can really kill
it but there's still
quite a bit of data out there to show
it's a tough one and
when they did some studies and field
trials this was
gosh i think back in the 80s and over in
germany or the uk
they were looking at field studies of
hop
late and viroid and and they were
studying to see how they could treat the
farm
or the fields right so if you're
planting this crop and think about the
hot uh hemp farmers
if you're planting seed that came from
infected moms with a hot plate and
viroid
and the probability of those seeds being
infected is
really high well that's going to be now
in your soil so now you have soil
and there's a lot of marijuana growers
out there too outdoors and in the fields
so now you haven't
and your soil is in at least infected
with these
um virus what do you do and so they were
looking to see
what chemicals and compounds that they
could use but also with the
farm equipment looking at their blades
during harvest
and what they needed to do and really
when it comes down to it we're still
looking at
the same thing that we've known for a
long time and it comes down to bleach
and a few
other chemicals out there that are on
the market but
10 bleach my friend it's tough on the
sheers but
would you rather you know suffer with
losing your moms and having to pay a
bunch of companies to get
like myself to clean them up or buy you
know thousands and thousands of dollars
in new genetics more frequently
um than you would like or buy some
shears every couple months
i i think to me the the business answer
there is pretty clear
so you mentioned that some viruses or
viroids
might be difficult to tissue culture out
um one of the things i wanted to ask you
about is i know i'm kind of vaguely
familiar with the idea of of keeping
plants
suspended in tissue culture as maybe
like a preservation tactic
um could that be like a feasible
strategy to sort of
have a tissue culture of a mom kind of
just in case
that mom does get sick instead of trying
to tissue culture something out you
could
sort of create a new one out of clean
stock is that um
is that a strategy yeah yeah it is and i
have
many customers that actually uh do that
because you don't want to keep
you know your your entire library
doesn't need to be you know
living in in your mother's space so
that's one advantage for doing that
um and you can companies uh you know
when we do plant tissue culture there's
a couple ways that we can maintain that
stock
um oh with the fires too or or the
hurricanes right if something just
happens and
and everything's gone because well
i mean everything that happened this
past
several years and this past year in
particular is horrible
so if you lose everything and because
you're just trying to save yourself um
uh and you lose your genetics what are
you gonna do well
um week um so we do this and this is a
service that we provide
um where we can do uh seed
banking so we can do that in um
liquid nitrogen so there's gene banks
plant gene banks all over the world and
and and they do this with liquid
nitrogen so just like you have you've
heard of
uh you know are for stem cells and cell
um those kinds of banks but plant
banking is
a very common thing and we just have to
do the r d and that's what i've spent
the last several years actually
you know fiddling around with in my lab
here in tempe
is is to actually work through that
again we start with kind of known stuff
out in the literature that's worked
in other similar plant species and we
just start things like can we just keep
it in
like refrigerated like temperatures for
a longer period of time than
keeping it on the shelf and having to
you know actively
keeps um subculturing it every couple
months in media drying out and this kind
of stuff
yeah we can can we actually preserve it
in liquid nitrogen so we call it you
know
cryopreservation um as seed and tissue
absolutely and so that's that's huge
because again if
if you want to have instead of limiting
yourself to the number
of strains in your library based off of
square footage in your mom room well now
it's a
couple tubes in a deer tank or some
shelf space
and a walk-in cooler or with
nurseries and companies like myself and
so that i think those are
all advantages uh to the industry for
for tissue culture
again this is early days for companies
um that are doing this
um tissue culture and preservation and
it's just important to know they're not
gonna have
all the answers just yet and they're
they're the good companies should tell
you what they've done
what's still not necessarily done like
you know i haven't been in business
and and and been able to pull tissue or
seed out you know five years after being
preserved in liquid nitrogen
and check for viability nobody has right
so
but companies should be open to have
that dialogue with anybody who's
interested in those services
and and it should i think let the
industry know that
at least this is a company with some
integrity and and we're all going to
give it the best shot
but and also there's no research out
there right so
like the hop industry well there's hops
industry associations where
you know um every um all poundage that's
sold
goes a certain fraction of that goes
into
uh for research and development as an
industry to pay for things for studying
all of these viruses and virals and
other diseases and hops
we're so young as an industry we have
nothing like that and so these companies
like myself who are out there and and
are providing these services are doing
it
all on our own and and yes
it's going to take a little bit longer
for that but at least know that it's
coming and then companies like yours
that are providing services so i use
the services all the time because i
don't necessarily have the sequencing or
being able to do the arrays within my
own facility
um you know i hope to grow up and one
day and be able to have a lab like that
too
and so um it's just all a matter of time
and baby
but at least there's more companies like
ours that are out there providing the
services
and and as consumers of those
products and services we have to just
learn to ask better questions and know
what the pros cons and and and you know
yet to be determined are
and yet again just another example of
how um
or just another example of sort of the
value of everyone coming together at an
annual event like a canmed
to to share what we've learned we've
learned over the past year
and continue to help each other sort of
grow up and
move this whole industry forward so i
think maybe that's a good place to
start i know that i've i've kept you
long over the the time that i
i promised i would keep you and i
promised i would have
a lot to offer so i i appreciate your
patience
and and actually asking me to
participate in this um i really do
and i miss being in person but we still
have this and it's
it's something for us um to be you know
all night in the hood trust me i'm
listening to a lot of podcasts
thank you for doing it absolutely and
thank you and
i look forward to seeing you out in
pasadena for canmed
heck yeah thanks
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
hope jones
check out the links in the show
description for more information about
the topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor
medicinal genomics
our next episode will drop january 27th
in the meantime please go to
canmedevents.com
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you into a drawing to
win two tickets to our canmed 2021 vip
dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
canmed2021
if social media is your thing you can
find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for can med events
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast
app go ahead and hit the subscribe
button so that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and please leave us a five star review
as well alright that's it from us
as always stay safe stay healthy and be
sure to come back for the next episode
of kmed coffee talk
[Music]
you