[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year
head over to canmedevents.com now to
learn all about
our canmed 2021 event that will take
place
september 29th through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets at our
special early bird rate
while you're at camminevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page which you can find in the
main menu
under the media tab you can also go
there directly by going to
cannemedevents.com
coffeetalk there is a sign up form on
that page
and if you complete it you will be
entered into a drawing to win
two canmed2021 vip dinner tickets
while you are there you can also listen
to all the canmed coffee talk podcast
episodes
in our archive on this episode i had the
pleasure of talking with dr
andrew horowitz who is the vice
president of r
d at cestina bio llc
previously andrew managed the
cannabinoid r d
program at dimetrix where he helped
develop the process for using
genetically modified yeast cells
to produce cannabinoids we discuss
the advantages of using yeast cells to
produce cannabinoids instead of cannabis
and hemp
plants how adjusting the precursor
molecules that are fed to the yeast
cells can produce rare and novel
cannabinoids how cannabis medicine
researchers can use this technology
to better understand the entourage
effect why
understanding the way cannabis plants
produce cannabinoids was essential
to developing this technology and how
this technology
is received by the cannabis community
before we get to my conversation with
andrew i want to thank this episode
sponsor
demetrix
demetrix is a biotechnology company that
believes in the power of science to make
the world
a better place the company produces safe
legal and effective health and wellness
products backed by science
including rare high purity cannabinoids
for pharmaceutical
and consumer applications to learn more
please visit the demetrix website at
demetrixbio.com
and be sure to check out their blog at
dmitrixbio.com
insights and as always this episode of
the canmed coffee talk is fueled by the
hemp and coffee exchange
if you don't know by now hemp coffee is
a healthy delicious
natural product rich in trace minerals
and nutrients
providing sustained energy without the
crash of regular coffee
for more information check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
10 off your purchase
okay now that we've gotten that out of
the way i hope you enjoy my conversation
with andrew horowitz
[Music]
good morning andrew thanks for joining
us thanks ben good to be here
i'm really excited to talk to you with
you today because the topic we're going
to discuss
which is synthetic biology and i guess
more specifically
using genetically engineered yeast to
create cannabinoids
is just a fascinating topic and i know
you've presented a camid
2019 on that topic and i've included a
link to that video
in the show notes for people to take a
look at um
and it got a great great response so i'm
really excited to dig into more detail
around that but
for those who aren't familiar with this
process or maybe haven't watched the
video yet
i was hoping we could start and you
could um
use you could perform a little explain
like i'm five
the the process of using yeast to create
cannabinoids
yeah sure so um the the basic idea here
is that you
obviously cannabinoids are made in the
cannabis plant normally
and that occurs through a series of
chemical reactions that the plant
is essentially conducting inside the
inside the plant cells and then in the
trichomes
and so those those reactions each each
step in that kind of assembly line to
build the final molecules
is uh controlled by a protein or an
enzyme
that basically manipulates the precursor
chemicals into the final chemical
each of those enzymes is uh you know the
blueprint for that assembly line
it's encoded by genes in the plant and
so so basically the whole idea of
biotech in general
and you know specifically for using
yeast to create cannabinoids is that
what we do is we identify those genes in
the plant which is
actually quite a difficult task but we
identify the genes
um when you get them all together you
say you've identified the full pathway
and then we put those genes into a yeast
cell and you say well why would you use
yeast
well it's because yeast are are quite
easy to manipulate genetically
and there's just a ton of knowledge on
how to grow them to really high
densities and gigantic fermentation
tanks
and then they can just spit out those
cannabinoids that you've you've put in
by
that genetic pathway
so you're essentially identifying the
genes in the plant
and then
you're identifying the genes that are in
the plant that are creating these
compounds
and then genetically engineering them
into yeast how are
how is that accomplished is that crispr
or some other technique
yeah so there's all sorts of ways to put
genes into yeast and i think crispr is
um you know the most recent uh trick for
getting getting foreign dna
into a into a microbe and crispr is
really powerful but there are
there are a number of ways one could do
it um but in the end essentially you're
you're getting the yeast cell to take up
a piece of foreign dna and
and um splice it into its own genome
that's fascinating and i know that in
the
in the canmed video you sort of
explained first
how the plant creates these cannabinoids
and one of the things that was really
interesting was that the conversion of
cbg to thc
and cbda actually occurs outside of the
cell
in the trichome which was really
interesting um
but i don't want to steal your thunder i
was hoping that you could
maybe explain briefly how the plant
creates
the cannabinoids yeah that's a that's a
great question because actually the way
that the plant does this chemistry and
this is some really interesting
chemistry that
and i'm not a chemist by the way i'm
going to talk about the biology but the
way that the plant does this chemistry
is both fascinating and creates a
difficult sec uh situation for the
genetic engineer who's trying to do this
in yeast
and so that's because um so in the plant
cell
um let me see how far to zoom back here
so when you're making cannabinoids
you you basically take two precursor
molecules
uh a livitolic acid and a molecule
called gpp
and fuse them together to make cbga and
and cbga so the a by the way when i'm
talking about cannabinoids
uh cbda thca you're hearing that a there
that's because the
the natural form of the plant is an acid
um
when when that natural form is heated up
uh the acid pops off it's decarboxylated
i think probably many listeners would be
familiar with that
at that point you get the more familiar
thc or cbd so it's the same for cbga
cbg is cbga
without the acid on it so just a quick
quick explanation there why i'm saying a
all the time so so cbga is the mother
cannabinoid and that
that's that molecule is produced in the
cell but then what's really interesting
is the final conversion of cbga into
these better known
cannabinoids like thca or cbda that
occurs
outside of the cell in this specialized
compartment called the trichome
and i think again most people have seen
pictures these are beautiful
uh structures in the plant it's when you
when you look at a a um
a bud uh cannabis bud you'll see the
crystalline kind of appearance on it
those are those are trichomes and so
trichomes are essentially um you know
chemical reaction chambers
where cvga can be converted
by enzymes called synthases cannabinoid
synthases
into thca that would be by the action of
the
the thca synthase or cbda by the cbda
synthase
those are the two major synthases it's
possible that those other synthases out
there like the cbca synthase
but those are the major ones and this
reaction is occurring outside of the
cell which is
which is somewhat unusual um and that's
what pose is really a
big challenge for the yeast engineer
who's trying to make cannabinoids inside
a yeast cell because as you can imagine
the situation in a trichome outside of
the cell different ph oily
is very different than the situation
inside a yeast cell so getting those
enzymes that are used to working in the
trichome to work in the yeast cell
i think represents one of the biggest
challenges for making cannabinoids by
biotech
so that's interesting so are there two
separate processes here first it's
creating that mother cannabinoid cbga
and then is there sort of a second
strain of yeast that's sort of doing the
synthase process
so i think that probably most people
would try to do it in the same strain
but
but you have a great point there which
is these are it's kind of like two very
different skill sets making cvga
which happens inside the yeast cell and
draws on these two precursor molecules
the lipitolic acid and gpp
that's one that's one challenge and then
it's almost an entirely separate
challenge to then convert that cbga so
it's
it's i know that folks have contemplated
doing these
these things in separate steps uh
certainly and um
because you're really looking for you
kind of need a an athlete that's
uh you know accomplished in two entirely
different events
so um i think that's a that's insightful
way to say it but i think ideally for a
for a fine economically feasible process
you would be
getting it all done in one one strain
would do the full conversion of
production of cbga and conversion into
the final thca or cbda product
so that's ideal but is that what is that
the reality right now or is that the
goal
so i think what you're seeing right now
is a lot of the um
a lot of the press releases i've seen
coming out from companies in the in the
you know biotech cannabinoids field have
been about cbga and about cbg
and cbg is a really interesting molecule
i think with a lot of of uh terrific
properties
i mean something i would say is that the
difficulty genetic engineering
difficulty does not necessarily
correlate with
the value of the molecule on a
biological basis so what i mean is that
it's you know it's more straightforward
to make cbga than it is to make thca or
cbda certainly
but cbga is a great target for biotech
as well and so
um i think that there's been you know
increasing awareness
of how cbga and the decarboxylated form
cvg
have a number of very interesting
effects that you know overlap in part
with uh
you know some of the profile of cbd for
example
so so i guess um i'm sure if i'm
answering your question exactly there
but i think i think that
cbga is a great first target for the
field
and i think that pulling that all the
way through to cbda and thca
is absolutely going to happen it's a
little more work
okay so if i'm understanding what you're
saying
are you saying that we're not there yet
are we able to create thca in cbda
through this process oh absolutely
absolutely and i think that's something
that's important to stress
is that um when you're doing strain
engineering to make biotech molecules
um there's there's a number of phases
there's the phase where you don't even
know what all the genes in the pathway
are
and that was kind of the situation i'll
say for example it
if you go back to the early days of
demetrics
demetrix was founded based on technology
coming out of jake's link lab
and jay had uh and his his team had
discovered a missing enzyme
in the pathway and so that's those are
the initial things right like we you
just have the the minimum number of
enzymes to make the product and then
you can detect the product right like
tiny vanishingly small amounts
and then you're making more and more of
the product and at some point you're
making so much of the product and you've
scaled it up that it's economically
feasible and you can go to market with
it
and so my point there about cbg was just
that
cbg because it is um you know
a step on the pathway towards cbd and
thc and the other
calling terminal cannabinoids there um
is
is something that i think the biotech
companies are able to hit first
because uh it's you know it's a partial
pathway
essentially so but definitely uh you
know a number of groups have shown
that thca and cbda can be made
okay and yeah i mean cbg is definitely
a a cannabinoid that's i on a lot of
people's radars
i i know especially on the cultivation
side trying to
create plants that are cbg rich
and of course that comes with its own
challenges of trying to find knockouts
in the synthase genes
so maybe that's a good place to kind of
step back a bit and
i was wondering if you could comment on
how does this approach
of creating cannabinoids how is it
what are the advantages to it over
traditional
cultivation yeah so i think that um
where where biotech makes a lot of sense
is when you're talking about rare
natural products
and that is what you know i don't
there's
there's i've said for a while i live in
california that
that getting high is a solved problem um
you know
it's i think a lot of the um in
california for sure
i think a lot of the interest here is in
these more we'll call them the minor
cannabinoids things like cbg
um things like cdc you know there's
there's just you know there's
over a hundred of these compounds right
and we know so little about most of them
so i think where biotech really shines
and where
um i think that it it really add
something
is is going after those more minor ones
um and there's been some amazing feats
of plant breeding
you know i i am not in that area at all
it's a different type of genetics i
don't know much about to be honest but
you know attending canmed in 2019 and
listening to some of these talks
it's clear that plant breeders are able
to do some pretty amazing things get to
get to
to plants that make some pretty rare
compounds and
you know amounts i wouldn't have thought
possible but it's still very hard um you
know you're
you're for example when you look at the
um you look at the barons for
uh example you're you're basically to
get to get high-level variant production
in a plant you would need to kind of
shift the
uh balance of fatty acid production in
the plant and these things again
anything's possible but it strikes me as
pretty difficult because the plant's
sole purpose is not just to produce
cannabinoids it obviously has to
support roots and leaves and growth and
all sorts of other things
so the advantage of the yeast cell in
biotech is that um
you know we can we can re-engineer the
yeast cell pretty radically it's a
single cell organism
it really just exists to produce more
yeast
and so we can redirect that energy um
and do things like uh you know
re-engineer
uh central metabolism in ways that let
us really focus on specific
rare cannabinoids and um so
you know to the extent that you're
trying to purify some rare cannabinoid
out of a bunch of plant biomass
away from other very similar but you
know cannabinoids that you don't want
that's that's much less of an issue in
yeast where we can we can essentially
put in a very specific pathway that gets
you from
you know point a to point b which is
your rare uh cannabinoid and and have
that be a single or
you know predominant product uh that's
that's secreted from the yeast cell
and so i think the advantage over over
agriculture
there's all sorts of advantages i mean
predictability
so the the product profile that you're
going to get coming out of the yeast
fermentation which is occurring inside a
stainless steel tank is going to be
much more consistent than what you're
going to see
out of a grow operation even an indoor
grow operation in
you know in a in a greenhouse you're
still dealing with you know whole plants
and you have less control over the
over the situation so that's one thing i
think the time
you know it takes about i would say one
to three weeks to do a biotech
fermentation process to make
cannabinoids
it's going to take um you know three
months to grow plants
um i think at the end you know i talked
a little bit about the purification
trying to purify
compounds out of a you know big plant
mess versus out of whole cell
fermentation broth
you get a cleaner product coming out
with biotech most often
um trying to think if i've hit
everything there
and then i think you know the the um the
other really
really cool thing and i talked about
this a little bit at canmed in 2019 is
that there's this
flexibility and optionality of the
fermentation platform
part of the part of the technology that
jay keisling described in
in his lab's paper on production of
cannabinoids and yeast and that
demetrics carried on was the ability to
feed these uh kind of precursor
molecules the fatty acids into the yeast
cell and have to be incorporated
into the molecule and so that allows you
to build a single strain
and then then produce you know either
for example cbd
or cbdv you know the varun's with
different different length tails on
these molecules and you can really just
customize that in a modular fashion by
feeding different fatty acids
so i think that in an unorganized way
covers covers some of the advantages of
biotech
just kind of precision purity
speed these are all all things that are
particularly important when you're going
after these very rare cannabinoids
yeah and i think that last point that
you were talking about was particularly
fascinating the the whole idea of
introducing different precursors to the
yeast
and then kind of being able to not
really mix and match but
like you said to customize different
cannabinoids
i wonder if you could speak a little bit
more to that and is it possible to
essentially create cannabinoids that we
haven't yet seen
naturally occurring in the plant yeah
absolutely and
i think that you know there's an example
of that in jay's paper as well
if you look at the paper they they um
use
called precursor feeding to get some
uh features on the molecule that don't
exist in nature and would would set that
cannabinoid up for further modification
through things like click chemistry
where you could create libraries
so that's that's what's known as a
semi-synthetic approach but
yeah absolutely you can make new to
nature cannabinoids in yeast
by a feeding fatty acid precursors that
don't exist in nature the yeast cell
sees these and just as great
and incorporates them into the pathway
pulls them into the pathway puts them in
the molecule
and so if you feed hexanoic acid which
is the
you know kind of canonical version of
the fatty acid then you get cbd
or thc but if you start feeding other
fatty acids you can
change the chain length and get these
other forms both natural
and unnatural
so i have to imagine researchers on
the the medical side or the healthcare
provider side or
maybe even you know kind of before that
sort of the the basic
um kind of drug development
side must be very interested in
exploring
that and being be very interested in
getting sort of
mass quantities of these rare
cannabinoids
yeah i think that's one of the value
propositions of biotech is the ability
to kind of
provide samples of these rare and new to
nature cannabinoids
for further testing um i mean
it's i think that you know when you
think about there's i guess a couple of
approved
fda approved drugs in the cannabinoid
family basically
you know maybe more than that but
roughly speaking thc and cbd so you got
marinol and epidiolex and then there's
some other variants of thc out there
and the question that i've kind of
struggled with is why
why aren't there more of these compounds
out there i mean they're so they're so
bioactive they're largely non-toxic
um it's a really interesting set of
chemical matter that seems underexplored
and i mean i think part of the reason's
structural
right it's been very difficult to do
research on cannabinoids for a long time
in this country
um but another another piece of it is
access i think it's
um you know if you're an academic
researcher trying to get a hold of these
rare cannabinoids
i mean it's you know they're present in
vanishing these small quantities and so
and the chemical synthesis to get to
these things is very very difficult
so it's very expensive to produce them
so i think that
yeah i think that one of the one of the
really exciting aspects of biotech
production of cannabinoids
the synthetic biology approach is is the
ability to get access
to researchers so we can start to really
better understand what the
medical applications for this rich
family of compounds could be
and now i have to ask too um
i have to ask about the entourage effect
um a lot of the
researchers i've spoken to healthcare
professionals you know they're
they're very i wouldn't say it's
unanimous but a
majority favor the sort of whole plant
medicine
with the idea of there being different
cannabinoid
concentrations or even terpenes that are
kind of
contributing to the medicinal effect how
can
this process sort of help them
mimic the entourage effect if they're
going to be doing some research
yeah i think the entourage effect is
really interesting because it's it's i
think it's been hard to get
you know solid data on it on on it just
because you're
again i mean one of the reasons why uh
most most drugs that approved by the fda
are single molecules is because
it's easy to understand then exactly
what the causal agent is etc and so
i think when you talk about the
entourage effect it gets very
complicated quickly and so i think that
you know something biotech could do
could be produce a palette
of individual compounds that could be
blended
in ways that would allow people to to
test these questions
um you know is the entourage effect and
the same in one strain produced in one
place as it is in another strain in
another place
probably not um you know i saw some
really interesting talks
at the 2019 canmed where um
people were looking at uh very fine
differences between
uh compositions of cannabis and seeing
very different effects and so
um for me it's it's really hard to tell
uh what's going on there
my my personal opinion um is that
uh the the cannabis plant did not
evolve to you know get as high
or to you know cure diseases this is you
know it's one of these things the
cannabis plant wants to make more
cannabis plants
and um my guess is that most of the
bioactivity of cannabis
comes from a very smooth few number of
compounds most of which are the
cannabinoids
but you know you absolutely can't rule
out the potential for
for synergistic effects for polypharmacy
so
yeah and i think it's a it's a
multi-faceted problem
and it's becoming more and more apparent
the more i talk to
people in different sectors of this
industry
um just i mean from a testing side
there's there's challenges in even
identifying these different compounds
in the plant and from the healthcare
side there's
there's challenges in getting a
consistent product to really do
solid research on so i think something
like this would would solve
some of those problems at least um to be
able to create something that's
that's more consistent or to be able to
to kind of tinker with
the different the various levels to
really dial in the effect that you're
looking for
yeah absolutely and i mean i think that
there's always going to be
i think there's going to be all sorts of
there's obviously
many many applications for cannabinoids
and many types of users of cannabinoids
and i think there's always going to be
people that want to interact directly
with the plant
that you know even going to growing
their own and
and curing and all these things and the
story of where the plant was grown and
how it was grown and
and all this and there's going to be
people that are just interested in the
in the single pure compound
and so i think it's you know it's gonna
be a wide range of
of users and a wide range of desires for
for what they're interacting with
i think you're absolutely right and i
think sometimes
in this industry there are sort of two
competing camps of the single molecule
versus the
the whole plant but i think that there's
room for both
really um but i kind of wanted to ask
you about that
you know kind of being a part of
synthetic biology or kind of creating
cannabinoids through a non-traditional
means has there been any sort of
pushback from
the industry from the more traditional
folks that you've experienced
you know i actually i was um i was a
little concerned about that going to
speak at
canmed you know that there might be some
folks that were angry about the idea of
biotech getting involved and
you know genetically modified and all
this but i found people were largely
people were pretty open-minded they're
largely
you know interested in the science
behind it and the access
i definitely you know had some
conversations where there was concern
about
um i would say two areas one about you
know genetic engineering in general
and i think i'm usually able to convince
people that
all of the you know the natural strains
we're talking about today are
products of extreme genetic engineering
right the plant
there were there were no plants i mean i
read somewhere that even since the 80s
the the content of thc in top strains
has doubled or tripled or something like
that so
that's all the result of genetic
engineering um you can you can do it by
breeding or you can do it with crispr
but it's it's all genetic engineering in
my mind
um that's that basically creating
organisms with extraordinary
uh capabilities um so that was one piece
the genetically modified piece
and i think that the the the canmet
audience was actually pretty
sophisticated on that one and understood
how it fit into the general
uh artificial selection and breeding
it's one of these many tools to
achieve these extraordinary capabilities
in an organism
but the second piece i think is the one
the idea that that
you know big biotech is going to put
the is out of business and you know
again i think that that
that's that's pretty unlikely just
because there's always going to be a
market
for for the plant for interacting with
the natural molecule
and at the same time you've got you know
companies that want to start
formulating um these compounds into
their products that are looking for a
really pure
uh dependable steady stream of product
and aren't going to move forward without
one
and so i think that you know what i
would say is that it's a big market
that's only going to get bigger
and so it's not like a zero-sum game or
where you cut a piece of the pie it's
coming from someone else's
slice so i think it's it's actually a
case where um
the number of applications is going to
increase because of biotech and you're
always going to have growing
so well that's good to hear
um i did want to ask you about terpenes
um
we've talked a lot about cannabinoids um
is there
an application for using biotech to
generate terpenes or are they sort of
more of a
um a common compound that's not really
applicable
so that's a that's a great question it's
funny because my most of my career
in industrial sin bio has been centered
on terpenes and so i
that's cool i started out working at
amorous a company called amorous that's
also in the
the biotech cannabinoids game at this
point
um and i left i left before they got
into that but
amorous was founded around um the
concept of producing terpenes and yeast
and so they've now made
you know at least a dozen different
terpenes and scaled them up to
you know multi-ton scale through
fermentation
and and so um the you know cannabinoid
pathway itself that gpp molecule i was
talking about that gets put together
with a livitolic acid to make cbga
gpp is is is the precursor to terpenes
it's it's
uh so and then the cannabinoid molecule
itself is what's known as amero terpene
it's part
part terpene and so then of course
you're talking about the terpenes in the
plant that give the the flavor
and the you know the the sensory
experience of cannabis
um and then and then of course also have
been cited in the entourage effect i
should mention that but
but yeah absolutely these are great
targets uh for for biotech
and um in fact i would say that
mastering terpene production
in in yeast was kind of a necessary
precursor to making cannabinoids in
yeast
very cool so one of the common
refrains in these conversations that i'm
having with people in the industry
is that there are still things still a
lot of things that we don't know about
cannabis
and i wanted to ask you are there things
that we still don't know about how the
the plant creates cannabinoids
that would be valuable information for
uh
biotech yeah absolutely i think it were
you know the now like i was saying it
was only
you know maybe four four years ago or so
that the the full genetic pathway was
described with the discovery of this
missing enzyme by the kiezling lab
and so it's not like we've known about
this for years you know we've had the
the genome sequence of the plant for
i'm going to probably get this wrong but
i would say about a decade now
and we've had a full pathway for about
four years but i'd say we're at the very
beginning of understanding how the plant
works and so
you know while i think we can describe
exactly how to make thca or cbda or the
variance
of those leveren variants of those
you start getting into the more rare
cannabinoids and it's it's
it's not totally clear at least to me um
you know if how those are made by the
plant and so
you know whether they represent chemical
breakdown products of
of molecules that we know how they're
made in the plant
you know that's the case for some of
them or whether there's um you know a
whole slew of different enzymes that are
acting
on um on cbga and other molecules to get
there so yeah absolutely a ton to learn
from the plants still
excellent always happy to hear that so
winding down here i did just want to
give you an
opportunity to let the audience know
where they can learn
more about what we've talked about more
about what you're doing
floor is yours yeah absolutely
um so i think that you know in terms of
understanding biotech cannabinoids
uh you know the the company i was
formerly with dimitrix
has put out a really excellent series of
blog posts
um kind of uh trying to break down the
science for the for the popular audience
and so
i know they've got a a few on cbga uh
cbg the
the you know the science and the
chemistry there and so that's that's a
great one i would check out the divitrix
website and try to learn more about what
they're up to
um so i think that's i think that's a
great starting point on the biotech side
um you know if um someone wants to
really get deep into it and
uh maybe has a little more of a
background i would read jay keys link's
paper from 2018 on the the biotech
production of cannabinoids that's a
that's a
excellent one obviously um so personally
um
i i left dimitrix um about middle of
this
uh last year in 2020 um entirely for a
personal opportunity i got the chance to
do another startup i love
i love doing startups so when i joined
dimitrix i was i think the fourth
fourth employee there you know that
there was no lab it was empty
we had to build everything from scratch
and i love that early phase where you're
going from
from zero production to something it's a
you know that first step is an infinite
increase right
so uh so that's really exciting to me
and i like building
building out an early r d team and so um
yeah about the middle of last year i got
the opportunity to do that at a new
company that's called sistina
and um sistina is also in the industrial
well in the it will call the synthetic
biology space similar to demetrics we're
not doing cannabinoids
um i think what's really interesting
about systena is that we're we're
focused on kind of
miniaturizing the the r d
uh process so a lot of the discovery and
work in r d
is done in what are called 96 well
plates which are kind of like 96 tiny
flasks that you can grow
grow cells in and what sistine is doing
is that they're
they're trying to move away from those
plates which physically take up a lot of
space and limit the number of
variants of these strains you're
building you can look at and move into
single cell technologies
and so now instead of having cells
growing in 96 well plates you have cells
inside of droplets or single cells and
there's a number of ways to do it
so that's one piece of it and the other
piece of it is that
we're partnered with a company called
inscripta which has made this
gene editing box called the onyx and the
onyx allows for this you know massively
multi-parallel genome editing where you
can basically
redesign entire genomes in microbes like
yeast and so it's really powerful and
allows us to
get really deep into the biology that
influences the production of these
these biotech target molecules and so
um you know this was those two things i
think were really exciting to me and so
i i jumped at the opportunity to do that
and um
we're at this point you know running a
screening operation the lab is up and
going and
having a great time
well that sounds amazing and i will
certainly put links to the resources
that you that you mentioned into the
show description so if anyone's
interested
you can definitely check that out so all
right
thanks again for joining us andrew um
and thanks i i want to thank you on
behalf of the canmed team as well
for being a scientific advisor and
helping us
to to choose the presenters for this
year's event
that's always very helpful and i hope to
see you out in pasadena
absolutely this was really fun ben
thanks so much
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
andrew horowitz
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to this episode sponsor
demetrix
our next episode will drop march 10th
in the meantime please go to
canmedevents.com
and sign up for email updates that will
enter you
into a drawing to win two tickets to our
canmed2021 vip dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
canmed2021
if social media is your thing you can
find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for kmed events
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast app
go ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device
and please leave us a five star review
as well alright that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
come back for the next episode
of cammed coffee talk
[Music]
you