[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year
head over to canmedevents.com now to
learn all about
our canmed 2021 event that will take
place
september 29th through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets at our
special early bird rate
while you're at camminevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page which you can find in the
main menu
under the media tab you can also go
there directly by going to
cannemedevents.com
coffeetalk there is a sign up form on
that page
and if you complete it you will be
entered into a drawing to win
two canmed2021 vip dinner tickets
while you are there you can also listen
to all the canmed coffee talk podcast
episodes in our archive if you're
looking for a more interactive
experience
we've started a facebook group to
discuss all things related to cannabis
from the bench to the bedside we're
calling it the canmed community board
and it's a great way to communicate and
collaborate with
experts and enthusiasts in cannabis
science
medicine cultivation and testing check
out the link in the show description to
join today
or just search cammed community on
facebook
on this episode i had the pleasure of
discussing the chemistry of cannabis
with dr marcus rogen in his various
roles and positions
marcus oversaw multiple teams that are
focused on the whole processing flow
of cannabis production from harvest and
drying
through processing and extraction all
the way to the formulation in quality
control
analytics the topics we discussed
include
the number of compounds that have been
identified in the cannabis plant
and whether there are more to be found
the complexity of cannabis compared to
other plants and herbs
the challenges with the entourage effect
could there be
invisible compounds that are responsible
for certain therapeutic effects
how different storage conditions and
extraction techniques
will yield different chemical compounds
and why the term
whole plant extract is a misnomer
but before we get to that conversation i
do want to thank this episode's sponsor
the cannabis chemistry subdivision of
the american chemical society
also known as can since 2015
can has been building a strong network
of scientists in the cannabis space
to promote scientific innovation safety
and the development through education
research
and the empowerment of the scientific
community to learn more about what can
has to offer
please visit their website at
www.c-a-n-n-a-c-s.org
and lastly our friends at the hemp and
coffee exchange
are creating some great coffee if you
didn't know
hemp coffee is healthy delicious and a
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information please check out hemp
coffee exchange dot com
and use the promo code drink hemp to get
10 percent off your purchase
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation
with dr marcus rogan
good afternoon marcus thanks for joining
us
uh good afternoon thank you for having
me all right i'm excited to talk with
you today because i know that your
your area of expertise is extraction and
we haven't had an
extraction expert on the podcast yet so
i'm excited to talk with you about that
but because you are our first
extraction expert i was hoping we could
start with the basics
so could you explain the general concept
of extracting compounds from cannabis
sure yeah it's nice uh to be called an
extraction expert so
i'm a chemist by background actually an
organic chemist so i learned how to make
molecules
and then in the cannabis industry i
found my niche in extraction
i hope that we can speak about some of
the other topics
that we're working on as well but so
extraction
um extraction in the cannabis industry
comes from the desire
of of making
or turning good part of cannabis and
good is a discussion we can have in a
moment
into other products than just joints
so then comes the question how do you
remove the cannabinoids
the the good part so to say from the
rest of the material of the plant that
you don't want like cell walls
chlorophyll
fats and waxes as they like to be called
fiber
and you can do that in various
or there might be various forms to do
that
um and extraction is the common and most
efficient way to do so
so extraction in the chemical sense
means you are dissolving
compounds of interest in your
solvent or in a liquid
and remove them from
the matrix or the undesirable aspect
of your material so
it might also help to think about what
extraction is not
and keeping ice water hash
and razon press is not an extraction
because that is a mechanical
manipulation
either by pressure or mechanical
agitation
um you're not using a solvent to pull
out the cannabinoids
so extraction would therefore be co2
extraction
butane uh or alcohol extraction
okay and so what are the benefits of
using a solvent
versus doing sort of those mechanical
operations like you had
just mentioned yeah so in a mechanical
operation
uh you have very little selectivity or
specificity of what you're doing
you are just hoping that
you can break off the compounds you like
and leave behind what you don't like and
then somehow all
separate them through a filter
uh and it work that works quite
nicely with with cannabis because most
of the cannabinoids are in trichomes and
they are smaller than the leaves so you
could filter them off
but in if you use a solvent
for extraction you can choose your
solvent specifically to do the job you
want
you pick a solvent that dissolves your
compound of interest but does not
dissolve the rest
so there isn't water extraction of
cannabis because cannabinoids do not
dissolve in water
so one picked another solvent and there
comes butane
a very a polar solvent aliphatic solvent
that is very good in
dissolving terpenes and pretty good and
extract
in dissolving cannabinoids but not good
or not at all compatible in dissolving
water
or other very polar compounds
in the cannabis plant and then ethanol
again very very good and dissolving
cannabinoids
good and dissolving terpenes but because
it is a polar solvent
can also dissolve other compounds that
might not be desirable
like sugar for example sugars can
dissolve in ethanol
and then co2 is a more varied solvent
where you can
try to play with conditions to
change its solvent capabilities
to fine-tune for different compounds but
basically
extraction allows you to pick a solvent
and pick extraction conditions
to to target your compounds of interest
and leave behind what you don't want
okay so it sounds like different
solvents are
are good for different parts of the
plant so how do you go about really
being selective of which one did you use
is it a bit of a trade-off game
in terms of which solvent you use yes it
is always the trade-off game
um so far
and it's getting better in the last few
years but but i've been now
in the cannabis industry for a few years
um
i think i started in 2014 uh which makes
me ancient
in in in this industry although there
were
a lot of grades before me
and they're still around so
in the cannabis industry what often
happened was
you picked a solvent and then you built
your
your operation around it that was either
because of beliefs
um public interest or
um regulations
i got my start in extraction and a
company that was in an area
where the only solvent allowed was co2
so
i became an expert in co2 extraction
not because co2 was what i picked
initially it was just forced up on me
and uh so you can also say oh butane is
the one that gives you the best
flavor so people pick butane
but a better approach which as i said
is slowly now taking over the industry
one should consider the inputs and the
outputs so for outputs is what do you
what is the product you desire to make
if you are making
a cbd isolate
you just need the highest recovery
of cbd and the fastest right you don't
think
about further precision because you will
purify afterwards anyway so
just through a lot of material
if you're thinking about vape cartridges
you're not thinking okay how do i
how do i customize my solvent system to
make the product
that i want and then there are also
inhalables adaptable products
which have other product requirements
or ingredients for edibles but then on
the other hand
you also have the inputs so what
materials do you have do you only have
20 kilos of cannabis flower from an
indoor grower every month that you have
to go through
or do you have 200 acres
of hemp that you have there where you
have one harvest
in all in autumn and you have to run
through that very quickly
uh so all these aspects you have to
balance to find the best
system for extraction so i'm curious
with that with that ladder example if
you did have sort of this
one large batch um you know
one large harvest would the strategy be
to you know pick one method and go
through it all or could you have
multiple different methods
that kind of target different compounds
within that harvest and then you can
kind of
join them together after the fact so
do you mean splitting the the harvest
into three product streams or going
uh through three
consecutive extractions with three
different solvents
for all of the material i was more
thinking to split it up so like say
okay okay yeah so splitting up so
splitting up might actually be a
good idea um because you have to balance
um speed precision and echo and
just business economics because if you
build an extraction
facility that can handle all of the
harvest
within a month you have a facility that
doesn't do anything for 11 months
so that's a very very expensive
facility that doesn't do much work
uh so you don't actually want to have
the opportunity or
if you could build a full assembly very
very cheap that can handle that size
then that might be an option so if you
take a really really big bucket of
ethanol
you could extract the whole harvest in
one dip
and a bucket isn't that expensive
does that make sense so yes maybe you
split it so you would have something
uh that goes through your materia uh
some of your material very quickly
uh like ethanol uh you could have
something
that handles non-dried material
well so that you can do fresh harvested
and directly do the extraction without
having to invest in drying capacity
which would be a butane or a hydrocarbon
extraction system
and then you could consider of having a
co2
setup which would
target to get through its allotted
material
over the course of a whole year so that
you're
very expensive instrumentation of co2 um
doesn't need to be so large that no one
can finance that anymore
but that would allow you to have
constant uh
production of material uh to a certain
level of precision
uh so yes it would be a very interesting
setup and uh i would like to help with
that
but there comes something else into that
um
the question of drying and preservation
of
cannabis or hemp material for extended
time
and so that's where my my general
research interest
didn't stop just that extraction as a
chemist i was thinking what
else is chemistry related in cannabis
that is
attached or influenced by
extraction and so we have been doing
research into drying and curing
and storage of cannabis uh with
different
drying or freezing methods
uh storage under various gases to
to affect terpenes and cannabinoids uh
consistency over time
uh so that they are either quickly
handled
or safely stored for extended time
so that they could then uh go into the
stream of co2 extraction half a year
after harvest
wow that's interesting so
i mean it sounds like there's there's a
lot of different methods to do
extraction
and then of course there's a lot of
different compounds in the cannabis
plant
is it possible to really get a full
spectrum
extraction or tincture or is that sort
of a misnomer
i would i would say it is um
i mentioned i termed this i just said
good
something good um and we can discuss
about good so we also have to discuss
about the question
what is full spectrum if full spectrum
means
everything of the cannabis plant you
can't use an extract because by
definition you left something behind
right there's no chlorophyll that there
aren't any leaves
there are no cell walls so it can't be
full spectrum because that is gone
so do you now define full spectrum as
all of the cannabinoids and all of the
terpenes
but what a because you test for those
but you don't test for all cannabinoids
and all terpenes
and what about flavonoids and sugars and
carotenes and we know that those are
around and they might have
some value flavor or medical or both
so how do you defel for a de fine full
spectrum
or is full spectrum just as
the opposite of isolated so full
spectrum
is not cbd isolate although
when you want to separate yourself from
a full spectrum from anything isolated
one of the most common method to isolate
is distillation
so how can you have a full spectrum ice
distillate i'm not kidding you can
buy full spectrum distillates on the
market
that's an oxymoron it doesn't make any
sense to me
so i pitched the question back to you
what is full spectrum
well i mean i i guess i can't define
that but i know that
at least the reason why people are
interested in full spectrum
is this whole idea of the entourage
effect right that there are
multiple compounds within the cannabis
plant that are
in some combination contributing to this
medicinal
effect that so many people benefit from
so
i think that's the reason why people are
so interested in full spectrum
um but what does that involve i think
that
i'm gonna throw that back to you and
because i know that you've done a lot of
work
in cataloging the various compounds that
are within cannabis so
what what do we know so far sure
okay so that that's a multi-step assay
it's a it's an entourage answer right
multiple aspects work together to give
the fuller picture
so first i'm a chemist and not a
medical or biological bioli biology
practitioner so i don't actually know
what molecules do with the human body
i just ensure that those molecules are
there or not
but i then don't know what the effect is
so yes i understand the the public
perception of entourage means
there are multiple compounds uh
that act either together
or independently on various systems and
then these com
over all activity in the body leads to
the desired effect
and that might be true but another
explanation i could have for entourage
effect
is similar to the full spectrum
something works we just don't know which
one and it might be a minor cannabinoid
that no one tests for
and it's just super active
that we only see thc in it as the main
ingredient
but this low concentration other
cannabinoid actually does all the work
and work by uh professor mary who you
had on the show
does point to that interpretation
in its spec particular area
so it's either multiple compounds do
multiple things or it is one compound
that no one tests for the but that does
all the work
um and i'm not saying which one is right
i
leave that to the experts in the field
although if you want to find that one
that does all the work uh i might be
able to help right
we can recognize we can find stuff um
then the next question is which
compounds are there
and uh that then comes to another
interest
that came out of of our research
uh push that we wanted to
somehow catalog and have a centralized
verified trustable source
that gives all the cannab all the
compounds that are in cannabis
if you start googling information
for uh cannabinoids you often
fall onto websites like reddit leafly
uh wikipedia and
those information are all
that is first you can't really find all
the information you want and
some of or many of the information is is
wrongly repeated um one of the things i
see a lot
is the melting the boiling point of thc
being 155 degrees
which is correct based on the primary
literature
where that was characterized the problem
is in the car
and in the primary literature i think it
was paper by michelin
it actually says it's 155 to 157 degrees
celsius
at reduced pressure they did the
distillation on the vacuum
so if you only give the temperature and
not the pressure
everyone assumes that at room room
pressure and you wonder why it never
boils because if you would translate
that into
room pressure conditions it would be a
burning point of 425 degrees
and i'm even wondering if at that point
thc just decomposes and
just like dies
so by having
incomplete and imprecise and often wrong
information interdispersed through the
web
we thought it would be useful to try to
build a database
that tracks all compounds that are known
to the cannabis plant
and have them in one database we started
that in-house so that we could
just do our research better
but later we thought it might be of
interest to other people outside of our
company and so we
built a website for it that
then allows everyone to search through
and so we
the database is incomplete there are
always new compounds found
and not all physical and chemical
aspects of the compounds are known
because they might have
only been identified in small quantities
so that no one really measured that
but we're trying to add to that with
literature that we find
with research from collaborators and our
own research so over time this database
will just grow
and i think the next upgrade we are
planning
so we initially had all the compounds we
had them in categories like cannabinoids
and terpenes and flavonoids and so on
and then we added a physical com
physical aspects we could find melting
point boiling point viscosity
uh density and so on and so forth
and now we are looking at adding
spectroscopical data so what is the
right lc
or gc method to look for the compounds
at what time would they elude
how does an nmr and ir spectra look of
those compounds
so that and then either allows you to
build your own methods to look for the
compounds or to
to interpret the spectra you're looking
at right now
so we're slowly bringing that out and um
it's kind of a
project i had in my mind for a long time
um and i just
hope now that other people see the value
in it
um and i'm learning new things like
databases
and user
user interactions with websites like
things that as a chemist i never had to
think about now i
know i play with that well that's one of
the the perks of being in the cannabis
industry
you get to wear many hats and take on a
lot of things you never thought you'd
get into
uh i know that yes i study chemistry to
not have to go into a law career that my
father
uh wished for me my father's a lawyer
so i studied chemistry it's like pattern
lawyer i was like no no i'm not doing
that so i want to be a chemist
and i end up in canada uh cannabis and
one of the main things i have to deal
with is regulations and rules and
uh and and the law um my company is in
canada because
in canada it's federally legal and i'm
allowed to do research
by a federal agency and i can do it in
collaboration
with a federally funded university
because
which cannabis company can afford an nmr
so
we're doing it with the university so
that we have access to those
instrumentation and uh
yeah i have to deal with law now uh
and a very very excited puppy uh
that is just coming back from a walk so
uh please excuse the
the tip tipping feet uh noise in the
background
of course um so i i wanted to
come back to that cannabis compound
database i mean that seems like
a tremendous resource for the community
so how many
how many compounds are we up to uh
we are above 750 i think i hope that
a update soon will bring us over the 800
compounds
we have over 200 terpenes uh
we are around 80 cannabinoids i know
there are over 140 already known but
often they are just just a
letter combination and
they don't even have a physical
description so if i can't really draw
the compound we haven't
added them yet so we were slowly trying
to bring those in as well
flavonoids we have a few we also track
sugars
that are known to the cannabis plant and
should be of interest to track
um we have even some proteins and
minerals in there that
might actually be of interest for some
practitioner in the industry so over 800
compounds how does that compare to
other herbs or plants
yeah um actually if a few years back at
the canals conference i saw a
very good description of about the
complicate or like a visual
description or about the complexity of
the cannabis plant versus
other agricultural plants and it was a
mass spectrum
uh trace of uh
of a cannabis extract versus i think it
was a rosemary
extract and
it was basically a forest the extract of
cannabis was just a forest there's
so many compounds uh that
i fully understand that people go with
uh they like
uh the term full spectrum because
defining this spectrum is
so difficult
if you have a cannabis plant that has
well we have 80 and
in our database but there are over 140
cannabinoids known
uh and all of them are potentially
medically active
or biologically active um that just
blows most other plants out of uh
out of the water we actually talking
about plants there are also other
organisms that are of medical interest
like mushrooms
um our company recently uh got a
a license to research psilocybin
mushroom compounds and
there are less tryptamines one has to
deal with than cannabinoids
so even compared to mushrooms it's much
easier
oh mushrooms are much easier than
cannabis right
no and this whole idea of that you know
there are these
many different cannabinoids in trace
amounts and they still
will may have a medicinal benefit
is very true i mean we've seen it time
and time again where people have
presented at canmed
of using thc in much lower doses
in getting a better medicinal effect so
one would stand to reason that there
could be other
cannabinoids in the plant that we're not
testing for
that are in small amounts but you know
really pack a punch
so that's interesting i
i i do actually in my time
in california when i work for a
vertically graded cannabis
company and i headed the extraction
formulation aspect
we also had a dispensary on site
and we had a we had a mother
coming by for an a male
adult patient um he was suffering from
adult onset epilepsy
and she was looking for a treatment as
the
the common uh classic medical solution
hadn't helped
so she wanted to try cannabis and uh
she after some discussion with her so
again i'm not a medical doctor like
i i could guard what i understand and
guide her towards
medical help but eventually
the mother took home for the patient
a tincture of thc cbd one to one
no wait it was a three to one cbd thc
tincture
i think yeah and she took that home
and the patient uh
got immediate relief um it went down
from
nine seizures a day to zero for the next
two months
and after two months the the tincture is
running out
the mother comes back and buys more of
this three to one cbd thc tincture
and starting the new tincture
the patient starts to show epileptic
seizures again
they're back she uses the rest of the
first tincture
and they're gone again it's a three to
one
cbd thc tincture and we tested both
again on the same day we send it off to
a testing map and we got the test back
it was
uh cbd thc three to one as it should be
there was the same amount of thc acid in
there there was the same amount of
cbd acid nothing in there
um cbn both nothing
uh cbc more or less the same
concentration
between the two and basically the test
results were
very effectively identical of what we
could see
uh because unbeknown to anyone else in
the company except the formulation team
uh we make these tinctures uh with cbd
isolate
plus thc extract from
our co2 machine
and we used to use
diamond og for the thc part of that
tincture
and at some point that oil had run out
so we switched to the next cultivar
which was
a sour diesel or girl scout cookie
but we formulated to the exact same
concentrations of cbd and thc
so by that it doesn't matter
and in both cases you could call our see
a
thc extract from the co2 machine full
spectrum
so we have a full spectrum they're
different full spectrums but they're
full spectrum extracts
with the same amount of thc and cvd in
there and the patient
ex shows completely different effects
and to our test results they are
identical
so yeah there's something else
that that is of importance but we don't
know
and and this this this annoyed the hell
out of me
because i have full control over the
extraction
i full control over the
uh the formulation i have control over
the testing lab
or that i send it to a testing lab
but i don't actually have any control i
don't know what i'm doing
and and this like question like what
else is in there
how do you affect that um
that just neg it was just
so annoying that i had to leave sunny
california
and move to rainy vancouver
yeah i can imagine that would be
frustrating and i have to imagine that
it must be quite the task to even try to
begin to tease that out
given the fact that i mean you've
identified over 800 compounds
in the plant how do you even begin to
start
um trying to determine which compounds
are doing what in
in what combination too that adds a
whole another layer
yeah so it is definitely something i
can't solve
right um and that is that is the best
advertisement tech line on a podcast i
can't do it
uh you need a community like a canmed
community yes
yes the point is that it has to be a
collaborative effort
um actually one of the founding
principles of
our company is fundamental collaboration
and yes i'm a chemist and i've now have
my expertise in extraction
but we work with university research
groups
that are focused on computational
chemistry
on metabolomics so analytical chemistry
we have collaborations with
pharmacologists formulation science the
school of pharmacy so that
if we just go through this example
we have the skills to do full
metabolomic workup to
figure out like every minute mass that
comes out
then one can figure out from the mass
and the breakdown of those
ions what the structure could be compare
that to databases
hence our database
we have the access to nmr to actually
identify the compounds if it's something
new if we isolate it
we have computational teams that we have
working models
to dock cannabinoids and terpenes to
various receptors
and predict their binding affinity which
would give an indication of how
strong or not strong there might be a
medical effect
then we have pharmacologists with which
we can work on like
thinking about some some actual in
vitro studies in vivos sorry in vivo
studies
and and then we have the school of
pharmacy right there we might have
access to mass models or at least like
skin permeability
pigskin to just see how this
actually absorbs for the formulation
aspect
these are all things that only work in a
team
only work in a collaborative effort
excellent um so yeah it sounds like you
have a lot
going on there at your company um talk a
bit more we
we talked about the compound database we
talked about extraction what else
in psilocybin testing as well what what
else are you guys working on
yeah so before you get into society
which is now the new cannabis
thing uh yeah um
there's the whole stocks uh public
market story and craziness about this
part
which i leave to to the experts
for everyone on podcast i'm doing air
quotes
uh for a moment let's stay with cannabis
so the question of
that you post like how do we find these
compounds that
are important but currently not looked
for it
it's probably impossible to do this on a
single extract and a single case
uh patient case um
we have to find new solutions
to or modern solutions uh
to those medical problems and it will
involve a lot of data
population size data sets we cannot do
it on one or two cannabis plants we have
to look at
dozens hundreds of thousands uh of
cannabis plants
to to to spot the difference
by exclusion and comparison to other
plants
so um we can't just take one plant
isolate every single compound and then
try it on every single uh in vitro
study one can think of like that's just
not doable from the effort so
um data analytics becomes something and
actually this this topic of data
analytics we
we also embrace in other fields of our
research and
extraction research so coming back to
the start of this call
i i'm considered an extraction expert
because i remember that early 2017 i got
on stage and i explained to the cannabis
industry what a design of experiment is
and how to optimize the co2 extraction
with six experiments yes and
that worked and at the time in the
industry that was something new
by now i've moved past that because six
experiments optimize something but the
imprecision is large
and the factors you can look at are
small temperature and pressure
but water content in the plant mill size
machine flow rate all those influence
extraction as well cannabinoid content
so now we're looking at dozens of inputs
dozens of factors and we're looking at
dozens of optimization
targets high terpene pure cannabinoids
fast all those and that's not doable
with experimentation
or targeted experimentation anymore so
we actually
doing a big data approach to extraction
we work with our customers and clients
uh on taking in their old data sets so
now we have
thousands and thousands of extraction
runs and we can use
now more advanced statistics that are
beyond me as a poor organic chemist and
i have my
data scientists and mathematicians on
that
to to really tease out effects
um that are then better understandable
and controllable
so yeah now we are extraction experts
uh and like a big data approach uh has
been
very fruitful so far it's a complicated
question in cannabis because not only is
the
the system difficult but also the input
data is imprecise
um everyone who worked in cannabis
industry and has seen people writing
stuff down on paper understands that
problem
so i think this data approach or the
modern technologies uh that
are used in other fields translate
should translate well into the cannabis
industry because we don't have historic
baggage of how we have done
stuff before because there wasn't
a legal industry before right
yeah so that that's one of the benefits
but
we also don't have that history to to
fall back on either you know we're we're
pioneers we have to build that all
right right and i said there's no
baggage because there was no no
legal industry but there was a
illegal or underground uh industry of
cannabis and that brings its own
historic baggage
um some of it is helpful and some of it
is not helpful
and one has to deal with that so
therefore we move to a completely new
organism that has all its own
restrictions and illegalities uh
psilocybin mushrooms
[Music]
right yeah just just when cannabis was
sort of
entering the mainstream okay you had to
go yes
yes when it became too boring uh i
thought i'd do something else
yes it's very simple rock of you uh
yeah no i do no i don't think punk rock
does that
it's more like uh euro techno right
well i know punk rock is very uh
anti-mainstream you want to keep it
underground
i was more thinking of what the what the
audience would partake in while
listening to that music
oh yeah well i mean i when i think
psilocybin i think uh
the grateful dead and fish and uh all
that sort of stuff
okay but okay i have to admit
i have to admit so i and i think that is
by now
known um i have no idea of cannabis as a
perk
as a consumer so i didn't know how
cannabis smelled when i started
in the industry i i thought you smoked
the leaves like i had no clue
and i take all this knowledge
into the mushroom space i again have no
idea about
any any consumer effects
and i just have to catch up and
understand
so mushrooms are
well i'm in the lucky situation that
canada has already its
solid legal framework work for cannabis
which allows us to do our research and
they have also
now established a legal framework for
psilocybin research
it's somewhat behind in time
and more restrictive in its regulations
so i can do
far less with mushrooms right now
that i can do with cannabis one example
is uh when you are in these
this space of restricted compounds and
and
uh organisms you have to buy them from a
uh licensed producer
and in cannabis as everyone knows
there's way too much cannabis right now
on the market in canada so for me
getting anything from my research is not
an issue
psilocybin
they are maybe single digit
number of producers that actually grow
silver cyber mushrooms that you can
legally buy
for research purposes um so it gets way
more difficult
actually luminos is a licensed dealer
that's that's the license you get for
psilocybin mushrooms
they are based in british columbia so
they're based around the corner
although around the corner of the
library of ubc is where you find your
psilocybin mushrooms but
those i can't use for research
different type of research
yes in closing marcus i want to give you
the opportunity to
plug any websites social media or
anything that you want to
get across to the audience to learn more
about the work that you're doing and or
to connect with you
all right thank you yes as we as i said
we
we set up a research laboratory here in
vancouver canada
uh to help the cannabis industry uh
in canada but also internationally
because data is free to travel across
borders
but also now in the psilocybin space our
company is called complex biotech
discovery ventures
ltd which is a mouthful but the acronym
is cbdv
and the website is cbdvvl.com
cbd v was taken already and
the lcd needed to go somewhere in the
name so it's cbdvl.com
that's you can that's where you can find
all our research
our uh projects we do
how we can help uh various customers
uh in the cannabis and now in the
psilocybin space
and also where you can find our compound
database
excellent i would uh be happy for anyone
to reach out
and talk to you how to make extraction
or
analytics better excellent
i will include links to all those
resources in the show description so
folks can
can click on that and learn more and
i'll also share a link to your canmid
presentations as well so great
thank you very much again marcus this is
a great conversation thanks so much for
taking the time
and hope to see you out at camden sure i
will try to i'm looking forward to it
[Music]
i do hope you enjoyed my conversation
with dr marcus rogen
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor can
learn more about them at www.cann
acs.org our next episode drops march
24th that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please go to
cannemedevents.com
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you
into a drawing to win two tickets to our
canmed 2021 vip dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
canmed2021
if social media is your thing you can
find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for cammed events
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast app
go ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device
and please leave us a 5 star review as
well alright that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
come back for the next episode
of cam ed coffee talk
[Music]
you