[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to
cannemedevents.com now to learn all
about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets at our
special early bird rate
while you're at candidevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page which you can find in the
main menu under the media tab
you can also go there directly by going
to canmedevents.com
coffeetalk there is a signup form on
that page
and if you complete it you will be
entered into a drawing to win
two canmed 2021 vip dinner tickets
while you are there you can also listen
to all the canmed coffee talk podcast
episodes
in our archive if you're looking for a
more interactive experience
we've started a facebook group to
discuss all things related to cannabis
from the bench to the bedside we're
calling it the canmed community board
and it's a great way to communicate and
collaborate with experts and
enthusiasts in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and testing check out the
link in the show description to join
today
or just search cammed community on
facebook
on this episode we discuss dosing
medical cannabis
with dr dustin sulak dustin is an
osteopathic general practitioner
who focuses on treating patients with
refractory conditions
using an individualized health-centered
approach
dr sulak is a founder of integrate
health
a medical practice in maine that follows
over 8 000 patients
using medical cannabis and co-founder of
healer.com
a medical cannabis education resource
dustin has also participated in every
canmed event
since our first event in 2016. he serves
on our canned med advisory
board evaluating abstracts and helping
select presenters
and he is an instructor on our full-day
canmed medical practicum
topics we discussed include why dosing
medical cannabis is different from other
therapeutics
the fact that cannabinoids can have a
biphasic and even triphasic effects
how a patient's optimal dose can change
over time
commonly going down how patients
commonly build a tolerance to the
adverse effects of cannabis
but not the benefits the benefits of
working with a trained medical provider
to determine one's optimal dose but also
strategies for how patients can find
their own
how cannabis can be used for health
promotion and disease prevention
and how using a variety of cannabis
cultivars and not sticking to just one
strain
can actually be a benefit for patients
before we get to my conversation with
dustin i would like to thank this
episode's sponsor
cannabis patient care magazine cannabis
patient care magazine is an educational
resource for patients
medical professionals caregivers and
advocates
on the latest research benefits and
treatment options
medical cannabis provides for a variety
of illnesses
they are excited to announce that their
march issue will be coming out next week
with a focus on chronic pain the issue
features content from
industry thought leaders and medical
cannabis including
brendan mckernan ceo of medicinal
genomics
eloise thiessen board certified adult
geriatric
nurse practitioner president of the
american cannabis nurses association
and a medical leader of this year's k
men medical practicum
and others visit canna patientcare.com
to learn more and lastly our friends
at the hemp and coffee exchange are
creating some great coffee
if you didn't know hemp coffee is
healthy
delicious and a natural product rich in
trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy without the
crash of regular coffee
for more information please check out
hemp coffee exchange dot com
and use the promo code drink hemp to get
off your purchase okay
and without any further ado please enjoy
my conversation
with dr dustin sulak
good afternoon dustin thank you so much
for joining us
my pleasure ben glad to be here okay
let's talk about dosing it's one of
those topics that our audience
is always curious about and for good
reason i suspect
it seems that cannabis is difficult to
dose properly
for a number of reasons is that fair to
say
i would call it different maybe not
difficult it's it's different than
what medical providers are used to
because
you know we're used to saying oh you've
got high blood pressure here let me give
you
this number of milligrams take it twice
a day and that's kind of the standard
prescription
and cannabis really requires that we get
into more of a
personalized recommendation a
personalized regimen
for each person and not only that but
sometimes for each problem
so it's it's more individualized and
therefore more nuanced but i think with
some basic principles it doesn't have to
be
difficult or confusing
okay so what are some of those basic
principles okay
well let's let's start out with the fact
that everybody's different in their
response to cannabis in particular their
response to thc
so if i'm sitting across the room from a
new patient that's never tried cannabis
before and say they're wanting to use
cannabis for pain or sleep or anxiety or
anything else
i have no idea is this a two milligram
person or a 20 milligram person
and and literally that it's that range
and sometimes even broader you know i
have some people that
would be sensitive to as little as one
milligram of thc
when taken by mouth and some people that
can go way higher than that without side
effects
or or tolerance building which i'm sure
we'll talk
talk about in a little bit so without
knowing where someone's at in their
level of sensitivity
which probably has many factors that
influence that
including one's age one's gender
probably
less so influenced by one's size or
one's body weight
but um there's probably genetic factors
in there and we don't know all of them
so if i don't know if you're a two or
twenty milligram person we start at two
and we methodically work up through that
range
with a lot of patient education on
here's what to look for
when you start responding here's what to
look for when you might start having
adverse effects and that's going to
inform you where that therapeutic window
is like where does that range
between what works for you and what
starts to cause side effects and so
we we identify that and it often takes
people anywhere between a week and
even a month depending on how slow and
cautious we're going
and and then i'll just comment on cbd
which is you know so
so similar to thc in a lot of ways in
terms of it can help a lot of the same
things it can help with pain
inflammation anxiety and so forth but
very different when it comes to dosing
because people it's usually very
forgiving right people
rarely get into trouble taking too much
cbd
uh you know it's a more common problem
is that they're not taking enough so the
milligram dosing for cbd and thc is way
different you know i
think very few people are ever going to
feel 2 milligrams of cbd
most people need to get to 5 or 10
milligrams before they even start to
feel something
and with cbd often more is better
especially if they're using a cbd a
really cbd dominant like a hemp
preparation
it's usually upper limit limited by cost
you know i think a lot of people would
be using higher doses and getting better
results
if it weren't so expensive but then that
there's the opportunity to really
uh do what i think so many of your
listeners understand is the combination
of the two it's not thc or
cbd it's it's really using both of them
strategically together
and then i would imagine too beyond just
thc and cbd there's there's terpenes
there's other
minor cannabinoids that could be playing
a role so how does that
entourage effect further complicate
dosing considerations
sure so i you know i think the biggest
influence
is when it comes to inhaled cannabis you
know when people are either smoking or
vaporizing cannabis flower i will see
extraordinarily distinct extraordinary
distinctions between
you know one variety of cannabis and
another one might be very uplifting and
energizing one might be very sedating
one might do nothing for pain but really
help with anxiety
and the other you know the opposite some
might stimulate appetite or suppress it
so
it's just really all over the place with
those varieties
i think that in most situations once the
flower is processed
into an oil or a tincture or a capsule
or edible or something like that
a lot of those differences are kind of
washed out with the processing
now more people in the cannabis industry
and my company healer
are one of the leaders in this are we're
working on how do we get all the virtues
of that flower
into a bottle you know or into a pill
because those distinctions are are
really nice
there's also um in my mind and in my
experience a lot of rationale for
blending
the varieties together and having you
know like a wide spectrum kind of a
shotgun approach product
which can be more straightforward and
easy to use and
and more versatile for a wide range of
people
so um yeah so i guess getting back to
you know your question terpenes
i think i think of that more as like the
fine tuning
and so my first goal with the patient is
to
kind of orient myself to their general
dosing range general sensitivity like
first of all are they responding to
cannabis i mean believe it or not not
everybody
who tries to use cannabis for pain or
sleep or one of these conditions
uh receives benefit even though most do
you know what
and um those who don't usually we can
kind of switch to
cannabis plan b and get some good
results there too because there's always
so many different things to try in the
world of cannabis
but if they are responding general
ballpark of what number of milligrams
are we talking about that's like
the big knob on the old-fashioned radio
where you're like tuning into the
station
and then the fine-tuning knob we do it a
follow-up visit which might have
everything to do with
the terpene profile of the product
they're using and
then what's been really exciting to me
are the acidic cannabinoids
so i've been watching this for several
years now that thca and cbda in
particular are powerful agents that have
been
overlooked for a long time they seem to
be more top
you know better tolerated more effective
especially at very low doses than their
neutral counterparts
but not substitutes you know i'm not in
any way suggesting that thca is a
substitute
for thc they act very differently but i
almost
always recommend including some thca
in any thc product and and that's for a
variety of reasons number one thca
does have some distinct mechanisms of
action that thc doesn't have
but also it's been shown to be a
positive allosteric modulator
at the cb1 receptor which means it can
kind of turn up the volume turn up the
activity
and actually potentiate or make the thc
more potent and more effective so one
could use a lower dose
also the the pharmacokinetics are all
interacting which means
when we take these cannabinoids together
especially say we take
thca and thc we take them by mouth and
they go to the liver
well now we've got two compounds that
are competing for metabolism in the
liver
and that would slow the breakdown of thc
so having some thca
in there again kind of not only
potentiates
what we would call the pharmacodynamic
effect it doesn't
only make the action of thc more potent
but it slows its breakdown
and therefore makes it last longer in
the system and be more potent in that
way
and then finally these acidic
cannabinoids are absorbed way better
you know what makes them acidic is they
have a carboxylic acid
functional group on them so they're a
little bit more water-soluble
and that increases their absorption it
looks like
you know the uh the cbda is absorbed
somewhere between 5 and 11 times better
than cbd
thca might be absorbed up to 50 times
better
than thc when taken by mouth so you
don't need much of those so that that's
another
really exciting piece uh for improving
results with and
being able to use a lower dose
yeah and i would imagine being able to
use a lower dose
is better for patients just because cost
has to be such a limiting factor when
trying to determine dose it really is i
mean my
like kind of the nature of my practice
is cost effective solutions to
problems that have failed to respond to
conventional treatment this is what i've
been doing
for 11 years and um yeah it's
finding a way for people to afford this
or to be able to produce their own
and and make their own and sometimes not
have to
to be able to do that without spending a
lot of money on lab tests and all that i
think these are two
really important strategies for
empowering patients
you know the the self-cultivation and
self-production
is just such a therapeutic activity unto
itself you know i feel like that alone
has
great healing power and the patient just
feels so good about the fact that
they've made something that's now
bringing them relief so i support that
in a lot of my patients as well it's
obviously not legal for people to do
that everywhere but it certainly is here
in maine
that's excellent and so you talked about
when you're starting with a patient you
you have a starting dose to sort of be
able to
determine the therapeutic window what is
that where where do you typically start
yeah so on a thc side of things if
there's no
nothing that informs me that they're
either
super sensitive to thc or that they're
not that sensitive
you know if i have no historical
information like that i started two
milligrams
i warned them that the starting dose
might do zero for them
but um we're gonna we're gonna go up
methodically and find the dose that
works
um and that you know there's some
exceptions to that sometimes if it's a
daytime treatment and somebody's very
active and they're driving and i want to
really make sure that there's
no impairment i'll start with say one
milligram we have a product here that's
four one part thc and four parts cbd
with a little bit of the thca and the
cbda in there
and so a common um kind of take with
breakfast recommendation i have it would
be
start with five milligrams total of that
so that's
approximately one milligram of thc and
one of c
and five of cbd and that's a nice safe
starting place and
believe it or not a lot of people are
starting to say yeah i think i actually
felt a little something there
and then as we go up it it starts
getting better and better so that kind
of orients that lower end of the dosing
range
and so in preparation for for talking to
you about about dosing today i went back
and i watched the
the panel from kmed 2019 that you were a
participant on along with
a number of other doctors and you guys
got into some really great data a lot of
great information and i'll share the
link in the show notes here
and one of the things that was really
interesting was sort of this
biphasic effect that cannabinoids can
have
where at a low dose they can be not as
effective but and at a very high
dose they can't be very effective i was
wondering if you could talk more about
that
right so this sweet spot that we see in
cannabis
is um yeah this this is what can i say
is known for these dichotomies like
everywhere you look in cannabinoid
research you see them
it's of course it's going to show up in
dosing as well but
this would indicate that if someone
starts at a low dose
and they gradually increase the dose for
a little while there
each dose increase is going to result in
a stronger therapeutic effect so that
would be
one phase of the relationship a direct
relationship between dose going up
and therapeutic effect going up and then
at some point
there's an kind of an apex to that phase
and as you
increase the dose even more the
therapeutic effect will start
to diminish and what what often happens
to patients that don't understand this
is they're saying wow i increased the
dose and it's not working as well as it
used to
you know something must be wrong with
this i should increase the dose even
more
right it's it that only makes sense to
most people
so they increase the dose even more they
might temporarily feel
a stronger effect but then within a few
days they're feeling even less of a
therapeutic effect than they did
previously
and they repeat and repeat and before
long they're taking this high dose and
barely feeling it at all
and this is a process known as tolerance
building it happens readily with thc but
it's also
very easy to reverse and we can talk
about that as well
another really strange thing about thc
is that it's might not just be biphasic
it could be triphasic so at very high
doses
they could start to recover that direct
relationship and have the therapeutic
effect start growing
again in the in the in a positive
direction unfortunately that's going to
be a much more expensive treatment
and usually the kind of maximal
therapeutic effect at the high dosing
range
isn't as nice isn't as beneficial to the
patient as it is in that kind of low
moderate dose
so the other thing is though people
when they find their sweet spot like if
they really explore this dosing range
and figure out what is that
maximum dose that gives me the benefit
without the tolerance building without
the loss of efficacy
people are able to stay at that dose for
years or decades without it ever losing
effects
so it really benefits people to take the
time to methodically figure out
what is their optimal dose because when
they know that they're set they can
stay on that dose for a long time and
usually
over time people will start to feel
better and then their dose goes down a
little bit you know as their health
improves they require less and less
cannabis maybe
the physiology just doesn't need it as
much
so that's the trend i typically see but
most people would never think
oh wow the cannabis isn't working as
well as it used to i should reduce my
dose
like that's just not that intuitive but
that's actually what works
yeah that's really that's really
fascinating and
i wonder and you can certainly tell me
if i'm wrong
but i mean the whole idea of having a
cannabinoid therapy
is to make up for a deficiency in
endocannabinoids right
so could it be that by using
cannabinoids
it sort of retrains your system to be
producing those endocannabinoids and
maybe that's why
you don't need to supplement so much
absolutely
that's i think that's a lot of what we
see in that lower dosing range when we
first start out you know there's a
a handful of animal studies that have
shown when you administer thc to
rodents in particular at certain doses
you can kind of
up regulate their either their
production of endocannabinoids or their
cb1 receptor
density meaning how many receptors their
cells are producing
or the sensitivity of those receptors so
there's some evidence to suggest this
but i i think this takes us um back to
this concept of therapeutic window
what we see in um because this this
concept of tolerance building
can happen at different rates in
different parts of the body in different
parts of the brain
and reverse tolerance can also happen
you know i think
one of one of the really interesting
features i've recognized about cannabis
over the years
is when i ask large groups of people you
know the first time you ever smoke
cannabis when you were a teenager or
whatever did you feel it
and so many hands go up like no i did
not feel it
right some sometimes people have to use
it two or three times to even experience
it at all
now that might just be due to the fact
that their kind of sensory awareness
wasn't attuned to that
psychoactive shift and they didn't know
that they were stoned but they really
were i think there's probably some of
that
but there's also some evidence
suggesting that it was that first dose
of cannabis that kind of primed their
system
and then made them more sensitive to it
when they took it
the second time and so from a
therapeutic window perspective
what i see when people that are cannabis
naive so they haven't used cannabis
before when they first start using
cannabis and we get kind of over that
threshold
of some therapeutic effect
in the next few days they become more
sensitive to that without changing the
dose at all
so like say two milligrams did nothing
three milligrams i start to feel a
little bit of relief in my back
okay stay at three milligrams on day
three or day four that three milligrams
is starting to feel stronger than it did
when they first started three milligrams
so that would be a widening of the
therapeutic window with the
lowest effective dose actually going
down a little bit
and then we also get this widening of
the therapeutic window
with the dose that causes the adverse
effects getting pushed back a little bit
and this we typically see it with some
of the um
the motor effects so when when people
first kind of go over that line
into side effect territory one of the
things they
they report us either dizziness or
clumsiness or just feeling a little
unsteady
and that has to do with kind of the
psychomotor response in some of the
areas of the brain
that control our body movements and it's
it's been
shown that the areas of the brain that
control these
physical functions will build tolerance
to thc
faster than areas of the brain that
control pain signaling or that control
anxiety
or some of the other effects some of the
cognitive and cerebral
effects of the thc and so
people could stay at that dose they're
feeling a little wobbly
okay well don't go up anymore but just
stay at that dose for a few days
and a few days later the wobbly thing is
gone but the pain relief is still there
so this whole idea that you can build a
tolerance to the adverse effects but not
to the benefits
exactly and to do that you got to be
methodical
and you really have to be paying
attention to your body's response and
your mind's response to cannabis
um but but yeah absolutely and same with
the memory loss same with the kind of
uh you know the giggles i mean anything
whether it's a
an adverse effect uh in some situations
and maybe not in others but
you know most of my patients don't want
to be high all the time and
you know even without cbd even with a
pure thc
treatment i really want to emphasize
that people can get relief of pain
relief of anxiety spasm
many other symptoms without getting into
the territory of
impairment you know and and even if at
first they're feeling a little bit of
that
they can build tolerance to that and
maintain that therapeutic efficacy
so seeing as though you need to take a
real methodical approach and there's a
lot of
patience that needs to be taken as well
with really finding the right dose
how important is it for patients to work
with an experienced health care provider
when trying to figure out their optimal
dose
i really don't like to limit people
because unfortunately there's not a lot
of experienced healthcare providers out
there
that work with cannabis and so you know
a big part of my mission is to help
people
circumvent that if they need to but of
course if you have the option of seeing
someone that's been
you know treating patients with cannabis
for five years or something like that i
i encourage any listener to at least
explore that they're likely going to
find
uh some pearls there that they wouldn't
have found on their own
plus it's um a lot of people just in
in general in our society but especially
people that have been suffering for a
long time have been through the medical
system and haven't found the
results they're looking for they might
be less aware
of their bodies and less aware of their
you know just kind of like where they're
at i had a patient yesterday who i was
you know i said well how have you been
doing in the last month since i saw you
last well
you know my back pain is a little bit
better okay
how much better you know and eventually
i
kind of fished out of her that it was
about 30 percent better and she really
noticed that she was able to do the
dishes
without having you know to stop a few
times in the middle so that was a big
a big one i said anything else no i
think that's it otherwise i'm doing
pretty good
how about your migraines how many of
those have you had in the last month
oh my god i've had none okay and so like
she wouldn't even have known that she
wasn't paying attention to that she
wasn't taking notes on that that was a
huge surprise for her when i asked her
that question because previously it was
one to two a week
and and the listeners right now might be
thinking like oh my god how can this
woman not know
that you know that she stopped having
migraines but this is very common so
people
sometimes really benefit from a third
party there that can
be more objective and hold them
accountable and ask the right questions
and kind of reflect back to them
the progress and the pitfalls and the
successes
to help people accomplish that without
the help of a provider
i developed something really simple
called the inner inventory
which is just a three to four measure
scale that takes about 30 seconds to
perform on oneself
you take a deep breath you rate on a
scale from one to ten how smooth and
easy that was
you hold still for a few seconds and you
rate how comfortable you are in your
body
and then you put on a fake smile and you
see how real it feels
over the course of a few seconds and
that's you can rate that on a scale from
one to ten and then if there's a primary
symptom you're dealing with you can
rate that's and that that symptoms
intensity and
and so with our products that we make we
provide worksheets
for people to record their inner
inventory a few times a day basically
before
in a little while after their cannabis
dosing and a shift in that inner
inventory is a nice sign
that they're at a dose that they're
starting to feel a response to
and and so that's you know there's all
sorts of ways to circumvent but i think
i would recommend the listeners if
you're using cannabis and your goal is
optimal health and you have access to
someone like me
that's been doing this for a long time
it's probably worth a consult
and then if you're new to cannabis and
you're
worried about it and you just want
someone to be there to support you and
supervise this i you know i think
working with an expert is going to
create a faster path to success
that's excellent those resources sound
great and i'd love to link
those as well in the show notes and one
of the things i was going to ask is
you know what about folks who are
looking to use cannabis just for kind of
general wellness or just
general well-being maybe they don't have
a specific condition but
you know everyone wants to everyone
wants to feel good everyone wants to
feel better
i imagine that those principles would
hold true for those folks as well
yeah this is a great topic that i'm very
interested in
cannabis for health promotion and
disease prevention you know i feel like
if if you could take almost any field in
medicine
whether it's psychiatry or pain medicine
or neurology or gastroenterology
and take all their the cases that have
failed to respond to all of their
treatments and send them to me and i'm
getting success with 80 to 90
you know if cannabis can be so useful
for all these refractory conditions
what could it do to prevent them what
could it do to keep people healthy what
could it do to help people perform at
their best and feel their best
i actually wrote a chapter on this in a
book that's coming out in the next month
or two
that i wrote for physicians and other
clinicians but it's
uh yeah cannabis for health promotion
and disease prevention
i think there's some you know very basic
principles that i'll share with the
listeners here you know number one is
you do not want to build tolerance to
thc
because building tolerance to thc means
you've down regulated your cannabinoid
receptors
and that means that you are undermining
the function of your
system and this is a system that is
there to keep you healthy
to respond to injury and to respond to
illness and to keep everything in
balance in the body
so so no tolerance to thc um
you know that that's the number one rule
another another rule
or another set of rules has to do with
using cannabis to support
other lifestyle factors that are known
to be healthy
so if you're not sleeping well ask
yourself well how can i use cannabis to
optimize my sleep and that's probably a
whole nother
podcast worth of information there but
but we have a lot of that info on my
website and people can find that as well
if you're
if you find that cannabis is a nice
adjunct to exercise either because it
makes you look forward to it more and do
it more frequently
or if it's because it helps you feel
like you recover faster
and get ready for the next workout use
cannabis as an adjunct to exercise use
it as an adjunct
to meditation or spiritual practices to
creativity
to socializing which you know it's i
mean
i used to not have to tell people to do
that but of course now in this day and
age
you know so many of us are socially
isolated and um
really missing the healing aspect of
those social connections in our life and
i think
uh it's important that cannabis can
really deepen relationships quickly and
help people open up and share and
collaborate
creatively and i think that's that's
really essential when it comes to health
promotion
and disease prevention and then the
other thing that i want to share is if
you look at
some societies around the world that
have used cannabis for this purpose
it's often the acidic cannabinoids that
they're relying the most on so
cannabis tea is a wonderful tonic you
know think of
think of this as something that you can
do that really has no downside
that's just going to help mitigate
inflammation in the body and
kind of nudge your endocannabinoid
system in the right direction
and so and that's that's a no-brainer
you know almost every morning or about
six days a week because i do take a
cannabis fast one day a week myself
along with um calories and caffeine all
on the same day
but i um i just throw i just throw a
little bit of bud
like maybe the size of a of a pea a
fresh pea throw that in the cup and
you know maybe i'll add another tea bag
maybe i won't pour hot water on it let
it steep for five minutes and drink it
and if you know that you're not very
sensitive to thc you could even eat that
little bud at the end of the cup
you will get some thc in that dose but
it might not be a lot it
kind of depends on how strong the flower
is and
how big of a bud you pinched off but
cannabis tea is a wonderful tonic
and so i like people to think about
a lot of my patients as they get better
and better we kind of
transition their treatment to you know
from
not how can i use this as a crutch to
manage my life to get on top of my
health care to you know
become more self-efficient and then it
shifts to
cannabis as a tonic how can i use this
to stay healthy and the tea is a big
part of that
well that's that's really that's really
cool and one of the things that stuck
out to me when you were talking was this
whole idea of building a tolerance
to thc and how that could actually
hinder your body's
own endocannabinoid system i had never
really thought of that you know
folks who you know unfortunately maybe
uh use a little too much thc could
actually be doing themselves a
disservice because you're
affecting the way that your
endocannabinoid system is working
i think that a lot of the listeners well
first of all i want to say that
it's okay it's totally okay to overuse
thc to build tolerance there's no
judgment that's a useful experience to
have and i think
that a lot of the listeners who have had
that experience where they found
themselves smoking joints all day
long for weeks at a time and then they
realized at the end of a joint wow i
didn't really feel anything
i bet if you really look at yourself
when you stopped using it a couple days
later or a few days later
i bet you started to feel better now
this doesn't happen to everyone you know
about
somewhere around 50 of heavy cannabis
smokers
will experience a withdrawal syndrome
which is not that strong but it's
irritability loss of appetite trouble
sleeping you know things like that but a
lot of people
after they stop using it they suddenly
start to feel like
normal is the new high you know like wow
that feels really good i wanna i'm gonna
feel like that more
and um and that's a you know i think
that's an important
transition point between the crutch and
the tonic
you know if you're a cannabis user and
it really is helping you
you're likely going to feel a lot better
after you use it i would encourage you
to watch for when you don't feel better
after you use it or when you feel
even a little worse after you use it and
that's a that's something that
your body will show you if you pay
attention and you're honest with
yourself you'll note that
and that's a really beautiful
communication from your system
that it's time to shift your
relationship with cannabis into a
different mode
so so watch for that but this um this
process of regaining our endocannabinoid
receptors can happen
rapidly it's been shown in one mri study
at least in men
to happen over a period of 48 hours so
if you're
dabbing or smoking joints all day long
and you don't feel it at all
you can stop for 48 hours start at
say a 50 lower dose and you're
you're gonna feel it and and that's
that's just the thing like
how would you like to spend half as much
money on your medicine
and feel it either the same or more with
less side effects like
it's only upside for that so and that's
why years ago on healer.com
we put up this free program called the
sensitization protocol which really
holds people's hand and walks them
through not just those 48 hours
but i do give a lot of strategies for
how you can deal with those 48 hours you
know it's for
easier for some than others so there's
exercises and meditations and foods you
can eat and all sorts of things you can
do to
get through that period and then a guide
for how to
very consciously restart
the cannabis at a lower dose and watch
what it does for you
that's excellent and winding down here i
did want to ask you about
product variability and how that can
sort of play into
finding the right dose like maybe you
were using a product
it was you found the right dose it was
really effective but then
for whatever reason that product's not
available at that dispensary anymore
how can that sort of throw everything
off
great question so i think there's some
value in that first of all
you know for years people have been
telling me that if i just grew one
strain in my backyard you know for the
whole year it seems to not work as well
as if i grew four and kind of switch
between them you know for maybe i'll do
a couple weeks with one in a couple
weeks with another or
one in the morning and one in the night
things like that and so i i
think to keep well let me say that
physiology tends not to be static
you know we really do well with
fluctuations
in our system and and you know that's
that's biological life for you
and so i don't think it makes sense to
really strive to use the same exact
cannabis at the same exact dose every
day for
a long long period of time now little
fluctuations are okay skip a dose once
in a while
or get a product that's very similar but
slightly different
that's that's usually very helpful i had
a lady yesterday
who's um in her mid 70s she's using
cannabis
for pain and the dispensary sold her the
same potency product but this one was
hybrid instead of indica
and she said i don't know why they sold
me that that you know i i was buying the
indica every time and i said well
what did you think you know and she said
it works but it doesn't seem to work
quite as well
you know and that's i said well that's a
fine experiment it's a little bottle
go back there next time and say the
indica works better and now you know and
you know and and that's not a big deal
what is a big deal in my mind
is when the label is just way off and
unfortunately we see this
so often in cannabis so what if this
lady goes to the next dispensary and
because of the label on the first
product
she thinks she's a 10 milligram doser
and she you know she asked the
dispensary agent how many drops of this
is 10 milligrams and whatever they tell
her
maybe she's getting 20. i mean this is
this might sound unusual to listeners
but this is not unusual to me
like this this is happening all the time
because um
first of all the testing labs have a lot
of inconsistencies
people don't necessarily measure how
many drops are in a milliliter so
they're just like kind of picking some
number between
20 and 50 and and saying that that's how
many and then doing the math there
a lot of times the labels don't make it
simple and the patient actually has to
try to bust out a calculator and figure
out
milligrams per milliliter and drops per
milliliter and
you know that's that so um you know
we've really
put a lot of attention and time into
simplifying that for patients with the
healer line of products both our hemp
products and our
thc containing products that we have in
maine and in maryland
and we include dosing guides i mean it's
just
so often that people are making mistakes
having to do with either inaccurate
labeling or misleading or confusing
labeling of the products so that that's
where the real pitfall is
but when it comes to um you know a
certain preparation being like the one
you know i
sometimes see that in my patients with
seizures where
we can really determine like wow you
pretty much are getting the same dose of
cbd or thca that you were getting before
but
but really this product isn't working as
well and the parents are like absolutely
not so i do see some real
specificity not in all seizure patients
but in a few seizure patients
but in general i think variability is
okay as long as you're in kind of that
same range
right so i guess it must have to be a
certain
psychological mindset you need to be
into too is to kind of be open that
there might be a little variability and
to be able to to roll with that
oh ben our um yeah i think we've our
species has really um
lost its comfort with ambiguity and this
is a big
problem you know we all really want to
pin it down and
i identify all the discrete you know
kind of cause and effect relationships
in our life
not just with cannabis but with so many
things and i think it
that's extremely stressful because we're
living in such a complex system and we
are
we are such a complex system that we
can't really
always uh pin down all the discrete
causes and effects and
you know i invite the listeners to be
comfortable with ambiguity whenever it
comes up in their life and they don't
that they don't really understand what's
happening or they can't be
certain they're getting the right dose
that's okay
you know what i tell my patients is that
if you accidentally take a thousand
times the dose of
this medicine you know a thousand times
the dose i'm recommending it's not going
to kill you it's not going to cause any
brain damage or organ damage or
anything else like that you might be
sick for a day have someone put you in a
calm reassuring environment and
you know call me if that happens but
it's um
you know people do make mistakes and and
sometimes there's great lessons that
come out of that as well
all right um one last question before i
let you go
we talked a lot about having resources
to help patients with their dosing
what about physicians or health care
providers
who are maybe new to cannabis and want
to start recommending it to their
patients
what sort of resources are available to
them to help
to help guide their patients yeah great
question
so you know my supreme offering is this
book that i've been working on for the
last year and a half it's coming out
through norton professional and even
though on major booksellers it says the
release date is august it's probably
going to be in the next month or two
that it's released and that's available
for pre-order right now so that's
the best i have to offer you it's called
handbook of cannabis for clinicians
now there's some other resources i want
to point you to one is the society of
cannabis clinicians it's a great
membership organization and we just
released a new curriculum of about 20
modules that you can take online so
that's a
nice resource and then healer.com
which is my free patient education
website we also have a paid
training certification program on there
which includes
um kind of bite-sized online modules
plus a bunch of videos and then a
monthly webinar
and the monthly webinar is actually free
for everyone to attend but in the
training program
we have all the previous webinars that
are all time stamps so people can go
right to a topic
that's important for them but that was
originally designed
for dispensary agents and for caregivers
and people that were just
wanting you know kind of lay people that
we're really wanting to dig in deeper
but what we found is now we've got 200
clinicians that are in that program and
they all love it
i think because it's it's just kind of
very concise
quickly applicable you know that was my
goal with it is to make
not not to make this a scientifically
dense curriculum but to
empower people to get good results very
quickly so all of my education
on healer.com i think is empowering even
even physicians i would say start with
my patient education
material maybe that's all you're gonna
need and you're gonna you know pick it
up faster but
those are those are the resources so
cannabisclinicians.org for the
society of cannabis clinicians
healer.com and then the book handbook of
cannabis for clinicians
yeah those are great and i know that
you're going to be participating in our
medical practicum
canmed as well um i think that'll be a
great resource for clinicians as well
okay it was so sad to miss canmed uh
this year and i know it's going to
happen again ken met has been a
wonderful conference and a great
resource and i know
that clinicians that have that attended
the 2019 that i've stayed in touch with
it felt so empowered by that by that one
day session that we had there
you know it was kind of like the soup to
nuts in one day
that that was such a beautiful offering
and a great attendance and i think we
really made a difference in the world
with that so
i would greatly uh look forward to the
next canmed
i do as well um thanks again dustin for
taking the time to talk with us today
and i do look forward to seeing you out
in pasadena for canada
thank you ben it's been a pleasure have
a good one
[Music]
i do hope you enjoyed my conversation
with dr dustin sulak
check out the resources in the show
description to learn more
and thanks again to our sponsor cannabis
patient care magazine
visit cannapatientcare.com to learn more
about that publication
our next episode will drop wednesday
april 7th
two weeks from today in the meantime
please go to cannemedevents.com
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you
into a drawing to win two tickets to our
canmed 2021 vip dinner and keep you up
to date with all things canmed2021
if social media is your thing you can
find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for cam at events
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast app
go ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device
and please leave us a 5 star review as
well alright that's it from us
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
come back for the next episode
of cammed coffee talk
[Music]
you