[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to cammedevents.com
now to learn all about
our cammed 2021 event canmed 2021 will
take place september 29th
through october 1st in the pasadena
convention center
in pasadena california and right now we
are offering
50 off all our canmed 2021
ticket types through april 20th use
promo code
420 sale at checkout to receive
discounted pricing
on full conference medical practicum
full conference with medical practicum
and expo only tickets again that promo
code is 420 sale all one word
and the offer is good through april 20th
while you're at cammanevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page which you can find in the
main menu
under the media tab you can also go
there directly by going to
canmedevents.com
coffeetalk there's a sign up form on
that page and if you complete it
you will be entered into a drawing to
win two cam ed
2021 vip dinner tickets on that page you
can also listen to all the past canmed
coffee talk podcasts
on that note april 1st was officially
the one year anniversary of the podcast
thank you to everyone who has helped
make this possible
from our wonderful guests incredible
sponsors and dedicated team members
thanks again
on this episode we welcome dr peter
grinspoon
dr grinspoon is a primary care physician
at massachusetts general hospital
and an instructor in medicine at harvard
medical school
he is a contributing editor to harvard
health publications and the harvard
health blog
where he frequently writes about
cannabis medicine issues
dr grinspoon also writes about addiction
from both the perspective of a clinician
treating the disorder
and as someone who is in recovery from
opioid addiction
we spoke a lot about how cannabis can be
used to treat addiction in our
conversation
as well as why dr grinspoon believes all
primary care providers should be
knowledgeable about medical cannabis
how medical cannabis offers a safer
alternative to medications used to treat
chronic pain
and insomnia how years of anti-cannabis
propaganda
has tainted the medical cannabis
conversation
why both sides of the cannabis issue
need to behave better
when discussing the benefits and risks
the five ways cannabis can help with the
opioid crisis
how prescription drug usage tends to
drop in legal cannabis states
whether cannabis itself is addictive and
more
before we get to my conversation with
peter i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor
mace media group who is hosting the
original
cbd expo midwest 2021
an in-person event april 9th through
10th
in indianapolis indiana this event will
feature exhibits from
end product producers equipment
manufacturers and ancillary businesses
including financial and legal service
providers
in addition the expo will offer unique
cannabinoid education seminars
from leading cannabis and cannabinoid
phds
physicians scientists researchers
and industry pioneers the expo is open
to anyone who may be interested
from entrepreneurs and professionals to
curious consumers
join expo tour and explore the latest
and most innovative
advancements in cbd to attend this
year's event
or to learn more visit cbd
expo dot net
and lastly our friends at the hemp and
coffee exchange
are creating some great coffee if you
didn't know
hemp coffee is healthy delicious and a
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information
please check out hempcoffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
off your purchase okay and without any
further ado
please enjoy my conversation with dr
peter grinspoon
good afternoon peter thanks for joining
us thanks for having me
all right i'm excited to talk with you
today about how
you incorporate cannabis into your
primary care practice particularly when
it comes to treating addiction because i
know you have a lot of experience there
so maybe a good place to start is to
have you describe the types of patients
and conditions you treat
and then we can get more specifically
into cannabis and addiction
absolutely um i incorporate cannabis in
my primary care practice
and then i have a a private practice
that i on the side where i
do consultations and certifications um
i think it would be great if all primary
care doctors is certified and advised
people on medical cannabis
that's sort of my vision for the future
where you know all
doctors are conversant and comfortable
discussing cannabis with patients they
all know about the endocannabinoid
system
and they all can can give their patients
good and helpful advice
unfortunately we're not quite there yet
because of the 80 years
of drug war mentality and the fact that
the endocannabinoid system hasn't been
really taught much at all in medical
schools
um the irony is that medical cannabis
makes my life
as a primary care doctor much easier
because it offers me
tools that i wouldn't otherwise have
some of the most difficult things to
treat as a primary care doctor are
chronic pain um and insomnia
and the alternatives for these are often
much more dangerous than cannabis
so i would say two of the most common
things i treat
in my primary care clinic are insomnia
and chronic pain
for insomnia i'd be using ambien or
sedative
or amyl triptyline some kind of
tricyclic and those can affect your
memory
they have side effects they make you
groggy and you compare that with a
maybe a drop or two of tincture of
cannabis tincture and
the person has a slight euphoria and
gently falls to sleep and they're not
groggy the next day
i mean it's sort of a no-brainer to try
cannabis
and it's much less habit-forming
obviously than the benzodiazepines like
valium or clonapin
and then for chronic pain what are your
options nobody wants to be on opiates
tylenol doesn't do anything and then the
non-steroidals i see
so many patients with their kidneys
dying in their 50s
60s and 70s you know if they haven't
died of a heart attack or an ulcer first
just from using chronic aleve naperson
ibuprofen
advil cannabis is can be a much
safer and healthier alternative as
americans get
bigger poorlier and more arthritic in
their knees and hips and backs
so chronic pain and insomnia are two
examples
of things that not only do i treat
frequently in my primary care practice
with cannabis but i think that cannabis
would help
primary care doctors across the board if
they incorporate
it as a tool it would make their lives a
lot easier
yeah agreed and i think we all share
your vision or your goal
of educating primary care physicians and
helping them understand the benefits of
using cannabis
do you see that trend starting do you
see
more primary care physicians or even
physicians in general
opening up to the idea of using cannabis
and
learning more about the endocannabinoid
system absolutely
first of all among younger doctors
they're very and doctors in training are
sort of outraged
that is not being taught and they are
very
much more educated about the war on
drugs and the social history
and a lot of the younger doctors are
like i can't believe you guys aren't
teaching this
the endocannabinoid system is sort of
the control system for all the other
neurotransmitter systems why would you
leave this
out of the medical school curriculum but
also
in general doctors are becoming so much
more accepting of cannabis as the
feedback from patients of positive
clinical
outcomes reaches them you know um i
can't say that doctors are taking the
lead with few exceptions doctors have
sort of been on the wrong side of the
whole cannabis debate
but to their credit doctors are they're
following the patients but they're
they're starting to listen to them
and i think generally doctors are
getting on board
but they doctors generally have a
a pretty big task in terms of not only
learning
how to incorporate medical cannabis into
their practice but they have to sort of
unlearn some of the nonsense that
they've been taught about cannabis along
the way
so if you think about having to unlearn
stigma unlearn nonsense and then learn a
whole new
treatment modality you know it is a
pretty tall order i mean it's it's
doable and
doctors have an obligation to do it
because they've been getting it wrong
thus far and it's a really uh critical
way to help patients
navigate a whole host of medical issues
but it is
you know it is going to take some time
it doesn't happen overnight
yeah one of the things you mentioned was
following the patients and that a lot
oftentimes patients will come to their
doctors
interested in cannabis do you find that
a lot in your practice or
are you suggesting it to your patients
well it's interesting you know it
becomes a little bit self-selecting
because once you get known as
a physician that's sort of interested
and advocates for cannabis
people do sort of seek you out for that
and then you know my colleagues refer
patients to me for cannabis so on the
one hand quite a few patients
come to me for that but on the other
hand you know just for my
routine primary care patients that
really don't know
anything about me aside from the fact
that i'm their doctor i will definitely
bring it up
uh a perfect example of a patient that i
might bring it up to is
the patient with moderate chronic pain
whose kidney function is starting to go
after being on
non-steroidals for several decades this
might be a patient that i've
adopted inherited you know doctors
retire they leave you inherit a patient
from someone else
if it had been my patient all along they
wouldn't have been on non-steroidals all
along and their kidneys wouldn't have
been dying in the first place
because i would have had them on medical
cannabis but if i adopt a patient whose
kidneys are slowly dying
because of the non-steroidals that will
be someone that i will say
hey you can control your chronic pain
with medical cannabis
we could use low doses you probably
won't have very much of the high
at all if you don't want to because we
could use cbd or we could use low dosage
or we could use topicals and so forth we
could experiment with different
modalities different doses different
strains
and um we could really make a go at
protecting your kidneys and
you know most people are open to trying
this uh you know if they're elderly
if they're conservative uh they might
have too much stigma still internalized
from the 80 years of drug war propaganda
but
more and more people are are open to it
uh some people are very enthusiastic
about it
and more and more people are open to
trying it and then you know when you try
it
it's not a success for everybody for
some people it doesn't help their pain
for some people they have side effects
like anxiety or they just don't like how
it feels but i would say
for for most people it helps them
absolutely and of course we're talking
about using cannabis to treat
chronic pain and another drug that's
commonly used to treat chronic pain is
opioids which kind of brings us to this
whole idea of addiction so
um how can cannabis be used to to treat
opioid addiction
well there i view it as there are five
ways in which cannabis can help with the
opiate crisis
four of which i support and one of which
i
i don't support yet because it's not
evidence-based cannabis can be used
instead of opiates to treat chronic pain
for new patients so you fewer patients
that are on opiates
that could potentially get addicted to
them you could take patients that are
on opiates because we over prescribed
opiates for the last 20 years and we
have a ton of people on
opiates that don't need to be in opiates
and we could offer to transition them
from opiates to cannabis and again get
them off of opiates now this has to be
done voluntarily i don't believe in
forcing anybody off opiates if they're
on opiates
the third way is if you add cannabis to
opiates the dose of opiates can often
be 20 of what it was you could lower the
dose by 80
because cannabis and opiates work on
very similar receptors
so and a lot of the mischief you get in
with opiates in terms of addiction
dependence uh
overdose is dose related so if you can
get someone
from like 100 milligrams to 20
milligrams of morphine equivalent that's
a great thing
and the fourth way is that cannabis can
be really helpful
and there's some studies that show this
and i can tell you this from personal
experience
because i'm in recovery from opiate
addiction cannabis is probably the most
effective medication for opiate
withdrawal
symptoms when you're getting off opiates
or transitioning onto
buprenorphine you know suboxone cannabis
can be really helpful so there are four
ways
in which cannabis is extremely helpful
in getting people off their opiates for
chronic pain
cutting down their dose for chronic pain
or helping them transition off street
drugs
the fifth way which i can't quite
recommend yet is
can we use cannabis as a drug like
buprenorphine
suboxone or methadone as a replacement
for opiates in terms of medication
assisted treatment
now i know of thousands of patients that
have
vouched that they've used cannabis to
get off opiates
and have used cannabis as a replacement
for heroin and i truly believe that in
the future this may be the case that
you're not just gonna have
buprenorphine methadone you're gonna
have buprenorphine methadone and
cannabis
to get people off of opiates however at
the moment
the data is that buprenorphine and
methadone
have been shown to reduce overdoses and
death by 50 to 80 percent
and we haven't shown that yet with
cannabis so i feel uncomfortable
recommending cannabis
for this because it just hasn't been
shown yet to reduce overdose and death
now say you're my patient and you have a
migraine and i treat you with medical
cannabis
and it doesn't work the worst case
scenario is you get
a migraine we try something else but if
i treat you for opiate addiction and it
doesn't worse
work you overdose and you can die that's
a really big deal
so i think for that particular
indication you have to stick with the
data
just because the consequences of
overdosing are so dire
it desperately needs to be studied and i
think again in the future we probably
will be using cannabis as a medication
assisted treatment
for opiate opiate use disorder but for
right now i stick with buprenorphine
and methadone and i do prescribe
buprenorphine to my patients
that are addicted to opiates we're not
allowed to prescribe methadone
in clinic we are for chronic pain but
not for addiction it's really
an old-fashioned law so
what is sort of the course of treatment
if you know i'm addicted to opioids and
i come with you
i come to you sort of what's your what's
your plan of action
well um we have a great team at mgh uh
we have a fantastic team
and we do a just an unbelievable job
with opiate addiction
we have a recovery coach we have an
addiction
psychiatrist we have a social worker
that links everybody together
we have the primary care doctors all of
them prescribe suboxone or buprenorphine
um if you're sick we have a great
addiction console team in the hospital
and we have a bridge clinic that bridges
people from the inpatient to the
outpatient so no one gets lost
in the cracks and every single one of
our er doctors
is uh certified to prescribe suboxone
so no matter where you come in my
hospital you get hooked up with suboxone
and you get hooked up with a primary
care doctor to follow up with you
and you get hooked up um with a recovery
coach someone who's not going to judge
you
who's in recovery who's going to connect
with you
if you're a complicated case you get
hooked up with a addiction
who could also help with the you know
people who are addicted also very
frequently have
untreated anxiety and depression so
someone who can help
disentangle that or childhood trauma
help you with that so we have a very
coherent
and comprehensive addiction
addiction team in my hospital what i can
add
is i can add medical cannabis to
patients which
in some studies has been shown to
increase retention
in buprenorphine programs but it
certainly can help
with the chronic pain the anxiety and
the insomnia as well
uh that's not technically an official
quote-unquote
part of our addiction team because it's
controversial
um addiction uh physicians are
there's a continuum among how accepting
doctors are of cannabis
and addiction uh physicians and
psychiatrists in general tend to be less
accepting
than doctors in general whereas
oncologists for example tend to be
extremely accepting
because the oncologists see that all
their patients benefit um it's very
complicated and a whole other discussion
why
addiction uh psychiatrists are are sort
of against cannabis
you could come up with a very cynical
explanation or you could come up with a
less cynical explanation but
so it's um but they tend to be uh
a little bit less supportive of it but
um the team that i work with the teams
that i work with at mgh are very
supportive of it and we've just had a
lot of success
that's great to hear so it sounds like
cannabis is
sort of a supplemental drug in this
this whole program that you guys have
put together
yeah it's supplemental people are
accepting of it um
you know but again i would have to say
that in my hospital
you know just like everywhere it depends
who you talk to if you talk to certain
doctors
cannabis is a helpful wellness tool and
if you talk to other
doctors it's like the devil's lettuce we
have a split just like you have
everywhere else
so you're talking to me and i'm a
supporter of it
um you there are other doctors in my
hospital that you could talk to that
would
completely disagree with what i just
said over the last five minutes
so it's not like all doctors have this
monolithic
acceptance of it there's a wide variety
of
of opinions some of which is very
negative so
it we do have a long way to go towards
universal acceptance
yeah and how do we break through there
is it just we need to we need more data
we need more clinical trials
well we're getting there we need more
data we need more clinical trials we
need more time
acceptance is heading in the right
direction across the board with patients
with doctors with nurses
with healthcare professionals across all
age groups as we legalize
the sky doesn't fall as people get more
clinical experience with it it gets less
stigmatized as people
see relatives that benefit from medical
cannabis
and they use it and they don't become a
motivational
and irresponsible and they don't just
sit in the sofa and eat doritos all day
they actually go on with their lives
they actually um you know their lives
can actually be enhanced
if they're not suffering from insomnia
and chronic pain they actually can be
more active and more engaged
so i think with time this is just
getting better but we also need people
to like
counter uh the propaganda there's still
a lot of propaganda out there like
uh just yesterday there was a very
disappointing piece in the new york
times
that was based on a very disappointing
book that was sort of dressed up to look
like a medical
textbook which i've actually been
reading and tweeting and making fun of
for the last three weeks
and it just calls itself an
evidence-based approach
but it and again it's dressed up for
doctors and it looks like a textbook but
it just
cherry picks on the evidence that's
against cannabis i guess it is an
evidence-based approach but
it's not really a balanced
evidence-based approach if you just take
all the evidence against cannabis
and put it in the book and ignore all
the evidence in favor of cannabis
so we really do need people to be
vigilant
to look at the studies um some of the
studies
about cannabis are really helpful and
really valid and people that are
pro-cannabis need to accept
the valid studies that show negative
things about cannabis
just like people who are anti-cannabis
need to accept the valid studies that
show things
about the medical benefits of cannabis
both sides need to behave better
but some of the studies are still these
propaganda
attack studies so you need to you know
they're just trying to show harm
for no re you know just as as part of
like a social
statement not as part of advancing our
science base
so we just need you know neutral
skeptical people to look at the studies
to contextualize them
if they're helpful to say this is
helpful all right we shouldn't use it
i'm just making this up during pregnancy
and other people to look at the studies
and say all right look
teen use hasn't gone up 50 times in
colorado since they legalized
it this is bs so we need to really
evaluate the literature
objectively we need to educate people
accept the harms
we need to i think not have
self-inflicted injuries
i think there's no reason to make
cannabis into gummy bears that pets
and little kids are going to eat that's
just a self-inflicted injury and is
dangerous
if cannabis is medicine make it look and
taste like medicine
i know a lot of people get got upset
when i wrote a blog about this but
i really firmly believe it so but i
think with time
and with like people being responsible
and with good information out there
um this is all gonna fall into place
yeah i think that's a a great point to
say that
you know we do need to be accepting of
the harms of cannabis because they do
exist
um and that's and that's okay as long as
we know what they are
and can can act responsibly but i think
you know especially being in this
industry people get kind of wrapped up
and
and kind of presented as this panacea
and with no downsides but
that's that's not always the case right
and it's particularly difficult because
the government spent 80 years like
only funding studies about harm and a
lot of the studies were just bs
you know give a monkey like 80 000 times
you know the amount of cannabis i'm
exaggerating a little bit that a human
would take and then the monkeys you know
unconscious for four days and they'll be
like cannabis makes you
unconscious you know they just do these
ridiculous studies so
people don't trust the anti-cannabis
literature because
it's really was abused by the government
and it was misused
or parroted sort of unreflectively by
the medical establishment
so there's a lot of distrust and i think
and the scientific establishment needs
to regain
the trust it would be great if they
acknowledged
their role in it i think that would
really help to to regain trust
but the problem is that none of the
pro-cannabis people
trust with good reason any of the
anti-cannabis studies
but that leads to another problem is
that some of these studies that are
coming out are really good
and you can't just ignore these good
studies but i understand the distrust
so we've got a complicated situation
absolutely and one of the things that
you mentioned before
is that when cannabis is legalized in
these states that the sky doesn't fall
but one of the things that does fall and
that i know you've written about
before is opioid prescriptions and
opioid overdoses so there definitely is
something going on there with cannabis
and
in opioids yeah well in colorado
medicare d prescriptions across the
board fell wow not just for opiates and
i think that you know people
were just taking a puff instead of
waiting to see their doctor and getting
a muscle relaxant
instead of trying to get a prescription
for viagra they take a puff
instead of getting an opiate they just
take apart i think people were
self-medicating with cannabis instead of
trying to get an ambient prescription
from their doctor or benzodiazepine
they'd like
take it puff off their vaporizer i think
people were self-treating and i think
that they
were realizing that you cannabis does so
many different things and the
endocannabinoid system
is involved in so many different aspects
of our body that
it really does have a lot of different
effects and if you know how to use it
you can treat
many things that these different
pharmaceutical
agents that do one thing can treat
you know which is why i think initially
at least the pharmaceutical companies
donated
so much money to the anti-side of the
cannabis
referendums and with opiate um with
opiates
one study showed that the opiate
overdoses dropped but then another study
re-evaluated it later and it's
questionable whether the opiate
overdoses
dropped yet i'm sure that they will be
dropping because so many people are
using cannabis
instead of opiates but it might be just
too early to
show that um but certainly the opiate
prescriptions are dropping that's been
shown
in so many studies and it follows that
if the opiate
people are using cannabis instead of
opiates it's hard to imagine that the
opiate overdoses won't be dropping
and then finally at least three states
these exchange programs where you could
exchange your opiates for cannabis
so i mean it's how do you it's hard to
overdose on opiates if you're using
cannabis
it's like you know apples and oranges
so um i i honestly think it's going to
be
extremely valuable in helping us work
through
the opiate crisis of course the opiate
crisis has gotten much worse
in the very short term because of the
covid pandemic so sort of all bets are
off and it's going to be impossible
to sort of evaluate what's contributed
to what last year this year and probably
the next year because
everything's out of whack you can't
really compare this year to anything and
the overdoses
are up so it's going to be really hard
to like sort of analyze
what what happened to what and what role
cannabis played
yeah that's a great point and one of the
things that you mentioned too was
it's not just opioids that people are
substituting
with cannabis it's it's other
medications as well and
and you're right the endocannabinoid
system is involved in so many different
body systems it's almost like why not
try cannabis
responsibly and see if it helps
right and these days it's such a pain to
like see your doctor
and go to the pharmacy and get a
prescription and pay a co-payment
and um you know these drugs have
side effects like ambien
you know people driving ambien and don't
remember they were driving something
like ten percent of traffic accidents
have ambien in them
or they wake up and they're like who ate
all the food in the refrigerator and
left all the wrappers in the table and
it turns out it was like them
and they don't remember it because they
were an ambient and they were in this
weird dissociative state like
an ambient might even affect your
dementia risk like
it's hard to argue the cannabis for an
adult is not a thousand times safer than
ambient for example
so not only is it more convenient in the
legal state but it's
probably a lot safer i mean the
opponents of cannabis go on and on and
on about the harms and the risks
and there are harms and risks
unquestionably
but you've got to compare it to what
else we'd be using
you can't just talk about the harms and
the risks in
a vacuum you've got to talk about the
relative harms and risks
and you know melatonin is good for sleep
and that seems pretty
risk-free but melatonin doesn't work for
that many people
but then once you move beyond melatonin
to the ambience
the tricyclics which can give you
arrhythmias the benzodiazepines like
valium which are so addictive or ambien
which we just talked about
it's really hard to make an argument
that those are safer than cannabis
yeah we've if we've talked a lot about
using cannabis
for opioid addiction but can it be used
for other addictions as well
well i think cbd is going to have a huge
role in addiction
there is pre-clinical research and
some clinical research um the cbd can
help with cravings
cue induced cravings um
they studied it in animals for cocaine
addiction for methamphetamine
addiction there's been some preliminary
research actually for cannabis addiction
and then for there's been human studies
for tobacco
addiction and some for um opiate
addiction
and cbd really um shows a lot of
potential there's a lot of studying
that we still have to do but cbd
preliminarily seems like it has a lot of
potential to help
people with the cravings and the
rumination
and the urges to continue using um
so i think cbd is going to have a a huge
role
and then um for cannabis in general
um i think for withdrawal symptoms i
mean for
many drugs when you withdraw you have
anxiety you have insomnia and you have
this general feeling of ill ease and
discomfort
and i think cannabis is going to prove
to be very helpful for the withdrawal
symptoms so you know with opiates uh
it co-works on some of the same
receptors so i think it's particularly
helpful for opiate
uh withdrawal but i think in general um
you know you're withdrawing from
nicotine you feel grumpy
you feel irritable a cannabis can be
very helpful for that kind of thing so i
think cannabis is going to be helpful
but i think
on a kind of neurochemical level cbd is
going to target the addiction very
specifically
so that's interesting so if i'm
understanding correctly it's almost like
cannabis is used more to quell the
unpleasant trees of withdrawals and less
as sort of a replacement
for the drug itself is that
accurate right yes but with opiates it
might turn out to be
enough of a replacement we'll have to
see
because so many people say that it works
it just hasn't been shown yet officially
to reduce overdoses and deaths
so i don't feel comfortable like using
it in that manner
sure you know something that's serious
you have to go with the evidence
absolutely and do we understand
sort of which cannabinoids or compounds
within
cannabis are are really kind of doing
the heavy lifting here is it's is it thc
cbd a combination
well um you mean for the for the opiate
yes
replacement um well i think certainly
thc is a big part of it because
that um what we
the short answer is we we don't know yet
the medium answer is that thc plays a
role in cbd plays a role
um because of all the different
receptors that they hit and there's some
overlap with the opiate receptors
and cbd is really complicated in how it
works
and there's a bunch of theories about
how it can potentially help with
addiction but they're not quite sure
how it works yet because cbd affects
like
a ton of receptors and i don't think
they're quite sure how it affects
addiction
um i'm not quite sure how to um
how to explain how cbd would in
particular
affect addiction i've read a bunch of
articles on it but it's very complex
sure okay and so winding down here we
talked earlier about
sort of acknowledging some of the
downsides of cannabis so i wanted to ask
you
um is cannabis addiction a real thing or
at least
dependence yes absolutely
people can get very dependent on
cannabis
people can overuse it people can have a
hard time
getting off it and it can be very
difficult
once per a person has been using
cannabis
for a long time to know whether it's
help cannabis is helping them sleep
or whether not using cannabis is keeping
them awake because they you know if they
don't use it they can't sleep
so it could be a fine line between
cannabis is treating their insomnia
or not using cannabis is causing their
insomnia it could be a very fine line
you can get physical dependence
and you could definitely have withdrawal
symptoms and you know they could be
they're not anything like opiate
withdrawal symptoms like
you're not like feeling like you're
gonna die you know as i like to say no
one
robs pharmacies no one's like breaking
into dispensaries because they're that
sick
from a cannabis withdrawal whereas you
know people do
i'm not trying to stigmatize any
addiction but you know people get so
sick with opioid withdrawal they do like
the
craziest things to get drugs um but
at the same time you know if you use
cannabis every day your receptors
down regulate because you're always
bombarding them
with external cannabinoids and so
they're fewer and farther between
so then if you stop using it your
natural endocannabinoids
have many fewer receptors to work on
and so you have a relative
endocannabinoid deficiency
and you have withdrawal you have
grumpiness insomnia
lack of appetite irritability
um probably pain sensitivity so
people do have withdrawal and
uh they do have tolerance obviously
people
you know use more as they go along so
can definitely get dependent and the way
i view addiction is
continued use despite negative
consequences
and we all know people that should stop
smoking for one reason or another and
just can't
like they have a drug test coming up for
work but they can't do it
or i have a patient who i'm pretty sure
has
cannabis hyperemesis syndrome he ends up
in the emergency room
every month barfing and having to stay
overnight and i'm like can you
let's just stop smoking for three months
if you
still end up in the emergency room every
night then it's
cyclic vomiting syndrome if you stop
vomiting and don't end up in the
emergency room then by definition it's
cannabis hyperemesis
it goes away if you stop the cannabis
that's
literally the only way to distinguish
between
cyclic vomiting syndrome and cannabis
hyperemesis is to take the cannabis
away and my patient's having a really
hard time doing that
and i would call that continued use
despite
negative consequences i would call that
an addiction
yeah i certainly would yeah and you
mentioned
cannabis hyper hyperemesis is that the
frequent pronunciation and this
means barfing a lot it's just how
doctors used latin words
yeah i first became aware of that
condition
at the last canmed event where we
actually had a panel about it
and um that was that was really
fascinating and i think it's a it's a
conditional not a lot of people know
about um i don't know if you want to
speak a bit more to that
oh sure well it was under diagnosed
because when it was
cannabis was illegal no one would
mention that they're using cannabis
because they didn't want to have their
kids taken away
now it's over diagnosed because it's
like a trendy diagnosis that all the
emergency room doctors are making
any time that people come in vomiting
and
cannabis is anywhere on their list or
they mention cannabis using
but in reality it's a fairly rare but
real and significant condition where
it's thought that cannabis um suppresses
nausea for example with chemotherapy
patients
but if you use a lot of it over a long
period of time and this is the theory
you can overstimulate the receptor
probably the trpv
receptor and then you have a paradoxical
reaction and it causes
uncontrolled vomiting and it's really
uncomfortable
it's not responsive to your traditional
medications for vomiting
ironically it's sometimes responsible
it's responsive to like a
hot shower or hot bath um or held all
that antipsychotic that
is just awful uh can make it go away as
well
but it's very hard to distinguish from
something called cyclic vomiting
syndrome
which is just vomiting for no reason
every once in a while
and the only way to distinguish it again
is to take away the cannabis for like
a couple months and see if the vomiting
goes away
so that's actually a really good test to
see if someone's dependent on cannabis
if they could stop or not
because you know if your doctor who for
example
is very pro-cannabis doctor says you
have to stop for three months
there's no stigma there's no shame
there's just we want to see if you're
vomiting
is because of cannabis and you can't
stop that would be an example of someone
who has a real problem with cannabis
i would definitely agree um like i said
we
had a few people on the panel who had
actually experienced
the symptoms and describe them on that
panel and um
yeah if if stopping cannabis couldn't
prevent
some of the things that were described
then i would definitely call that an
addiction because it sounded pretty
awful to to go through that
yeah no i've seen it twice the person
was barfing like for hours
uncontrollably um and like there was
nothing to do
i tried compazine i tried odansetron
literally nothing worked and for hours
like they were
so miserable
all right that's not really where i'd
like to end the conversation so
oh about a few of the harms
you know to have a balanced discussion
and you know every medicine i prescribe
has potential harms
like there's no medication that i
prescribe as a primary care doctor that
that might not have a bad reaction
absolutely absolutely um all right
well thank you for saving that um
before i let you go i do want to give
you the opportunity to
share with the audience um whether it's
ways to connect with you
or keep up with your work any website
social media anything like that
please plug away oh sure i'm on twitter
a lot
at peter underscore grinspoon or people
can
check out my website at
petergrinspoon.com they can communicate
with
me or sign up for uh you know
consultations
or send me a message
and that's about it between those two
things i'm pretty accessible
absolutely and i will put links to both
of those in the show description so
people can get to them nice and easily
all right peter thank you again for
doing this it was a great
it was a great discussion and i hope to
see you out at cammon
forward to it and yeah thanks for the
great discussion this could have gone on
for hours
thanks all right take care
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr peter grinspoon
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor mace
media group
who is hosting the original cbd expo
midwest 2021
april 9th through 10th in indianapolis
indiana
learn more at cbdexpo.net
our next episode drops april 21st
that's one day after our 420 ticket sale
expires
don't miss this opportunity to save 50
on all canmed ticket types
go to canmedevents.com now and get your
tickets
also don't forget to sign up for email
alerts at kmidevents.com
coffeetalk that will enter you into a
drawing to win
two tickets to our kmed 2021 vip dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
related to canmed2021
the social media is more your thing you
can find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for can med events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast
app go ahead and hit that subscribe
button so that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and please leave us a five star review
as well
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of canmed coffee talk
you