[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year i hope you all had a
wonderful 420
and i hope you are able to take
advantage of our special 420 pricing on
canmed2021 tickets
if you did not you're in luck i managed
to pull some strings
and get that deadline extended an
additional day
exclusively for podcast listeners so
if you use promo code 420 sale all one
word
at checkout you can receive discounted
pricing on
full conference medical practicum full
conference with medical practicum
and expo only tickets that discount by
the way
is 50 off so again that promo code is
420 sale
all one word and the offer expires at
the stroke of midnight tonight
4 22.
while you're at kim at events.com be
sure to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page which you can find in the
main menu
under the media tab you can also go
there directly by going to
canmedevents.com
coffeetalk there's a sign up form on
that page and if you complete it
you will be entered into a drawing to
win two cammed 2021 vip dinner
tickets while you're there you can also
listen to all the canmed coffee talk
podcast episodes in our archive
okay on this episode we welcome dr debra
kimliss
she is the cmo at pure green
pharmaceuticals
where she oversees clinical medical
testing patient and physician
educational programs
and medical product development deb and
her team
recently published an open label
clinical trial for treating diabetic
neuropathic pain
with a water-soluble cbd tablet
in our conversation we discuss results
from that clinical trial
what makes diabetic neuropathic pain a
good candidate for cannabinoid therapies
comparing the adverse effects of
standard dnp treatments to cbd
the advantages of delivering
cannabinoids via a water-soluble tablet
why there are not more clinical trials
into connect
into cannabinoid therapies and tools
consumers can use
to identify proper clinical trials
before we get to that conversation i
would like to thank
this episode's sponsor pure green
pharmaceuticals
pure green pharmaceuticals manufactures
the finest
medical products using selected
cannabinoid molecules
as primary ingredients their goal is to
relieve human
and animal suffering through use of
purified cannabis
learn more at pgpharma.co
and lastly our friends at the hemp and
coffee exchange
are creating some great coffee if you
didn't know
hemp coffee is healthy delicious and a
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information please check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com and use the promo
code
drink hemp to get 10 off your purchase
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation
with dr debra kimlis
good afternoon deb thanks for joining us
hi ben thanks for having me absolutely
and it's always
it's great to catch up with you um i see
you a lot out on the conference circuit
you being a
frequent presenter and a very good one a
former canmed presenter
but obviously given the circumstances
we haven't been out there on the circuit
so i wanted to
maybe ask you how has not going to
conferences
and kind of being out there kind of
helped you i don't know maybe refocus
or concentrate more on other work
yeah so this whole coveted pandemic
shutdown thing has been uh
kind of a double-edged sword you know
the good part about not having to travel
outside of your home is that you have a
lot of time to
um dedicate to doing all kinds of
different projects and no excuses for
not doing
them and then the the the bad part is is
one you you miss that collaboration that
face-to-face time with
with people where you know a certain you
know
a simple hello could lead down a path of
a great idea
and so the challenge is
trying to recreate that in creative ways
you know so i think the
the internet was a positive regarding
that you know these podcasts are great
but i think when it comes to
face-to-face
time with people i think you know as
humans we're
we're meant to be social creatures and
and it's you know that part's been kind
of challenging
um i did get a lot of work done though
staying home
um uh and and the challenge with that
also is when to shut down because you
know your workspace and your home space
become
sort of uh and one you know an amorphous
one
yeah you definitely need to keep that
balance and you make a great point about
sort of the
the collaboration in in being in person
with people and
and thankfully it seems like there's
more in-person events being announced
and
of course we're planning to hold canmed
this fall out there in pasadena so
you know fingers crossed everything
keeps trending in the right direction
and
we'll get to talk to each other in
person pretty soon but
but until then we get to talk uh on the
podcast here and i'm excited to talk
with you
about a a new clinical trial uh that you
guys just published about where you were
looking into treating diabetic
neuropathic pain with cbd which is
is really interesting so um let's dive
into it and maybe the best place to
start
is to kind of let's talk about what
exactly is diabetic diabetic
peripheral neuropathy and why did you
think that would be a good target for
cannabinoid therapies so yeah this was
an incredible opportunity to to do with
this study
um we chose diabetic peripheral
neuropathy
because it's a kind of a nerve damage
caused by diabetes elevated
chronic elevation of blood sugar
and um it's quite debilitating it leads
to numbness
loss of sensation pain and usually they
call
this a stocking glove distribution so
it's in their
people's feets and and legs and hands
um and sadly it's the most common
complication
of diabetes it affects upwards of 50 of
patients
and why did yeah i know it's crazy and
why do we think it was a great target
or potential target to to explore is
because there's a lot of
basic science research you know super
smart people
are are creating these animal models um
to look at different types of pain
and they there was a basic science
research that shows
um in a glycine-induced neuropathic pain
model that
cbd seemed to have had a reduction in
pain
in this model um sarah jane ward at a
temple university
my mentor and somebody i admire hugely
looked at cbd to prevent or reduce
um paclitaxel-induced peripheral
neuropathic pain
so from chemotherapy and so diabetes
because it's
rampant and widespread um
and is so debilitating with with this
painful thing we thought this would be
an interesting um target for cbd
oh excellent so it seems like there was
already some
some groundwork laid um through others
who had
kind of been investigating this um at a
more um
uh plant model level does that have that
right i'm not plant i'm sorry animal
animal model yeah i like plants but yes
definitely
definitely at the at the animal you know
bench top model and there's also
a lot of what people like to
sort of turn their nose at but anecdotal
anecdotal evidence
clinically where people seem to respond
to cannabinoids broadly in cbd
specifically so we thought that we would
take a look at it
great and so what are some of the common
medications
used to treat uh dpn and
you know what are their side effects is
is that another reason that
can uh cannabinoids might be a good
candidate here right
so some of the well the the
the main treatment is to try to get some
tight control
um with blood sugar to try to prevent it
but you know sometimes it's it's a
challenge especially if people don't eat
right and
don't understand what the mechanisms are
of why they have diabetes and how to
prevent therefore those
spikes of blood sugar and uh the
chronicity of it
and and so the only two fda
uh approved drugs or lyrica or
pregabalin
and cymbalta otherwise known as
daloxetine
and um they're they're tough drugs to
take i mean
and they have a ton of side effects they
can something is you know
minor until it affects you is dizziness
and nausea
and extreme fatigue you can have weight
gain
you can have amnesia it can affect your
platelets it can cause heart failure so
we're getting into some
you know more serious of these side
effects
um seizures and these also carry a black
box warning
of of um suicide and suicidal ideation
and so yeah i mean you always as a
physician want to balance
efficacy of a drug with side effects
right because what good is it if
something works if at the end of the day
it makes you kill yourself
right you know and as we in
in the cannabinoid or endocannabinoid
industry
have come to learn is that
for the most part when taken prudently
cannabinoids don't
you know have serious adverse
effects or events
certainly certainly um and so one thing
that you mentioned there about
sort of what causes this pain i just
wanted to make sure that i understood
that
correctly is is it something that's
caused by um
you know for lack of a better term like
poor management of diet or
blood sugar is this something that can
be prevented if
if folks are managing things properly
you know it depends i guess on what that
management looks like right
so if you are someone who
eats garbage and and
just takes a pill to sort of counteract
that
i think that the glycosylation of these
nerves is what's happening that leads to
this damage of the nerve of these
peripheral nerves
um will continue and i've read studies
that even
slightly elevated but chronic slight
elevation of blood sugar
can also lead to these um
neuropathic pain issues so
really it's it's got to be looked at in
a more holistic way where
you take charge of what what you eat
and so when i take care of patients who
are tired of of having diabetes and
taking medication
i transition them to a whole food all
plant no added oil no processed food
diet
to help manage their diabetes and the
majority of
of my type 2 diabetics
um are able to reduce or
or replace all of their medicines just
by diet alone
wow that's because they're not spiking
their blood sugar
and sort of creating this nerve damage
exactly and
and it's weird because you know when in
medical school we're taught about
diabetes being a problem with blood
sugar that's sort of like a
um an end result but really the primary
result is
diabetes is because fat
blocks insulin's ability to take
sugar that we need to have for function
and energy our brain
functions on glucose it's not like you
don't need
glucose you just need it in a wholesome
way
not in a refined sugar kind of way but
the real cause of diabetes for people
who are predisposed to
having this is is that fat inside a cell
blocks insulin's ability to bring
sugar in for metabolism
i know right and so because of that then
you see
a blood a blood sugar spike in your
blood because
it's in your blood and not in the cells
where it belongs
right okay very interesting
okay so now that we've sort of set the
table there so
what were the results um of your study
incredible i mean
yeah it i mean so so we had 31 subjects
with
um diabetes this was an open label
meaning
i knew that they had to draw that they
were getting cbd they knew that they
were getting
cbd and um
we had them use a smartphone app we
designed a series of questions looking
at a whole bunch of different endpoints
um one is of course safety you know to
make sure that that this preparation was
safe with no adverse events
um and then the second is efficacy
you know what was a pain scale score did
it go down
and was it statistically significant and
the answer was yes
it was statistically significant and
because this was an
open label i didn't
have anyone get off their lyrica or
cymbalta or any of the off-label
medications that are often used or
prescribed
for this treatment of uh diabetic
neuropathic pain
because if they're they qualify
with a pain scale score an npr score
from zero to ten of a five or greater
than they made the grade and they can be
on it you know in spite of the fact that
they were still taking these meds
so we had you know
more subjects on these pain meds
still with an average pain scale score
of of close to seven
on medication and we even compared it
with their with with with patients
who weren't on these medicines with
their average pain scale score
close to seven and they both
statistically significantly dropped
by almost half
yeah that's that's pretty remarkable um
it's huge
it's it's huge and and when you look at
mprs score
um and something like diabetic
neuropathic pain there's something
called
what is um minimally clinically
significant
so what makes patients say
that was worth my while and generally
speaking they
you know an nprs of a
a reduction of two points
is clinically significant for patients
and we were down by three
as an average right and that i was going
to ask you about that because when i was
reading through the
the um the study there um the results
were
presented as an average um were there
any uh participants who had
a reduction of pain so much that it was
zero or
is that yeah yeah three
that that's that's incredible it's it's
that's what i'm saying like these
results were incredible
absolutely um incredible and
and the results were um
robust enough for us to say
what if we do this again
but we do it with a placebo control
double blind
randomized trial and so that's what we
did
and literally last week we just closed
out
51 subjects
double blind randomized trial placebo
controlled
and now it's the data sets are with the
statisticians so now we wait
okay so no no indication or
any idea of how the data looks or yeah
so there is an indication
for a statistically significant
reduction in pain
and we took people off their payments
wow well that's that's certainly
significant and i want to
go ahead please smart people the smart
statisticians to get their hands on it
so this is uh
you know another story for another
podcast hopefully and another manuscript
but um there are you know there are
um some indications that show
similar type results
yeah that's that's certainly remarkable
and another thing that i read
um in the study is that i think
and if i read it curricula you could
certainly tell me that some of the
participants
actually wanted to stop using their
medications
um but i think you advise them not to
just because under the terms of the
study like you said you wanted to keep
them
you know consistent or keep them on the
medications
consistently um which certainly makes
sense but
i was curious that now with that study
over
do you know how did any of those
participants actually
stop using their medications so good
question because
we're a clinical trials company per se
there's no
they're not patients of ours you know so
they're we don't follow up beyond
you know what our our protocol
is so i don't know that but i would
imagine
if i were one of those patients i
certainly would
would replace my medications or augment
my
medications with cbd after the use of
this yeah if if for no other reason then
uh what we've touched on before that you
know some of those
side effects from those other
medications are
pretty significant and um
conversely i read also in your study
that
none of the participants rep reported
any adverse revi
excuse me reported any adverse events
from
the cbd which i have to think that
um that's very uncommon in a clinical
trial is that fair to say
it is very fair to say i mean
generally speaking you know it's fair to
say
you know for anything that people
always have some sort of an issue with
something
um so yes it was very rare and again
that's why
you know this was a really informative
trial
albeit an open label um
and so that's why we wanted to see what
would happen what if
we did this again you know everybody
blinded
and placebo controlled
yeah absolutely and you know kind of
just going back to the whole
idea of there being no adverse events
know it's sort of something that comes
up a lot when i talk with with
physicians or
clinicians in general is that you know
that's one of the great things about
about cbd or cannabinoid therapies is
that
really the adverse events the likelihood
of an adverse event is very low
not that it's not that it's zero but it
is so low that
um it's often a good idea to at least
try it
and you know and if it doesn't work for
you then kind of no harm no foul
but um that's one thing about
cannabinoid therapies that's
um pretty remarkable absolutely i call
it like the therapeutic order of
operations
right so first you know change your diet
and lifestyle
take away all the things that are
adversely impacting
your your health and then
if you still have a condition
start adding on things with the least
amount of side effects
so i'm not saying that pharmaceuticals
are terrible but i'm saying that
there are other things including
cannabinoids
that should be tried first before we get
to something because you want to have
something that's effective
with the least amount of side effects
right
right yeah so with that i'd sort of i'm
curious to talk with you about
sort of the medicine itself that you
were using to treat these patients
and if i understand correctly the cbd
treatment you studied was
actually in a tablet form which kind of
struck me as
rather rare for cannabis treatments
is that true well i mean there's
oral ingestibles of of all sorts right
so um the owner of the company pg
forma had the idea
that he wanted to create a
administration form that
doctors would be comfortable with and
familiar with patients would be
comfortable with and familiar with
that it would be an ease of use they
would be able to titrate it
you know up or down depending upon the
the effects
of the of the of the medicine on the
indication
and so it's it's rare that
it's a water solubilized iteration of
cbd
it goes under your tongue it rapidly
dissolves
and so you know lots and lots of people
use
a sublingual version that's oil-based
and dropper-based
and so this was formulated in a tablet
form to
to look familiar and feel familiar and
look
like real medicine that it is right
no it was something that came up when i
was talking with uh dr peter grinspoon
on um an earlier podcast he was pretty
adamant that you know if we want
cannabis to be treated like a medicine
it should look like a medicine um you
know
to be sort of treating conditions with
with gummy bears or things like that
it just doesn't it doesn't fit so i
think
moving more towards a traditional look
would certainly help at least
with adoption from folks who are maybe
not as comfortable
with cannabis absolutely you know i
always say i don't
like to vilify any cannabinoid nor do i
want to
vilify any administration form
for sure i can assure you that as a
physician i've never written a
prescription for a brownie
right however if that's the only way
someone with horrific anxiety
you know will take a cannabinoid and
that cannabinoid seems to work
for that anxiety i'm just using as an
example
then gosh why not you know but
there are subset of people who look at
cannabis and think of it as
you know um something that you know
stoners use and they think it's only
about smoking and there's no way they
would ever use this
you know without remembering that this
was in the u.s pharmacopoeia
up until the early 1940s and
my grandfather a pharmacist probably you
know
had alcohol extractions and of you know
tinctures of
of cannabinoids on a shelf that he gave
people
so you know everyone i i think the
beauty of
of this industry is that
there's something for everyone you know
if somebody's
um inclination is to say i want to get
closest to the plan as possible and
feels that vaporizing or inhalation of
some sort is
is the way to go then and it works fine
you know if
somebody wants to say i'm not really
excited about
that method of administration these
sublingual tablets make the most sense
to me
i i i'm we're right there for him
yeah absolutely and i think at the end
of the day we want to um
we want to make this as accessible as
possible to as many different people as
possible right
well i i think that's what we want for
the medical industry right i think
it it makes sense and again just based
on
the safety profile and the and you know
and and potential
efficacy absolutely
so more about um this tablet and what
you used in the study
um i understand it was it was cbd but i
was curious
were there any other cannabinoids or
terpenoids sort of in that formulation
or was it
just cbd only so it is a proprietary
blend
so i can't disclose but it had
curated terpenes and uh some secret
sauce
and uh cbd
excellent excellent so i mean
i guess the obligatory question about
the entourage effect
so i i take it that if there are other
cannabinoids and terpenoids in there
then
um it's certainly playing a role at
least um
in the benefits here so
i think we we can all agree about the
synergistic
effects you know reign supreme even in
traditional medicine
you know as an anesthesiologist we would
use
a bunch of different medications to um
[Music]
induce somebody you know for general
anesthesia
as opposed to one medicine and just use
a whole lot of it
again to reduce side effects of one
medication so synergistic effects of
of different molecules make
a lot of sense and have always made a
lot of sense
um i kind of struggle with
if you have an oral ingestible you know
what happens in the stomach when
you know it's a ph of less than two and
um hydrochloric acid is there
and then it goes through the digestive
process and i think about
you know we eat a lot of terpenes all
day long in fruits and vegetables and
herbs
and spices
i i don't know if in that method of
administration
if it matters as much as it would with
inhalation like
aromatherapy right or
a sublingual where you where you
it is potentially absorbed into the
systemic circulation
bypassing that that gi tract in that
you know metabolism piece
yeah that is that is interesting it
hadn't really struck me until you
you mentioned it that um you're right we
we are ingesting all different types of
foods that have different terpenes and
different compounds in them and
if we are if we all agree that there is
an entourage effect going on here how
could
you know eating an edible after you eat
a cheeseburger different than
be different than if you ate it after
you had a salad um
something i'd never considered before um
or augmented better with a salad
well let's just say the salad had some
kind of olive oil on it so people aren't
saying you know to themselves listening
to this podcast
oh well it's the fat content of the
cheeseburger and by the way
disclosure i'm not advising a
cheeseburger but that content of the
cheeseburger that allows for better
absorption of the
terpenes in cannabinoids um but
but still i think we can agree
that you know cannabis is a very
efficient
manufacturer of terpenes
and other plant sources have a greater
amount
and yet you know i i just don't know
you know this is something that keeps me
up at night and someday i would love to
run
you know clinical trials somebody wants
to fund me doing this
you know looking exactly at this
question
yeah we just don't know it's something i
hear a lot talking to
folks in this field which um is always
exciting
and um you know if nothing else it's job
security right we still have a lot to
learn
and on the and on the topic of clinical
trials you know another thing that
always comes up when i talk with people
about cannabis and cannabis medicine is
you know we need more clinical trials
there's not enough clinical trials
um so now you've completed one here and
you have another
double-blind study in the works um
why do you feel like there aren't more
clinical trials being done now
so one they're difficult
they're expensive you have to be
clever enough to work around the legal
and regulatory landscape in a
using a federally illegal substance
you know and then there's covet right so
um of course
you know add that to the mix and and
i would also i mean expensive probably
should have been number one more than
difficult
i mean because there's always ways and
of figuring stuff
out if i did it you know i'm sure other
people can too but but it's expensive
and if you think about it
you know for the most part universities
don't want to touch it because
of federal funding and they're they're
nervous about it and anytime you onboard
a university
generally speaking it becomes very
cumbersome and a lot of red tape
um and businesses who
are you know cultivating processing and
selling
on a retail sales landscape
are busy doing that and
it's hard to monetize a clinical trial i
mean
pure green pharmaceuticals in the midst
of
of uh trying to fundraise to be able to
take these this
these pieces of information that we're
getting to the fda
to get an ind to make make a true
pharmaceutical
you know no differently than gw forma
and you know it's it's hard people
generally
don't put their money where their mouth
is
yeah no it's an it's unfortunate but
it's it's encouraging at least that
that you're managing to to get it done
and we
are seeing more or come around um so
hopefully that's a
that's a trend that continues right it's
not just me
it's you know pharma is um
was self-funded by the ceo for a long
time
and then through connections in the
largess of an investment company
out of pennsylvania go figure um
who believed in you know making real
medicine
right and now in terms of clinical
trials like are there
are there certain standards that must be
met to kind of perform like a
quote unquote proper clinical trial in
terms of
sample size selection criteria time
period
or things like that i ask because i mean
unfortunately in this space and i
imagine in any space there's sort of
there's pseudoscience there's you know
um
maybe some less scrupulous studies that
are out there that
folks might tout as being a
quote-unquote clinical trial but
maybe aren't um as
robust as as a proper one i wonder
if so are there some sort of like red
flags that consumers
might be able to kind of look for if if
there are folks
claiming to have performed a clinical
trial
so for sure there is i like the term
proper
proper clinical trial absolutely and
there are rules that
govern and standards that govern what a
clinical trial
is i mean people go to school for years
and years i studied
passed an exam and i'm actually a
certified principal investigator
as well as my other um my other initials
so i have cpi going for me
and you know it it's it's hard so yes
sample size is
calculated it's called power through
smart statisticians looking at
what the endpoints are and what the what
kinds of results you want to see
um and
and you need to have this gone through
like a
uh investigators review board to make
sure that it's ethical
and that somebody independent is sort of
overseeing
what the what the protocol is that
there's informed consents to make sure
that
subjects are protected their rights are
protected their health
in the event of an adverse event or even
just publishing
any of this stuff you know so there's a
site called
clinicaltrials.gov
it's it's um actually overseen by the
nih national
national institute of health so all of
our tax dollars are paying for this
that true robust clinical trials
have to list on that site
and it's not easy to do it is probably
one of the harder things i've done
and i've studied for board
certifications for many
many different medical um
specialties and and it's really
challenging to do this but every one of
our trials is list is irb approved and
listed on clinicaltrials.gov
and you can see those trials you can
google it google
you know my last name and you can see a
list of
of trials that you know we've got irb
approval for
and we're just waiting for funding or
we've completed or we're in the midst of
recruiting
so you can see all that and that would
be something that
um patients if they're interested in
looking at can also see
but most of these manufacturers are not
doing these things
and most of these publications are not
in a peer review medical journal
you know so it's kind of like a buyer
beware as well
and not to suggest that the information
that manufacturers garner from patients
that use
their products is not valuable certainly
is
but there's a difference between you
know
a patient survey and you know a
real robust clinical trial
absolutely yeah that that
clinicaltrials.gov that's that's a great
resource
um to certainly um
maybe vet some of these these things or
some of these claims or
or maybe just to to keep an eye on what
clinical trials are being done
in the space so i'll definitely provide
a link to that in the show notes so
people can uh
can check that out um all right so
i guess wrapping up here um i wanted to
give you an opportunity to
plug any um any websites any social
media
anything that you would like to um to
let people know about so they can maybe
learn more about the work you're doing
or maybe connect with you
the floor is yours sure so thank you so
absolutely go on to
pg pharma.co
especially if you're an investor in the
space that
is excited about creating you know
fda-approved pharmaceuticals
because again like we you know with a
shout out to what we said before
some people would only take
what they consider to be the gold
standard of medicine which is
you know found in a pharmacy fda
approved with a thumbs up
and that's what we're trying to create
so pgforma.co has has all the links to
you know instagram or whatever and
you can go on to clinicaltrials.gov and
see what we're doing
and then our journal article is a
journal of of diabetes and metabolism
where you can read the full journal
excellent yep and again i will provide
links to each of those resources in the
notes so it's just easy for people to um
to check that out all right well
deb thanks again for for joining us here
on the podcast
and i do hope i get to see you in person
later this year
oh i do too and ben thank you for
inviting me this was great
absolutely talk to you soon take care
bye-bye
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr debra kimlis
you can read more about the topics we
discussed using the links
in the show description and thanks again
to this episode sponsor
puregreen pharmaceuticals our next
episode will drop
may 5th in the meantime please do check
out canmedevents.com
for all the latest news surrounding
canmed2021
and while you're there be sure to sign
up for email alerts
the best place to do that is on our
podcast webpage
that's at canmedevents.com
if you complete the form on that page
you will be entered to win
two tickets to our vip dinner for
canmed2021
if social media is more your thing you
can keep up with us
on instagram facebook twitter
and linkedin just search for canmed
events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app
please do subscribe to our feed and also
leave us a 5 star review
okay until next time stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of cammed coffee talk
you