[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now
to learn all about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets today at
our special early bird rate
while you're at cammanevents.com be sure
to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
the best place to do that is on our
podcast page
which you can find in the main menu
under the media tab
you can also go there directly by going
to kenmedevents.com
coffeetalk there is a sign up form
on that page and if you complete it you
will be entered into a drawing to win
two k med 2021 vip dinner tickets
while you are there you can also listen
to all the canmed coffee talk podcast
episodes in our archive
and be sure to check out the latest
issue of cannabis patient care
to learn all about how can men's parent
company medicinal genomics
got its start and why our ceo brendan
mckernan
and cso kevin mckernan remain so
committed to advancing the cannabis
industry
and helping patients in need just head
over to the canmed website
under the about us tab to find out more
special thanks to our friends at
cannabis patient care for publishing
this story
and while you're at it don't forget to
give them a follow at cannabis
patient care okay my guest
this episode is alice moon alice is a pr
and marketing professional who has
worked in the cannabis space
since 2011 in 2018
alice was diagnosed with cannabinoid
hyperemesis syndrome
and had to cease cannabis use completely
since being diagnosed with chs
alice has found herself being an
advocate for safe and mindful cannabis
consumption
awareness and research at kmed 2019
alice participated on a csh
panel which is the first time i had
heard about this condition
since then her passion for educating on
the subject has garnered the attention
of rx leaf leafly business insider
and forbes in early 2020
yahoo released a documentary featuring
alice
which i will link to in the show
description during our conversation we
discussed
alice's experience with chs what little
we know about what causes chs
what treatments provide relief from chs
strategies cannabis users can use to
reduce their risk of developing the
syndrome
how awareness for chs has grown since
alice developed the condition
whether patients who recover from chs
can go back to using cannabis
the three stages of chs and more
before we get to my conversation with
alice i would like to thank this
episode's sponsor
the american cannabis nurses association
acna is a national nursing organization
whose mission is to advance excellence
in cannabis nursing practice
through advocacy collaboration education
research and policy development founded
in
2010 acna is now in its 11th year
with almost 1700 members in the united
states
they continue to work on providing their
members with
up-to-date cannabis information and
resources to care for patients
who use cannabis join them today at
www.cannabisnurses.org
and be part of the change
and lastly our friends at the hemp and
coffee exchange
are creating some great coffee if you
didn't know
hemp coffee is healthy delicious and a
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information please check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
off your purchase okay
and without any further ado please enjoy
my conversation with alice moon
good afternoon alice thanks so much for
joining us thanks so much for having me
happy to be here
all right i'm very interested to talk
with you today
about an issue that i imagine a lot of
our listeners don't
know too much about cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome or cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome um so you have dealt with this
personally and i know you've told your
story
countless times but i hope you wouldn't
mind sharing it again
um just tell us about your your
experience with this
syndrome and then we can talk more about
um
kind of everything that goes into it
yeah so um i joined the cannabis
industry back in 2011
and in 2015 i started writing edible
reviews so i was consuming
a good amount of edibles about 10 to 15
milligrams of edibles a day i'd smoke
about half a joint a day
i wouldn't consider myself a heavy user
by any means but i was definitely a user
i used cannabis for anxiety and
depression and for sleep
so it was definitely a medicine for me
um while i also would use it
recreationally sometimes during the day
so it had a lot of benefits and purposes
for me
around 2016 i started to throw up and
i would just get really sick for a few
hours at a time they would go away and
it would happen
about once a month and then as time went
on it started happening
more and more like once a week and then
in 2018
i threw up for 14 days straight and that
was non-stop vomiting
all day every day 14 days and doctors
couldn't figure out what was wrong with
me
then eventually i saw a doctor who said
you know it's got to be the weed so i
took a three-month cannabis break
and then i reintroduced cannabis back
into my life and i got sick again this
time only lasting four days
and then i said okay maybe i can
introduce cbd
oh and when i reintroduced cannabis into
my life that was pesticide-free cannabis
i made sure it's pesticide-free um so
because a lot of people say that chs
caused by pesticides so
went pesticide free still got sick and
then i introduced cbd into my life
and i was able to use cbd for about
three months until i had
my worst episode yet where i threw up
all day every day for 16 days straight
so it's been a really crazy journey with
chs um
just being so sick for so many years not
knowing what was going on with me having
my near-death experiences with all my
throwing up
and my 16-day episode i got an
ulcer hernia and a bacteria infection in
my gut from all the throwing up
wow that is that's unbelievable really
um i can't believe you had to go through
that um
so when was it that you actually figured
out that this was
chs or that it was the cannabis that was
was causing this and i mean i'll be very
i'll be very frank i had never heard of
chs until i heard your story i came in
2019.
um so what resources were available to
you
at the time um when you were going
through this was it how well known was
it
it wasn't very well known at all there
was barely any resources
the only things i could find online when
searching um
were like very fear-mongering articles
that are like cannabis is bad and
people are getting really really sick
and it's crazy and just
it was very fear-mongering and wasn't
informative at all
um dr jeff rober um raber i don't know
exactly how to pronounce his last name
um
with um he's with the terpene company he
actually is the one who told me to put
capsaicin cream on my stomach and so
that did provide some relief when i used
capsaicin cream but then my skin was on
fire and was burning and so i used a wet
rag to try to
wipe the capsaicin off not knowing that
water actually increases the effects of
it
and so i just made it even worse and
then i was crying in tears
because my stomach was on fire um and so
i couldn't use capsaicin again after
that because it was so traumatizing but
capsaicin does help a lot of people um
but back to your question there wasn't a
lot of information out there at all
there's a few facebook groups that exist
that are great resources now but i
didn't have them at the time i wasn't
aware of them
it wasn't until i started publicly
speaking that people reached out to me
and told me about the facebook group so
it took me
a few years to like really find a lot of
resources on it and
when did i first truly believe that i
had it well before my 14-day episode
right before i had seen a doctor and she
had said it could probably be the weed
and so
before my 14-day episode i said okay i'm
gonna go have one last hurrah
i'm going to an infused dinner in the
malibu hills i just didn't want to pass
it up and
that last hurrah is what triggered my 14
day episode and so it became very
apparent that it was cannabis that was
triggering my symptoms
wow you know and i have to imagine that
that's that must have been hard for you
personally too because you were in the
in the industry you're very vocal
advocate for cannabis and then to have
this be
something that's causing you illness
must have been a hard thing to accept
a very hard thing to accept it's been a
very challenging thing i still you know
get upset about it from time to time
because
not only is cannabis my medicine but
cannabis is my entire life
like i'm a cannabis socialite i go to
events all the time i review
products i educate people on safe
consumption i
live eat breathe sleep cannabis it is my
world completely so
definitely hard pill to swallow on that
one
and i wonder if you could speak to what
has sort of the response been from the
cannabis community now that you've been
more vocal
about this issue i'm i mean i can speak
from
not really experience but talking with
other folks on the podcast who have
maybe
raised some concerns about potentially
negative effects of cannabis that
they do receive some backlash from
people in the community so i was
wondering uh
if you experienced that at all yes so
while i have had some support from
people in the industry i've also
had an overwhelming amount of backlash
um someone said i deserve to be beaten
up because i was speaking out about it
um i've received targeted attacks so
many different times um from people both
within the industry and without
outside of the industry i've lost a lot
of peers
in the space people who i thought that
were like friends
because they were just so frustrated
that i was speaking out about this
and they think that it's a potential
harm to legalization but i just think
it's a potential negative that needs to
be discussed and
by not discussing it we're doing more
harm than good
i agree with you 100 um i think we all
agree that cannabis has
amazing therapeutic potential um
and if we believe that can do all these
great things then
we have to assume that they it could do
some negative things too
in certain situations and thankfully um
it doesn't happen too often but we need
to acknowledge that there is a risk out
there
in some cases and the more we understand
it the better we can um
we better we can use the medicine
absolutely yeah
i really want the cannabis community to
understand that um
and become more accepting and aware of
it because i was sick for two years
before i knew what was wrong with me and
that's because there wasn't any
education and awareness and
i that's two years of suffering that i
went through that you know
things that i had to cancel all the time
flights that were missed things that
my life was disrupted because i was so
sick and i don't want anyone else to
have to go through that so i think
awareness
is super important all right so on the
topic of awareness so
as i was saying to you before we started
recording that back in
2019 when you were on the panel about
this this issue at kim in 2019
i had never heard of chs um but since
then i have heard of it a few times
most recently in a clubhouse room
discussing
thc limits that are going to be placed
on edibles where someone mentioned that
chs is a real thing
and um a lot of people on that call had
had never heard of it
and i actually actually uh raised my
hand and pointed people to
the video of the panel that you were on
uh and i hope people actually check that
out and i will definitely add a link to
that
in the show notes for um for this
podcast as well for anyone who hasn't
seen it
but back to the original question about
awareness that
how has awareness grown since 2019
um awareness is definitely growing i
mean i was featured by washington post
last summer
they did a cover story in their health
section of the newspaper
about chs so that was a big deal
business insider leafly high times
they've all done pieces on it
as well and then a few tv stations have
also done pieces
so i think awareness is growing um i
created an instagram account and a
twitter account
that um you know i use chs hashtags and
constantly i'm searching twitter for
people who are talking about chs that
way i can point them in the right
direction for resources
so i think awareness is definitely
growing a lot more people are hearing
about it but there's still
a lot more people who need to hear about
it so the work is not over yet
yeah and again during that panel in 2019
you know this whole condition was still
very mysterious as to
you know what are the causes what are
the treatments there hadn't been enough
research into
chs what's changed on that front do we
have any more
idea of sort of what's triggering this
condition or maybe
um at least some commonalities
between people who are experiencing it
so um at the canmed panel i had done a
survey of i believe it was like 130 or
150 people i'm since then i've done a
survey of 330 people
and i asked more in-depth questions and
really the only commonality that we all
have is that we use cannabis
the amount that we use the duration we
used um
the type used it all varies
um the age of people the majority of
people were using for eight years or
longer before developing symptoms but
there were people who were using for
less than a year that developed symptoms
so it's kind of
all over the place um and uh there was
one other point with it that
i just slipped my brain it'll come back
to me um but yeah
oh um there was a high amount of people
with anxiety and depression
so that is interesting i can't say that
oh if you have anxiety and depression
you're gonna get chs it might be
those people are just using cannabis to
treat their anxiety and depression and
that's why
we have a high amount of people that
have it but that was the pre-existing
condition that there was a high amount
of people having it
um as far as treatment goes 90 i think
believe like 97
of people use hot baths successfully um
to treat their symptoms
um haldol is a medication that is
commonly used and there was a small
amount of people who use haldol
and it did work for them but it gave
them such severe side effects that they
said they would have preferred the
nausea and vomiting over the side
effects
so aldol is really a medication that is
being used more it's kind of the go-to
now in emergency rooms so doctors are
turning to that medication
it's benzodiazepine and antipsychotic
and so for people who don't have
psychotic issues it can cause psychosis
so it is should be a last resort
capsaicin cream should be the go-to but
a lot of doctors are using haldol and a
few other medications
um university of calgary in canada is
currently doing a study to see
how beneficial haldol truly is as a
medication for treatment
so we'll see those results in a few
months see what they come up with
they did a study already on capsaicin
and so now they're working on hal doll
to see how that works out
oh well so that's encouraging that there
are some some folks that are doing some
research into treatments for this
yeah um i wish that there was some
research going on into the cause behind
it
i think that would be more beneficial if
we could figure out the root cause and a
way to test for it
to see why this is occurring and who
this is occurring in so that way people
if there's like some type of genetic
predisposition
we can figure it out sooner before
people go through you know months to
years of suffering
yeah and the thing that really kind of
stands out to me is that
you know as you as you mentioned in your
stories that you enjoyed cannabis
symptom-free for years um before
developing this condition so
i mean do we understand is there some
sort of
you know mechanism that flips that you
can no longer tolerate it i mean
obviously i think
as you said we still don't know but it
just
it seems interesting and not something i
can really think of happening with
any other allergy or condition or
syndrome
yeah it seems like it's just like a flip
that gets switched all of a sudden
your body just rejects it there's one
theory that too much cannabis can turn
off the trip 1
receptor the crpv1 receptor which is a
receptor it's a capsaicin receptor that
actually helps regulate digestion
and it's suggested that perhaps too much
cannabis can turn off that receptor in
some people
and the heat hot bath and capsaicin
cream on the stomach turn that receptor
back on because it's a capsaicin
receptor
so there is that theory that um
potentially that
receptor is what is getting shut down
but you know that is just a theory and
we don't 100 know
yeah and so is there any sort of general
advice that
that folks are giving to you know sort
of prevent that if it is sort of like an
overload of that system in terms of
you know whether it's taking regular
breaks from cannabis to kind of reset
the receptors
i uh recently did a podcast with dr
dustin sulaku
who recommended that not in not for chs
specifically but just in general to you
know
take a break every now and then and that
you can actually see some regeneration
of
um cb1 receptors in just 48 hours of
cessation so
is there any thought to maybe that being
a potential way to
prevent something like this absolutely
yeah i think everyone should take
cannabis breaks every now and then
just give your body a reset um yeah i
think that's very important and that's
something that i
rarely did is i didn't take breaks i was
consuming quite often
so i wish i would have taken more breaks
for sure and i think
you know there's three phases to chs
there's the padronal phase which is
nausea and stomach aches then there's
the hyperemetic stage which is where the
people are throwing up
and then there's the recovery stage
which is when you're getting better so
if people hate that for dramaal stage
the beginning stage of it where they're
just feeling nauseous
that's definitely a key sign that they
should be taking a break and then
hopefully by taking a break they won't
ever get to the hypometic stage
oh interesting so is that something that
you know
will start happening like you'll feel
nauseous with one session and it sort of
goes away but you continue to use and it
progresses or does it all kind of
progress one after another it kind of
progresses generally
um and some people won't even experience
the padronal phase like i didn't
experience that phase i went straight to
the hyperometic phase
so this hits everyone differently
unfortunately like there isn't like a
real pattern with things it kind of is
like all over the place with how it's
gonna affect people
and another thing is it's usually not
immediately after smoking
it's usually about 24 hours after using
so that's why it can be hard to
correlate that it's cannabis because
it's not always immediately after use
now once you get to the hypermedic phase
and you're like really bad off it can
happen immediately like right after you
smoke you're immediately sick but
generally
for people it's like 24 hours afterwards
which is really
why it's hard to correlate the fact that
it is cannabis making you sick
yeah and i think one of the things that
you had mentioned on that panel is
you know cannabis is largely accepted or
believed to be
kind of an anti-nausea remedy
so if what you're saying is that after
24 hours of using cannabis you could
start feeling nauseous
it's not um it could be a logical
response to be like hey i'll have some
cannabis to help relieve my nausea but
that could be the exact opposite of what
you should be doing
absolutely yeah a lot of people do use
cannabis to try to treat their symptoms
of chs and then they only make
themselves worse
and that's because they don't know about
chs and what's going on with their body
absolutely and then so i mean we're
talking about raising awareness
in in users but what about awareness
amongst
medical professionals and you know er
physicians for example
um you know what sort of efforts are
being done to kind of educate them on
on this condition so last year i worked
with the institute for safe medicine
practices in canada and we developed a
brochure to give out to
people in emergency rooms all across
canada so
now i have canada down now it's next to
us try to
work on something similar in the united
states so
um you know i'm just one person here and
i don't get paid to do this so i try my
hardest to get things done but
so we at least educated um you know
physicians and emergency room doctors in
canada but there isn't a lot of efforts
being made in the united states and
i think there's two issues right now
either doctors don't know about chs
or doctors know about it and they're too
quick to diagnose people with it
so a lot of doctors can misdiagnose
people because they just ask the patient
like are you using cannabis
okay that's what's making you sick and
that person could potentially have other
underlying conditions that the doctor
doesn't want to test for because they
just want to put it straight to cannabis
and we're seeing that a lot and that
kind of um
makes people disbelieve in chs because
then they end up finding out that
there's something else going on with
them and so they're saying you know
doctors are just too quick to make this
up
so i think that there's like two issues
at hand so we need to educate doctors on
it but we also need doctors to make sure
that they're ruling out every other
possibility before saying it chs
yeah that's a great point and now so i
guess in that
in that vein are there some symptoms
that are specific to chs that's sort of
a clear indicator that
that's what that's what this is finding
a relief from a hot bath
is one of the key indicators that
doctors use for diagnosis
because there isn't anything else that
really provides this kind of relief
i'm talking about like i was throwing up
excessively and i would get in the hot
tub and i would stop completely and then
within seconds of getting out of the tub
i'd be throwing up again
so it's really that like important
and just impactful the hot bath the heat
yeah i was like living on my bathroom
floor going between like throwing up in
the hot bath for quite some time
and you know that just leads to more
dehydration which is not good for you
um which you know there have been a few
deaths from chs
from dehydration and organ failure
because people are throwing up so
excessively and they don't know what's
going on with them
and they are treated properly and then
ultimately you know they have died
so there's been five reported deaths
total on chs
wow and so i mean
and i think you kind of touched on it
before but i don't know maybe we could
talk about it again but
yeah i mean what is it about the hot
bath specifically that
is providing the relief if we even know
or if there's a theory behind that
yeah so there is a theory about trpv1
receptor which i mentioned and then
there's also a theory about
body temperature regulation blood
temperature regulation
and i'm not too privy on that one so i
can't really speak on it too much but
there's just a few theories around going
around that but i think the trp v1 the
trip one receptor one is the one that
makes the most sense out of everything
i've read
that the hot bath turns that receptor
back on temporarily
and then when you get out of the hot
bath that receptor gets shut back off
and your body goes haywire
wow wow and then one of the other things
that uh you mentioned on the panel that
some folks get some relief with is
running which um the first thing
and the first thing that came to my mind
when i heard that was anandamide
you know could anandam be playing a role
but then i think the doctor on the panel
mentioned more about the temperature
regulation aspect of that but
i'll let you speak to it yeah so running
is something that has helped
in a survey that i did there was only a
small amount of people who got relief
from running
um only i think like i don't know
like 10 of people found relief from
running but that still is
a percent that's like 33 people who
found relief from running
um and there was one study um documented
case of someone getting rhabdomyolysis
from running so much
someone ran for like 17 hours straight
and just um did his body dirty by just
running so much
and his body just you know shut down on
him um he didn't die thankfully but he
got rhabdomyolysis from it
and yeah we don't really understand the
why behind it
um with my second episode i the one that
lasted four days i got up and went for
like extensive walks every day and i
don't know if that helped at all
but i know that my episode only lasted
four days that time instead of the 14 or
16 days
so that could have had some type of
impact the moving around the changing of
body temperature
that could have helped with my um
symptoms
and so i want to ask you um so what is
your relationship with cannabis
now um is it still that you cannot
tolerate
any at all or is there any um
are there any cases of folks who have
chs who
are able to reintroduce cannabinoids or
is it just
you know it's done so um from what i've
seen
people who reintroduce cannabinoids if
they have chs they do end up getting
sick again
but it's a matter of time it's not
always like immediate it could be after
years or it could be after weeks
um but it the symptoms do come back but
a lot of people don't want to give up
cannabis as their medicine so they
figure out ways to use it lightly
whether that be just using like one hit
a day
one toke a week or something like that
and there's a lot of people who still
consume
and they just listen to their body when
the nausea starts to creep up they take
a cannabis break
i personally um my endocannabinoid
system is so
overdone that i can't even handle
secondhand smoke now so my friends can't
even smoke around me
or i will start to throw up and so i
can't use cannabis at all
but i still work in the industry i'm
still extremely passionate about the
plant um i do pr
marketing and social media and um i
promote the plant and all of its
benefits and i love it so much
and i want to cure so that way i can go
back to using my medicine
no and i think that's an important um an
important thing to bring up again
because um like you said you experienced
some backlash talking out
about against excuse me you experienced
some backlash
speaking out about this issue and
oftentimes people you know are very
black and white when it comes to
cannabis it's either
it's either all good or it's all bad and
i think you're a great example of
you know acknowledging the bad and the
good and
you know having a very um level-headed
perspective on that so
yeah and i think something else that we
should touch base on is what happens
when somebody stops using cannabis
because that's also not talked about at
all you think you stop using cannabis
and then you're all better and that's
not necessarily true
people go through withdrawals so i had
extreme nightmares when i quit using
cannabis my anxiety heightened
um and you know that could be because i
had pre-existing anxiety um but
i've talked to plenty of people who
didn't have pre-existing anxiety and
they quit using and
they had anxiety afterwards they had
loss of appetite sleep issues
agitation so there's a lot of things
that can go on mentally and physically
with the body when you quit using
cannabis
so it's not as cut and dry as oh you
have chs just quit using it's like
somebody can go through a lot of really
gnarly withdrawals um
and the industry likes to say that there
isn't any withdrawals from cannabis but
that's simply not true your body is
going through some changes you know
your body can be so positively in fact
impacted by cannabis when you're using
it like
when you take it away can't you imagine
that some things could be going on with
your body then as well
absolutely and if everything we know
about the endocannabinoid system is that
you know it's
it's to promote homeostasis if you're
constantly
supplementing with cannabinoids um and
then you take those away
then there's gonna have to be kind of a
readjustment period it makes all the
sense
in the world and so there's been so many
people who go back to using cannabis
because they don't want to deal with the
nightmares and the anxiety and all that
stuff
and so then you know it's a never-ending
cycle of like getting sick and
having to quit getting sick having to
quit and it just
quite simply it sucks yeah absolutely
um but it is good to hear that you know
some people who experience
this can still um can still use cannabis
in small doses or more manageable doses
and again i've i've spoken to to doctors
here on the podcast who
who say that a lot of patients can get a
lot of benefits from from low doses
of cannabinoids still um so hopefully
if um if folks who are really using
cannabis to to treat a
severe condition or it's the only thing
that works for them
there's still some hope that they can
continue to use it
yeah totally and um you know anyone
listening to this who thinks they might
have chs
just listen to your body i think that's
really important if you are throwing up
all the time then definitely cut
cannabis out of your life but if you're
only feeling some nausea
and you're able to take breaks and then
reintroduce it like just
tread carefully and be very careful with
it because
you don't want to go into a 14 day
episode like i wouldn't do
yeah absolutely and i know we sort of
talked about it
when we were we're asking if there was
any kind of correlation between
the experiences of people who have gone
through this but um i don't think we
talked specifically
of you know are there certain
formulations or certain forms of
cannabis that
that seem to trigger this more than
others for example
you know smoking versus eating or
you know high thc versus high cbd or is
it sort of all across the board
so with my survey only three people were
edible users only
so that was surprising that only three
people were just using edibles the
majority of people were using cannabis
as the flower itself and the majority
were using it out of bongs
there was you know some people are using
dabs and bongs
some people using vapes as well but
majority of people were smoking flour
as far as if it was high thc low thd i
actually don't know the answer to that
question
i'm not sure but as far as if it was
pesticide free or not
there is about half of people who grew
their own and it was pesticide free
so and they still develop chs symptoms
so um
but half the people didn't know what if
their flower was pesticide free or not
um
so you know with legalization we'll see
more people who are like having access
to pesticide free flour
and so then they'll actually know what
they're getting but for now a lot of
people don't have safe access so they're
getting whatever they're getting but
i don't believe that pesticides are the
issue here at all
um i think if it was a pesticide problem
we'd see this a lot more widespread
and this has could occur with people
with synthetic cannabinoid use at all
um as well so that shows that it's like
something to do with cannabinoids is the
root cause of this
wow wow so
so what's next for you and your um in
your goal to try to raise awareness here
um what's next i'm just going to keep
doing interviews i'm trying to spread
the word you know my next goal is to be
new york
be in new york times that's like the
ideal goal
i was speaking with them last year
before covet hit and then when covet
became a thing that like cut that story
out of the picture but
that would be um my ultimate goal is to
get in new york times because that is a
story that
that would just reach a lot of people
and i want to just keep
reaching out to people talking to people
connecting and educating and letting
people know that they're not alone with
this because i felt extremely alone and
it was very isolating and
i just want people to know that i'm a
support for them if they have chs if
they have any questions about it they
can come to me
um i also built a website uh
www.cannabinoid
hyperemesis.com where people can read 20
plus research papers patient stories
there's an faq
and then there's links to all the
articles um that i've been in so for
anyone who wants to really deep dive
into chs the information is all readily
available for them
that's excellent and you know that's a
great segue here um
in addition to that website are there
any other resources that you'd like to
share
with the audience um that i can kind of
put into the show description so they
can learn more about you or about chs or
anything they that you think would be
helpful yeah so my instagram account is
the alice moon th e alice moon
and the chs account is cannabinoid
hyperemesis
and so people can reach out to me on
either of those platform either of those
accounts or they can email me at alice
moon alicemoon.la
and i'm more than happy to talk to them
about chs
all right excellent i will definitely
put those into the show description
all right alice um thanks so much again
for joining us today and sharing your
story
and you know helping us get the word out
about chs
um i hope to see a lot more research
into this
condition and i hope to see some of that
research presented at
a futurecam at event thanks so much for
having me i really appreciate it it's
been lovely
all right talk to you soon thank you
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
alice moon please check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed
and thanks again to this episode sponsor
the american cannabis nurses association
our next episode will drop may 19th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out
canmedevents.com
for all the latest news surrounding
canmed2021
and while you're there be sure to sign
up for email alerts
the best place to do that is on our
podcast
webpage that's at
canmedevents.comcoffeetalk
if you complete the form on that page
you will be entered to win
two tickets to our vip dinner for
canmed2021
if social media is more your thing you
can keep up with us
on instagram facebook twitter
and linkedin just search for
canmedevents
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app
please do subscribe to our feed and also
leave us a five star review
okay until next time stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of cam ed coffee talk
[Music]
you