[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben
ameralt i'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team that puts on the canmed
conference
every year head over to
cannemedevents.com now to learn all
about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets today at
the special early bird rate
while you're at cammed events.com be
sure to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
okay this episode we have a few
announcements before i
introduce this episode's guest first
the cannabis center of excellence
medicinal genomics and the umass
dartmouth charlton college of business
recently announced the formulation of
the health care provider knowledge
attitudes practices related to medical
cannabis research
study the intention of this study is to
collect information from health care
providers
in both the united states and canada
about their experiences with medicinal
cannabis in their practices
prior education around the topic and
interest in future clinical
education related to medical cannabis
if you are a healthcare provider we
invite you to take part in this short
15-minute survey your personal
information will not be collected
and as part of the study one lucky
participant will win
a full conference plus medical practicum
pass
to canmed2021 check out the link in the
show description to go directly to the
survey
or visit canaacenterofexcellence.org
for more information second
we are encouraged to see that the local
southern california governments
announced last week
that coveted cases are an all-time low
and as a result
their widest reopenings are still on the
horizon
leading up to khmed 2021 this is great
news
and a sign that we are trending towards
normalcy
as always can med and medicinal genomics
will continue to monitor reopening
policies
with various state officials lastly if
you are a facebook user and you have not
yet joined our camed
community group you're missing out on
some great discussions
we have a little over 250 members in the
group who share
articles post polls and ask questions
related to cannabis science
medicine cultivation safety testing and
more
it's a great way for the community to
stay engaged throughout the year
and a great way to stay up to date with
news related to those topics
which brings me to today's guest dr greg
gerdeman
greg gerderman is a neuroscientist and
educator with experience in the
physiological actions of cannabis
and the endocannabinoid system recently
greg has gotten involved in the
conversation around delta 8 thc
which is how i met him coincidentally
enough we met through the canmed
community facebook group
i explained how that happened at the top
of the interview so i won't
retell that story here but the takeaway
is that you can meet some very
interesting people in that group
okay i'll stop plugging the facebook
group down and get back to greg
he comes at the delta eight thc topic
from a neuroscientist
perspective questioning how much we know
about delta 8 thc
and how it affects the body in the brain
he also raises important questions about
how the compound is created
and what that means for consumer safety
and the legality of delta 8
thc products in our conversation we
discussed
what exactly is delta 8 thc and how does
it differ from
other thc isomers why there is a sudden
influx of delta 8 thc products
how the 2018 farm bill opened the door
for delta 8 thc production
the process for creating delta athc from
cbd
isolate and the risks associated with it
whether delta 8 thc is a is actually
produced in the plant and at what levels
what research has been done to
understand how delta 8 thc
affects users and more before we get to
my conversation with greg
i want to thank this episode's sponsor
project cbd
project cbd is a california-based
non-profit
dedicated to providing up-to-date news
and information
on the science movement and industry
around cbd
medical cannabis and plant-based
medicine
since its founding in 2010 project cbd
has been a trusted resource
for patients medical professionals
scientists
and like-minded advocates learn more
about project cbd
at projectcbd.org
okay and without any further ado and i
apologize for the additional ado this
episode
i bring you my conversation with dr greg
gerdeman
[Music]
good morning greg thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast
hi ben thanks for having me all right
i'm really excited to talk with you
today
about a topic that's been popping up a
lot lately
in the news delta 8 thc
in fact martin lee our friend over at
project cbd
recently shared an article on our canmed
community facebook group
called the delta 8 thc controversy and
does a great job describing this
situation
and really this that article is going to
serve as a foundation for our
conversation today
i encourage people to check it out i'll
put a link in the show description so
people can read it
um greg you were quoted in that article
and coincidentally enough
i had a question about one of the
comments you made made
a comment on the post and you responded
to it right on the
canmed community facebook group so a
shameless plug for that group um if
people
people should definitely join that as
you can see you can
communicate with a lot of leaders in the
space and make some great connections so
again i'll put a link in the show
description for that but anyway i'll
stop
rambling and we'll get into that
question that i asked a little bit later
but i think we need to really
start with the basics here for people
who aren't familiar with delta h thc
and uh i'm going to pass that over to
you greg can you explain to us a bit
what it is and why is it in the news
lately sure
and it's especially in the news that is
is generated by and about the cannabis
industry so far but it is going to be in
broader news and that's something that
that everyone needs to take
serious because there are risks and and
and issues related to how this could
affect
health and the industry what is delta
thc
you know everyone is familiar with delta
9 thc
it's the workhorse psychoactive
component in cannabis and you know for
for
decades delta 9 thc was considered the
only active
principle because that was sort of the
state of affairs and you know back in
the 60s
when when delta 9 thc was isolated
it was found to replicate you know all
the important
sort of behavioral and psychological
effects of of hash oil
and um other cannabinoids were
discovered back then
including delta eight but were not
believed to have that kind of potency
so delta eight thc is an isomer of delta
nine it has
a very similar chemical structure to say
it's an isomer means it has the same
number of carbons and
other atoms but there's a difference in
one
bond between two carbons in the molecule
and the position of that
double bond is in these different deltas
delta nine has it in one place delta
eight has it next door
and there are other isomers delta six
delta seven delta ten
all it means is the placement of that
bond shifts which
is not a very impressive change just
looking at the molecule
but it does have some functional
differences
sort of maybe the next question is like
where is delta 8 coming from
it has long been known that delta 8 can
be seen
in analyzed extracts of cannabis flower
so it's it's there it's found
naturally it is also discovered way back
in the 60s
that that delta 9 and even
cbd could change to delta 8 thc
under certain chemical conditions
especially low ph
acid conditions so this has been known
for many years that
for example cbd can convert
to thc and that's really what's
happening right now
in the industry delta eight thc is being
lab synthesized this reaction to create
delta eight from cbd has been
developed in different labs and it's
being created from
cbd isolate as a starting product
is that making enough sense for how
we're going yeah that is making
sense um so now that we know kind of
what it is
why is it popping up so much in the
marketplace now
right it there's i look at two
uh watershed moments here that have
caused this delta eight
to pop up in the form of uh
at the consumer end in the form of gum
ease and other edibles
and vape cartridges people have
concentrated d8 that they're doing
in like dabbing um
where's it coming from well you know in
there was the uh farm bill the news
version of farmville that was written in
past to really help advance a legalized
hemp industry and of course we've got
this long
you know winding relationship with what
we call cannabis
and hemp is now legally defined
based on its thc content and it has to
be 0.3 percent
delta 9 thc or less and if it is it's
considered hemp
and under the 2018 farm bill hemp
is not a controlled substance well
that farm bill did several things one
thing is it opened a real
rush of interest into growing hemp
extracting hemp
creating cbd there was a rush for that
and it was overproduced it was overgrown
a lot of farmers got nowhere near the
return they hoped
a lot of extraction companies had far
more competition than they thought
there was a glut of cbd on the market
and the price of cbd
fell dramatically so you had a situation
where
folks investing and going into this hemp
extract cbd industry
suddenly you saw their margins shrinking
dramatically
because the price of cbd isolate was
falling so much
um well at the same time
the the farm bill when it said that hemp
is not a controlled substance
the language of that bill which many of
people have dug into
says that extracts and isomers and
derivatives thereof
extracts from extracts and derivatives
of legally defined hemp
are also considered hemp and therefore
unscheduled removed from the dea's
purview
although it also says that it
synthetically
synthetic cannabinoids synthetically
manufactured cannabinoids i forget what
the exact language was
was not made legal by this
this is where there's a lot of tension
but these two things to answer your
question these two factors converged
where the price of cbd fell like a stone
and there was a legal loophole that made
some
enterprising chemists realize hey cbd's
cheap now i'll buy hundreds of kilos of
it and we can
start working in the lab to
convert it to thc delta eight thc
which isn't delta nine so if we come up
with a delta eight product that is less
than point three percent delta 9
it'll be legal and it also does get you
high
and it has effects that have consumer
value and
so the price of cbd dropping and this
perceived legal loophole that says if
it's not delta 9 it's fair game
led to this chemistry it led to this
development
and it led to a return of really high
profit margins for people who were
pursuing this and that drove an
explosion of entry into the field there
are
dozens and dozens of labs that are
buying cheap cbd isolate
and making delta eight products and
because it is a huge regulatory vacuum
right now
these products are popping up everywhere
vape stores gas stations
hemp shops certainly online direct sales
etc well that's part of the issue too
right that
these products are popping up everywhere
from
any number of different manufacturers
not all of whom are probably
uh reputable or knowledgeable in what
they're doing and how
can the consumers sort of tell the
difference or at least protect
themselves
if like you said there is that
regulatory vacuum
i mean to me the real issue is it is
pretty much that um that be honest i
mean the the end consumer at a vape shop
or a store
another retail outlet they generally
have no idea i mean you can see
i've seen delta eight products with
really slick clean looking packaging
and branding um that is
very dirty you know and that there's my
concern and by dirty i mean
it's not i'm not out on a crusade
against delta 8 thc a molecule
there has been a very limited clinical
experience with it
but delta 8 thc was studied in the early
90s in a
small clinical trial for kids with
pediatric cancers and were undergoing
chemotherapy
and in this small study delta eight thc
was
very well tolerated and helped them
through the nausea
of their chemotherapy so there's a
potential therapeutic use
no surprise because delta nine and cbd
both have
good anti-nausea effects
but my concern is what else is in there
and you can go to a lab
you can send your product to a lab
testing you know company
and get a certificate of analysis a coa
that people in the field are very
familiar with
and and you can test it and see here
here are the cannabinoids that are
present
here are maybe terpenes if they're
looking at that
quality control issues like residual
solvents and pesticides and metals
you can test for that but a lab doesn't
test for i mean doesn't show you things
that they don't look for
and there are in these delta eight
products a variety of
molecules that you see if you're looking
at the raw data on these lab
analyses there are a number of
components in there
reaction products that are unknown
and um there's a concern
for for the risk of unknown molecules
unknown products so this this comes to
another real for me
crux of the of the issue that i think is
sort of an
existential moment in the hemp cannabis
industry about
that that how we relate to this balance
between
natural or created within the plant
and lab synthetic
call it semi-synthetic if you want this
is a touch point because the dea says if
it's synthetic it's not legal
in my view i'm not trying to make their
argument for them but in my view as a
biologist and chemist pharmacologist
if you have a starting product and an
ending product that are different if you
convert something into a different
molecule whether it's an isomer or not
it is a synthetic process
and as i said it's acid conditions that
are the
that form a big catalysis to this
cyclizing reaction that basically if you
look at the chemical structure of cbd
compared to thc you can see how there's
kind of a loop that's not closed
in cbd and when the molecule is under
reactive conditions though some of those
loose ends and the oxygens in the
molecule want
to form partners and the easiest
quickest thing
for that to happen is the loop closes on
itself
and cbd closes that ring
and becomes a tetrahydrocannabinol and
at that moment
where the ring closes wherever that
double bond is
it kind of gets stuck and and that's why
the same reaction that creates delta 8
thc
can't create delta 10 or delta 7 or
these other
isomers there's another subtlety that
gets a little more
for the chemistry sort of intelligentsia
but
there's there's uh
racemic or enantiomers that get formed
too the position of hydrogens like on
one side
left hand or right hand side of the ring
that flips around and changes too when
you've got cbd
converting to thc in this reaction and
my point here is that
although there are subtle differences
you get not only delta eight thc but
kind of like four different
varieties subtly different varieties of
delta eight
delta 9 popping up when you
create it under this laboratory
catalyzed chemical reaction
does that create in and of itself a big
safety concern
you know i'm not particularly that
scared of it i'm more scared of things
like
aggregates that happen if the reaction
is uncontrolled
where the cbd molecule doesn't just
close on itself it closes on its
neighbor for example
you get longer larger molecular weight
molecules
that's not cleaned up i would never ever
vape it it could be something that
sticks in your lungs
and and is unhealthy
um so that's others so that's what you
mean by
you know the labs not not finding what
they're not looking for
is that yes yeah because they are
looking at the metals and
all these other things that are sort of
you know commonly tested in the
in the cannabis space but since it's
going through this
um synthetic process that's not being
done
in cannabis they're they may be missing
things is that right
yeah yeah they may well be missing
things and there are labs doing this
that
that again i'm not trying to rag on the
really good
chemists that are trying to pioneer this
space but there are others that
don't even have the sophistication to
know what i'm talking about at this
moment
um and and that that concerns me
um you know these reactions a good
chemist will know or we'll find out as
soon as they start looking into this
that all of this should be done under a
stream of
nitrogen gas that's inert uh and and
helps
the sort of runaway oxidation reactions
from happening
but if you don't you're going to get
more side effects if you cook it too hot
you're going to get
these different aggregates forming and
some of that can be cleaned up with
filtration
but to really clean it up and get delta
eight as a
as a pure molecule you requires
expensive product development r d with
techniques of chromatography that is to
say separation of the molecules that are
in there
that are not cheap and a lot of this
industry is just
chasing huge profit margins and they
will cut those corners and they do
and it's it's something where the good
players really ought to be inviting some
level of regulation
you know and and even testing for metals
and pesticides and such
you know there aren't national standards
for you know
how those things are implemented and
this applies to the cbd industry at
large i've seen many cbd
products that seem to have laboratory
coa laboratory coas that are
you know bogus you know so and i think
that that's a problem in delta eight
big time um cannabis has long
had an issue of lab shopping right we
want our
or our cannabis to have a higher thc
content and this lab we know
favors it that product is super
magnified in delta eight
and part of the reason is the very
technical point i just raised that you
get
different sort of small flavors of thcs
formed
these different subtle enantiomer
differences because people who are used
to looking at this chemistry
when you're doing a lab analysis you
basically get a readout that looks like
peaks right on a chart and
those peaks on the chromatogram are
theoretically
you know individual molecules if you
separated them out cleanly enough
every molecule would have its own little
peak well
if you're trying to move quickly in a
lab and you run your react you you do
that separation in a fast time
then you don't get much separation
because of the way that synthetic delta
eight thc and i will refer to what's out
there as all synthetic because to me
that's what i think it is
but lab converted synthetic delta a thc
because it has these subtle differences
the the peak for delta 8 or delta 9
is going to be wider and more
less precise because there's actually
three or four different varieties that
are in there that move
subtly different well how do you know
how much delta 9 is there to find out if
you're still
legal you run it against a known lab
standard
that lab standard is going to have a
very sharp precise peak
what happens in a lot of these delta
eight products is even when they're
testing for delta nine
right where that lab that that standard
peak is that's nice and sharp
it looks like okay there's only point
three percent there
but labs can sort of conveniently ignore
that there's a lot that the peak is
broader there's more there
and for example
some good labs and i i refer now to dr
chris udall
at proverity labs
he he's insistent that he's tested
thousands of delta eight products that
are out there on car
on in commerce and that none of them are
under point three percent delta nine thc
because the delta nine in these products
are also
synthetically generated from the cbd
reaction
and you're underestimating how much
delta 9 is there
and in in practicality i've heard this
talked about because of my buddies that
are
that are making this or that are buying
delta a distillate and diluting it into
tinctures or putting it into gummies you
know
again i'm not in a crusade against these
friends and others like them who are
trying to make a good
you know business out of this but you
know i've been told by a friend in this
business oh man you know i had this
product and like one lad told me it was
point three percent and the other said
it was like
six percent so there's
there's another piece where like i'm not
scared of cannabis right i think
cannabis
should be regulated and legal i think
people should be able to grow it in
their backyard
and i think that we need to have mature
open marketplaces about this
but there do need to be regulations and
because of this mystique and gray area
and market rush with delta eight among
the
many issues i've got some problem with
is just truth in advertising
you know i've gone to shops where delta
eight gets sold as
you know it's it gives you the high of
thc but not the anxiety
it won't get you too high it's thc light
and again if you had pure delta athc
the a good bit of the evidence that's
out there from especially from animal
studies is that it's not as potent as
delta nine maybe three quarters maybe
two thirds is potent
although some studies have found it as
potent some from the early 70s
and and you hear user reports on that
but i've also heard many user reports of
people that thought oh delta 8 is
lighter and safer and have ended up
consuming way too much of it
even experienced pot users that go into
that anxiety hole
and i'm concerned about the users who
aren't familiar with it and yeah you
know i'm not a
run save the children sort of fear
monger but
teenagers shouldn't be able to buy this
at a gas station thinking like it's
something that's just going to take the
edge off and not get them high
well most of them know it's going to get
them high that's why they're doing it
right
right anyway i'm getting a little bit
loose with it while we yeah so i was
going to ask i mean
why the focus specifically on delta 8
thc
as you mentioned there are other isomers
of delta 10 delta 6.
why is delta 8 more desirable than those
others
i think delta eight it was just the
low-hanging fruit
um as far as how it's popped up
delta eight uh emerges and and maybe
we'll get to your question that we
that introduced us in a moment from what
i'm about to say
because even if you've got a cannabis
extract or a cbd a hemp
extract with high cbd and you're
distilling it down
to make say a cbd oil and enrich cbd oil
for a tincture
full spectrum product or to take it into
isolate
putting that cbd rich extract in a in a
distillation vessel
and cooking it down if that's run too
hot or too long you get delta 8
appearing
that isomerization does happen even
without artificially lowering
the ph as is being done now to make it
more effective
so delta eight and again and delta
eight's been known like i said there's
not a vast literature but
there were people doing some human
studies with it in the early 70s
there were people doing some animal
studies with it pharmacology
studies in the 70s and 80s there was
that one clinical trial i mentioned in
pediatric
patients for the control of nausea
associated with chemotherapy
and delta 8 does have psychoactivity
but you do have these other isomer i
mean i think it's critical to be talking
about it right now
because i mean i could put up a picture
of cbd with all of the different
products that can be formed with
fairly simple reaction conditions some
of them are called iso thcs
which definitely do not get formed in
the plant but do get formed when this
chemical reaction is
catalyzed in acid cooking it up an acid
delta 10 may even be easier to form
um this is one that you know there are
delta ten products out there right now
people are
calling that like the the next thing and
my question is why
like i have a phd in pharmacology
focused on cannabinoids
although i think it's safe to say very
few people
in the planet had a cannabinoid
pharmacology phd before i did i
this was from 2001 when i finished my
work i've never stopped studying the
subject pharmacology is the question of
how drugs interact with the body
and i don't know what delta 10 does it
really hasn't been studied
and there's a there's a sort of an
anecdote out there
that delta tens emerged into this
marketplace
if this emergence came just a couple
years ago because uh or catalyzed
because
a cannabis farm in california
was impacted by the wildfires and they
had a cannabis harvest a bunch of flower
that was sprayed down with flame
retardant
and for whatever reason and i'm not
going to
drop the name of this because i'm not
sure how true the story is
they started analyzing to see well can
we extract the retardant out
anyway this has been this is the problem
of the kind of thinking that goes on in
this unregulated market
not oh crap this is ruined it's got
chemical flame retardants all of it
well people have investments in this
it's their livelihood they're like well
there's a lot of chemistry going on now
can we try to just extract that out and
get rid of it and not if it doesn't
show up in the final product then we're
good right
well that what was in the final product
included a lot of delta 10.
they didn't know why but something about
that chemical flame retardant
pushed that reaction to occur um
so there's an opportunism straight up
and i'm not trying to be
judgmental in a bad way i mean drug
development follows opportunistic routes
too
uh it does the
one classic example that just pops to my
head is like rogaine
minoxidil that's used for for you know
male pattern baldness and stimulate hair
growth
that was a drug that was being tested
for cardio like uh blood pressure
control
and as a side effect it grew hair and
the drug developers
were like hey maybe let's put this into
a topical and see if it can grow
hair on bald men so opportunism isn't
bad
but in that controlled industry there's
a great deal of what's called
pharmacovigilance you have to follow up
and you have to show
that it's safe in the world of
pharmacovigilance
an example that pops up is vioxx
selective cox inhibitors that
were developed because they don't cause
gastric bleeds as much
but it turns out they caused cardiac
related fatalities
well those fatalities occurred at like 1
in 10
000 or something now it was taken off
the market for good reason
but that wasn't detected until a lot of
people were using it
unfortunately and if
the cannabis and hemp space is going to
go into
laboratory based synthesis
even if it's just a one chemical step
conversion
you do get reaction products that you're
not looking for
and it needs to have oversight and you
ask
a great question why focus on delta
eight well now because it's everywhere
and it's the
mo it's the molecule the moment and it's
not going to go away because it's got a
lot of use
but delta tens coming out other deltas
other
cannabinoid variants like thcv
which definitely is created in the plant
in some
genetic lines of the plant some
varieties of cannabis
create these so-called propyl
cannabinoids i'm fast
i'm very interested in those but you can
cook them up in the lab using
cbd as a starting point you can i know
kim i have
seen conversations between chemists who
are
working on their protocols to make the
cannabinoid thcp
from cbd as a starting material what is
thcp
that was only just discovered early last
year or reported by italian researchers
who described this new phytocannabinoid
and the only reason it was a big
splash is because it's supposedly 30
times more potent than delta 9 thc
there are chemists right now trying to
iron out their protocol
where if they can start with cbd isolate
that was hemp derived
and make it thcp in an efficient way
then they're going to go through the
same loophole and say it's hemp it's not
controlled
and that's obviously a race for profit
margins because it's not what the intent
of the law
is and i think we need to have mature
conversations about this
or there's going to be possibly toxicity
effects in the population public health
concern
possibly a massive flow back on the
industry that just turns this into
an enterprise controlled by big pharma
and if we're not talking very
transparent about how to move forward
in the industry regulated way then
there's going to be
potential for real problems so
how open really is this loophole
um you know is what folks are doing
converting
cbd to delta 8 thc
is that technically legal or are they
kind of playing with fire here and it's
only a matter of time before they get
cracked down on
well i will say that i'm not a lawyer
i will also say that i have seen
well-heeled and respected lawyers come
on
both come down on both sides of that um
in my view as a pharmacologist who has
studied this
quite closely i think that it's not
legal delta 8 thc
is explicitly listed as a schedule 1
substance
at this point in time it is also
una to me as a as a
as a scientist it is unequivocally a a
analog of delta 9 thc it's as
close to delta 9 thc as you can get and
because delta 9 thc is still schedule 1
the analog act of like 1985
in my view clearly includes delta eight
so i think
it's kind of a double dose of schedule
one illegal
the dea sees it that way the association
of food and drug officials
who writes model code for the fda seen
it that way
i believe the fda sees it as as illegal
again delta nine thc shouldn't be in
schedule one the whole schedule one
status has never ever been based in
science and
you know as we're moving towards
wrapping up this conversation i mean i
think it's important to point out that
all of this stems from the absurdity
of cannabis policy i am someone who
believes
that human beings have not only a
natural right to cannabis
but seeking the psychoactivity and
therapeutic
medicinal effects of cannabis is as
natural
a behavior as you can get the the
cultural social religious evolution of
human beings
has been wrapped up in a dance with the
selected you know cultivated evolution
of the cannabis plant
right it's a huge fun fascinating story
the long
cannabis human relationship it's as
natural as can be
to seek out the use of natural plant
cannabis
and the fact that it's prohibited
has never been based in science it's
been contrary to human
medical history and it's led to things
like super
high thc content and breeding it's
leading to
seeking avenues for that experience
whether it's therapeutic or for just for
the mental effects because you want it
that are are less natural and i have no
problem
saying that how delta eight and these
other isomers are being made
is less natural um
maybe we move forward where you know hey
cannabis is cannabis we'll call this
cannabis
but we need to have those discussions
and all this stems around having an
unhealthy over-regulated prohibited
status of cannabis
and that's
yeah i guess that's kind of a mic drop
moment because i'm not sure where
that's where i end up yeah well i did
want to ask you too
and and you mentioned that you know the
way that delta h thc
is being produced now is unnatural but
is there a potential for the plant to be
naturally
making delta eight thc and perhaps you
know breeders selecting for that or
um you know can create a more natural
product you know that's a that's a great
question i
and i've talked i talked to one friend
who's
again i won't name drop but he's been a
very very influential
um infamous cannabis breeder uh
in in the world and and has studied the
chemistry of extracts quite a lot
and he told me he didn't think delta 8
is real at all he thinks even the trace
amounts that's been found
is a artifact of dissolving the stuff
in order to put it in chemistry to
analyze it
i bounce that off of another friend who
is
very well known in in cannabis medicine
um who says that uh i mean
so this was ethan russo i will drop his
name because i don't think he would shy
away from this ethan thinks that delta a
can be made in the plant
that he has seen analysis of varieties
in europe that seem to reliably have
higher levels
and you know he's i pitch his name
because he is involved in a group called
breeder's best and he
they have interest in breeding for delta
eight um i have no
idea where i don't know how delta eight
occurs
in the plant um you know you asked me i
will give a shout out to the question
that
brought this conversation together
because you said you know
dr g like if if your definition of
synthesis is cbd is one thing and it
turns to delta eight that's another so
it's synthetic
what about the decarboxylation reaction
because the plant makes
cbd a dhca and when we heat it
it converts to the neutral form thc as
we know it
cbd as we know it it's a very astute
question these are different molecules
but in my mind the what we the
decarboxylation that happens the
activating that happens
is it certainly absolutely occurs in
nature
when the plant stays out in the field
and it's got uv radiation and heat
that decarboxylation happens so whether
it's made in an enzyme or not it's
clearly made with
happens in the trichome of the plant if
it's you know in the field long enough
to happen
i also see it as a thermodynamic
inevitability
cbd will always break down to cbd
given just enough time and warmth and
heat to
bump the reaction over you don't have to
get it
to hundreds of degrees and that's the
point where it's at equilibrium and it
all shifts over
but you know it all it all will move
over just like a bowl of water sitting
at
on a 70 degree day will all evaporate
even though it never hits its boiling
point
cbd a is all going to go to cbd
eventually
that said you know thc is eventually
going to break down
delta nine it's more uh
thermodynamically favorable to turn into
delta eight delta eight is more stable
i suspect that's how it's coming in the
plant is some fraction of delta nine
which degrades into cbn right
some of it will shift into delta eight
first
i'm so i'm skeptical that we can breed
for high delta eight
but i would love to see it i think high
delta eight flower would be fascinating
um and i again because i will
fall back on an argument for whole
plants because i think that the
chemical phenotypic diversity of the
cannabis
genus is just so utterly remarkable
that if people want a lighter high
then let's focus on breeding type 2
plants that have
under 10 percent thc and a nice balance
of cbd there's so much potential that i
think the industry should focus on
i think that the route of hey let's
let's chase good margins by taking just
bulk cbd and processing it in labs
it's giving some applied chemists work
and i'm not against that
but i think it tilts the agriculture
towards a monoculture
that is not creative that is not
celebrating the diversity of this plant
it also creates you know if you're going
to do it that way then why not just
work on making more and more greater
efficiency with
you know transgenic yeast to spit out
cannabinoids
which again is not a you know
i'm not criticizing that as some sort of
ignoble adventure i mean i've met really
smart
cool people who are trying to make
cannabinoids out of yeast
but if that's what we're doing is making
a molecule
i think that the diversity we're at a
point in history where the diversity
of cannabis can be explored far
greater than it ever has been before and
i want to see that happen i want to be
involved with ventures that support that
and there's going to be room for all of
it
the derivative stream of hemp is going
to include everything from graphene
batteries
and you know hemp crete to
cannabinoid molecules and that's going
to take
chemical processing it needs to be
something that's done transparently
that's regulated in a way that you know
clean potentially risky products
risky manufacturing let's not forget
that putting
reaction vessels at pressure with high
acid is a dangerous thing to work with
if there's no oversight then
somebody that bought cheap cbd isolate
can cook it up and risk themselves their
environment
and also a plug i never put in there but
just on the this question of like
what's in there all of the conversation
that we assume is that
you're starting with a very pure cbd
isolate
if your starting product is dirty in the
first place
then these unknown reaction products are
going to multiply
you don't know what's in there yeah
so delta 8 maybe there will be delta 8
plants in the future i
weight that and find a great interest in
it um
but maybe not i'm not sure yeah and you
make a great point
about um you know if you're looking for
a lighter high
why are there not more type 2 type
plants
or products available and i can just
speak personally from up here in
massachusetts
uh if you go to a recreational
dispensary
it's rare if you ever find anything
that's not
a straight type one plant and
you know you ask people why why is there
not more variety here and
you know they say that that's all the
growers want to grow um
and i think that there is just a there
could be a wider market for people to
have
a more balanced experience um
but uh it's probably just going to take
time
for people to realize that i think it's
going to take time it could happen
we could be on the cusp of that um but i
agree i've seen dispensaries
where i've you know found a really
lovely
you know like outdoor grown type 2
variety that i thought
man i could use this all day
you know and i'm not a heavy consumer
and and
i like that i think that there's great
future
in those for the sort of
wellness aspect and those who like the
experience but don't want to get
feel inebriated by it
i think there's huge future in it and if
that's what's driving the
but i think there's a lot of you know i
think a lot of what's driving the delta
8 market is a so-called legal high
i think it's one step away from sort of
the illicit
mentality of the spice sort of market
the only difference is potency
and for that reason i think that these
synthetic
pathways i see them as
not actually a legal loophole i've
advised multiple companies
yet you might i'm not a i'm not an
economist i'm not someone who chases a
fast profit
maybe you're going to get where the
getting is good
but i wouldn't invest a market strat a
business plan in delta 8 because
i think that that the justification for
it being currently illegal
is just too strong
because of the synthesis the synthesis
of a delta 9 analog
all right well i do want to be mindful
of your time i know i kept you over the
half hour a bit
before i do let you go i want to give
you the opportunity to
plug any websites or social media that
you're involved in that
people can connect with you gosh i'm i
i have several different things going on
and my instagram is
is at ganjanesh um
g-a-n-j-a-n-e-s-h if you plug that
and it's kind of personal stuff but i i
comment on the industry i'm at um i can
be found on facebook
i've got a few different ventures i mean
i have a a license for a medical
cannabis dispensary up in weirton west
virginia
called weir wellness that's
underdevelopment
i'm with a cbd hemp company called
tennessee pharmaceuticals with an ftn
pharmaceuticals.com also very new i'm in
transition
and i'm i'm really i'm getting involved
in an exciting venture that's relevant
to all this that i
can't even really talk about too much
yet but it involves
wanting to [__] to create a better
transparent open marketplace for hemp
and cannabis derivatives where there is
authentication of the chain of custody
and the various validations and
certifications that go on
because right now the world of
buying and selling these cannabis
derivatives like distillates or
biomass even um there's they're huge
trust issues
there are huge transparency issues and
i'm involved with a venture that
is going to try to help be a solution
for those uh to to have a greater open
market exchange so
that doesn't really give people a plug
to look for a specific site but maybe to
keep their eyes open or if that if
somebody's mind
pops when they hear that and thinks oh
my god that's exactly like my tech
company
then you know reach out and connect with
me
excellent i will put links into the show
description so uh people can easily find
that
um greg thanks again for for coming on
it's a great conversation i think we
could have talked for a few more hours
but
thank you we'll cut it off here and uh i
hope to see you out in canada this fall
all right take care
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
greg gerdeman
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor project
cbd
our next episode will drop june 2nd
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out
canmedevents.com
for all the latest news surrounding
canmed2021
and while you're there be sure to sign
up for email alerts
the best place to do that is on our
podcast
webpage that's at
canmedevents.comcoffeetalk
if you complete the form on that page
you will be entered to win
two tickets to our vip dinner for
canmed2021
if social media is more your thing you
can keep up with us
on instagram facebook twitter
and linkedin just search for canmed
events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app please do subscribe to our
feed
and also leave us a five star review
okay
until next time stay safe stay healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode
of cammed coffee talk
you