[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to
cannemedevents.com now to learn all
about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and be sure to get your tickets today at
the special early bird rate
while you're at cam at events dot com be
sure to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
okay this episode we have a few
announcements before i introduce
this episode's guest first i'm happy to
report we have officially launched our
canmed archive page
which includes over 100 canmed
presentation videos
dating back to our first event in 2016.
the canmed archive is a free searchable
video library covering a range of topics
related to cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
go to cammed events dot com and click
the banner on the home page to check it
out
second we have gotten a lot of great
feedback and coverage
on the healthcare provider knowledge
attitudes practices related to medical
cannabis research study
that we are doing along with the
cannabis center of excellence
medicinal genomics and the umass
dartmouth charlton
college of business the intention of
this study is to collect
information from health care providers
in both the united states
and canada about their experiences with
medicinal cannabis
and their practices prior education
around the topic
an interest in future clinical education
related to medical cannabis
if you are a health care provider we
hope you will take part in this short
15-minute survey
your personal information will not be
collected
as part of the study and one lucky
participant will win
a free full conference plus medical
practicum pass
to canmed2021 check out the link in the
show description to go
directly to the survey or visit
canadacenterofexcellence.org
for more information lastly if you are a
facebook user
and you have not yet joined our camed
community group
you're missing out on some great
discussions we have a little over 250
members in the group who share articles
post polls and ask questions related to
cannabis science
medicine cultivation safety testing and
more
it's a great way for the community to
stay engaged throughout the year
and a great way to stay up to date with
news related to those topics
use the link in the show description to
join or search for canmed community
on facebook okay and now i'd like to
introduce this episode's guest dr
michelle
shuffett michelle is an accomplished
healthcare executive
marketing strategist speaker and
wellness enthusiast with over
20 years of experience encompassing a
unique blend of clinical medicine
communications and leadership much of
her recent work has been in the cannabis
industry
highlighting the potential health
benefits of cannabis and cbd
she recently joined radical science as a
founding team member
and chief growth officer at its core
radical is a rebellion against the
status quo of health care and research
and a movement towards democratized
personalized
medicines that have the potential to
deliver well-being
for all future generations as you can
expect
with a description like that we talk a
lot about what radical is doing to
achieve those goals
we also discuss michelle's journey from
being a practicing physician to cannabis
researcher
challenges with traditional clinical
research
lack of reliable data on the
effectiveness of natural products
how radical science recruits
participants and collects data
and ongoing and upcoming studies radical
science is conducting
before we get to my conversation with
michelle i would like to thank this
episode's sponsor
cannabis patient care magazine cannabis
patient care magazine
is an educational resource for patients
medical professionals
caregivers and advocates on the latest
research benefits
and treatment options medical cannabis
provides
for a variety of illnesses visit
cannapatientcare.com
to learn more alright and without any
further ado
please enjoy my conversation with dr
michelle chuffet
[Music]
good afternoon michelle thanks so much
for joining us
you're very welcome ben i'm happy to be
here
all right you are turning clinical
research
the clinical research model on its head
and i love it
um i really wanna i wanna talk about um
what i mean by that but first i kinda
wanna take a step back
and talk about how you got here because
i know you began your career
as a practicing md so how do you kind of
go from being a practicing
md to where you are today like i said
kind of
reworking the clinical research model
it's a it's a little bit of a story for
sure ben
i am a physician by training i did
my medical school program at the
university of kentucky and my residency
at ucla
i i practiced a few years and i think i
honestly knew in my heart
that i ultimately didn't want to
practice
and it was a bit of soul-searching to
figure out
how to apply medicine which i happen to
love
into something that that fit me better
as a
as a human overall and i i sort of
jokingly refer to myself now
as a as an md gone rogue um
after i stop yeah rogues you know i
i do work for a company called radical
science now so
um it it suits me well i
i left practice i did some consulting in
the entertainment industry
and you know my experience over the last
20 plus years or so has has really been
a blend of clinical medicine
marketing strategy education and
speaking
across a variety of healthcare
industries i
i started out in pharma and
did a lot of work there in the copd
space
and ultimately transitioned into medical
education
healthcare advertising and you know for
me that was a great opportunity to learn
more about how to deliver information
and really understand what clinicians
were searching for
in order to better understand something
to better take care of their patients
i i moved on from there because
i thought it was really important to
explore digital
and i worked for a digital health
marketing and publishing
company and that really introduced me to
the world of
wellness as opposed to illness and
after after spending some time there
that was sort of
an eye-opening experience for me that
it really inspired me and filled me with
passion to to do things
there that were focused on integrative
practices
and wellness and ultimately
when i left there i i took a little time
to myself
and i played around a bit with a digital
fitness and wellness platform and
ultimately stumbled across the cannabis
industry
and i say stumbled because it was
actually a really serendipitous
experience i was
i was at a cocktail party
and chatting with some folks and this
this one woman in particular
was asking me a lot of questions about
my background and the work i'd done as a
liaison and an educator and a speaker
and
i i couldn't quite figure out why she
was asking me all these questions
because to my knowledge there wasn't
particularly anyone coming to this event
that
was involved in that space and you know
long story short
at the at the end of it she's she
suggested to me that i meet her husband
because she said that i needed to work
for him
that's uh that's how i ultimately got
involved
at columbia care first as a consultant
and then moved on to become their vp of
scientific research and communications
and currently i still consult for them
as well but
that experience really really shaped a
lot of things for me
and you talked about turning research up
up on its head and
you know working with with columbia care
and their chief
scientific officer dr rosemary massenay
one of the things i learned is how hard
it
is to actually accomplish research
in the cannabis space i i see you
nodding your head and i'm sure you
you understand and have heard many many
times that
there's so much bureaucracy politics is
involved of course
and and a lot of the rules are quite
archaic
and that's so contradictory to what's
actually happening in the real world you
know we know that
we know that consumers are are taking in
natural products
at increasing rates and
the shocking part is they're doing this
without any
real solid evidence in a lot of cases
so i i got it i got more and more
interested in
trying to understand why that was
happening
most of the questions and my speaking
engagements from
from folks in the audience and also from
healthcare practitioners
because let's be honest they were never
trained on the endocannabinoid system
for the most part a lot of those
questions were
what is it how does it work how do i
know how much to take
whether it be medical cannabis or a cbd
containing product
so that was a really great opportunity
for me
to explore that that area
and over the course of the time i got to
work in a couple of other
fabulous platforms and consult for them
to help
communities understand natural medicines
and things of that nature
and then and then i think serendipity
happened again
i was looking at a website
for the holistic research and education
foundation
which our co-founder palin thoroughgood
started
and i saw a photo of a friend of mine
that i did residency with
and she's a pediatric endocrinologist
so i i did a little screenshot of her
photo on the advisory board and i
i sent it to her and i'm like what what
on earth when did you start
looking into cannabis research and
things of that nature and
you know it turns out that she lives um
lives near palin and they
they've known each other for years and
she was advising
as a board member in the insurance space
which is something that she's doing now
so
she connected me to palin and we had a
great conversation
and haley and jeff the other co-founder
jeff chen shared some ideas with me
about
what they wanted to do with radical
science and
it it hit all the right buttons and it
got me really excited and very
passionate
about being part of a company that
the entire mission is around uncovering
the data
around these natural medicines and
really empowering consumers and also
creating a source of data and insights
for a variety of stakeholders so
i think um all those things have finally
come together in a in a beautiful way
well it's it's quite the journey and it
is a journey
and it stood out to me that it you've
started sort of in the pharmaceutical
industry
and now you're in cannabis which i mean
a lot of people would probably consider
opposite ends of the spectrum and then
another thing
that you you brought up was sort of this
whole idea of wellness versus illness
and i wonder
is there a connection there you know is
pharma more sort of
concerned with the illness in you know
cannabis and natural medicines more with
the
with the wellness i think you are
you are spot on um it it is a very
it's two sides of the same coin in some
ways and
i think that the pharmaceutical industry
is
you know is very necessary western
medicine is very important in many many
cases and
we've all used it to our advantage to
help us
over our lifetimes in many cases and and
i don't think
any of us would trade that for anything
the way it comes about is to solve
problems to figure out how to
address a particular illness
specifically
traditionally speaking i'm generalizing
but i think it's a i think it's a fair
generalization
and when you think about natural
medicines they've always been much more
geared towards achieving balance
and promoting wellness and optimizing
health
and that's been happening for for
centuries
they're also used to to manage illnesses
as well
and i think the the crux of radicals
is built on this idea of what if you
could use
a natural product some people quite
frankly just prefer
a natural product what if he could use
it
and be confident that it's been tested
that we understand how it works
and we understand how to use it and that
you could trust it in the same way that
you would trust a pharmaceutical product
so we're we're certainly not not
out to to squash any of the work that
the pharmaceutical industry
has done what we're trying to do is
create a path and a way forward for
natural products
yeah absolutely it's it's not a zero-sum
game there's
um there's room for both absolutely
absolutely
and it's you know it's coincidental that
you bring up this whole idea of
providing consumers with some sort of
way to
to trust that a certain product is going
to work and that it's been studied
i was just reading an article about a a
probiotic that's supposed to help with
athletic performance
specifically with endurance and i'm
training for
road races and things that are
eventually coming back online and
i was curious in that and i was sort of
trying to find information on
this type of product and wasn't really
able to find very much of
anything so i think that's a good segue
into
what you folks are doing at radical
science to try to
um get that data and talk a bit about
what your approach is for sort of
collecting data around these products
sure
sure so um you know fundamentally
speaking radical radical science is all
about
validating natural medicines for the
first time
and it's it was born out of the idea
that there has to be a better way
so our goal is to create
a movement and that movement would be
going towards
a democratized personal medicine system
where
where we have the potential to to share
information
and deliver well-being if you will to
everyone
and we we do that by disrupting
the traditional approach to to clinical
trials so
a you you can kind of think of us in in
some ways as
a a hybrid of a lot of things we we have
the reach
of a market research company but we
combine that with rigor um it's
it's of utmost important to us
importance to us that everything we do
is grounded in science and is incredibly
rigorous so you can compare that to
perhaps a research university and then
last but not least we're a health tech
company
so we also incorporate agility
into our approach and what we're doing
is studying natural medicines
in a similar fashion to the way that
pharmaceutical
products are studied so we have a
great group of advisors and scientific
experts combined with
the knowledge that our co-founders have
accumulated
over the past few years so um our
co-founders are
are jeff chen and palin thoroughgood and
they
you know built this company around all
of these ideas
after getting really frustrated
with the current model in their
respective
areas so um jeff i think you might you
might
know and have met a few times before but
he started up the ucla cannabis research
institute
and stumbled up against all those
challenges that we talked about before
with bureaucracy
and being able to do something in a
timely fashion a cost-effective fashion
things of that nature palin started
a foundation called the holistic
research and education foundation
and she's raising money basically to
help fund
these research projects and again
kept coming up against all these blocks
that
that made it much more difficult than it
needed to be so
the two of them came together and came
up with
an approach with the goal of reducing
the cost and time of research
while still providing rigorous health
data
so if that probiotic you mentioned
if we um if we were working with that
company
and and able to study it we would be
able to
provide potentially real world evidence
that would help you
understand as a man of your age
with your goals what might be the right
dose to help you what might be the right
time of day to take it
other areas that it might improve your
overall well-being
it would all depend on on how that
particular study was designed but we
would be able to provide that
information for you
so that's interesting you'd be able to
kind of provide
almost some personalized information
based off of demographics
absolutely and you know the personalized
aspect of it i think is something that
that we're very excited about as well
because the the
individuals that participate in our
studies
they're just as important as a customer
as as the folks that are the brands or
the customers that are paying for the
studies
and we want to make sure that they're
provided with value
because they're providing the research
community with value
so every participant in our studies gets
their own
data back in a personalized insights
report
so it will help them understand how
their
data looks amongst the the aggregate or
the cohort
in that study so they get a sense of oh
wow
you know the folks that that were taking
and i'm obviously making up an example
here but
the folks that were taking 25 milligrams
of cbd
had the best improvements in a sleep
score
i've only been taking 15. maybe i should
talk with my healthcare provider or
maybe i'm going to make the choice
myself
to try a product with a higher dose and
see if that actually helps me sleep a
bit better
so we're trying to to leverage that
power
in numbers and and share some true
insights back with these individuals
yeah so you say that the the individuals
are very important and
it definitely sounds like they are so
how do you recruit the individuals to
participate in these studies
a couple of different ways um you know
our model is
definitely direct to consumer from from
the perspective of
what we're doing in these virtual
clinical trials and
if um if you'd asked me prior to 2020
how how i felt about that concept
i i might say that it could be really
challenging because
there's a lot of different things to
wonder if people will actually
follow through with and and i think
covid
and the pandemic really showed us that
that consumers are very willing and able
to do things virtually
and it really helped prove out that that
model for us
and when we recruit participants for our
studies there's a couple of different
ways
we can approach it part of it is based
on the trial
design part of it is based on
what our brand is actually able to do
you know some brands are better set up
than than others from a customer list
perspective or recruitment perspective
so you know
we bring in our participants through
either working with a brand
and leveraging whatever list they might
have from their existing
customers if we want new participants
people who haven't tried a product
before we
can leverage a consumer research network
that we work with to get new
participants
and you know ultimately we we truly hope
that we we create a network effect and
the general public will start to know
about radical and and know about what
we're doing and
they're going to want to sign up and
really want to participate
to help generate data and grow this body
of evidence
not only for the community as a whole
but
but also for their own personal
information and learn about themselves
yeah i mean i think that last group
[Music]
is a really interesting one i think that
there's definitely a lot of people out
there who would be
very interested to try these new
products and and get a personalized
report
um based on that so is there any way
that people can
you know sort of sign up for to know
about what studies are coming up and
maybe
you know take part absolutely
so we um we have our website up and
running and there's a couple of
different places
within the website that you can sign up
to be alerted about
future opportunities the website is
radicalscience.com and radical is
spelled
r-a-d-i-c-l-e so it's a
a little bit of a play on words um the
radical is the first part
of a plant root that emerges so it's
it's the seed of the idea
so we intentionally
created a created that play on words
because
it aligns with the concept of natural
medicines
and plant science and plant medicine but
also the fact that
the idea in what we're doing is is a bit
disruptive
yeah for sure i like that um
and you you mentioned that there are
different types of studies that you can
do
um does that include sort of like open
label or double-blind placebo-controlled
is that what you meant in
in some ways yes what we're doing right
now
are a couple of different study types
one of which is real world evidence so
we
know that particularly in the cbd area
that the fda has really been
asking for real world evidence
from from manufacturers from from
different brands
because there aren't any randomized
controlled trials
so real world evidence is is an
observational
approach if you will we also can do some
studies that
we call discovery studies that will
allow brands
a safe environment to look at different
formulations look at different products
and try to figure out which one is most
effective
and in what combination so if you can
imagine
think about all the cbd products out
there a lot of folks are combining in
other other apis active pharmaceutical
ingredients and
maybe maybe you're just not quite sure
does that need to be in a two-to-one
ratio a one-to-one ratio
something else altogether full spectrum
versus broad spectrum lots of
lots of different types of formulations
and combinations
and if you want to bring one to market
you want to be able to test it
understand
which one is most effective and save
yourself the time and effort of putting
something out there that
that may or may not work so we can help
in that way
and then last but not least and this
goes back to the idea of validation
is we can do those placebo-controlled
trials which will
validate the natural product and
actually allow
folks to be able to make structure
function claims
which is something that's really
important and
not done often in this area excellent
and are the results from these studies
made public absolutely
one of uh one of our core values is is
transparency
and we make sure that
the studies that we do particularly
those validation studies and such are
going to be
published um the real world evidence
studies most of those
will result in aggregate data
publications
but uh we're working on a really
interesting
multi-brand cbd study right now that
will launch
in june which will be um published in a
peer-reviewed journal
and you know we're going through all the
all the things we need to do to make
sure that happens and abiding by
all the regulations clinicaltrials.gov
irb submissions all the check boxes if
you will
you have to uh to fill in order to get
something into a peer-reviewed journal
yeah that's excellent
um and i was going to ask you about that
uh particularly clinicaltrials.gov
i i spoke with deb kimlis on a previous
podcast in her groups working on a
clinical trial on a cbd tablet for
chronic pain
that we um we discussed and and at the
end we were talking about you know
um what are some ways that consumers
can uh i don't know look for red flags
or
have a way to kind of validate some of
the claims that some manufacturers
make and one of her suggestions was to
check clinicaltrials.gov to look for the
real
robust clinical trials so i'm glad to
see you guys are on there not that i
doubted it but um
i'm glad to see that that um that advice
is
is sound absolutely um
you know the the consumer is is in a bit
of a
double quandary in my opinion because
they're trying to figure it out
and unlike other areas
there aren't necessarily as many
clinicians as you might imagine that are
familiar with
with cbd and natural products so there's
a lot of self-learning
and a lot of sorting through very
complex things
um you know when when you see something
on a website that says clinically proven
you you often take that for face value
and unless you dig
in and actually look to see what really
happened
you you don't know if that's a valid
statement or not
and our goal as an organization is to
ensure that if if someone hears that
that radical studied a product that you
know that that was done
with the highest level of rigor we have
a compliance
process that we ask brands to go through
where we we have a minimal set of
standards that were established by one
of our
collaborative partners clean label
project in order to make sure that
they're doing all the right things
from a manufacturing perspective and a
labeling perspective excellent
um i was wondering if you could talk a
bit about what studies you've done to
date
and or what other ones you have planned
i know that you've recently
announced a sleep study that launched in
april
um i wonder if you could speak a bit to
that and in other studies that you have
going on sure sure so um
radical is uh is fairly new the company
uh
kicked off last fall and you know we're
really excited
about the fact that we have uh a good
bit of
data getting ready to to come out um
one of the i think first things will be
released uh the first week or two of
june we worked with
a cpg brand to compare eight different
cbd formulations
head to head and over one thousand women
so we feel that's even more important
because women's health is often
overlooked when it comes to research
and this information helped the brand
determine which product to bring to
market
and we're releasing a white paper with
details of that analysis
in june we've also been working
with two different cbd brands on
real world evidence studies and we've
been really
working with them to help them
understand their existing
customer base so this is one of the
cases where
they targeted their existing customers
to understand how they were using the
products and
and what experiences they were having
and and their perceived health outcomes
and then we also have the study that i
mentioned earlier the multi-brand study
which will be kicking off in june and
we're really excited about it
it's called aces radical aces
advancing cbd education and science and
it's the first multi-brand observational
study on cbd efficacy
that covers anxiety sleep pain and
general well-being
and to our knowledge it's the the
largest and most comprehensive
longitudinal study
ever conducted to examine the the
efficacy
if you will of hemp drive cbd products
and
you know we're really excited to say
that um we have
as of today i think we're up to 14
brands that are participating
many of which are quite familiar and
i believe uh i believe you could
the top three brands in the us are
participating in the study so
we'll be able to share their names once
we announce the kickoff of the study
a couple other things that are going on
right now are
the sleep study you mentioned which
launched in
april and you know that was a really
great partnership because the brand is
is truly passionate about research and
science
they really want to understand how their
product is
is helping their customers and you know
they were able to partner with a variety
of
different other sleep related products
to raise awareness about the
availability of the study
and get folks involved and you know
they're they're essentially looking at
different
validated sleep indices over the course
of a 30-day
study period and we had
ultimately about 200 participants um the
study's still ongoing so
i can't tell you exactly how many are
going to end up completing
but the the original goal was to get 200
completers
and i believe um last patient out will
be
middle of june so there will be data
coming out from that study a couple of
weeks after that and
as a real world evidence study the brand
is committed to sharing the findings
and radical will take their lead on on
sharing the findings
as well so you know there'll be some
interesting stuff
to help us understand why they're using
cbd you know what's their their primary
motivation
what are they consuming when are they
using it and
and and how are they actually how are
they actually experiencing it
and what do they think about it so we're
pretty excited about that as well
yeah and we i don't think we talked
about it earlier but
um i believe when i was looking at your
website
that the way that the participants get
the data to you
it's through a an app on their mobile
phone correct
it's through a website interface okay um
we're reaching out to
we're reaching out to the uh the
participants in the studies
either via email or
text alerts so when you when you sign up
part of the study process
is choosing how you'd like to be
communicated with so we're working
through both options
um the the study platform itself
is uh is part of our proprietary
approach
and we are learning new things every day
and evolving it to make it to make it
better with each study we
we kick off yeah because i was curious
especially with
with a study about sleep that i know
that
you know certain wearable devices that
are pretty popular like
apple watch um fitbit and others they
have
sort of a sleep tracking capability and
i was curious if
any of that data would be valuable to a
study looking at cbd and sleep
that would absolutely be valuable um
this particular study doesn't include it
but that is uh definitely on our list
for the future to make sure that we
incorporate other technologies and other
potential
data gathering collaborations in order
to build that body of evidence because
the the more information you get
and the more you can connect and
correlate
you know what someone is saying and how
they're answering
those questions with actual
data from from one of those devices that
that tracks is going to be really
interesting
yeah cause i imagine that is a bit of a
a challenge with with some of these
studies as it's
um you know self-reported data right
it is yes um the questionnaires we use
are validated questionnaires though and
they're the same questionnaires that are
used
in in standard standard clinical trials
so uh when when we start to release
the insights in the data and we talk
about certain indices
and certain questionnaires it's the same
thing being used by academic researchers
so uh we think they'll get pretty
excited about it it's not
um it's it's not just a how are you
today
kind of kind of a question sure sure um
so winding down here um i did want to
you know touch on a couple
relevant news topics that came out that
i was curious how that might affect what
you're doing there at radical
uh the first being that cbd is
the fda is talking about you know
approving it as a food supplement
um how will that sort of um
affect what you guys are doing there at
radical
well i think it's i think it's super
exciting um i mean we touched on this a
little bit
earlier you know see cbd is such a
regulatory conundrum for lack of a
better word
um the farm bill makes hemp drive cpd
legal yet the fact that
the molecule itself is an approved drug
epidialex from gw means that
it's technically not a food supplement
so it's uh it's this very
very confusing gray area and getting it
approved or
getting it named as a food supplement if
you will is
is i think a great thing it's going to
introduce
a regulatory framework it's going to
structure and what we're doing now
sets sets the stage for that so i
i firmly believe that a lot of the
information we're providing is
ultimately going to be required
information
once uh once cbd is designated a food
supplement
yeah and how would that be different
from other um supplement
well other supplements or other natural
products um
are they sort of operating in that gray
area as well
well they're not because if they're
deemed
a supplement there's a very specific
rules and regulations
whether it be manufacturing claims data
things like that that they're subject
to whereas cbd itself right now is
is not subject to those since it's not a
food supplement
got it got it and the other
news item is this expansion of
is essentially expanding the
types of organizations that can do
research into cannabis
um i imagine that's going to open up a
whole number of possibilities
uh for different trials no absolutely
um you know this one i'm i'm actually
super excited about
given given my work at columbiacare
previously um
it's it's been it's basically been a
monopoly
up until this point so you know since
the late 60s
there's only been one dea approved
source
of cannabis and and when i say cannabis
in this sense i'm referring to
thc containing cannabis hot products if
you will
and you know that that product came from
the university of mississippi
and you know the product that
that was being provided most researchers
and most healthcare practitioners
felt that it wasn't representative of
what's actually available in the market
now
and a lot of folks have been
really leading the charge and pushing to
to get
these these research i'm going to use
the word licensed
licenses um open up
so that they're able to provide
medical cannabis products or cannabis
products for these research studies such
that there's more diversity in
what you can use in the studies and
that the products are actually more
aligned with
with what folks use on a day-to-day
basis
a lot of it has to do with like the
percentage of of thc
in the cannabis that was available for
research versus
the percentage that that folks are
buying
when they go to a dispensary and get
medical
cannabis so it's uh it's it's really
the first chance to use real world
cannabis
in studies and and provide opportunities
for
for more scientists and more researchers
to be able to actually do it
um you know sue sisley in arizona has
been
leading this charge for years and has
very successfully
i believe received one of these licenses
so it's pretty exciting to
to hear that amongst a few other other
folks i don't think they've released the
full list this news is hot off the
presses i believe it came out about a
week or so ago so it'll be
it'll be great to see the the full list
and understand when these changes can
start to be implemented
and you know for us um not being part of
an academic institution at radical
where we haven't been held to the same
types of
rules that that academic institutions
might be held to
but opening it up in general
all tides rise it will make the process
a bit easier for everyone we haven't
started
doing cannabis studies yet but we will
be uh doing those later this year
yeah that's excellent and i agree with
you that you know the more
sites that we have exploring cannabis
and
kind of wading through or breaking down
some of the restrictions that have been
put on this
then it's it's great for everyone and
especially as the can med because we
love to showcase all the great work that
that everyone's doing in the space so
winding down here i did want to give you
an opportunity before i let you go
to um plug any websites or social media
that
you'd like to make people aware of that
they can connect with you or stay up to
date with anything that radicals doing
yeah thank you very much for that
opportunity um
you know we we have uh our website up
and running
radical science.com r-a-d-i-c-l-e
s-c-i-e-n-c-e radical science
and we also have a bit of a presence on
linkedin
we'll expand into social channels later
this year as we start to
uh have data and insights to share but
the
the best way to know what we're doing is
to go to the website and
and fill out a form on the contact us
page or sign up for
our newsletters which will start going
out
in the next month
excellent um well thanks again michelle
for
for coming on and talking about uh all
the work that you're doing and all the
research that's going into cbd and
natural products um
we could have talked for a few more
hours uh i didn't even get to all my
questions but uh
i know you're busy and i'll let you go
and hopefully
i get to see you out at canmed this fall
absolutely hopefully we will uh submit
some
data for you and we can share some of
that information
with uh with your audience uh
we could make that happen all right
we'll talk more we'll talk more
all right thanks again thank you have a
good one
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr michelle shuffett
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor cannabis
patient care magazine
our next episode will drop june 23rd
that's two weeks from today in the
meantime
please do check out canmedevents.com
for all the latest news surrounding
canmed2021
and while you're there be sure to sign
up for email alerts
the best place to do that is on our
podcast
webpage that's at
canmedevents.comcoffeetalk
if you complete the form on that page
you will be entered to win
two tickets to our vip dinner for
canmed2021
if social media is more your thing you
can keep up with us
on instagram facebook twitter
and linkedin just search for canmed
events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app
please do subscribe to our feed and also
leave us a five star review
okay until next time stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of chem-ed coffee talk
[Music]
you