[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to
cannemedevents.com now to learn all
about our canmed 2021 event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
okay we have some pretty big
announcements to make this episode
the first is that the early bird
deadline for canmed 2021 tickets
is coming up fast be sure to register by
july
7th to save 300 on your full conference
pass
second we are excited to announce that
medicinal genomics will be featured
in an upcoming television series called
high
science a production created to
highlight various facets of the cannabis
industry
and the struggles in its quest for
legalization
the series will be produced by an
acclaimed team of seasoned television
executives
including david mckillip the former gm
of a e responsible for multi-emmy
award-winning documentaries
including the 20 minutes that changed
america
and gettysburg along with other notable
television
productions mgc scientists will dive
into cannabis genetics
safety testing regulation challenges and
much more
you'll also get an in-depth look into
canmed 2021
one of the industry's leading cannabis
science conferences
as film crews tape behind the scenes and
during the conference
interviewing speakers sponsors and those
who make it happen
to learn more about this partnership
check out the blog on canmedevents.com
in other news we have officially
launched our canmed archive page
which includes over 100 canmed
presentation videos
dating back to our first event in 2016.
the canmed archive is a free searchable
video library covering a range of topics
related to cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
go to kmedevents.com and click the
banner on the home page to check it out
i also want to remind everyone that the
healthcare provider study
we are doing with the cannabis center of
excellence is still ongoing
if you are a health care provider please
take a few minutes to complete the
survey
to help us better understand medical
cannabis knowledge
attitudes and practices among health
care providers in the u.s and canada
as an added incentive one lucky
participant
will win a k med 2021 practicum
and full conference ticket the link to
access that survey
is in the show description okay
our guest this episode is emissions and
air pollution expert william veswete
dr versuete works as the chief
scientific officer
for buyer's scientific where he analyzes
cannabis and hemp
plant emissions and helps to develop
state-of-the-art order
and emission mitigation solutions and
equipment
for the past six years dr versuete has
led a team of cannabis industry
experts focused on site-specific
research
to increase the overall knowledge of
cannabis industry emissions
educate local communities and improve
the tools and methods that cultivators
and policy makers use to evaluate
the environmental impacts of cannabis
cultivation
and processing dr versuete is perhaps
best known for his groundbreaking
research
into cannabis emissions and air quality
in denver colorado
during that study dr versuete began
creating a first of its kind
cannabis terpene library dr versuete
will participate in the expert panel
titled the hidden cost of cannabis the
environmental impact
at cam mid-2021 topics we discuss
in our conversation include how
emissions from cannabis and hemp plants
affect air quality
and ozone the difference between vocs
and a vocs how the type
and concentration of emissions from
cannabis plants can vary widely
from strain to strain why cannabis
cultivators should be concerned with
controlling odors from their facilities
whether terpenes emitted from cannabis
plants can taint
neighboring wine grapes and strategies
cultivators can use to mitigate odors
and emissions
from their facilities
before we get to my conversation with dr
versuete
i would like to thank this episode
sponsor 10 buds
a site dedicated to all things cannabis
with a special focus on growing and
cultivation
10 buds is packed with fascinating and
informative articles
resources and reviews cannabis growers
enthusiasts and industry professionals
alike can explore
in-depth looks at everything from
considerations for cannabis
business owners to the evolution of
marijuana's place in society
its health benefits and so much more
visit
10buds.com to learn more
and without any further ado please enjoy
my conversation
with dr william the sweater
good afternoon will thanks so much for
joining us
thanks happy to be here okay you are
participating in a panel discussion that
came at 2021
that's all about understanding the
environmental impacts of cannabis
and hemp cultivation and i know you are
an expert specifically in the area of
emissions and
air pollution so maybe we can start the
conversation with you
explaining how cannabis and hemp
cultivation can impact
air quality that's a great question and
i think
it might be really helpful if we kind of
start with a little bit of some
definitions of names and a lot of names
being thrown around and
we're going to be doing somewhat
technical terms so
let's talk about emissions from these
plants and a lot of folks kind of talk
about terpenes i know that's a word
that's used quite a bit or vocs there's
another word that's used quite a bit
so let's just find what define what that
is so a voc is a volatile
organic compound so that's an organic
molecule so carbons and hydrogens
that at room temperature would rather be
in the gas phase so that's what we call
them volatile organic compounds
and volatile organic compounds include
lots and lots of kind of organic
molecules
and one important organic molecule is
called isoprene
now isoprene is emitted by every living
thing on the planet
you and i right now are emitting
isoprene out of our breath
and so is plants right and we've known
that for
quite a while now if you take that
isoprene and you put
two isoprenes together as a building
block what you end up with is what we
call
monoterpenes which is a class of
thousands of molecules including alpha
pinene
d limonene some of these things maybe
your listeners are familiar with
if you put three isoprene molecules
together you have something we call
sesquiterpenes right and so people like
to talk about terpene but when we talk
about terpenes there's actually
two large classes of terpenes one's
called monoterpenes and others called
susquaterpenes
and isoprene which is a building block
for those those things
now all these vocs that come from plants
we call biogenic vocs or biogenic
volatile organic compounds
the ones that are made from humans that
usually come from gasoline or things
like that
we call anthropogenic volatile organic
compounds
and now we know in the air quality field
where i come from
all these vocs whether they're from
plants or from people
can participate in chemistry in the
atmosphere and form both ozone
and particulate matter or aerosols and
so
understanding how these vocs come from
these plants
is just as important as understanding
where these vocs are coming from people
otherwise we won't get a full picture of
our air quality as being impacted in the
atmosphere and so that's how
i came about looking at these emissions
of these terpenes and their impact on
air quality
excellent and i know that you um you
published a pretty
notable study analyzing the
air quality in denver specifically with
relation to
cannabis cultivation i was wondering if
you could kind of explain the results of
that
yeah sure so um you know like i was
saying before we've known for a long
time scientifically there's a connection
between
these vocs monoterpenes sesquiterpenes
and isoprene
and the formation of air pollution in
the atmosphere now i should note that
you know these
molecules by themselves are not toxic to
humans
in fact most of these things have that
you know nice smells and things and
we've
come to become accustomed and like these
sorts of
molecules and so being exposed to high
levels of these terpenes
is is not harmful to human health
however when you have
combustion sources that are with these
vocs in the presence of sunlight
they can form ozone and particulate
matter
now it actually depends um how much
existing vocs are already in the
atmosphere to see how much that really
has an impact
and in denver colorado denver happens to
be high desert
and there happens not to be a lot of
biogenic or
vocs that come from plants due to its
um its you know its high altitude
and so you have a city that has lots of
combustion sources
which are the cars right uh from a large
metropolitan city
um but is starved if it only had more of
these vocs it could produce more ozone
now the other issue with denver is that
the city of denver
is in near what we call a non-attainment
or
is in violation of the federal standard
for ambient ozone
so any little bit of ozone contribution
is going to push them
in the wrong direction now that's unique
about denver
is that it needs those vocs but the
state of colorado has also made
cannabis production under secure
premises which has forced a lot of
cannabis production
indoors and mostly in warehouses and
warehouses are usually located
right near major transportation hubs and
so
if i wanted to create more ozone in a
place that was starved
for vocs i would place those vocs
as close to the transportation centers
as i could and that's effectively what
has happened
and so i saw this and i thought well
we need to figure out whether it's large
enough that it could have an impact on
the regional air quality because that's
really what
the question is now if i wanted to do
this for say automobiles or new power
plant or a new gas station
i could go to the epa scientists and
literature and look up what
you know the emissions would be from
burning so many tons of coal or
for burning so much fuel or for
decreasing an engine
and i could look up how much emissions
would go into the atmosphere
and then we have existing tools that
both the state of colorado and the epa
run that could predict
its impact on air quality and so when i
went to look at this for the cannabis
industry there was
no information available no emission
factors there to allow me to build an
inventory
no information to allow me to create
those inputs into an air quality amount
to allow me to predict
and so through a phd student
and some money from the national center
of atmospheric research in the state of
colorado
and some collaborators were able to for
the very first time
um measure what these emissions would be
build an inventory for the cannabis
industry for the state of colorado
and then used epa or approved air
quality models
to assess its impact on regional air
quality
so that's interesting so i just want to
make sure i'm understanding this
correctly so
is the issue it's not so much the vocs
that are coming from
the plant themselves it's when it's in
combination with
uh the emissions from um
like you said um combustion or some sort
of um power plant or cars or something
like that
that's absolutely right and you also
need sunlight as well so it's a
combination of
all three of those things yeah denver
right exactly um
and you know so in the atmosphere and
and so
it also depends it's a it's a very uh
complex chemistry
so in fact it's so complex that the
clean air acts
specify specifically that you have to
use an air quality model
to assess whether your controls are
going to work in the future
because there's all this combination of
emissions
chemistry and meteorology both winds and
sunlight
all forming together to in this really
complex non-linear chemistry
that's occurring in the atmosphere so
it's it's really difficult which is why
we run these air quality models right
because i couldn't tell you you know
just from looking at denver to tell you
what its impact would be because
of all the interactions of these things
right and so you're exactly right
you could also think of indoors as well
like if you had these vocs
you have a light source which could be
your uv lamps your grow lamps
and if you have any kind of combustion
source or you're bringing in nox
combustion sources from the outside
you have a possibility of also
generating ozone or particulate matter
inside your facility as well but you're
absolutely correct
the vocs themselves are not toxic
you can breathe them in at elevated
levels but as soon as
they mix in certain combinations with
what we call nitrogen oxides or nox from
combustion sources
in the presence of some sort of light
there's a potential for forming ozone in
particular matter
yeah so that's interesting so moving
forward will some attention need to be
paid
as to where these cultivation facilities
are placed
that's absolutely correct so you know we
have we know what's nice about this is
that we have the tools to do this right
uh you know anytime somebody wants to
install a new boiler or do a new
power plant right and they go for
sighting there are tools that are out
there to predict
what the impact on air quality water
quality is going to be
if that facility was put in
right and so we have those tools epa has
those tools we uh the permitting
we have a nice long history of being
able to use these tools to develop these
things
what is missing is the input data is the
understanding how the cultivation of
these plants and
what the response and temperature and
light and type of strain and life cycle
contributes to these emissions and then
once we have that then yeah i could we
could
cite these things we could predict its
impact on communities
we could talk about setbacks we could
talk about um
you know what sort of controls would
would be required
and what those controls would do in the
future if we had this sort of so
it kind of all goes back to if we
understand how these plants behave and
what they emit into the atmosphere then
we can rely on tools that we already
have
to learn about those impacts on both air
quality on terpene drift
and also on odor but it goes back to
understanding
what is being emitted by these plants
and before my publication there was
absolutely nothing
out there on what is coming out of
these plants so how
does the emissions from cannabis compare
to
other commercially grown crops
yeah so as it turns out the amount of
emissions that come from plants are as
varied and wide as there are species of
plants
um just to give you an example an oak
tree admits
oh i think an order of magnitude higher
rates of isoprene
than a pecan tree right they're both
trees
and so there's a wide variability which
and this is why this has been a
subject of investigation and research by
epa noaa and a bunch of other national
laboratories all around the world
trying to understand these emissions
from all these different kinds of plants
and species
and so we have a nice database of you
know other commodity products
and other large species of trees because
we have to run those in our air quality
models
now when it comes to cannabis as it
turns out
they contain a lot of the similar kinds
of what we call mono terpenes
which is a class of those terpenes and
some cesque terpenes
that we find in many other planets and
so there's nothing really unusual
as far as the type of monoterpene that's
being emitted
as far as the rate the amount the
magnitude that's being emitted
there i would say on average i mean
they're not the highest emitting plants
that we've ever seen
but they're also not the lowest emitting
plants that we've ever seen
um and so they're you know about an
average emitter now what's really
interesting about the cannabis plant
however that's
may or may not be different than other
plants um and that we've seen in our own
analysis
is that the amount so the rate
and the kind like you know the profile
of gases of monoterpenes that are being
emitted and cisco terpenes
varies wildly by strain so
depending on the strain you can have a
much different amount
of monoterpenes and cisco terpenes being
emitted as well as
kinds of and we also see differences in
the life cycle whether it's a juvenile
or a flowering plant we also see subtle
differences whether it's grown indoors
or outdoors
and so that was actually the most
surprising finding i found in my
research is
how varied widely in composition and
rate among the life cycle and strain
that we see
and that means that there's not a
one-size-fits-all emission factor
um and every facility if you want to
build an inventory has to do what we
call a site assessment like which
specific strains are you doing
what life cycle are they are they're
being grown indoor they've been growing
outdoor
and because all those things affect the
emission rate and then once we have
that information then we can build in
control we can have impacts on air
quality on terpene drift and odor but
again it goes back to understanding
those emissions
sure it makes complete sense that you
would see a wide variety in the
different strains
we see it in every other aspect of the
plant whether it be the height or the
the the size of the flowers the the
amount of the trichome so i
imagine that you know the emissions
wouldn't be any different
um now you said that there's a diff
difference in the
concentration in the different types of
of terpenes or emissions that the plants
are giving off are there any
uh molecules specifically that are
more troubling than others or is there a
certain combination that
that's more um a threat or is it kind of
all the same
well it kind of depends on the problem
that you're dealing with um so
what we're able to do in our own work is
um
we can give a full compositional profile
full characterization of every single
kind of molecule and there's
lots of different kinds of things it's
more than just the terpenes but there's
other
kinds of molecules that are being
emitted by those plants and so the
techniques that we have allow
us to measure all those things right and
so we have a good understanding of
almost every molecule that's coming from
that plant
and so then your your question was which
which molecules are the most important
and so
that depends on the question you're
trying to answer so for example
if we're looking at terpene drift one of
the culprits that has been
um identified as as uh has the potential
to taint wine
is eucalyptol which is a type of
monoterpene and so
for um terpene drift we would model
eucalyptol that would be the um
the molecule of question right and since
we're able to measure all the molecules
i can say okay i know exactly how much
eucalyptus coming from each strain
and each plant and we can build an
inventory and we can model eucalyptol
going forward
if you're interested in air quality then
it's all the molecules actually so every
single one of those vocs
um can react um and and potentially form
ozone or particulate matter
uh it has more to do with the um the
the alkene where the double bonds are so
the reactivity
and in fact in our air quality models we
treat almost all the mono terpenes the
same
from a reactivity standpoint and however
from an odor standpoint it's something
else altogether and so
we um things define that it's not the
terpenes
um that are a main driver for the other
although i think they
play a part in that we're still trying
to figure that out but it's a different
molecule that you'd have to track and
follow if you're interested in odor
um and so you know all three of those
problems right
come down to what's being emitted by the
plant and so if you know which molecules
are emitted by the plant
you can target those you can model those
and you can also control specifically
for those molecules no and that
that's interesting you bring that up and
this might be a great way to kind of
pivot into
another area that your group is
concerned about which is odor
um and i know that recently your team
had either put out a study or a press
release i think i saw the press release
about that you have identified the
molecule
excuse me responsible for the skunky
odor
um associated with cannabis i was
wondering if you could speak a little
bit more to that
yeah so um you know there's been a lot
of
work trying to understand odor impacts
right and it's it's
certainly an issue it's definitely a
community issue
it's a real issue and i think it's one
that
you know responsible cultivation owners
should
keep an eye on uh and it's also
something that's coming down the pike
with regulations um you know whether
it's there already
or coming it's happening right and so
understanding this odor
issue has become a focus of our research
in our
in our company for for some time now um
and we've been
able to collaborate with some really
interesting folks um
who have also been in the odor space but
in other industries
not necessarily in the cannabis industry
like i think landfills and
and meat rendering facilities and so
um working closely with these folks
including iowa state university
we and our own techniques and our
ability to um
fully characterize the profile of these
plans
we use both odor experts and high-end
analytical equipment to try to identify
what we think
might be ultimately driving a large
source of the objective over cannabis
and so the compound we found was this
thing called 3-methyl 2-butene 1-dial or
3-2-1
mbt it's a type of file so it's a sulfur
containing
compound and so we were able to identify
that and we've seen that in other
industries as well however that's just
kind of the beginning because
we're seeing all kinds of other
molecules that are also there as well in
addition to the mbt
and it's not quite clear how the
interaction between those terpenes and
vials
impact our perception of smell um so
there's a lot going on so we you know
i think it's just the start here that
we've been able to identify what we
think
might be one of the objective molecules
um
that um it makes a lot more sense in
assuming the monoterpenes were driving
odor which
didn't make sense just from you know
smelly monoterpenes on their own they
don't
have that odor but you know these styles
that seem to
make more sense to that and so currently
since we're able to identify the kind of
molecules there are we're able to adapt
our
control mitigation strategies to really
go after those sorts of molecules
prevent them from
leaving the facility at all yeah that's
that's really interesting
and i wonder if you could speak more to
the issue of odor in regards to cannabis
cultivation facilities
in general what is sort of the risk to
cultivators if they don't have their
order under control
yeah yeah um so you know i'm not an odor
expert so
um i can't talk about um you know for
example
are there medical issues associated with
odor
and so i'm not going to speak on but i
do know it's a nuisance right i mean at
the very minimal
people are not happy when they're
smelling um that odor and it's
strong odor um and it carries a very
very long way um and depending on how
you're growing if you've
i mean we've seen even juvenile strains
have odor issues right and i remember i
was saying that even juveniles and
and mature plants have different
profiles and different strains well
sometimes we come across a juvenile that
may have a higher you know
emission rate and those are skinky so
you could have at any point in time from
your facility you know 24 7
you know odor issues um and so yeah you
know
you know i've heard enough communities
who are next to these facilities who are
being impacted by these odors to know
that it may affect your quality of life
right you don't want to be outside you
don't
you have to close up your windows and
doors um you know and
and some people do suffer you know
physical um
you know impacts as a result of
continuously smelling that order
so it's not a good neighbor policy right
nobody wants to be next to something
that stinks really bad
um and and it brings a lot of attention
uh
and issues um to a facility that might
normally
might try to be doing the right thing um
and and
because of that odor it puts all kinds
of scrutiny
on the facility's operation and what
it's doing um and they may have the best
intentions
and so you know it's a naturally
occurring process that comes from the
cultivation of these plants
um and there's really no way to get
around it and so you have to control for
it and
you should strive to be a good neighbor
otherwise you're going to get
the scrutiny of not just the community
but also the regulators
yeah you mentioned regulators and i
think you mentioned it earlier too
have there been any you know regulatory
actions
in terms of requiring that cultivation
facilities control their order or is
that still coming
well so you know the thing with the
legalization of recreational medicinal
marijuana
is that it's a it's really a patchwork
kind of
place across the country right there's
no there's no federal
and even within the states sometimes the
counties have different ways of doing or
approaching it so
um you know are there places that are
regularly saying that you can't do odor
from a county yes i have seen that or
the places that don't have it yes i've
seen that as well
are there places where it's exempt for
example it's considered agricultural and
therefore it doesn't have an order i've
seen that as well so
you know it's all across the board right
um and it also depends on where the
facility is if it's an indoor girl like
in denver
there's more likelihood that they'll be
next door to residential communities
if it's grown outdoor on a farm you know
maybe their neighbor is a vintner and
not a
you know community so you know they're
more interested in the odor from their
tasting room than they are
you know from a you know community so
it's it's always
you know again just like the uh strains
and how they're
site-specific i think dealing with this
odor issue is also a
specific thing because our approaches
are different depending whether you're
an indoor grow an outdoor group
a hoop house you know all these things
require kind of different
um approaches for control mitigation but
again if you understand the rates and
where you're what's coming out your
plans
you know you're already halfway there
and trying to combat that issue
yeah so what are some of the solutions
that you've developed in terms of
controlling order
sure so um buyer scientific has a number
of equipment
um that's available um for mitigation
technologies
um so uh this includes uh combinations
of
um you know filtration systems where we
sequester odor molecules so molecular
scrubbing
which uses carbon um then we have uh
our patent vapor phase system that uses
waterless vapor technology and that
controls
uh some of these kind of what we call
fugitive odors odors that
kind of leak out or that there aren't um
uh
you know effectively mitigated by a
molecular filtration system right
um and so you know with the combination
of those two things that allows us to
um have a very good success for not only
capturing
you know preventing the majority of it
leaving in closed facilities
but also allowing us to deal with
facilities that aren't enclosed that
aren't conducive to for example
um carbon control all right um and so
and then we use um what we call a
coconut shell carbon uh so these are
campfill coconut shell carbon canisters
that we're using
we also have an option to include a
photocatalytic oxidation
as another means of reducing some of the
organics if you want to we want to do
that so that's in that system that
allows us to
uh you know uh mitigate these kinds of
odors and you know it also allows us to
capture the vocs that may contribute to
terpene drift or may contribute to air
quality impacts as well
yeah so are these air filters that are
sort of incorporated into the hvac
system they can be yeah so you know so
each um so we
do on-site solutions so it depends on
the system that
you know it depends on what how you're
growing or how you want us to be putting
but yeah i mean eventually what
we want to provide is um so what the
emission rates allows you to
quantify is what exactly is the breeding
rate of the plant right
what are they breathing out in what
amount
is that happening and so with that
information we can size our
instrumentation and our flow rates to
capture
what it breathes out we breathe in right
no more no less right you don't want to
do more because you're just wasting
energy
you don't want to do less because
that'll lead to a violation right
and so um and so we work with the
facility to make either an integral part
of the hva system is a standalone
process
or however it works best with the
facility that we're dealing with
and what about outdoor facilities i
imagine that's going to be quite the
challenge
right so that's where we have that our
vapor system and so it's a it's called a
stationary vapor system um it's quiet
and um it it's it creates an it's an
it's a mist but it's invisible miss uh
so you can't
really see it and and that has and that
it creates kind of
um uh you know like a curtain if you
will right
and so and then when the emissions from
the facilities
hit this kind of curtain it mitigates a
lot of eliminates the odors
from going downwind so in places where
you
can't control uh with um
carbon right which is like an open farm
or things like that
uh you can control with some of these
vapor systems that we've been able to do
outdoors so we've been successful in
mitigating odors both in
indoor outdoor grows and kind of mix
pros as well
so do you essentially set up a perimeter
around the grow and that sort of creates
that curtain so that if any molecules
interact with that they're sort of um
neutralized yep that's right wow that's
that's pretty that's pretty cool um
you didn't mention terpene drift as well
i didn't want to touch on that um
i'm i'm pretty sure that you you all
were
involved in a a lawsuit where i think it
was a
um a wine producer who was claiming
terpene drift from a nearby cannabis
facility
was tainting their grapes um i hope i
have that correct and if so i wonder if
you could speak a bit to that
yeah sure yeah so we were definitely
involved in that and so
um yeah that was the question and it
continues to be a question
and so they asked us to kind of
investigate and research that and so
we developed a scientific way of trying
to quantify
uh the amount of of material that would
end up
you know and whether it would or would
not taint um so
let me just back up a second so you know
there's been there's a published
literature out there that has shown that
eucalyptol
which is a type of terpene and a terpene
that is emitted
in the gas phase by um the cannabis some
cannabis plants
not all of them by the way but some of
them and um
eucliptol has been found when it makes
its way into the wine process
uh is has tainted the wine and the taste
of the wine ruining the wine
and so this is a known thing uh so
things when you have vineyards that are
near eucalyptol trees by the way and you
get eucalyptol leaves
as part of the harvesting those leaves
make it through the processing and
that's a large amount of eucalyptol oil
that ends up in your
in your wine and so uh when it was found
out that eucalyptol
is a molecule that is emitted by some of
these cannabis plants
then the question became is in
sufficient quantities that it could
taint
the grape tissue right so how do you
find that out well again
like i've been saying this whole podcast
it goes back to the emissions right so
if you know how much is being eucalyptol
is being emitted by these plants for a
facility
you could input that into an air quality
model that uses local meteorology
you could then predict where those
eucalyptol
molecules end up and go and you can see
how many of those end up
at the um the vineyard in question and
then you can
calculate you can predict what the
concentration of that eucalyptus would
be
outside that grape tissue and then you
could predict okay well
of that gas phase eucalyptol this is how
much that's absorbed by the grape tissue
and that would be the amount of
eucalyptol in your grape tissue
and then we could compare that to the
other studies that showed
um taint and how much material they had
in their grape tissues
and see how close we would get to that
right
okay so what we did is we went on site
or
rather this was a take that back this
was a facility that was being proposed
so there was nothing on site so
what they did was they told us which
strains that they were going to grow
and then we went to our other various
contacts in the business and we did our
own
measurements and develop leaf enclosure
measurements and develop emission
factors for those proposed strains
he the facility told us how many plants
they're going to build and we built an
inventory
then we took three years of neurological
data from the closest weather
station was at the proposed site uh and
we ran three years of
model simulations using that meteorology
um and predicted the you know the worst
case kind of concentrations
at the location of the of the existing
vineyard right
and then i said okay of that this is how
how much of it would uh deposit
and then this is how long it would take
at that rate under the worst conditions
of meteorology
uh for it to equal what was published
for um taint
and it ended up being i don't have the
numbers in front of me unfortunately but
i mean it was something
on the order of a couple years for it
for the amount that's been predicted
to get to levels that were seen in other
publications as far as taint
um and so that's kind of what we we
ended up with and so
and it makes sense if you think about it
right because yeah the the difference
between what
has been reported is that eucalyptol
leaves which contain
um pools of oil of eucalyptol and so
that's a large amount of eucalyptol when
you're in that concentrated oil form
right
what's coming off the cannabis um is in
the volatilized form
it's in the gas phase and these are
volatile organic compounds so they don't
want
it's hard for them to go back into a
liquid phase
and once they're volatilized and they're
in the gas phase they tend to stay in
the gas phase
and so very you know we have some that's
being emitted some that makes it over
there
some that makes it on the grape tissue
is but just not at
really measurable quantities and that's
what the predictions and then
the data told us okay so in this example
it's good news terpene drift is not
tainting any grapes
are there any other potential um
scenarios where chirping drift
potentially could be
an issue for other agricultural crops i
mean so i'm not sure
because um you know that i'm not in that
area where you know what what sort of
uh terpenes may be harmful to what sort
of plants the only thing we've heard
about
is is wine and specifically eucalyptol
and maybe
a couple others that have been shown in
the literature right
um and so that's why that's an issue
right now i mean there's still several
things that we don't know about i mean
for example
uh you know i've measured we have this
library right of um emissions factors
from these strains but
you know just in the state of colorado
alone there's 600 plus different strains
you know we have a number of strains but
not nowhere approaching
the order of hundreds of strains right
so there's still a lot of uncertainty
and just within the strains that we have
we see some plants with no eucalyptol
emissions and some with right
and so there's a lot of uncertainty just
in the emission factors and then
you know there's uncertainty as to you
know how much is too much stain right
you know
there's this number that we got from
this other study
but you know that's a whole lot you know
is there
you know what's the minimum amount
what's the threshold value like what
would be the target
and that's still kind of an unknown
thing right
there's a lot of research that still
needs to be done to really understand
whether this is an issue or not you know
but from what i've seen and
my gut tells me is that since these
things are volatile
and given the amount of emission rates
that we see it's something that we
should
probably model and look at but
you know just from the data that i've
seen so far it may not be a huge huge
issue right um not something that's
really surprising
or really popping out but you know
unless we have some data we can't
quantify these things we can't predict
these things and this is what we're
trying to do we're trying to fill in
these
answer these questions with some real
data and some real science so that we
have an understanding of whether things
are an issue or not
and to what extent they're an issue and
you know and by the way
those models were done with no controls
right and so if we had controls in that
facility
uh we would even less eucalyptus would
make it over to the vintner
and lastly i don't know if you remember
me saying this earlier but you know
these monoterpenes like to react in the
atmosphere
in the middle of the day they have an
atmospheric collapse time of a few hours
so they're not just hanging around in
the middle of the day they're actually
reacting away pretty quickly
and that's another thing that we didn't
assume in the model so we had a very
conservative upper bound concentration
and we still didn't even get near
what we would think would be shocking
levels of eucalypton like grape tissue
you know it's funny i've been doing this
podcast for over a year now and i can't
tell you how many times guests have said
we just don't know yet and there's still
so much we need to learn
um it's just such a common refrain
in this industry which is what makes it
so fascinating so exciting and
why we love doing this conference every
year and
happy that you're going to be a part of
it i'm really looking forward to the to
the panel that you
you're going to be on so winding down
here i did want to give you
the opportunity to plug any websites
social media or additional resources
that you think might be useful to the
audience
yeah sure i mean i think uh everything
if you are interested in learning more
about the company
including the documentation some of
their case studies
and uh references that i've published
i think your best fit is to go to our
website so that's buyer's scientific dot
com
buyers b-y-e-r-s dash scientific dot com
so check us out on the world wide web
excellent i will do that i'll put the
link in the show description so people
have an easy way to
to get over to that website so well
thanks again for
for joining us uh it's been a great
conversation and i look forward to
seeing you out in pasadena
all right i look forward to go out there
and take it easy thanks for having me on
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr william veswette
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor 10 buds
our next episode will drop july 7th
that's two weeks from today and it's
also the deadline
for our early bird rate please go to cam
at events.com now
to secure early bird pricing and save
on your full conference ticket be sure
to keep up with us on social media we
are on
instagram facebook twitter and linkedin
just search for canmedevents and finally
we appreciate it if you rate review
and subscribe on your favorite podcast
app
doing so will make sure that we can
reach more people with the podcast
alright that's it from us thanks again
for joining us
and be sure to stay safe stay healthy
and come back for the next canmed coffee
talk
[Music]
you