[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt
i'm the marketing manager at medicinal
genomics and proud member of the team
that puts on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now to learn all about our canmed 2021
event
that will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
and if you're listening to this podcast
the day that it comes out that's
wednesday
july 7th then today is the last day that
you can purchase
your full conference pass at our early
bird rate
that's a 300 savings off the full price
of that ticket
so go over to canmedevents.com right now
and get your ticket so you'll be all set
to join us in pasadena this fall
in other news we have officially
launched our canmed archive page
which includes over 100 canmed
presentation videos
dating back to our first event in 2016.
the canmed archive is a free searchable
video library covering a range of topics
related to cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
go to kmedevents.com and click the
banner on the homepage to check it out
i also want to remind everyone that the
healthcare provider study
we are doing with the cannabis center of
excellence is still
ongoing if you are a healthcare provider
please take a few minutes to complete
the survey
to help us better understand medical
cannabis knowledge
attitudes and practices among healthcare
providers in the u.s and canada
as an added incentive one lucky
participant
will win a k med 2021 practicum
and full conference ticket the link to
access that survey
is in the show description alright this
episode's guest
needs no introduction kevin mckernan of
medicinal genomics is back
to talk about psilocybin and the
mushrooms that create it
kevin and the team at mgc have published
a highly
contiguous reference genome for
philosophy cubensis
which some listeners may know is the
species of mushroom
often referred to as the magic mushroom
kevin and the team have also sequenced
several different
mushroom strains to try and better
understand
the genes of interest and pathways
responsible
for psilocybin production if you're new
to psilocybin
and mushrooms don't worry we cover the
basics
as well as new findings in our
conversation
including potential therapeutic
applications for psilocybin
what is fueling the rapidly growing
interest in psilocybin
psilocybin's path towards legalization
other psychoactive compounds found in
mushrooms
how mushrooms are cultivated and bred
and what that means for applying
genomics
the discovery that there is more than
one way mushrooms
synthesize psilocybin and more
before we get to my conversation with
kevin i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor
the new scientist magazine and their
upcoming campaign
titled the future of psychedelic
medicine
the future of psychedelic medicine
campaign highlights the r
d and innovations currently taking place
within the psychedelic space
to raise awareness for how psychedelic
medicine
could transform mental health treatment
the campaign
also aims to highlight the potential
psychedelic medicine has
to help with a range of mental health
conditions
including depression addiction anxiety
ptsd abuse disorders ocd
and address the stigma surrounding this
type of treatment
read the future of psychedelic medicine
campaign
on july 22nd in the new scientist
magazine
and on health awareness dot co dot uk
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with kevin
mckernan
good afternoon kevin thanks for joining
us thanks for having me i know it's
uh it's really odd to have such an
outsider on your podcast
well it's funny you say that you were
the first guest on the podcast
and now you are the first repeat guest
on the part
podcast so uh congratulations on making
history
yeah yet again i try hard speaking of
making history
you recently published a highly
contiguous
reference genome for the cilla psilocybe
cubensis is that i think so i used to
say that as well but i
the way i've heard people who are more
familiar with space than i am is they
call it philosophy
but i used to call it psilocybe as well
because psilocybin is probably what
you've
heard of that's the compound it makes
right okay so that's good
i wanted to lay some groundwork here in
terms of uh
terms for people who might not be as
familiar here so
silasippy is the genus of mushroom
yes correct and then silas b cubensis is
a species
of mushroom that's typically referred to
as the magic mushroom
yes that produces psilocybin which is
the psychoactive compound
that makes you trip yes and now to make
things more confusing there's also this
compound called
salocin okay so now you can trip over
that one too
yeah that was good so that was going to
be one of my questions
you say all five things fast is there
compounds in addition to psilocybin that
can create the psychoactive
effect so there is a uh a suggested
um entourage effect if you will that we
don't know
much about at the moment so i don't know
how psychoactive they are
um but there are certainly tryptamines
so there's other tryptamines in the in
the mushroom that are in the pathway
just like
in in cannabis where there is a livital
and then you get cbg
and then cbg gets folded into a variety
of other cannabinoids there's a similar
thing going on in in making these
tryptamines
is that there are precursors to
psilocybin which is silocin
and then in the pathway there's also
these other different
methylations on the molecule much like
maybe different tails you might have on
cannabinoids that are
baiocysteine and origination and then
there's
narcilocin and norvaocystin so
there's there's a spectrum of these
things and i'd say we we mostly know
about
psilocybin and we do know the mushrooms
make a variety of these different
compounds
and we don't yet know which mushrooms
make how much of
each of them and what the um
contributions are
to the psychoactive effects so um
there's a lot to learn there another
thing that came out very recently
that people may not fully appreciate on
these mushrooms is they also make
monoamine oxidase inhibitors
this changes the metabolism of these
compounds in your stomach
and your liver so um that's kind of rare
in that
when you look at the story of other
beans like dmt
is quite known from in ayahuasca but
they actually have to mix
ayahuasca with some other plant that
makes a monovinoxidase in it
because because dmt itself doesn't get
through the gut
so the mushrooms figured out a couple
different tricks here it's figured out
how to phosphorylate salocine into
psilocybin so that it can get through
your gi
uh it's also figured out um how to make
these other monoamine oxidase inhibitors
to alter your liver metabolism
so that more of these things get through
so there's there's there's a lot going
on
inside this tiny little genome and uh
that's what i think piqued your interest
it has shares a lot of the same
similarities to canvas and that uh one
molecule was getting all the credit when
there's probably more
and it looks like it's probably going to
be going medical soon
at least it's recreationally approved in
several jurisdictions including three
here in massachusetts
and we in order to understand
which mushrooms make these other
entourage effects
we wanted to just go do a huge survey
and all the mushrooms out there to
figure out if we could find genetics
that altered
the the expression of these things
so that's kind of where it started okay
and so it seems like interest in
psilocybin
is at an all-time high now so what
what's what's fueling this interest well
there's several things i think um
the mo the best work on this is out of
johns hopkins looking at cancer
related depression um however at canmed
i kept meeting people
um that have also seen some remarkable
effects in cancer like glioblastoma i
think bonnie goldstein told me about one
case that responded to psilocybin for
a glioblastoma that was not responding
to cannabis uh which is kind of
fascinating i don't i don't understand
the pathway and why
but um they are neurogenerative so they
they do have the capacity
to uh you know reprogram this default
mode network in your brain
and uh they seem to have a lot of the
properties of cbd and that they're
neuroplastic they help
to help regenerate neurons so um they're
looking at this i think for beyond just
depression but probably ptsd
and maybe even brain injuries so um
that works really exciting that when you
look at the work in depression
um it seems to be more promising than
cannabinoids in many ways in that and
and johns hopkins they're doing like
three treatments and getting like over
success rates and then it's like
permanent it's not like this chronic
you must be on cbd the rest of your life
type of thing for ptsd
or thc whatever it may be whatever can
happen but what you tend to see with the
cannabinoids is folks tend to be using
those
consistently to manage the effects
whereas the data that you're seeing
with um psilocybin is that three guided
treatments these are therapies that are
monitored with
we know the professionals and they have
a
massive success rate on turning around
uh depression so that's
that's unique you know you don't see
that in a lot of other antidepressants
it's kind of like you're on them for
life
and um i'm curious if that's one reason
why it's not getting a whole lot of
attention to the pharmaceuticals
but that said there was a recent article
in new england journal of medicine
that was comparing um psilocybin
with it wasn't fluoxetine but it was a
similar ssri
which is a cert selective serotonin
reuptake inhibitor so these are the
traditional tricycle antidepressants
that are out there
and there are some drawbacks to those
ones i some of my earliest work in
this field at emory was on those
compounds and they're not as serotonin
selective as you think
and they come with all types of labels
such as suicidal ideation so
those are a little frightening when
you're trying to treat suicidal ideation
and one of the
side effects and label is suicidal
ideation you're you're kind of
putting the patient a little bit of a
catch-22 there as to whether or not this
drug is going to work for them
so um that i i'm not seeing that with
psilocybin granted certainly we don't
have really these you know randomized
control trials that might that might
find that but um there is certainly a
lot of
um i think human population use of these
things at least like like cannabis
uh we have you know hundreds if not
thousands of years of human experience
dosing with these things that
um the the toxicology on this is
understood it's they're not toxic
uh in fact i've even seen some evidence
i'll have to find a good citation for
this but generally lsd
and psilocybin are thought to be less
toxic than even the cannabinoids if you
can believe that
like there's just not overdoses with
these things you might do stupid things
on them right but they're not
they're not chemically toxic um so what
about
what about lasting effects you hear
people who who trip and they're
never the same i know i know i don't i
don't have i'm not good
resource on that that's probably um i
bet johns hopkins has better data
on what some of these chronic conditions
and flashbacks and other things that you
hear about may
um may play a role in because there's
certainly the same type of
conundrum we have looking at
schizophrenia in cannabis and looking at
you know mental illness with with these
psychedelics is that
um they attract a lot of people who have
a mental illness and are seeking to
treat it
and oftentimes you don't know whether
the compound helped or accelerated it
right right
so um that though those need good
randomized control trials to really sort
out but
um uh that that's uh there's certainly
that issue with the current treatment
status that we have with ssris i mean
you see a lot of these uh unfortunately
when you hear about a lot of these um
you know gun effects in the united
states where there's you know kids that
are
running around shooting up schools it's
quite frequently they're on ssris
and so um there's there's a lot to be um
i think reckoned with here that that the
current treatments we have
aren't clean of those things either and
so we need to be looking at things that
are non-toxic and be giving these
alternatives a chance
yeah another thing that you had
mentioned there is when you were talking
about
three treatments that could kind of
eliminate
symptoms you mentioned guided um
treatments under the supervision of a
professional i was
wondering if you could do that i don't
know what those are i have not
experienced one so
um that's probably a better question for
um we'll have to find somebody uh
who has more experiences yeah and maybe
just in general like why is it
why is that more um
prudent in this type of therapeutic i i
think they're so
they're such powerful compounds um that
uh somebody who has a bad experience
with them probably needs a sober person
next to them to help talk them off the
ledge so to speak
uh and that's the intent there is that
the dosages that they're using for these
types of
um you know reversing depression almost
permanently
are up in the using one to three grams
of these
uh mushrooms which if they're one
percent uh psilocybin
these things get up into um what does
that put a set if it's three grams it's
one percent it's like 30 milligrams of
pure compound
um these uh you know there's also a
whole
um interest in microdosing these things
which is a completely different
scenario this is not putting yourself
into the point where you start to
hallucinate
this is just getting a you know a
serotonin agonist in your system
that is a bit more stimulant and many
people are reporting that they have
more productivity on these things that
they're better for computer programming
we have these waves out in silicon
valley where
there seems to be a you know this
popularity and and
and utilizing these things for for
almost as a performance-enhancing drug
not necessarily for sports but for
um for getting work done so i don't
think that's necessarily getting guided
yeah i think that's that's self-guided
but i think when you get into the stage
where you start getting dissociative
effects
um there it's as a safety side of the
equation they probably won't have
someone else around
yeah that makes sense and now in the
whole idea of micro dosing now is that
psilocybin um specifically or some of
these other
psychoactive compounds i think i'm
hearing of it another with lsd and with
psilocybin
and um i think it probably spans the
gamut but
um you know my dipping my toe in there
just to talking to people it seems as if
mushrooms are quite popular for that
just because of their
uh there's some slightly different
pharmacology to those in lsdl which is
externally potent
and the receptor biology there is i
probably need a refresher on but this is
the civil side is mostly hitting
serotonin five it's 5ht2a
and lsd may tickle a few others
okay so we've talked a bit about the
you know therapeutic uses for for
psilocybin and you mentioned that you
know it's legalizing it in more states
how do you see the legalization of
psilocybin
um what's the path there and how similar
is it to what we've seen with cannabis
i think it's going to proceed faster
than cannabis because it can go in the
wake of cannabis
it can follow the same model it can go
through and
effectively utilize the same all right
let's get medical out first and then
perhaps there'll be a recreational
component to this later
much of the legislation for doing
dispensaries is already in place and
people know how to
use that playbook so we've already seen
oregon go completely recreational i
should say recreation decriminalized on
an organ i think berkeley oakland denver
cambridge somerville and northampton
here in massachusetts have all done it
there's i think there's some rumblings
of other jurisdictions as well maybe in
dc and a few others
um so it seems as if it is moving at a
bit of a faster pace than cannabis
originally did where we you know we
first saw cannabis
uh you know back when the hiv epidemic
just started with a medical campaign and
it took you know almost a decade for
more of that to spread whereas we're
seeing
the psilocybin motion go rampant very
quickly i think
canada is probably taking the lead here
they seem to have moved
moved ahead much faster than anyone else
so
i'm hopeful it'll move much quicker now
exactly how it's going to roll in the
marketplace is a good question that
you know i i don't see the um
you know cannabis flour is still half
the market and you have all these other
edibles
and extracts and i don't think that's
going to go away because there's just
you know a connoisseur of people who
like terpenes and like the the
experience of smoking flour
i don't know that we have that with
chewing these mushrooms
i think not it's not shiitake it's
probably going to go more into an
extract mode
or capsules or teas who knows but
um there's certainly a different um
bearer to entry as it comes
when it comes to growing these things i
think if you want to get involved
growing cannabis
if it's indoor there's quite a setup
involved there to get lights and
everything and you know maybe a hydro
and everything else involved
outdoors perhaps you know you set it and
forget it outside and hope for the best
but
um it certainly takes more like you know
eight to twelve weeks to get something
off of
cannabis plant whereas these mushrooms
can grow in like two months
in a tupperware bin in your basement you
know this is not something that
is the barrier to entry is much lower on
this so there may be more people trying
to homegrow these
much like beer than you might see with
cannabis that requires lots of lights
and you know the
growing cannabis in your house everyone
knows just stinks up your whole house
very hard to deal with that if you if
you want to keep it discreet
that's not the case with some of these
um folks who like to cultivate these
things on their own so i think there
still will be a homegrown market
and uh you know a dispensary based
market for these things and then there's
also progress moving
on the therapeutic side through the fda
many people are optimistic that we'll
see
mdma probably through through a
successful trial this year and maybe get
some advancement the fda has designated
this as a breakthrough therapy
so that means it's going to have an
accelerated path through the fda and i
think once the fda has some approved
versions of this
that will help guide the folks in the
nutraceutical side of what to do and how
to apply it now there'll probably be
some labeling constraints that fda is
not going to want to see the
dispensaries or the nutraceutical side
making medical claims on whatever
they're selling
but um they're i think that's going to
very much
lead the charge that when you start
seeing the fda versions of these things
roll out it's going to give many of the
physicians a whole lot more comfort and
it's going to give i think better
guidance as to how these should be
handled in
um on the dispensary side of things i
was
hoping we could talk a bit more about
the cultivation of this because it like
you said it is very different
from cannabis and i'm thinking from a
genomic side too
um how does the difference in the
cultivation of
these mushrooms kind of affect how
genomics could be used for breeding or
purpose that's a really good question
that's one reason why we set about
sequencing all these genomes is just to
figure out like
how is this market going to be different
cannabis is so diverse that every time
you make a cross you're kind of
you're playing you're gambling with a
new game which is kind of fun you get
new genetics of your cross
most of the market here seems to be
propagating asexually derived spores so
there's actually a little bit more
clonal consistency so when when we
when we sequence the first 80 genomes
here um we did it all with spores
so don't so you can ship spores legally
which is really bizarre because you
can't ship cannabis seats likely
uh well maybe you can do the hemp seeds
now but but in the past there
you couldn't you know and now with
spores
they're legal for taxonomic purchase
because there's no um
you can't detect any silicon in them so
you know if anyone gets caught with
spores they ultimately test to see
there's if there's scheduled compounded
and there isn't
um so i've heard from some people though
this is an illegal opinion so don't bank
on this but from
some people that you can actually
culture them with
minimal mediums they don't express any
stylus item if you want to do like you
know some mycology stuff but
for our purposes we don't need to we can
we can get enough dna out of spores and
sequence their whole genome from them
so typically what happens is people will
get spores from either a spore print or
from a syringe where they'll put the
spores in some kind of liquid media so
they're in
a 10 10 ml syringe and then they'll
inject that
into a sterilized bag of grains these
things love to grow in grains
and that has to be a very very pure
injection if there's any bacteria around
the bacteria like we experienced
doing all this plating and stuff with
on the cannabis microbial detection
front if there's any bacteria around it
doubles every like 30 minutes and the
mold can
can take you know a month to grow so the
bacteria can like take over the thing
and destroy it
but the goal is to get a spawn bag that
is grown with mycelium from this thing
from the spores
and that takes maybe a month and then
once that's done
you immerse that grain that's got a full
mycelium
grown throughout it you dunk it in water
for 24 hours to simulate like a
rainstorm
pull it out and put it in a humidity
chamber for in a few weeks you have lots
of mushrooms
so i think the key the key aspects are
making sure that there is
absolutely clean spores going in and
that's one thing we did notice we did
use some of our
pcr tools that we have here to look for
total aerobic count inside of these
things
and we saw many of the different spores
that were provided had
high levels of attack and those tended
to have you know they gave us more
sequencing
i don't know how well they grow but i've
heard from people that growing those can
be complicated if there's any bacteria
around
but we can gauge which ones that we can
get clean genomes from just
up front by looking at how much
bacterial to fungal dna is around and by
looking at that ratio
we can say okay this one's got a lot
more with dna and bacterial dna use that
one for sequencing this one's got too
much bacteria don't sequence it or
you'll get a metagenome
but that was probably in like 20 to 30
percent of the spores that we collected
we threw out or or when we sequenced it
we realized that they were dirty
and they gave us dirtier results so um
now would that be like in
a beneficial upfront screening tool for
whether or not you were going to it
might be yeah
it might be i would imagine um as you
scale this
up a lot of people are growing these in
compartmentalized um
boxes for that reason because if they
get a bacterial contaminant they don't
want it to go everywhere
and so they break them up into small
bins but um
even so how they're how they're mad
getting those spores i i would imagine
to scale this up
syringes probably don't scale they
probably have to put the syringes into
some type of liquid culture and grow a
huge culture and then spread that
everywhere but you would want to monitor
that large culture to make sure that
there's no
bacterial contamination in there there
are some folks a little concerned about
putting antibiotics in the mix too
because the antibiotics
sometimes slow down the growth of the
mycelium and at the same time they don't
want it to get absorbed into the
mushrooms
and then people start eating you know
gentamicin labeled uh
mushrooms so they're trying to do this
without adding any antibiotics which is
it means you probably have to be very
very sterile in the process
and maybe even monitor for bacterial
load throughout the process
you you brought up an interesting point
in the genomics of this which is
um this works really well in cubensis
but cubensis isn't the only species that
makes these things there's about 200
different mushrooms that make psilocybin
there's even one that infects cicadas
that makes them hypersexual and spread
the spores
every 16 years um and yeah yeah so
there's
it's called masapora which is really
interesting one it infects the cicada
and then starts making um psilocybin
inside
the cicada so that it goes crazy and and
ends up getting
bisexual and hypersexual and starts
spreading its spores everywhere instead
of like an orgy fashion
and that's a that one's a really bizarre
genome it's like 600 megabases which is
much larger than the 45 megabase genomes
we see
with cubensis but what we're trying to
look at by
by sequencing outside of the cubensis
species uh is to see do they all make
psilocybin in the same way
there's been some great work out there
by jason slaat's lab and
reynolds and frick and huffmeister
these are all folks who have published
in this area um
that have noticed that a lot of the
psilocybin
um synthesis genes are all clustered
together they're all in this tight
little 20 kb region in the genome and
that seems to
horizontally transfer to other mushrooms
there's also been some
evidence that they're not always
clustered together and and some of these
other mushrooms that the the pathway is
a little bit more
separated and we don't know why um but
they're also diverged enough from a
sequencing standpoint that the primers
that we use in the juventus front
probably aren't going to work really
well when you go into tampanensis or
when you go into a
xero sense or mexicana
these are all these other types of
mushrooms that make
they're all philosophy and there's a
couple that are even outside of
philosophy
that make psilocybin but they are
sequent from a sequence standpoint
they're diverged enough
that the primaries we use to target
these genes in the
cubensis are probably not going to work
on those so
that's different than the cannabis run
the canister we can pretty much although
it's very polymorphic we can make
primers that hit thc and cbd
and and these genes pretty readily once
we have a good map of like 40 or 50
genomes we can target that throughout
the population without tripping over too
many
the differences but the differences that
we're seeing even amongst the cubensis
lines is probably a variant every 150
bases
what we see in the hemp front is you get
about a variant every
50 bases if you compare it to something
like jamaican lion it's probably about
every hundred bases when you compare it
amongst uh
drug-type cultivars like all type ones
so there's more polymorphism there's
more it's more repetitive in the
cannabis front but the genes that are
responsible for making cannabinoids are
really conserved
whereas you get into the philosophy
front and it is
not just stuck into cannabis sativa that
makes it it's you see this like
philosophy multiple different species of
philosophy that actually make this and
so they're much more diverse than what
we see in cannabis
which means the genomics in many ways is
more complicated
but the propagation of it is much more
simple they're not there aren't people
doing these crosses
not yet it can be done but most people
are just asexually reproducing these
spores
and um and and then when they see one
particular mushroom that produces a
really like
large mushroom cap it grabs wars from
those and try and repeat the process
because maybe there's a mutation in that
one that that means it produces a lot
more yield
that's kind of how the game is going now
but there isn't this like i'm not seeing
a lot of people take different mushrooms
and cross
them very much to try and get new
varietals that seems to be um
probably only very few people in the
world that know how to do it right and
so
it's not uh most people are just hoping
for for mutations inside the batch that
they have
and then try to propagate those so it's
it's a different game
um but i think genomics is going to play
a role we're already seeing some
benefits uh
in and that we're finding variants that
are in the pathway that we think are
responsible for certain
cultivars or strains i should say um
having
um and there's there's a complicated
word it is a strain in this strategy
yes not cultivars uh and varietals they
don't think are yet appropriate because
varietals kind of um imply you've
stabilized the genetics and no one's
doing that yet
uh what is kind of interesting about
them is is if you read about how people
do cross them as they put different
things down on plates and grow maybe we
can back up for a second here because
i'm not sure i fully
understand it so explain how
a mushroom does reproduce asexually
first
it's got two life cycles one life cycle
is um when it makes a fruiting body it's
making a cap
like the mushroom that you see and those
are asexually reproduced spores
however there is a part of the life
cycle where these things form
clamps so when two mycelium grow into
each other from two genetically unique
uh mushrooms and then they're all the
same species us
essentially it's like the root system
yeah okay
so these things if they have compatible
mating types which is
and something that we have not yet
identified we have some hunches as to
where the genome the mating type is but
this is kind of like in cannabis there's
an x and y chromosome well in fungi they
have mating mating types which aren't
limited there's there could be a much
bigger spectrum of gender if you will
right so you can have many you have more
than just a versus be mating type some
fungi have you know thousands of mating
types
if they're compatible mating types
they'll form a clamp connection which is
two mycelium that kind of like
um kind of it's kind of like a usb port
coming together and they can trade a
nuclei
and when they do that you end up with a
a new part of the mycelium which is
dikaryotic it has two nuclei in it which
are now two different genomes together
and then there can be a stage of its
life cycle where those things go through
meiosis
and they exchange most people aren't
doing that they're not
taking two different things putting
together and using a microscope to find
if they make clamp connections
when they don't have compatible mating
types they usually will grow
and then they'll be like you can see a
visual barrier between the colonies like
they won't grow into each other as it's
the mating types are usually pheromones
and the pheromones
are usually if they're compatible
pheromones then they'll grow into each
other and you'll get clamps and
clamp connections and if they're not
they'll kind of grow and they'll be like
a colony exclusion zone there where they
don't
actually dmz or dmz or they don't touch
and so um there are there are a few
people out there that know how to do
this they're rare
but um that they're they're some are
even trying to cross things across
species lines because there's some
debate that
maybe these things will even cross
between species which would be
interesting but
um so unlike cannabis breeding i there's
there's far more people in the world
that know how to breed cannabis
and do crosses i think in the in the
mycology side at least with philosophy
you can probably name the people on your
hand that not do it and and most people
aren't resorting to it because it's just
it's just easier to like pick the
biggest mushroom out of a particular box
and see if you can grab those spores and
and keep propagating and selecting for
things that make very large fruits and
have high
high potency so um where exactly where
do the spores actually come from oh they
come out of the cap of the mushroom okay
yeah yeah so when the
when the mushroom the mycelium is almost
just like a network of roots
um it's not technically correct but what
it looks like inside of some of these
grain
or spawn bags uh and then once you
heavily soak and wet it
that's a trigger that hey we've got
enough water content here start making
fruiting bodies and they pop out
mushrooms and then when the cap unfolds
those gills that are in the cap just
dump spores
and that's something that is uh that
people can collect and they can either
put those into
you know uh culture and solution or or
just collect them
on a piece of tin foil and you get like
a sport print on tin foil and they can
store that
and then and then inoculate something
with that later
um so uh we were that's something we
set out to do is to see what was the
diversity if you collect
we're not sequencing a single four when
we do this we're seeing collections of
spores so initially we're worried that
when you did that you might have so much
genetic variation it'd be a mess but it
turns out you can do it and
and it's not too messy and you can
sequence the genomes and assemble them
and
um and count the variants that you see
yeah so
are the spores that the that it the cat
produces are they
clonally identical or they are they
should
be haploid and they should be um
not 100 identical in that they should
represent two different copies of the
diploid parent genome
uh so there is a stage where the diploid
genome starts making haploid copies
uh and so you can get you get a good
representation when you do a spore prep
of both
the mother and the father if you will uh
in the original diploid dikaryotic
genome uh it goes to this weird stage i
have to point you into a video because
it's unlike anything you've seen in like
mammalian genetics or plant genetics
with these they have these two different
life cycles of asexual and
and meiotic reproduction okay um but uh
there's a video that we
have here we can link to this podcast
that kind of walks people through this
but um
and when you do sequence a whole
collection of them uh
you end up getting enough haploid copies
from the mother enough haploid copies
from the father if you will that you can
you can effectively see both versions of
the genome
there probably are some unique mutations
on any given spore level
but we probably can't see those types of
that level of resolution of mutations
unless we sequence really really
differently
deeply because we're we're collecting
like a million spores at once
so we get kind of an average picture of
what the
the the the diploid genome look like uh
when we sequence a collection of spores
uh but we're not going to see those like
tiny mutations that might make each
spore
itself individually unique just because
they're so small and it would be kind of
there's just such a small number of them
yeah there's like in any sport prep we
might be
peppering a million of them and if and
if every one of those had
one unique mutation in them they'd be
drowned out because they'd be one in a
million
but the real true differences in the
parental lines that make them different
well those are going to be 50 50 in all
the reeds
that we see and so we can call those but
the actual
uh really rare events we're not going to
see but you said there's two different
types of
reproduction right there's asexual as
well yes there's asexual which is what
comes out of the spore generation from
the
um from the fruiting bodies but there's
another stage
that goes through meiosis after these
things have formed a clamp junction you
have two nuclei they're together
eventually those nuclei fuse and then
you go through a meiotic stage where
they split again
and that's where you can get some of the
genetic recombination very few people
are collecting spores at that stage
right collecting the ones out of the
that are really easy to get
and so for the for the purposes of
sequencing i think we're
just based on the way the law is today
you can legally sequence the spores you
can't legally go sequence the other
stuff
so we don't know what that does at the
moment uh we've seen some models of what
it does
but um you uh the spores are the one
thing that
that don't have tissue don't express any
of the compound and so those are
those things are legal for taxonomic
purposes and genomics is like the
ultimate
taxonomic classifier so we're good on
handling the spores that come
out of the fruiting bodies but uh it's
unclear if we're ever gonna be able to
until it legalizes more whether we can
go and investigate some of the questions
that you're asking
so kind of getting towards the end here
what is sort of the
most surprising thing that has come from
the work that you've done
um i think what stunned me about it is
the um the work that's coming out in
in the sars kobe 2 space where they're
seeing
these drugs not exactly psilocybin but
fluoxetine in particular
is being is very promising for shutting
down the virus replication that that was
a shocker to me i didn't even know about
that until i
read or saw peter mccullough's work on
that um
but people who are on tricyclics have
less likely infected with sars
so there's a whole pathway in the ace2
receptor when
when you're expressing ace2 it
co-expresses
um dopa decarboxylase which is involved
in the serotonin pathway and so they're
finding
serotonin you know giving people
serotonin agonists or serotonin
selective reuptake inhibitors which
accomplish very similar ends
uh is fighting off the virus i had no
idea these things
play a role there um so there's a whole
focus
in the field on antidepressants which is
great but
if they're antiviral to some extent at
least viruses that are coming in through
ace two
um that's a whole other interesting side
of of this story so
um so that was kind of exciting to to
read about
what we're finding on the genomics front
is that the pathway that
makes these um compounds is far more
complicated than we than initially
hypothesize it was initially thought
that there's this 120 kb cassette that
was
horizontally transferred everywhere we
can now see when we start sequencing
outside of cubensis
that's not the same it's there's a the
the genes aren't clustered they're
scattered throughout the genomes and
there's and they're very different
so we already have a really nice picture
of variants
in all of these genes across 80
different cubensis genomes including
outside of cubensis in azura sense and
in tamponensis
and in galindois that we're now starting
to see
other ways these mushrooms have figured
out how to make these things so
there's an argument for convergent
evolution going on simultaneously to
this horizontal gene transfer
and that's going to be interesting
because some of the other
non-cubensis species like azure sends
are reportedly make more psilocybin than
cubensis
they're just really hard to find they're
mostly in the pacific northwest i think
paul stamets is the person who figured
that out or found those
and we don't sequence those very much
and you don't see them much in the
underground markets for growing although
people do sell the spores
the fact that they're making psilocybin
in a kind of a unique way is very
interesting to us because that might
help guide
all right what properties that those
mushrooms have can we breed into the
more commercial lines because mostly
people for commercial purposes are
growing
cubensis and maybe five or six of those
strains it's mostly b plus golden
teacher
penis envy another another you know
enlightening name we have in the
mushroom space you think cannabis strain
names are bad we can get into mushroom
space right
um those are really probably the three
maybe the albinos as well
are maybe four the most commonly used
because they grow very large fruits but
size isn't everything sadly to use that
pun
because some of the smaller ones are
more concentrated in the compound so
there might be a way to intercross those
or or learn what we can learn from
reserve sense to get the production up
on the other ones
likewise there are some that are named
beosysten which i assume is because they
make more of that one compound so
now that we have this pathway mapped out
we can begin to look at the variation we
see between all these different
types of mushrooms to try to custom
breed them in one direction another or
there's already people doing work on
cloning these things into yeast and
getting beer to make it
right so um right that's uh
that might be the ultimate way to make
some of the more rare versions of these
things right just like in cannabis
we're not seeing people wanting to clone
cbd into yeast i mean
they do it as a control but you can get
cbd road cheaply out grown outdoors
but cbdv and maybe uh well maybe seth
crawford has that one nailed but
some of these really rare esoteric
cannabinoids that we don't yet know how
to breed into the plant people will
probably be very successful brewing
those i think that might be the case
with some of these compounds out of
cubensis as well that some of the rare
ones get moved get shuttled into yeast
um and since it's fungi to fungi that
transfer will probably happen really
readily
um but maybe the more popular ones you
want to breed for
mushrooms that just grow very
productively and then that might beat
the east out so
um yeah that's uh it's been a really fun
project and i have to give
actually credit speaking of seth
crawford their team actually helped us
get that first reference out
um so they they played a pivotal role in
getting some of the sequencing done
and since then we've now tacked on
another 80 genomes against that
reference
using illumina sequencing and that's
giving us a really nice perspective on
every variant the pathway that might be
playing a role in how these genes are
behaving
so um it's a it's really an exciting
time for the field because
suddenly there's like this mountain of
data to come through
and we can't comb through it all
ourselves so we've been putting a lot of
it uh
into ncbi uh and you'll see another
pre-print
our first paper in the reference is out
published and peer viewed and we're now
just submitting another one that has
another 80 genomes
that we're playing with to kind of paint
a picture of how complicated this
particular pathway is
what's next um after that
um i don't know i think after that we
have to have reach out to the field a
little bit more and find out okay what
are the real pain points
um what does the market actually need
it's such an early market that
um we don't know where to move with this
data i think
what might be next is understanding
which variants in each of these genes
are connected to the chemotypes
right we we can't do the chemotypes
right so we have to partner with people
there's people out there
that are really good at chemotyping
these things we want that dna to
sequence it so we can correlate what
variants we're finding
that might predict what chemotype you're
getting that's probably the next phase
um so we've got to team up with people
who who do that there's there's an
equivalent of a cannabis comp i heard
out in oakland
that that may be able to help out there
so we're probably going to reach out to
some of those folks and say hey whatever
you're chemotyping
if it's if it's one of these oddballs
that makes a really different compound
or makes a lot of one particular
compound
let's get sequence pop it onto the map
there will be a version of canopedia
that we're gonna fork
uh into being a phylogenetic tree or
mycelium if you will that will
kind of display these things that we're
working on so we'll have some of the
same functionality there
um so that people can get their um their
stuff sequenced with us
get it compared get a list of variants
people can start tracking these things
to see if they're
you know if they're predicting the the
patterns that they're seeing on the
chemotype front
so all of that uh is soon to come needs
to be built
well excellent it's very exciting a lot
of work to be done
um before i let you go is there any
social media or
websites that you want to plug to make
sure that people can keep up with you
uh well obviously medicinal genomics uh
has
a lot of what we're doing um you can
follow us on either facebook instagram
twitter
um i'm occasionally on linkedin but
um those are the areas that uh that
we've been posting a lot of this content
on
um a lot of credit obviously going to
seth's group for
helping us get to get the initial
reference sequence and then um there's a
lot of the sport providers have been
that
been helping as well the group at uh
inoculate the world has
been very supportive in getting us
information on this um
and you'll probably see more of this
getting
some attention with the high science
group that's going to be
coming through here to take a look at
canmed and all the work that we're doing
here so
that's another another plug for those
folks it's safe to assume that your kmid
presentation this year will be on this
topic yeah we'll have some detail on
this as well yes we're going to probably
go through these 80 genomes and whenever
we've discovered by
uh september and um you know we're also
doing some very interesting
stuff on the cannabis front so they'll
probably be some some
virus material there that we're working
toward and a lot of the work we're doing
with aoc
all of this actually was a project um
that got kick-started because we were
sequencing so many genomes for aoec
to look at these yeast mold tests like
what's actually growing on these things
and we got kind of depressed because
we're constantly focused on like the
pathogens the things that hurt people
and
that's giving fungi a bad rap they're
not always hurting people so we said why
don't we throw on the same aluminum runs
some uh
some of these things that help people um
just so we're not always running out
there yelling
you know chicken little in the field
with with dangerous pathogens the world
needs to remember that actually a lot of
these fungi are beneficial
and particularly for growing cannabis
getting the root systems like
interacting with some of these things is
really important so
just to spice it up a little bit we
wanted to make sure we weren't out there
being chicken little and fungi and that
there's a fungi in the same runs that
were
quite beneficial so these ended up being
fillers for aluminum runs
and so you'll see kanmed um
we will be equal opportunity in fungi
we'll show the bad ones in the good ones
excellent well looking forward to seeing
that presentation out in pasadena and
thanks for joining us again all right
thanks man appreciate it
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
kevin mckernan
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor the
future of psychedelic medicine campaign
which you can read july 22nd in the new
scientist magazine
and on healthawareness.com.uk
our next episode will drop july 21st
that's two weeks from today and if you
are listening to this
on july 7th please go to
canmanevents.com now
and secure early bird pricing on your
full conference pass
the prices only go up from here so don't
miss this chance to secure
your canmed ticket at a great price
follow us on social media we're on
facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter and if
you're listening to us
on your podcast app please rate and
subscribe
we always appreciate it alright until
next time please stay safe stay healthy
and come back for the next canmed coffee
[Music]
talk
you