[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben ameralt i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
now
to learn all about our canmed 2021 event
which will take place september 29th
through october 1st
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
just last week we added new presenters
and panels to
our schedule we also rearranged the
order of some of our presentations and
panels
so that each of our focus areas gets a
dedicated time to shine
on our main stage while you're at
camminevents.com don't forget to
purchase your canmed
2021 ticket although the early bird
deadline has come and gone
you can still save by purchasing your
tickets in advance
plus you can check something off your
to-do list and that's always a good
thing
and if september can't come soon enough
for you
we do have a few things that can hold
you over in the meantime
first is our canmed archive which is a
searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels
you can find the canmed archive on
canmedevents.com
just click the banner on our home page
we also have the canmed community
facebook group
where you can interact with other
cannabis science enthusiasts
who share relevant articles papers
videos photos
memes podcasts you know all the stuff
you love about facebook
go to facebook and search
canmedcommunity to join the group
or use the link in the show description
i also want to remind everyone that the
healthcare provider study
we are doing with the cannabis center of
excellence is still ongoing
if you are a health care provider please
take a few minutes to complete the
survey
to help us better understand medical
cannabis knowledge
attitudes and practices among health
care providers in the u.s and canada
as an added incentive one lucky
participant
will win a k med 2021 practicum
and full conference ticket the link to
access that survey
is in the show description our guest
this episode is dr
jeffrey raber ceo of the workshop
an independent testing lab established
in 2010
dr raber is trained as an organic
chemistry scientist
but he is also a serial entrepreneur
patent inventor
and executive with over a decade of
experience
in cannabis testing at kmed 2018
dr raber presented cannabis compositions
viewed through molecular glasses
which you can view on our canmed archive
page
at 2021 dr raber will present
thermal degradation a fly and the
cannabis vapor ointment
which explores how the act of heating
cannabis oils for vaping
can alter certain molecules and how that
information can be applied to testing
regulations
we discuss what we have learned from the
vaping crisis and how those lessons are
being applied
what additives pose a threat to vape
users
the lasting appeal of vaping products in
terms of convenience
and consistency how inconsistencies and
vaping hardware play a role
how cannabis vape products differ from
nicotine
products the challenges and limitations
of testing
equipment and methods and signs
consumers can look for
when evaluating the safety and quality
of vape
products before we get to my
conversation
with dr raber i would like to thank this
episode sponsor
agilent technologies whether you
manufacture or test cannabis you face
the challenge
of delivering high quality products
increasing sample volume
and meeting emergent regulations agilent
offers best in class cannabis and hemp
analysis solutions
featuring robust instruments software
services
and consumables their team of experts
can develop
implement and optimize methods to get
you up and running quickly
to learn more check out agilent.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation
with dr jeffrey raber
[Music]
good afternoon jeff thanks for joining
us thanks for having me ben
appreciate the opportunity absolutely
okay so we're talking about
uh vaping cannabis with you today um
you're going to be doing a presentation
at canmed2021
titled thermal degradation a fly and the
cannabis
vapor ointment um first can you give us
a little bit of a
for for those of us who aren't chemists
in the
in the room here or on the or listening
on the podcast here what do we mean by
thermal degradation and how does that
apply to vaping cannabis
sure that's a great place to start how
do the molecules change upon heating
and degradation usually means breaking
apart
or changing or becoming something other
than what you started with
so degradation i think is usually looked
at in a negative context but it's not
always negative it could be that it
broke down into its starting components
and there really wasn't that big a
problem with it
so would i be correct in assuming that a
simple
example of this would be thc a breaking
down to
thc when it's um when it's heated or
combusted
sure the decarboxylation process would
definitely be a you know a thermal
change right you heat it up and you
liberate
co2 to you know change the acid to the
neutral compound
so and there is a great example of
degradation
technically not being maybe a
deleterious or bad thing
so um good example for sure okay good
glen i'm on the right track
all right but let's step back for a
minute here um and i imagine the
inspiration for
doing the the research that you've done
into looking at
you know how these compounds break down
in vaping has something to do with the
i guess we'll call it the vape crisis of
2019 where a great number of people are
getting sick from
contaminated vape products so
let's talk a bit about that um what was
the cause
for that do we think and um how has
how have vape products kind of changed
since then
sure um i think you know right out of
the gate everyone was questioning what
may have been the cause
and being you know having the benefit of
time now i think we're all able to look
at it and
pretty concretely say we believe it was
vitamin e acetate
was the culprit in that respects um
there was some other conjecture that
maybe there were heavy metals
and things of that type that might have
caused some of those cases
but um i heard last week in a vape panel
someone commented
from the audience they said they were
doing some studies and they've
always done trace metal analysis and
they concretely can say that they
don't believe it came from heavy metals
now even though we're going to see
colorado require
you know heavy metal analysis of things
coming up next year
like i think we're seeing the regulators
react to this
concern and mostly in rightful ways
right i have no problem
studying the metals thinking like let's
really be aware of that that's not a
problem so we don't encourage it or
allow it to happen
but i think we can all say we've got a
pretty solid handle
on it with being vitamin e acetate and
that it broke down
upon certain temperatures which are
rather high temperatures and i think
there's an important point to be made
there
it broke down into a very reactive
molecule called ketene
and this molecule then was reacting
rapidly and adversely with the long
lining
so it wasn't um anything that had been
found
in cannabis this was an additive that
was put into these vape cards
predominantly
in markets with no testing um you know
most likely the illicit markets i think
was the high prevalence of this
to give the appearance of a thicker oil
and
when you don't have testing to verify
that that thickness wasn't coming from
thc um
it was a visual representation so they
said
like how fast do i see a bubble go from
one side to the other if i flip the vape
cart 180 degrees
and that was kind of the visual test you
know on
passing along the supply chain without a
tested label
so we didn't see this problem in
regulated markets
as nearly as much we didn't see that
because everyone was pushing the potency
numbers higher and
required testing to put it on the label
you know would tell you hey this was
40 or 50 thc was not 70 or 80 that
everyone was aiming for
that visual trickery was what was you
know
being at play there and was used vitamin
e acetate to get there
and i think you know we the first
assumption was vitamin e
you know everyone kind of familiar with
that one vitamin e acetate
generally recognized as safe for
cosmetic and topical use
and i think that there's a big word of
caution there
you know just because it's safe for a
specific type of use does not mean
it's safe in other types of uses so
while it's fine to rub it on my skin
it was not fine to put it inside of a
vape device
and i'll i'll kind of highlight that
temperature piece you know
at what temperature does this break down
to form
the problematic ketem it's rather high
temperatures
like 500 degrees celsius so it's
interesting that you
see this and it makes you think it's not
only chemistry
and formulation that's at play but also
the hardware device
you know how hot does the hardware
device get are there
localized hotspots across the heating
element you know
what really do all the molecules feel in
terms of
temperature or thermal profile from the
devices
and how might we need to regulate both
the hardware
componentry and the construction of
those and its performance
in addition to which formulations and
molecules you put in there
okay all right a lot to lots of unpack
there
good question right yeah no it's all
good stuff
so going back to vitamin e acetate um i
think you sort of already answered this
but i'll ask again
so was it known that that would be
potentially harmful
kind of before this event if it were in
a vape
uh product or was this sort of an
enlightening event that
kind of revealed that i don't think it
was known and i don't think it was even
suspected
um so it kind of was you know alarming
and enlightening in the same
uh regard like wow that can happen and
why did it happen
in this case and i know there were some
others saying but
wait we think we've been using vitamin e
acetate for a while in this respects and
we haven't seen the problem
and i think that then ties to you know
how one
we don't know how prevalent it was being
used but we believe it was you know
rather prevalent and then two did every
single user that was experiencing that
have the problem or was it related to
the hardware that was actually
you know getting really really hot was
it a certain hardware and combination of
vitamin acetate that caused that problem
i think that question still remains um
but you know i think there's good reason
to suspect
it was related to specific hardware with
the use of that
so i think others would say they had
been using it and didn't see the problem
or it was unbeknownst to them right
maybe it was still happening but it
wasn't reported it wasn't tracked it
wasn't in the news and you just never
linked it to that case um so i think
it's
difficult to always know like you know
what was the
the problematic component there how
might we suspect that this is coming
but it is important that we now know it
that we apply that to
other things that are coming and i
wanted to be sure to try and highlight
the rise of the acetates so vitamin e
acetate is a phenolic acetate
and other acetates that may be present
might impart flavor
and other pieces they're known to
cannabis
not every acetate will have this same
fate
but the phenolic acetates will be able
to break down at this temperature to
cause ketene you need the phenol
group to kind of support the chemistry
of how that transformation happens
thc acetate you know delta 9 delta 8 thc
acetates
um those products are starting to you
know and even cbd acetate could do the
same type of thing
because those are phenolic structures in
the core components of the cannabinoid
that would be acetylated as well and you
might see the same chemistry going on
with that
so we've i've started to see in the last
few weeks you know delta 9 thc acetate
becoming more popular
and i'm really concerned that we might
see valley types of results for
the use of some of those products as
well and i think
in general we should say look let's err
on the side of caution
these thc acetates weren't produced by
the plant they're not found in the plant
that probably is a great line of
demarcation to say let's
stay away from those molecules until
they're formally studied
and they're really looked at and
understood from a toxicology perspective
to say
should we have those in these devices or
be able to use it in a dab or anything
else of that type
that class of compounds it's it's kind
of like
what we know from cigarette world and
other worker exposures of
diketones the diacetyl compound is known
to impart a buttery creamy flavor
but it's also known to provide popcorn
lung to those that are over exposed to
it so this was a very popular flavoring
over half the components in the nicotine
space in 2016
had this compound but it's now been a
banned class of molecules you're like
you don't want those things because they
may form
this type of problem and i think we need
to think of phenolic acetates
in the same way because we saw this with
vitamin e acetate
we don't want delta 9 or delta 8 or cbd
acetates
to be used in inhalation without fuller
like more fully
formal studies on them to really be sure
how to best use them that way
okay so what would be the benefit of
using an acetate form of the compound
rather than
a non-acetate form like as a as a
manufacturer as a consumer is there a
benefit to that
i don't think there's a significant
benefit in this regard so
some sometimes you see these they're
called pro drugs so that you know maybe
their absorptivity is a little better
they get more into different places in
the body than you
you know may be able to live them
deliberate orally whereas before you
weren't having that
actually be absorbed um you see pro-drug
formulations and stuff
in the pharmaceutical space all the time
it also opens
up patentability um you know it's
another molecule so i might have a
reason to kind of go down that path
in this case i think they're looking at
it more from a regulatory perspective
like hey it's a different molecule
that's not
um maybe outlawed or banned if it's not
delta eight if i made it in acetate is
that something that the legal language
hasn't caught up with
but physiologically speaking you know
there's not
perhaps a great deal of advantage to
using that it's typically
meant from formulation and absorptivity
we know we get thc in us pretty well
right we i don't see the advantage there
we've formulated it in tons of products
that doesn't seem to be a big you know
advantage in that respects
i think some of the manufacturers are
trying to
amplify a message saying the
physiological effects
are bigger and better but i'm not
hearing anyone substantiating that so i
don't know if that's more marketing
speak to say
hey you know like hey come buy this and
try it but
you know i think we should err on the
side of caution and say well someone
clinically study that
show me blood data that proves that this
would give me those responses
and maybe the form that it's best in is
an oral dosed form and it might be very
helpful in that respects
but it it doesn't have the ability to be
made manufactured cheaper
and it's you know gonna definitely not
be as cost effective
and physiologically i'm struggling to
find why that would be advantageous
so you mentioned earlier that some of
the regulations are changing
around testing vape products where do
those stand now and where do you kind of
see that
they might be going so colorado took a
good lead in saying let's understand the
heavy metals that are coming out of the
device
um other some states require like end
product testing so you'll say
you know one state would say test the
oil before you put it in the vape device
others will say hey test the oil once
it's been in the vape device and
packaged and we'll take that
that might be able to catch a little bit
more of the leaching but it's not the
same as when you're using it of course
we see more and more states saying let's
see what components are going into these
inhalable formulations
they're not necessarily requiring
testing for that other than
test for the presence of vitamin e
acetate and assure me there's none
in there and some are starting to add
like squalane squalene and a few other
components to that list
so colorado again it said no mct
no peg in pg and no
vitamin acetate and some states are
saying you know you might have to test
to prove that vitamin e acetate is not
present
but we're not seeing a tremendous amount
of
you know outlawing or requiring a lot of
testing for
different molecules in vape devices but
we are seeing regulators starting to say
okay what are we putting in there
disclose to me your formulation
all the ingredients how much of these
things you're using
um and then let us know and some states
are also saying
put this list of molecules in the
package for the consumers to have access
to
um which i i think is is nice and
interesting
but some of these you know big chemistry
words people just give me like
whatever you know i think it's kind of
like a package insert on your
pharmaceutical product i don't know how
many folks read all of those
if you have trouble sleeping it might be
good to start reading some of that stuff
it can be very technical very you know
it's very informative
but only to someone that may be trained
in a lot of those technical words
um and if you cherry pick you know like
one molecule and say hey look i found
this one in here
it's not just the molecule but the
concentration and exactly how much would
be
you know introduced to the individual
during normal course of use
i think that's another interesting
challenge with cannabis you might have
someone that takes one or two puffs of
their vape device a day
all the way to the other extreme where
someone consumed an entire gram
um you know the entire cartridge in a
day so
what's the exposure limits and use
regimes that we have with that
much like we want to say we want to put
a ceiling on the temperature so that
we know these devices aren't going over
the temperature
should we guide users to say like hey
we've kind of looked at like normal use
would be
you know this range if you're going over
that you might see other problems we're
not aware of
and how do we then start to track those
types of things too
but this is a enormously complex
and multifaceted problem from you know
hardware to formulation to toxicology
to what chemistry changes are happening
in these types of things so it's it's
going to be a little while till i think
we start to get a better handle on some
of it
yeah i mean i was going to ask you about
that specifically the hardware
um i have to imagine that the different
heating elements in different ways
in different products could you know
really be a variable that'd be hard to
control for
exceptionally so and even some uses
right if you
you know see the the wick that that is
no longer really present anymore but if
it wasn't wetted and it was dry
like that could be all of a sudden
getting much hotter before the oil melts
onto those things
some of the heating platforms might have
the same effect
so what's the material of construction
of those are they ceramic is it touching
any other metals
um what else may be in or not in the
glass
chamber is it even a glass chamber um
there are
a lot of components that are wetted or
in touch
with the the oil and the formulation in
a vape device
so it becomes you know a lot more
challenging in that respects now
they're not all at the same temperature
right the outside of the chamber is very
different than what's on the heating
element
which is very different than what's on
the very tip that's at actually at my
mouth and my airway
and i think trying to get a better
handle on that is really a difficult
challenge in its own right too
yeah do you foresee that there might be
some standards that
need to be uh put in place for for the
hardware so that it is more consistent
i think so i mean i i think that might
be one of the things coming down the
path
we we're going to learn a little more
about hardware and some of these things
from the fda and the tobacco space right
as they're all now going about
registering these things i think we'll
start to say
okay like these types of hardware were
able to get through the gauntlet
and are acceptable with these
formulations and that
might cause like a de facto
manufacturing
standard because they're going to want
to make much the same components or same
devices so you say look if these are the
ones getting through
then i'll start applying you know my
manufacturing effort elsewhere i've got
economies to scale and now i can offer
it cheaper
um there are differences though from
when you're looking at in the nicotine
space versus the cannabinoid space you
know cannabis
is more oily it has different components
in there it needs different temperatures
to vaporize the mixtures
so we'll learn some but not everything
but there are groups you know like astm
and some other groups that are trying to
be forward-looking and
start to establish some standards for
formulations and componentry of the
hardware
so i think it won't be too long until we
get at least a starting point in that
respect
um and then hopefully we can have many
labs starting to study those
to say hey look here's what we're seeing
across the board on
four or five different hardware devices
not just the one that i i picked for
myself
[Music]
yeah so i was wondering if you could you
could talk a bit about the research that
you've done
um what did those experiments look like
what were some of the
results you found so we started from
looking at you know just the terpene
formulation and what might be
uh problematic in its analysis so it's
it's really easy to say hey look here's
this terpene formulation
and i know there's nothing in there
that's not supposed to be but why is it
failing for a residual solvent
and it was much harder to actually go
about trying to understand
where that might be forming when it was
present to eliminate all the potential
sources of external contamination from
the lab
and to really start to find out that it
is caused by
temperature in the presence of air so
when you start to understand
you know oxygen is the enemy of
degradation it is actually the one that
catalyzes a lot of these problems
we see oxidative degrading they can then
form allergens they can form other
products
well if i start to form a residual
solvent and i'm failing a residual
solvent test
then the products can't go to market you
can see it to a greater extent with the
neat terpene formulation so you can
start to understand
okay when i have only these ingredients
in this mixture
and i put it inside the headspace
analysis what am i starting to detect
why am i detecting more than just these
components
it starts to make you think well at
certain temperatures i see this and i
can accelerate that if i raise the
temperature
and what else might be showing up in
that regard
is generated predominantly by oxygen in
that case
so in these studies you know air was the
enemy
and you probably have a little bit of
air in your vape device too but we
didn't have
any external metals or any other like
hardware components that might be
present inside of the vape device either
so the molecules weren't sitting on you
know this wetted surface that was
hitting that temperature
with this metal catalyst perhaps and in
the presence of air
it really was just the molecules
themselves in air in a glass vial
um and you could still see some break
down into a couple of the residual
solvent components that that might
like make you wonder why they're there
they're not at alarming levels
and this is a neat formulation so these
things are always used in 10
or less in the vape devices so we're not
even sure if you'll see them
outside of the vape device while they
may be there they may not be detectable
depending upon the actual limits that
are in there
um so it raised the concern of like what
temperatures
under what conditions do you start to
see these things
um and really i think you start to see
them as you raise the temperature and
definitely in the presence of oxygen
then it raises the question of well what
else might accelerate those types of
um those degradation pathways so
would the hardware component do it or do
i see something
otherwise because of the hardware
component tree as well
so am i understanding this correctly
that the actual
terpenes or cannabinoids in the oil are
breaking down
to resemble residual solvents or
are the residual solvents in some cases
no like they are definitely
solvent free when you get them and when
you test them the right way you can say
like i'm seeing none of these but if you
you know put it in the presence of
oxygen and heat it up too much
you can start to see one of the residual
solvents predominantly acetone
um so it's not a significant concern and
certainly at super low levels so from a
toxicology perspective
it's not alarming but from a perhaps
regulatory perspective of like oh great
are people going to
fail their regulatory checks once it's
in the final packaging
and then why would they fail it who
would they be blaming you know who's
responsible for those things
are the limits for the regulatory line
set at an appropriate level and or does
this just need to kind of
help educate labs into setting them up
in different fashions so they run the
test without
generating that problem so this is much
an analytical problem
um probably more so of that that what
we've kind of worked through than it was
um worrying about a toxicology problem
but it does start to make you think
about these degradation pathways and
what else might you start to see
especially when you couple it with
vitamin e acetate and you start to know
that there are you know deleterious
degradations
of some of the molecules interesting
and i'll just like like maybe i'll throw
it out there to everyone else
when you combust cannabis right we know
how much thc you have on the flower
material
but our study that we had done i think
it's 2015 like we can only find
40 plus percent of the actual thc
molecule
so looking everywhere at the smokestream
the
side streams inside the rest of the
combusted plant material that was there
like capture everything possible i don't
know where the rest of it went
right it didn't all become cbn it breaks
down into many different things
so if you look at combustion analysis of
plant material
you see some of these same um you know
residual solvent pieces like acetone
that's known to form just from the plant
materials because these components will
break down like that
but when you look at a combustion
analysis you see many many many many
more
molecules that actually form the
question is what's their concentration
and with cannabis or the good molecules
greatly overwhelming any potential
concerns
i think we've known people to be
combusting cannabis for long periods of
time and we don't see deleterious
toxicological outcomes from that so the
molecules
present in cannabis are not nearly as
much of a concern even at combustion
temperatures
as something that's a brand new additive
like vitamin e acetate
so i think you know that's where you got
to start to say like we're never going
to know this problem tomorrow like we're
not going to have all the answers
tomorrow it's so big and complex
how do we step safely today with some
sort of sense of comfort especially if
i'm a regulator that's tasked with
protecting public health and safety
and even a responsible you know provider
of brands how do we do this
we think that it's best if you stick to
what we know in the plant already
so if those things are modeled after the
plant that they
you know are closest to those
formulations they're in similar
concentrations and ratios
then you have a little bit more you know
comfort level with a from a
toxicological perspective
to say well people have been combusting
these molecules for a long time
and we haven't seen them you know really
with like alarming outcomes
so unless there's something uniquely
being catalyzed or the temperature is
way higher than we think in some of
these vape devices
we're probably going to be you know in a
decent realm
at least one that we can be comfortable
enough with today while we embark on the
further study
and you know how long have people been
using cannabis vape devices
is another key thing to think of 2013-14
i mean it's not like they just showed up
last week and we're
really having these problems so there's
been a lot of use
so far that we haven't seen you know a
valley in every single scenario
so it does inform us that hey we're
probably in a pretty comfortable realm
we're probably okay when we stick to the
molecules that are in cannabis
but we should be very careful if we
choose to step outside of what's there
because we don't have a body of
knowledge with that and we might see the
unexpected
and that can be catastrophic like we
learned in 2019
yeah and that's a great point and the
fact that
you know these products have been around
for a number of years and
it doesn't seem like they're going to go
anywhere either because there's a lot of
advantages to their
to their appeal right in terms of the
convenience of being discreet
and you know just being something that
people can enjoy
um and even consistency and
standardization
right so if i can make that formulation
consistent
if i can have a solid hardware component
tree that's made the same every time
then i can give a patient something that
they know they can you know i get my
response that's required off two or
three puffs
depending on the day and what else might
be going on it's maybe it's not every
single one but i get a rapid response
you know i can really use that to
titrate myself and i can look at it
more like a medical delivery platform
than you know highly variable plants or
something that somebody keeps calling
the same name
and i you know every time i get a
different blue dream experience with
somebody please
stop doing that to me you know i think
cannabis patients really
struggle to find something that works
but if you can make it consistently and
then they find that it works for them
then that's fantastic there's nothing
more cruel to me of saying here this
worked once but i'm never going to give
it to you again
even though i'll label it the same so i
think they you know
they shouldn't go away they represent a
really like strong
position for standardization and for
real
you know all the other beneficial uses
that you said but in addition
patients can greatly benefit from the
use of these devices
when made well um and i think that's
what we really need to strive for
and set those standards accordingly yeah
that's a great point
um and i think that your your call to
kind of stick to
the components of the plant and not
not be adding additives to it and kind
of introducing
these different variables makes a lot of
sense but what about you know adding
in additional terpenes to kind of create
a different profile a different flavor
are there concerns with doing that or
you know is there certain limits that
should be placed on you know the
concentrations of those
terpenes a huge word to a chemist like
myself right there's like tens of
thousands of those
unknown on the planet um we know maybe
150 of them
inside of cannabis so again if they're
found in cannabis we've seen some of
their uses we understand what their
concentrations are in that um and we
stick within that relative ballpark
i feel pretty good about that but taxol
is a terpene
and you know that's cytotoxic right it's
a great anti-cancer agent but i wouldn't
want anyone trying to put that in a vape
device because they thought it was
another terpene
so you know that word is very broad to
chemists and maybe to others that are
looking there now if i'm
playing with you know botanical terpenes
or sourced differently
um molecules a molecule as long as that
is that molecule it's the right one at
the right purities
then i have no concerns with that as
long as again it's at the right
concentration so too much like high
terpene extracts
may even be kind of problematic because
too much of those things
the plant makes them to kind of keep
things away like it might become an
irritant to some folks it could irritate
the airways
again oxidative pathways for degradation
of those might cause some of them to be
allergens or really irritating
so there's a fine balance and a realm
there too
we might find that there's some that we
want to remove as opposed to
putting in there so having the ability
to kind of tailor which ones you use
might be very very advantageous
especially to certain populations
but you know terpenes from cannabis or
found in cannabis from other sources
even i i feel pretty comfortable with
that
but if you start to grab like you know
some unbeknownst terpene from somewhere
else because you think it drives a
unique effect
well then we might have other problems
especially if it was something that was
never heated and inhaled before
excellent all right winding down here i
was wondering
is there anything consumers can look for
in products
that can kind of help them determine um
safety
quality or anything like that so they
can maybe
kind of avoid some of these pitfalls
until we kind of really figure out what
the regulations or what the standards
should be
it's probably going to be different in
different states you know some states
will
already have been putting rules in place
but i think we'll see more of them catch
up and evolve their rules to do so too
like say
what's in the product you know are these
components found in cannabis or not
what might their concentrations be which
i can infer from the thc concentration
or the cbd concentration of the product
um what does my brand or producer
tell me about their quality how
transparent are they
what are they trying to demonstrate to
me
you know what do i see on the label of
the packaging like those types of things
you kind of got to look at it
holistically like each part of it is
going to be a little bit of a clue
but i think that along with standardized
or consistent products
being generated if i can consistently
output the same thing
i'm probably watching my quality very
consistently to make sure i'm doing that
and i'm probably more minded towards
being careful of what i'm putting in the
products
so i think you know ask the brands ask
the producers ask those that are
providing the products and see what kind
of answers you get
um you know it might not always be on
the label or in the package
but most of them are pretty engaged with
consumers especially via social media so
you can kind of see hey they're trying
to tell me the right things
you know do i really know well if i'm
going to use this product for the next
five years maybe it's worth me sending
one to the lab and paying a couple
hundred bucks to go find out myself
every lab that i know of will be happy
to to work with an individual
at pretty reasonable prices to say like
yeah if you want to
check your consistency or you want to
know that this one's fine
most all of them will do that too so
that's a little bit more extreme and a
little more costly because i know even
the products can be expensive for
patients
but you could go to that extreme if you
wanted to
excellent all right before i let you go
i wanted to give you a chance to
plug any social media websites any
any any any and everything you'd like to
share with the audience so they can get
in touch with you or follow up with what
you're working on
sure um the workshop
t-h-e-w-e-r-c-s-h-o-p
um we have our website.com it's all over
social media
instagram linkedin things of that type
um mine's at dr jeff raber you can find
me
on instagram mostly that way i don't
post much but i i do respond to folks if
they write to me
and certainly more than happy to receive
emails to
jeff at theworkshop.com as well but yeah
feel free to reach out and follow along
there whichever way might be
best to your liking all right excellent
thanks again jeff for joining us and
can't wait to see you about in pasadena
thank you again for the opportunity ben
i appreciate it look forward to seeing
you in pasadena as well
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr jeffrey raber
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsor agilent
technologies
our next episode drops august 18th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime go to cannemedevents.com
to check out our canmed archive
go to facebook and join our canmed
community group
like our canmed page follow us on
instagram
linkedin and twitter and if you're
listening on
a podcast app please do rate and
subscribe we always appreciate the
support
alright until next time please stay safe
stay healthy
and we'll see you on the next canmed
coffee talk
do
[Music]
you