[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
ok
you probably already know by now but
after careful evaluation of the current
situation in los angeles county and the
restrictions and requirements that would
have been necessary to hold canmed 2021
in september
our management team has made the
difficult decision to reschedule the
event from may 3rd through 5th
this was not an easy decision to make
it's been almost two years since we had
a live canmed event
but everyone including the conference
organizers our sponsors and the
presenters strongly believe that in
order for canmed to be a success it must
take place in a comfortable
collaborative environment
and that's just not possible during
these uncomfortable and restrictive
times
so we will press on
we will continue to bring you new
podcasts every other week we will
continue to interact with the canmed
community on our facebook group and we
will continue to share all the great
canmed presentation videos that are in
our free searchable canmed archive on
all of our social media channels
you can find links to all those great
resources in the show description
and also if you have not signed up for
email alerts yet you really should that
is the best way to stay up to date with
all the updates around the canmed
conference delivered right to your inbox
alright with that news out of the way
let's get back to the podcast our guest
this episode is justin bueno
justin is the scientific director of
goodness growth holdings inc and since
joining the company in 2018 dr bueno has
published two peer-reviewed articles in
the field of cannabis science
one article published in the journal of
cannabis research described the
validation and the science behind the
novel terp safe packaging system
towards the preservation of terpenes in
cannabis flower
that article will be the basis for his
presentation at canmed 2022
titled the preservation and augmentation
of terpenes and cannabis inflorescence
my conversation with dr bueno is all
about terpenes including how terpenes
contribute to cannabis effects in
overall quality
why using thc potency as an indicator of
quality is short-sighted
the difference between terpenes and
terpenoids
how the terpene profile of cannabis
flower can change over time as molecules
evaporate
the inconsistency of terpene
concentrations from flower to flower
within the same batch
and how the new terp safe technology is
addressing terpene preservation and
batch consistency
before we get to my conversation with
justin i would like to thank this
episode's sponsor cannasafe
cannasafe is a california-based cannabis
analytical testing lab paving the way in
the industry through research
education and social equity efforts
championing safe and effective cannabis
hemp and cbd for all one test at a time
learn more at csalabs.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with justin bueno
[Music]
good morning justin thanks for joining
us on the podcast
hey ben thank you so much for having me
all right i'm excited to talk with you
today about a topic that i'll admit i
have a bit of a love-hate relationship
with and that's terpenes
i say that because i think terpenes are
are truly fascinating compounds for
reasons i know that we're going to get
into in this conversation but i still
feel like the average consumer out there
is very unaware of terpenes has that
been your experience as well
oh absolutely
um
you know there's a focus right now in
the cannabis industry to look at thc
content which is obviously critically
important
but
terpenes are relatively
under considered when looking at the
whole phytochemical composition
especially for
newer patients
as markets are continuing to
open up for both
medicinal and recreational applications
as additional legislation is passing
there's an increased increase in the
patient base
and
to your point
with this increase in patient base we
also need to improve patient education
and talk about
different phytochemicals in the plant
outside of cannabinoids
yeah and it's interesting you say that
because i just recently saw an article i
think it was on weed maps and maybe i'll
put a link in the show description so
people can read it as well
and it was all about
the author was making the case that we
need to kind of break this idea that the
highest
potency the high or the highest thc
cannabis flower is the best quality
cannabis flower and that you know that's
only looking at this one cannabinoid one
specific cannabinoid where you should
really be looking at the full breadth of
the other cannabinoids and of course the
terpenes as well to really gauge your
quality or the experience that you're
having with that so
um would you agree that the industry is
still really kind of stuck in that
thc
potency number more than anything else
yeah it's a great point and you can kind
of understand where
this tribe originates from so if a
patient's at a dispensary looking at
different label claims for cannabis
flour or
extract products
if they see a higher thc reported value
for one product they associate that with
improved efficacy for treating their
disease state you know if it's
looking at pain management or a variety
of other conditions
you can see where
you know they'd make the correlation
with higher thc content improved
efficacy
but uh you know to what i talked about
previously
um you know the whole
phytochemical composition of the plant
really contributes to this efficacy
across treating a variety of disease
states
and when you talk about product quality
that's a really interesting
attribute because especially experienced
cannabis users
when we're talking about flour
specifically
really associate the aroma
and flavor of cannabis with product
quality
and as we can get into
we know that terpenes are the main
driving force behind this characteristic
aroma and flavor of cannabis flower
so terpene content is critically
important
for
both the perceived or actual product
quality and
as
research has shown there's also
interesting medicinal
recreational and what we can talk about
entourage effects
associated with terpene content and
terpene profiles
yeah it's a great point and another
point that was made in this article was
this idea that
the
the chemo type information for a
cannabis flower it's all based on
percent right so if you're if you have a
very high percentage of thc then
it makes sense to think that you're
going to have a lower percentage of
those terpenes so even though you might
have a high thc flower it might be
relatively lower
in those beneficial terpenes for quality
aroma or even effect
yeah it's a great point so
there's a couple interesting discussion
points around this question first
cannabinoids and terpenes
have shared biosynthetic pathways in the
plant
so
at some stage there's a precursor that
has to be
it can only be sent towards synthesizing
a cannabinoid or synthesizing for
example a mono terpene so there may be
some type of competition there where
depending upon what the plant wants to
make
you may drive cannabinoid production
which would relatively reduce
terpene content
so that would be one
uh hypothesis
to look at that relationship however
kind of in my role at goodness growth
holdings
we do some interesting
fundamental r d on the cannabis plant
and one project we just completed was
looking at
uh different fertilization
schedules
and their impact on
the subsequent
phytochemical content of flour
after harvest
and we found that um
and it may kind of seem like common
sense the healthier the plant the higher
content
of all phytochemicals you'll get in the
resulting flower
so
that kind of
is another aspect of that relationship
where you're
getting different ratios of cannabinoids
or terpenes but in general plant health
overall may drive an increase in both uh
phytochemical classes
yeah well that's really interesting i
didn't realize that cannabinoids and
terpenes may
share sort of a precursor molecule that
is that is used to synthesize both did i
understand that correct
you are correct
um
so it's a couple
um biosynthetic pathways
are required to make both cannabinoids
and terpenes and one of the earlier
um
reactions
the same precursor is required for both
uh
cannabinoids and terpenes
wow that's really that's really
interesting so before before we move on
to more of the the nitty gritty science
sciencey stuff in terms of terpenes and
kind of the organic chemistry and all
those things just before we leave behind
maybe some of the folks who aren't as
well-versed in terpenes i know that
sometimes my mom listens to this podcast
and we would totally leave her in the
dust are there is there sort of a high
level or kind of cliff notes
version of what people should understand
about terpenes so that they can get the
most out of their cannabis experience
sure
so terpenes are part of a class
called terpenoids more generally
that are one of the most prominent
class of plant secondary metabolites
found in nature so what is a plant
secondary metabolite so it's a molecule
that the plant synthesizes that is not
required for
its day-to-day function or its life
cycle it's used in uh
subsequent
interactions either
in ecology in nature maybe it's a
molecule that would attract
some kind of insect that could help
spread its pollen
or there may be other
evolutionary
basis for for wanting to produce this
molecule
so
terpenes or terpenoids
and that's an interesting thing that we
probably should define so generally
terpenoid
is a molecule
uh that contains an oxygen atom
and terpenes are um
within the same class but aren't oxygen
oxygenated so i'm going to use those
terms uh interchangeably or just
simplified for this podcast we can just
call them terpenes
um but that is one thing in the industry
where uh that's another kind of
definition that could confuse newer
patients
and is there
and
is there a difference in in effect if
you if you have one or the other or is
it just sort of
um different stages of
of that molecule within the life of the
plant
oh absolutely so
over 200 different terpenes have been
identified
in cannabis
so
when we're talking about the potential
pharmacology of these molecules
found in cannabis we actually have a
very broad scope of chemicals and that
results in a potentially broad
pharmacology
from each of these individual molecules
and you know some of the highlights
there's been numerous research articles
you can find online about pharmacology
of terpenes
but some of the highlights i like to
emphasize are you know they've been
shown to have anti-inflammatory
properties
antholytic which means anti-anxiety
analgesic
and antioxidant properties among others
and that last one i like to highlight
because
the fact that a terpene may have an
antioxidant property of course when a
patient consumes that terpene it may
protect
tissue in the body from free radical
damage
but it also
may protect
other phytochemicals
within the plant from oxidative
degradation so for example a really
interesting application would be what
do terpenes do to preserve cannabinoid
content in cannabis flower or
you know other uh cannabis based
formulations
that is interesting but just to go back
to the terpene versus terpenoids
distinction
um could you could you play that one
back and maybe we can explore that a bit
more sure
so terpenes are
part of a class a broader class called
terpenoids
and the
accepted definition in the industry
would be that a terpenoid
has an oxygen atom
as a part of the molecule and terpenes
are part of the same class
containing
a so-called isoprene unit
but without that oxygen atom so
if we may we take one step uh further up
the chain
so
terpenes are a part of a class call if
we really want to get into the yeah
let's do it or natural product chemistry
um
terpenes are part of a class called
isoprenoids so
an isopanoid contains a specific
chemical constituent called an isoprene
unit
and
the most prominent
terpenes found in cannabis are
monoterpenes which contain two isoprene
units and sesquiterpenes which contain
three isoprene units
and we can further
uh
differentiate these these classes
if we add an oxygen atom to them or
numerous oxygen atoms so oxygenated
terpenes are often referred to as
monoterpenoids
and oxygenated sesquiterpenes are also
often referred to as
sesqui terpenoids
but i think for simplicity um
you know you can refer to all terpenes
as just a terpene
got it so all the terpenes that we know
and love mercene limonene
beta-caryophyllene are they some kind of
combination of monoterpene
sesquiterpenes are they kind of all of a
similar class
yeah that's a great question so
each terpene is only going to belong to
one
terpene subclass
so for example mercying is a monoterpene
beta karyophylline is a sesquiterpene
and
those have slightly different
physical properties based upon their
differences in chemical structure and
that actually comes becomes important
when we talk about the stability of
these various terpenes
in uh formulations or flour and we get
into that i think a bit later
yeah
well let's do that now because
one of the things that's that's common
amongst all the terpenes is that they're
very volatile compounds correct and that
they're not
um
they're not staying around on the flower
for very very long that's one of the
reasons why we're smelling them right
they're com continually being
um emitted from the flower so i know
that a lot of your research has been
done on preserving the terpenes on the
flower so maybe we could talk a bit
about the strategies that you have come
up with
yeah ben you're exactly right so
like we mentioned before terpenes are
responsible for the characteristic aroma
and flavor of cannabis
and
um this is because they're inherently
volatile
are constantly evaporating from the
cannabis plant mixing with the air
and that uh provides us an opportunity
to spell them because uh we can access
um they can access our olfactory
receptors so it's kind of a double-edged
sword they smell amazing because they're
volatile but since they're volatile
they're
evaporating
from flower
and that causes a relative reduction in
concentration of terpenes and flour over
time
so
there are um
a couple parameters we should talk about
with the associated with the volatility
of terpenes first and foremost different
terpenes are going to have uh different
relative volatilities the smaller
terpenes or mono terpenes are more
susceptible to loss over time as
compared to the larger terpenes
sesquiterpenes
so
when a patient you know uses
flour on day one
they're going to have
one terpene profile on terpene content
and that may provide them
with a certain efficacy that they were
looking for
over time that not only is that profile
gonna change due to loss of terpene
content due to their inherent volatility
but the overall terpene content is also
going to be reduced so that's where the
loss and product quality is really
um
exaggerated over time due to the
volatility of terpenes and not only
product quality but potentially the
efficacy of the flower may change
towards treating different disease
states if we're changing the terpene
profile for example many monoterpenes
are associated with analgesic properties
so those are the terpenes that are
evaporating first you may not get that
same pain relief
from your cannabis flower on day i don't
know 30 as compared to day one
after purchase
so
um
you know what
it's important to try to understand this
from a scientific perspective about
what is the rate of loss of these
terpenes
and
um there's been some prior research
uh done on this so
dr asholi of course was ahead of the
game and published a paper in the 90s
um describing a 45 loss
of terpene content and cannabis flower
over a one month storage period
so
that that's a pretty quick loss almost
half of your terpenes are gone over one
month um
one month after purchase pretty much of
your of your package product
uh we also recently published a paper
that showed a similar result uh 50 of
the terpene content was lost after four
weeks of storage
and this does depend this rate of
degradation does kind of depend on a
couple factors environmental factors
including temperature
the terpene profile like i said if it's
if it's dominated by monoterpenes you're
more susceptible to a
faster
reduction in terpene content and kind of
the patient's
cadence of use of the product
so
the fundamental
reduction in terpene content from
cannabis flower comes from the fact that
terpenes are volatile and they evaporate
from the flower
and they'll fill the headspace
of the packaging that the flower is in
and when a patient goes to use that
flower they open up the container
and the terpenes that are in the
headspace are lost in the environment
so
um you know how often are the patient is
using flour
opening that opening and closing that
container will also affect the rate of
degradation
and i would i would imagine the method
of storage would would change that too
versus if you have it in a excuse me a
plastic bag versus a glass jar or
something like that
absolutely so
the
permeability of these terpenes through
different media may affect
the the rate of loss
something like glass you you wouldn't
expect terpenes to penetrate
that medium
whereas certain plastics they may be
able to
penetrate over time um
so yes i would agree with that
assessment
and you mentioned temperature as well
and i know that you know one of the
old-school ways of storing your cannabis
was to throw it in a freezer is that a
good strategy or no
yeah i mean it depends on the
application that you're
you're looking for
when we talk about
grower operators looking to obtain
a product such as live resin which would
mimic the phytochemical composition of
flour at the time of harvest they do
freeze that product immediately after
a harvest to preserve
that native terpene content at the time
of harvest um
so so that temperature is a
critical parameter in uh terpene
evaporation the hotter the temperature
the faster the terpenes will evaporate
and be lost from
all right so yeah let's let's talk a bit
about the research that you've done and
that you're going to be sharing at camed
2021 that's about
some novel technology that you have
developed to preserve and maybe even
reintroduce terpenes into flour do you
have that correct
yes we're very excited
at goodness growth
about our novel patent pending terp safe
technology so the origin of this product
was when we talked to
cultivators
they said that you know their biggest
fear is losing terpene content after
harvest they can cultivate the most
beautiful
cannabis flower with amazing
aromas and terpene profiles but after
harvest
they're susceptible to terpene loss and
of course there are things you can do
with drying and curing that kind of
reduce
um
terpene loss you know a slower lower dry
will preserve terpenes versus a hot
quick dry
but you know that that can only get you
so far once it's in the final package
product kind of like what we were
talking about before
terpenes will evaporate from the flower
and be lost the environment over time
so
uh with that in mind
we developed the
terp save technology
and the main principle behind it
is
if your patients are or excuse me if
your listeners are familiar with the
uh yeah maybe i'll take a step back
grab a drink
sure
so the main principle behind the terp
safe technology is the addition of
external or exogenous terpenes to the
packaging system and we feel that this
is a
meaningful
we feel that this is one of the first
meaningful improvements to cannabis
packaging in some time
so
the principle
is based on le chatelier's principle
if your listeners remember from general
chemistry
so terpenes are in an equilibrium
as far as the vapor stage
or
the solid stage
so the solid
solid stage terpenes are
a part of the cannabis flower and
they're in equilibrium evaporating and
condensing back on that cannabis flower
over time
with the turpsafe system we're adding
additional
vapor phase terpenes to the cannabis
packaging to drive terpenes back into
that solid phase of the cannabis flower
and in a peer-reviewed study we showed
that we can maintain the native terpene
content of cannabis flower for up to six
weeks
and we are continuing
to research this technology and we hope
to make additional claims in the future
about longer
storage durations
so not only does this maintain
the
product quality as far as the flavor and
aroma of cannabis flowers longer it
should also provide a more reliable
efficacy
from dose-to-dose or cannabis patients
as we are providing a more
reliable terpene profile
and content
independent upon many factors that can
cause variability in those two
parameters
so if i understand correctly then the
package itself is containing
terpenes that
that aid in sort of
keeping the the terpenes in the solid
stage so that they stay on the flower so
do you have to have the same terpene
profile in the package to match what the
flower has
yeah that's a great question so again it
depends on what application you're
looking at
so
one of the
basic applications for this technology
is to obtain a
terpene extract that mimics the profile
of your cannabis flower and that will
preserve that terpene profile longer as
compared to a
sample without terp save or control
another application that we're looking
at developing
is tuning the terpene profile
to achieve
specific
concentrations of various terpenes for
targeted disease states and this would
coincide with additional research
around terpene pharmacology but we're
really excited about that aspect from a
medicinal
or that application from a medicinal
aspect
yeah so in that case could you take
sort of a flower that's
where you know a lot of the the chirping
content has been evaporated off and then
sort of put it into this packaging and
reintroduce some terpenes into it
yeah that's a great question and that's
one of the experiments we report in the
peer-reviewed paper we rejuvenate
cannabis flower that was relatively
depleted of terpene content so i think
the flower had about point one percent
uh terpene so
almost
non-existent
um you know typically flour available
for
um
for consumption has about one to three
percent terpene content so you know
we're an order of magnitude below that
and using terp save we
uh
reinvigorated
or rejuvenated that terpene content uh
upwards of one percent so now we're
achieving
a terpene content suitable for
um pulmonary delivery
excellent and now is there sort of a a
limit to the amount of terpenes that you
can reintroduce into a flower like is
there just so much that it will
that it will
will take on
yes um and you can tune
uh
that value
by the amount of
uh external terpenes added to the
terpsafe system
so we found a linear relationship
between the amount of
external terpenes introduced and the
resulting
terpene content of the flower so this
would provide
grower processors with
a
application to
obtain cannabis flower with a specific
terpene content you know based upon uh
market and patient needs
excellent and so now what is the what is
the size of this packaging is this more
for you know wholesale large batches or
is this even down to like the individual
uh packaging that a consumer would would
take home
yeah that's a great question so
um we have launched terpsafe uh
nationally through licensing our
patentee bottles we can get that and we
can get into that in a little bit but
basically the
terp safe system
can be used at any
scale
packaging size
independent on on flower amount but for
our initial launch we have um
an all-in-one system where the turb safe
component is integrated directly into
the cap
of the cannabis packaging jar so
um i think the initial system is for 3.5
grams of canvas flour or eighth a pretty
common amount in the industry
but uh future iterations um
you know what it will be independent
upon
size
um
simply
for larger batches
uh you know for a grower processor who
wants to preserve uh terpene content
prior to packaging that material
you can just add a couple of these terp
safe components to larger amounts and
you get that same preservation that a
patient will experience in their
3.5 gram
container
excellent and now how many different
terpenes are you able to to use in this
system i know we mentioned that there
are there are over 200
um how many different ones are you able
to reintroduce or preserve
so we found in our initial study that
the system
was effective independent upon terpene
utilized
now the uh rate of
preservation
or infusion
may vary based upon
terpene utilized we found that the
monoterpenes are more volatile so they
offer a higher infusion rate
as compared to sesquiterpenes but in
principle
any terpene can be utilized in this
system that includes uh
terpenes derived from botanical
non-cannabis sources terpenes extracted
from cannabis plants can be reintroduced
to get that strain specific
terpene profile preservation and
even synthetic terpenes could be
utilized if the appropriate safety
considerations are
adhered to
wow well that's really that's really
fascinating
um
before i know we're kind of wrapping up
here but i i did want to touch on just
the difficulty of actually measuring
terpenes i know that something has come
up in
in conversations that i've had with
others who are kind of in the analytical
space or the the testing space
how difficult is it to test for for
terpenes specifically within the
cannabis matrix is that
um one of the reasons why maybe not a
lot of labs are testing for it and why
when we go to the dispensary we don't
always see terpene content
um on packaging
yeah as with any
botanically derived
samples there's going to be inherent
heterogeneity so there's going to be
variability across cannabis flower
you know even from the same location on
the cannabis plant
and like i mentioned
earlier in the talk
there are numerous sources that can
cause
variability in terpene profile and
terpene content and these
include cultivation and growth practices
how you're curing and drying your flower
genetic
and numerous other factors so because
this
there there is an inherent heterogeneity
of the sample that can definitely
cause
difficulties providing an accurate and
precise uh terpene content when tested
um
another thing is that
terpene analysis is expensive if you
know a girl processor wants to do it
in-house
the equipment is quite expensive the
headspace gc ms
is not cheap and you need someone with
some sort of experience or skill to
operate it
on the other hand
i found as we do
uh terpene analysis in-house that has
supported some of this research we
discussed today um
there's over 200 terpenes that have been
identified in cannabis flower
but when you're analyzing
uh for terpene content you're not gonna
quantitate all 200 of those
so there's going to be a lot of
potentially interfering compounds
they're quite similar as far as
many of them are isomers of one another
so my point is that terpene analysis
takes a lot of time
to get inaccurate and
to interpret the data to get an accurate
and precise result
so for a third party testing lab that
has to pay an analyst to do this that
there's definitely
um
you know a labor component that is
represented in what the charge for for
that analysis is going to be so a grower
processor really has to
weigh
if they want to spend that
amount of money to determine terpene
content
um
even though you know most
new patients are not familiar with what
a terpene even is so is there any added
value there
so i think the usp
cannabis expert panel recommends the
quantitation of five terpenes
for
all cannabis flower products
but um you know i don't think the
the industry has caught up to that yet
and frankly five is probably too
minimal you know 20 or more maybe a
little bit more appropriate
but um
you know with further uh patient
education and maturity of the industry
uh hopefully we we can improve this and
that may result in improved outcomes for
patients if they have more information
to make their decision decisions on what
cannabis
product to buy
absolutely and it is a great point you
make about sort of the
you know the heterogeneity of of the
plants themselves that you know if you
take one one bud from one section of the
plant and compare it to another uh they
could have different
concentrations of these terpenes and
then
if you
layer in the other variables
of time how
how long has it been since that sample
was analyzed until it gets to you and
could the
the chemo type of change between
then and now so
it does
it does make sense that your solution
here is is going to create a much more
consistent product uh so that people can
get some more reliable results
yeah ben you describe one of our main
applications for terp save which is a
more reliable terpene profile terpene
crop content across the entire batch of
cannabis flour
and
we envision batch to batch
reproducibility as you know different
harvests if plants are grown in the
winter versus the summer may have
different terpene profiles if they're
exposed a different amount of light
they'll have different terpene profiles
so all these are factors that we can
reduce their impact on the variability
of terpene profile
of cannabis flower using the terp safe
technology
all right excellent so winding down here
i did want to give you an opportunity to
share any additional information that
you think the listeners might be
interested in that could be a website or
social media accounts or some of the
studies that you may have mentioned
i'll jot down the notes and be sure to
put them in the in the show description
so people can learn more
yeah i appreciate that then so our
peer-reviewed paper talking about the
science
proof concept and validation studies of
terp safe was published in the journal
of cannabis research so you can find our
paper there
our website is
terpsafe.com that is t e r p
s
dot com
and um
there is an email uh contact us there so
please feel free to reach out with any
questions
and
that brand is available nationally
through our
partner ebottles
and our in-house terpsafe brand known as
amplify
is available at goodness growth holdings
dispensaries in maryland and arizona and
those dispensaries would be green goods
dispensaries
all right excellent
thanks again justin for for coming on
and talking terpenes with us and i look
forward to seeing you out in pasadena
for canmed
hey thanks ben appreciate it
all right
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
justin bueno check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor cannasafe
our next episode drops september 15th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
canmed archive and join the canmed
community facebook group to stay
connected with us
of course you can also stay in touch
with us on social media facebook
instagram linkedin and twitter just look
for canmed events
also sign up for their email alerts on
cammanevents.com
and be sure to rate review and subscribe
on your favorite podcast app
i do sincerely hope to see all of you
out in pasadena this spring but until
then stay safe stay healthy and join us
on the next canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you