[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
okay
you probably already know by now but
after careful evaluation of the current
situation in los angeles county and the
restrictions and requirements that would
have been necessary to hold canmed 2021
in september
our management team has made the
difficult decision to reschedule the
event from may 3rd through 5th
this was not an easy decision to make
it's been almost two years since we had
a live canmed event
but everyone including the conference
organizers our sponsors and the
presenters strongly believe that in
order for canmed to be a success
it must take place in a comfortable
collaborative environment
and that's just not possible during
these uncomfortable and restrictive
times
so we will press on
we will continue to bring you new
podcasts every other week we will
continue to interact with the kinmed
community on our facebook group and we
will continue to share all the great
canmed presentation videos that are in
our free searchable canmed archive on
all of our social media channels you can
find links to all those great resources
in the show description
and also if you have not signed up for
email alerts yet you really should that
is the best way to stay up to date with
all the updates around the canmed
conference delivered right to your inbox
all right on to today's guest
i had the pleasure of speaking with
evelyn alvarez the quality assurance
director at encore labs evelyn has 10
years of experience working on
analytical instrumentation and in
regulated lab environments including
work on epa and osha methods
she received a degree in environmental
science with research experience on
pesticides
evelyn was recently quoted in a refinery
29 article that revealed an unfortunate
element of the unregulated delta 8 thc
market
that being that some delta 8 thc
producers will falsify lab results
also known as certificates of analysis
that they post online
we cover that topic and others in our
discussion including
how coas differ from state mandated
compliance tests
how the lack of regulatory oversight of
delta 8 thc products puts consumers at
risk
red flags consumers can look for when
reviewing coas online the recent
increase in delta 8 thc products
how the process of synthesizing delta 8
thc from hemp may introduce contaminants
that most labs are not testing for and
more
before we get to my conversation with
evelyn i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor encore labs
encore labs is the premier cannabis
testing facility licensed in california
with iso iec
17025 certification they offer statewide
comprehensive analysis to cultivators
infused product manufacturers
distributors providers and dispensaries
not only for regulatory purposes but
also to characterize the unique aspects
of your cannabis
encore labs is also a bronze sponsor for
camp med 2022 which we very much
appreciate
for more information go to encore dash
labs dot com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with evelyn
alvarez
[Music]
good afternoon evelyn thanks for joining
us
hey thank you for having me very excited
to talk about these uh very important
topics for consumers
yeah about that so
you were quoted in a pretty wild article
that came out last month on the website
refinery29
i find the story concerning in a lot of
ways
but uh let's just start i guess with the
general premise so i don't know if if
you want to kind of explain
how you got involved in all of this or
if you want to if you want to do that
first sure yeah into some of the
concerns that it raises
yeah so uh a while back we got email to
our our
lab
uh and
molly the journalist from refinery29 was
reaching out initially just asking some
very straightforward questions about a
delta a product that she was going to
write a
review piece on
uh when i started digging into the
sample
information i realized that the reports
were very clearly fabricated just
completely
made up
uh when i reached back out to her with
that information she was pretty blown
away as well and that just kind of
started a good back and forth between
her and i which ended up turning into
this great piece by her i i mean she
really went down the rabbit's bowl and
spoke to many different people in the
industry you know from researchers to
regulators it turned into be a good
highlight for for everyone you know for
consumers especially in terms of safety
yeah exactly so
so basically molly had taken this delta
thc delta athc gummy and had a pretty
intense experience right more intense
than she was expecting or that was
advertised
and so she she went to the website and
looked at the coa that was listed there
um as many of these products have and
she looked at it everything looked good
less than 0.3 percent thc no residual
solvents everything looks good but she
goes one step further and actually
reaches out to the lab how
how common is that do consumers actually
reach out to your lab to confirm a coa
that they see online
prior to delta eight not very common
now that delta eight products have
become more and more popular we've
gotten a lot more inquiries to to our
line and it's it's good it's good that
people are asking these questions that
you know
there unfortunately is fabrication out
there um there's unfortunately not
enough education about what these
products are and what uh regulations if
any
that there are so
the more that people can call in and ask
us questions you know we're we're happy
to help
essentially relay the data to them we we
can't go into
safe
in terms of the physicians end of things
but we can interpret the results
right so i guess before we get too deep
into it can you briefly explain sort of
what a coa is and why is it important
for cannabis users and patients in terms
of product safety
yeah so uh coa
simply put is a
summary of the results of testing
performed on the product
so coa stands for certificate of
analysis
depending on the number of tests
requested it can tell you a lot about a
product so
uh it's cannabinoid profile you know how
potent it is how much thc or cbd is in
it it's terpene profile uh we
test for a lot of harmful things
things like pesticides heavy metals
residual solvents microbials mycotoxins
um
all of those are important in terms of
safety if we detect it's one of those
harmful compounds you know you shouldn't
be consuming it um
just the ponzi profile alone is
super important for the consumer
uh if they are purchasing these cbd or
delta eight products how do they really
know
that that's what is in the product or
how do they know that it doesn't contain
delta nine thc
um
i've heard of situations where
people consume cbd products and then end
up failing a drug test
uh you know maybe if they would have
gone one step further to look for for
the report
it could have helped
um
[Music]
but
even the
more importantly for
patients that are trying to dose
if
they want to make sure that what is
labeled on the container is actually
what it contains so that they can have
accurate dosing for whatever it is that
they're trying to
to focus on
exactly and so
so the coas that the manufacturers put
up on their websites it seems like a lot
of the things that they're testing for
is similar to what you would do for
compliance testing for products that are
on a dispensary shelf is that is that
fair to say is it is it really the same
battery of tests that are done for these
coas is it does it depend on what the
manufacturer requests what are the
differences between the two types of
tests
that is a very important question uh it
really depends on what they are
requesting for testing
for compliance testing here in the state
of california there are very specific
regulations that we follow uh
really from the beginning of testing to
the end and i can kind of get into that
um
how the sample arrives to the lab
and this is important
for
a compliance sample
we are required to send one of our
trained samplers out to
the facility
and we're required to sample something
that is unbiased and representative and
there are a lot of other requirements
say the larger the batch size is the
larger sample we pull
so
even just getting to the lab a
compliance one is is something that
we picked
uh we refer to non-compliant samples as
r d so things like cbd and delta eight
that are submitted uh those don't have
any requirements
manufacturers can send them in um
they can drop them off
they can cherry pick if they still wish
uh it's unfortunate but they do
um so
number from the get-go you're getting
something
potentially different than what you're
buying because of how it was submitted
uh when it gets to the lab
that was a great question that you asked
what kind of testing is performed so for
compliance testing
we
perform the whole gambit that the state
requires so a lot of what i mentioned
earlier pesticides microtoxins heavy
metals however for these
non-compliance tests it's whatever the
manufacturer requests so if they're only
concerned about cannabinoid profile
that is the only thing that
we test because they have no
requirements
um
so if it did have something harmful
since we're not testing for it
there's really no way for that to be
communicated to anyone
um
yeah besides that and
sorry go ahead no sorry and then and
furthermore even if that were
requested by the manufacturer
say microtoxins or heavy metals or
something like that
if you report that back to the
manufacturer is there any mechanism for
that to be reported also to some sort of
regulator or anyone to
make sure that that product still
doesn't
make it to the market like i assume
is in place for compliance testing
yeah another huge difference there is no
requirement for that information to be
submitted anywhere else than to the
person that requested it for anything
that is non-compliance
for
our compliance results the state has
really specific regulations when when we
finish and approve
the results we're required to
simultaneously report it to the
distributor that the people who
submitted and requested the testing to
the state of california the department
of cannabis control and we have to
upload it to a system
a track and trace system in california
we use metric and
all of that keeps
you know digital
data for everything so
even if this uh distributor tried to
transfer it elsewhere say to a retail
shop they won't be able to do that
because those failed results
are stuck with it um and even so since
we notified the the
department of cannabis control they're
already going to take action on that
but for these non-compliant samples um
those manufacturers really aren't
required to do much uh you know
maybe they're good actors and they're
going to go back and remediate their
match and submit again for testing and
then sell the product but maybe they're
not and they're just going to
submit a different sample and still push
it through elsewhere
right and you and like you mentioned
earlier the fact that they can sort of
submit samples that may not exactly be
representative of
an entire batch
um
yeah issue as well
yeah
yeah i mean there's really no way of
knowing
um that what you're buying is what was
tested for
anything that's not in these state
regulated
areas
and another thing that you mentioned
when i asked how common it was for
consumers to actually contact you to
verify results of a coa you said it was
more common now with delta eight thc yet
i know that coas have been in place for
cbd products um you know in the past so
what is it about the delta eight thc
products that are causing more red flags
i guess
um
i would imagine it is because of the
mild psychoactive properties
so
say you bought cbd and
um
cbd gummies
you may not necessarily get high you may
have some feeling but probably nothing
that's concerning
i think what happened with delta eight
is um you know it's very new so people
don't know how to dose um
it's
very new on the manufacturing end so you
also might be getting something that you
weren't expecting so if people are
having a psychiatric reaction that they
didn't expect uh that is more cause for
concern of like what did i just take you
know like let me dig into this and
unfortunately a lot of the times the
calls that we get are after the fact not
before so after they've consumed it
and so how often are those inquiries do
they
does it come up that
they may have
used a product that had a fake coa or
one that's been modified is it is it
increasingly common
um
i can't say increasingly and
even for the common um for the number of
calls that we get it it actually hasn't
been as common
okay um
but at the same time um
i also don't know how many people
go to that extent you know someone may
buy product
look up the report find it and think
okay this looks fine um so there could
be a lot out there that we just don't
know about
right but like you said you
you encourage people to reach out to you
um to confirm that these results or is
it is it becoming overwhelming
uh
you know on some days
we do get a good amount of calls but we
definitely do not want to cut that off
you know we're
we are a cannabis testing lab we're not
just gonna hide behind our results we're
going to
help
absolutely and
i guess to that end
are there any red flags or maybe warning
signs that people if they're if they are
looking into a coa for a product that
they had a maybe a strange or unexpected
experience with are there some some
indicators they can be looking for
yeah um this is a bit of a tough
question because uh to the trained eye
like uh
me and our staff we can quickly tell
what's what um
i guess
the
main points that i want to pass on is
most coas have pictures of products
so if you pull up a coa and the product
that you have in hand does not match
what is on the report that is a huge red
flag
already they're just
slapping on a qr code to a different
product assuming that you're not gonna
go to the extent of scanning it
um
even on the pictures
we we take the pictures in our lab
um
we take some nice pictures
don't expect a like a marketing
photograph to end up on a report that
comes from our lab you know if it has a
fancy background that's
that's going to be a red flag
we take very simple pictures
um
[Music]
i mentioned qr code so
qr codes are not only on products but we
also put qr codes on our reports and a
lot of other labs do as well
and
um this helps a lot because if you scan
the qr code on the report it actually
takes you to
the website that we use to host our
reports
so if
you're pulling up a report if you're
just getting a qr code and it's taking
you to some random website that doesn't
pair up to what is on the report that
could be a red flag as well because that
means they've probably downloaded it
possibly changed something uploaded it
elsewhere because they can't upload
anything to our site it's only
what we upload ourselves
um
if it is missing a qr code
that
could be red flag as well depending on
where it's coming from um but other than
that it's a lot of kind of minuscule
differences that would be
more so caught by us than anyone else
no but the one with the fact that the
report is most likely going to be hosted
on
the lab's website that
that i think is is a pretty good
indicator right there so if
if it's a pdf uploaded to the
manufacturer's website that's probably a
little more concerning than if it's
going to
encorelabs.com correct
it may or may not be um some some do
download it and and re-upload it very
directly without changing everything but
let's say
they uh they did do that and you scan
the qr code as long as it still goes
back to our hosted website um
that that would be fine and as long as
the one that you're looking at on their
website isn't any different than the one
that's on our website that would be fine
um
we do we use a lymph system that's
called confident cannabis and here in
california actually across the
nation a good amount of labs use that
website as well so that's a common one
that you would see reports on
excellent excellent
okay so i want to talk a bit about delta
t8 delta 8 thc specifically too because
you did
mention that
you know folks are still not
really familiar with how
these products are manufactured and how
kind of the differences in how they're
manufactured could introduce other
concerns
i was wondering if you could start maybe
briefly explaining what the process is
for creating these products and then you
can go from there
yeah uh i don't have hands-on experience
with this part more so just on the
testing
but just kind of very briefly
um
they're not extracting it from the hemp
plant there's not enough delta eight
naturally occurring in the hemp plant to
do that extraction like would be normal
for
cbd or thc
um what is actually being done is
uh cbd isolate which has had an
overstock because of the the hemp
legalization they're taking the cbd
isolate and they're introducing a
catalyst so a lot of the times it's a
combination of acid
[Music]
solvents and heat
and they are
converting
cbd into delta eight thc
uh so it's it's a it's an isomerization
process it's a conversion it's not an
extraction
right
um
and so i guess
in general how do sort of delta eight
thc products compare to the more
dispensary grade products that you test
in your lab i mean i i know i saw one
article recently out there and someone
was calling some of these delta ap thc
products bathroom gin
um is that is that something that you're
seeing
how do they compare to to things that
are coming from the regulated market
uh
you know unfortunately because
they don't have all of the required
testing
we don't have as much data points so a
lot of it is
kind of ignorance is bliss you know they
may have solvents but since they're not
required to do all this testing we don't
have those data points
um in in terms of cannabinoid potency
we have some pretty consistent products
that we see
with
90 plus
uh potency so
what i mean if i say
to say by that is uh
if we have a an oil that is coming from
a delta eight cartridge we're seeing
that it has uh
greater than ninety percent of only
delta eight thc in there which is pretty
comparable to some of the the delta nine
thc products
um
we see
a good amount of gummies and a good
amount are hitting the targets that are
labeled and
you know visibly
gummy looks like a gummy
overall um
but
i think what's really difficult for for
the consumer
is
that delta eight thcs is
as a primary cannabinoid is is new uh so
the effects are different the effects
are different from person to person
um
that is something that
needs to be
studied more
absolutely and
yeah i i just keep coming back to the
just the process of synthesizing delta a
thc and how that can just introduce all
these other you know residual stall
solvents or other compounds that you
wouldn't traditionally see if you were
doing just a straight extraction of
sort of naturally occurring
compounds in the plant
and it sounds like a lot of these
manufacturers aren't even going as far
as what's
what's commonly performed on
products in california to maybe even
capture those additional compounds that
come with the the process of
creating delta 8 thc so that's a that's
a little concerning
it is yeah and another key point to make
on that is the testing that we perform
is based on the california regulations
which were based on the knowledge of
historical
thc manufacturing so so these lists that
they create especially for like solvents
you know we're looking for butane and
that's a very common extraction solvent
but what is common for for delta 8 thc
is kind of still being figured out
there's a lot of different extraction
methods that are being tested so even if
we test for residual solvents with that
california list
it's not going to encompass
all
of the potential solvents that they
could use all right
yeah i just
the whole delta athc thing really
concerns me just because i feel like
that there's so many
so many great
growers manufacturers in the regulated
space that have all these regulatory
hoops that they need to jump through and
are doing things the right way
and you know have gained a lot of trust
in the marketplace for people to to
trust cannabis products
and now we have this new compound that's
coming out it's
unregulated
folks aren't
not testing for the things that they
should and i worry that they're
going to sort of erode the public trust
a little bit with cannabis products
because
they're not doing things the right way
yeah i would definitely agree with all
that it's it's not to say that there
aren't um
companies that have good manufacturing
practices and that are doing a good
amount of testing and have transparency
but there's a lot of bad actors that are
completely taking advantage of of this
uh seemingly gray area you know that is
up for interpretation
but um
yeah i mean a couple states have already
taken action outlawed and and we'll kind
of have to see what the
continuing regulatory landscape turns
into for this but
um
i guess another thing to worry about is
even if delta 8 becomes outlawed or
included in regulatory schemes who's to
say that the next cannabinoid isn't
going to become the next trend you know
right delta 10 thc sure so
we'll really have to see how this
evolves but i mean on our end the main
thing is
for consumers is continue to ask about
testing uh from the manufacturers
continue to push for that because if
there's no regulatory push then it has
to come from the consumers
yeah agreed um
and yeah i think it's unfortunate that
some states have taken to to banning
delta a thc instead of what you
suggested you know maybe sort of
bundling it in or including it with um
with the with the legal market and kind
of letting sort of things like we've
said these established
um operators who are operating within
the regulated market making sure that
you know they're
maybe the ones that are that are
bringing these delta athc products to
market instead of these new actors who
may be just um
sort of trying to make a buck no and
like you said not to say that there
aren't some good ones out there but it
seems yeah at least it seems to me as a
consumer
a potential consumer it's hard for me to
be able to suss out who are the good and
the bad actors if if folks are sort of
um
doing what they're doing with the coas
yeah definitely
yeah
um and yeah so just in general with with
delta hchc testing how much has that
grown in the past 12 months because it
seems like it's really exploded as
as a recently
yeah it has um it definitely
hasn't taken over a majority of our
testing we really still focus on on our
compliance testing and uh supporting r d
testing that that supports that
compliance testing but um
you know a year ago if you asked us
about delta 8 thc it was
it was a minor cannabinoid that
occasionally came up
because uh someone didn't treat their
their normal thc distillate well uh but
now you know we're seeing a good variety
of products come through
that are solely for for delta eight and
um you know some days we we see 10 to 15
of our r d testing is solely from delta
a
wow
wow yeah and so maybe this is a good
point i know we're coming up to the end
of it um maybe if you could tell us a
bit about encore labs what you guys do
and
how people can learn more about you guys
yeah so um we are a
licensed
cannabis testing lab here in california
[Music]
different states obviously have
different
regulations if it has become legalized
so in california you have to be licensed
to test for these compliance tests uh we
are iso accredited as well so that's
kind of a big thing for us and to
educate the consumers on the differences
between iso credit labs and non-iso
accredited labs
we have to go through an accreditation
process
that encompasses a huge list of
requirements
and we have met that
so if you're looking at a coa that's
actually another thing to look for are
the testing labs being used iso credited
are they licensed by your state
if they're not then there could be more
questions on the lab producing the
results
um
so
we are
located in pasadena california and we
feel like we have a very uh strategic
location
for
the
cannabis landscape
um
[Music]
we've been here since 2018 and have
really grown
with our experience and with our team
and
we're always looking for opportunities
to educate consumers and um to partner
up with different companies to
to push for testing
absolutely and you're located in
pasadena california which is where i
came at conferences
so that's um it's great that we're very
happy to have you guys on board as a
bronze sponsor
and um
i think if you're looking to partner
with companies that are looking to to
educate you you've come to the right
place
yeah
so
all right evelyn thank you so much for
taking the time today and like i said
we're really looking forward to to
seeing the team out there in pasadena
for canmed
yeah thank you for having us and uh
reach out to encore if you have
questions on reports
absolutely i'll put a link to your
website and your social media and
everything in the show description so
people can find you
great thank you all right thanks
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
evelyn alvarez check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to encore labs for sponsoring this
episode
our next podcast drops september 29th
which sadly would have been the first
day of can med
but fear not we'll be back with another
great podcast episode for you to tide
you over until may
speaking of tiding you over until may
please do check out our facebook
community group just search for canmed
follow us on all of our social media
platforms that's instagram linkedin
twitter facebook
just search for canmet events
also be sure to check out our
canmedarchive
on canmenevents.com
it's an unbelievable free resource
that has all of our past canmed
presentations going back to canmed2016
it's all searchable and it's all free
please do check it out
okay what more can i say
rate review subscribe on your favorite
podcast app
and stay safe stay healthy and be sure
to come back for the next canmed coffee
talk
[Music]
you