[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
head over to cannemedevents.com now to
learn all about our canmed 2022 event
which will take place may 3rd through
5th at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
this three-day event begins with a
full-day medical practicum led by dr
bonnie goldstein the practicum's
originator as well as dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise thiessen
each of the presenters will share the
latest research as well as their
clinical experience and practice
guidelines related to cannabinoid
therapeutics
a new section of this eight-hour course
is dedicated to reviewing different
types of extractions products and
optimal dosing for cannabinoid
therapeutics
after that we have two full days of
presentations and panel discussions
covering the latest research in the
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing taking place may 4th
and 5th
the full schedule is up at
canmedevents.com
you'll notice that each of the canmed
focus areas are anchored by a keynote
presenter
dr ethan russo for science seth crawford
for cultivation dr bonnie goldstein for
medicine and grace bandong for safety
testing
each of our keynotes as well as many of
our presenters and panelists were guests
on the podcast and you can listen to all
our previous episodes at
cammanevents.com coffeetalk
while you're at canmedevents.com you can
also watch video presentations and panel
discussions from all of our previous cam
and events in our canmed video archive
presentations include
canmed2022
dr rousseau seth crawford and dr
goldstein as well as professor rafael
mishulam david miri marcus rogen zamir
punja stacey gruber and many many more
as you can tell we have a lot going on
at kmanevents.com
and the best way to keep up with
everything is to sign up for email
alerts using the simple form in the page
footer
or on the pop-up form that you'll find
at camedevents.com
you can also follow us on facebook
instagram twitter or linkedin
just look for cam at events
this episode's guest is dr david jolie
he is the associate professor at the
university of moncton where his team
investigates cannabis and cannabinoids
dr jolie has a unique expertise in the
field of plant genomics and their
associated microbes and his work has
been cited more than one thousand times
earlier this year dr jolie published a
paper titled genome-wide
characterization of the mlo gene family
in cannabis sativa reveals two genes as
strong candidates for powdery mildew
susceptibility it's an important paper
when it comes to breeding powdery mildew
resistant cannabis plants
as we discuss pm is as common as it is
destructive and it torments all types of
cannabis growers from the hobbyist home
grower to large-scale commercial
operators
in our conversation we discuss how pm
infects cannabis plants and how
environmental conditions play a role
the prevention and remediation options
cannabis cultivators currently have
the difference between pm resistance and
pm susceptibility and how both
variations can affect the severity of
infection
how breeding out pm susceptibility genes
provides more robust protection than
breeding in pm resistance genes
what are mlo genes and how do they
affect pm susceptibility
how mlo genes were used to breed out pm
susceptibility in other crops
the importance of having a quality
reference genome to investigate genes of
interest and much more
before we get to my conversation with dr
jolie
i want to thank this episode sponsor
canopedia
canopedia.net is the world's most
comprehensive cannabis genomic library
and a recent update has made it easier
than ever for customers and researchers
to explore canopedia's database of more
than 1400 cannabis cultivars to make
smart breeding decisions and demonstrate
novel genetics
canopedia.net now has a number of new
features to help explore your cannabis
cultivar's genomic data
improved search and filtering make it
easy to identify cultivars of interest
within the canopedia database
new visualizations and variant tables
highlight high impact variants in genes
of interest including the mlo genes
cited in dr jolie's paper
responsive design means you can view
your reports on any screen
private reports allow you to keep
sensitive data hidden and much more
to view all these updates visit
canopedia.net
that's k a n n a p e d i a dot net to
learn more
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr david
jolie
[Music]
good afternoon david thanks for joining
us
thank you
all right so you and your team recently
published a pretty important paper on
powdery mildew
susceptibility which we are going to get
into but first i wanted to lay some
groundwork
our audience here on the podcast
includes people from all facets of the
cannabis industry and not everyone's
going to be intimately familiar with pm
so let's start by outlining the powdery
mildew problem so i was wondering if you
could explain
why is powdery mildew a threat to
cannabis cultivation and really you know
what is at stake here
yeah well uh first of all i would say
that powder mildew is a threat because
it's very common first of all so it's
not something rare that you know people
are likely not to expect so it's it
certainly will happen at some point so
it's very common and
it can spread very quickly so when once
a crop is infected so usually the
recovery options are
often limited so we don't want growers
of course to use those nasty fungicides
that we we see sometime on other crops
so we still have access to a few uh
environmentally friendly
options but those are not always
very efficient or they are not easy to
apply on larger scale
so
now about its impact on the plant itself
of course it will really kill it because
it's what we call an obligate biotroph
so it needs living tissues
to
propagate but it can severally reduce
photosynthesis when it gets out of
control especially and thus it will in
the end affect yield so something that
no grower wants won't
another impact i can think of is of
course it will affect the smell of the
plant so when you have a plant infected
by padre mildew people will notice it as
a different smell and so we know that
consumers are more and more interested
in you know the flavors and the scent
uh the aromas of their
of their cannabis
so certainly it's a problem that people
will want to avoid
sure and now
it's called powdery mildew because it
has sort of a powdery white look on the
leaves when a plant is infected and i'm
familiar with the fact that it will show
up on the leaves does it also infect the
flower itself will it sort of affect
the bud that eventually would get to the
consumer
yeah well we we often say that uh that
powder mildew can affect
uh all aerial parts of the plant so it
will include stems
as long as they're non-woody
it can infect the leaves and it can
infect some part of the
of the flowers not all but like when we
refer
uh to cannabis flowers so of course we
have the like the bracts and those can
be uh can be infected by powdery mildew
but but we need to understand that
powdery mildew so you know
you will hear a lot of things about
polymer people will will say it's
systemic and stuff like that
so
if i can describe rapidly how powdery
will do work so usually like uh pardon
me will do first it's it's a fungus
right so it will propagate mainly
through its
asexual spores that we call canadia
so those pores will land on a leaf
and then they will germinate and produce
those
kind of tiny projections into
the cells from the epidermis and only
the epidermis so powder mildew will only
affect one layer of cells which is the
first layer of cells it won't get
further down than that compared with
other
fungi so it is certainly not systemic it
is very restricted to the epidermis now
we have epidermis on
leaves but we also have epidermis on the
stem so that's why you can see
uh powdery mildew
elsewhere so those tiny projections i
was i was talking about so that gets
into the plant cells so
they are
needed by the fungus to absorb its
nutrients from the plant uh but it will
also be a way for a fungus to suppress
the defense response from the plant
but then
why do people think it's systemic
well there's many reasons for that so in
in other plants that
survive
winter for example so people tuck it
with systemic because very rapidly in
the spring you could see powdery mildew
appear
and so the reason for that is that it
can stay dormant within
buds and i'm not talking about cannabis
buds here but like any axillary buds
that you can
find on a plant and it can also stay
dormant on plant debris
and
mostly i think the big reason is that
it can be present but at a very low
level so people will think that the
plant is healthy they will then
propagate it or share it with friends
and then suddenly the conditions become
favorable and it will
be a big boom
for the fungus but it was there it can
stay you know dormant at very low levels
yeah so
important thing you mentioned there so
environmental conditions can sort of
bring on an infection
yeah for sure and i mean so that's why
usually so you know people will have uh
their mother plants
um and so your mother plants are in
a sitting where usually the humidity is
not as high as the cuttings will be
once the you know once they start
propagating that plant
so you have a plan that was maybe not in
the ideal conditions for the fungus so
you don't see it but it's still there
it's still somewhere and then when you
do the cuttings you put them you know
into higher humidity level and then the
fungus likes it it will start to
propagate and then when you
when you get your
your plants outside
outside of the
of the
uh well outside of the rooting period
uh
it will add time to
get established and then
people will often also see it getting
more important during flowering so is it
because it had time to mature or because
the canopy is maybe
more dense
or also because i don't know if the
light can affect i'm not sure it has
been studied but maybe like because we
changed the uh the light regime during
flowering maybe it also helps the the
apology mildew to propagate
more easily
okay
so
i know you briefly touched on it but
i mean a lot of your paper is is about
trying to identify these genes that may
be responsible for susceptibility to
powdery mildew and then there's also um
the opportunity of finding powdery
mildew resistant genes which i'm sure
we'll get into but in the absence of
sort of breeding for
la uh resistance
what
steps do cultivators currently have
to either prevent pm infection or once
it's happened sort of remediate it
uh yeah so i mean
right now as i said at the
very beginning so there are a few
options that exist to kind of reduce
uh the the incidence of the incidence of
the disease um
so and and about those products so i
know there was uh there was a study
conducted by the group of uh the group
of zamir punja at simon fraser
university who you also had on your
podcast a year ago
uh so they
they tested a bunch of uh of different
products so some are based on the use of
bacteria that will attack the fungus
so we can talk about the
products like actinovate or rhapsody
but they also look at products that are
based on plant extracts such as neem oil
and also some other products that are
well known in the in the organic farming
uh such as uh potassium bicarbonate
or that we know uh as milstop is the
name of the product that we often see
for cannabis use
or
hydrogen peroxide also which is another
product so there are different products
some people will talk also about
silicon because in in other crops it has
been shown to be very useful to reduce
powdery mildew
uvc lights that are getting also
popularity so those are
different methods that can be used to
reduce
the incidence but i guess before we have
to use
those those products i think the key is
to try to keep your plants as clean
as possible so as soon as you detect
infection remove
uh the infected plant parts try to not
have dense canopies as i said earlier
try to keep the humidity maybe a little
lower
of course it is a fungus that is
airborne so those pores are very
easily transported by by any air
movement so you know
outside it's easy to understand that i'm
talking about wind but in inside you
know just people moving around or
so you can get spores on your on your
clothes and then you get into another
another room and then those spores can
infect
uh the plants
and uh
so yeah so trying to reduce so if you
have a room that is completely infected
of course don't go in that room before
going into your cleaner room so you know
just simple steps like that trying to
reduce the inoculum levels
excellent excellent and so that breeds
it brings us to
the prospect of actually breeding for
resistance to pottery mildew which is
what your paper is about so
first of all
powdery mildew doesn't just infect
cannabis and infects a whole range of
other crops so i was wondering if you
could maybe explain how
breeders have successfully bred for
resistance in other crops and how we
might use that information to uh to
achieve it in cannabis
yeah yeah so as you said exactly so
powder mildew is a big family
of
fungal pathogens so we have different
species some will be very host specific
and others have a broader host range and
it is the case for the one we have and
and before we talk about resistance this
is
something we can just talk for a few
secs so it's it's a problem in itself so
when you have something that's very host
specific as long as you don't have any
of those plants nearby so
you know you you're less likely to get
that disease so let's say you have a
cannabis feel but you know there is no
cannabis field around if if the fungus
was specific to cannabis then it's less
likely it will get into your field but
the problem is that the species we have
is not specific to
uh only to cannabis so it can also
infect a lot of different plants from
the
the aster family so we have a lot of
flowers like when we think about
dahlias and
sunflowers so they can get infected by
that same species and also some
weeds like ragweed can also be infected
so that's something also to consider
when we're growing outside
but let's get into the
the resistance at least
what we learned from other crops so
um
i think some of the the first things
that were discovered so it was on barley
uh more than 50 years ago so they they
they discovered
some uh accessions
from africa that were completely
resistant to uh
to padre mildew and then
that was the the first point
and so they started to investigate
trying to understand what was going on
and and they realized at some point that
it is a form of resistance but we prefer
to call it like a loss of susceptibility
so
resistance and susceptibility you know
we we kind of try
we often think that it is the same thing
so one is uh you know the plant is
either resistant or susceptible but in
terms of breeding so when you breed a
resistant plant we can see it as we're
bringing something new to the plant we
bring a new genes that will confer
resistance but there's another way to
to achieve resistance is to
reduce susceptibility so you know you
have maybe something in the plans that
confer susceptibility
and you want to remove that from the
plan so of course people will think well
susceptibility if there was something in
the plant that would cause
susceptibility
it would have been you know eliminated
by years of
natural selection
but the problem is that maybe those
genes are very useful for the plants so
the plant cannot get rid of them but
there's a caveat of having those genes
is that they you know they cause
susceptibility to some
to some fungal pathogens and this is
exactly what
some genes are and people are getting
interest into those genes but mlo is one
of those examples so it's not a
resistant gene it's a susceptibility
gene so we need to
find
cannabis strains that have either an
inactive
version of that gene or a mutated
version of that gene that will
make it more difficult to the pathogen
to infect
and so one interesting thing also when
we're talking about
resistance so
as as you said so i published a paper
recently about the mlo family but almost
at the same time so there's another
group that published a paper about pm1
which is a resistant gene so we can talk
a little bit more about those two
side of the coin
so resistant gene the way that
i can describe it from a genetic point
of view is what we call
a gene for gene interaction so you have
one resistant gene in the plant
that is able to recognize one gene from
the pathogen so it's a little bit like a
you know like our own
immune system so it's not it's not
working the same way but it's easier to
understand if we compare it to that so
we have something that is more of a
recognition system so that gene can
recognize the pathogen and triggers
defense responses that will kill the
pathogen
um
the problem with that types of
resistance
is that
it's usually isolate specific so it will
recognize only a few isolate or you know
one population of the pathogen or it can
for a while looks like if it's
recognized the whole
the whole species but after a while the
pathogen will rapidly evolve to overcome
that resistance so
uh leading us to what we call a
co-evolutionary arms race
um
and so we constantly need to find
new genes of that kind so new resistant
genes and we can try to
breed
a lot of them together so that would
mean maybe it will be more durable but
usually if you have only one
it will likely not be durable
and now when we talk about
susceptibility then it's different so
susceptibility is usually more durable
and the reason for that is that
you're removing something that the
fungus needs to enter or to infect the
plant so it's very
difficult for the pathogen to adapt to
that kind of situation something is
missing so it cannot you know just
create it so that kind of resistant
resistance it's
loss of system of susceptibility less of
susceptibility will become a form of
resistance
so it is in that case way more durable
but the problem is it's also more
difficult to breathe because it's a form
of resistive resistance a little bit
like if you have two people with brown
eyes you know it's easy it's easy to get
a child
with brown eyes but to get a child with
blue eyes then it it depends of if there
are some blue jeans hidden
somewhere so it's the same thing here
you need to
find uh to bring that
level of um
having the two mutated copies or or the
two
different genes
must be inactivated at the same time so
it's it's a little bit harder uh to
breed but if i come back to that uh to
that example of barley i was talking
about so
15 year
50 years later so it's still
working so we can see that still very
durable
so yeah and that was
something that i needed to kind of wrap
my head around when i was reading the
paper was that
um you actually want less
mlo for to really kind of simplify
things you want less mlo to have more
resistance and one of the quotes that i
pulled out from the paper that really
hammers this home is that you said
expression of mlo is necessary for the
successful invasion of pm
so
really what you're trying to do is
eliminate that mlo so it can't
successfully invade correct
exactly exactly but then as i said it's
it's not
that easy because
if that gene is still there it's because
it plays another role and that's usually
what people are
seeing is that if you inactivate a
susceptibility gene you can have some
pleiotropic effect so in the case of mlo
so it's very variable so in some crops
where they did that so you have some um
they will see that they have either
an increased susceptibility toward other
diseases so it's more resistant to palgy
mildew but it becomes more susceptible
to other diseases or you will have
early leaves in essence and stuff like
that but in in other crops
there doesn't seem to be any effects so
maybe under some conditions it will
it would cause something bad but under
the conditions that we keep our plants
into you know we take care of our plants
we fertilize them and so on so maybe
it will never show any bad effects so we
don't know for cannabis it will if it
will show some of those pliotropic
effects but if not then it would become
something very interesting to breed
sure and now do we understand what mlo
does to sort of help pm invade the plant
like what the mechanism is there
no even though people have been studying
it for a while so they they consider mlo
as a negative regulator of plant immune
plant immunity uh but apart from that we
have no clear idea of what it does there
are other mlos uh that are not involved
in powdery mildew susceptibility so we
know a little bit
of the functions that those genes are
are doing but clearly it
it is not an indication that the the one
we're talking about here that dictates
patreon do susceptibility would have a
similar function
sure yeah and that's a good point so
there are more than one mlo genes in the
plant and not all of them are sort of
implicated in this pm
infection correct yeah exactly so in in
some plants you can have i don't know
five maybe six ah
okay no let's start wider in that so
most plants will have you know around 15
or more
mlos but within those mlos
you know you have different subfamilies
if i if i can say and there's only one
that is
involved in uh powdery mildew
susceptibility
so the other one they play other roles
as i was explaining earlier on but so
and even within that subfamily so then
it depends between crops so for some
plants
if you have for example three
three genes uh in that subfamily maybe
you will need to inactivate all those
three to get resistance but in other
crops there seems to be maybe one that
is uh
the leader or more important and then if
you inactivate that one it should be
enough so in cannabis we found two genes
in that in that subfamily but we don't
know yet if both are
required
for for susceptibility or if maybe it's
only one of them
okay
and now to your knowledge
are there pm resistant strains of
cannabis out there currently do they
exist
um
resistant
strains i would say yes
resistant strains that are resistant
because of mlo inactivation
i'm not sure maybe
um
so because as i said so we have those
other examples like like the the the
strains that have the pm1 gene
and i'm aware of other people that have
those plans that will stay completely
you know clean of powdery mildew and
even though they are surrounded by you
know plants that are covered with it
so clearly there there are probably a
lot of those genes that are similar to
pm1 uh so it's just a matter now of of
uh i did identifying a lot of those
genes and trying to bring them all
together to have a very
resistant plan that will
resist to you know a lot of different uh
poger mildew populations mlo i'm not
sure the problem right now is that if we
look at what was done for
uh for barley and it was the same for
peas and for tomatoes so
the
the plans the accessions they found that
add that mlo
resistance it was always you know in in
ancient land races and stuff like that
something that you know
we haven't explored that much uh for
cannabis yet so and even
if we consider going back to wild
populations then it will be a matter of
trying to find those wild populations
because it's not clear if they still
exist
right and yeah so going back to sort of
that that pm1
side of the coin as you said so and if
i'm correct that group that that
published on the pm1 gene they were
looking at one snip
to sort of indicate whether or not a
cultivar was resistant is that enough
information to to really make that call
it seems
um well i mean it it would not be a
first for sure so if we look into uh
uh where
a lot of different genes
like that have been identified and
studied so we can think about wheat
with regards to rust which is a big
problem affecting wheat or even
potato in its relation with late blight
which is also another big uh big problem
so
uh in those two systems there is a lot
of genes like that that have been
identified and sometimes that's that's
the only thing that will be different
between a susceptible and a resistant
plant you have one snip in that
resistant gene that will cause an amino
acid change and that's enough to gain
resistance or lose it depending on how
you want to see it but but then the same
is true on the pathogen side so that
gene that is recognized only one snip
can make it not being recognized anymore
so that's that arms race i was
i was referring to so
it's always difficult to predict how
long it will be useful
sure and then i guess another point that
you had made is that there can be a lot
of different ways to to skin the cat
here it could be a combination of
different proteins that are inferring
the
resistance or the lack of susceptibility
so
um
it could be that uh you know a snip
that's identified in a certain
population might not necessarily apply
to a wider
a wider population correct
yeah maybe yeah we don't know enough
about about those genes as of now and
then there's also
that idea so for now i talked about
susceptibility and resistance but within
resistance so what i was talking about
mostly is what we call
uh qualitative resistance so it's either
your resistance or you're not but then
there's also what we call
quantitative resistance which is a lot
different
uh
harder to breed as well because it's
we don't know exactly how it works uh
there is a lot of genes that are
involved each one you know playing a
minor role and it's together that they
bring resistant
resistance to a strain and
so
trying to find an example for cannabis
would be maybe the the genes that have
been identified by the medicinal
genomics group
so they identified
chitinases and automatons
that seem to correlate with the levels
of padry mildew resistance so in that
case i would tend to believe that maybe
they are involved in something more
quantitative and so those are very
interesting because quantitative
resistance as i said is harder to breed
but as anything that is harder to breed
it's also it also means that it's harder
for the pathogen to defeat
interesting and another thing that that
i picked up in the paper that sort of
maybe talks to
maybe more of a quantitative type of
lack of susceptibility
was that
if i understood correctly hemp actually
has fewer mlo genes in which case it
might be less susceptible to pm did i
get that right yeah well i mean it's
it's uh it's uh
i would say it's a hypothesis that we
that we put forward uh of course in our
paper so we looked at five different
genomes uh those genomes are certainly
not all perfect and there was only one
that was really from hemp uh so finola
genome cbd rx is is uh considered as you
know having some hemp ancestry uh so
those two were the one that only had one
uh well for one of the copies the the
then
for one of the two genes they only had
one copy so
is is is this an indication that hemp
would be more resistant and and it's
also
uh it's also hard to talk about hem
because what we call hemp in canada is
sometimes different than hemp in the u.s
so hemp in canada it's often what we
call industrial hemp
uh while the us hemp is more like cbd
producing plants but they often have the
same ancestry as you know
thc producing plants
sure
yeah and so you touched on the fact that
sort of the process that you went
through to investigate these genes is
you used a variety of different
reference genomes um
sort of
how important is it to have a really
strong reference to do this type of work
and sort of what was the variation in
quality that you encountered
yeah so i think i mean any people
doing
research is is always looking for one
reference genome so you usually that's
what they have in other crops so when we
started uh working
um
we were looking for
which one we could we should use as the
reference because it was not clear like
you know a lot of people
were considering purple kush as the
reference just because you know there
was a first draft of it in 2011
but
we were aware that purple kush was not
the best one so some people were
considering cbd rx as as the new
reference genome because you know it has
a very high quality so we decided to
uh
first decide on which one we would call
our reference genome so we had a look at
first jamaican lion cbd rx and purple
kush
and then only looking at those tree it
was not easy to decide which one was the
best so you know each one has its
as it benefits i would say so cbd rx was
you know a very clean i would say so
maybe two clean we'll talk about that
maybe
maybe later so you know uh very less
repetitive compared to the other genomes
uh and it add the um
it had a chromosome level assembly which
was uh very interesting so we kind of
uh
you know we were considering maybe that
one is the best one jamaican lion was
also very good but it was
maybe a little bit more repetitive
and also
there was no chromosome level assembly
at least available to the public uh
purple kush well it was the worst of the
three so we can skip this one for now
but so it was you know deciding between
jamaican lion and cbd rx and from what i
said cbdrx you know might have looked
better but as i said it was maybe too
clean because when we started looking
at origin family so
so we realized that one gene that we
found in in the other genomes was absent
from cbdrx so is it something real maybe
cbdrx is missing that gene so we haven't
looked into that uh or
has it been you know clean a little bit
too much so they try to remove you know
repetitive elements from it and by
accident they they removed
uh that gene so it's not it's not clear
so
we kind of decided to move forward with
more than one genome and then we decided
okay so we're just going to add the
other two
that were available at the time so
finola which was also interesting
because it was hemp so you know it was
maybe a little bit different and then
jamaican lion there was also a male
version
um
so we decided to add that as well
because then we had finola and jamaican
lion males
uh so two males three females so just to
see if there could be differences as
well you know with the y chromosome and
the x chromosome
and did you find any difference there oh
well there were there were some
differences but you know
at this stage
uh is it you know real biological
differences or are they
different that are caused by you know
technical uh
aspect of you know some genomes being uh
better than others so for sure i would
say that purple kush
uh finola as well so you know
they were showing a lot of um
errors in the sequences when we were
looking at the genes like if we would
try to transcribe those genes
they would not transcribe well into
proteins because they add you know some
extra
some extra letters or some missing
letters and again
we talk well maybe it's a reality maybe
those genes have been inactivated in
those plans but then when we looked at
other data from the same plan so we had
a look at some transcriptomic data from
from those plans and we see that those
uh differences were not there so clearly
it was an error during the assembly
process so
those two had more problems i would say
they were more fragmented as well so
uh it was um
so for those two it was
easier to say that we would prefer not
to work with those two maybe they will
get better at some point i don't know if
they're still trying to you know uh
to to make them cleaner or to make them
better
uh but for the other two it really the
difference that we talked so maybe cbdr
is being too clean but jamaican lion
i don't know maybe still too repetitive
you know it's hard to come with the
perfect genome
and so how does
the
the quality of reference genome that
that we were working with in cannabis
compared to some of these other crops
are we are we still very far behind
uh we're not that far behind i mean
i think we're we're certainly getting
there it's just a matter of uh of the
community you know deciding on which one
is their reference and then we start
building on that one
um
i think one of the problem we add is
that you know and it's not only for i
mean it's the same for all crops and i
would say for all organisms you know
people it's so easy right now to
sequence things to sequence complete
genomes
people will sequence it the quality is
not good but how we're still going to
you know
upload it onto
ncbi and so you end up having access to
a lot of
genomes but the quality is not there and
then if you try to work with those then
it it's you start with a big you know a
big bias in your study because you try
to predict genes but if the genome is
not complete then you will miss and
genes will lead you to erroneous
conclusions so it's important to have a
good reference genome but i think we i
think we have we have maybe two right
now so i think we're
we're getting there yeah for sure
yeah but to your point it we sort of
need to choose a gold standard so
everyone's working off the same
reference correct
yeah but then it leads us to you know
maybe the other problem that we have is
that
usually uh when you have a reference
genome for another crop so
that plant that you know was used to
create that reference genome is also
accessible to scientists so people can
share that plant or that actu accession
and so they will conduct studies on that
same plant from which the genome was
obtained and right now i mean it's not a
matter that
people don't want to share that they
cannot share the plan because it's
forbidden
so jamaican lion i mean i'm sure that
people would like to get their ends on
it but right now especially between
countries so from canada we cannot
import from the us
and i'm not sure you guys could export
anyway uh so it's it's very a big
problem so when even going further so
you know
most crops they have those germplasm
repositories you know that
that scientists have access to so they
have all those different accessions land
races sometimes mutants
uh or sometimes mapping populations and
that's how that's how the scientific
community will move forward more rapidly
but we don't we don't have that for
cannabis yet
so winding down here for the for the
purposes of
maybe breeding out some of these mlo
genes that are causing susceptibility
where do we go from here what are sort
of the next steps
well what i just talked about so if we
could have access to more plants you
know more more
uh you know a lot of because right now
we know that what's available in the
commercial space is still very limited
from a genetic point of view so we know
that there are
huge
like yeah there is a lot more variation
elsewhere
so we need to to get our hands on that
and see if that mlo based resistance
maybe already exists within
that germplasm
if it doesn't exist then maybe we need
to create it so we have access now to
some biotechnological tools like crispr
to do some genome editing but those
tools are not working for cannabis now
so i know a lot of people are trying to
develop those tools but once we get them
it will be and i'm not talking only
about mlo here
but you know for any trade that we
will discover maybe a you know a link
between a genotype and a phenotype let's
talk about you know a trichome formation
or flowering or
other types of disease resistance so you
know we we see correlation between the
genomic data and the and and what we
observe of the plant but we need to
confirm those by you know inactivating
genes or over expressing genes so some
functional studies but
right now we don't have the tools to do
that so that's where where
we're lagging or where there is a
bottleneck right now
do you worry about how the cannabis
community might accept crispr
uh well you know
maybe
so
that's where also we that's why i always
like to you know have both words so we
develop the biotechnological tools but
at the same time we try to explore as
much as possible you know the natural
variation that that we have
and then if if the community really
doesn't want to hear about crispr then
maybe we can find some alternative that
have been accepted by the the the
organic farming world so when we talk
about
uh
traditional muted mutagenesis so you
know we have the the
pink ruby grapefruit which was created
that way but you can still grow it like
organically so
to me crispr is not different from that
it's even better but
we'll go with what people accept
all right well it seems like the
regulations though are really an
impediment to really making a dent in
this and many other
um breeding breakthroughs that we could
be making
yeah for sure but you know at the same
time you know doing research on cannabis
was not even possible 10 years ago so
things are moving fast so maybe those
those impediments will also fall in the
near future
let's hope so so
um
before i let you go i wanted to give you
the opportunity to share with the
audience um
any
additional resources you think might be
of interest or any
website or social media to stay in
contact with you
share away
uh well i mean i'm on twitter
id
j-o-l-y so that's my username there
so i i don't tweet that often but you
know when i tweet it's usually because
we have a new paper or something so
that's a good way to know uh what we're
doing so we we published quite a few in
in the last
few months so we're also working on you
know
looking at beneficial bacteria or they
can promote
uh
cannabis growth and stuff like that so
there's a you know it's not only very
hard to understand genomic stuff but we
also do other type of stuff so and
hopefully we'll continue to to look at
that in cannabis so and not only disease
resistance so you know we're interested
in looking into other traits
so we'll see what the future brings
all right we'll be the topic for another
podcast i'm sure yeah
all right well thanks again david for
joining us um and hopefully we will see
you about a cam ed for sure see you
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr david jolie
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor canopedia.net
our next episode will drop october 13th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out
canmedevents.com
to view the canmed 2022 schedule explore
the canmed archive listen to previous
podcast episodes and sign up for email
alerts
if social media is more your thing you
can stay connected with us on instagram
twitter linkedin and facebook
speaking of facebook check out the
canmed community facebook group it's a
great way to connect with fellow
attendees and presenters in between
events
and one last thing please rate review
and subscribe on your favorite podcast
app
doing so really helps the podcast reach
more listeners
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please do join us for the
next canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you