[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
head over to cannemedevents.com now to
learn all about our canmed 2022 event
which will take place may 3rd through
5th at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
this three-day event begins with a full
day medical practicum led by dr bonnie
goldstein the practicum's originator as
well as dr dustin sulak dr kevin
spellman and eloise thiessen
each of the presenters will share the
latest research as well as their
clinical experience and practice
guidelines related to cannabinoid
therapeutics
a new section of this eight-hour course
is dedicated to reviewing different
types of extractions products and
optimal dosing for cannabinoid
therapeutics
after that we have two full days of
presentations and panel discussions
covering the latest research in the
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing taking place may 4th
and 5th
the full schedule is up at
canmedevents.com
you'll notice that each of the canmed
focus areas are anchored by a keynote
presenter
dr ethan russo for science seth crawford
for cultivation dr bonnie goldstein for
medicine and grace bandong for safety
testing
each of our keynotes as well as many of
our presenters and panelists were guests
on the podcast and you can listen to all
our previous episodes at
cammanevents.com coffeetalk
while you're at canmedevents.com you can
also watch video presentations and panel
discussions from all of our previous
canva events in our canmed video archive
presentations include
canmed2022
dr rousseau seth crawford and dr
goldstein as well as professor rafael
mishulam david miri marcus rogen zamir
punja stacy gruber and many many more
as you can tell we have a lot going on
at kmanevents.com
and the best way to keep up with
everything is to sign up for email
alerts using the simple form in the page
footer
or on the pop-up form that you'll find
at camedevents.com
you can also follow us on facebook
instagram twitter or linkedin
just look for cam at events
this episode we welcome colin palmer who
is the chief experience officer at
vessel life science colin has been
obsessed with growing cannabis since he
started growing in his backyard at 15
years old
since then he has consulted with many
cannabis companies on a variety of areas
including genetic selection lab
optimization product development
branding and more
over the past several years he has
worked on bringing that experience to
vessel life science which has been
focused on working with several brands
to bring new solvent-less products to
market in 2022
during our conversation we cover
colin's journey in the cannabis industry
starting with his first plants to his
current projects
the education and mentorship he received
from cannabis cultivation pioneers
how regulations create barriers for
legacy growers to participate in the
current cannabis industry
how business pressures stifle innovation
from commercial cultivators and
encourage copycat tactics
why thc and cbd values alone do a poor
job of describing cannabis products
the fact that how and when cannabis is
harvested cured and dried can influence
taste and experience for the user
why plant pathogens seem to be more
prevalent now than ever before
how plant pathogens especially hop
latent viroid can destroy a cultivation
business
subtle cues that hop latent viroid
infected plants can show
and more
before we get to my conversation with
colin i'd like to thank this episode's
sponsor vino express
fino express offers low-cost genetic
testing services to cultivation
facilities
using qpcr technology phenoexpress helps
cultivators identify genetic traits such
as plant sex while plants are still in
the seedling tray they can also identify
plant pathogens such as hoblaten viroid
lettuce chlorosis virus and powdery
mildew before plants show obvious signs
of infection
contact phenoexpress today so they can
help you predict prevent and eliminate
major crop problems before they happen
to learn more about how you can
accelerate your final hunt with
phenoexpress go to afinoexpress.com
that's p
h e n o
x p r e s s
dot com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with colin palmer
[Music]
good afternoon colin thanks for joining
us
thanks for having me everyone it's
pleasure to be here
all right um so i'm really excited to
talk with you today because i know you
have a lot of experience and a lot of
different areas of cannabis cultivation
from from breeding to extraction i
couldn't even call it from seed to sale
and i know in our email exchange before
we started recording we identified a
couple different topics that we want to
cover but i thought before we get into
that a good way to get started might be
it might be appropriate for you to tell
the listeners a bit about yourself how
you got started in
how you got started in the industry and
what you're doing now
yeah so
thanks for having me um you know the
cannabis plant has been a part of my
life since i've been a young guy being a
you know
15 16 years old i started growing my
first plants
really
in an amateur sort of way being
influenced off of books from mel frank
and things that i was reading a lot of
pop culture kind of influenced me from
the grateful dead scene to the fish
scene
and of course other styles of music like
jazz
um so
you know i got really excited about
plants um at a really young age and
cannabis was um to me at the time really
the ultimate plant to explore
um there was a lot of uh it was very
apparent very quickly
that there was a lot to this particular
plant and a lot of um
a lot to explore so um you know whether
that be uh different types of varieties
or you know just a plant morphology in
general was very interesting at the time
and that really you know drove me into
looking and reading and researching and
it drove me to places like you know
laughingmoon.com which was uh
run by a canadian group which
you know kind of formed into uh
you know overgrow.com from the you know
british columbia growers associations
days
and there was a wealth of knowledge
there were you know there are people
like vic high
and um sub cool and um dave watson
robert clark and and several other
individuals that were posting
information that i could quickly grab
onto and start to read and start to
iterate on
my own uh version of what that was at a
young age
um and you know
i you know immediately i've been an
artist my whole life and um i started
studying horticulture um in a really
serious way as i got into my 20s
um i went to school for art and design
and science
and i studied organic chemistry during
that time
i went to school in new york and had a
really big deep dive into that world of
looking at um
you know this just organic chemistry in
a really
open-minded way and that's what led me
to uh
cannabinoid distraction and really
starting to learn
about what that was you know i just
immediately started washing hash in 1999
and that was my first forte into
actually extracting any type of
cannabinoid from the plant um and any
type of chemical you know so to speak so
it was you know those days it was a hot
wash it was you know ice and water
middle of the day or mixing with a
wooden spoon or a spoon and then you're
drying it in these large patties
creating pretty much charis which is a
you know
a type of hash that's a cured resin
that's an air dried resin
and through that time you know you
started
you know started noticing
the nuances of extraction through that
that simple process but it also got my
curiosity into solvent-based extraction
so i started you know playing with
ethanol and
as soon as the other types of
extractions came around i was naturally
just interested
but circling that back into where i
began and why um you know it was really
um the idea of art and science merging
together that really caught my attention
to this is that you know plants were
like art you grow these things and
they're immediate art is very immediate
it's a very immediate
function that you and reward that you
you can you know give yourself
and i really enjoyed that simple
pleasure of that so that's where the
idea of growing lots of different
varieties
at a young age came into play because it
was very fascinating to see a california
orange next to
a skunk or
an nl5
you know sitting next to a strawberry uh
cough or a sour diesel and you could see
the the
not only the polymorphic you know
differences but the aromic properties
and and the actual
you know just the the presence of the of
the plant structure itself
really was immediate in terms of the
reward that you saw and then the
exchange of information between
you know comparing and contrasting those
it was really interesting to me and it
really just drawn me in and drew me into
the world of just getting into reading
everything that dave watson had you know
put out and skunk man sam had put out
and diving into robert clark's
literature and then going even further
you know going into real
you know
looking at white papers that i could
find
um and ultimately becoming friends with
uh you know marcus richardson who is a
dear friend of mine and somewhat of a
mentor
at an early age of all this
we were exchanging lots of information
and um
yeah so it just kind of snowballed from
there but it was really the intent and
the uh
the ideology that we could we could
learn more about this plan and it was
immediate and we could actually react to
it
that
simple thing actually
through the years you know grew into
what i would consider today
an actual business which i didn't really
plan for
at all um i wasn't you know i never
really bel it's not that i didn't
believe i didn't really know where this
was all headed um and i knew at some
point we would be able to grow these
plants and mass population as we see
today
there's you know there's more people
growing this plant than there ever has
ever in the world so you know with that
comes what we see
of an industry there's the good bad ugly
and um you know the the the legacy
farmers and then there's the the new
uh
you know individuals that are coming
into the industry that are now
interested because of um
you know interests that are that are
beyond the plan you know which quite
frankly yeah the plan is a part of it
that the driving factor is not the plan
um
in most cases
yeah
so
you started when you were 15.
yeah you must have had um
either some
understanding parents or some parents
who weren't paying much attention which
was it
um i had some parents that were
understanding and um also cautious at
the same time
um
you know i i think you know my my dad um
was really encouraging and he
you know he didn't actually believe that
i could manage all of it honestly and
when he saw all of it he he kind of
chuckled and said well
at least they know what you're good at
and uh
you know
you know i i was obsessive you know like
every day after school straight to the
patch you know and this is outdoor at
the time you know the indoor was really
um difficult at the time you know a
young guy like that you're not growing
going under lights like that it's uh you
know
but um what i would say is um it was it
was uh all i thought about all i could
think about um every day day in and day
out um that art and music were the the
three things for me that were
just all-encompassing it's all i cared
about um and still to this day it's
quite frankly it's all i truly care
about um and um
you know it's
it's interesting you know it's um
like music um cannabinoids are really um
dynamic and
and like harmonics you have this moment
where things come together and dissipate
and that's um
that's cannabinoids to me in a in a
nutshell after you've uh combusted them
you know or or you utilize them for um
for delivery
so you know they have this beautiful
harmonic frequency that they bring to
your body and your body is able to grab
onto your endocannabinoid system which
is very individual just again just like
how sound travels to your to your your
nervous system
the rest of your body
so
with that said you know
i had an opportunity to build a company
in uh in in the you know in the state of
massachusetts so i spent um
you know the past three four years of my
life dedicating my time and um
to bringing all the things that i've
researched um and consulted on
because i was a consultant before i went
after my my own license
and i was working with several different
outfits to optimize their workflow
lab workflow their sku creation
you know their branding their
go-to-market strategies
um how
a product sits in a market
and why
that said sku should be made
and these are questions and things that
need answers to that
you'd be surprised not many people have
answers to them
um in in the market today um
so
i think there's a big big white space
right now
um and there continues to be um because
the spirit of cannabinoids is still
widely under
really understudied and underutilized
um so yes we have products we have we
have things that we grab onto such as
tack and
you know the the ideology of terpenes
and in by volume
um but these are widely uh understudied
and under underutilized in terms of um
quantitative and qualitative results you
know so
when you look at these things you know
we we're
at this moment in the industry there's a
really great opportunity for innovation
and um
and uh you know expansion in the terms
of product skus and offering and
delivery for the human
we really aren't
where
most individuals want us you know
believe that we are which is really far
ahead and we have very sophisticated
delivery systems
um you know it's it's
it's going to take some time it's going
to take the right minds to come together
yes we have a culture
but
we don't study
toxicology
in these these environments we study
the plant we study
the chemicals that grow on the plant to
optimize those chemicals to to you know
so we can then utilize them for
extraction but there's there's so much
more to explore
and um
you know it's it's a it's a really
exciting time because i think everyone
um has an opportunity to really have a
voice right now
and the industry really needs um
needs innovation
yeah you know
we're i feel like we're kind of
stuck in a vacuum and a lot of respect
yeah no i i think it's interesting you
say that that
you know maybe the industry is not as
far as long as we like to think that it
is so
where do you
where would you like to see it
um
see it go
you know it's a good question um
i i'd like to see us go into more um
you know real research on on these
chemicals and better testing standards
for um
you know building the right testing
procedures to actually tell the a larger
and more detailed story
right now it seems like we're about five
percent of
the chemicals we're
we're testing for about five percent
right now it seems you know based on
what what is known that is there on the
plan
versus what
um the test results that we get back
from these labs
and um that doesn't really give you much
insight you know it's very top it's not
even top line it's it's just very
overview and very general
um so i'd love to see a standardization
but i also
don't through that
through that lens i don't believe we
should be hindering labs because they
need to be developing new standards
along the way
yes we need to agree on something but we
also need to let them
innovate and and collaborate with policy
makers to help them understand
the intricacies of you know testing for
these chemicals
um you know i see
you know a lot of different states have
a lot of different types of mandates for
different requirements that they have in
their rules and regs and you know if we
can't all agree on something
behind the scenes i think it's
problematic
state to state it just it really becomes
difficult
if you're an operator in florida
you have sops that are specific to that
state and those mandates you go to
california
are those the same sops and how do you
standardize a product across
markets if you don't have the
standardization
um
you know from the from a testing
standpoint
so um and and you know i'd also like it
to go into um
you know just want to add this is that
you know there's a lot of legacy growers
that
have put
more work in than they can actually talk
about in a bed
and the um the path that they've walked
is a path that has been
extremely stressful and dangerous for
them and their families and their
communities
and i feel that
sometimes yes
it's hard to run a business and not
everyone's fit to run a business but
i think it's hard to swallow when we
don't have a path for people to
create a business
in a market or
if you want to call it a state or
whatever you want to call it
for these individuals to live on and to
pass those torches on you know you're
talking about generational growers and
individuals have kept these varieties
that a lot of these big box individuals
are coming in and just getting a cut for
five six six hundred thousand dollars
and
all of a sudden they have a brand too
and they're growing the same varietals
um and
you know it's it's tough to swallow that
there's um
you know
there's really no one to help
the dying breed of community and um
and culture that that is you know legacy
cannabis
um it's really hard to see so
uh a good example of that is is where
we're at in california um and i think
you know if we can have better policy
um better cooperation from
you know
how things uh had run from 215 to 64 to
where it's going now
um i think the conversation could be
steered and
we get to have a better future for a lot
of these individuals that are truly
truly here for the plant truly here for
um
you know the best
resin the best uh terpenes that they can
they can grow on the plant and the the
fullest expression these these specific
rivals that they can't get so
i'd love to see a path for everyone to
participate legacy the corporations
the you know the niche
um you know and that's what i'd like to
see yeah
and how much of it is
sort of over regulation creating
barriers for some of these like you said
legacy growers or those who don't have
you know endless funding to sort of pay
for all the necessary licenses or
requirements that the regulators set
forth like how much of that is the issue
with
kind of
gatekeeping these folks
i think it's i think it's a lot of um
over
regulation in terms of the
the steps you have to go to get to
market and what you have to pay for to
get that product in market
and what the
the pit stops of of that cost structure
meaning
if i pay for testing
if i'm making water hash let me just use
an example i'm i'm testing the flour i'm
testing the water hash and i'm testing
the rosin right that's three touch
points of rosin earth of testing
that um could be
you know half the cost of the overall
grant
um and
you know if you're not doing large
batches the state is going to tax you
based on that number and the times that
you're testing and then it has to go to
distribution and they have to do their
own
right
so there's there's um
there's too many pit stops and um
the cost to do these things
amounts
to you know just pricing yourself right
out
you know so i think that
that's the biggest problem too and also
the cost of uh you know cost per gram
now is
you know it's strong in some states but
really weak in others
and it's really hard when you know a
farmer's been
doing this for a really long time and
then all of a sudden
you know
yeah they might be making a pound for
450 and
you know
but by the time they add up labor and
testing costs and everything else
they're more like 750
you know and that's a really difficult
thing to swallow
as a business that is growing and young
and you know like i was young once too i
i i learned a lot about business through
lots of trial and error you know and you
know i'm fortunate to have come out the
other end really
sound and
you know better for it but um
you know i didn't have catastrophic
events happen where everything was gone
so
that's that's what i see
just the way that it's evolved is
there's a lot of pit stops and then you
have to deal with distribution which is
kind of
its own beast in itself and um you know
these things need to be streamlined so
individuals can get product to market
where they're not taxing themselves
literally out of the market
yeah
all right i want to
switch gears a little bit and start
talking about um genetics because i know
uh you've got quite a collection of
cultivars
uh we've amassed one over the years uh
including some rare genetics some land
ray strains um sorry if you talk about
like what are some of your favorite cuts
that you have or that that are out there
and maybe kind of talk about
what we're seeing in the marketplace in
terms of different varieties
yeah so that's a good question so when i
say we're we're in a vacuum i i i think
um
i think i'm really talking about that
from not only a product's u perspective
but also a varietal perspective um you
know we let pop culture drive a lot of
our decisions as humans around us and
and i think
in
the instance that we're in right now um
you know there's there's certain players
in the game and certain individuals that
are um are really pushing their
their point of view in terms of what
they believe is good and that's
resonating with
everybody you know and and back to the
music analogy
um you know there's trends that come
along you know their styles of music and
their styles of genetics that are going
to come along and we're all going to
start doing that type of style
to stay current to say contemporary
right
and um you know cannabis has just like
music has vintage varietals it has
classic varietals it has
the backbone and the the language of in
which we
you know are the building blocks if you
will of of it all you know it's the
your your
your nl5 and your your skunk one and
your haze
and then moving forward from your haze
you have your modern haze which is the
jack herrera which is kind of been
you know again that's another bridle
that is in a vacuum you know it kind of
does chirps that terpenolane just kind
of took over
um jack carrera was probably you know if
i was i'm
kind of
you know making a joke about it he's
kind of like the first kind of uh
influencer you know that was ben donkers
kind of took jack carrera and utilized
him as a as an influencer and and
created the varietal around him right
and that was really to curb the sativa
to be more commercial to be a 16 12 you
know 12 16 week variety could be
um could be actually 11 12 weeks you
know
so
um i think you know genetics today
um
you know i think we're getting a little
not bottlenecked but um you know i think
just in the commercial sense
we're all growing the same things
um and we're all trying to package them
differently
and they're predominantly the same
and you know yeah this guy may have used
more sugars in week seven than the next
but
predominantly at scale in a commercial
setting you know there's it's all the
same stuff you go on everyone's menu
it's a version of each other
um and you know look the cannabis is
it's such a vast
i mean look at the canopy it's such a
vast sea of amazing
uh chemotypes and phenotypes and i i
wonder um yes i understand in commercial
that we we have to stay within certain
scheduling but i always wonder
why we pigeonhole ourselves to
try to try to get things out onto a
market to just stay relevant um and you
know listen i i'm a true believer if
you're not innovating you're dying
and if you're just buying and saying
growing the same cuts everybody else is
that's not innovating to me
you know um and there's just so much
good stuff out there you know i have
older land race stuff that i was gifted
that you know
i would still consider a hybrid of of
sorts you know sure it's it's
quote air quotes uh land race but um
you can see the expressions out of these
plants that they're um they're robust
they have great resin production
their you know terpene profiles are
super intense they're a bit more spicy
and a bit different than you know a lot
of these contemporary varietals but
they're very special
very different um
in terms of how they produce and and
and all the things that go along with
that so um i i would love to see people
start to explore um
you know just new new avenues um and
yeah
the thing that's really interesting to
me is like flavors now this idea of
flavors right are all being repackaged
and represented to us but
i mean none of this stuff is really new
in terms of taste right i mean all these
flavors have been here um
you know when gmo came through it was
just like a really great super skunk to
me you know it just started really
producing
it had this really dank you know
beautiful um you know chem d feel to it
but it was tight and better better you
know tighter structure so that's where
the girl scout cookie came in on that as
an example of the contemporary variety
that everyone grows
and look most of these things are grown
time and time again because it's
horticulturally sound to do that it's
at scale
you know it's why people love to hate on
blue dream but man if you've ever grown
that variety it's it's
it's pretty great to grow i mean yeah do
i do i think there's much better things
yeah but but
in that moment you see why you're like
oh yeah okay
it's insane that's a great plant it's a
grower's plant so
on the flip side og kush is not really a
grower's plant it's really sparse it's
really lanky it falls over all the time
it needs lots of support so you know in
commercial settings those plants are
hard to grow and they don't yield much
you know
so
my point is is that
there's a lot to explore
there's a lot of great breeders out
there today that we just didn't have
before um you know you could really
count them on your hands for a while you
know it was really that was it and and
beyond that was like you know of course
you know
the common turn a pollen checker right
um but you know let's face it most of
our contemporary and you know varietals
that we have seen through the 90s were
all bag seed
chem 91 chem four
you know ken juan you know
sour d all these things were not
actually bred by someone intentionally
um they were
people that were good stewards of the
plan
so um with that i you know
i encourage people to explore explore
the bag see that you were going to throw
out
grow seeds and you know be a good
champion a good steward of them
i'm not saying you're going to find the
next chemd but i think it's good to
live in that world of um
i want to explore and you know in the
world of discovery
yeah
no and it sounds like from what you're
saying that
sort of all the overhead all the
additional testing all the licenses
is sort of stifling innovation right
because you want to grow these plants
that are going to yield the most and
that are proven
uh winners in retail too like they're
gonna they're gonna sell so right sort
of the appetite to really put yourself
out there and take a risk is not really
there
yeah and especially when you have um
you have people to answer to right if
you're let's say your company that has a
set schedule and you only have a certain
amount of rooms
you can only produce a set amount of
pounds per month per year
you have to stick to the schedule
because that's tied to other things that
are way outside of creativity right
these are these are hardline things that
don't incorporate creativity but i have
to
to remind everyone and invite them to
say look
then you need to build creativity into
the business plan because if you don't
have it
then
what are you truly doing you're just you
know
is that is that uh
is that what you want you know
um so
that's one thing i would i you know i
truly look at a lot as um how people are
looking at the world around them and the
the space that they occupy
and um you know again it's it's
retail is predominantly not all that
different than one another go to another
shop it's just a different registers and
to the left instead of the right and
there might be a touch screen in that
corner instead of the left hand side
corner right but predominantly the
education isn't really there yet and we
don't have the language quite yet to be
educational on a sales floor and to be
able to talk about a varietal in a way
that actually
um
does its justice you know is is really
it's tough man
um but it's uh it's something that i i
really hope that we can get
a good handle on in the next you know
five to ten years and
start to develop language around um
you know the right way to talk about
cannabis it's it's really hard man as
much as we all think we know we just
don't know yeah
no and you're spot on with you know the
retail experience being
being very similar i mean i i can only
speak really to here in massachusetts
and i know it might be different in
other states but sure i mean you you
look at the menus and it's all the same
stuff
um they're only really reporting on thc
cbd content they don't even really talk
about the terpenes
and it's it's sort of like how am i
supposed to know
if one's better than the other um right
and
i mean it's all thc dominant too like
you rarely ever see a one-to-one or any
other even just
different ratios of cbd to thc let alone
uh turbulence so yeah i agree with you
there's just a huge fact
yeah we need to be exploring more
cannabinoids um i i
you know to your point to the one to one
point i you know one to one two to one
three to one uh
twenty to one you know forty to one i
mean listen
there's a lot of um
there's a lot to be explored with how
cannabinoids interact with one another
and then how that interaction interacts
with you
and to you your point here um thca and
th delta nines
ruled the game right it is
is the selling a quantitative selling
point for for bud tenders right now and
i have to say this out loud that is
completely a false
sense of reality
that is not going to tell you
anything about what that varietal is
going to do for you individually
at all it's going to give you a glimpse
into what the testing told you
what could possibly be there by mass by
weight right
um and you know furthermore
it's not telling you how that variety is
was taken down or trimmed or cured
and uh are the the trichome heads cloudy
or amber
um things like this are
are wildly left out of the conversation
and you know harvest date you know when
was it harvest
do you buy do you buy based on
expiration date i mean when you go into
whole foods you buy based on expiration
date
and the back label
right and
the unfortunate part about cannabis is
we can't lead with the back label quite
yet but i think that what we can do is
we can look at the chemical properties
by volume and generally start to draw
these correlations between what your bio
assay is telling you
and you can start physically
kind of in your you know in interacting
with this product
in a way that tells you the results so i
do think that there is value in the data
i think we need to start looking at it
from educational standpoint and better
build better language around it so then
the blood tenders that we give these
amazing products to can actually talk
about them
and have a person walk away with some
sort of subtype of substance
that allows them to be better educated
and better for it yeah
no it's a great point you make about you
know how it was aged or how it was cured
and you know i always sort of
draw the analogy whether appropriate or
not to to alcohol right like
a lot of whiskey products are
are marketed based on you know how they
were aged which type of barrels they
were put in so i mean the whole concept
shouldn't really be foreign to people
that
you know we could be looking past just
data points that come out of the lab
that there there's more to the end
product than that
that's right and you know back to this
one to one thing i want to touch on that
just one more time is one of my favorite
varieties for
searching for those types of things is
the work that ringo did ringo's gift and
the varieties that come off of that um
harlequin is another one from um
wade laughter
house of harlequin has been a staple i
think in those types of
ratios of cannabinoids and the work that
he has put in
um over the years to to make sure that
those varieties are in circulation is
is really inspiring in stellar work um
you know cantatonic is another great
variety
um
so there's there's there's quite a few
and that's just me you know throwing a
few out there but um
yeah those are some varieties i think
would be uh
great to explore and there's a lot of
possibilities there
now
kind of going back to that whole idea of
drawing the parallels to
alcohol
um do you ever see envision a future
we'll have something that's similar to
like say craft beer where we have more
craft cannabis like these smaller
growers who maybe do smaller batches
of these more unique varieties
i know it doesn't sound like given the
climate today that that's really
feasible but
you know potentially
that would be i mean that'd be great
right
yeah i think i think it would be great
um you know
boutique cannabis is um you know
cannabis is a perishable um i just want
to start saying that uh let's have to
get that in there um cannabis is a
perishable and you know there's a point
when you do have too much
um you know and i think that's something
not everyone has the foresight to to
check themselves on um when they start
looking at balance sheets and you know
pounds per month it starts just you know
you get in a different mindset and i i
invite everyone to look at this from a
more practical standpoint
and you know ask yourself could we be
better for it if we focus on other
things rather than more
um you know look at the industrial age
it's mediocre products for mediocre for
a mediocre environment
and um
that shouldn't be cannabis um i i don't
you know sure there's people that want
that angle and you have to kind of ask
yourself who you want to be
but um
yeah you know i think that there's a
world where craft canvas
is what people
truly want and i think that's the world
that we're going to that will shape up
eventually
you know if we can learn from
all the other markets that have
developed around us
and and you know specifically a federal
market
you know going big is not has not really
worked out and um you know growing an
ornamental crop like cannabis
is very difficult at scale and you have
to be you know your teams have to be
firing off on all cylinders everybody
has to be in great communication the
systems have to be running great
in most all cases that's not the case
you know and
that's problematic i think for high
quality cannabis and and all of these
things that we've been speaking about
which is getting
bulbous and capital cecil and capitate
stocked
you know resin glands to grow in in
large amounts and the nasal chemicals to
grow within them um you know you have to
have um you know you start at 100
and everything you do wrong knocks the
point off right
and it's
you know whether it's environmental in
your vpd or ppfd you know you don't you
don't know
but
all of these things together have to be
in harmony and
those that harmonics has to come
together um together
in a really methodical way to make high
quality cannabis at scale happen
and i don't think the world's seen that
yet i think we've seen some pretty
you know some pretty great things happen
i think the the industry is evolving in
a really interesting way but there's a
lot of a lot of room there for
improvement and and
i invite everyone to look at you know
just because you can should you
yeah
no that's a good point about you know
growing at scale
and kind of going back to this whole
idea of
you know the everyone's growing the same
thing and how much of that is that
because
you know if you were growing all
different types of varieties you're
going to have to have them in different
environments that are sort of best
suited for those plants and like that's
just that's just not gonna work
we're not there yet you know in terms of
you know genetics um
you know look
we're super far away from this idea of
standardization and maybe there are
teams that aren't sharing the
information that i don't know about
which is entirely possible and i always
say this if you're thinking about it
it's happening
um you know
it it
we have a long way to go to say that
these varieties should be grown in these
regions at these temperatures
um we've just a lot of data to collect
and a lot of breeding to do
um to be able to get the the genetics in
a place like that um
but you know i hope one day we we have
some ideology um around that but i don't
at the same time i want to say this as
well it's like i don't
in this in the pursuit of
standardization let's not lose sight of
creativity and the fact that f1 and
the idea of of not leaving an f1 is um
is exciting now i think that the
industries pigeonholed itself to not go
past f1 because people are just moving
on too quick right
but to standard you know stabilize
something to have something that's truly
unique in uniform
i think um
you know we have we're a long ways away
from that
yeah
and i guess another thing that kind of
just struck me too is you know
if
you know until the industry sort of
keeps up and they're able to to innovate
and and grow these different varieties
i mean i guess there's always the option
to to grow yourself right to home grow
and that's a good way to express
or to connect everybody varieties
everybody should grow at home everyone
should have plants at home i think they
you know look growing cannabis is very
hard it's not an easy task and i think
it's important for people to understand
um
understand that it's it's uh
again back to music it's like music you
can grab a guitar from from a guitar
center but you still have to learn how
to play it before you get in front of
people and that's similar here you gotta
learn and go through it and understand
what uh
what spider mites are um well nowadays
what what pm looks like you know and um
what the hop laden viroid uh might look
like you know these are all things that
um you know those are two newer things
that we didn't have
as prevalent back uh in the early 2000s
and late 90s but
these are things that you have to go
through i think
and sometimes listen you can grow some
amazing stuff and you can have your own
your own version of what you see around
you in pop culture
so you mentioned pm and
and viroid kind of being these
newer issues on the scene that
cultivators have to deal with
uh i guess i was more familiar with
hoplate and viroid sort of being newer
but it was interested to hear that pm
wasn't as much of an issue uh years ago
when you were first getting started
yeah no you know i
yeah honestly um
you know
those types of diseases um
i was not pre you know i i was not aware
of
you know
in
let's say 99 2000 2001
and then that's when i started reading
more about
powdery mildew
and seeing more powdery mildew um being
passed around through cuts or
friends that were you know saying hey my
my whole grows bond out what do we do
and that's where products like green
cure came in and
you know sulfur and all these things
were being talked about
at a at a time like that now
was uh pm
a disease that's been identified yeah
absolutely
but for myself and other growers um
we were not um
as as infected by things like that at
all
um sure you'd see the case of like you
know mites and stuff but
again we didn't have russet mites right
we didn't have
these super bugs that
took out whole gardens in the matter of
you know 72 hours
so
it's
you know those types of things were
really new at the time and then you know
that you know of course we made all
kinds of bad mistakes everybody used
eagle 20. i mean gosh it was it was bad
um
you know and again this is all because
we didn't have anyone to talk to
there's if if we had a bigger
pipeline of communication everyone could
have been better educated at the time
and we just weren't yeah and i think
that's highly contributed to that
and then fast forward to today with
hoplade and viroid you know um
we had identified a couple plants that
came from a nursery in california that
um were hot for hlbp and with top lane
viroid and um
you know it's
it's it's heartbreaking to see things
like that because we don't have the
right guidance um that's publicly
available and a roadmap that doesn't
cost you 12 months and and 15k
to get a varietal clean again and the
best answers i've gotten were call the
plant today or
you could go into the deep dive right so
how you know as a community do we
start to talk about this and have
dialogue on it to help
help each other
not have this type of viroid wreak havoc
on your businesses because
cannabis has always been kind of loose
right like yeah it's weed we grow plants
you know but today it's not loose it's
tight it's there's margins there's
people that have their whole lives on
the line and a viroid like this will
wipe out your whole business
and from growing these plants and
studying a hotblade enviroid in confined
spaces
and having my own bio assay with it
as i call it
you can see how
it performs and adversely could totally
ruin everything
i mean
the way that the flower structure grows
on these plants versus plants that don't
have it is night and day
um and if you didn't know what you were
looking for you would never know
you just said oh that's a low yielding
yielding plan that's just one that's the
way she is
that's not the case um oh she's you know
they didn't produce enough terpenes this
run well no it's because it's sick how
does a human perform when you're sick
right how is the plant supposed to
perform when they're sick
so
those are the things that we have to be
really um we used to be looking out for
not only ourselves but each other
because
one day you're going to want to cut from
your buddy who's going to be happily
giving it to you
and you're going to then grow it and
start cloning other things with it not
even knowing because it's your buddy and
you trust your buddy
and your buddy's just a nice guy and
he's unbeknownst to him he's passing you
know hot blade and viroid to your whole
garden and it's it's a it's a domino
effect of just
great intentions with the worst outcome
you know and and that's what i see today
is you know nurseries they have all the
best intentions you know we all do we
all have great intentions but um if if
we're not checking ourselves and that's
why i think you know the work that
medicine genomics is doing is super
important
um
to the future of where agriculture and
and horticulture is going for cannabis
um because we need
to have the insight
to be able to make better decisions that
are educated based on
cleanliness
uh
vigor and fit to perform
you know and and
if these things aren't done
one day we might find uh sour diesel
chem 91 and chem d completely out of our
language because the last man standing
got got hlv because
he uh took a cut from his buddy
yeah i mean and that is sort of the most
at least in my mind the most kind of
insidious thing about it is that it's so
like you said
unless you knew what you were looking
for you wouldn't you wouldn't know you
even had it i mean things like pm
um it's pretty obvious you know you have
white splotches all over your plant like
oh i got pm but up late and viral it's a
lot harder to identify
yeah it's impos it's not impossible that
it's it's um from a visual standpoint
there are cues that i've been learning
that the plant will give you like
like your stems will just snap like
clean
like surgical clean bone snap right in
half um
it's like cucumber almost it's like a
cucumber snap so you start to pick up on
these these these cues that six plants a
sick plant will give you but um again
there's no
real literature that will say that it's
definitively can be eradicated from the
plant quite yet there's there's some
and if someone does out there on this
it's a listener under no away
please reach out and um we'd love i'd
love to speak with you on to how
you're approaching um you know you know
eradication
um because you know most of the things
we see
are you know therapies and in different
you know tc and meristem
um you know paths to to do it however
there's been no definitive evidence that
it doesn't come
back and this is probably a dumb
question but i'm going to ask it anyway
um
i i read that it's not common for hlvd
to be passed through seas so
what about sort of selfing a sick plant
in trying to grow from those seeds
um you know i think there's
i think i think that needs to be studied
more um you know i i
i've i've heard that you know five
percent of the seed could be infected
right um
you know i
it's really who knows i think that's
that's the the larger
honest answer there
but um i think that larger populations
and studies larger studies need to be
done to better identify what um is being
passed on and
you know
again it needs a host right so how is
the seed going to be a host um
you know so there's a lot to to learn
but uh i think that you know
that's a really good point you know i
i'm not sure if an s1 would do the trick
um
but i think it's something that you know
again we need we need
more long-term studies we need some
we need to really understand it
yeah absolutely i mean it's a lot of
work to be done on that front
all right um i definitely do want to be
mindful of your time calling and thanks
so much for taking the time but before i
let you go i want to give you a chance
to plug any website social media any way
people can get in touch with you or or
follow what you're doing
yeah sure um so you can walk you can
follow me on vessel life science
on instagram and vessellifescience.com
we
are a we are extractionists we're
cultivators and
we are building uh different sku
offerings and different brands in the
marketplace through the country
and i'm really excited to uh be working
with an in particular company to date
that um
we're doing some really great projects
together that will release solvents
products in the markets so
um you should see some products uh
next year start to trickle out and in
the meantime we're uh focusing heavily
on genetic r d
uh formulation r d and innovation uh and
on on all those fronts
so um
you know if people want to reach out to
us please do and i'd love to collaborate
with anyone that's
interested
all right excellent and when those
products start coming out we'll have to
have you back on again because we didn't
even we didn't even touch on solventless
extraction so that'll be for another
podcast
yeah no doubt yeah solving this
extraction um
it's our it's our that's our number one
so
i appreciate it
all right well thanks again for the time
and hope to see you at canmed
yeah thanks so much guys thanks for
having me
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
colin palmer check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
our sponsor fino express
our next episode will drop november 10th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out
canmedevents.com
to view the canmed 2022 schedule explore
the canmed archive listen to previous
podcast episodes and sign up for email
alerts
if social media is more your thing you
can stay connected with us on instagram
twitter linkedin and facebook speaking
of facebook check out the canmed
community facebook group it's a great
way to connect with fellow attendees and
presenters in between events
and one last thing please rate review
and subscribe on your favorite podcast
app
doing so really helps the podcast reach
more listeners
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please do join us for the
next canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you