[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben emerald i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
head over to cannemedevents.com now to
learn all about our canmed 2022 event
which will take place may 3rd through
5th at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
this three-day event begins with a
full-day medical practicum led by dr
bonnie goldstein the practicum's
originator as well as dr dustin sulak dr
kevin spellman and eloise thiessen
each of the presenters will share the
latest research as well as their
clinical experience and practice
guidelines related to cannabinoid
therapeutics
a new section of this eight-hour course
is dedicated to reviewing different
types of extractions products and
optimal dosing for cannabinoid
therapeutics
after that we have two full days of
presentations and panel discussions
covering the latest research in the
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing taking place may 4th
and 5th
the full schedule is up at
canmedevents.com
you'll notice that each of the canmed
focus areas are anchored by a keynote
presenter
dr ethan russo for science seth crawford
for cultivation dr bonnie goldstein for
medicine and grace bandong for safety
testing
each of our keynotes as well as many of
our presenters and panelists were guests
on the podcast and you can listen to all
our previous episodes at
cammanevents.com coffeetalk
while you're at canmedevents.com you can
also watch video presentations and panel
discussions from all of our previous cam
and events in our canmed video archive
presentations include
canmed2022
dr rousseau seth crawford and dr
goldstein as well as professor rafael
mishulam david miri marcus rogen zamir
punja stacey gruber and many many more
as you can tell we have a lot going on
at kmanevents.com
and the best way to keep up with
everything is to sign up for email
alerts using the simple form in the page
footer
or on the pop-up form that you'll find
at camedevents.com
you can also follow us on facebook
instagram twitter or linkedin
just look for cam at events
this episode's guest is dr deddie miri
dede runs a lab at the technion israel
institute of technology that
investigates the anti-tumor effects of
cannabinoids more specifically his team
identifies which combination of
cannabinoids can kill cancer cells most
notably his team identified a
combination of three specific
cannabinoids that kill leukemia cells
and that formulation is currently being
tested in a clinical trial
dede is a three-time canmed presenter
most recently he delivered a one-hour
keynote presentation at canmed 2019
where he talks about the work going on
in his lab
i highly recommend watching that in all
of dede's presentations not only is the
information fascinating but daddy has a
very engaging presentation style
if you watch daddy's 2017 presentation
video you might actually see a cameo
from a certain podcast host
at about 30 seconds in
anyway daddy and i discussed a number of
topics related to his work including the
fact that daddy entered the cannabis
medicine research space skeptical of its
therapeutic potential and how
understanding the mechanism of action
for the endocannabinoid system made him
a believer
he also talks about how he uses his own
experience being a skeptic to convince
other skeptical physicians and
non-physicians
he talks about the database that his
team created that tracks all the active
compounds in medical cannabis products
available in israel as well as which
products are effectively treating the
patient's conditions
this unique database allows dede and his
team to identify which products and
compounds they want to study in more
detail
we talk about the diversity of cannabis
chemotypes and the diversity of cancer
types and how that combination makes it
nearly impossible for patients to select
the right strain for the right type of
cancer given what we know
we also talk about whether synthetic
biology will be used to produce minor
cannabinoids at scale
and also the two broad classifications
for cannabis medicine
one for general wellness using whole
plant extracts and another for targeted
treatments using individual compounds
before we get to my conversation with dr
denny mary i want to thank this
episode's sponsor advanced nutrients
founded in 1999 advanced nutrients was
the first to develop a complete nutrient
system that unlocks the true genetic
potential of the cannabis plant
since its inception the brand has
introduced more than 50 innovations to
the cultivation community and continues
to revolutionize the space through
proprietary scientific discoveries
learn more at advancednutrients.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr daddy mary
[Music]
hi daddy thanks for joining us on the
podcast
hi thank you for having me it's a it's a
pleasure to be here
yeah and i'm glad that we got to do this
because i feel like it's long overdue
you've been
an important contributor to canmed in
the cannabis community for a number of
years now so i'm glad we finally got the
chance to to talk on the podcast
so in in preparation for the
conversation i i re-watched your keynote
presentation from canmed2019
which i highly recommend all the
listeners check out i'll drop a link in
the show description so people can see
the video
and in that talk you were very open in
sharing that you were skeptical when you
first started researching medical
cannabis so i'm curious
first what got you started in
researching medical cannabis and second
was there a particular moment or a
discovery that made you a believer
so i will start from the first question
i
my background is from plant medicinal
plant biology i did a phd in
molecular and genetic plant biology i'm
son of agriculture i live in the fields
i was the head of the botanic gardens of
tel aviv university and the medicinal
plant a
greenhouse there which is a big
greenhouse and and then i moved
to
my postdoc where i did totally different
their work when i did the
cancer research or you know anti-cancer
properties
of different molecules and when i got
back to israel and got my own lab i want
to create a heterogenic laboratory or
multi-disciplinary laboratory taking my
knowledge from plant to see how
it's affecting you know cancer cells
and and this is not i'm not a
unfortunately i'm not the one that
invented most of the chemotherapies and
the treatments against cancer coming
from from plant you know taxol is from
paxus bush and the vincrestine
vimblastine these are names for the
major chemotherapies are all coming from
plants
so i started to to look for plans that i
thought that they have anti-cancer
properties
and i started to work with a few plants
and one of them was cannabis i saw a
work by manuel guzman and christine
sanchez from spain that show that if you
put cannabis on breast cancer or on
glioblastoma every one of them you know
manu guzman work on glioblastoma and
christian sanchez on breast cancer show
that if you put the cannabis on them
it's a inhibit their ability to migrate
and create metastasis and global
stomachs kill the cells
and i started by repeating these
experiments and i was quite
surprised by by the results and quite
fast being
you know it's funny to say that in the
cannabis
field but become addicted to this plan
so
it's phenomenal results and now i will
answer the second question i started
very skeptical i'm not a user you know
i'm not against it i tried few times i
didn't like the feeling and
now i have a friend that's saying that i
don't like to do things that i don't
like so
you know i
i'm not against i just didn't i don't
like the feeling
and
and it was kind of a i don't want to say
gimmick because
in dead times in 2014 i it wasn't the
hype yet and nobody
it was kind of undercover and the
technique on the institute and working
they did that really didn't like that
i'm working on that so
but
the first result with were extremely
extremely significant and strong
in in the first conference that they
flied it was in prague
you know it was around 90 people
you know it's kind of the founders of
this field you know and they were the
people they just
established chronos and aurora and
canopy and kilray you know i remember
they showed that they are starting to
plant in tillery they started to plant
like two acres of cannabis and everybody
hold their heads you know like it was
like are you crazy something like that
yes
and and
and
i was you know very skeptical i was
sitting there and saying you know
they're for one hand they're showing
that it's make you sleepy for the others
say hey they said it make you alert it's
helping diabetes it's helping pain it's
helping maybe epilepsy it's helping
psoriasis come on guys like you know
be real you're all you know
yeah so you're gonna be true
between also understanding how biology
is working
if it's doing that it won't be able to
do that you know it's the opposite it's
not working
learning and understanding the
endocannabinoid system its role and how
it's operating every cell and how
complicated it is
explaining why it's reducing pain
affecting sleep reducing increased
appetite
affecting the immune system when you
understand the mechanism of action of
the endocannabinoid system then it all
makes sense and if you're asking me
what's
triggered me or
convinced me about the that everything
that i see or you know a lot of things
that we see is is real
is understanding the mechanism affection
of the endocarditis because if you
understand how white is doing that and
how then you believe
and and before you asking this the next
question you know you give to scientists
to speak you won't stop
so
i'm finding myself give
and i'm not exer exaggerating hundreds
of talks and a lot of them it's in
hospitals
and when i'm sitting in front of
the physicians
in the beginning there is the same joke
always did you brought samples
everybody's laughing
and then and then i'm starting to show
the results and there is always this
kind of the stoppingness daddy come on
really you do really think you think
that
but when i'm starting to explaining
in the highest level of science and that
physician can understand
why it's working like that which
you know which receptors operate what
which cannabinoid binding what is
happening downstream to that and what is
the mechanism of action
there is always the moment in this talk
and i did hundreds of that and never had
the different
something that happened different there
is a moment that they know that i have
them
they got it they understood it's real
and from here
it's easy
to collaborate it's easy to start to
engage them to
to prescribe it's easy to engage them
to work and then to give data and and
all and all that there is a logic behind
it it's real and
for that reason it's easy to explain
that's great and so
what about
non-physicians
is there
is there something that
when you're speaking with them
that you can explain that kind of helps
it click if someone who's a
non-clinician is a skeptic
sure again
when you give
something that somebody can connect with
and understand it
then it's become
easier to believe if i will now explain
you one why when you smelling a barbecue
it's increase your appetite and actually
the cannabis is doing exactly the same
he said yeah i know that i'm smelling a
barbecue or you know i'm i'm feeling a
nap
it's increased my appetite or a dish or
why i'm eating a dessert after the meal
you know when i'm not hungry anymore and
i'm explaining by the evolution what
happened
and why it's happening and why the
cannabis just mimic them
then you can connect to the teacher i
know that they you know i'm full and
then they bring this you know great
brownies in the
restaurant i'm eating that also
not make sense you know or things like
that
and and and what is the difference
between when you
you know feel pain why when
our body operates the opioid system we
have an opioid system in our body
and when it's operate the
endocannabinoid system and why now we
can use the cannabis when it's fit to
that and you use opioids when it's
not opioid to everything you know right
i i can explain it in in a lot of sense
and and for that reason i think
everybody can connect and and sometimes
it's it's challenging in conferences
that there are physicians scientists you
know
fathers and mothers of a sick child and
a grower
and now you need to
to give the talk that the physician will
admire what you're saying and not say
hey this is a lame guy
but also you know the grower and the the
father of a child a sick child will
understand you too it's it's not an easy
mission but
i must say that i'm enjoying that so
yeah it's a challenge it's certainly a
challenge and again just to plug your
keynote from 2019 i think you do a very
good job of
of explaining it for everyone in the
audience so because we do have a diverse
audience at the conference so uh just
another plug for that
i did want to get into talking about
your laboratory because
i mean at least for me it seems quite
unique
especially comparing it to labs that we
have testing labs that we have here in
the united united states so is it true
that all cannabis grown in israel goes
through your lab
yeah i had a i was fortunate to get a
huge amount of money from
from a foundation in the state that gave
money for a breakthrough
you know
science
to create the israeli database on
patient and i got
five million dollars to create a big
database in academia it's a huge money
at least in israel and and what we did
um until last year we had just eight
authorized growers that can supply you
know israel
in israel we have just medicinal
cannabis
medical cannabis we don't have
recreation at all and it's under
healthcare from 2007 it's under
healthcare israel is a half social
country so
we all have insurance whether it's
dedicated from my salary or the
government will pay you if you're not
working you know so we all have
insurance when i'm going to a physician
when i'm going to the hospital i'm not
paying i already paid you know from my
salary
or the government paid we all been
insured and this is the health care in
new zealand so cannabis
is being prescribed by physician
under health care and you get in in
pharmacy as a as a prescribed medicine
which is saying
that you're paying a fixed price the
government decided which not related to
the amount that you're getting and so on
and so on and it's very simple but it's
all under health care so it's very
controlled so it's easy every
every product
need to go through a specific
test in order to be an effective like
like every medicine okay so on that
process everything is reaching to my lab
we're examining all the active compounds
and then creating a database with the
pension
i can speak about that four or five
hours there is something that is saying
in in creating big data garbage in
garbage out and it's a little bit
garbage in because the data that we get
from the patient is very very very
problematic in the way
being collected and for that reason
there are things that we succeed
to recruit from that not in the level
that i i wanted
okay so
again comparing that to
what we have here in the united states
where multiple different states with
multiple different systems some are
medical some are recreational
labs are testing for for some compounds
in one state and not in another um
that that's pretty unique that you're
able to put together a database to
really start tracking um you know what
types of
what types of cannabis folks are using
for certain conditions and to try to
to actually draw some correlations
between what the active compounds
are responsible for the response right
that is the goal
yes so i'm doing kind of a reverse
biology first i see what's happened on
the patient then i'm taking it to mice
you know it's
it's usually the the opposite so so this
is something that from the beginning
was
very unique to me so i started with the
materials that actually patients are
already getting you know when i started
there were 18 000 patients in israel
today there are 105
000 so five times more
and and but there was still 18 000
patients that getting these materials i
know it's not toxic but i see that they
killed the cancer cells very efficiently
so
when i started usually when you study in
a lab you see something that have a lot
of efficacy and kill the cells
when you will go to mice model and then
to humans
the first trial and the most
tough one is toxicity
which side effects that you're getting
whether you know it's kill the cancer
cell but also kill your liver and your
brain it doesn't help okay there is very
good materials that kill everything you
know
you know i'm sure yeah blocking your
oxygen will kill the cancer cells you
know so but this is not what you're
looking but here there was something was
potent is the best chemotherapies that i
have and i know that it's already
patient taking it it's not toxic and
this is extremely unique so on the same
level like i said if i know that this
strain
causing
67 of the patient to be sleeping to
sleep very deep now i can take it to the
lab and starting to examine
which
cannabinoids or in which molecules
inside is causing them what is the
mechanism of affection does it cause you
to feel sleepy to sleep deep
to be you know which
when we're talking about sleep there are
different part of the sleep how fast
you're falling asleep
how deep you you're sleeping you can
fall asleep very fast but wake up every
few minutes right if you're getting this
the rum sleep whether you are it's
efficient sleep or not how how
how difficult it is for you to wake up
so there is these are being controlled
in different areas of the brain and
different types of cannabis affecting
different
areas or in different part of the sleep
so if you ask just the pension
does it help you to sleep you will get
an answer yes or no but you don't know
in which part of the sleep it's
affecting and
and this is taking it to different
resolution
of questions and answers and fine-tune
which patient should get what
okay so we mentioned cancer and i wanted
to get into that because
correct me if i'm wrong but your team
has identified
a combination of compounds that are very
efficient at killing very specific types
of cancer correct and
i know that's what you presented on in
2019 and
have have you been able to identify
other similar formulations or different
ones that can be equally as effective
against other types of cancer
yes so i want to take one step backward
and be clear to the audience you know
cannabis is not killing cancer and
cannabis is not a treatment to cancer so
you know many people say why to take
chemotherapy i will take cannabis it's
not working that way
cancer is a given name to hundreds of
different diseases you know right breast
cancer liver cancer propriety cancer are
totally different diseases
and what can help on breast cancer can
damage
ovarian cancer you know because they
they work differently okay and and the
drug that they're working today on
breast cancer let's say tamoxifen is
working exactly the opposite on ovarian
cancer and people don't understand that
unless your oncologist or something like
that so first of all cancer is the given
name to hundreds of different diseases
and in the same type of cancer let's say
breast cancer you have hormonal
sensitive hair plus brachii
mutation
you have more than 20 different types of
breast cancer so which one cannabis is
killing it's
what we call personal medicine and now
we'll go to the cannabis world there are
hundreds and thousands different types
of cannabis
so what is the possibility that you have
a specific types of a breast cancer that
you will take the specific types of
cannabis that really
interfere with the pathway of the the
cell to to block it and to kill it or to
stop proliferation it's a lottery okay
and for that reason without really
knowing
deeply what you're doing it's better
sometimes not to do okay
so
what we defined in in my lab and we're
working on
more than 10 different types of cancer
but at least
in three types of cancer we already
succeeded to understand to screen
hundreds of different
chemo chemoverse of cannabis to describe
one of them or discover one of them that
was very efficient killing the cells
and then for this one
to
er
to analyze and to separate and to
understand which molecules which
cannabinoids
is
responsible for the effect i understand
the mechanism of action which receptors
are binding what they are doing in the
cell and why they are keeping these
types of cell with this mutation not the
others
and and we are studying clinical trials
in humans in this indication so
in leukemia specific types of leukemia
in breast cancer and in colon cancer we
are having advanced results that we're
already taking to clinical phase
and but this is very specific in
leukemia we're talking about three
molecules in breast cancer it's one
molecule it's a very unique cannabinoid
a little bit similar to cbg but with
different structure into oxygen in the
aromatic
so there because there are two oxygens
there is
less
hydrophobic more available whatever it's
a unique cannabinoid where the first one
to discover and and to analyze it and to
understand the structure so what this is
what we call minor cannabinoids you know
not always it's minor sometimes they are
stranded in this one they are not minor
we just call them like that because we
don't
identify them you know right we don't
have standards for them
so so yes
going to
the bottom of your questions
in specific types of cancer we already
found specific molecules
that affecting these cancer because of
their
is
special
a phenotype of mutation you know every
cancer have its own
characterism
and so if we define molecules that
affecting these
types of cancer now it's very specific
and this one we're starting clinical
trials
that's excellent
um so going back to the the minor
cannabinoids
um and you sort of you mentioned that
they're considered minor
for one reason because we're not
specifically testing for them but are
they also in very low concentrations in
in the plant
not always so you know first of all i in
my lab we divide them as major medium
and minor
so majority states in cbd maybe also cbg
you know we see strains of 20 cbg
already so it's not minor
and i i just came back from the state
and i saw that in california and in also
new york there are strengths of 20 cbg
in israel i'm
familiar with that in in the last few
years so
um
so 20 is not minor for sure
and then there are the the what we call
the medium one which is cbc and cbn and
thcv and cbdv so usually you can find
strains with a two three percent of
these
cannabinoids but they already saw
strains of 13 14 percent etv and 30 14
cbdv so these are kind of medium okay
and then there are the minor
cannabinoids they are probably
degradation of the major in the medium
or or a specific cannabinoid that
usually you're not finding them
more than
0.5 or something like that in the
flowers and in this we called miner
and we found out that sometimes
they are extremely important so
sometimes they are more important than
the usual ones and then when you're
taking them isolating them or creating
strains with high percentage of them
they are very very efficient in specific
indication
and you know this is this is our you
know claim of fame so this is what i'm
focusing on it doesn't mean the thc and
cbd and cbg are not important
but the rest of the world doing that so
i'm looking on on the special one that
that i can see in other notes so this is
this is the reason it's not the theaters
even in cbg are not important and again
when i'm finding
you know amazing results with cbg i will
go with that
and but i'm quite upset when it stays
and it is the case sometimes that they
are involved in sort of the combinations
of course of course of course now
now given the fact that some of these
minor cannabinoids that are you know in
relatively low concentrations could be
very important in these treatments i'm
curious what are your thoughts on
synthetic biology like creating some of
these cannabinoids through yeast or
things like that as a way to
you know make more of these than the
plant is is typically producing
so first of all i don't find an
advantage by
[Music]
creating the yeasts or creating them
synthetically in the lab
so
in the plant there is the entourage
effect and something that you're getting
and we can speak about that
later if you want to but but there is
a bunch of of cannabinoids going
together if you look on high cbd strain
there is a portfolio of cannabinoids and
terpenoids that will go with that if you
look in high thc and when you are
you know taking an extract or using a
vipering or viping or smoking cannabis
you're getting
these whole complex
there are there is plus and minus in
there
if you're taking an isolate cannabinoids
or
so i don't find a difference between
isolate from yeast or either or make it
synthetic isolate and purify that
it's quite of the quite the same then
you know to ask what is the advantage of
of creating that initial in bacteria on
that
but basically i i think that we will
find out in few years from now
different types of of medicine that
coming out from cannabis
one of them is
whole extract when people using for
you know
for
not occasional but but for quality of
life improving quality of life and
wellness okay because you're taking the
whole extract and it's a little bit help
you with sleep with pain with a mood
with a you know appetite you're getting
a variety of
of effects
that affecting your quality of life
which
each one of them it's a different
combination of molecules that you have
in the whole extract and there is a
benefit of that instead of taking five
drugs you're taking cannabis and doing a
little bit here a little bit there and
you're getting something
and you're improving your quality of
life and and i totally i think that
80 percent or even more of the pension
that getting today cannabis and also in
the recreational you know we can argue
if recreation it's not part of
healthcare or part of improv if it's
improving your quality of life if you
are very
angry and and you have anxiety and now
using in the evening and you're smoking
cannabis being relaxed
does it
does it medicinal or does it react
you know
it's a big question but in general i
think that eight eighty five percent of
the user using that
quality of life and wellness
and the other fifteen percent using it
is to treat specific indications like
epilepsy or what we spoke now cancer
and and maybe other indications and i
think for this one we will be much more
accurate it will be specific combination
of cannabinoids or specific molecules
that might be from the plant but might
be also from yeast or synthetic i don't
see if you're already
purifying them and using as purified
for my point of view i don't see a big
difference
no and that's such an important point is
is kind of talking about the two
different ways you can use cannabis one
for general wellness and one for you
know treating very specific conditions
that you're looking for um with your
team so i think sometimes in the
industry
kind of becomes an either or is it you
know is big pharma going to come in and
sort of take over cannabis or should it
stay um
you know kind of like it is now with
whole plant extracts and you know the
benefits of the entourage effect and it
sounds like there's really a space for
both
i i think i think there is facebook for
both and we need both so so you know
when you have a child with leukemia and
you have a six with tl and you have six
months to live
i don't think that
either of us want to play games with
that okay you need to give them the
treatment the most obvious treatment
that you can give to save his life and
and if
and i don't care and i don't i care for
the child i don't care about the
industry in that point okay
save the child and i think if you have
accurate molecule that you know exactly
the the dosage and how to give it that
you need to go the direction
and you know i have four kids and then
also a lot of friends i don't think that
any of us will play now with a you know
herbal plant so let's see an entourage
if again i don't know what there is you
know we'll go
with the physician
on the other hand
when you want to treat something that is
more general you have now
suffered from ptsd which is problem with
anxiety
and the problem of sleep and mood
and other things that
cannabis give
a treatment with is more complete
and and you don't need now to to kill a
cell you don't need to to to stop
something very accurate you need
something more general you know what i
will i will give you a different example
as i like to that
i started to see in israel more and more
you know ordinary people
my parents are 85 years old
and they are already you know suffering
from what older people are suffering a
little bit pains more even than a little
bit okay they don't fall asleep
very well
they know what the meaning of 85 you
know they're probably even when you're
singing them until 120 it's not a lot
so
you know it's a mood and
my mother don't have too much appetite
anymore
and
now she's taking cannabis high cbd
strain
she's sleeping better she's eating
better she's feeling better
she is have less pains
nothing critical it's not like taking
opioids that the pain is disappearing
but you reduce
two levels down
and you improve all the quality of life
so instead of taking a meals of pills
that every one of them also create a
different damage and then you're taking
a pill for that damage and then you're
taking deal
she's taking few drops of cannabis and
this is really helping and i don't think
that in that term
we will be isolate cannabinoids or
molecules because you're talking about
variety of things that happened there
but now
six days ago
some girls entered to my lab she's a
friend of a colleague said this next
slab to me and said daddy you must help
her she came she's suffering from
insomnia
she had a treatment of cancer from
chemotherapy in this schemata because
her insomnia in the last five years she
can't sleep more than 15 minutes
okay
pretty woman lovely woman everything
she's a professor whatever she can't
sleep the she don't have she just want
she just asking one thing
help me to sleep now it's not pain no no
no no it's one thing help me to sleep
so now i want to come with the big
cannons
whether from cannabis or not to help
heroin sleep i don't need the old
variety
what is the best molecule so the best
combination
that will cause her to fall asleep and
not wake up for four hours
and if i can create it
i prefer to create it in in in if i need
two molecules from this strain and one
molecules from that trend maybe a
molecule from
algae i don't care maybe it's
combination from one place i want to
help her and i think that we will find
out
more and more complicated medicine this
is a different you know a branch that
i'm opening here
of things to help this kind of patient
which is
treating very accurate in cannabis they
can be give the best in example is
epilepsy
you know kids with epilepsy 80 seizures
a day don't have life you know they
can't
operate
if you just stop the the the
the seizures
now they're coming back to normal life
so it might be one compound maybe it's
the cbd like gw head or something like
that if you're blocking that that's it
you don't need
the whole package
so i think that you will find that we
will find out in few years
that the pharma company really
swallowing this kind of thing when it's
one compound two compounds for a
specific indication
but the majority
will stay with the whole plant
yeah
no and that's such a it's such an
interesting approach too is you know you
have a condition you start treating it
with cannabis and it's sort of this like
shotgun approach right you're you're
getting a lot of different compounds
and if you find a strain that works for
you then you can really start to kind of
narrow it down right okay what compounds
are in this strain and can we start
isolating it down and narrowing it down
to just a select few and you know and
it's great that you guys can do that in
israel with with your database and again
i i
i come back to the united states i mean
we have 3.6 million medical cannabis
users here in the united states i
imagine if if you could get your hands
on on that data how much how much more
could we learn about you know what
cannabis can be used to treat other
conditions
so so the problem is the other side when
somebody say cannabis today you know
this has helped me to
to treat the
parkinson's disease what do you mean i
took cannabis it's it's meaningless to
me
so somebody's calling me from
you know from boston a few weeks ago
you know
with connection he he found out that
they asked me to speak with him said
look
i used i tried many types of cannabis
and now i find one that really helps my
father with parkinson
it's meanless to me
who cares what the name of this cannabis
i don't know what are the cannabinoids i
know do the dosage i want to reach
unless i will get it here and and
examine it and start to work with it i
can do that but i can't get it here
right from boston unless i'm going with
the suitcase and you know
and become criminal so i think the
regulation is still blocking that
right the database that and i did it in
the past from canada and from the state
the database that i'm getting is almost
meaningless and you know we publish i
will give you an example we published a
paper
a few weeks ago i think it's four weeks
ago about the difference of
sex
you know gender sorry not sex okay
and we know from our database
that
women's have way more side effects
they're saying that they have more side
effects
and also they are using sometimes
different strains there are strains of
just male using the strains of just
women using
and we thought that this the reason
there is more side effect is whether
they're using a different strains that
have more side effects
or
it's something related hormonally you
know to estrogen progesterone
testosterone whatever that are
difference between
and because
we have the ability today to check the
endocannabinoid system very deeply we
can look on 38 different receptors and
endocannabinoids in the blood samples
and also can analyze all the
cannabinoids what they're getting we did
a clinical trial on 200 patients
around it was a little bit less than 200
it was around 160 it was something like
90 males and 70 winners
and
first of all this was a pain patient
neuropathic pain patients so first of
all we look how many patients using
cannabis we took neuropathic pension
that using cannabis said that it's
helped them this was a criteria okay
and then we started to to check
how much it's helped them we find out
that women and men describe that it's
the same on the effect of reducing
neuropathic pain okay
and then we ask okay what about the
negative side effects that you have
and women had a way more
than men's almost men's almost didn't
have side effects and then
you're asking the woman
okay
how
you saying that these strengths cause
you dizziness okay
how much how many times in
in a month you feel dizziness so first
of all she said what does the uh are you
asking do you have a negative effect
yeah this could strain cause me
dizziness dizziness it's writing
terminology you know when your head is
turning right
so
so you are
she said yes i have i'm suffering from
this side effect it's it's happened a
lot you said okay how many times amounts
you feel business you said
four times a month okay now you're going
to the males that using the same
strength said
does it help you for pain yes it reduce
pain do you have a negative side effect
no i don't have negative side effect i
really like the strain
do you have dizziness you ever done
feeling this yes a little bit how many
times a month four times a month the
number is the same number yeah and this
is the problem of the the data if you're
not getting deep and you don't ask the
right question you're getting wrong
answers
and that's what we find out in the
database sometimes if you're not going
deeper you're getting different answers
so
these
actually work show that there is no
difference in the side effect it's
exactly the same the same strains
causing the same side effects in women
and men's lifting what we checked
but if you don't ask it in the right way
you are falling
and failing
okay so
so this is part of this
so i want to come back just for a second
what you said about
having this ability from the database
the doctor-based giver you give you just
in a hint
or a clue where to start looking
but from there in the last six years we
develop
abilities to do extractions in many
different types of extraction butane co2
super critical you know a press whatever
to learn what are the differences and
then to analyze all the active compounds
all the cannabinoids flavinoids
supernovas and it's different machine
different abilities okay
then we develop method to screen
on many different
indications or diseases
usually a scientist is focusing on on
one thing
you know my supervisor for my phd said
that a an expert is somebody that know
everything about nothing
so usually you are expert for a you know
specific types of cells in the heart
and and this is how labs usually look at
the academia because of the cannabis
because of the variety
my lab started to do cancer but then
said okay it's also working on epilepsy
let's let's have you know a mice model
for epilepsy and for alzheimer's sleep
disorder multiple sclerosis screen
disorders a autoimmune disease
and in the end i said just a moment in
order to look on medicinal plants you
know now there is also a hype
on a a
psychedelic mushroom or whatever
so i thought about that you know four
years ago i said this is not just
cannabis this is medicinal plant
so we create
in 20 models for diseases that we can
screen very fast so i'm doing extraction
analyze the active compounds screen it
on 20 different diseases every types of
cannabis or mushrooms or whatever
see where i see the effect where i see
something unique
that no
other plant or no other strands is doing
when i've defined it
i know to separate to analyze the active
component these are different machines
okay that can separate it and analyze
separate and define which molecules with
what are the combination of the
molecules they're doing this effect
whether this is one three seven i can i
can narrow it down very efficiently
today
after i narrow it down i can ask okay
why and what these molecules are doing
to the cells and to the mice and
whatever okay which receptors are
binding what they are doing so
understanding the mechanism of action
and when i have all these circles now
i'm ready to convince the physician to
do a clinical trials i have the
molecules i understand i can go to a
clinical trials with the whole extract
which i know that i have the right
combination inside and this is
medical cannabis i can go on the farm
away
purified compounds fda
and usually i'm doing that parallel
there is advantage to both of them so if
i'm if i'm closing what i achieved or
what that we have
i have in my lab
38 people to death 38 scientists and i
have a company called kennesaw they have
around 45 scientists there so all
together we're around 80 90 scientists
that can take
a plant
whether it's cannabis or other plants
we're working with algae mushrooms and
cannabis
and to go all the route analyzing all
the active components we call it
metabolomics first of all doing
extraction different way
analyze the active compound define the
effect on on on cells or mice
understand the mechanism of action doing
preclinical in mice and take it to
clinical and this is
i i think it's a it's open a huge window
to a different approach of medicinal
plants that are more complicated
than single molecule single and you know
target
absolutely fascinating um i do want to
be mindful of your time daddy and i
thank you again for taking the time um
but before i let you go i want to give
you an opportunity to
share any
um any websites any social media
anything that you want to get out there
to share with the audience so that they
can stay in touch with you or stay up
on the work that you're doing
so
you know i'm a scientist i'm professor
in the university there is site for the
lab put my name and you find it at the
technion i have a
company called canaso and council have
the lab there is a synergism between
what we are doing in the lab and cancel
actually where one big group
that they doing rnd and trying to
understand
which compound and how these components
which plant and how they are working and
to define the things that can help
us to live better
and to you know smile
i have two goals first of all when we're
coming to work me and my workers that we
will come with a smile and second when
patients are getting to hospitals or
sick we'll smile more so this is two
two projects work together and then
meanwhile it's working very well so
yeah no that sounds like a great
approach
thanks again for the time daddy um i
hope to see you out at canmed um in 2022
and and many more to come
thank you very much for having me it's
always a pleasure i
you know i'm i'm waiting
and that
these conferences will open again you
know i just came back from after a year
and a half that i didn't fly i came back
from a touring in
in new york so the skies is open
life is coming back i hope to normal and
i hope to see you face to face soon
all right looking forward to it okay bye
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr daddy mary please check out the links
in the show description to learn more
about the topics we discussed and thanks
again to this episode's sponsor advanced
nutrients
our next episode drops november 24th
that's two weeks from today and one day
before thanksgiving
to celebrate the holiday we have planned
a special giving back themed episode
that you won't want to miss
in the meantime please do check out
canmedevents.com
to view the canmed 2022 schedule explore
the canmed archive listen to previous
podcast episodes and sign up for email
alerts
if social media is more your thing you
can stay connected with us on instagram
twitter linkedin and facebook
speaking of facebook check out the
canmed community facebook group it's a
great way to connect with fellow
attendees and presenters in between
events
in one last thing please rate review and
subscribe on your favorite podcast app
doing so really helps the podcast reach
more listeners
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please do join us for the
next canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you