[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben ameralt i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference every year
first and foremost happy thanksgiving to
all of our listeners
listen we know it's been a tough year
for all of us and some more than others
but regardless we hope that everyone can
think of a few things to be thankful for
maybe it's your health your family
friends your job your dog your bong
blunt your edible whatever it is
just know that we are thankful for you
thank you for listening to each podcast
episode engaging with us on social media
leaving comments on the videos in our
canmed archive sharing content on the
canmed community board and creating a
vibrant and valuable canmed community
and if you haven't checked out any of
those resources i just named check out
the links in the show description to
learn more
and if you haven't yet bought your
ticket to cammed 2022 you should treat
yourself it's the holidays after all
head over to
canmanevents.com now to see our schedule
read about our speakers and their
presentation topics
and learn all about what makes canmed
the cannabis conference you don't want
to miss
this episode is all about giving back
i had the chance to catch up with amy
simpson and big mike stromatis to talk
about humanity heroes a charity that is
providing essential living supplies to
the homeless community living on the
streets and in shelters across america
big mike who you likely know as the ceo
of advanced nutrients founded humanity
heroes with the idea that if a company
has the financial resources then it has
a social responsibility to help humanity
as a whole
amy is the fundraising manager at
humanity heroes and organizes all the
events the team puts on each year
we discuss the origins of humanity
heroes the growing homeless population
in the united states and los angeles
specifically how cannabis medicine and
the cannabis industry can potentially
help the homeless population
how humanity heroes has expanded to help
the cannabis community especially those
affected by natural disasters
future goals for the organization and
more
before we get to my conversation with
amy and big mike i'd like to thank this
episode's sponsor the canmed giving back
campaign
medicinal genomics believes in the power
of education to inspire science
community and hope so we've decided to
give back with a chance to win one of
four tickets to our canmed medical
practicum taking place may 3rd in
pasadena california
go to canmedevents.com to register and
don't forget to tag your friends and our
social media posts to increase your odds
of winning all the details are at
canmedevents.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with amy simpson
and big mike stremeatus
[Music]
big mike and amy welcome to the podcast
thank you
thank you glad to be here
all right and as you know we're entering
the holiday season which is
traditionally a time to consider giving
back
so we thought it fitting to have both of
you on today to talk about humanity
heroes which is a cause that i know is
important to both of you so first for
those who are not familiar was hoping
you could tell us what is the mission of
humanity heroes
humanity heroes our mission is to touch
as many as many homeless people as many
lives through direct action
and we do that by
giving our backpack campaign
which we do every year
to homeless people this year our goal is
7 000 backpacks filled with hygiene
items
cleanliness items protection ppe and
goods like that soap shampoo
writing paper pens razor blades
socks caps
blankets the things that the the basic
necessities that keep them warm and
healthy down and skid row
fantastic
so and that's a great cause so
when and why did you decide to create
humidity heroes
well
well we first started it in bulgaria
because there actually were no legit uh
charities uh we believe if a cus if a
company is successful they have an
obligation to give back directly
to the community in which they make
their money from and society
as a whole
excellent excellent and so what are some
of the things that you've learned
throughout the years we're
doing your work through humanity heroes
um for me myself um i've definitely
learned a different appreciation for
life
this work for me just giving back and
helping those in need it's been a very
fulfilling
experience
and also to learn that when working in a
big company like advanced nutrients it
brings together
the employees because every day i see
employees here in our office that ask me
about volunteering when is the next
event and i realize that it creates a
company morale that's really positive
because people are happy to work for a
company to for for an owner of a company
that likes to give back and so you know
definitely it um it's affected us in
that sense and you know the more and
more we come together and get more
people involved more companies involved
um we'll be able to
make
an impact greater than the problem right
and the problem is getting
worse and worse every year
when we first started this program was
it five six years ago yeah yeah
uh we gave out 1800 backpacks we pretty
well covered everybody down in skid row
now we're doing 7 000 and it's a drop in
the bucket and so we really want other
people to join other corporations to to
help out and join in with this cause
with us and together we can make a
significant impact in fact
we we do we go beyond actually giving
out those backpacks we've gone down and
giving out masks uh and all kinds of
things during uh kobet during the worst
of cobit we were down there on skid row
uh helping out
excellent excellent and so
you mentioned that the problem is big
and it's only giving getting bigger so i
was wondering if you could expand on so
what are some of the biggest challenges
that humanity heroes has been able to
help the homeless community in la
overcome
go ahead um for me through our direct
action program with the hygiene
backpacks you know we simply deliver a
glimpse of hope
there's different levels to the
homelessness in los angeles and one
thing that we do every year is we walk
the outskirts of
skid row and we hand deliver backpacks
and knock on tents and usually those
people are just experiencing a bad time
in their journey in life and so to just
show them that we care that we took the
time to walk the streets and you know
give gifts
of daily essentials um clean garments a
warm blanket a warm meal um
you know it's just a small token of love
but it helps overcome a lot mentally and
food for their pets as well uh dog food
very very popular down there a lot of
folks have pets yes
and now you mentioned that that some of
the people who who you're encountering
might be kind of going through a
temporary issue or something and i you
know that might be a misconception some
people have about
homeless patients what are some other
misconceptions that you you typically
see amongst amongst people
here's a statistic that most people
aren't aware of
of the american population is one
paycheck away from being homeless
and when you think about that
you uh
i can't help but want help
absolutely because i can tell you it
could be a a friend someone you know
someone in your circle
is one paycheck away from being down
there and what would you do for that
person
yeah absolutely yeah when you put it
that way
that's
that's pretty sobering
um and so
and given that you know many homeless
people
suffer from mental illness and or
substance abuse um obviously not the
people that you were just referencing
but but a significant amount of them um
do you think that cannabis medicine
could potentially help some members of
the homeless community because we are
seeing some research that it can it can
help some of those conditions
i believe it can absolutely i i know
that uh
so depends on mental illness it you know
whether you want to give them or can't
give them cannabis or not but for
substance abuse
absolutely there are
rehab
facilities that now give away
cannabis
uh to the the people that are in rehab
and they're finding it
very good for people especially who are
on oxycontin or heroin
that they they are switching
off of that and onto cannabis
and it is working extremely
well
so cannabis is a healing plant and it
can
absolutely help
some of the people down there on skid
row the mental health issue is
is an important one the state of
california here they have spent a lot of
money i believe it's about 3 billion
on mental health and getting those folks
off the street and
getting them help
amy anything to add there
um no big mike said at all so
excellent all right well now i'm going
to put you on the spot
so
i know that homelessness it's a
multifaceted issue um
but if there were one thing you could
change whether it be a policy or
something culturally or logistically
something that could help solve the
problem um what would it be
i've got an answer for that
uh i would like to see
states build
cities
out in the desert that teach people
trades give them education
getting get them prepared to go back
into
the communities and work now it sounds
simple to do
here's the issue
there's a lot of
civil liberty organizations out there
that are saying well if a person wants
to be homeless it's their right to be
homeless you can't force them to go into
these places
on the other hand
they're all over the streets it would be
great to get them into a community and
really start rehabilitating all these
folks and that would be
monumental and it's
not like we don't have the money in the
state of california to do that we do
have the money to do that it's just that
there's a lot of interference from
other groups that are making it very
difficult to uh to hit that goal
well it's a that's an innovative
approach so really just kind of having a
more dedicated education
um
system in place to help help them enter
the workforce absolutely you know give
them computer skills vocational skills
uh just just skills that they'll need to
go back into society
and and become a uh
a a good part of society
excellent excellent and now you
mentioned earlier your goal for
2021 um being what was it did you say 7
000 backpacks do i have that correct yes
yep so what are some of your goals for
2022 in in and
yeah
some of our goals for 2022 are to
continue to build
our cannabis coalition so that we can
raise more money and to help more
homeless people through our direct
action
with our humanity packs and we'd also
love to
give more support to our cannabis
community who is dealing with natural
disasters
we're going to do a lot more charity
events to help raise money and also get
more people involved and hopefully
that'll move us towards the cannabis
rehabilitation educational and
relocation program for homeless people
that just need um you know a fresh start
and a helping hand and i'd have to say
there are
a lot of cannabis companies now that are
starting to step forward and and work
with us and donate money
and uh realizing that this is uh an
important uh part of
the community
absolutely i agree with that so if we do
have some listeners who who want to get
involved what's the best way to do that
yeah definitely they could go to our
website which is
www.joinhumanityheroes.org
or you can follow us on social media we
also have donation buttons as well as
volunteer options there all of our
social media is join humanity heroes
and if someone wishes to send an email
to have an appointment
info at joinhumanityheroes.org
excellent i'll make sure there's links
to to all of those in the show
description so people have an easy way
to access that
one of the things one of the things i
want to ask about when you were talking
about your goals for 2022 and beyond was
this um what did you say the the
cannabis education and um
uh i i don't remember the name of it
exactly but it sounded similar to what
big mike was describing before where are
you going to have a program to educate
some of these people in maybe the
cannabis field so that they can
participate there
um that would be like a big picture
thing but just my own experiences in
skid row are that peop the skid row and
the homelessness homelessness there is
in levels so you have mental illness you
have drug addiction which are beyond
what we can do um but for those people
that are just in a bad place in life
it would be a really great idea
if it were possible to come together
evaluate some of these people maybe put
them through some sort of educational
program that lasted six or nine months
work with some farmers or cultivators
around the country that could utilize
entry-level workers and somehow create
an educational rehabilitation and
relocation program
in our regard absolutely
yeah that sounds that sounds great that
sounds like a great marriage of the two
um there's two projects that you have
going on here um another thing that you
that you touched on that i wanted to ask
you about was i know that humanity
heroes has expanded to also helping
members of the cannabis community
dealing with natural disasters i was
hoping you could talk a little bit more
about that
yeah absolutely um this year we've been
very busy providing aid to our cannabis
community um in april of this year we
helped a number of wildfire victims in
northern california
with monetary as well as nutrient
donations
we also
donated humanity packs and warm meals to
these communities
we also helped over 70 bushmen in saint
vincent in the caribbean
island when the la sophia volcano
erupted it took out 70
of the
island's agriculture so we were the
first international aide
to help the people there
with
nutrient donations as well as some
humanity packs and warm meals and then
um
in september i traveled actually to
upstate new york
there was a small hydroponics store that
was flooded out with four feet of water
from hurricane ida
it's also a customer of advanced
nutrients so we were able to make a
monetary donation
to that hydroponics store and it was
actually a blessing in disguise for that
store because they were able to expand
their store to a very large facility
so that's just some of the stuff that
we've done well over four hundred
thousand dollars worth of aid directly
to our cannabis community and we're
prepared to do more there's a lot going
on for cultivators around our country so
that's excellent and that's that's so
fantastic that you were able to give
back to to your customers you know to
show that uh you're you're able to help
them in a time of need that's fantastic
um and just
i mean just thinking about how some of
these cultivators are you know
i can't help but draw a parallel here
between you saying that you know 59 of
the population is one paycheck away from
being homeless i got to imagine that you
know a natural disaster for a cannabis
cultivator with you know all the
overhead and all of the
the things that they're dealing with um
that's potentially devastating so the
fact that you're helping them out is is
huge yes yes it is
thank you for that
absolutely so
so winding down here um i wondered if uh
there's a
[Music]
if you'd like to add up the work that
you're doing humanity heroes here and
again if there's any um other ways that
people can get involved
please do share
yeah absolutely um so next week we start
our big push to
um unpacking 37 pallets which
is the 7 000 um products that we'll be
putting into the backpacks and that'll
be taking place next week in valencia so
we're looking for volunteers for that
event and then on december 4th in los
angeles we're going to have a big day
where everyone comes together and we're
actually going to assemble the 7 000
backpacks and um donate to the community
as well as other homeless organizations
in and around los angeles so we're
looking for volunteers we're looking for
donations um and you can go to
joinhumanityheroes.org for information
on either
and what day
what day do we pass those backpacks out
we will be passing out the backpacks on
saturday december 18th in skid row there
you go
and we would love folks to come down and
help us out
absolutely
join
humanityheros.org right yes that's it
absolutely we'll get that link out there
for sure
all right well big mike and amy thanks
again for everything that you're doing
for the cannabis community and the
community as a whole i think it's a
great cause that you're that you're
working on and thanks again for joining
us on the podcast and i can't wait to
see you guys out in pasadena for can med
and thanks for having us
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
amy and big mike
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor
the canmed giving back campaign
our next episode drops december 8th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out all
the resources we have available at
cannemedevents.com follow us on social
media and don't forget to purchase your
ticket to cam ed 2022 i look forward to
seeing you there all right that's it
from us again we hope you have a safe
and healthy thanksgiving and we hope
you'll come back for the next chamed
coffee talk
[Music]
do
you