[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
head over to canmedevents.com now to
learn all about our canmed 2022 event
taking place may 3rd through 5th at the
pasadena convention center in pasadena
california
quick programming note off the top this
will be the final episode for 2021
our next episode will be january 5th
when we welcome back kanmed 2022 keynote
presenter dr bonnie goldstein
we hope you've enjoyed all the episodes
this year we've had some great ones
if you're new to the show or maybe
missed a few episodes please take this
opportunity to go back and check out our
previous episodes
it's evergreen content after all which
is perfect for the holiday season
all the previous episodes are available
in all the major podcast apps and at
canmedevents.comcoffeetalk
of course we hope that you'll stay
connected with us on our social media
channels we're on instagram facebook
twitter and linkedin just search for
cammed events
also i hope you'll join our canmid
community facebook group the link to
that is in the show description and i
hope you'll explore our canmed video
archive that includes all the videos of
our past canmed presentations
you can find that at canmedevents.com
and the link is in the show description
as well
and finally give yourself the gift of a
world-class cannabis education by
purchasing your ticket to canmed2022
today
head over to kmedevents.com to see our
schedule read about our speakers and
their presentation topics and learn all
about what makes canmed the cannabis
conference you don't want to miss
this episode we discuss outdoor hemp
cultivation with dr allison justice
i do want to apologize for the audio
quality on this episode
it seems we had an unreliable internet
connection and as a result some of the
audio got a little garbled i don't think
it'll be too distracting and the
information that allison provides is
great so stick with us
anyway alison is the co-owner and
manages operations at the hemp mine a
40-acre farm in south carolina that
manufactures consumer-ready products the
hemp mine currently produces a wide
array of different products ranging from
smokable flour to tinctures of all
different concentrations for both humans
and animals the hemp mine also breeds
regional trials indoors and outdoors at
scale in order to offer validated hemp
genetics to the hemp market in the form
of stage 3 tissue culture
unrooted cuttings and rooted cuttings
also known as liners as well as clones
topics we discuss include how the hemp
boon that occurred after the 2018 farm
bill helped and harmed farmers
research that universities are doing
with regards to photo period drying and
curing and more
how understanding a plant specific photo
period can be used to maximize yield
how using supplemental light outdoors
can prevent flowering in semi-autoflower
varieties
the importance of selecting hemp
varieties that suit a regional climate
and how hemp mines field day helps
educate new hemp farmers
before we get to my conversation with
allison i want to thank this episode's
sponsor 10 buds
a site dedicated to all things cannabis
with a special focus on growing and
cultivation 10 buds is packed with
fascinating and informative articles
resources and reviews
cannabis growers enthusiasts and
business professionals alike can explore
in-depth looks at everything from
considerations for cannabis business
owners to the evolution of marijuana's
place in society its health benefits and
so much more
visit tembuds.com to learn more
okay and without any further ado i hope
you'll enjoy my conversation with dr
allison justice
[Music]
good afternoon allison thanks for
joining us on the podcast
happy to be here
all right so let's talk about hemp
you own and operate a farm in south
carolina called the hemp mine tell me
about your operation and what got you
started growing home
yeah so we are a vertically integrated
hemp company
um do a little bit of everything from
breeding to young plant distribution
um co-owners in an extraction facility
and we also have a consumer good product
line
uh what got me into it um honestly it
was a
i i suppose a jump from marijuana uh
after i graduated
with my phd i went out to california and
worked in the marijuana industry for
about three and a half years
and
being from south carolina where i am now
um
south carolina
came out with regulations to allow for
growing hemp and my family being farmers
they got involved and you know
eventually it just made sense to to take
some of the knowledge i learned out in
california back home and um take it away
with cbd and cbg and all the other
uh cannabinoids that were allowed to
grow under help production
excellent
and now a few years back a lot of people
got really excited about the hemp
industry with the passage of the 2018
farm bill
of course that legalized some
cultivation and many farmers and sounds
like your family is one of them switch
their farms over to hemp or some you
know added hemp as a supplement to their
traditional crops uh to get in on the
boom so
what is the state of the hemp industry
now and where do you see it in the next
few years
yeah so you know that that first year
was a really big boom and you know a lot
of people jumped in
um i think even the year after
even more people jumped in and
so you know on one hand it's it's great
uh you know with the amount of people
growing him you know people
understanding it not being scared of it
but at the same time that initial jump
was
not great for the industry in a whole
um you know it put a lot of
biomass in the market put a lot of
people
you know whether whether they had uh you
know
a positive mindset for being in the
industry or not um they were there and
so there were a lot of people
selling you know seed they ended up
being marijuana or
um you know performing these co-ops that
they promised all of these farmers that
you know were basically on their last
leg this being their last hope to save
the farm and this huge co-op was going
to put all these farms together and they
were all going to be rich together and
then you know did not shake out
um so you know a lot of horror stories
came from it a lot of people lost money
um
some people have stayed in it and done
well um
and so there you know there's there's a
lot of good and bad of it you know i
think
this first initial
kind of shakeout uh
has really caused us the beginning of
restructuring
um how hemp is and and and how it's
grown and kind of you know the business
model and the landscape that it should
be in the u.s and it's finally getting a
little more um
legit
you know a little more um as any other
agricultural
industry
um wooden should be but it's it's been
slow and a hard road to get there but
you know but besides that portion um you
know the past few years have been
extremely exciting i mean
what we've learned about this plant and
and what it can do has been incredible i
mean just just for example i work very
closely with clemson university and you
know up until two years ago you know
they didn't even want to hear the word
help and now
i'm on grad committees with students who
are able to use their host plant as or
hemp as a host plant
um and just the amount of research
they're putting out and just just in my
little section of horticulture you know
uh vegetative production flowering that
sort of thing not even touching them
[Music]
and
uh
the animal science you know everything
else that can go
into it
just my little world of plant science
has just explode
some of the effect from just our own
customers uh you know
those are the things that i suppose keep
us going um is that that medicinal piece
that yes we really are helping people
and uh you know the industry kind of
straightening out
yeah no and you mentioned sort of the
other uses for hemp whether it be fiber
or um
uh the other ones that you've mentioned
so where where do we stand right now is
the lion's share of the market going
towards cbd or cannabinoid production
or are you seeing more more farmers
growing for fiber
you know i think people want to they
desperately want
i think the infrastructure is on its way
and on its way fast
and i know there's a few spots that
you know are either on in their late
stage of r d you know ready to to make
whether it's manufacturing
or
are growing um commercial um and then
there are a couple in existence but i
think
the demand of of wanting to grow that
type of crop versus
having everything lined up as far as
equipment
just to harvest an equipment to to
process it to fiber or
you know whatever the the industrial use
there might be is lacking a little bit
but you know i think by next year
there'll be a good many acres grown for
that here in the us
interesting yeah i
i'm a believer that you know hemp fiber
could be the future in a lot of
different ways it's just it's
i'm just surprised i haven't seen it
happen yet so i'm glad to hear that it's
that it's right around the corner
you touched on research as well and that
a lot of the universities are now
willing to to do the research into hemp
production i was wondering have there
been some breakthroughs recently that
that you could kind of
tell us about and how can that research
into hemp also apply to cannabis
so again i'm going to go back to clemson
just because that's you know that's the
group i work the closest with i know
there's all sorts of great work going on
medicinally and and with fiber and and
animal feed and etc but
um
just with what i'm you know really
closely privy to
clemson university and a good many
others are doing some some really neat
work into
um you know the the physiology and um
direct application of science to help uh
flowering and so what i mean by that is
um
taking a hemp plant uh cbd dominant
and putting that in an indoor condition
so exactly what you would do with
marijuana you know 100 percent minus
you know just being a different
cannabinoid and so you know they're
they're able to you know have these
wonderful
um
grow chambers and get really nitty
gritty with everything from temperature
to
light intensity light spectrum
um
clemson right now is really digging
deeply in which is one of my favorite
things to study is uh the drying and
curing and so looking at um you know
what is what is ethylene's role because
you know in
in other
horticultural fields um you know whether
it's storage of apples or storage of cut
flowers you know we understand that
backwards and forwards we realize you
know what what sort of co2 o2 is going
out you know do we want ethylene there
to ripen up a banana or do we want to
pull ethylene out
because it's making our cut flowers
degrade and and die very quickly and not
be able to make it on the ship from you
know africa to to wherever
uh you know all of those really
important things as far as plant science
goes that we just have no idea how they
apply to to the cannabis plant
and so um you know nothing published
right now but that's just some of the
things that they're looking into and
um you know being directly
uh relevant to the marijuana industry um
you know that's just some some short
examples but you know the work they're
doing is is very critical
um to the point where
actually dr faust and i and so that's
that's who i
i work with very close to clemson that's
actually who i got my um
my phd under uh he's a flowering
physiologist so he has spent his
lifetime working
with the flowering of poinsettia bridge
looking at
um
unrooted cuttings and and those being
shipped across the us and you know how
to keep those alive longer
um how to preserve them and so
you know being being extremely relevant
to marijuana or
cbd production indoor so basically any
sort of smokeable flower production
um
[Music]
you know he's he's really grabbed hold
of and so
um
other industries so let's say the the
floor culture industry
they have organizations where you know
there's researchers that are really into
research which is immediately applicable
to to growing so you know be able to
increase efficiency or reduce labor
costs you know whatever it may be that's
applicable
um
they form these associations so for
floor culture it's the floor culture
research alliance um you know growers
will pitch in a little bit of money to
help support that research where they
can just you know go deeper and harder
um with it versus only being able to get
grants and then those growers are able
to take advantage of of you know being
first to the line up to receive that
information all through the year versus
you know wait two years for a paper to
get published
um
and so dr faust clemson university and
and the hip mind we have formed a
non-profit called the cannabis research
coalition um where we are
doing this exactly so forming an
association where growers you know
vendors people can join who really want
to push
research forward with the research um
you know knowingly really circulating
around uh smokeable flower production
and post harvest and you know the the
factors of hemp that our skill set is
really in
um
and so that's something exciting we just
launched you know a month ago
um and have had
a lot of interest um and interestingly
enough a lot of interest from the
marijuana industry because you know like
i said it's it's all exactly the same
and extremely relevant so
um yeah it's really exciting and i can't
wait to see what
what we'll be able to put out
absolutely i'm excited too and um
i think if there's room for a genomics
company uh to be part of that coalition
i i think i might be able to get you in
touch with one that that would be
absolutely we love that that's awesome
uh i will definitely follow up on that
um another thing you touched on that i
want to come back to is drying and
curing um
and that sounds
really interesting in a number of ways
but one from at least our perspective
medicinal genomics we we do a lot of
microbial testing and
how important is the drying and curing
process and
maintaining your you know mainta making
sure that your your finished product is
clean and free of any microbes because i
know i've talked to other testing labs
who have actually helped
their customers you know pass
yeast and mold testing
largely in part by looking at their
drawing and curing process
oh yeah i think
it may be the most important part um
you know granted you're not
spraying
some sort of beneficial microbe the day
of harvest you know granted you're not
doing that
um you know i think it could be the the
number one factor and and being able to
pass those sorts of tests um
you know again reaching out to under
other industries and and understanding
how they
uh function and use science to make
healthy product um you know
understanding your water activity
and and how that influences
um so you know
basically water activity being the
amount of water that's there available
for microbes to to grow and prosper
um you know understanding how to
knock that water activity down fast
enough
to not allow for
continual microbial growth
but at the same time teeter-tottering
that line where you're not drying it so
fast to where you're losing all your
terpenes yeah and so there's there's
definitely a fine line
um
but in general yes if you if you bake it
you know dry it very quickly immediately
obviously you're going to have the least
risk of microbials
um
but you know we can't do that if if
we're growing for smokeable flour we
need to we want it to look and smell
good and so that that requires uh you
know a different scenario which we can
achieve and we can achieve but like you
said being able to to really dig into
somebody's drawing and curing and even
you know i kind of like to include it
when i do work with
growers in their post harvest
we don't just look at the day it enters
the dry room it's it's more of looking
at
um specifically the last few weeks in
the grow cycle you know what are you
applying what are you not applying
um
you know
how are you watering are you watering
with you know sprinklers from not
sprinklers but the uh the types of
emitters that kind of bubble up from the
bottom you know are you still applying
beneficial microbes through that and
it's actually aerosolizing to some
extent you know all of those factors
you know i like to look at and then of
course in the dry room you know how's
your air circulating where's your
where's your dead spots
um
you know where's your hot spots uh you
know all of those little factors are
just are so invaluable when
not only just producing a good quality
smokable flower but yeah being able to
pass those microbial tests
yeah and i gotta have to imagine that
being in a climate like south carolina
that's very humid that's even even more
of a consideration and i guess sort of
to that point i i did watch an interview
that you had done um with another
podcast when you were talking about
sort of the regionality of hemp
production and how you know you being in
south carolina and working a lot with
cultivators sort of in the southeast
and talking about some of the special
considerations that need to be taken
for what region that you're growing hemp
in so i was wondering if you could speak
a bit more to that
yeah yeah um
you know every i'd say every month
the importance of of having a variety if
you're growing outside
that
is conducive to that
environment for one reason or the other
is just is so important
and so i'd say that the two biggest
factors um you know with the the most
importance is one the the natural
disease resistance
so you know in the southeast you've got
really high humidity really high heat
and just uh you know a bountiful
natural
microbial existence of of pathogens
and you know with with considering you
cannot apply fungicides that
that are curative
let's put it that way
um
uh so being you know
synthetic pesticides uh fungus to the
ground having that natural population of
pathogen there just ready to fight your
plant
um
having some natural disease resistance
in the variety that you're using
um
it's just night and day i mean we grow
hundreds of different cultivars in our
field every year
and i mean it looks like we've done some
sort of chemical experimentation because
you'll see some roads that look like you
know the burning bush
you know it looks like it's been
completely burned where it's it's a it's
a fungal pathogen that
um there's some varieties that
no matter what you do i don't care if
you put the most expensive uh you know
beneficial fungus
fungal product out there on it every
single day it's not gonna it's not gonna
touch it
and so breeding and selecting for
those varieties which can
naturally ward off
um some of those problems is
is
beyond important
um
i would say the the second most
important factor
uh especially considering you know being
[Music]
being a vendor of the whole united
states yes we we focus in in the south
um
but you know understanding photo period
and so you know again working under a
professor that you know his research
revolved around poinsettias you know i
got a really nice intro to that in grad
school with another house plant
um but understanding that photo period
and you know being able to take
advantage of what you're doing by
understanding that per variety
it's just extremely special and
important and i think more important
than
many like to consider yet
um and so just to kind of give you an
example of that we have one variety
called southern sunset
and in the south it does fantastic
it it fly it initiates flower the latest
meaning it has the uh shorter flower
initiation time so for example
most varieties are somewhere around you
know once once the bell curve of
of time so if you think about
oh goodness you know the apex of the
summer where the days are the absolute
longest
um when it starts going back down so
we're going back into short days
once it hits a certain point that's when
a variety will flower so most will
flower when you hit about 14 hours
sunset on the other hand
it initiates at about 13 hours
30 minutes so it's only about a 30
minute
time difference but in reality it's
about a
two and a half to three week difference
and so what that means is this plant
initiates
two to three weeks later but then it
also finishes two to three weeks later
and so again in the south that is
wonderful
um it's starting to get cooler for that
late harvest um you can plant other ones
in your field that
um you know we'll have that 14 hour
photo initiation time and so then you've
got two weeks between your harvests so
you know you can harvest half of your
crop
put it in the the barn dry it uh clean
the barn out and then do the other half
farm so staggering
um so it really helps save that that
time and labor there
and so that's great it's a great plant
for the south but because we've done
trials in other areas
we understand well if you go if you go
above basically west virginia and you
grow this plant you're going to be in
trouble
very likely because it's going gonna
also finish late it's gonna grow well
it's gonna look you know look just as
good as it does in the south but the
problem is the frost sneaks up on you
because of that late harvest it's not
able to get to its its greatest maturity
before
it's killed by the frost
so um you know that just being another
example of why it's so important to
if you're if your goal
is to produce plants which grow outdoors
in a wide range of environments and
photo periods
you know while we do it
yeah so so you're really taking
advantage of the fact that you have a
warmer autumn down there in the south by
having this
this plant that initiates flower much
later in the season that makes
that makes a lot of sense um especially
as a
hobbyist grower up here in the northeast
definitely gotten burned before having
things finished late and not even so
much the frost but we always seem to get
battered with just
cold wet raw
um type of days that just i mean
botrytis just loves that sort of stuff
so exactly
so speaking of disease resistance
because you did bring that up and you
said that you select for disease
resistance now are you
intentionally inoculating these plants
to see if they develop symptoms are you
just sort of putting them in the field
and and kind of letting nature do its
thing
so in the southeast uh you don't need to
inoculate
i mean if if we're talking botrytis um
southern blight
you know some of some of those are
really common ones you don't need to
inoculate you know it it's there it's
there and it's gonna take down those
plants uh which
you know are either naturally
unresistant or if if let's say you don't
water them for four weeks or you know if
if by your own fault you make the plant
week it shows up as well um but yeah we
don't really need to
yeah and and going back to the photo
period thing too because i did i did
read about it on your website and i was
kind of fascinated to hear it because of
course the general
rule of thumb with growing cannabis is
you know vegetative it's 18 hours of
light and then when you want to flip it
to flower it's 12 hours but it was
interested to hear that you know that
that 12-hour rule is not
set in stone that it can be
can be variable right
oh yeah yeah that i'm
that's perfect if you're inside and you
know all you got to do is flip a switch
or or set a timer but
nature has its its own photo period and
it's you know we we never get to that
18-hour time slot
and so
yeah
we're
our varieties are nowhere near what we
do indoors
but we do it indoors because it works um
that's not to say
you know where we're
that's not to say that that 12 and 24 or
12 and 18 wherever it may be um you know
that's not optimized you know some of
the work again that they're doing at
clemson is showing you know again how
you can even endorse
how you can manipulate
some of
those metrics uh based off of a
variety's response you know you can you
can have your plants
take off a week
um to begin that flower initiation or
you can on certain varieties you know
be able to apply 14 hours of light and
that's during flower and that's four
that's two more hours that you could you
know fill that plant full of photons
and so um you know it's it's not just an
importance understanding it outdoors but
the the indoor cycle too really being
able to maximize yields is
um
you know i think we're going to get some
some really funky rules and recipes to
follow in the next couple of years
versus just the the 12 18.
yeah wow that's that's really
interesting and when you said that it
reminded me of something else that i saw
on your website was
using supplemental light as a way to
sort of trick the plant into not
flowering um do i have that right i'm
sorry i'll let you yeah yeah
that's
that's right so kind of opposite of
sunset you know that's initiating flower
um at 13 hours
we have varieties that
you know i've termed as semi-autos
because i don't really know what else to
call them especially in this industry
and how we use certain terms
um because it's not a true autoflower
because autoflowers
you know it's it's basically just a
ticking clock it's uh once it gets to 63
days you know whether the lights
um right one hour or 24 hours it's gonna
flower based on age uh meaning you
cannot take clones from it you can only
reproduce it through c
um
whereas these flowers um you know they
truly are photoperiodic it's just they
have a really long initiation
um so
in order for them to stay vegetative
they have to have 18 hours
and so if you think about it anywhere in
the u.s at any point of time you're only
ever going to top out at what 15 15 and
a half hours
and so
um
you know if you if you are in a
greenhouse growing this plant as stock
you keep it under 18 hours you're you're
able to grow stock plants you take
cuttings from it keep those cuttings
above 18 hours
it's just like any other plant but then
you take that plant the the liner and
you plant it outside and it flowers you
know it gets to maybe a foot tall and
it's done
and so
you know
you you think all right well maybe this
is terrible this is a terrible thing
let's trash this variety but if
if we if we work this right we can
really take advantage of of this
knowledge around this plant
and uh
and and do some really cool things so
what some of my growers and and
ourselves at the hip mine um have done
i think our top
semi-auto uh selling variety is peach
haze
smells great
um
you know what we're able to do is
in south carolina you know
basically
may 15th we can plant our first plant
and and when i say that i mean it
because that's when the last frost has
came
um you know we can plant
pjs out there turn on a flood light
from two sides
and
as long as that flood lights on it'll
continue to grow vegetatively
and so you know two three weeks however
you know close or far away you want to
space them
you cut that light off
and then you're flowering
and so you know that's that's really
special and important because in south
carolina um
we can do that three times in a season
um you know without the expense or
annoyance of pulling shade cloth
building a greenhouse you know having a
hoop house where you've got guys out
there pulling cloth every single day
and able to really maximize that growing
season outside
the other thing it's it's really useful
for
is you know greenhouse growers
if if you're an existing greenhouse
grower if you're wanting to put in a
blackout system
it's just as expensive as basically you
know building in a greenhouse it's just
about impossible and so
instead you pick a different variety you
pick peach hays um you know you grow it
just like you would any other plant
except you put maybe string lights you
know just very inexpensive led string
lights across the row
you keep it again you keep it vegetative
for
a couple weeks
turn the lights off and you're flowering
and you never have to pull shade cloth
um and you can do that all year long
because again you're never getting under
18 hours
right so you're flowering right in the
middle of summer
wow that's great you know and and you
touched on too that's it's great for for
you as um as a clone producer as a
nursery um because you're able to unlike
with autoflower like you said you can
still take cuttings
you can still clone so i think that's a
nice segue to talk about um maybe seed
production versus clonal propagation
so i was wondering i mean maybe we can
start
with you
kind of explaining from from a business
perspective why did you decide that you
know clonal propagation or selling
clones is is more
um
advantageous than than being a seed
producer
yeah
well i guess a lot of things go into
this answer
um
you know first off you know if we go
back to
2016 when when hemp was well
i'm sorry when i was i guess 2016 i was
playing with him in california under the
marijuana rules so you know when i'm
when i'm playing with him
um
you know
you can look at it a few ways one
if you're a marijuana grower you know
how how are you propagating
it's usually from clone
and what's the reason for that well
because we want high consistency
um we want ease
we don't want to have to pheno hunt
um
there's a there's a million reasons that
i could go on and on
um you know again at the beginning of of
when him really got going the the price
whether you were growing just for
isolate or you know the
uh let's say the product you would get
the least return on whatever it was the
price was still that
um clones were
were achievable you were gonna meet your
roi
um
the other thing i would like to add to
that and is very important and i feel
like from from your point of view
it makes a lot of sense you know
how long have we been breeding
him
um
you know
being from the horticulture industry you
know
it for just a platoon a new petunia to
be released you know it could take eight
years
you know to breed it to be confident in
it to send it around to uh different
regions to do trials and understand the
data and then be able to guide your
customer on how to grow it to the to the
greatest extent and then
them do well and want to order from you
again
um and you know going back to that first
year there's sea producers where in the
world they came from i don't know
um you know popping up saying that
they're home based in north carolina
and uh
you know
giving out genetics that are crushing
people
you know are not doing what they say or
you know have four percent thc in it et
cetera et cetera um and uh you know
we've had time since then and and there
are some um you know legitimate seed
companies out there now um that have had
time and
um
time to to not only help homogenize
their seed lines but time to
to help themselves understand where
those varieties can grow best
um
so in in in short it takes time to grow
a really nice homogeneous line of any
plant
um
and so you know between those two
reasons
it made a lot of sense to
breed select and and find those clones
those uh those vegetative plant
materials that you know i could be
extremely confident
in
you know be be able to
you know lead my customers down a path
of success whether that's you know this
is when you're no matter where you're at
you give me your zip code and i can tell
you when this plant is going to initiate
and when you should get it tested and
when you're not you know at what point
you're going to go hot what diseases you
know will
will you struggle with you know
every single detail for success that you
know
i was able to do that by understanding
the plants i was working with which
would only happen at this point in time
through clonal lines
um
you know that's not to say that i don't
believe that
for for oil production um that seed is
is not the future if it's not the now um
you know if if you are
are
struggling to get 200 per kilogram of
isolate
it probably makes sense to grow seed and
if there's a little bit of variability
between you know
six and twelve percent or
if they don't look exactly the same or
if they have let's say a stagger of of
two weeks finish time you know maybe it
doesn't matter because you're just going
to chop them all down with a tractor
anyways
um
and so
you know the the market that we're
really approaching and
you know customers that that we work
with or are the ones which
are growing for smokeable flower
um many of them now
this past year and and especially coming
up this current year uh you know they're
growing for terpene production
and so
you know
the the variability
in seed with terpene production is also
there
and so if you're growing for terpene
production you want every single plant
to to basically have that same terpene
profile
and so
you know again with the the return on
terpenes being
much higher than let's say isolate you
know they can afford a little bit higher
plant cost and it makes a lot of sense
because their quality at the end there
is going to line up be all the same um
and and be able to to get a good price
point for it
excellent
yeah glad to hear that you know terpene
the terpene market is flourishing it is
it's always good to hear um so winding
down here i did want to give you an
opportunity to talk or i did want to ask
you about uh the field day event that
your your team puts on um because i
think it's a great educational event
um where people get to
get to actually experience the plants
that you're producing and and really see
how things
uh um
are performing in the field before they
purchase it so i was wondering if you
talk a bit about that and um
why you believe it's it's so important
yeah so it's my i guess you say most
stressful but favorite time of the year
um i know i know the feeling we put on
the conference every year yeah pretty
much the same way exactly you look
forward to it and you're like
but uh no it's it's something that i i
really love doing and i i
you know from the get go i saw value in
but year after year you know really
seeing um
seeing how it's shaped out and the value
that is brought to other people has has
been
very endearing um
but what we do is we host it's usually a
two day field day
and so i was saying earlier um you know
we always send out our new varieties old
varieties to very different regions of
the us
and and collect our data that way
um south carolina being our our home
base
um you know we we do our own variety
trial and so um you know brand new
varieties existing varieties
pheno hunts um you know we we have just
about you know
as many plants there in a 30 acre plot
than maybe some states have it's it's
really cool the testing costs are
outrageous
but it's totally worth it and it is such
a treat getting to to see them um
change over time and
you know version three of cat daddy
let's say uh come down the line but
anyways we we plant those out
um we invite the public
farmers
everyone out to see it
and really the goal there is to
you know allow a farmer who is unsure
you know whether they want to plant
cedar clone whether they want to work
with us or another company you know
whether they even want to get into him
we try to provide guidance uh education
and show them you know if you're looking
for smokable flour you know this is what
the expectation is you know here are
varieties which that which fit that
demand if you're looking for
um
i don't know a purple flower you know
here's our segment of purple flowers um
and really allow a farmer to
see and touch and fill with his own eyes
before putting in a purchase
you know
it's it's getting better and better but
you know the days of of just being
thrown one coa
um and a picture and saying this is how
it's gonna go you know send me twenty
thousand dollars you know that's that's
just not good enough you know people
being able to come out and look at it is
uh is highly important and then on top
of that we have um you know i get up
there and talk about all of our new
introductions um
you know i i
talk about some of the contract research
we do um so you know within within our
variety plots
um we'll do research so this year one
big one was with pro-mix they're a
mycorrhizae company
and so
um you know having treatments with them
with different varieties and you know
being able to show the farmer that and
show them the difference and what to
look for
um and then pro-mix being their own site
where if they do have any questions you
know they can talk to their technical
rep and
um so it's a little bit of a you know a
mini trade show i guess you could say
with you know about eight different
vendors ones that i i use and would
trust
um to come and and and you know discuss
everything from soil to
zero tall
but no it's a good time and then this
year we had dr phil's come out and and
give a lowdown of what he's got going on
there and on campus green houses so
now it's it's a fun thing we do every
year and um we'll keep doing it so yep
next next fall come and see all right no
i think i think it's a great a great
reef resource because as we said before
there's a lot of people getting into the
hemp industry and it's hard to find good
guidance and good information so the
fact that you're you're providing that
for them is is fantastic and of course
it aligns with kind of our mission here
at canmed as well and and to that point
please do let us know when the next
field day is we'd be happy to spread the
word to our audience and try to get some
people down there
um
all right so with that wrapping up i
know i've taken you over the time um but
i've just enjoyed talking with you a lot
so um
wrapping up if you have any social media
or website or anything to plug to
help people get in touch with you or
additional resources that you think
would be beneficial for people to read
up on please do share
yeah so please check us out our website
is just the hempmine.com
um we also have a youtube page where we
get super nerdy and and talk deeply
about photo period and
and uh you know field maintenance and
care etc etc we try to update it pretty
regularly with with things that are are
you know directly useful for for farmers
and producers um check out our instagram
and facebook um it's just the handles at
the hempmine
and um of course reach out to me with
any questions my email was allison at
the hempmontmine.com
all right allison it was really great
talking with you and uh i hope i get to
see you out in pasadena for canbed
absolutely thank you for having me
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr allison justice check out the links
in the show description to learn more
about the topics we discussed and thanks
again to this episode sponsor 10 buds
as i mentioned at the top of the episode
this will be our final episode for 2021
and our next one will be january 5th
when we welcome back canmed 2022 keynote
presenter dr bonnie goldstein
in the meantime i hope that you will
stay connected with us on social media
join our facebook group and check out
the canmed archive and of course if you
haven't yet bought your tickets for
canmed2022
do it now and we look forward to seeing
you out in pasadena this spring
okay in closing we hope you have a safe
and happy holiday season and we hope
you'll join us for the next canmed
coffee talk
[Music]
you