[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
happy new year everyone
i hope your 2022 is off to a good start
and that the year continues to bring joy
and prosperity to everyone
speaking of 2022 canmed 2022 is coming
up fast we are less than 120 days away
from making our return to pasadena
california for three full days of
world-class cannabis educational content
it all starts on may 3rd with our full
day medical practicum led by dr bonnie
goldstein dr dustin sulak dr kevin
spellman and eloise thiessen np
each of them will share the latest
medical cannabis research including
information on dosing drug interactions
and different product types
they will also share the clinical
experience they have acquired treating
patients with medical cannabis
this really is a must attend event for
any healthcare professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but is not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event head over
to canmedevents.com
practicum to learn more
that brings us to may 4th and 5th the
main event canmed2022
two full days of oral presentations
panel discussions
poster presentations and industry
exhibitors covering the latest
advancements in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
we are really excited about this year's
program it might be our best yet
just look at our keynote presenters we
have dr ethan russo presenting cannabis
and psychiatry dr seth crawford talking
about innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and dr bonnie goldstein will discuss
cannabis medicine for children
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to
kmnevents.com
to see the full schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at cam med 2022 check out the
canmed archive which is a searchable
video library of all the past canmed
presentations and panels
you can find that at cannemedevents.com
as well and there is a link in the show
description
which brings us to this episode's guest
dr bonnie goldstein as you just heard
bonnie is a canmid 2022 keynote
presenter and an instructor on the
medical practicum in fact bonnie has
presented at every canmed event starting
with our very first at harvard medical
school in 2016.
there's a good reason for that bonnie is
one of the country's most respected and
experienced medical cannabis physicians
having treated thousands of patients
with medical cannabis
she is the owner and medical director of
canna centers wellness and education she
is clinical advisor to can formatics and
she is the author of the book titled
cannabis is medicine how medical
cannabis and cbd are healing everything
from anxiety to chronic pain
bonnie and i discussed examples where
cannabis can replace traditional
pharmaceutical drugs to treat a variety
of conditions including pain anxiety
depression sleep problems and more
bonnie offers guidance for selecting the
right products for those conditions as
well as how to find the right dose
we also talked about a new paper that
bonnie co-authored that investigates
whether cannabis can be used to treat
patients with autism
before we get to my conversation with dr
bonnie goldstein i'd like to thank this
episode's sponsor canformatics
can informatics is an early stage
biotechnology startup focused on
developing cannabis responsive
biomarkers as a universal tool for
measuring cannabis's and cbd's
physiological impact
can informatics provides healthcare
professionals patients and medical
cannabis producer processors
with the tools and technology needed for
developing evidence-based medical
cannabis and cbd treatments and products
can informatics mission is to develop
technologies that enable predictable and
repeatable science-based medical
cannabis outcomes that improve health
and quality of life
to learn more visit canformatics.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr bonnie
goldstein
[Music]
good afternoon bonnie thanks for joining
us on the podcast
thanks so much for having me
yeah welcome back
um it's been a while you joined us way
back on episode 4 of the podcast where
we talked about cannabis medicine for
pediatrics great episode one of our most
downloaded episodes so any listeners who
maybe came later to the podcast and
haven't had a chance to go back and
listen to that i'll put a link in the
show description definitely check that
out
but today
we're going to talk about a few
different examples where cannabis can be
used to replace some medications you
might have in your own medicine cabinet
now some of these are over-the-counter
drugs others are prescriptions but
nevertheless bonnie you've identified
some common conditions where cannabis
may be a safer or more effective option
than traditional pharmaceuticals so
maybe a good place to start is with a
drug that i bet is in everyone's
medicine cabinet and that's nsaids
non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs
you're aleve your ibuprofen motrin
tell us why cannabis might be a good
substitute for these drugs
sure and just to add in there are also
prescription
nsaids like moloxicam and diclofenac so
it's always good for people to
always anytime you get a prescription go
online look up what kind of drug it is
and read about the side effects just
doesn't mean you're going to have the
side effects but it is good to read
about it so um what we know about nsaids
of course they're very common
um you know we
you go for a run and you know you're
gonna pay for it later you pop a couple
of ibuprofen or something like that and
so i think we don't really think about
them very much but we know that nsaids
can disrupt
uh the gi tract and cause you know
stomach ache for some people
can aggravate heartburn for a lot of
people
and even now because of that heartburn
there's even now nsaids that come with
antacids attached to them so like a two
in one and the problem with antacids if
you use those long term is you buy a
whole new slew of problems including
dementia you can get kidney stones so
um but
one of the main things that
nsaids do is that's pretty severe
is to cause stomach ulcers which if
you're not familiar with an ulcer is
it's basically a hole in the lining of
your stomach or your intestines and
it can even cause a perforation meaning
a hole all the way through which can be
very dangerous in fact i had an elderly
patient
years and years ago who came to me and
said you know the first time we met um
he said that he could no longer take
nsaids because he had
a perforated stomach ulcer he fainted in
the um grocery store
he got hauled off to the hospital and he
had emergency surgery for a perforated
stomach ulcer
from taking long-term nsaids so it does
happen it's it's not as rare as one
would think in fact there was a study
back about 15 years ago that looked at
chronic nsaid users and 71
of people who were chronic users like
you know daily maybe a couple doses a
day had evidence of gut injury so you
know no joke there other very important
symptoms that you can or side effects
you can get from nsaids to which nobody
really even seems to know about are
strokes
heart attack and increased risk of
cardiovascular death especially when
used for a long time
so
i always tell people you know your back
hurts and you want to take some
ibuprofen that's fine or you have an
injury for a few days but long term
probably not the safest medicine in
terms of that
in terms of its profile and one other
thing too there's negative effects on
the kidneys
and a number of years ago
there was this initiative called
choosing wisely and if you people
listening want to google just you know
google choosing wisely
initiative and you'll see that what
happened was
this group went to various specialists
and said give us the top five things
that were you know primary care doctors
are kind of missing on out on like
meaning
they go to an orthopedic surgeon and say
what's the top five things that maybe
the primary care doctor shouldn't be
doing in the face of back pain but
anyway one of the things that kidney
doctors put on their list
was
for people who have high blood pressure
or diabetes not to use nsaids and i
can't tell you how many people i know
who have high blood pressure and or
diabetes and take nsaids it can damage
your kidneys it can negate your blood
pressure medicine you have to be very
careful so um you know look the fda
released a black box warning on nsaids
back in 2005 and if you're not familiar
with the black box warning it is
an extra special warning saying you know
buyer beware and when the fda does that
that means there is
it's a serious thing so we want to just
be very careful with
you know
kind of chronic heavy use of nsaids
right
and so
when we're talking about maybe cannabis
being a replacement here for nsaids is
it more for that use case there like for
managing chronic pain or could cannabis
actually be used to
relieve acute pain
well so the studies support the use of
cannabis for chronic pain but more so
remember nsaids really target
inflammation they work on
stopping a pro-inflammatory compound
called prostaglandin
um
by blocking the enzymes that make
prostaglandin those are called cox
enzymes cox and so
um
when you're using nsaids you really are
targeting inflammation well look
cannabis
all these compounds in cannabis right
cbd cbg cbda thc they're all potent
anti-inflammatories this is not even up
for discussion anymore there's multiple
studies that clearly show
anti-inflammatory effects so
um when somebody comes with acute pain i
have to be honest this research doesn't
support the use of acute pain but i have
patients who let's say will have surgery
and they'll take opioids for maybe two
days after surgery and they introduce
their cannabis
they're able to get off those opioids
and we know that people stay and we're
going to talk about opioids i hope down
the line here but like you know if
studies show that if you're on opioids
for two weeks you're likely to have some
dependence and that's kind of gets to
the slippery slope of dependence and
addiction at that point so having
cannabis on board
helps with that inflammation and it does
seem to help with acute pain i've had a
fair amount of patients um
tell me that it helps with acute pain
and i don't disregard that i do think
that
research has lagged behind our clinical
experience and so
it would be helpful to be able to do
studies in humans right because we're
still prohibited so i think the answer
from research is still not there but
certainly clinically i see that
interesting okay so if there's someone
listening now who's maybe using nsaids
somewhat regularly and maybe is a little
alarmed about some of the things that we
talked about and is thinking about maybe
trying cannabis as a substitute what
kind of products should they be looking
for maybe in terms of the cannabinoid
profile or even just you know the the
route of administration sure so um
because all of these compounds so cbd
thc cbda thca cbg cbc i mean i could go
on and on right
um lots of different so remember the
plant has over 140 different
cannabinoids that have been described
there's what we call the main
cannabinoids and some minor cannabinoids
there they're available people you can
get them um all of those that have less
than 0.3 percent by weight thc are
usually available online and it is buyer
beware so make sure you check test
results but
you could really dial in your own
um regimen there is no one regimen so
some people like cbd and are low-dose
responders for people who find low doses
don't work that well escalate the dose
and see if you can find a cost-effective
dose that can help but what i have found
is that combination so cbd plus
its precursor cbda can be a very nice
combination for inflammation because
they both are potent anti-inflammatories
what we know about cbda and thca which
are the more are the raw cannabinoids so
those are the compounds that come from
the fresh plant before they're heated up
we used to think you have to heat them
to activate them but they actually have
potent anti-inflammatory effects in the
raw form
i find that combination can work really
well cbda plus thca
and of course thc thc is a potent
anti-inflammatory
and
so
kind of playing with each one to see
what works best
we have a saying that people are
probably tired of hearing by this point
start low go slow but i'm going to steal
from dr dustin sulak one of my
colleagues who says don't be afraid to
go all the way so you can push the dose
look i have people just recently treated
someone one of my long time patients
who uses cannabis for like wellness he's
89 90 years old
he's in general pretty good shape takes
cannabis in a tincture form but he
recently developed gout
which if you're not familiar is a very
painful condition where uric acid builds
up in your joint just wreaks havoc you
know um so
he had seen a number of doctors they all
gave him medicines that he didn't want
to take that a list of side effects
so i encouraged him to try cbda at very
high doses
and what does that mean he took 100
milligrams in the morning and 100
milligrams in the evening and within
about five days his gout was it gout
pain was resolved
and
he called me to tell me i can't believe
that this worked and it worked so well
so
i
encourage people to try different things
don't be afraid to go high on the dose
of course thc
there's a much smaller window for dosing
and
you want to kind of tip toe up a little
more slowly so you don't have an
unpleasant experience but all of these
can be helpful for anti-inflammatory
effects and one thing that people
shouldn't be afraid of is using blends
because it appears that you can get away
with lower doses
because these compounds work what we
call the entourage effect or synergy and
they can enhance each other's benefits
and minimize the the risk of having to
take you know much higher doses
yeah absolutely and i recently talked
with um dr david miri who i'm sure you
know from the
um the the conference circuit and he was
talking about how the cannabinoids can
work on similar receptors and sort of
overlap in and sort of complement each
other with the whole entourage effect so
that makes perfect sense that um using
sort of more of a whole plant extract
that has
a wider breadth of cannabinoids could
could give a better
result
so i think a good segue here um would be
to talk about opioids since you already
touched on it and it also being a pain
reliever um let's talk a bit about
um opioids how does
their use differ from folks who are
using nsaids
and again how can cannabis be a good
substitute there
right so
they both fall under the category of
pain relievers right right but nsaids
are working more
as an
anti-inflammatory by blocking
production of pro-inflammatory compounds
and opioids work more by blocking
actually working through the central
nervous system your brain
and through your spinal cord by blocking
the pain messages that the body is
sending to the brain
and so um now interestingly enough
opioids are anti-inflammatory in their
effects there are some studies that show
that but they're not really used for
anti-inflammatory they're really used
for those types of pain that are
considered
you know difficult to control type of
pain you know cancer pain
post-surgical pain
when you read the research though you
know we know that people are using
opioids for long-term chronic pain
relief but they don't really work that
well for that and there's multiple
studies have come out and said we got to
find something else and you know
cannabis is a great option
um in that
uh
both canon cannabinoid receptors and
opioid receptors are kind of located
anatomically close together in
our brains and what's interesting about
that is that they can influence each
other
and so
um
remember opioids have the dangerous side
effect of
blocking your ability to breathe right
the what's called what we call in the
medical world respiratory depression
stops you from breathing if you take too
much
um and what's interesting about this
kind of combo of the receptors is that
if you target each receptor opioid
receptor and cannabinoid receptor you
can get again a kind of synergy because
we know that opioid receptors and
cannabinoid receptors can influence each
other
there's a lot of really interesting
research
looking at it and the science of it is
very complex and we definitely need more
research
but there's no question that people
can either
replace
um
opioids with cannabis or can add
cannabis as an add-on
and minimize the escalation of their
opioid use so remember with opioid
receptors you can develop
dependence and tolerance you might have
to escalate your dose
and that's when you start to get into
trouble
and it's
we have some evidence to show that
cannabis kind of can and i've had i've
have patients like this they take you
know three vicodins a day morning
afternoon and night
and now 10 years in they've never had to
change that dose or even sometimes they
can skip a dose because they've added in
cannabis
um and so i just wanted to quote some
studies because so that people
understand that this has been looked at
in a 2016 survey of almost 1500 cannabis
patients across 18 countries
reported improvement in pain
and 25 substituted cannabis for opiates
that's pretty good numbers right and
it's uh it's a it is a survey but how
else do we measure pain right um another
survey from israel looked at elderly
patients specifically because you know
the older you get the more likely you
are to have pain and chronic pain they
looked at 901 elderly patients
um that started medical cannabis and
93.7 uh percent reported improvement in
pain reduction from eight out of ten
down to four out of ten
on a scale and 20 almost 20 were able to
either discontinue or reduce opioids and
sometimes older people if they're not
encouraged by their doctor to reduce
they just kind of stay on their medicine
so one wonders if we you know pushed it
a little bit we probably could get some
of these people off and then another
survey that came out of california last
year 180 patients with chronic low pain
about 50 were able to stop opioids by
using cannabis and remember it has to be
you know you want safe access legal
access and you want lots of products to
be available so you know we're still
fighting that battle a little bit to be
able
but i think cannabis for sure is um
a strategy to help reduce the opioid
epidemic that we have in this country
that's excellent and i hope you'll share
links to those surveys and studies um
because we have a nice section at the in
the show description with uh additional
links so people can easily look at i
think that's that's great information so
again it sounds like cannabis is really
um where its place here
is
sort of in the long term use of opioids
again and not so much like you know the
acute use like you were saying you know
a post-surgery type of situation sure
uh for cr i mean chronic pain is
definitely uh
the national academies of science came
out and said yeah chronic pain in adults
is absolutely something that the
evidence clearly shows benefits
despite the poor
amount of research that we have and you
know in terms of products when people
ask how you know i'm using cannabis
doesn't seem to be helping me
there are studies that show that cbd can
help with pain and that thc can help
with pain but the combination
is something that can be really
beneficial so i've had a lot of success
with what i call low ratio cbd to thc
like a one to one or four to one so that
means four parts cbd to one part thc i
find that's a very nice
ratio to help patients one because you
don't have to take a whole
heck of a lot because thc plays a role
but the four parts more of cbd seems to
dampen down some of the thc unwanted
effects maybe
sure and
um i've even had look i have some
teenagers in my practice that have some
really complex medical conditions
and four to one seems to be that kind of
sweet spot ratio that works for patients
without
um
the risk of being impaired remember when
i'm taking care of teenagers i'm trying
to get them back to school
functioning learning
you know they want to get their driver's
license you know these are people who
are struggling to kind of get their life
off the ground and pain is in the way
whether they have a syndrome or and they
had an accident or you know when i say a
syndrome i have some patients that have
syndromes that are have you know pain as
part of it
and that four to one ratio just seems to
be a real nice sweet spot for a lot of
those patients and again they don't have
to take big doses that synergy
is there and can really help
and now is that typically taken in the
form of a tincture or some sort type of
edible rather than like a smokeable
flower that's right and so um some of
the adult patients i mean every now and
then you can find some flour that is
that ratio yeah if you can find high cbd
flour and thc flour you can blend you're
not going to hit on the four to one
probably right out of the gate i mean
you can kind of eyeball it but i often
tell people who are using um flour
whether they smoke it or vape it to
blend their strains i mean you get blend
their products because you can get a
really nice effect
in pediatric patients we use mostly
tincture
i don't know really of a four to one
edible that i can think of but in
general
tincture allows for that now if you're
using tincture and you have separate cbd
and thc you look at the label
and do the math to figure out what's
you know four part what ends up being
four parts cbd and one part thc so you
can kind of recreate your own you don't
have to find that particular product
yeah
yeah that makes that makes perfect sense
okay so moving out of the pain arena a
bit um let's shift to talking about um
anti-anxiety or anti-depressant
medication um
so first of all maybe explain some of
the the drugs that are typically used to
treat those conditions some of the
negative effects of that and then
why cannabis might be a good substitute
right so um
ssri selective serotonin reuptake
inhibitors you know fancy words for
basically saying it just lets your
serotonin hang around a little longer
and then there's some other medications
in the similar category called snri
selective norepinephrine reuptake
inhibitors
and for some people these can be very
effective but certainly
uh
not everyone and often those are the
people that i see
and also those are the people who are
turned to cannabis um the side effects
from these drugs again black box
warnings on these drugs for suicidal
ideation
um and there's some question as to
whether or not that caused you know a
little bit of uh
kind of over fear and people are afraid
but i kind of would be afraid to take a
drug that might make me want to kill
myself if i'm already um
kind of depressed and anxious so it's
you know it's fine a kind of a funny way
to treat people but some of the other
side effects agitation loss of appetite
dizziness insomnia
stomach issues and a big one especially
with young people but certainly old
people as well sexual dysfunction so
you know nobody
it certainly doesn't make you have less
anxiety and less depression if you can't
have an intimate relationship with
with someone i mean that's just you know
in terms of quality of life that's very
important so
uh and again there was a black box
warning
and especially they say for younger
people it's interesting i don't know if
you saw this there was an article in the
new york times a few months ago
two physicians who kind of pooh-poohed
the idea that you can't get off of these
drugs they have something called the
discontinuation syndrome that's been
described where like you can't just
abruptly stop a drug like prozac or
effexor or one of these types of ssris
because they
you have terrible side effects from
removing it right
and so they label it discontinuation
syndrome and they say oh it's no big
deal only 20 of patients
it turns out these two i think they were
both psychiatrists they wrote an article
for the new york times saying well we
tried to get off and it's really hard to
get off these drugs
so we're sorry that we did that to told
everybody the wrong information so
that's the other thing is when you get
started on something let's just say
you're going through a phase a difficult
time in your life right
do you actually need this drug and now
when you don't need it anymore it takes
you six months to get off of it i i
don't know that doesn't sound great to
me
um and we don't see that with cannabis
so certainly cannabis can substitute
there's significant
research showing cbd is a potent
anti-anxiety
and
of course the problem with these drugs
and with cannabis too is that can take
time to kick in nothing's magic
so remember you're asking
these drugs to change the
neurotransmitters in your brain so you
have to give it time
i do find with cbd that you know often
people are excited about using it maybe
it's a placebo effect but they feel
better hey who cares you know i'm happy
they feel better
um thc as well really can work very well
for depression and anxiety
dosing matters with thc
um and with cbd as well some people who
let's say take a low dose of cbd they
take i don't know 25 milligram little
gummy
and they do it every day for weeks and
say i just don't feel any better likely
you're under dosing and again that goes
back to don't be afraid to go higher
dose cbd has this really wide range of
dosing you don't absorb every milligram
so i've patients that responded 10
milligrams and i've got patients that
need 400 a day
okay and that's kind of where thc comes
in if you can't afford those very high
doses adding in a little bit of low-dose
thc to it can really make a difference
and help minimize tolerance with thc
help mineral
minimize any impairment
so again combination can be very nice
yeah no that's good advice okay one last
thing sorry i'm going to interrupt you
one last thing cbg counter-badgeroll
only on the market now for a few years i
have a lot of patients who report
terrific anti-anxiety with cbg
excellent excellent
no i was just going to say that i mean
with thc i imagine you have to be a
little
cautious in terms of anxiety because i
know a lot of people have
um the opposite effect of of when they
have a high dose of thc where actually
causes anxiety and i wonder if that has
something to do with the
biphasic effects of thc that i know that
dr sulak and others have talked about um
so
i just want to get your thoughts on that
like is it again it's probably best to
start low and go slow with something
like thc
right and it's good to start low with
the other ones too if you're new to them
but you can escalate a little bit more
quickly with thc you kind of you want to
just go in smaller increments somewhere
between 1 and 2.5 milligrams for most
people who are new to it you don't want
to go
and take 5 milligrams and then go to 20.
that would not be the advice you i
usually recommend 2.5 milligram for an
adult
and and uh increase in somewhere between
1 and 2.5 milligram increments to find
your sweet spot without
you know hitting up against what i call
that sealing dose where you're
uncomfortable
so
the biphasing nature is very important
very important to understand biphasic
means that these compounds can have
completely opposite effects at different
doses so thc and the low dose can be
very anti-anxiety
but if you take too much you can have
anxiety and paranoia and you know cbd
has biphasic effects as well you with
cbd you can have
very alerting effects at low dose and
say oh how do people use this for sleep
i feel wide awake but in much higher
doses it's more sedating so
until you've explored what i call low
medium and high doses you really don't
know what these compounds do
and so but one of the other things is
that there is a small percentage of the
population that just does in
i think it's something like 20 and
caucasian lower in other
races that are
um that people cannot metabolize thc
very well
right and so
you may fall into that category if just
thc does just not sit well with you and
again you don't have to use thc you can
manage with cbg cbd
um even i find thca can help there's a
very tiny amount of thc in there that's
probably doing something it is hitting
your reset your cannabinoid receptors
but i find especially in my autism
population thca works beautifully for
reducing anxiety in this in this
particular group
yeah and i think it's important to note
that with with all of these conditions
that we're talking about there is an
element of experimentation that goes
with with using cannabis right really
trying to figure out what product's
going to work for you but dosage um
maybe timing too i was going to ask you
about that um especially if you're
taking an edible or a tincture what
about taking with food or the beginning
of the day versus the end of the day
what's sort of the best
advice for that yeah great question so
um if you're taking cannabis under your
tongue sublingually or edibles
or taking uh you know a drink with
cannabis in it you definitely want to
take with food those studies are kind of
clear on this that you definitely absorb
more
when you take with food especially food
that contains fat so they did this study
uh i think last year the year before
where they showed that they gave
volunteers a little thc capsules
and um they did it on a fat what they
call a fasting state and then they did
it with what they called an american
breakfast so what do you think that was
loaded with eggs bacon hash browns
cooked in oil you know lots of fat
and it turns out that
when they uh check levels in the
bloodstream those those who took the uh
the thc
capsules with
a fatty meal or a meal with high fat
content
had higher levels and a longer exposure
interestingly in their study they found
it delayed the onset
for the cannabis to kick in but then
there was kind of a longer and more
substantial uh absorption and uh
evidence in the bloodstream so that's
number one doesn't mean you can't take
it on an empty stomach you can it's just
saying you're absorbing more uh when you
take it with food that has high fat
content remember a lot of the tinctures
have oil base right so either either in
olive oil or mct or coconut oil so the
fat's already there
okay um in terms of timing it's a great
question so
you know
in my book and also when i counsel
patients i kind of talk about first you
want to find the dose
and so starting low dose and titrating
up when you're not going anywhere don't
do it on a you know don't start
something new
when you you're starting uh you know you
have to be at a meeting or something
this is when you know your time off so
you can really take the time to assess
how you feel
if you feel better with your cannabis
pay attention to how long did it take to
kick in
how long did the effects last right
when did it wear off how long did it
take for the next dose to kick in
because all of that information is going
to be somewhat individual because some
people absorb better and quicker some
people metabolize slower or faster
so
you know for instance for me i know if i
take a tincture it takes about an hour
and a half to kick in but i know people
who say it kicks in in 30 minutes
well that's gonna if i know let's say
i'm having chronic pain
and i know it's gonna take an hour and a
half for it to kick in i am not gonna
wait for it to wear off
so that i'm going up and down with my
pain spikes i'm gonna know gee i know it
so last time i took it it lasted five
hours so at the four hour mark i'm
probably going to redose or the three
and a half hour mark so it's good to pay
attention and
oftentimes it's hard to remember so i do
encourage people to journal
or may you know there's websites there's
apps that have this but you can also
just get a notebook
and just um
document took this dose at this time
felt this
and this is how long it lasted and that
helps you figure out your timing because
there it's not like we know for instance
like ibuprofen you can take every six
hours
that's what kind of the drug companies
have figured out through extensive
research and so on but your
endocannabinoid system is unique to you
it's controlled by your dna
and it's influenced by lots of different
things in your life and so how you
respond to cannabis
we have to treat it as a customized
medicine or you're just not going to
find you know what's going to work
yeah that's great advice and yeah it
goes back to that whole point there
there is this element of customization
or experimentation that just sort of
comes with the territory but very much
worth it
when you can figure it out well and i
say what what you know the price you pay
is less side effects
right and a chance to use natural
medicine
absolutely absolutely and that's great
all right i want to move along here
because i want to be very mindful of
your time um
something you touched on uh was sleeping
um and i know that cannabis can
be very useful for that as well but i do
want to i want to say that
i personally sometimes find the opposite
problem and you kind of touched on that
too with with cbd um sometimes i find if
i have too much cannabis i'm wide awake
i'm wired so
what am i doing wrong
good question
it's dosing it's clearly dosing if
you're using thc it's dosing so the
first thing i often tell people is that
in my experience the best compound for
sleep even though there's lots of people
out there that may disagree is thc
it helps with sleep now
in the industry people call it indica
strains really when you're talking it's
kind of a misuse or you know misnomer
but really what you're looking at is you
want thc
in a and you want the terpenes which we
really only touch on
but uh the terpene myrsine and is a um
terpene known to kind of boost the
sedative effect of thc so when you get a
combo of thc with a significant amount
of myrsine you can get a nice sedating
effect in addition you can get linolol
in there as well linalool is just
another terpene found
it's cross species with lavender and
it's very calming and relaxing and often
if we can alleviate anxiety people can
fall asleep because many of us we're
tired but the brain won't turn off
because we're worried about this and
that the other thing so um i do find
that thc plus mercenary linoleum is kind
of like the first thing that people
should try
uh there's this myth that cbd helps with
sleep and it can and but it appears to
be in higher doses and in fact there was
a study which i'll be happy to give you
the um
the reference for that looked at um cbd
for um
sleep and anxiety
and they uh found that
most of the people in the study did get
relief of their anxiety
and that sustained over time
initially people did find some benefit
with sleep but they lost that effect
over time
and that's so interesting but part of
that is because i just think you know at
some point your body kind of
accommodates to the effect of cbd
remember it's not hitting the receptor
directly
it works differently and maybe you
accommodate to it so it just doesn't
help those and remember why did it help
with anxiety well we know it to be a
good anti-anxiety um and again dosing
wise they didn't go super sky high dose
so you're not getting that sedating
effect um one thing to say in terms i
mentioned some ratios earlier when we
were talking about pain i do find that
for some people a one-to-one ratio for
cbd and thc works very well
and can help
people who when they take thc and you
say you know it keeps me up what am i
doing wrong it may be that it's just a
little too much thc effect and you may
get i call it it's a funny thing i say i
you're like getting too thinky you just
start thinking and you go off on all
these tangents i've heard so many people
say that
i've experienced it myself but it's a
i feel like that one to right one ratio
allows the cb the thc to do its thing
and the cbd kind of keeps it in check
from letting you go too far with the thc
but dosing matters and if you take just
a little bit extra thc sometimes that
can actually make you stay awake a
little bit more and like i said some
people are super sensitive especially if
you can't metabolize thc so
um dosing matters and if you feel like
oh okay i took five milligrams of thc
that doesn't seem very high and it's
keeping me up well take half of it
or even you know half of that
again you may find that a little bit now
the other thing is for some people
they're able to take cannabis and then
go right to bed like take it and go lay
down with if they inhale
other people tell me they need to take
it
relax for a few hours and then they feel
like they can go to sleep so that goes
back to timing
pay attention to your timing try it both
ways try it right before bedtime try it
a few hours before bedtime because for
some people two or three hours in is
when they feel that fight that kind of
full relaxation they feel like the
anxiety's down maybe their pain is down
and they're able to then turn off their
brain and go to sleep
yeah no that description of being too
thinky yeah i've definitely
been there and i wonder too because you
said that sometimes cbd can be used to
sort of counteract those effects if you
had say um a cbd vape or flower or
something when you kind of have that
feeling happening could you use that and
they could sort of help balance you out
sure you certainly could try that
there's no question that people do that
sometimes if they feel that they got
they took too much thc they try to
counteract it with cbd they work a
little bit opposite of each other
um
in their mechanism of action so
sometimes you know that can work out one
other thing i hope i could mention ben
is that for cbn so cannabinol there's a
lot of cbn on the market now cbn is the
breakdown product of thc
so right thc ages or thca ages what you
end up having is cbn which is cannabinol
um
years ago somebody kind of posted
somewhere that it helps with sleep and
then kind of took off and i have to say
clinically i just haven't seen great
results here and there i've seen
a patient who says oh yeah it helps with
sleep or
when i combine it with thc i get better
sleep but i just haven't been that
impressed with it if you read the
research on it the and again limited
research and much of it old
there's just really no evidence
whatsoever that it seems to promote
a sedating experience so
i just want people to there's it may not
be anything wrong with you you may be
getting misinformation
um
in uh you know when your product where
they say it's for cbn for sleep
there's really no true scientific
evidence that
that is that it really does promote
sleep and i have to say that when you
look in the research
there is so little about sleep as a
primary effect
in terms of
um human clinical experience i mean or
clinical trials it's just
it's usually a secondary thing like
you're studying pain and then you ask
people secondary symptoms you know is
your anxiety better is your pain better
you know interpersonal relationships all
that kind of stuff but it's really
interesting that here we are in 2021
this plant's been around forever
california's had you know almost 26
years of medical cannabis and i still
can't quote studies on cannabis for
sleep because there just really aren't
any
yeah
no and i guess that makes sense if if
you're using cannabis to treat your pain
or your anxiety and you know you're
having less pain and less anxiety you're
feeling better you're going to sleep
better right
so i guess oh there's no question that
that's a component of it and and
um
it seems that um when you really look at
some of the data that's out there in
terms of surveys and so on that is what
people are reporting
is that my i feel better my back is not
hurting you know my joints aren't
hurting i don't have this throbbing and
remember too that if you're busy during
the day you're not really paying
attention
when you lay down at night is when you
go oh my back is killing me yeah right
so
it would be nice to be able to control
the pain and also all the anxiety that
we're all been living with regular
anxiety and then added anxiety the last
number of years
and um to be able to eliminate that just
allows you to
to turn off at night and you need to
sleep you need that that restorative
um sleep or you're just not going to
function great the next day
absolutely
all right moving on to to the last
um drug that you had mentioned here for
that we could use cannabis to substitute
alcohol
um
so again i mean i guess we're talking
about sort of using it alcohol as a way
to unwind or decompress after the end of
the day um
why do you think cannabis might be a
better option yeah
well and so let's just talk about
alcohol there's no like
equivalent to an endocannabinoid system
in our body for alcohol right it doesn't
have a target
it does stuff to us but it doesn't have
a target system it's the cause of many
medical conditions including causing
it's a direct cause of like seven
cancers it causes cirrhosis of liver i'm
not trying to talk anybody out of
drinking but it's not my favorite thing
when you're when you go through medical
training you really do see a lot of
hideousness from alcohol you know
chronic pancreatitis duis domestic
violence all kinds of crazy stuff
and then you know experts have reported
that there's no real safe amount of
alcohol but why do people turn to it and
exactly what you said
it's legal
right and it's easily accessed and it
can numb you and when you ask people who
are abusing alcohol while they're using
it they'll tell you it helps with their
they feel at least initially it help
with anxiety depression and pain
those are the main reasons that people
use alcohol and so
and i think too
we can lump in ptsd
in there as well because i think a lot
of people do turn to alcohol
um anyway um
i want to point out a great article so
this article was written
back in
by a doctor by the name of dr todd
mcaria and if you don't know dr todd
macaria so he was one of the first
doctors in california who after the law
was passed in 1996
who was willing to put his license on
the line and treat patients he was a
psychiatrist with a very long esteemed
career
he understood cannabis and he wanted to
help people with it and so he wrote an
article published in 2004 and the
article title is cannabis as a
substitute for alcohol
so it's a wonderful article i really
encourage people to read it you go to
google scholar put in cannabis as a
substitute for alcohol and you can write
dr todd and you'll find it so he
documented 92 patients that he
successfully treated who were able to
substitute cannabis
become quote sober off of alcohol
and you know from a medical approach
this is what we call harm reduction
right we don't have
cirrhosis of the liver with cannabis we
don't see
you know cannabis causing cancer we
don't see cannabis causing
cardiovascular disease or chronic
pancreatitis or
you know people beating up their family
members from cannabis so again it's a
harm reduction approach that he took
but i just want to say something that
just really stood out to me and i reread
the article in preparation to talk with
you
and he made this very interesting
observation that the patients recognized
that alcohol was damaging them
physically and emotionally
and that cannabis was doing the opposite
it was making them feel both physically
and emotionally well you think about
that
you're going to put a substance in your
body
it should make you it may even if it's a
brief happiness from let's say getting
drunk
long-term what ends up happening i have
yet to meet an alcoholic who
you know they don't want to go through
the detox but if they could quit they
would quit on a dime but it's not that
easy and it appears that cannabis can
help people so what he did was he
encouraged people who had cravings for
alcohol every time they had a craving to
use their cannabis
and eventually what happened was it kind
of shifted over from alcohol use to
cannabis use and so
um you know i i think
certainly when you look at the costs to
society of alcohol in cannabis i mean
very low cost with cannabis especially
since they're trying to
hopefully stop arresting people for it
but in terms of medical certainly
alcohol is a much larger cost to society
um
and
and and the question becomes is why why
does it work well because it is treating
these underlying conditions that you may
have
wanted to use alcohol for and so again i
just really encourage you to read the
article all those people listening it's
a great article he just makes a lot of
really interesting points and
um even goes into the history
cannabis was being used to treat the dts
delirium tremens which comes from
withdrawal from alcohol back in the
1880s
how do we ignore that in 2021 right yeah
now that we have some science
and that's a great point that you make
that you know cannabis can help with
some of these underlying conditions that
folks are
suffering from to turn to alcohol for
sort of that that numbing effect but
instead of you know replacing one
numbing effect for another they're
actually
improving it
well and he writes this little part
about it where you just get blotto and
it dis-inhibits you and you kind of go
off the deep end with alcohol right you
know you just have this kind of outburst
where cannabis makes you contemplative
helps you look inside maybe gives you
some perspective on
you know a situation that you're
struggling to deal with and
it's just a complete you can't compare
them they're not equal right
again you don't have it an alcohol
system in your body that is a target we
make cannabis-like compounds in our body
for a reason it's helped to balance us
to keep us in homeostasis and all you're
doing when you're taking cannabis is
augmenting that system we don't have
that with alcohol so it's just important
for people to separate because for all
these years
you know
law enforcement and everybody else wants
us to lump them together as drugs of
abuse and i'm sorry cannabis can be
abused but certainly cannabis is
medicine alcohol is not
absolutely that's a great point and
you're right about cannabis being very
contemplative when i when i'm having
those
experiences where i'm too thinky and
laying in bed awake uh i'm i'm
definitely auditing myself and uh
i have a nice to-do list the next
morning but that's okay it gives you
perspective it gives you a chance to
kind of step back and for a lot of
people they'll say to me it removes the
emotion so i can actually make a
decision without being so emotionally
engaged
absolutely yeah it is great for that all
right
so
thank you bonnie for for all of this
this has been great and before i let you
go i do want to talk about um the new
publication that you were recently a
co-author on um that was investigating
using cannabinoids to treat
children with autism spectrum disorder
so tell us a bit about that and um tell
us is this going to be part of your
canmed 2022 presentation
so yes i will include it in my canmed uh
presentation
so i joined forces with a company uh
called canformatics and their websites
campformatics.com if you're interested
in looking at their what they do
but basically they measure
what's called cannabis responsive
biomarkers from your saliva
which can determine your response to
medical cannabis so we're in the early
stages of this we're still doing
research but it's been about three years
of r d
and so let me explain you know the the
research real quick and then you can
kind of get what i'm talking about
so
i have many patients in my practice with
autism and we selected out a handful of
them who were already on
a regimen of cannabis that seem to be
helping them for at least a year
okay so we've established that these are
patients who respond to medical cannabis
and what we did was you know going
through a
rigid scientific method we
recruited them plus
so they're about 15 children with autism
and then we recruited nine children what
we call typically developing so no
autism no epilepsy that kind of thing
and what we did was we collected saliva
from all of them and in the group with
autism we collected the saliva before
they got their morning dose of their
cannabis medicine and just be aware they
were all on different customized
regimens they were not on the same
product or the same regimen some on cbd
some on thc some on thca so
a lot of different
regimens
and then what we did with the children
with autism is after they got their
morning dose we waited to what we called
the peak effect
when most parents felt was about an hour
and a half
after they got their morning dose and we
collected saliva again
and then we looked at the biomarkers in
the from the more you know comparing the
pre-cannabis dose
biomarkers in the post and what do you
mean biomarkers so
these are compounds that reflect
chemical pathways in your body
so for instance something that people
might understand is a typical biomarker
in men is psa they get a psa test it
looks for prostate cancer
okay
so when you go get your blood work they
draw your psa and if it's elevated you
know they start the work up to see if
you have prostate cancer and then let's
say you do have prostate cancer they
follow the psa level over time to see
are you responding to treatment did it
go down did it shoot up reflecting that
the cancer is active again so biomarkers
are already being used in science
you know quite a bit and for a lot of
things including
you know inflammatory conditions and
cancer and so on so
this group of what we call cannabis
responsive biomarkers were already kind
of shown
before our study to respond to cannabis
and so a handful of them that we looked
at for children with autism one's called
naa n acetyl aspartate and it's a
reflection of kind of neuronal brain
dysfunction and inflammation we looked
at something called spermine which
measures kind of pain response cortisol
which measures stress response
glutamine which is a neurotransmitter
anyway what we found
was that
in all the children in the study that
once they took their medical cannabis
um
that their
and by the way the typically developing
children when we collected their saliva
that kind of established what we call
the physiologic range okay
so between two certain data points with
a mean
tells us okay within here is kind of
what we're looking for
to see if it corrects to that
we saw a major shift in the biomarkers
of the children with autism towards this
physiologic range of the typically
developing children so this is clear-cut
objective data showing
that
medical cannabis in this particular
cohort was correcting
this kind of abnormal chemical pathway
biomarkers um
what we also saw
was that each child's you know biomarker
um
uh pattern let's say was very different
um and so
it's just
there's so many people out there saying
you know we need proof that it works
right
and so here is some objective data i
take a parent's word for it if a parent
tells me my child stopped you know
putting their hand through the wall
and stopped self-injurious behavior and
is sleeping through the night
you know
look i have very close relationships
with my families i know when things are
going well because they tell you but
when it's not going well they tell you
too but
for those out there who want a little
more proof this is
objective data showing that we can
correct some of the abnormal chemical
pathways by using
cannabis and remember anti we just
talked about this anti-inflammatory
helps with pain helps with stress
all these biomarkers were completely off
the charts at some of these kids and
they corrected so it's very exciting to
be able to show this
in an objective way
and so i'll definitely be talking about
it more this is our first paper we got
so many data points that we have a
second paper coming out we're very
excited about that so
um and somebody might ask well to what
end and so the way i look at this is
that potentially down the line
this would help me optimize treatment
for patients so i could get a baseline
before we get started
maybe three months in measure this and
again it's saliva it's not invasive a
parent could collect the saliva at home
mail it in
and then we could measure to see what
biomarkers are improving
is inflammation down enough do we want
to add in maybe cbda to help with more
inflammation
you know that kind of thing so
we're not there just yet but that is my
hope that we'll have some objective data
the same way we use lab data now
to try to help us make clinical
decisions
wow yeah that's that's really
encouraging and now i'm curious we were
talking about the different biomarkers
and how after the cannabis treatment it
kind of got more to the um sort of the
baseline mean that you were looking for
i'm curious
was the cannabis increasing
the levels of those biomarkers
decreasing or combination of both since
we know that you know
you know the endocannabinoid system is
sort of a regulator i'm curious if you
saw
both effects yeah we did and that's so
amazing right so when the when the
chemical was low it seemed to boost it
back to the mean or towards the
physiologic range and if it was high it
brought it down again going back to that
idea
of homeostasis balancing
and that's one of the most exciting
things that i saw because you know you
read all these articles and we've we've
got all these um brilliant scientific
minds that have written papers and i
read it all and it's like oh it's all
about homeostasis they hear somebody
says i don't know i'm going to challenge
that
theory how do we know that's what it
does how do we you know and here in this
research
we see that we can see it you know for
instance let's say
a biomarker was like minus five
a standard deviations below the mean it
would bring it up or if it was plus 40
it would bring it down so there you go
getting right back to that you know and
it didn't bring everything into
alignment like by no means but certainly
the overall
um results that we saw clearly show that
these compounds
are are homeostatic
and helping patients achieve that and
you know someone might say well these
are kids are already doing well and so
on but remember too that their
biomarkers before they got their medical
cannabis dose and we had we didn't have
them take the cannabis you know we had
like at least an eight hour wash out
beforehand which we know that you'll
metabolize a lot of that out of your
system by then
that they were kind of starting from
scratch in the morning before they got
their dose so
um and of course you know it would be
nice to repeat the studies the the next
study that we're going to try to look at
is is how
biomarkers for neuropathic pain
to see if there's a
improvement in that
and if so you know how does that work
and so on so you know there's a lot of
exciting um value here and utility with
this this type of um objective um
uh
measurement
excellent yeah and i mean we need we
need more data so thank you so much for
contributing that and uh we look forward
to hearing more about it at canmed
so
all right bonnie i definitely kept you
over the time that i i promised i would
keep you so thanks so much for um for
doing this is some great information i
think a lot of people are going to get a
lot of benefit out of this um
before i let you go
please do share any
social media or websites or any ways
that people can stay in touch with you
and keep up with everything that you're
working on
so my website is canadacenters.com and
um
on social media uh
bonnie goldstein md
that's on instagram
and then linkedin i think is under
bonnie goldstein i don't do much on
twitter so it's mostly instagram where i
try to post some you know informative
things
um
but also the name of the article if
anybody's interested and i'll definitely
um send you the link
um
cannabis responsive biomarkers a
pharmaco metabolomics based application
to evaluate the impact of medical
cannabis treatment on children with
autism spectrum disorder and again it
was published last week
and then also look for the paper coming
down the line and the next few months
thanks again bonnie um and i can't wait
to see you out in pasadena for cam ed
looking forward to it hopefully we'll
we'll get there i hope we're going to do
it we're doing it with you we'll be
there
sounds good thanks so much ben
[Music]
i hope you enjoy my conversation with dr
bonnie goldstein check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics to be discussed and thanks
again to this episode sponsor
canformatics
our next episode will drop january 19th
that's two weeks from today
in the meantime i hope that you will
stay connected with us on social media
join our facebook group and check out
the canmed archive and of course if you
haven't yet bought your tickets for
canmed 2022 do it now and we look
forward to seeing you out in pasadena
this spring
all right that's it from us thank you
for joining us for another can med
coffee talk we really do appreciate all
the support we hope you stay safe stay
healthy and you'll come back for the
next episode of cam ed coffee talk
[Music]
you