[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing i am your
host ben ameralt i'm the marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
canmed conference
i hope that all of you will join us this
spring for three full days of
world-class cannabis education at canmed
2022 in pasadena california
it all starts on may 3rd with our full
day medical practicum led by dr bonnie
goldstein dr dustin sulak dr kevin
spellman and eloise thiessen np each of
them will share the latest medical
cannabis research including information
on dosing drug interactions and
different product types they will also
share the clinical experience they have
acquired treating patients with medical
cannabis
this really is a must attend event for
any health care professionals who are
interested in recommending medical
cannabis but is not limited to those
folks
anyone who is interested in learning
more about medical cannabis can and
should join us for this event
head over to canmedevents.com practicum
to learn more
that brings us to may 4th in fifth the
main event can med 2022
two full days of oral presentations
panel discussions
poster presentations and industry
exhibitors covering the latest
advancements in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
we are really excited about this year's
program it might be our best yet
just look at our keynote presenters we
have dr ethan russo presenting cannabis
and psychiatry dr seth crawford talking
about innovations in hemp breeding
grace bandong will talk about building a
comprehensive analytical testing program
and dr bonnie goldstein will discuss
cannabis medicine for children
those presentations alone are worth the
price of admission but please go to
canmenevents.gov
to see the full schedule
and if you want a preview of what you
can expect at canmed2022
check out the canmed archive which is a
searchable video library of all the past
canmed presentations and panels you can
find that at cannemedevents.com as well
and there is a link in the show
description
this episode we welcome back iniafia to
talk about the push to standardize
cannabis testing labs in california
in late november the california
department of cannabis control issued a
statement that they are planning to
standardize operating procedures and
methods for california cannabis labs by
january 2023
this announcement got mixed reaction
on the one hand consumers and producers
have expressed frustration with
inconsistencies and lab results so they
welcomed the idea however many
laboratory professionals were quick to
point out that standardization is easier
said than done
especially because the state didn't
offer much insight into what exactly the
dcc would standardize or how they would
do it
any is qualified to speak on this
subject because he is the chief science
officer at canasafe a licensed cannabis
testing lab in southern california
he has also set up multiple labs with
best in-class methodology processes and
technology throughout his career
and at canasafe he has led the team
towards greater credibility consistency
and accountability for their clients
regulators and consumers
during our conversation we discuss why
lab standardization is a good idea
the problem of lab shopping
why some labs intentionally inflate thc
values
how natural variations in the cannabis
plant can create a range of potency
results how mishandling certified
reference materials can throw off lab
results
why labs need to be more transparent
with their measurement of uncertainty
and whether standardization will stifle
lab innovation which is so important in
an emerging industry
before we get to my conversation with
any i would like to thank this episode's
sponsor cannasafe
candasafe is a california-based cannabis
analytical testing lab paving the way in
the industry through research education
and social equity efforts
championing safe and effective cannabis
hemp and cbd for all one test at a time
learn more at csalabs.com
okay and without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with any afia
[Music]
good afternoon amy thanks for joining us
good afternoon thank you for having me
of course as always
all right so lab standardization in
california were you surprised when you
saw this news come out in late november
or was it something you knew was coming
um this sort of came as a surprise
announcement i mean if you looked at the
regulations
or i should say sb 544 you knew
something should have been coming but
the way it was announced was
kind of a surprise
what was surprising about it
well you know
it just seemed like it was just thrown
out there
as oh here you go let's see how people
digest this um i felt like there could
have been a little more
uh meat to it um it was just sort of
hey we're gonna standardize and then
everybody's like okay what does that
mean yeah
right and so have there been details
kind of since then and i was going to
ask you about that because i mean in the
articles that i've read it's basically
that you know the dcc is supposed to
standardize operating procedures and
methods for
california cannabis labs by january 2023
now have you gotten any sort of
indication of whether they are going to
involve labs like yourselves kind of in
that process in terms of
recommending certain instruments or
methods or standards has there been any
more details come out about that
um you know there hasn't been any formal
details that i've seen
sort of come out about that
however i have seen something about the
bcc cannabis committee
being formed and they were asking for
some representative folks to apply to be
on that committee
so i suppose those are all connected and
headed towards that way and i've heard
some new stories about you know state
reference labs and whatnot um that's
underway
um so i would assume all this is tied
into that
the state recently um i've been sending
out emails to labs getting trying to get
them to standardize the way they report
on their coa specifically how labs are
reporting total cannabinoids
and and some and some units on the
limits of detection and limits of
quantification so i think they're
already starting work towards that
standardization and getting the coa to
all look the same is probably one way
they're trying to make it easier to
quickly read that and and folks who
understand it
okay
and now
do you have any indication
are they going to actually
standardize certain equipment like are
labs like yours going to potentially
have to purchase new equipment i know
that that
that stuff doesn't come cheap especially
when you're talking about you know the
instruments used to analyze pesticides
and things like that
yeah you know honestly um if they do it
correctly which again i'm excited to
see how the state plans to execute this
because one thing to say it in a
secondary thing to execute it
i don't believe that they would ever
move to the standardization of equipment
or even necessarily a single compendium
method let's say for instance an aoac
method or
or an astm method um i do feel that in
standardization you know they would
recommend some things let's say we're
talking about potency
sort of the way usp does it is if they
are
putting out a compendium method they
refer to a certain column like a
consumable like a column they would say
usb l1 column to designate like a c18
column right they wouldn't necessarily
say oh the c18 raptor from rustic or you
know
agilent or whatnot so
um i feel like in some sense no it
wouldn't necessarily tie you to a
certain vendor
it might for some labs to upgrade
equipment
personally
my lab has high level equipment that is
able to
really meet the demands or whatever sort
of regulation might be put out there in
terms of limits of detection and whatnot
but for folks who maybe were not
thinking ahead of that yes they might
have to upgrade in order to meet certain
limits of detections if those are
changed or even certain um let's say
potency if they force you to look at the
spectra you may have to get a different
detector if you have a uv vis uh you
cannot do that but you may have to go to
a diode array detector to look at you
know the wavelength several wavelengths
of cannabinoids
yeah and you touched on a good point
there is
is it on the table that some of the
actual
requirements or regulations might change
as well are you going to potentially
have to be looking for new pesticides
new microbials things like that
you know i'm really hoping that they
will
what is really of concern is the
category one pesticides
that currently essentially allows the
labs to set their own limits of
detection now the state does say you
have to get to
0.1
milligram per gram but essentially
allows labs to set as high as that and
others who are perhaps more concerned
about consumer safety or perhaps
are utilizing the sensitivity of their
instruments are
validating accordingly and doing the
statistical analysis to arrive at a set
lod q based on
what they've done with matrix
interference and whatnot but then there
are just other labs who may take
advantage of that situation
and um
push that limit as far as possible
so it creates this uneven playing ground
in the industry where
you know i'm sure we'll touch on this it
kind of allows for lab shopping based on
whose loq is here who's lod is here if
my sample passes one lab it's gonna fail
at the other lab so hey i'm gonna go
here and that's what we're trying to
avoid
having that sort of um
uneven playground and just caring more
about consumer safety and and making it
uh standard that's where i would assume
the state would go
after things like that
right so yeah maybe it's a good point we
should kind of set the table here and
talk about
the reason why the state's looking to to
standardize and that is for the most
part to
to
tackle this whole issue of variability
between
lab results and which can lead to as you
said lab shopping so people who aren't
familiar with that term maybe um you
could explain it a bit and then i'd also
like to
ask you kind of how pervasive is lab
shopping is it as common as
we we hear it is
yeah you know
lab shopping really is around
um certain manufacturers
um there's about i believe there's about
43 i want to say 43 labs in the state
currently i might be wrong on that
because you know new ones are getting
added daily um but essentially it it's
great right there's competition there's
options but because there is no standard
um
way or standard methodology folks would
go out to you know i might have a a
certain flower maybe i use the west side
maybe i didn't i'm gonna send it out to
five labs
um they're all gonna come back given
we're dealing with an agricultural
product
they're all going to come back
differently potency is going to be a
little different
based on limited detection my pesticide
residue might pass or fail
so as a manufacturer
i'm going to
you know probably go with the lab that
is uh most likely to pass me based on
whatever standards they've set for
themselves
and i really think the problem with lab
shopping is um
it's it's many factors fold uh issues in
many ways so
for one it does force competition in a
detrimental way where all parties lose
i look at it this way
first of all the consumer loses right as
a lab may falsify results leading to
higher uh higher prices for sub potent
products and perhaps even false negative
products where a contaminant is being
put out there so consumers are living in
that and
the buyers and the dispensary lose
because they're paying more for inflated
values if a lab is cheating on potency
the regulators lose because essentially
they lose control of that process if
they don't have a standardized method
the labs themselves lose right as
there's a race to the bottom on pricing
we all know inflation is rising
consumables are higher test costs
unfortunately seem to go lower you know
everything in the world is going higher
but somehow test costs seem to be going
lower which doesn't make sense right
competition is great but they're losing
in that way
the employees lose work as
you know a race to the bottom is causing
laps now shut down as they can remain
competitive they cannot afford to pay
employees you know of course what
happens the taxpayers lose because
people go unemployment unemployment
increases it's just slippery slope you
can see how it really isn't great for
anybody to allow this to continue
absolutely and in terms of
shopping
is it mostly around potency numbers is
it brown contamination is it a little
bit of both or is there sort of a test
that that folks are shopping for more
than others
well personally i can tell you that i
see it a lot around potency
where folks are sending in samples and
you are doing your best to give
um a high
quality controlled result and folks are
saying hey well lab b
is giving me 10 points higher on it so
you get a flower in and you're testing
at 19 but lab b is testing it at 27
which clearly doesn't make sense now yes
there's arguments around hey it's an
agricultural product is it a top nug is
it a bottom was it outdoor was it indoor
you know you know there's variances but
those sort of variances are highly
unlikely
um so
yeah
sort of in addition to that i mean at
least here locally we're out in
massachusetts we're kind of seeing some
thc numbers get up in the realm of
the very unlikely like a friend of mine
recently texted me and said that there
is a dispensary that had a bud on the on
their menu that was 47 thc
which
i mean you tell me
does that seem likely
so you know as far as flour that is a
flat
what do you want to call it just just a
lie that seems highly unlikely i don't
care how great your growing conditions
are but now you starting to push a limit
of what the plants could produce 47 thc
that would mean
thc a would have been at least 13
higher
um i mean now you're just beginning to
push the limits of what's possible
and and would really do see that a lot
you know we we really do see
um i've done some sort of um
round robin testing uh with some venable
labs where we've sent
some samples out right flower
homogenized flower and what's been
interesting some some some of them know
about it some don't but what's been
interesting is
all other cannabinoid numbers would line
up within one to two percent except thca
um for certain labs would be 10 points
higher i'm talking about i would get 20
they would get 30. or or the last would
get 20 something left to get 30. so it
kind of begs the question when you're
looking at about 10 different
cannabinoids and they're all lining up
but one
why is lab b
of sudden 10 points higher on this one
compound but all the other compounds are
spot on with everybody else i mean
that's a clear indication of inflating
potency for flour based on that of
course those labs will not do it based
on an edible delta 9 knowing that well
if you if manufacturer gives you a 10
milligram edible you know you're not
going to give them back a result of 15
milligrams right it doesn't quite work
out or 20 milligrams but you can on
flour
and they build in this unscrupulous work
and this is what we see of course we
would lose business because well
lab b does give them that number
and unfortunately not much we as labs
can really do about it you know the
owners is really on the state to enforce
some of those things um from happening
yeah and i have to imagine that a lot of
this is based too on the fact that
consumers
really look to that thc number as the
indicator of quality for the cannabis um
i'm still waiting for the day when
that's not the case and that consumers
will will look at you know aroma or bag
appeal or just flavor more so than just
a raw thc number you know i totally you
and i both i think we've beat this thing
to death about hey it's not just about
that thc number as an indicator of
quality i mean cannabinoids or cannabis
depending on how you're using it um
really depends on a myriad of factors
you know we all talk about the
entourage effect and whatnot you know
there's turpin's effects and there's
been talk back when where people were
saying well you know this 12
flower from california knocks my socks
off and i get a 30 from nevada and it
doesn't do anything and it's like well
yeah because it's not just about the
numbers it doesn't mean that you know
the lab in the other state was cheating
but it's not just about that thc number
it's an entourage effect along with your
body as well your receptors and how
how those behave how
you your genetics are playing a factor
into it so
yeah it'd be great on the day when you
can really you know
look more to the science of other
compounds and not even just cannabinoids
but the whole set of compounds in
cannabis and how they play
with your receptors to really give you
you know certain relief that you're
looking for
well that end you know not all of us are
looking to get their our socks knocked
off either right you know when you
you're buying
alcohol you're not
going for everclear every time you're
you're going for a nice wine or
something like that so
one of these days it's gonna change this
week and we can only hope
uh so but talking about the variation
between labs and you know we've touched
on the fact that you know some labs
might be unscrupulous and kind of
inflating numbers but i was wondering if
you could talk about you know just
more natural variations whether it be
like you've touched upon before that the
plant is is not homogeneous and there's
going to be some some variation in the
plant itself
um but what about different instruments
different different reference standards
different things like that could could
those be be causing the variations as
well that we're observing
you know that's really a good point uh
that you brought up then yes so
um
when we talk about you know an
agricultural product that's grown acres
and you have lights hitting different
parts of it and and your nutrients uh
getting certain parts or or disease
hitting certain parts of it uh yeah your
cultivar would necessarily have the same
value homogenously throughout so there's
yeah lots of other factors that affect
that
honestly
it starts off in sampling even how you
sample the product right when you're
sampling for an assay are you
doing it in a statistically significant
manner are you picking evenly or you
only picking top-notch top nogs versus
you know smaller popcorn but you know
depending on what you're looking for
and then yes you get to the instrument
there is the issue with
manufacturer of your certified reference
material
right you have to
vet that very well make sure it's an
iso-created manufacturer and make sure
okay i've i done my due diligence and
make sure that this compound is at the
purity that they say it is and is it
stable enough because i've seen a
situation where we all know once you mix
this cannabinoids even in standards
together um interactions are some
interactions that begin to happen and
there is some breakdown
the carboxylation depending on your
storage condition and how many
cannabinoids are mixed together it's
unstable right so
the lab has to do the due diligence and
make sure they're storing their
standards correctly they're vetting
their vendor correctly and they're
calibrating correctly you know each of
the standards come with a certificate of
analysis just like we put out for the
public you have to look at that what is
the purity of my thca
does the vendor who did their work and
say hey we've done
the analysis and the period is really 90
percent so if i'm getting a 1000 ppm
standard um when you shoot it on your
instrument it's really 900
but
as an analyst am i typing in 1000 into
my
hplc that would be wrong right because
the vendor says this is a 1000 ppm
standard however based on the purity
it's really 900 so technically you
should be typing in 900 so you can see
how things start to get funny if even
the analysts may not be even
unscrupulous about it may just be
ignorant to that fact now they're
looking at coas
these are all things
we have to consider that adds to that
variability
right and all these things can kind of
come compound upon each other right and
kind of create even bigger variances
they really do i mean we talk about we
talk about methods of
measurement of uncertainty you know has
every lab really done this how your
pipette has an effect is was it
calibrated everything you do adds to
your measurement uncertainty so has
all the labs
necessarily
analyzed for the measure of uncertainty
what is that value how far away what is
the error that you expect per your
result you know we've talked about it
several different ways is that something
that should be reported on a coa should
you report your cannabinoid value as a
range rather than a single certified
value because technically a range makes
more sense and it's probably the most
accurate
now i get where folks wouldn't want that
right if i'm selling and i'm reporting
oh the sample is between 18 to 21
well i guess
there are certain folks who are selling
it that may not want that right but that
is the truth and is that something the
state should regulate you know i will
leave that up to the states to make a
decision
[Laughter]
yeah smart man
um
we're talking about standardization too
and
if the state's going to come out and and
dictate certain standards
do you think that that would potentially
stifle innovation that the labs need to
do
i know i've listened to
panels that you've been on on canmed
before and you've talked about how
it never surprises you the different
matrices that come through the door and
that each one is sort of a different as
a small science project to be able to
fully analyze it and
how would a standardization push like
this sort of prevent you from from doing
that
um you know great question
um honestly you gotta talk about what
the
the the rules are looking to standardize
right it depends really on what you're
attempting standardize uh we're talking
about homogenization are we talking
about the prep method talking about
sampling or the instrument method right
i think when we talk a lot about this a
lot of folks refer straight to the
instrument method but uh forget to
realize that those other parts play
probably a bigger role
in
the variability that we see
how how labs are homogenizing their
sample can make a huge difference you
know you're picking off uh kefir
material versus a homogenizing the whole
uh flower um you know
that has to be regulated
and yes i do believe if we head towards
you know some of maybe the instrument
method it is going to stifle innovation
you know you see labs out there as more
standards become available while we're
getting to analyze more and more
cannabinoids you see coas with you know
20 or more cannabinoids being analyzed
for this gives the consumer more
information
i think if you look at sb 544 you got to
ask the question is it referring to the
state reference lab adopting a standard
test or for all licensed labs being
forced to adopt a single method you know
it's all about interpretation
right um so
i think the intent of of the of the sb
544 is noble but if the goal is to
stabilize an agricultural products
potency
enforcement is really the way um i think
they need to head as rather rather than
try to
force labs to use a single method which
would stifle the innovation
even when you look at a
usp yes there are compendium methods out
there but it allows
also for each individual lab to be able
to validate a method per
the the the
criteria set forth by the regulating
body right so yes you can use my method
or if you don't or don't have that
instrument you can use this other
instrument but you have to validate
following this criteria
and that's where things might be a
little bit better and easier if the
state went that route right
um i you know honestly i think they need
to perform more on label round robins um
fro with with all different cannabinoids
to get the labs to align a little better
you know it should be within a 10
deviation
um it shouldn't be as far as what we're
seeing now up to 40 deviation
right
um
it shouldn't be able to only force labs
to analyze a certain subset of compounds
you know if they do this will they be
forcing you to analyze on the thc cbd
cbda cvga
you know what exactly will they
establish a list of compounds
so
again i'm really anxious to see you know
what kind of how to execute this how the
dc execute this and that'll really
determine the success of that program
yeah and so
would you
not necessarily support but would you
expect that the the state would
potentially do sort of a
a proficiency test where they kind of
homogenize a big batch and send it out
to all the labs and then see if
um what the variation is between the
results
uh most definitely i would expect that
uh something like nist has been doing
which you know we've been participating
in
for all the rounds where the homogenized
one and send it out but here's a problem
when
the state does this
if a lab is doing something unscrupulous
they know this and they know the right
way to do it so magically the state
numbers from all the labs are probably
going to align right right so i think
the statement is finally blinded or
something right it needs to be blinded
needs to be really blinded the cities
find a way to do this probably through
the
manufacturers or whoever they want to
use without the labs knowing and and
that will be the true test right if they
just send in some
manufacturer hey you know we're looking
to be a new client here's my uh product
we'll quickly find out which labs are
you know especially if you send them a
homogenized product that'll eliminate
the variability or at least reduce the
variability and then you can really see
who's um boosting numbers
absolutely and now
what do you think about producers and
manufacturers having their own in-house
testing um is that something that could
sort of help
um regulate or or stifle some of this
lab shopping
yeah you know
i've worked with a few
producers that do that um and some of
the best ones work directly with the lab
and say hey
we're going to develop this relationship
i have an hplc in-house
here's my method let me see your method
let's get on the same page
and then you begin to analyze together
and look at the school analysis the
differences in your methodologies and
you come to some sort of
consensus in what you're doing and those
folks get you know um
they would do their in-house and they
will be directly in line with what is
expected because they wouldn't have to
necessarily depend or go lab shopping
but there are some considerations when
you want to do something like this you
know
for one you should follow some kind of
strict qaqc procedures
uh with your third-party lab
and it's important that you're aligned
with who your crm vendor is
even so many consumables
the method is it standardized even the
instrument they're using you know the
labs have to get
preventive maintenance done every so
often
i would
expect the producer to do the same with
their instrument and even more
importantly qualified personnel to run
it
because again this is not like uh you
know just a plug and play oh let me do
this like like you mentioned before a
little bit before um every day is a
little experiment as you get these
different matrices in and you need to
have somebody who's qualified to
understand what they're dealing with
to be able to think on their feet and
understand when things go
out of whack or
or really understand the instrument
itself so yes i think it's a great thing
that folks should be doing um but it has
to be in line with how the lab tests as
well
yeah and that's a good point when you
when you talk about just
you know competency competency of the
lab techs and you said that you know
there's 40 plus labs in california and
as we know cannabis is a very
complicated matrix with a lot of
different compounds and
pesticides that have similar molecular
weights to the compounds and
you know
not that you need to name any names but
how much of this variation could come
down to just you know either whether it
be inexperience or incompetency as well
oh you know that that is a very good
question and i don't know if we'll ever
find out i feel like um it's complex
however
um cheating is easy
right i i think folks hire some pretty
intelligent folks um um and cheating is
really easy cheating consistently is not
easy right and that's where you start to
weed out uh those labs and we've seen
all kinds of stories and the headlines
of you know recalls and labs doing this
and that
um so i think um a lot of it i wouldn't
chalk it up to
competency there's a
percentage of it i do chuck it up to
direct negligence um on either the
analyst the the lab
ownership management staff it's it's
it's intent right of course it's hard to
prove intent but i think you know if you
look in the right places you can see
that
um and and that's what unfortunately
really bothers me
in that with with this
competition that's happening is not
being regulated in the right way and we
cannot expect the lab to be you know the
regulators um i think the state needs to
listen when when folks do tell them
about potential issues and they should
do the due diligence and they've done
great i know
you know 43 laps across the state or
more and you know so many staff in the
state to be able to handle this they've
done a great job you know doing their uh
their own audits and whatnot but you
know maybe there's some better ways to
make it a little bit
easier to weed out some of this
unscrupulous players
and you know that's always something of
course i'm i'm willing to help if needed
um i think we all need to
be the beacon in this industry you know
like somebody once said all boats rise
in the tide and and california is set an
example
excellent
all right so so winding down here and
forgive me but i'm going to put you on
the spot a little bit
so it sounds like i mean you're in
support of of standardization and this
push here obviously probably with some
caveats too like that you know there's a
certain
um level that you're you're willing to
go to so so what is that so say i'm
putting you in charge of standardization
of labs in california
um how would you do it
oh wow yeah you definitely put me on the
spot
i wasn't ready for that one um no but
honestly
how would i do it um i would kind of
follow usb's footsteps you set out some
or work you know not just usb but work
with aoac work with astm with some of
those companion methods out there make
sure it's modern first of all you know
nobody wants to work with a method that
is using uh some ink blood tests or
whatever
but yeah um really look at okay
if you want to analyze cannabinoids you
can say
give a myriad of detectors you should
use a myriad of instrument types you
should use and i'm talking about you
know hplc or lcms i'm not talking about
manufacturer specific instruments
um
a column specification
right
some mobile phases there are certain
parameters i would say this should be
followed and each lab would essentially
could have a couple options
um you have to be able to replicate the
standardized method and you can have
your own
innovative method as well
right so
and those two
based on whatever analytes you're
looking at should match
right so if i randomly send you a sample
and i say run it on you know the the
your your standardized method and your
own innovative method you should come up
with the same results that's how we do
it have the labs sort of maintain
a state reference method and they can
you know report on their own method
based on a validation that meets the
criteria that was set forth so
validation is important as well set
specific criteria and specific uh ways
reference fda or
or whatever other organization
you would like to reference as far as
validation
parameters
and enforce that
secondarily continue having blind
round robin sent out
randomly throughout the year to make
sure that labs are in line conduct a
more regular audit and audit the
different
areas of the lab not just you know a
certain essay or certain
personnel
or instrument but
keep it fresh
right this is how you keep people on
their toes this is how you keep people
honest
that's really what i would focus on
and
additionally you know the potency thing
is a huge issue
but i'm more concerned about contaminant
levels
making sure that labs are not putting
things out there that folks that could
be detrimental to folks health
right that's very important you know
yeah they can play the potency game but
when you start messing around with
instrument limited detection to pass
things that perhaps shouldn't be out
there for you know we always talk about
immunocompromised patients but it's not
just about them it has to be the entire
population
whether i'm immunocompromised or not
doesn't mean i want to smoke a product
full of chlorphenipia or or middle
corporate right
nobody really knows how this affects
your body based on the route of
administration
so that has to be of utmost importance
to the state and i guess that's what i
would really focus on
finding innovative and efficient ways to
enforce
while
enforcing on
modes of validation
i think as opposed to trying to stick a
lab to say oh only analyze this four
cannabinoids by diode array detector and
and that'll be the standardization
right
all right well you handled the question
well very very good
try
all right i'm gonna let you go thanks so
much for for joining us and it'll be
very interested to see how this all
plays out in california and um good luck
yeah thank you very much thanks for
having me
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
indiafia check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
our sponsor cannasafe
we will be back with a new episode on
february 2nd groundhog day that's two
weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out all
the great resources we have at
canmenevents.com
you can view the canmed 2022 schedule
explore the canmed archive listen to
previous podcast episodes and of course
sign up for email alerts
if social media is more your thing you
can stay connected with us on instagram
twitter linkedin and facebook just
search for can events and speaking of
facebook check out our canmed community
facebook group
it's a great way to connect with your
fellow attendees and presenters in
between events
and one last thing please rate review
and subscribe on your favorite podcast
app doing so really helps the podcast
reach more listeners
okay that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy and please join us for the next
canmed coffee talk
[Music]
you