[Music]
I mean for a lot of us in the industry
we take a lot of this information for
granted and assume that it's common
knowledge but it really isn't so having
a show like this that's more accessible
to the general public so that they can
start understanding what we already know
um is very
powerful you know I ran up against that
one at the History Channel you know when
when we first took over history it was
there was a lot of criticism that we
were showing shows that weren't really
about history and I thought well you
know everything we do is about history
but what we did find was that
it it inow television is a wonderful
means of expressing emotion it is a
terrible means of giving
information um but if you tell as I say
if you have it's a great emotional
that's like you know you see a cotton
commercial and you cry right I mean it's
uh so it has a
it it triggers people um and the one the
most successful thing we did at history
was that it wasn't so much that we were
just reciting like a historical
encyclopedia we just got people excited
about history and as they got excited
about history we went from the number 34
Network up to number
three um and people knew where they you
know you get them excited about American
history they go on to the internet and
they learn about it here if we get
people excited about cannabis they'll
start doing their research they'll come
back to you and they'll find
you um rather than having to go to the
conference they'll be doing their own
research because of their passion and
then they'll find you excellent you know
the other thing the other Beauty about
the show uh a lot of people think that
these entrepreneurs are just sitting
back making boatloads of money yeah uh
not true they're fighting for their
lives uh you know uh the millions and
millions of dollars that it takes to
build a grow an indoor grow the the the
amount of money that it takes to open a
dispensary the not only the the
regulations you got you know federal
state county Parish you know depending
where you are which is changing daily
and stick around it'll change in the
next 20 minutes uh it's it's like you
know banks close you down because for no
reason because we don't have safe
banking in the industry you know they
because you work in a cannabis industry
you can't go buy a car you can't buy a
house uh because you're using federally
illegal money well it's the same damn
money that's in my pocket uh that's in
yours I I mean the list goes on of what
these poor guys uh men and women in this
industry are fighting uh and we touch on
on all of it in the show uh to show
people that hey it's not all you know
champagne and Popp and corks these guys
are actually busting their butt because
they believe so much in this plant
they're willing to do this and that's
what high science is all about is
showing all of it
[Music]
a