i want to thank canmad very much for
inviting me and it's
like dr i'm going to say michelle who
spoke earlier from uh columbiacare
this is the first cannabis conference
i've been to blue since covid and so
it's great to see some old friends see
some new friends
sister laurel how are you
and uh
some dear friends on the panel here i've
known three of the four for i've been in
this industry for about 10 years my wife
and i cringed i'm not gonna get
emotional now uh started this uh
started this journey in 2010 cannabis
wasn't our lifestyle and i'll just do a
cliff note version my father-in-law was
diagnosed with stage four uh lung to
brain cancer and he was on 24 7 oxygen
and he was
declining every day so every morning we
would call to make sure did he make it
through the night and i said i'd like to
go to your next oncologist appointment
and we went and karen and i found a
study that showed 20 excuse me 40 of
cancer patients pass some malnutrition
before cancer takes over so while we're
in the oncologist's office we asked how
much time do we have and his oncologist
said
two weeks and through tears
uh more from me my father passed about a
year and a half prior not from cancer
but from a heart attack
her grandparents were still alive 98 97
they they were together since age 16 so
if that's not a beautiful way to live
and i said what about cannabis for
appetite stimulation not knowing the
true medical benefits of this incredible
plant
and i call it corinne mary poppins
because she didn't drink and she didn't
smoke and i said dean kerr the caregiver
and we did and we went on this journey
the blind leading the blind and back
then in 2010 2011
there was no guidance there wasn't uh
top doctors in this industry scientists
that were really out there talking about
the benefits of cannabis
dosing dosing there was nothing about
dosing you would say
enough for one person but it was really
enough to feed the whole nfl football
team with what the what the the dosings
were
so we found a coconut game a piece of
chocolate knocked him on his behind and
we found a coconut and capsule that the
reason we went that way allowed us to
freeze and cut into slivers
and within 24 hours he was eating
and
six months later hospice fires him as a
patient at nine months he was never
going to get scanned and he came back
with no evidence of recurrent disease
we said wow this is a miraculous plan so
we went on this journey to educate
education is the key
uh not only in life but especially with
this this uh
plant
as the laws in the united states are
growing
for cannabis use
the lack of doctors knowledge is is far
far behind
and so it's tough when a patient calls
hey my doctor just recommended cannabis
what do i do now
and that's frustrating and so
conferences like this conferences i look
at it as the ripple effect
pebble in the pond ripple effect the
education that's going on so what we've
learned here this week we'll take back
to our home and share with our doctors
our families our patients etc
2017 my wife was diagnosed with
pancreatic cancer and she passed four
months later
to me
success with this plan is saving a life
like we hit a grand slam with my
father-in-law
other success is getting out of bed
seeing your loved one sleep
pain relief wellness
and so
i continue this journey this is real
life for me and i know it's real life
for a lot of people who've been into
this injury and who
changed their whole careers eloise
eloise has worked with us for years she
was an oncology nurse
to see all these patients passing away
from chemo radiation
it was affecting her health
affecting her health and she saw the
benefits of this plan she changed her
whole career
bonnie goldstein the same thing
ucla studied
medical doctor saw the benefits really
stuck took a step forward
i mean all uh
dustin and and
kevin as well
uh
putting their reputations on the line
and and it's nice to see that their
stigma of this plant has really dropped
because before it was
hush we're not really going to talk
about it so
anyway um i'm here
proud to represent the medical cannabis
community and where we're going um i'm
here with some colleagues that i
admire
and i look forward to where this
industry is going
they're rock stars in this industry if
you have not already realized that
we have a resident singer in eloise
thiessen so thank you for that as well
so
i'm booking shows into 2023 so
so how many patients in the audience
good to see you
yeah i think we're all patient yeah but
good good to see you and uh
you know don't be afraid to ask
questions because it's not illegal to
ask questions as a matter of where you
live here in the united states in some
countries it is but don't feel this is
your body
if your doctors aren't open to this ask
them for a recommendation for another
doctor and so
um i'd like to start off with uh dustin
you know one thing that you taught me
and i share with a lot of people is
sitting there taking a deep breath
and just taking a body check and so i
know we're i don't wanna say we're
saving the best for last but uh uh
thanks for sticking around for this uh
this panel here but can you share i i
love what you do of with that body i
know you spoke about it at the medical
practicum on tuesday but if you can
share it with the audience too sure i'm
happy to and for the amazing av crew in
the back if there's any way to get more
monitor on the stage so we could hear
john more clearly that would be great
so
um
probably about seven years ago i was
wondering how to help my patients detect
a
kind of subtle change in the way that
they're feeling based on a certain dose
of cannabis because i became very
interested
in using the lowest effective dose to
nudge the physiology using a term from
kevin uh
so that we don't overwhelm one's
physiology we can work in concert with
the endocannabinoid system instead of
undermining it and i developed something
called the inner inventory which is nice
it feels good and it just takes about 30
seconds so we could all do it together
right now and the way i recommend my
patients do this is to practice the
inner inventory maybe write it down in
fact our healer products come with
little workbooks and worksheets so you
can keep track of how you're feeling
with certain doses of cannabis and
really get a highly individualized
treatment regimen
so there's three measures could be four
if there's a symptom that you're
experiencing and you want to check in
with that the first one is breath and so
you're going to write on a scale from 1
to 10 how smooth and easy your breath is
when you just take one nice deep
inhalation and exhalation
and so you could just think about what
that number is for you for me it's nine
right now
and the next measure is body so
uh just wherever whatever position
you're in just kind of remains still
there and right on a scale from one to
ten how comfortable that is
and i'm at about a six
and then the next one is mood so you
could rate how content you feel at this
moment or you could put a fake smile on
your face and give it a few seconds and
see how real the fake smile becomes
and i'm i'm like 9.5
um and then you could rate a symptom so
say you were gonna inhale some cannabis
you would maybe recheck that in 15 or 20
minutes or if you were taking some oral
oral mucosal cannabis recheck that in
about 90 minutes and see if that dose
affected you now other things might have
happened in that time that could have
changed your inner inventory score and
the the secret is that
just checking in with yourself is
probably going to make you feel better
but that's a good thing to do anyways
you know if we can kind of capitalize on
this placebo acceptance effect and make
ourselves feel better just by paying
attention to ourselves maybe given a
little self-love
that's that's just helpful so there we
are thanks for checking in everybody
thank you
and you are right
i can't hear you from here
so when hearing all the other speakers
saying i didn't catch that it's
enough can you turn this on this this i
think it's the side one pointing at us
might be helpful but
anyway i wanted you guys to introduce
yourself as well and so
eloise if you like start
sure i have new initials i'm eloise
thiessen no
no i'm an adult geriatric primary care
nurse practitioner
[Laughter]
and i'm an osteopathic physician a
traditional osteopath been practicing in
maine for 13 years and using cannabis
with my patients that whole time
i'm a pediatric trained physician here
in los angeles and after doing pediatric
emergency medicine for many years i
switched to a cannabis specialty
practice about 14 years ago
and i am a phytotherapist and let me be
clear that's not using small dogs as
therapeutic agents but phyto as in plant
or in the states we say a clinical uh
herbalist
sense of humor
thank you
[Laughter]
so
you know i always say cannabis is not a
one size fits all type of medicine age
weight current health condition
sensitivities stage and drug to drug
interactions and so
i wasn't getting into drug drug drug
interactions but let's talk about this
one comes up too and bonnie you talk
spoke about this earlier
is
i want the re i want the medical portion
of the plant
not
the recreational portion of the plant
and we spoke about thc there's a lot of
benefits of t of all the cannabinoids
you know when i usually present i
usually have a wall with a roll of duct
tape up there and people look at me like
hey dummy you have the wrong the wrong
slide up there and i kind of laugh
because when people ask what about this
what about this what about this ailment
i don't want to say it's like a million
and one uses like duct tape but when you
really get down to it really is
and uh
there's so many
each cannabinoid plays a role
thc
we're here in california my brother's in
the wine business i'm in santa barbara
it's like you know we can have a sip of
wine chip wines of wine and wine tasting
and the same thing with thc and you've
always shared that less is more so can
you talk about the less is more and not
only beneficial because it's not covered
by insurance yet but also saving money
but also you might find your sweet spot
at the lower amount
um would you like to talk on that and
that and the same thing down there with
you kevin please
sure i'll just jump in real quick bonnie
showed nice slides earlier that
depicted the internalization of the cb1
receptor when it's over stimulated now
we have heard over and over again how
important this endocannabinoid system is
in responding to illness and injury in
supporting our growth and development
our neuroplasticity we want that system
working as efficiently as possible and
when we build tolerance to thc at least
to some extent we are decreasing the
capacity of that system to to keep us
healthy so um
you know one of the nice things is that
it's easy to reverse tolerance to thc it
happens probably more quickly than a lot
of other agents but
so it's not like a lot of harm done and
maybe even a useful lesson learned from
overusing thc and building tolerance to
it but what i see with my patients is
when each person has
kind of figured out their optimal dose
of cannabis the retention of efficacy
could be decades i mean they really
don't
lose the beneficial effects and over
time they tend to use less and less
cannabis the dose goes down low slightly
we saw that in ethan's slide this
morning and i think that's because we're
becoming more balanced inside we're
establishing a greater homeostatic
capacity and and people are healing when
we're less sick we tend to need less
cannabis so that's my perspective on
always using the lowest effective dose
and just to comment uh yeah that this
whole you know i think it came from cnn
this
like a lot of other things this whole
concept that cbd is medical and thc is
recreational it's just it's crazy and i
think you all know that but for anyone
in the audience that hasn't realized
that yet after listening to all these
panelists today thc is an incredibly
powerful therapeutic agent and quite
versatile it does not need to be
psychoactive there's almost always in
every patient a therapeutic window where
there's a certain dose of thc that will
create beneficial therapeutic effects
and then a higher dose that'll start to
create potentially adverse effects which
might be impairment or or unwanted
psychoactivity
thank you yeah and i'll take it from the
30 000 volt view since uh dr sulak just
did such a good job of explaining on the
cannabis level so there's a concept that
goes across all biological kingdoms and
it's called hormeses
it's had several names over the last
decade
today we know it mostly as biphasic
response and essentially what that means
is that a low dose can be incredibly
beneficial and a high dose can actually
even be toxic if not damaging right so
the concept there is that finding the
right dose is really key so dose
titration or slowly scaling up your dose
to that optimal level is something that
i used to do with other plants besides
cannabis
in the clinic i mean i think it's really
really key to recognize this
interestingly a quick story on this is
that
in the 19 so the homeopaths back in the
early to mid 20th century were looking
for a way to explain their medicine
scientifically and of course if you
understand homeopathy truly understand
homeopathy um there's it's we're going
to have to change the laws of phases
physics and chemistry to
really be able to embrace homeopathy in
a scientific way not that it doesn't
work i've seen it work and i've seen it
work in in laboratory situations as well
but they needed a way to explain it and
so the hormesis concept was really big
in the early to early 20th century in
fact there were multiple journals
dedicated to just that concept that low
dose could be very beneficial and high
dose and you know they were talking
about toxins for example
the guy that
has brought it into modern age
found by
trying to poison a plant that he
actually made it grow more because he
deluded the poison too much
and i'm not saying go out and drink
poison give me give me clear here that's
not what i'm saying here but that
concept of one dose having one effect
and another dose having another effect
that biphasic response so the homeopaths
jumped on this model they were like
that's how our stuff works really low
doses of whatever it was whatever the
homeopathic remedy was akin item or
arsenic or you know that's that's how
our stuff works
well
interestingly
in a very political move in the sciences
which we're supposed to be immune to
the concept of hormesis dropped
off the map
and
calabrese edward calabrese brought it
back in about 1980 and so now there's
hundreds of publications on hormises so
interesting story there the homeopaths
kind of
we lost the concept because the horm
because of the homeopaths and i just
want to add one other thing about the
homeopaths that a lot of you might not
realize but this whole breaking cannabis
down into two things cannabis indica and
cannabis sativa this was an early
homeopathic concept they had two
different cannabis remedies that had
some overlapping but distinct features
and again these were just incredibly
small quantities of cannabis like to
some extent diluted beyond avogadro's
number where you're just getting an
energetic essence of cannabis and no
actual molecular content potentially at
least and um and that there were these
differences among this plant and so
thanks to the homeopaths for the whole
indica sativa nomenclature nightmare
and by the way that's a that's a really
important point is people say homeopathy
when they really mean herbal medicine
and they're not the same
right what dr sulak was just talking
about is
dilution beyond avogadro's number which
basically means
technically there's
one or two molecules in your remedy
depending on how diluted the remedy is
so
that's why i'm saying they'd have to
change the laws of chemistry or physics
to really be able to scientifically
explain homeopathy
thank you
you know the discussion of products
comes up quite a bit with patients and
so
bonnie you and louise spoke about
you now there's an overabundant cbd and
now you can't find the good products of
thcs thc products out there
can you explain
the difference to patients
of
medical products versus recreational
products okay so they all can be used
for either right i mean cbd dominant cbd
you might have to drink the whole bottle
to get a little buzz going but for
anything that has thc in it it can be
used recreationally and can be used
medically so i just had this come up
with a patient where a parent went in to
a dispensary to pick up a product and
the person behind the counter because
she has a letter for a child and a
caregiver letter for herself they knew
she was there picking up a product for a
sick child and the person behind the
counter said well that's not a medical
product that's a recreational product
what i i don't know really what that
means it's a it's a i want this these
compounds in this dose to try with that
child so
why are we labeling medical versus
recreational now certainly something
that's 90 thc i think we could all
probably
say that that's leaning more towards the
intoxication
goal
but at the same time i have some chronic
pain patients who adult patients who
suffer terribly and have used very high
potency just to be able to step away
from their pain even for an hour you
don't get to take your back pain off or
your botched back surgery and walk away
from it and then come back later so how
do you disassociate is you can
use this medication to step back and
distract yourself and maybe focus on
something else for a little while so i
don't make a distinction between medical
and recreational i'm i'm all about
what's in the product and what's the
dosing for that particular patient
yeah thank you would you like to add
that no
no i think she covered it
no
i mean i agree with bonnie there's you
know in california there's no real
distinction right they try to distinct
it by what license you get but the
products are all the same
and
you know i wish that we could see more
products that had more versatility
in the thc world we're just trying to
make more and more concentrated products
and i think
we're missing a large population
that you know i wish the industry could
appreciate i think um it was in um
now i'm forgetting her name doctor who
did the opioid um talk
oh
um you know was talking about you know
the the people come back when it's
medical when they're using it
medicinally they come back and they
purchase it and they purchase it
multiple times a day and you know that's
a market that we're missing here an
opportunity to really you know provide
for these patients when we're just
focused on cannabinoid content you know
i'd like to see us
provide more variety for consumers and
healthcare consumers and patients
yeah
you know bonnie you and i've had this
discussion over the years
you know with california
passing the 21 and over
and i'm seeing this in other states as
well
it's pushing out the the true medical
professionals because a lot of patients
now say i don't need to go to the doctor
i'll just go down dispensary and it's
unfortunate because i truly believe
especially if battling is something as
serious as cancer a medical professional
should be involved um
a senior citizen we're not 21 and you
know 19 20 21 like won't do that again
you know type type of thing
there's so many products out there
especially cbd product it's confusing
people ask me what about this i mean
there's a there's times that i
it's hard to
point them in the right direction
this topic comes up all the time and i
know bonnie you and i have spoken about
this about
suppositories is there any
bioavailability in there because that
comes up quite a bit years ago karen and
i didn't had wrote an article about
is the posterior superior
we got a lot of [ __ ] about that one
believe me
and so uh we had to take it down because
uh there was a lot of fighting on that
one and but
i don't want to take i'm not into taking
giving false hope but i'm into giving
hope and if eating this flower worked
with a cancer patient i'd say eat the
flour
[Music]
what are your thought process on
different products especially this
suppository discussion because it's
coming up quite a bit and some people
say it's working it's working
and i don't want to say
what you shared if you can add to that
so there's a few ways to look at this so
number one if we look at the
clinical research
right now there is no evidence that just
cannabis alone and suppository will be
absorbed into your
bloodstream at sufficient levels
so
if you have a suppository that there's a
study that shows that the cannabinoids
if
bound to a
compound in this particular research use
the drug called hemi succinate which is
what we call a permeate permeation
enhancer it helps bring it in it helps
cross
the barrier that you have to cross over
to get it into your bloodstream that
actually showed some very good success
but that is not what as far as i know
what's available on the market in
california
i have had patients who report
especially cancer patients back in the
day
that they reported that they were doing
well but remember that they weren't just
doing suppositories they were also on
chemotherapy they were also on vitamin c
infusion some of them were taking
mushrooms some of them were taking
vitamin c
and all kinds of other concoctions i
think it's a very nice thing that they
wanted to believe it was the cannabis
that was working but when you have so
many variables you cannot say what is
working
if it's not in your if you have thc in
your bloodstream you should have some
effect in your brain if it's in your
bloodstream at any
you know a significant level that we
would think that would be needed to help
kill cancer cells
however
in my experience so and
i always learned
that
cancer patients should not be putting
anything up their bum because you're at
lower immunity and you can introduce
bacteria into your bloodstream and get
septic and if you read about this this
is a real thing that you can develop
sepsis especially when your immune
system is not working well
in pediatrics
here and there when i first started in
this some parents were trying to put
tincture
rectally to stop a seizure because there
is a drug called diastat which is a
rectal valium which will stop a seizure
that's clinically proven
and parents would say oh the seizure
stopped and i said i would say well the
seizure's going to stop anyway at some
point you don't know if it's the
cannabis or not so we need to have a
clinical trial to see
however in general that's kind of like
most people don't do that anymore i
think they're uh
would rather not do that to their child
um but in general i am not a big fan of
suppositories i think it's kind of a
waste of money and
unfortunately uh there are still a lot
of products out there though that are
being used that way
i'd like to add a couple of things i
think that suppositories can be useful
for local problems so if somebody
hemorrhoids is a good example a very
common condition itching pain
inflammation thc is great for all of
those things
vaginal pain can respond to thc
i think that some patients do absorb thc
through their rectum because they feel
high and they feel euphoric and good and
whatever that patient
preparation combination is great that
works well i think where bonnie was
going is that we just hear about a lot
of people that say i need to take these
heroic doses of thc but when i do them
by mouth i get so high i can't take it
so i'm going to insert them rectally and
just assume that they're getting into my
body and i'm not getting high so it's a
great way for me to avoid this adverse
effect and there's one
mechanism that might explain that but it
cannot explain it fully that's that when
we swallow things all the blood from the
gut goes to the liver first and the thc
gets converted into an active metabolite
that's called 11-hydroxy thc might feel
a little stronger for some people but
really that's not a full explanation so
i just wanted to add that and then you
know when you say
some people said that the rectal thc was
helping them even though it wasn't
getting them high i just want to point
out that there is something very very
interesting happening in the ultra low
dose range of thc but there's a lot more
cost effective way to get that ultra low
dose range than putting a whole bunch of
it up your butt
and a lot less invasive intrusive right
yeah and one other thing there is a
study on cbd for um
in a rectal suppository for colitis
so and remember that's kind of like
local application so that's that's what
that looks at
kevin you want to add anything
[Laughter]
so are there any contraindications you
know
with patients that
you know liver schizophrenia
is there ever a chance ever a time where
you totally
route patients away from cannabis
so i had someone in my office who was
full-blown
psychotic and i
kind of didn't trust her judgment just
in general yeah and so i told her that i
this is many years ago i told her that i
could you know see her if a family
member
would come back with her just so i could
get the full picture i mean she was
going off on the people next door got
the tin foil and the you know the
cameras and stuff and so i just felt
uncomfortable because i really wasn't
sure what her status was and i wasn't
i'm not a psychiatrist so i'm not
qualified
do i think it would cannabis would have
helped her yes but i just felt
uncomfortable at that moment in time
i have a young man in my practice who's
been my patient for
13 out of 14 years that i've been doing
this who has schizoaffective disorder
and what i did with him
was i
uh in california we normally give a
letter for a year an approval letter i
gave him an approval letter for one
month and i made him check in every
single month with me so i could just see
his progress
he has so he had the typical
type of
unfortunate course with schizophrenia
where he would
become psychotic get hospitalized go on
medication do very well
he hated his side effects he would go
off medication
and then end up in the hospital it was
this vicious cycle and i'm happy to say
that in 13 years using predominantly thc
because we didn't have cbd back when he
was using it he has managed to not have
one hospitalization he has not gone off
his other medication
low-dose thc has helped him
so it can't you you can successfully
treat people and i would here and there
i would get
um
older adults come in with their
children who were adults and say
my son is smoking pot but boy it's so
much easier to live with him with his
schizophrenia he's calm he's not
destroying the house he takes his other
medication he seems to have some joy
because one of the biggest problems with
schizophrenics is they have no joy in
life
and when you hear a parent coming in and
telling you this is what's happening
it's very hard to
deny and i remember this is back when i
was first doing this
i felt very comfortable recommending
cannabis to those families because there
was a caregiver involved and they're
reporting to me
what the results are
and they're the ones that are living
with the patient
i don't think there's any firm
contraindications for cannabis i think
one area that we should be extra
cautious is in cancer patients that are
undergoing immunotherapy especially the
the um uh navalo mab drug which has been
published in two studies and shown so
this is a type of cancer treatment that
revs up the immune system and causes a
lot of inflammation in the body to help
the immune system fight the cancer and
of course with cannabis being an
anti-inflammatory compound we have to be
cautious about not dampening down the
effect of that drug but i wouldn't even
say that it's a firm contraindication
for example we know that corticosteroids
like prednisone decrease the
effectiveness of those treatments but
sometimes when people are on those
treatments they'll develop too much
inflammation they can get pneumonitis or
colitis or reactive skin conditions eye
conditions and they'll be given
prednisone to help settle that stuff
down and still remain on the treatment
we know there's a lower rate of efficacy
but
still they can complete the course and
so i think cannabis could be viewed in
kind of that same light it should be
used with a lot of caution but not a
firm contraindication
thank you
you want to add to that are you
you want to follow no no
just like it says right there right
so what about so eloise you work with a
lot of patients and what about
cannabis use disorder
that follows up on some of those contra
maybe contraindications with maybe a
patient who's schizophrenic
yeah i mean there's definitely diagnoses
i'm not comfortable working with i don't
feel qualified to
manage and a lot of them can be complex
mental health conditions
i have a patient right now who is quite
interesting he's got pretty significant
post-traumatic stress and came to me
already consuming 200 milligrams of thc
100 milligrams at a time twice a day and
his psychiatrist was on the call with us
and just said wow you know when he takes
these dosages our therapy sessions are
incredible like he's so open and i've
just seen so much great progress in him
now i'm starting to see
him
rely on the thc in a way that's making
me uncomfortable
i've increased him to 300 milligrams so
his doses three times a day but i do
think we're starting to see
i'm not sure if it's cannabis use
disorder or cp1 downregulation but i my
concern about cannabis use disorder from
the non-medical cannabis community is i
don't know that they're qualified to be
making these diagnoses when they don't
really understand the endocannabinoid
system they don't understand the
complexity of legalization and
prohibition
and so i think it's grossly over
diagnosed
in patients and
i'd like to see it you know
like i said there's diagnoses i'm
uncomfortable with right i'm not going
to diagnose somebody with post-traumatic
stress i'm not qualified i don't know
that some of these clinicians are
qualified to diagnose cannabis use
disorder but i think it's a conversation
we need to be having in the community
because it's very divisive
um and i would like us to be more open
about you know i see many cannabis
professionals try to deny that cannabis
use disorder exist i i think i can count
on like two fingers how many times i've
actually seen it out of you know over 7
000 patients but
um you know we do need to be aware of it
we do need to be thoughtful about it
like as dustin was saying you know i
don't know that there's
contraindications but we need to be so
thoughtful about how we approach these
patients
can i just make a comment so when we
look at studies on young adults using
cannabis excessively or what they call
chronic heavy use
really what it comes down to is poor
judgment how many people know a 15 year
old to have good judgment i mean
i just survived my son being a teenager
and
and he wasn't
a difficult teenager and it was still
very difficult so i think i would see
you know back again back in the early
days of my career
being a cannabis specialist i would get
19 year olds that would come in and 21
year olds that would come in that had
legitimate
medical conditions you know
you see um
gymnasts they in high school they beat
up their bodies how about the kids that
play football in high school i mean i've
i had a kid in my practice who's had
four shoulder surgeries by the time he
was 16.
well he got offered pain pills or guess
what his buddies gave him some cannabis
is that a cannabis use disorder now by
the way he takes cannabis he feels
better so what does a 15 or 16 year old
do they take more it feels good more and
more and more they have no judgment
whatsoever
so the idea of this cannabis use
disorder
that kind of stems from that kind of
chronic heavy use in certain
age groups really is just a lack of
judgment because i will share with you
that
with continuity with these patients
because remember before 2018 you needed
me to approve you to get into the
cannabis dispensary right so these
kids that i would see let's say 18 19 20
with legitimate
conditions
i is a very interesting phenomenon it
was usually male because i think women
are a little more risk averse and a
little more thoughtful at that age or
maybe just more mature
but every now and then i would see
somebody who would come in and they'd be
23 or 24
and i'd say gee you know i haven't seen
you in a while it's what's going on oh
you know i took a break
and then you know i i stopped using
cannabis for five months i realized i
was overdoing it and i would put my hand
across the table and say welcome to
adulthood right they're being thoughtful
about their use finally and some of that
is just a just being mature and being a
ability to start like listening
uh to your body and instead of just kind
of going along with the program so to
speak i hope that makes sense
i'd like to make a couple comments about
that it's interesting because from time
to time patients come to me most recent
traveled from out of state with
self-diagnosed cannabis addiction
looking for my help getting off cannabis
which i'm happy to help with the
you know my initial response is like
thank god you're addicted to cannabis
right it's not cigarettes or alcohol or
stimulants or opioids or a number of
other uh to tobacco and a number of
other substances
and you know i think a kind of a
progressive way of looking at addiction
is that the drug isn't the problem but
the drug is the solution and there's
some underlying problems so we work
together to figure out what is this
underlying problem and how can we best
address it and often it's just a
different
use pattern of cannabis that can address
it so for this most recent patient who i
mean she had a very unique response to
cannabis she literally had to smoke
every two hours or she would have a
panic attack
get up in the middle of the night to
smoke and so forth but by shifting away
from thc dominant uh type 2
cannabis varieties with more cbd and
less thc gradually reducing her dose
layering in some oral dosing all the
meanwhile getting to the underlying
problem now she has a balanced
relationship with cannabis that's no
longer problematic and i think you know
cannabis is just so versatile
the diagnostic criteria for cannabis use
disorder is almost like you know almost
any cannabis user could fit into it it's
like you go to extra trouble to get your
med to get this substance like i you
know yeah i have to drive to the
dispenser but um
but but really what it comes down to i
think when i'm working with my patients
and this is an important uh transition
point for people who are healing using
cannabis for healing the question is are
you feeling better after you use the
cannabis or are you feeling worse after
and and it's interesting as people get
healthier and healthier they've been
using cannabis as a crutch for a long
time suddenly they don't need it as a
crutch anymore if they keep using it
that way they're going to take some and
be like wow i actually felt better but
if you didn't ask them that question
they might not realize it and once they
hit that point that's a celebration now
we can kind of shift cannabis into the
form of a tonic like something that you
can use to improve your resilience to
stress to stay healthy to treat acute
illnesses and symptoms but it doesn't
have to be this kind of daily all the
time management strategy for you so it's
i i think an important question is like
are you continuing to use cannabis
despite the knowledge that it's making
you feel worse or that it's interfering
with your life if that is if it's a yes
then there's something there that needs
to be changed
love it you're okay
no
so following that
so a daily use patient you know we hear
this i don't want to be
is cannabis addictive
i think it's habit-forming i don't think
it's addictive
is there a difference
there's psychological addiction versus
yeah right
yeah well i i mean i i think maybe what
you're alluding to is this uh fixation
like when people have their attention
fixated on the cannabis and it's like
starting to consume their life and
that that i have seen and i think um
there's certainly a way to kind of
synchronize with that individual and
help them kind of restore reward to the
natural pleasures in their life you know
cannabis is often the solution to the
the problem that cannabis chooses it's
just
you know or the the problem that
cannabis causes it's just a an evolution
in that individual and their
relationship with the plants and it is a
living dynamic relationship right
i often feel like i'm not the teacher
cannabis is the teacher maybe i can help
interpret what this teacher is saying to
the individual so they know how to
listen to those lessons and respond and
make the changes that are indicated
and i would like to say there is a
described cannabis withdrawal and thc
and it's usually only after very high
doses for quite some time i have seen it
in pediatric patients i had
two patients different types of cancer
both children very young and very sick
where in california they were receiving
from my protocol getting chemotherapy
from an oncologist
usually some dietary changes and then we
were using high dose cbd and thc of
course thc was titrated up and they were
using it over time and
both of them ended up being accepted
into
clinical trials in other states and the
parents at that time were talking quite
some time ago
they were afraid to travel with it and
neither of them really updated me that
they were going to be leaving town
without their thc after their child had
been on thc for a while because what i
would have done was weaned it down
not abruptly stopped it and i got calls
from both of them
one a child was at sloan kettering and
actually a nurse practitioner called me
and said we've this kid is just wigging
out and i said well that's what happens
when you stop high-dose thc on a dime in
a small child and really what is that
it's that down regulation of those
receptors like i showed in that picture
and now we're just kind of waiting for
those receptors to kind of come out what
he just was irritable
and he didn't really want to eat
anything and uh it was over in just
about four days i'd say but he was kind
of miserable those four days
and so there is and in adults that if
you've known anybody with who takes a
high dose of thc on a regular basis if
they uh stop abruptly they might feel
lousy for a little bit and it's usually
not so bad they talk about it's a
two-week period
and usually the first three to four days
are the most difficult a lot of people
who want to abstain or cut back by that
day three or four they kind of can't
take it so they go back into it and this
is why
often times in my experience what i'll
do is just continue the cbd
because that will help mitigate some of
the symptoms and then just wean down the
thc and you don't have to do it slowly i
usually basically take 25 percent of the
dose away every day every three days and
that seems to do the trick
that's just my my protocol that i came
up with
and i think one of the gifts of cannabis
so everybody's different but the typical
cannabis withdrawal syndrome will begin
usually around 48 hours people might
feel a little off for those first 48 but
the irritability and loss of appetite
and trouble sleeping
usually kicks in around that 48 hour
mark and that's actually about how long
it takes for people to
up regulate their cb receptors and
become more sensitive to cannabis so if
somebody stops cannabis for 48 hours and
jumps right back into the dose that they
were using beforehand they'll have kind
of nothing gained from that experience
however if they start at a lower dose
and just use the the lowest effective
dose to mitigate those withdrawal
symptoms if they're having them or to
cause like a change in their inner
inventory then they're actually
contributing to this up regulation of
their endocannabinoid system now that
that statement is based on some
pre-clinical data and what i've observed
in the clinic
but but in general i think that this is
a really forgiving part of this plant
also that if we build tolerance to it we
can reverse it quickly and effectively
without having to endure a brutal
withdrawal period and cbd can help with
with those 48 hours exercise
there's all sorts of
ways to
successfully sensitize one system to thc
into cannabis and we have a free program
on healer.com that'll walk you through
that hold your hand and show you videos
give you worksheets and other activities
that you can do to be successful with
that if any of you are regular moderate
to heavy cannabis users and you haven't
tried taking a 48 hour break and
sensitizing your system i highly
recommend you give that a shot and see
what you find
yeah and i think what is really
important here too i've seen withdrawals
with cbd high cbd use
but i think what's what's really
interesting is if you've ever gone had a
patient go through withdrawals from
opioids or ssris or other medications
it's nothing
compared to the withdrawals they might
have from cannabis so you know i always
tell them yeah you might have a little
diarrhea you might be difficult to be
around but it'll be over quickly i mean
my personal experience with opioids was
a month
of
withdrawals and symptom management and
when i said how long is this gonna last
i said a week and i said well i'm in
week three
and he said uh four i mean they just
don't know right and they don't offer
you any solutions so the good news at
least with cannabis it's a lot easier to
come off of if you need to
thank you um you know following that
what about hyperemesis syndrome with the
patients at
are i guess taking is it normally just
with too much t is it normally that
you're seeing in in teenagers and 20s
and 30s or it's thc
related yeah it's usually not medical
cannabis patients although i've seen two
cases in my career so that's in my
career it's not very common but i got
yelled at by a gi doctor who yelled at
me and said it's all over the er so how
come you're not paying attention well
because i work in the medical side of
this not the adult use slash
recreational side or where teenagers are
just doing it without some direction
or self-medicating and again poor
judgment leading to overuse
but the two cases that i saw were people
who went from
kind of um
what i would call moderate thc use to
the very high potency dabbing
and the concentrates and one patient it
took six er visits to get the diagnosis
because she didn't disclose and for
whatever reason they never did a talk
screen they thought it was a pelvic
inflammatory disease or a ruptured
appendix
she got worked up for a ruptured spleen
even though she had no
sign of trauma i mean so there was a lot
of money spent on her work up and when
she finally admitted she was very upset
about it because she felt
that she did something wrong and now she
couldn't use cannabis anymore because
any time that she went back to it she
would have a recurrence of symptoms
but we were able to get her on some cbd
oil to help with the original
diagnosis which was anxiety
and then the second patient i had could
not go back onto cannabis at all
or at least thc cannabis no he couldn't
do it
and i think it gets complicated if you
have somebody who has chs and they have
to stop abruptly now you're also going
to possibly have withdrawal symptoms
i mean it can be really problematic but
i think there's i've noticed at least in
my medical practice there are some
people that end up in that prodromal
phase where they're not actually
vomiting yet but they have early morning
nausea maybe some weight loss maybe some
diarrhea
and so i think you know it's really good
to be aware of the different phases so
that you can try to catch it
but i've also i mean dustin and i wrote
up a couple atypical chs cases and
sometimes they can go back sometimes
they can't
and i think maybe we should define this
does anyone want me to define chs
does everybody know what we're talking
about
okay so cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
usually occurs to
long-term heavy thc users and it's a
violent nausea and vomiting episode that
can last a day or days and it's
typically
relieved by
excessive hot bathing and um and that
heat temporarily turns down the nausea
now there's another clinical entity
called cyclic vomiting syndrome that
presents very similarly but the
difference is cannabis can help cyclic
vomiting syndrome
the the thing about chs
is that people don't know it's related
to their cannabis it's not like they
just took a hit and the episode suddenly
started
it kind of appears out of nowhere so
they're baffled by it and the
kind of test to see is this really chs
is stop using cannabis
for a month and you know see if an
episode comes back or not now in the
atypical cases we presented they were
there were some lower gi symptoms uh i
believe that cbd dominant cannabis in
both our cases trigger to relapse and
and so
so some people are so ultra sensitive or
maybe it's some of these trace compounds
that daddy's waiting to discover for us
and it's not the thc at all that that's
certainly possible but um i think that
often like eloise mentioned there's this
prodromal phase where before the episode
kicks in if they pay attention
they're a little off in the morning and
if they stop using cannabis before it
goes to this full-blown episode wait a
few days then that'll subside and they
can actually start using it again very
cautiously but never to in my experience
able to go up to that full high dose
where they were previously and i've had
about a dozen cases over the years
and i'd like to point out that dr russo
and len may from endocanna health did a
genetic study
to look at if to see if people were
genetically predisposed and they found
some very nice results so i encourage
you to read that article i think it came
out last year i believe
i haven't forgotten you down there
sorry
i'm good i know the light's blinking
over there so i had a couple other
questions but let's just go with um you
know over the past 12 years i've seen so
many changes in this industry some good
some bad
and some really
uh exciting times ahead what what can
you all add to uh the future of our
industry and and and beyond
kevin i'll start with you my friend well
in terms of the future of the industry i
mean a couple things need to happen
really bigly politically that needs to
settle down right making access
not making people criminals
not punishing parents who
are giving their kids medicinal cannabis
for good reason
i think those are really keys but also i
think quality control and labeling is
still an issue in a lot of states
and you know i come from the natural
products industry so
to me we're trying to the cannabis
industry is trying to reinvent the wheel
and you don't need to you already have a
guide the american herbal products
association will guide you through all
those steps of what you need to do in
terms of quality control and and
labeling and you know all of this so
i think we need to learn from the
existing model that's out there
to improve
um our
safety our quality control our adverse
event reporting i think that's really
really key
there are cases of adverse events and we
need to know who they who these people
are and why they're responding
in a negative way and and that's going
to propel the industry forward it sounds
like it has set it back but it won't
it'll propel it forward
well i just have one ask and that is to
get it off the uh controlled substance
act so we can research it
when i think about cannabis uh you know
it seems
always so perfectly fit to our
contemporary problems in society our
health problems our psychological
problems you know you look at this this
world we're living where there's huge
amounts of psychological stress and
cannabis is a solution for that where
we're you know kind of bathed in this
environment of toxins many neurotoxins
we have the neuroprotective effects of
cannabis you know and so on it's often
this solution to our most challenging
problems in healthcare and i you know
hope that we stay open-minded and allow
it to kind of evolve with some of these
challenges one in particular that was
brought up earlier today is and
yesterday as well is just the rate of
mental health challenges that the
adolescents in our world right now i i
think it's are experiencing it's just an
incredibly hard time
for most to be a teenager with the
social media and the the technology
influence and algorithms uh really
learning quickly how to dictate behavior
and um you know kind of bring people
away from their authentic self and
high stress of this kind of cognitive
dissonance we're living in a world where
people are doing things all the time
that just don't make any sense and
telling them to to follow these things
and do them and they might know it
doesn't make sense but they're doing it
anyways so i've seen a huge uptick in
adolescence in my practice and they are
you know either the parents are
cannabis friendly or cannabis curious
and bringing them in because they don't
like these psychiatric options that are
available or the parents are discovering
that this this kid is using cannabis and
kind of punishing them and telling them
to stop and then watching their you know
kind of social interaction and grades
and
family communication and relationship
deteriorate and then
you know telling the pediatrician hey i
think the cannabis was helping
pediatrician says go see dr sulek and we
we validate what this young person has
already found so that's one example of
an area where i hope we see
our
kind of culture able to embrace cannabis
for that population as well and i know
it was very helpful for me when i was 15
years old and i didn't have a fraction
of the challenges that today's young
people have
yeah
and i hope to see more healthcare
professionals become educated because
then it increases our advocacy our
opportunities for research our access
you know as healthcare professionals we
often are able to consume if we're
taking positions at institutions or
organizations that you know try to use
the 1980s drug place work act to say you
know you can't test positive i want to
see healthcare workers access this plant
in a way that's meaningful
really high burnout rate right now we're
all talking about mental wellness and
and how to help with the burnout and i'm
like oh oh i know
let us all use cannabis please for the
love of god you know i think you'll see
much
happier
health care workers not that they need
to consume at work
but i just i want us to i mean we all
deserve choices most so many of us
raised our hands that we're patients
right we deserve choices um so
congratulate for be yourself for being
here today and getting educated and
being part of the change
[Applause]
thank you very much you know we're all
ambassadors for this great plant and
we're all the pebble in the pond that
hits that ripple effect so
bring it home with you and thank you all
for being up here and thank you for
joining and thanks for canmed and all
the sponsors as well and
bless you all thank you
thank you to the canmed crew it's been a
great conference and i i think we are
welcome uh welcoming questions if the
audience has any
and pictures yeah anybody want to take
some pictures of us please thank you
i'm gonna do my put up my scrapbook
all right i've got a question over here
in the in the recreational market we're
seeing um an increase in the use of nano
emulsions to make the cannabinoids water
not water soluble but
immersed in in water products so
beverages are coming online
gummy products are being made with nano
emulsions i haven't heard anybody talk
about those types of products here and i
was wondering if anybody could comment
on patients that are using maybe these
new nano emulsion products and how the
dosing of those could be different from
the dose of traditional products because
of more rapid absorption
sure so you know i think one part of
that is getting the
the cannabinoids and other compounds
into a matrix that's desirable and i you
know that's fine if if somebody prefers
to have it in a water-based beverage and
it it gets in there better that that's
okay um when it comes to claims about
increased bioavailability meaning you
know i can take a lower dose and it's
going to have a stronger effect i
we've seen very little data supporting
any of those claims i think a couple
companies have published a little bit
and what we've seen is that there can be
like a three to four fold increase in
absorption from some of these nano
emulsions and other technologies now
it's also important to know that if you
take oral cannabinoids with fat
containing food you'll also see about a
three to five fold increase and um and
so the the cost benefit of some of these
technologies which do raise the cost of
the product typically i think we could
probably just achieve that by by taking
it with food and you know for for the
consumers out there if somebody's
advertising something fancy and new
that's going to improve the delivery of
cannabis i'm all for it i would just you
know invite the company to show us the
proof that it's doing what they say it's
doing
yeah i agree i think there are a lot of
unsubstantiated marketing claims in the
industry and working with knowledgeable
healthcare professionals can really help
a patient make good choices
first i want to thank you all for being
here i'm really excited to have you all
in one place to ask this question
over the last couple of years with the
passage of the farm bill we've seen a
lot of
other cannabinoids hitting the market
delta 8 delta 10 hhc some of those types
of things and i'd like to hear what your
opinion is on some of those products
that are trying to circumvent the thc
laws and prohibition estates
okay sure well my my first concern is
residual solvents um
that that's obviously an issue and it's
been an issue in the past as well i know
in in oregon we had this problem
uh i think that the other cannabinoids
um you know for the most part we've got
pre-clinical research
we don't have a lot of human research
that doesn't mean necessarily that
you know we can't use them but if
they're isolated and we can get much
higher doses
i tend to fall on the safety side you
know these things have never been
isolated and we've never taken them at
higher doses it's that they've always
been in a mix as minor cannabinoids so
that makes me feel better to think of it
that way than isolating a bunch of stuff
that we've never
tested on humans or even pre-clinical
research
can i just chime in so the way it's been
explained to me is that the delta eight
thc that's on the hemp market now is not
from
directly from the plant it goes through
a what's called acid catalysis from cbd
to delta eight and the concern there is
that
uh you may convert let's say eighty
percent of that cbd over but then the
rest what are those and they basically
saying they're uncharacterized
either cannabinoids or something else
and nobody knows so far i'm waiting for
somebody to say oh i figured out what
those are
and the concern is what are they and are
they safe for you
so that that's the way it's been
described to me i have had a few
patients use delta eight with some nice
results with anxiety in lower doses and
especially in patients who don't seem to
tolerate delta nine but there's still
that concern of safety
yeah i'm okay with people experimenting
on themselves you know i think life's a
big experiment
um
you know that that's all right i think
we they should just do so with the
knowledge that there's probably uh
unidentified compounds that they're
consuming and
we don't know what that's going to do to
them and it's probably going to be
different from one preparation to the
next
yeah and i don't think our testing is
very sophisticated either so that's
another concern where you can see there
was a report that came out i think it
said like 56 percent of at least delta 8
products were mislabeled you know we saw
that with cbd as well and there's a lot
of people that um don't realize that
there's also likely to be delta 9 thc in
some of these products so it can be
quite impairing
nicole i um thank you very much for
being here and for doing all that you do
um my my question is this one of the
things that we're finding as we speak to
the practitioners
um is
their fear of stepping into this
culture
um my question to you because all of you
are so open and especially dr goldstein
because this is
um directed uh for someone who we know
who is a pediatrician that we're trying
to help
move into that cannabis space
what recommendations do you have just
to communicate to the doctors the
practitioners
anything to to
kind of allow them to step into this
question so i i had a little difficulty
hearing you but you're asking me what
would i say to other pediatricians well
what i would say is your fears are
unfounded because i'm the biggest
chicken around and i'm doing this so
it is your fears are unfounded and it's
based on research from the you know dare
to say no
time and even from before that but
everybody talks to me all the time what
about the brain development about this i
just don't see issues and if i saw
issues of course i would step in do no
harm right
so i'm not ignoring my patients and you
can tell by my slides and my talk i am
heavily involved in my patients lives i
mean i have some patients that email me
three times a day with pictures so
we are very there i'm like closer to
them than i am to some family members
if something goes south and i stress
this at every you know talk with the
first the first appointment and every
talk after if there's a downside of a
side effect
anything you're worried about there is
no stupid email or phone call you just
let me know
i try to prepare people but in general
if you are practicing good medicine the
same way you practice any other good
medicine whether it's rheumatology or
hematology oncology and you know
um
especially with cannabis it's a lot
safer because you're really not going to
harm anybody you may not find the answer
right out of the gate but if someone's
willing to work with you you usually can
find some benefit
the fears are unfounded and i've been
saying this for years and yet there's
still a tremendous fear factor and part
of that is
the ignorance because you don't know
because you haven't had a chance to read
the research so it's just a matter of
education
but i think part of it too once someone
once said to me doctors are really good
students they're taught something once
and they hang on to it for life
so
it's very hard to undo
i wanted to add to that you know this
came up earlier and it's i think a
little better for nurse practitioners
but physicians have the highest suicide
rate of any profession
we are mostly damaged
by our training incredibly close minded
and rigid in our thinking and scared of
things that we've been told to be scared
of and so we don't learn very well while
we're scared our brains are not
discerned designed to learn when we're
scared we're designed to react
emotionally and so when you find an
intelligent person that's reacting
emotionally the first step has to be to
help them feel safe and comfortable and
do something that will help disarm them
and you know i think there's a variety
of of ways that we can just synchronize
with the the person we're talking to
this isn't about breaking through to
them and getting the truth to them
that's that's not the effective strategy
the effective strategy is basically like
sit there with this scared rigid
thinking individual that's missing an
opportunity to really like help a lot of
people and have a much more meaningful
career sit with them and see how you can
love them
like look at them and love them that's
probably a really nice first step
that'll change the vibration in in the
room and um and then maybe like take a
different tack like not for their
patients maybe this could be something
for themselves or for their mom who's
got arthritis or someone else say no and
just kind of find where those inroads
are and then i say this from experience
it's gotten a lot better when i used to
be in front of a crowd of doctors not at
a cannabis conference but a different
conference you could feel the energy in
the room like
you know they would be it would be so
intense uh the fear about the words that
were going to come out of my mouth there
was no way i could teach a crowd like
that you know and and now it's it the
the work has gotten a lot easier you
know because people are i think you know
and i mentioned this in my book um
cannabis is not just a solution for the
patients it's a solution for the
practitioners uh and for the system
itself it's a solution for their
miserable practices that are you know
full of toxic tools that are ineffective
and it's a solution for their personal
lives if we can weave it in there
somehow so those are some of my ideas
that's that's great i mean i need to
applaud that right there yeah
and i i think so much of it is false
evidence appearing real you know that's
the fear for me going now into
palliative care at stanford i'm going to
be prescribing opioids for the first
time in my career and i'm way more
scared of that than i am cannabis so you
know it's all about perspective
and
i want self-promotion so i think you all
have books right
sort of sort of anyway look
lola
ah yes sir so uh thank you so much uh
guys for what you're doing in this space
okay
yeah this is really great
i hate this stuffed
car
okay
so my quest i'm a clinical pharmacist a
cannabis psychological consultant i'm
also a cannabis educator
so earlier when dr bostin was talking
she said
about the route of administration first
of all where i'm coming from
when it comes to cannabis and not even
just cannabis medication drugs generally
i believe is all in your
route of administration
and your dosing and when you look at
conventional medicine
big farmers they have perfected the acts
of route of administration and one of
those areas is in your transdermal
patches like your fentanyl
and suppository those are one of our
effective the most effective
agent uh routes that we have so i would
say that when we look at the way we are
seeing cannabis as a support city we are
fee we have a feeling is not
really where we need it to be
do you guys think this is a way this is
an area where we can actually
collaborate with the big farmers
uh when we eventually get into that area
where we have legalization and everybody
can actually come into the opens
and embrace this uh these plans because
i really do feel that support c3
is is gonna be a game changer as well as
transdemo approaches
i i think that
we could advance cannabis in that way i
have to say in 13 years of clinical
practice i can't recall when i've been
dissatisfied with my available routes of
administration what we've got right now
seems to be working very well maybe it's
not the most cost effective but then
again newer technologies that can
enhance bioavailability they have a cost
as well so i i i think we'll probably
make progress there but i don't see that
as a priority in cannabis i'm curious
what my panelists think
for me personally i just feel like
especially when you're thinking about
cancer or folks that have
nausea and vomiting especially when
you're looking at the
uh the fact that when you use a
sublingual rod of administration we
don't even know what about availability
of these agents are and we already have
proven routes of administration
that is extremely effective that's why
we have problems with fentanyl
that is one of the main reasons why we
have problems with fennel because of the
way the absorption rate i think that
when someone needs a parenteral route of
administration the lungs is ideal the
onset is so rapid it's very easy to
titrate again i'm not really seeing the
need
but but there are some patients that do
better with a patch eloise presented
that case and thank goodness for that
ultra sensitive outlier that there was a
patch available
i think maybe patches i would love to
see more variety and opportunities for
four patches in the market i mean i'm
very limited and they're very very
expensive but sometimes they are
game changers
okay
thank you guys for what you do
appreciate that
yeah and i'm just gonna chime in here if
i'm not anti-pharma but i do think
pharma is at the root of a lot of
problems in medicine
if you if we try to collaborate with
pharma with cannabis they're just going
to take it away from you
that's what they're going to do it's all
about corporate it's all about profit
we're not being exclusive we're being
inclusive
that's the way i see this is a
grassroots movement
it's not exclusive
[Music]
yeah i don't think anyone else here yeah
i'm sorry because the rest of the room
can't hear you unfortunately but the
message is that we can collaborate and i
think that's a great one we don't have
to be anti-pharma i don't think that's
that's going to help us but we have to
know them for what they are and and
recognize the patterns of history and
the way that they've behaved we can
invite them to behave differently and
maybe if again if cannabis becomes a
bigger part of their lives they might do
that let's let's take the next question
thanks
dr goldstein mentioned the one patient
who had
repeated hospitalizations and that
seemed to be solved with the low dosage
thc i was just wondering what was the
actual dosage and what would you define
is that low dose range
sure he he actually was inhaling with a
flower vaporizer so i don't really know
but he would just take one or two puffs
and he would spread it out throughout
the day so it was kind of like micro
dosing via inhalation
all day long and it just kept him even
and so
he found that that was the best way to
do it and i didn't want to change that i
wanted him to be able to decide how he
what worked best for him and this was
flour not oil it was flour
yes
he would buy flour and he used not a
volcano but kind of like a one-off from
a volcano type bag vaporizer
so i have a few things to add to this
someone asked a question earlier and a
paper came out today that may have shed
some light on this it's in chem archive
from monger at all and it is vaping
cannabinoid acids leads to ketene
formation which is a poisonous gas they
think may have been involved in a valley
with vitamin e acetate so
um encourage people if you're looking at
some of these other products this is
specifically about delta eight and delta
eight acetate which might be some of
these other delta eights that are
showing up in this this acid catalyze
catalyzation but
something new that just published today
that may shed some light on what are in
these vape pens
but i'm also going to add to this that
uh i'm kevin mckernan and i'm here to
let everyone know that we have finalized
canmed22
and
i wanted to thank everyone involved for
it
i also have some exciting news in that
uh many of the sponsors of this event
have come back uh in droves with much
support for next year so we have
survived covid
uh which is great canmed will happen
next year uh we're still sorting on
where we usually do uh two years in each
location so it's about time for a shift
and we'll be sending out emails in
regards to where it's going to be
probably the next month
with that i want to thank all of our
panelists and everyone who came this is
a really been a fantastic year long
overdue
and we're looking forward to seeing
everybody again at the next event thank
you
[Applause]