hello everyone
um
thank you uh thank you very much for
sticking around until uh until the last
uh the last presentation I have to say I
feel super humbled to be up here
speaking because everyone in this room
is probably way smarter than I am and I
just want to thank everyone that we've
been talking to over the past couple of
days and thank you cadmed for
making this work
so vaping a lot of controversies I'm not
going to dive deep into a lot of detail
of of what's doable I just want to give
an overview because we still need to do
a lot of research when it comes to
vaping
we're going to specifically focus on
emissions and rheology
a lot of people talk about viscosity
when it comes to vaping well viscosity
is only a little piece of it there's a
lot more involved the process of
vaporization
is a mix between chemistry fluid
mechanics thermodynamics and not just
putting oil in a tank
one of the key things here to understand
as a consumer when you buy a product
you're not buying just the oil or just
the hardware
it has to be a symbiotic relationship
between the two you can have the safest
cleanest oil uh in a bad hardware and
the consumer will still have a bad
experience and vice versa
the initial goal of this was really r d
uh and understanding how we can better
deliver the cannabinoids terpenes uh all
of the different components that were
continually discovering every day for
patients
but we kind of made the scope a lot
bigger as we're pulling back these onion
layers of research and what's going on
with cannabis vaping
so what are the variables
that affect aerosolization everyone says
vaping but it's not really Vapor it's
aerosols through the use of for instance
a 510 thread cartridge and how do we
measure the influence the answer is
emissions testing and rheology
emissions testing is testing really The
Vapor that comes out of it all of the
regulation right now tests the oil that
goes into these devices the problem is
there's a state change there what comes
out of it is not at all what goes in
so obviously why do you do emissions
testing consumer safety
transparency
quality control
future Regulatory Compliance I think
it's very easy to understand that once
we enter Federal legalization FDA is
going to come in and they are going to
regulate the hell out of this and ask us
for all of this data it happened with
the nicotine vaping industry it happened
with food supplements it's going to
happen with cannabis and I think it's
very important that as an industry we're
prepared with data with information to
explain to these Regulators exactly how
things work and start working today for
future regulation
when we look at emissions
one of the components is a puffing
regime so a regular tobacco puffing
regime is 55 milliliters inhaled during
a puff for three seconds every 30
seconds
cannabis is consumed in a total
different way it's more sessions it's
only a couple of Puffs it's not
necessarily like a cigarette where you
have to have the 12 the 12 quote unquote
12 Puffs for one cigarette all at once
because it's consuming cannabis vaping
you can literally have it in your pocket
and some of you have seen me I've been
vaping for three days you can
Vaped completely differently and if you
want more info I think the decks are
going to be available there's a link
here that shows our 2021 survey of
vaping topography uh where we actually
come up with a vaping regime specific to
cannabis
so with that regime That's the basis for
all of the emissions testing because
emissions are different depending on the
regime of course
now looking into emissions
what's the link with rheology
there's there's a lot of different
moduli on storage loss doing a
temperature sweep I'm going to show you
some uh some some highlights after this
and most importantly how do we measure
all of this it's with the ACM the
aerosol collected Mass
leaking clogging of a cartridge
are are really a function of all of
these parameters and controlling those
parameters allows to bring a better
experience
better aerosol collected mass or better
deliverability for patients
now on the left side you see a
rheological report this is a temperature
sweep where we're basically testing the
product in a cartridge from 20 to 70
degrees Celsius on the left side you
have the consistent storage modulus that
is the blue line that is the most
important here the red line is viscosity
very easy same in in in both graphs
obviously goes down more uh with more
temperature
the green line is the loss modulus where
we do see a consistent loss of energy in
Pascal that's really what's expected now
the focus is the blue one that's the
storage modulus that's how much energy
in Pascal does the concentrate and the
Cannabis inside your vaping device store
basically it's it has to be something
fairly consistent for the deliverability
to be here and for bioavailability to
work with your patients and that's what
you don't see on the right side it's
basically the elasticity of the oil
that's in your cartridge
foreign
some of the variables and what they mean
when we're looking at emissions testing
so we just spoke about aerosol collected
Mass we also measure this of course with
dwl divide weight loss to correlate with
ACM and understand exactly what was
vaporizing how rheology
affects the emissions
pressure drop that's basically the
resistance to airflow that's when you're
simulating a puff
the delivered cannabinoids and I'm going
to show you a little slide at the end
where we can really pinpoint how the
cannabinoids are delivered throughout
the life cycle of a device or a
cartridge and it's it's scary sometimes
because some of the cannabinoids
actually disappear when you get towards
the end of the cartridge so if you're
looking for instance for a for CBN at
the end of the cartridge after using it
for a couple of days there's no more CBN
in there it all disappeared
so it's very very important to
understand how each of these
cannabinoids is delivered as well
something you'll see and you can see
this really everywhere in tobacco is the
aldehyde exposure now why would we look
at the aldehyde exposure that's really
the dry hits basically when your coil
and the medium the wicking material that
contains and and aerosolizes the the
extract
is burning and that's how we can measure
if there's a dry hit or if the wicking
material is uh has all the right
properties to encapsulate and deliver
that aerosol so very easily if you want
to simulate for instance a dry hit on
any cartridge take a couple of Puffs in
a row and you'll quickly see that the
last Puffs don't taste good and when you
measure that on a vaping machine you're
going to see that the uh the delivered
cannabinoids are completely different
off the charts not to mention the
potential degradance which I'm not even
covering here
and and finally heavy metal exposure
um there's a there's a lot of talk about
heavy metals and the uh the immediate
go-to is it's the device well actually
eighty percent of the heavy metal uh uh
results for cannabis and vaping products
comes from the oil
um that said what is responsible for
heavy metals in emissions is uh very
often due to the hardware and the
concentrate that you're putting into
these devices
to give you a very simple example you
look at distillate roughly a pH of four
the more terpenes you add the more pH
goes down the more acid it is and the
more leaching can happen with the
materials that are in your device
so this is basically the the three
potential results once you go through
all of this test is
a restrictive
um uh attribution uh which really shows
that there's potential aldehydes flavor
poor performance this is really again
the Genesis of Starting All of This
research is to make sure that we're
delivering product in the correct way to
patients
um when we're looking at something
that's oversized that means potentially
the intake holes are too big the wicking
material is is absorbed it's not
absorbing enough of the concentrate that
leads to clogging which then turns into
leaking
um and then there's the sweet spot and
that's where we hit the symbiotic
relationship between the hardware and
the concentrate
um is a proper feed in matched rheology
now you want to adapt and do rheology
testing with every single concentrate
out there it's practically uh impossible
but in certain cases when you're looking
at very specific applications it is
definitely needed and unfortunately not
many people are willing to do this in in
this industry I mean we're an ancillary
company we met manufacture Hardware
sometimes I get asked by my investors
why are we doing this research why other
processors doing it
um well we're neutral we can anonymize
we can take our clients oils and test it
without knowing which is which uh I
think a lot of the processors are afraid
of the liability of potentially finding
something that they're not going to like
and ending up with a master settlement
agreement in 20 years uh like tobacco
finally a little nugget of information
here this is what I was alluding to in
the beginning
we have three different types of
Hardware you can see when they're filled
at a hundred percent at 50 percent at
ten percent we track all cannabinoids we
also track terpenes I just put the main
two here CBD and THC and you can see
that in certain cases when the product
is for instance 10 percent full you see
these numbers change drastically
now when you're providing these products
to patients who don't know anything
about the science who don't know
anything about cannabis it's very very
important that they are made aware that
at the end of the cartridge you're not
going to have the same experience uh
than than at the beginning of it
basically is decreased efficiency
um over time with with this hardware and
this is something that no one's ever
going to be looking into because it's
essentially admitting that the hardware
doesn't match the oil
but it happens today in 95 percent of
the products that are on the market
um that that's it thank you um thank you
very much