good morning everyone
all right
my name is yvonne and i work for
medicinal genomics not only do i hand
out drink tickets but i also manage the
r d team
so
plating
plating methods are considered to be the
gold standard
the petri dish was invented in 1887.
and
the phone
1887.
this is the phone in 18 oh crap sorry
this is the phone in 1887. is this not
working
this is the cell phone today
now if i told you all to take take your
cell phones away and you can only rely
on the newspaper for your information
you would think that i'm crazy
yet we rely on petri dishes to give us
results for microbial testing
and we think that qpcr or
molecular methods aren't as good
now i beg to differ
you're growing on a plate
how do you know what it is unless you're
a trained mycologist who has years of
training it's very difficult to
determine what's growing on your plate
and even if you do know what's growing
on your plate there are things that look
very similar for instance aspergillus
niger
aspergillus niger has also been mistaken
for aspergillus brazilians and they were
once deemed the same but through
molecular techniques they've determined
that they are actually different species
so
why are we still doing this
you know
let's bring it into the next
to the 21st century
we have the ability we have the
technology why are we still relying on a
standard that's 135 years old
for instance salmonella testing
you can target portions of the
salmonella genome and run molecular
methods and determine that it's
salmonella within as little of a 16 hour
incubation
yet if you were to confirm salmonella on
plating methods that could take up to
three days
and then they want you at the end of
three days of plating and confirmation
to send that sample
back for sequencing to confirm that your
three days of plating was right
why are we doing this
and there are some state regulators out
there that aren't allowing molecular
methods for species specific detection
it's crazy
right
why are we doing this why are we making
it more difficult than it needs to be
so we've been publishing on these
problems since 2015
the past eight years this is what i do
on a daily basis try to explain and
educate people why
plating methods aren't the gold standard
that everybody thinks that they are
most recently we published this past
february and i'm going to touch upon
some of that data a bit
i want to go back to a study that we did
last year um with michigan
and trying to
determine total yeast and mold that's
another problem totals but we can get
into that later
so
there was sample it was collected it was
homogenized by third third party lab and
distributed it was broken up into a high
medium and low categories and it was
plated on three different types of
plates
these are the three different types of
plates that were used in this study and
as you can see these three particular
plates
are supposed to be isolating
yeast mold fungi
yet when you look at these plates you
see
very different results
the top row is drbc plating and you can
see there's a lot fewer colonies growing
on these plates than at the bottom which
is potato dextrose agar
now
to a lab technician that doesn't know
the difference between a bacterial
colony and a yeast and mold colony
you're going to get very different
results
the pda the blue dots that you see are
counts
the majority of those blue dots that are
being counted for totally used in mold
are actually bacterial
this is some sequencing that we had done
we picked colonies from these plates
and we put them through genomic
sequencing to see what they actually
were
and on the three plates that are
supposed to be growing yeast mold and
fungi
you see that bacteria is indeed growing
on these plates
and what's really interesting is
oh
can you advance
what there should be a circle that comes
up can i do that
yes sorry
so it's really difficult to see what
that circle up at the top says but it's
a actual bacteria by the known the name
of pantoa algomerans
now pantoa
is a gram negative which makes it an
entero
um lactose fermenting bacteria lactose
from fermenting makes it a coliform so
we got a bacteria
it's an entero and it's also a coliform
and it has actually recently been in
2019 there was a publication
as a growth promoter for cannabis
okay so now we have a bacteria that is
used
to help
grow cannabis
it's also been known to show in skin
infections in humans so you could have
this growth promoting bacteria on your
cannabis plants and then you have your
trimmers come and trim it up and they
get skin infections what's going on
so we have done previously previous
studies on different microbiomes and we
found that in
30 of the 172 microbiomes that we've
surveyed pantoa glomerulons has come up
so this was interesting so we decided to
look at this
with an actual atcc culture
oh just to touch back so i said it was a
bacteria it's an entero it's a coliform
therefore it's a btgn
these
are the different states that regulate
that have regulations for those tests
i believe the top
this is states that have a total aerobic
regulation
these are states that have a coliform
these are states that have an intro and
i don't know why it's not showing and
this one over here has btg and
requirement so
that's important
so we take this pantola algorithms and
we incubate it and we put it on plates
and
for this particular plate this is a
total aerobic complete it's a rapid
total aerobic complaint as as you can
see with the manufacturer's instructions
it says to grow it at 35 degrees plus or
minus 2 degrees for 24 hours plus or
minus 2 hours
and when you do that at
the recommended growth temperature you
can see at the bottom there's no growth
yet if you grow it at 30 degrees or you
grow it at 26 degrees
you do have growth
so if labs are following the recommended
manufacturer's documentation for this
which
they haven't tested it in a cannabis
matrix with which any um just said was a
very important factor it is it needs to
be tested in cannabis matrix you get
very different results
and i said that it was also an
enterobacteria well we grow it on the
plates at the recommended
temperature
and at two differing temperatures
and you get no growth
coliform plates they said it was also a
coliform this is what happens when you
plate it on a coliform plate 26 degrees
you see it 30 30 degrees you see it
36 degrees it's there but it's minimal
so if you're having
labs test
for these organisms at the recommended
temperatures and they're not showing up
they're passing it
this isn't a fluke this is another
organism this is aeromodus hydrophylla
you see the same thing
and this is a bacteria that causes
gastroenterol
entero
titus and 13
of humans
yet when you do qpcr methods or
molecular methods
temperature doesn't matter
and
you detect it across the assays
so again why are we relying on a gold
standard that is missing stuff and then
molecular methods
well
why doesn't it match
it doesn't match because you're
comparing two totally different
technologies
so
we did another
experiment and this was in matrix this
is a hemp sample
and we decided to test this hemp sample
divide 10 grams three different bags
test it at three different temperatures
three different plating types
three different scientists processing
so
with the qpcr method there's no
incubation up front for these these
particular tests for species specific
that's different i'm not going to get
into that right now so we did an initial
time point and then we incubated those
bags for 24 hours
no incubation
three temperatures which weren't really
put at their temperature yet so that's
this is showing
why doesn't it like
okay i don't know why it doesn't show up
over there but
so three bags three scientists pretty
similar results
this this green one over here is an
outlier unfortunately that's me but what
are you gonna do
so
the average cfu for these
tests right here is 150 000 cfus if that
was a total aerobic test that would fail
if that was an intro that would fail
if it was a coliform it would fail
you incubate those at their respective
temperatures for 24 hours it goes from
150 000 cfus to over six million cfus
clearly
what's on that plant on that flower
is alive and growing
yet
when you played it
24 hours three temperatures
it would pass
48 hours all of a sudden you start
seeing stuff
and 72 hours it's it's essentially the
same as the 48 they're just a little
larger
okay that's one carbon source
you change your carbon source
totally different results
this is 2xyt agar
26 degrees is where you're seeing that
growth you're not seeing that 30 and
you're not seen at 36.
this is lb argor
again similar types results
so what's going on here
well there's a couple of things
not all organisms grow at the same rate
me at the same temperature which i think
i clearly demonstrated to you before
not all organisms grow on the same
carbon source
and not all organisms grow at the same
rate
and these three things are very
important when you're dealing with
plating
and this is not something that we have
when we're testing with molecular
methods
now it's very interesting
remediation practices are becoming more
common
and i think a lot of what may be
happening here and this is hypothesis
and this is something that i want to
investigate further and maybe i can
present to you guys next year on my
findings
but i think a lot of what may be
happening here is this viable but
non-culturable event and what happens is
is that some of these remediation
techniques involve sterilization whether
you're using ozone gamma radiation x-ray
radiation what whatever hydrogen
peroxide treatment
and they're knocking
the cell they're knocking the organisms
down
but it's kind of like a boxing match as
i'll use exact terminology here
they're knocking them down but they're
not going to not knocking them down for
the count they're down
at the eight count they're kind of snap
staggering back to life
and then
they'll start growing again and that
could be why on some of these plates
at 24 hours it's just not enough but if
you give it a few more days they start
reviving
and and this makes sense i mean you kind
of see it
in food right you go to the grocery
store you buy a pack of strawberries
they look fine you bring them home you
stick them in the refrigerator two days
later you gotta eat them and you're like
oh [ __ ] they're all moldy
same thing could be happening
so just because a sample
leaves the lab on day one and passes
microbial doesn't mean it's going to go
sit on a shelf in a dispensary and not
still continue to grow the mold or
bacteria
so this is something that's really
interesting i think it's something
that's important and the whole point of
it is is that qpcr or molecular methods
are gonna pick up these
viable but non-culturable and so
we may be seeing well how come if i use
qpcr
i have you know i'm failing my product
but i played it and there's nothing
there i believe that it's this viable
but non-cultural event that's happening
so
am i really that early
i think i've made a ton all right so
this is our team staff i want to thank
these people
um you know we're always
looking for things to test and and this
whole plating vs qpcr or molecular
methods
isn't going away and i will continue to
come here and educate all you all you
all so if anyone has any questions i'd
be happy to answer them
[Applause]
you