hi I'm Lin ohlbrecht and I'm really
honored to be here with so many
qualified people my qualification I'm
Ross Ulbricht mother but that has given
me a crash course in the drug war and
what I think it's really about my son
Ross is a peaceful person he has no
history of violence whatsoever and yet
the judge sentenced him to a double life
without parole plus 40 years for all
nonviolent charges he's an example of
what's going on and the war on drugs the
government wants to cage Ross for life
for creating and allegedly running a
website so everyone who is a website
that might be interesting for the
government should take note of the
precedent that is being set here the
precedent is that a website host can be
held criminally liable for activity on
his or her site Ross is in prison not
for selling a product but for creating a
platform the site was Silk Road it was
an Amazon style online marketplace that
operated anonymously on the darknet with
tor and used the cryptocurrency Bitcoin
it was essentially a a free and open
market where vendors and buyers could
pretty much sell and buy whatever they
wanted however there were restrictions
the site was based on the principle of
everything being voluntary so the
administration restricted things that
created victims such as forbidden were
child pornography there was no child
pornography there were no stolen goods
you couldn't hire a hitman on Silk Road
nothing that created victims there are
many legal things sold but also illegal
including a lot of drugs now I said
allegedly running because Ross has pled
not guilty to that the trial was a
travesty it is now being appealed the
investigation was riddled with
corruption there are
two corrupt federal agents in prison
right now for their activities on the
site and their ability to tamper with
material on the site as well as stealing
over a million dollars and recently
since trial that proof has been found
that evidence was tampered with and
there's a whole lot more that you can
read about at free Ross org now before
Ross was arrested I didn't really think
much about the drug war it wasn't really
on my radar my kids didn't have a drug
problem they hadn't gotten in trouble
about drugs and so I didn't really think
about it and then all of a sudden my son
was the poster boy of the drug war or at
least as it's gone digital and so I was
propelled into the crash course I told
you about where I've learned a lot and I
was talking recently with Ross about the
drug war and and he made the point he
said you know no decent person would
wish that destructive drugs like heroin
or crystal meth existed the trouble is
when you use government force to fulfill
your wishes first of all it doesn't work
and it compounds the misery involved
they can't even stop drug dealing and
drug use in the prisons so the drug war
has not worked
it's been over forty five years now over
a trillion dollars and I've asked myself
you know well if it's such a failure why
doesn't the government try a new
strategy why don't they do something
that works and I've come to the
conclusion that it's not such a failure
after all just consider what it's
accomplished see the results if you want
to make a lot of money you want to
expand government power and the ability
to intrude
the drug war has been a resounding
success unfortunately in the process
countless lives have been destroyed a
trillion dollars has been wasted and our
constitutional protections have been
terribly weakened
the drugs war started out by ignoring
the Constitution and it's continued on
from there when the government wanted to
prohibit alcohol use it passed the 19th
amendment a constitutional amendment and
then 13 years later when it realized it
wasn't working because prohibition never
does it passed the 21st amendment to
repeal prohibition well with the drug
war the government hasn't bothered with
all that they've just declared the drug
war and given themselves the authority
to wage it and one of the obvious
casualties of it is the erosion of the
Fourth Amendment the Fourth Amendment is
the the document that protects our
privacy and in this day and age privacy
is a huge issue and it's a major part of
Ross's appeal because unconstitutional
warrants and sometimes no warrants were
used in his case and his defense isn't
the only one saying this the National
Association of criminal defense lawyers
and EF F Electronic Frontier Foundation
joined Ross's appeal to say yes these
are unconstitutional warrants and should
not be allowed and Ross's case isn't
unique you can't even begin to calculate
the number of people who have been had
property seized been searched with
unlawful improper warrants
not to mention on illegal surveillance
unlawful wiretapping raiding homes with
SWAT teams on flimsy evidence sometimes
seriously harming people and all under
the name of the drug war so it's all ok
and this is basically what happened to
Ross the government essentially said
that because drugs are involved they
could pretty much do whatever they
wanted they could ignore his due process
rights and trial or trample on them they
could keep the jury from knowing about
corrupt investigators they could smear
his name with unproven and uncharged
allegations and many more
violations this sets a very dangerous
precedent and now there's an entrenched
and generally accepted drug exception in
the courts where if drugs are involved
the Constitution essentially takes a
backseat one lawyer called this the get
out of your constitutional obligations
free card for law enforcement and
prosecutors Thurgood Marshall in 1989
saw the slippery slope that the drug war
was putting us on and he dissented in a
Supreme Court decision that was it was a
drug testing case that used the drug
exception and he said no there is no
drug exception to the Constitution
there's no exception and principles of
law once bent do not snap back easily so
what is the result of this overreach and
this bending of the principle of law
which doesn't only affect drug cases by
the way once law is bent and and damaged
it filters into all kinds of cases well
it's given the United States the dubious
honor of caging more of its citizens
than any nation on the face of the earth
this is the land of the free as this
chart illustrates the prison population
since the 80s and the drug war has
metastasized 500% is the latest figure
I've seen 2.2 million people in prison
this is a 500% increase and over half of
these people well over half are
nonviolent drug offenders and the main
drug involved is marijuana
the US has 5 percent of the world's
population and 25 percent of its
prisoners there are more people under
correctional supervision in the United
States than were in the Gulag
Archipelago
under Stalin at its height according to
book caging of America so what are some
of the policies that have reaped this
evil and tragic harvest mandatory
minimums which take judicial discretion
away from judges and sentencing longer
sentences and a spike in life sentences
have all crammed our prisons to
overflowing now according to the
Sentencing Project life sentences have
quintupled there are five times as many
as were in 1984 and the drug war one in
seven prisoners are sentenced to die in
prison one in seven over 17,000 of those
people that are serving life sentences
like Rosses are nonviolent people who
like Ross have never physically harmed
or threatened anyone and now because
there's no parole in the federal system
again since the 80s life means life and
Ross said to me he said mom a life
sentence is a death sentence it just
takes longer now this is a quote from
the Atlantic by Judge Federal Judge
former federal judge nancy gertner who
is now a professor a law professor at
Harvard and judge Gertner said that the
vast majority of the sentences she had
to impose over the 17 years she served
on the bench were unjustified and she
believes Ross's is - which is why she
joined Ross's appeal challenging that
sentence as did drug policy Alliance Law
Enforcement Against Prohibition and just
leadership USA who said this sentence is
excessive barbaric and unfair and
taxpayers are footing the bill for
housing all of these people for life
there's a lot of money being generated
more than 80 billion dollars a year on
this system and
so there's people who are very
interested in keeping it going now who
is that I think you can get a good idea
from this list the top 5 anti marijuana
legalization groups first we have the
private prisons where human beings are
inventory they have lockup quotas that
they have to meet that gives them every
incentive to keep those cages full you
can invest in human beings on Wall
Street even if you're a judge and a
prosecutor by investing in these private
prisons I would like someone to explain
to me how this is not human trafficking
or even slavery then you have the police
unions and the prison guard unions one
person wrote the drug war is not a war
it's a jobs program and Mark Victor
writes about how he had a law
enforcement officer say to him yeah I'm
for the drug war I'd be unemployed
without the drug war the FBI data shows
that there are more arrests for
marijuana possession than alone than for
all violent crimes combined wow I feel
safer don't you I'm terrified of those
pot smokers I'm so glad they're behind
bars and you know don't worry about the
violent people
then there's asset forfeiture which
comes to billions of dollars that the
government's in various agencies seizes
from citizens it's often unconvicted
under the name of the drug war next on
the list are pharmaceutical corporations
and alcohol and beer companies well what
better way to eliminate the competition
than to keep it illegal and not on the
list but worth mentioning are the
violent cartels the violent drug cartels
that infest our cities and are attracted
and are able to have the power they do
because of the artificially inflated
prices that drugs get and there's also
the banks like hsbc who launder billions
of
in drug money and nobody went to jail it
would they paid a fine so unless you
measure the human costs the drug war is
quite successful but of course there are
terrible human costs statistics are real
people Ross is one of them I am one of
them because I can tell you when you
have a loved one in prison the whole
family is doing time here I am going to
the prison to visit Ross which I do
regularly and I've gotten to know the
other families and the children and the
children of the real heartbreak they
come so excited and enthusiastic about
seeing their dad a lot of them have a
little t-shirt I love my dad and they're
just jumping up and down with enthusiasm
and when we get upstairs they leap into
his arms and they're crawling all over
them and sitting in his lab and just
clinging to him and then after our
measly hour they're torn away from him
and it's a very different child going
back down on that elevator they're
crying they're brokenhearted they're
wounded these children are being hurt
and there are 2.9 million of them with
an incarcerated parent in this country
and 2/3 of those parents are nonviolent
mostly drug offenders and there's a
terrible ripple effect from this judge
Gertner said we know that the sons and
daughters of the people we sentenced are
now in trouble with the criminal justice
system but hey that's guaranteed
inventory for the people making money
off of this drug war and this system so
no problem with that plenty of future
inventory I had the privilege of
speaking in Eastern Europe about a year
and a half ago and I visited the
concentration camp Auschwitz in Poland
and Here I am at Auschwitz it was an
incredibly grim and impactful experience
to be there and to actually experience a
place where people did this to other
people it was hard to believe it even
happened
and I overheard a tour guide say to his
group the lesson here is watch your
politicians this wasn't that long ago
now I'm not implying that where Ross is
is comparable to Auschwitz although that
although the UN has called MCC torture
but it's not Auschwitz
however concentration camps and gulags
were created by governments who claimed
the group they were doing the greater
good also and who were fulfilling wishes
with force also we need to pay attention
to what's happening here and where we're
going we need to end the drug war it's a
national disgrace and it's a crime
against humanity here is my son Ross in
prison he is a danger to no one and he
has a lot to contribute like so many
he's being warehoused his life is being
wasted to no good end but a great cost
if you're interested in his case and
learning more please visit our website
free Ross org if you're so moved
please help us in this fight and not
just for us but for the precedents that
are being set with this case that will
impact all of us if you care about your
constitutional protections and you're
against this drug war helping us is a
good way to help make a change thank you