my gym we're going to be discussing some
metadata about the effects of cannabis
and cognitive function you know it's
quite an honor to close the conference
with your presentation it does feel a
little bit like Jimi Hendrix at
Woodstock
while people settle down I'd also say
you know this is a controversial issue
what effect cannabis has on the brain
and I encourage you cannabis users not
to take it personally you know don't be
so vain that you you think this data is
about you so I like to say that I do
have a disclaimer and that's largely
because life has been good lately and I
do provide consulting advising to
businesses the government the industry
as well as work in academic circles so
today I'm going to discuss a little bit
about cannabis as a factor at health it
can be a good factor it can be a bad
factor but ultimately what this data
shows this is a bit of a spoiler so if
you don't out for the rest of the talk
this is all you really need to know is
that in the younger you are more
cannabis you use more likely there will
be issues associated with that use but
for most individuals cannabis does not
pose a significant health risk but don't
appear to be long lasting effects any
cognitive deficits appear to go away
with abstinence and all this is what I'm
presenting to you X actually is from a
paper that my colleague Adrian Lee who's
a student at Oxford for Canada
mathematics PhD have compiled and it is
a review on the metadata alright so
we're going to just kind of go through
this a little bit and one of these have
to remember is that this data is far
from being predictive there is no like
if you use cannabis this part of your
brain will shrink or this part of your
brain will increase in size there's
lacking a lot of longitudinal data so
I'm gonna start off with talking about
some cannabis research issues on what
type of data is there we often hear this
erroneous thing about there is no
research on cannabis or certain kind
produce all the research on cannabis and
things like that but we'll talk about
some of these spurious correlations and
why you should never use the c-word when
you talk about cannabis if you don't
know what that is you'll learn what the
see where it is we'll talk about some of
the political and health observations so
before we had meta analyses on the
effects of cannabis we have
international reports we'll talk about
some of their outcomes and their impacts
and then we'll jump into what these
systematic review of some of these
studies what they found and then I'm
going to share with you quotes from
researchers about their own research and
what they think it means and we'll end
with how I stopped you know learn to
stop worry and love research on
cognitive effects of cannabis so let's
start with this cannabis research issue
so always be careful with saying
cannabis causes anything whether it's a
therapeutic effect or a negative effect
for this good factor bad factor
Association does not equal causation and
we'll go over a number of reasons why
this is not true this is the most common
mistake proponents and opponents of any
sort of drug legislation or marijuana
legalization tend to make so you know
cannabis is a factor it's often
associated with things but it is not the
cause of a lot of things I think that's
an important thing to think about is
this cannabis as effect so we have our
pyramid of data so at the very bottom we
have like case reports and a total
reports from the foundation of data
quality then we have our observational
studies these are often like the easiest
to do but also are these are some of the
weakest studies in terms of they're here
they're at the mercy of their methods so
if you're relying on self reporting
about cannabis use for a financial
incentive hey I'll give you ten bucks if
you tell me you use a lot of cannabis
you can see there could be some biases
in that but also a lot of these studies
on cognitive function don't confirm what
people are using or if they're actually
using cannabis presently or having the
passes a lot of it is all surveillance
these studies have gotten more
sophisticated recently and what kind
go through their evolution bless you at
the top of the pyramid we see more like
the randomized controlled studies at the
very top we have reviews and and what a
meta-analysis is you take clinical data
individual clinical report like we saw
some dr. Staci Gruber presented a that'd
be one study you take ten of those
twenty of those forty of those together
you got yourself a meta-analysis but you
can treat them as one study and look for
similarities but it's very very
difficult so you wrote this article for
nature last month which is discussed
that while there is research allows of
candidates there are these terrific
hoops that they live on fire that you
can jump through to be able to do
cannabis research you still really it's
not legal to study products on the
market if you're federally funded so and
you'll see disclaimers if you look for
them in publications about cannabis
varieties we'll say here's the chemical
profile of the plant but due to
regulations in the state we cannot
publish any of the physiological data
because it's still federally illegal
just a fun fact I know many people
assertive unfamiliar with drug
scheduling but just as a fun fact but I
like to throw this up there THC actually
appears in three different scheduling
categories why nobody really knows the
past FDA there's no clear answer on this
but if it appears in the marijuana plant
it's a Schedule one if it's a liquid
form by syndra's as scheduled - it is
purified in a pill that's Schedule three
and then way by itself and schedule five
we have a dial answer purify it CBD but
again these are the sort of the
limitations of research we don't see a
lot of products here that are on the
market the current sort of holy grail of
medical cannabis among a lot of circles
is National Academy of Sciences report
again and this is really nice because it
does provide some conclusions about what
cannabis will be effective for there's
the whole three plus one right it's been
shown to be effective for pain multiple
sclerosis and other evidence as well
including a late one addition to that
was for pediatric epilepsy it also
contains some associations
it doesn't say cannabis causes mental
health issues but it is associated it's
a fact
in this way to be very careful by just
you know getting upset at people who say
it causes psychosis or causes violence
because we lose the ability to develop
studies that you own if you're looking
for extreme effects of cannabis you will
under power your study to be able to
detect those and why why do I tell am i
talking about associations so much
well wrote an article for project CBD
called channeling and slinger
you know cracks in a crackpot theory
about a pop book and there's a lot of
spurious correlations out there I just
put up a few here for posterity say
you're welcome to take a picture but
there there's so many out there
for example ice cream sales increase as
do drowning deaths on the same day
you know the ice cream sales are not
count causing the drowning deaths there
might be relations there having a high
intelligence is actually linked to
developing mental illness later in life
getting straight A's in high school is
linked to developing ADHD this doesn't
cause it but it is linked there so let
me make these correlations and think
about them really really think about it
I mean you know high blood pressure is
linked to violence high blood pressures
are causing the violence so there's some
things I think of it as you go out in
the world and are trying to disentangle
some of the messaging about cannabis
especially with what's going on with
product safety concerns if you know
cannabis and it's decisions are a factor
probably not the cause but what they
aren't present so we're gonna talk a
little bit about and this is coming
straight out of the paper a review not
only of the clinical cannabis and
cognition studies but what have we seen
before these meta-analysis and basically
these are the Commission and Academy
report so the Indian hemp drug
Commission's which is a very short
report and with the digital access today
you can read an original copy of it
online but basically it said you know
cannabis there was a lot of cannabis use
going on and people were really
concerned about it was the cause of
violence and murders and also and mental
health issues it turns out that the
Commission concluded it was it and that
was far more widespread than anyone had
ever considered across classic costs
religious values in the cross cultures
following up to that was a 1925 Panama
Canal Zone report and basically they
conclude a very similar thing you know
this is not the cause of all societies
mills and they shortly refill out the
military personnel to carry cannabis on
them because of the perception shortly
after that in the u.s. due to concerns
of you know this is when you saw kind of
henry Anslinger coming rising to fame
and his ill same things like you we use
cannabis and you'll fall under the
influence of listening to jazz and they
say you only have to do something about
this this is the first time you ever saw
cannabis or hemp being described as a
narcotic words like addict and addiction
were replaced by a moral street user and
don't feed and we start to see these
gears or the turn and how people
discussed and perceived it it was blamed
for causing a lot of societal issues we
fast forward to the the LaGuardia report
which is again Fiorello LaGuardia was a
beloved mayor of New York his name
actually literally means little plant
and he commissioned this report done by
the National Academy of scientists have
found that there was nothing to
substantiate these claims about cannabis
causing negative effects shortly after
that there was under Nixon the Shafer
Commission report as it's commonly known
another bloke politician said you know
after doing their own research looking
at all available evidence they said it
should be decriminalized and it doesn't
constitute a major public health threat
which is why it ended up in schedule one
shortly after that
so it's you know disconnect between the
science and the policy they're
fast-forwarding I'm gonna skip one of
the National Academy reports from 1999
but the most recent one as we know has
shown that cannabis is effective based
on looking at you know tens of thousands
of articles on the subject so what about
cannabis use in the brain well I'm going
to go through a little bit of a history
here
and take some liberties with what these
people may have said a little bit this
is our clinical distillation and then
I'll share after this like I said quotes
from the researchers from their own
articles about this stuff so Nadia so
Louise is a brilliant researcher threw
the gauntlet down in 1999 with her book
cannabis at cognitive function there was
really nothing available at the time I
have even used this handbook to design
studies and around memory retention and
reaction times camps a very useful book
but it did conclude that the weight of
the evidence suggests that you know
cannabis does not result in any severe
or gross debilitating impairment of
cognitive function right regardless sort
of the amount of use remember these are
just surveys people who are admitted to
using cannabis and they're putting them
through a battery of cognitive and IQ
tests following that study another
person said well you know there are
metabolic changes and we look at all
these observational reports but there's
so many discrepancies like some cannabis
users their IQ increases over time some
decrease what you know this is one of
the things is used there's a really
poorly done study that talks about
cannabis users experience at eight
points of IQ decrease over time if you
look at this statistic on that it's plus
or minus 8 IQ points they're the
greatest increases and the greatest
decreases over time from the group so a
lot of discrepancies hope in 2003 or - I
can't read it from here to us - he
actually threw another novel down so
actually you know what during impairment
there are changes to the brain there's
changes to how the brain is functioning
and how it's adapting and having a ton
of THC floating around in there but any
measurable effect in the clinic
disappears after about 28 days of
absence you cannot detect it through a
battery of cognitive tests regardless of
the amount of use another researcher
seemed to conclude something similar
saying well there's a small magnitude of
a
here especially while people are using
it actively using cannabis but if
cannabis does have therapeutic effects
this is an acceptable margin of safety
for a medicine like this Sola we came
back almost ten years later and said you
guys are all wrong
there's actually impairment past 28 days
but I don't know what it means because
it's not significant but there really
she really counted that there are
effects on the brain but they didn't
seem to be clinically impacting any of
the battery tests that were administered
to people then we started to see a
change in 2006 with the meta-analysis
teams became more sophisticated
equipment became more sensitive quick
fallen colleagues were like actually
we're seeing adaptive changes of the
brain from long-term cannabis and if you
went to Stacy troopers talk today you
got to see some of that data and some of
the differences when you start to drill
down or people using this as an
intoxicant or as is a medicine there can
actually be significant changes they
started to draw a line a little bit
about their so and we started to see a
couple papers you know the next one
they're looking at these effects which
are associate with heavy use of cannabis
that yeah there are changes in the brain
if while they are using cannabis but
there are adaptive changes in the brace
you're not just saying an
across-the-board atrophy of the brain or
things like that and you know they're
basically starts to build up that there
is minimal evidence of these long-term
effects and some researchers started to
look back through this data at about
this time 2009 they discovered that some
of the studies that had found a
difference of significant difference in
the effect of cannabis on brain we're
actually looking at two sets of data
that were identical from Finland they
actually had combined them this one to
come it was one to six it's like oh we
have two men analyses but they pick two
groups they combine it so there was a
correction they're done and they said
actually there's no differences in
global measurements
and brain volume and there's not a lot
of evidence there as well so moving
forward closer to our time you know
there is residual effects people have
thought but one of the things that came
up around this time was that if users
reported using CBD again just reported
like this literally questionnaire do you
use cannabis that contains CBD
surprisingly these patients or users in
New Zealand did not have any cognitive
deficits regardless how much THC
cannabis they use which seems a little
weird because you know if you know
anything about cannabis you know there's
always a little bit of CBD in there is
that what's doing it or you know they
did not test any of the products of
history we're using so again we start to
see more refinement of these things
people are began really thinking about
what abstinence means from candidates
due to its half-life on the body and how
long it stays there
not seeing cognitive impacts after
abstinence
you know chronic cannabis use may or may
not alter brain structure this was a
conclusion from a research study because
they saw it in some people but not
others remember they're not controlling
for things like how they're
administering it what they're using are
they getting it from a legal market or
getting it from an illicit market is it
tested for things they don't even
confirming if they're actually using
cannabis and a lot of times these are
confounded as some of these studies are
I'm sharing here more recently because
they would go to New Zealand and other
European countries and do these studies
to try and see if they could find the
same effects what they call a joint in
Europe and New Zealand Australia is not
what you call it here in California but
a joint out there is a lot of tobacco
with a little bit of cannabis sprinkled
in it and once they controlled for that
a lot of their effects disappeared
especially in the effects panel essence
so you know tobacco you seem to be more
highly associated with many of these
cognitive deficits impairments and you
know less academic achievement and
things like that a lot
researchers started to think about what
is the mechanism of this data how is it
translated and they says that you know
this means that there is a lot of
causality here it is a factor it can't
be a good factor or a bad bad factor but
you know the regular use of cannabinoids
exerts structural and you know changes
in the brain that all seems to be
temporary and transitory you know we
have you know our brains are very neuro
adaptive and it's taken a while for
people to accept that stem cells it's a
relatively new thing before the 1990s
people just thought hey you had brain
cells eventually he'll lose them all but
now we know that they get replaced by
stem cells they don't just sort of
slough off like leaves on a tree than
you're done one day so they started in
look more and more at acute THC and
another group found that there is
evidence for a protective effect from
cannabidiol
so if patient if people in these studies
observations report using CBD they don't
see them performing poorly in these
cognitive tests they don't see the
differences in brain bond it's much much
less likely and so when it gets stiff
functional alterations it started to be
more and more cemented that these
findings are largely compensatory for
the brain to adapt in a life of swimming
in THC and so these changes go back to
baseline or to other levels after say 30
days or so of use yeah and a little bit
more the same I know it gets a little
redundant but as we start to come to a
crash here in 2018 and 2019 people start
to try and Link candidates to it's very
specific changes in the crane and
they're they're failing there's a lot of
issues here there see things are not
expecting they're seeing increases
decreases across the board so there is a
reason why and I'll get to that in just
a second so when we think about cannabis
and themes from this metadata I know I
flew through it
that of the day I want to keep you guys
here too much but basically cannabis use
is associated with changes in the brain
and that is from acute use if you're
impaired on cannabis oddly going to
perform poorly on a variety of cognitive
tasks especially if it's just pure THC
that is something that's been shown
fairly conclusive however it seems to
differ with experience tolerance and
things like that so when you talk about
cannabis naive users are getting exposed
to th so you will see effects less
likely in people who have used it but
again this stuff is far from predictive
you know it's science I'm always trying
to figure out how to predict things how
things will behave what will be the
outcome you know that's why you know
astronomy Rose the power to predict the
phases of the Moon right really far from
that with this brain to skin so if you
can't say a child who's using a lot of
cannabis is going to have this part of
their brain be affected we know for sure
it's far from predictive we don't have
the ability to identify who's at risk
and who isn't but one of the biggest
issues with this data and why we decided
to write this paper was in response to a
science fiction book that was published
earlier this year and basically when you
when researchers go out there and are
trying to take hyperbolic messaging and
inflammatory messaging and then just
sort of dramatic sensationalistic
headlines and you use that to guide
their research their data their
experiments design would be under power
to find those results I'll give you an
example if you believe say just bear
with me a cannabis use even a single
one-time use will cause irreversible
changes to the brain lead to psychosis
and violence and you say that the study
to find it you're probably going to have
a really tough time finding evidence for
that right but if you start to ask more
subtle questions about whether or not
it's a factor and what is the good
factor of that I start to drill down a
little bit you might actually generate
some good data but you know don't take
Adrian and ice words for it we're going
to talk some quotes from the researchers
about their own research so so one of
the authors we talked about this grant
makan and so basically said current
human observations on the effect of
marijuana for cannabis on development
are sparse and contradictory you know
very very interesting so they're the
result of our meta-analysis study to
reveal I see a substantial effect of
long-term effects on cannabis yeah you
know basically they're saying they can't
find it there I see I can think I can
read this next one I apologize the way
of the evidence suggests that long-term
use of cannabis does not result in any
severe gross ability aiding impairment
of cognitive function actual quote and
she's done a lot of these observational
studies and meta analyses you know the
long-term risks do not appeal sorry
intermediate risk for most users are not
severe and their effects are remarkably
subtle so again these are actual quotes
from researchers about their papers and
again was cherry picked and taken out of
context a skill I learned from each
Andrew so who is like the god added on
if you read any of his work but my she's
he phenomenal at this so why do they see
these differences in these studies some
studies see in effect a dramatic like
some don't some see this impairment some
don't what what are some of the factors
so in our paper it wasn't just a you
know unload on this these studies but to
try and make them better so one of the
things that you really have to start
asking about it maybe even testing for
is what are people using what it's the
chemo type of candidates and how are
they delivering it another really
overlooked aspect is genetics genetics
especially pharmacogenetics the mouse
Hafsa is dirt cheap it's easy to do it's
rapid you can some places do it in-house
there we collaborate with a sexual
health clinic in New York they have
on-site genetic testing from certain
markers this is really easy to do and
the reasoning
this is your how fast you metabolize THC
could play a role in how often you use
it and the effect so there's a whole
spectrum of people yeah low like very
people who metabolize stuff really
really slowly you have sup to metabolize
up really fast if you're using cannabis
you know just conceptually one person
might get smoked 20 joints a day and not
feeling well one person might have a
little bit of cannabis but stays in
their system a really really long time
the other thing is defining withdrawal
for cannabis which is again it's
controversial but when do you consider
someone cleared out of cannabis when is
that some people say 20 days some people
say 30 in those studies it range some
people had no apparent cognitive
deficits that could be detected 7 hours
some people that lasted 20 days what are
those differences this also isn't a lot
of longitudinal data here they're not
looking at before and after people
initiate cannabis but this never
happened and so that would be two veils
and also objective measures of use how
are people using this is you know if you
use it one time or you included this
study what is the cutoff and what is a
cannabis user you'll see this term used
without ever being defined in a study
day this is the user group and it's like
willing to use like five times in the
last year maybe its whole life this is
that a user there really is not a good
discussion there gender differences are
also an important thing to control in
these studies men and women respond to
cannabis differently and even endorse
different positive and negative aspects
of cannabis use in terms of relations
with their family effects on job and
things like that and that's something
that's not often taken to account when
you love all these brain scans and
observational studies together I'd also
say do not really rely on IQ scores
especially don't use them alone now my Q
scores and IQ testing has been misused
throughout the history of the United
States we really got it wrong I don't
know if you knows but they used to be on
the IQ test or M
it's coming in through Ellis Island
you'd begin a list of names you had to
identify which one was a New York Yankee
that was part of the IQ test and so what
IQ tests are incredibly subjective and
based on cultural values like complete
this picture that could be a picture of
an airplane or a pipe or some sort of
object so these tests are notoriously
unreliable and they're not intended to
establish someone's words or criminality
it really went on IQ test is the only
thing I can really compare it to would
be like going to ophthalmology
appointment and getting a prescription
for glasses that is the only intent in
the only way that's ever been approved
to use IQ tests really is to correct
identifying correct learning
disabilities much like you might correct
your vision by going to see an eye
doctor you also need to adjust for body
size this was perhaps the most shocking
thing different people of different
heights will have different brain sizes
and so let's imagine you got a bunch of
tall people who don't use cannabis with
a bunch of short people who do cannabis
you might be like my gosh these cannabis
users have really small brains quit
supply and this is something that has
never been controlled for in these
studies so again something else really
simple it seems to make intuitive sense
brain and body size are linked why not
adjust for that in these studies
especially small ones the biggest one
the biggest ask I've had is
pre-registration how are you going to
conduct this study you can put it online
and have people from the community
review and make recommendations so you
can incorporate all these things I'm
talking about but I think that that is
one of the things you really want to
adjust in the future is getting the idea
of we live in this community it's very
accessible you want to do a study post
the methodology and how you're going to
do it online so that you can make sure
you're not you know
confirming your own bias and vacuum so
again just to reiterate about these
studies you know THC or cannabis this is
not debatable it does lead to
intoxication it is associated with
impairment and temporary alterations in
brain signaling if it wasn't it wouldn't
have fair pubic effects you know more
like a lot of whom say THC is not
psychoactive it's like well it goes into
the brain and it's certain receptors the
same targets as anti-anxiety medication
it goes in the brand it's adenosine the
same target as caffeine it alters
cognition right even if it's improving
cognition that's still psychoactive so
again it's an on a toxic ating component
again all the effects of cannabis in
terms of deficits impairment appear
reversible and time who has never been
any confirmation that there are severe
debilitating conditions we actually used
some of this data to sue the DEA a few
years ago to change their website they
changed some of these things because on
their website actually said a single use
of cannabis leads to irreversible
changes on the brain or irreversible
toxic effects to use their terminology
but in their denial of the petition to
reschedule cannabis they actually cited
other research that said there were no
lasting cognitive impacts and in you
know in the case we visually said well
which is it
are there no lasting impacts from
cannabis on the brain or does a single
use permanently change the brain there's
about 20 points that they ended up
changing on the website in terms of
claims about these things so the main
takeaway is that the the clinical impact
of cannabis on the brain and cognitive
function is inconsistent and and you
could probably appreciate a little bit
more why because this these
observational studies are like a Hail
Mary pass to figure something out and
we've reached a point where they're not
really helpful anymore they're getting
tingly misused in the media getting used
to influence policy but you know give
you an example
Massachusetts wanted to propose putting
cannabis may cause psychosis on a
cannabis
well you know what put it in there with
the other 30 warnings that no one's ever
going to read ever if I did a study
right these release these piece will
relate to the party because a study came
out saying that even experienced
cannabis users cannot comprehend
labeling of a lot of cannabis products
and the labeling and warning labels
actually covers up useful information
like dosing dosing size how much in the
prize in the product and how long the
effects last for and most experienced
users could even identify the universal
symbol for a product containing
marijuana a more rational sense solution
to this would be to rotate the warning
labels like you see on tobacco and other
products versus listing all 30 of them
on a 1 you know 10 milligram serving so
I guess you know in conclusion we really
start to have to start controlling these
studies better and not jumping and
dropping the c-word about cannabis and
really fight back on anyone who talks
about positive effects of cannabis
things are associated things are linked
and thinks are factors and with that I'd
say please feel free to email me I'm
happy to share this presentation and to
take any questions thank you
[Applause]
well I've answered all your curiosities
about candidates on the brain it jobs my
first time ever give me this top so
that's pretty good alright
yes a lot of these studies claim to look
at healthy populations and they try to
control for diseases but yes there's
there's a lot of these very interesting
case reports of people who say severe
muscular disorders it was a truck driver
in Germany he couldn't pass his driving
test cos of muscle spasticity and he
passed and got his license with a very
called a very legal amount of THC in
your blood like a skyrocket amount of it
and so yeah we have to think about the
context of use when it comes to this
because there are a lot of studies where
people who again if you have suffer from
tremors and it approves your tremors
that is a case and even with visual
processing and cannabis on the brain
cannabis seems to affect the mechanics
of the eye but not the actual visual
processing of information that is a
great point yes sir
hi Christian associate when you when you
do your MIT analysis how do you factor
in the political environment right
because we've seen it in your own slides
we've heard it a few times I think in
the conference you know a lot of it is
about the governor and the rules that he
puts in his state and or hers and and
you end up with a lot of skewed science
essentially apparently according also I
believe to some of the examples you are
given so when you do the meta-analysis
do you classify politically which gets
obviously very dangerous what how do you
do what you do with that data interpret
that yeah that's an interesting question
ultimately you want to start thinking
more about how do you generate
scientific information that will
actually influence policy and this is is
very difficult
yeah there is no I don't think there
really is an answer how do you factor in
political information you can definitely
tell when you read some of these papers
like man they have a chip on their
shoulder about this issue there are
implicit
and I think you know as humans we're
kind of evolved to look for patterns and
and people are being really lazy out
there with a lot of this data to be
quite frank a nature is lazy right so
official have said so it's human nature
and so part of that I think it is by not
being lazy and by doing your due
diligence around this work because it
wasn't the researchers who combined the
same population twice there were like
oops they're like well hey this is
politically good for us to show this
effect so it was other researchers who
had the guts to step up and say actually
you made a mistake here let's correct
this so I think if you find a mistake in
the literature find a mistake out there
you know it happens all the time
something that people just accept
something they hear all the time they
just don't question it gets cited
repeated repeated repeated you know I
think that's what it's going to take and
more people are being more comfortable
with taking those stances
so also I'll assume that motor
impairment also varies greatly among
individuals including you know their
abilities to drive a car I also
understand a breathalyser who's also
about to hit the market so you know is
that is that technology that whatever
we're going to face is it going to be
accurate or a lot of the people gonna be
swept up or not impaired and what are we
looking at in in that realm I think
there is for those devices but it also
you know begs the question of there are
a real aside from alcohol just to speak
simply about blood levels no other
pharmaceutical drug blood levels do not
correlate to impairment it's very
surprising right there isn't if this was
the case you'd have a benzodiazepine an
opioid roadside sobriety test right
doesn't exist
why because blood levels do not
correlate to impairment and also the
thing is if you're using a product
CBD rich with a little bit of THC you
could get popped for the THC content
product they're not testing for CBD as
well it's a very broad stroke the some
of the ones that concern me are
definitely false positives you might get
especially the mouth swaps like you
might never have touched cannabis but be
around people the vapor vampires are the
people who just changed smoking cannabis
and you could fail one of those mouth
swab tests but they do have their I
think they do have their applications
and potentially looking at recent use
but there still are some issues of how
do you address the most positives and
what's the goal here we did a study with
American Chemical Society that we talked
about where we suggested that the
roadside sobriety test that's already
used the horizontal gaze and the
three-point turn walk is actually more
reliable than urine or blood testing it
but detecting impairment for all
substances I mean you could be too
sleepy to drive you could still be
classified as impaired so there are a
number of reasons there but as a
confirmation about the substance that
people were using at the time of being
impaired that's probably in Seoul's
menus but I think those devices have a
long way to go but again law enforcement
party has a great tool that's routinely
used to check for impairment and whether
or not you can drive regardless of the
reason but I will help anyone develop a
breathalyzer that it's looking to do it
yeah I think they're used clinically as
is also potentially in these
observational studies if you could
convert quickly whether or not people
are actually using cannabis and
participating the study that'd be a
great use of these devices moreso than
looking for intoxication but alright is
that it okay thank you so much
[Music]