I got my PhD in 1995 I've worked on a
wide range of plant viral diseases and
um I've met folks uh I joined let's see
I joined Texas A&amp;M about five years ago
and I've been working on a wide range of
of problems and I got involved with hopl
and vroid when I met folks from Rare
Earth genomics and started working with
uh Russ Jessup U who's a breeder at
Texas A&amp;M to try to tackle some of these
these questions and issues and uh while
I could say I'm an expert at plant
virology I'm also feeling like I'm an
expert at something in Hop light and
vroid we know very little about so um so
I'm excited to be here and I'm excited
to take on this
project there we go
so um we've developed an infectious
clone of hop and vroid and uh this is
actually my my starting talk I am in the
Plant Pathology Department at at Texas
A&amp;M and this is an example of some
plants that we infected in our growth
chamber and one of the biggest questions
that we have is you can look at these
plants and the same variety has
different disease patterns so how do we
explain the disease how do we conquer
the disease how do we recognize the
disease um there's one healthy plant
here in the corner and you can see very
severely um chlorotic plants and mildly
chlorotic plants and they were all
inoculated at the same time um and so
this creates a challenge in itself for
working with Growers trying to help them
identify healthy from infected
materials and I wanted to start by
telling you a little bit more more about
the life cycle of viroids so it's very
easy for non virologists to think a
vroid and a virus are the same thing
they have the same life cycle and they
really are quite different um viroids
are small circular RNA molecules that
don't encode for any protein they're
only 250 nucleotides in length um which
is crazy small um I work on RNA viruses
that are 10,000 uh base pairs in LAN so
250 is about as small of an infectious
agent as you can get because they don't
encode any proteins they are kind of a
miracle I think because um how do they
cause such an amazing disease and cause
so much changes to a cell into a plant
Without Really encoding anything at all
um hot PL and vroid is a circular RNA
this is its replication cycle um it
encodes a single strand nucleic acid and
and it replicates in the plant cell
nucleus so it depends upon the host
Machinery in order to replicate and
cause
infection um and so the host RNA
polymerase um acts on the genome and
produces a copy and that copy then
serves as a template for production of
multiple strands and each of those are
produced and circularized and it
continues through a cycle of synthesis
and
replication and it's able to spread
through throughout the plant so that
means it must exit the nucleus move
through plasma desata between cells
enter the vascular system and somehow
Rec havoc on these plants hopl and vroid
causes dud disease in case you don't
know um and so it's interesting for me
as a plant virologist to try to
understand how a 250 nucleotide amino
acid can um cause a latent infection
where you don't see any symptoms for a
while and then suddenly um destroy the
flowering ability and um affect its
complete
development um so thyroids many viroids
not just top latent vroid are latent
viruses they are latent diseases it's
quite common amongst the um
vroid uh pathogens that they cause
latent infections and then you don't see
them until much later one example is
peach latent vroid there's huge problems
of viroids in stone fruits um Peach is
one example and you don't see disease
until the plants start until the trees
start to wither so because of there are
issues in stone fruits as well as in in
um in Hops and in hemp they are
economically very important category of
pathogens um and as you know uh hop plat
and vroid causes extremely important
significant problems in the in the hemp
industry which is how we got involved in
this and so as we got involved about
year and a half two years ago working on
hopl and viroid we started developing
the tools to detect it um one of our
first most important questions was early
detection of hopl and vroid in infected
plants and um uh how do you know if you
and the the main approach is to use a
PCR technology and we're very concerned
about quality control and our research
in our efforts and making sure that we
get true positive results not false
positive results true negative results
not false negative results so when
you're dealing with a plant with such an
array of no symptoms to severe closis um
and death how do you know that you might
have missed a positive outcome and so
one of our T PCR Technologies has
allowed us to identify the genome which
is 256 nucleotide Sid Es as well as
replicating intermediates which can be
500 to 750 up to 1,000 um this virid as
it replicates produces multimer of
itself and then they cleave into mature
products so we've been able to detect
the replicating units both as monomers
diers and
trimers and through this technology
we've also developed infectious clones
that are themselves monomers diers and
trimers and are using that to inoculate
plants so we can begin to study
uniformity of inoculation uniformity of
infection and start to provide real um
uh workflows for how to identify the
problem how to solve the problems how to
uh make sure your mother plants are
clean um so our major goal right now is
to understand uh some of the things
we're interested in is understanding
nonhost resistance as a guidance for
design and thyroid resistant plants
we're looking at screening germ plasms
to identify germ plasms that may not be
susceptible to hopl and vroid that would
be
nonhost and compare them and perform
crosses with very susceptible plants and
see if we can understand the genetic
basis of resistance we're wanting to
understand what happens in the host
during latency that's different from
what happens to the host during severe
symptoms um what is the viroid doing is
it just dormant not doing anything or is
it doing something metabolically that
the host actually is having an immune
respon response maybe after latency that
immune response is failing so we need to
understand what is the host response um
and how immunity functions against vroid
diseases and then we'd like to engineer
vroid resistance using a range of Novel
Technologies um and so these questions
that we're asking they're also asking in
a wide range of of um other viroid
diseases globally um the problems that
we're facing in in hemp with toate and
vroid are the same problems they're
facing in stone fruits like apricot
plums
peaches um and so what I also wanted to
to start my talk was differentiate hop
Laten vroid from Hop stunt vroid um I
found in talking with folks that it's
very easy to mix the two up they are
actually two different species of
thyroids they both infect hops they both
seem to cause a stunting when they cause
disease but hop stunt vroid is a
different uh organism together um hop
stunt vroid infects hops it infects
grape Vines it infects Citrus cucumbers
and a range of stone fruits hop latent
vroid which is a huge problem for the
hemp industry and cannabis industry does
not infect those
hosts um we uh did a sample when we
began this work of over 111 plants and
we found that 80% of those were infected
with hop lat and vroid and we found no
evidence of Hop stunt vroid co-infecting
these plants so we're clearly looking at
a single infection problem not a
potential for mixture of the two
um and so um I wanted to throw in some
pictures of folks that are working with
us and again pictures of our friends at
Rare Earth genomics that are helping to
support this research uh this is one of
the scientists in my program who was uh
speaking with our collaborators um and
these are some of the experiments that
he's been running we've been interested
in looking at developing sensitive
detection methods we want to perform
assessments of vroid host interactions
we're looking right now at different
hopl and vroid variants and comparing
the different variance across different
plant genotypes and trying to track the
progression of the
disease major fundamental question are
there different strains of hop plate and
vroid is there a severe strain and a
mild strain so the we're trying to tease
All Those Questions apart and it also
requires understanding the different
genotypes of the hosts that we're
working with and so here's an example of
some of our experiments uh perhaps
there's different variants between the
two different hosts and so how we're
going about solving that is using
infectious clone technology when we take
sap from an infected plant that we get
from uh from a grower we don't know if
that infected material that we get from
him uh has a mixture of variants or is a
single variant or a single strain so
using our infectious clone technology we
can make one single strain one single
variant and introduce that into a
variety of different genotypes and start
to characterize the nature of the
symptoms the nature of the disease and
then we can start adding new layers of
different variants and making
comparisons between them so this is some
fundamental work that we're performing
now um and again we've identified seven
we are examining and working with 71
different isolates we found 41 different
mutations across the populations and we
are now looking at how these different
mutations influence
symptoms and so this is one of our
exciting new um PCR Diagnostics that we
developed we've developed some PCR
primers that overlap a highly conserved
region of the viral genome and it's
extremely sensitive we can take an an
asymptomatic leaf that we know we
infected the plant we know it's infected
but it's not producing any symptoms and
we've been able to develop a diagnostic
PCR that can detect 10 to the n 10 to
Theus 9th molecules of
infection um and so we're moving forward
with our diagnostic um analysis we've
compared using infectious sap uh and
we've also used our infectious clone
that we've uh generated in our
laboratory and we wanted to understand
if you use sap from an infected plant
that we've taken from the field is our
infectious clone technology as sensitive
as robust of an inoculum as taking sap
from an infected plant and as you can
see when we're looking at inoculated
plants at 26 days 39 days 60 days and
then when we use our own in-house
infection system at 21 and at 42 days we
see 100% of our plants are infected
systemically and 100% of our plants are
infected locally whereas the Infectious
sap is a little slower at producing
infection in some hosts um so we're
comfortable with our Technologies we're
able to move forward this is a study
that we performed using different hosts
we want to understand how many different
plant species are infected with hop plat
and vroid that are not reported in the
literature in fact very few people are
working on this problem at all I've um
traveled through Europe every everyone I
know in Europe is working on hops stunt
vroid which is a huge problem in the
Hops industry there and I have yet to
meet uh an academic that's working on
Hop L and vroid full-time as their um as
as their problem apparently Europe is
restricting the ability to do this type
of work um as well as many states in the
US so we're really happy that in Texas
we're able to do our studies on Hop PL
and vroid um we found it infects
cucumber in infects tomato and it causes
some pretty pretty severe death of
chrysanthemum so uh if you are a uh
vegetable Gardener as well as a grower
you may want to be aware of your
vegetables as being a reservoir or or
your chrysanthemum plants in your flower
garden as being a reservoir for
disease um this is an example of our PCR
diagnostic so you can see what kind of
results we get when we look at our
different um plant hosts we get very
clean very robust PCR products across
our plants those that are negative is
our healthy here uh just to show you how
our how our data looks um we found in
our studies that arabidopsis plants
which is a model genetic system um
arabidopsis was one of the first major
uh plant genomes to be sequenced and it
is a model like dropa is a model for um
for human genetics Mamon genetics seelan
arabidopsis is our plant model genetic
system that's used uh globally for uh
UND dissecting genetics and we found
it's highly susceptible to hoplon vroid
which is exciting because it's the only
vroid that is known to infect a rabid
opsis um and it also infects cucumber
and we found that those plants die at
maturity um and so this is an example of
of a a Rabbid opsis plants that we have
growing in pots
and the infected hlate and vroid
infected plants once they reach maturity
it's called a decline or a dieback
disease the plants don't die until they
reach maturity and then you see the
necrosis the death the the Browning
tissue just going backwards down towards
the base of the
plant um for me that's exciting it's a
it's a novel symptom and it's a way we
can characterize and start using rabid
opsis genetics to um
uh to study Decline and here's an
example of younger plants that we
infected with hopl and vroid using
different versions of the Infectious
clone and with a higher level of
inoculum we can see earlier decline of
the tissue this is a healthy infected
healthy plant and then all of these
declined quite rapidly before they could
produce
flowers um so again here's our Mock and
here's our uh a mutant version of hopl
and vroid that's not supposed to produce
a dieback and as you can see the
mutation eliminated the dieback
phenotype um so we're excited to now
have good diagnostic tools a good
infectious clone technology and a good
genetics that we can begin to look for
host nonhost resistance and understand
host immunity
responses um as we've moved forward one
of the major questions that we wanted to
start looking at is developing a
workflow for how to sample how to
perform Diagnostics in hemp when you
have a latent vroid where do you sample
if you get a NE negative result did you
sample the right
tissue um or do you have to keep
sampling how often do you have to keep
sampling to make sure that your mother
plants are healthy and remain healthy um
and so our approach has been uh to
develop a strict inoculation technique
where oops sweet does that go back yes
we inoculate a specific leaf on the
plant and then we start sampling all the
way up the plant to identify where does
the virus move move first if you
inoculate one leaf 3 weeks later where
is the vroid 4 Weeks Later where is the
vroid 6 weeks later where is the vroid
and can we track its movement up the
plant is it doing something unexpected
as you know um as you may know the
literature has shown that the vroid this
vroid tends to move to the roots first
and then moves further up the plant next
um and so the best sampling results can
often occur by testing Roots early and
then testing the tops of the plants
later um with our new sensitive Tech PCR
technology uh we're been looking working
at verifying that pathway for virus
infection in plants and uh continuing
our PCR testing uh to streamline a
protocol in a way that we're not
damaging the plants but we can reduce
the amount of times you have to sample
and test at the same time we're trying
to understand the kinds of symptoms we
can see with different variants of the
viroids so we can be the experts of
telling you how to manage disease in
your crop
um so here's an example uh based on our
new knowledge of the dieback symptoms
that we see with hop PL and vroid in
arabidopsis we wanted to ask can we see
similar phenotypes happening in hemp or
yeah hemp is what we're working on in
Texas so um what we were excited
recently we this here is an example of
Brandy Wine variety or cherry wine
variety I apologize um and you can see
that the leaves are starting to die off
on the plant and it's looking pretty
sick um at maturity but you know how do
you know if your plant's just sessing
naturally or maybe there's a nutritional
issue and it's die back or not we've um
we're starting to feel more and more
comfortable that when we inoculate a
plant we switched over to using another
variety called Puma 3 in this variety
you see extreme yellowing of leaves
within 2 weeks we can inoculate a plant
2 weeks later we see this extreme
yellowing here and then this is what the
top of the plant looks like in in other
examples where you get this crazy Mosaic
pattern on the plants and so by
controlled inoculations and testing
different varieties we can then start
reporting what you should see when
certain varieties are infected with
certain variants of the viroid so it's
exciting for us that that with um uh
Puma 3 we get this yellowing and this
plant progresses to Yellow every week
until it just completely turns dead
completely
dies um and this is work that's being
done uh by another student in our in our
lab uh s Sydney Abbott who's been
managing our propagation she's quite
excited to see uh this is example of
Puma 3 is just continuing to Yellow this
is the uninfected healthy version of the
plant you can see the severe differences
between infected and healthy and uh it's
the only time I've seen a grower who's
excited that she's gotten infection in
At first she was scared she's like oh my
plants don't look good I'm like no this
looks great this is fantastic this is
what we want to see so um so we're proud
of the direction that this work is going
in so what we can say right now is we
believe that we have that hopl and vroid
causes a dieback disease that the
yellowing and the phenotypes that we see
is is an example of the symptoms that
you can see early uh we're starting to
work at developing technologies that
maybe can pick up on the vroid before
you see that extreme dieback and maybe
ways of managing the plants um we're
comfortable with saying this dieback
disease is what the disease should look
like based on studies for instance with
peach latent Mosaic vroid um uh this is
an example of infected Peach latent
where the plants look great until they
don't you know um you can see the plants
look like they don't have very much
leaves on them this is example of
infected peaches versus healthy Peaches
I mean how do you know that you have
infected peaches until you started your
Harvest very similar problems to what
we're having in the hemp industry so the
vroid problems that we're having here in
the hemp industry aren't unique virid
problems to just hemp but these are
Global issues that we as a community
within the vord community can start
discussing amongst each other and I can
pull plls from some of my colleagues uh
working on other crops and work towards
common Solutions and build on their
knowledge to uh to uh help find
solutions for this industry so we're
really excited to be moving in this
direction um you can see the differences
in the healthy and infected Stone fruits
healthy and infected leaves flowers
change colors all these are symptoms but
they're not obvious symptoms to a grower
they might be anything
else so um as we're moving forward uh
this is an example that I wanted to pull
also from Peach Lon vroid to show you
how you've got this 250
nucleotide size pathogen and a single
variant with which means a change in a
couple of couple of nucleotides can
completely change the symptoms that you
see so in this example this is a diagram
oops sorry this is a diagram of what the
peach Lon vroid looks like when it's
folded into its mature State and what
this shows here in panel B is these four
nucleotides are changed here and look at
the difference in the
symptoms this is an asymptomatic disease
and this is a complete chotic uh disease
so based on that knowledge we started
looking at a number of informative
mutations and as I've mentioned we have
a total of 41 mutations in our current
population of hopl and vroid we have
been performing some bioinformatic
analysis to understand which are
probably the most informative and useful
mutations to go after to study and we
are starting now to look at the effects
of different mutations on dieback and
closis in plants so hopefully this time
next year we'll have some up ated
information for you on what types of
symptoms that we
see um so I wanted to end my talk the
same way that we began uh with a thank
you to Rare Earth genomics uh for their
uh contribution support funding for This
research without them we would not be
even beginning to explore this very
important problem um and uh again to our
our colleagues at Texas A&amp;M who have
been working in the breeding programs
and devel velopment of improved genetics
along with rare earth genomics and uh
Texas A&amp;M University so thank you very
[Applause]
much any
questions
yes how is the viroid transmitted in
nature transmission of the virid in
nature there this thyroid we don't even
know what if there's an insect Vector
what the insect vector is there's really
very little work done on this problem um
which is shocking and also for me quite
exciting I can make some Headway on this
um we do know that it's it's extremely
um infectious you get one infected plant
it spreads through everything and to me
that's not much different from tobacco
mosaic virus where the Dew in or the
humidity in the greenhouse can be enough
to spread it through the greenhouse or
you get it on your hands and you can
transmit it um I would advise if you
have an infected plant you be wearing
gloves and change gloves between
individual plants and take your cutting
tools and your pruning tools bleach them
in between plants so that you don't
transmit them um we recommend different
virus sides for treating bench stops and
the like to keep everything under
control yes
on that picture on the left and um at
least one other on that you showed the
control plan that was not inoculated
what's the smallest one is that by
chance or is have these all been
inoculated at the same time or are the
different variants because it's you know
what what we see in our in our Gardens
is that the the infected ones are the
smallest
ones okay yeah so good question these
were not clly propagated these were
grown from seed and so there's some
heterogeneity in the
seeds
so investigated some mutants in
arabidopsis such as replication factors
or small RNA molecules Transportation
within the plants have you already used
these mutants to address is the
replication mechanism or the transport
of the molecules within the plants so
that's some ongoing work that we have
going on right now and I'm not at
Liberty to speak about it
so
yes so um whenever you're working in a
room uh with infected plants and you're
saying change gloves and clean your your
work toop and bench Toops and all the
tools that you're using I've heard
because this viroid is so small that
it's very very hard to to kill because
of that reason what is like a protocol
that you'll use in your laboratory to
stay as sterile as
possible very good question um we've
just gone through a major cleanout we so
you see the plants are on the benches
there between experiments we bleach the
entire bench um with 10% bleach um and
everyone has to wear a lab coat when
they're near our plants the lab coat
stays in the room you don't leave the
room with the lab coat uh gloves stay in
the room all of our tools TOs and shears
stay in the room they don't leave that
room so we're not spreading it from room
to room with us um we disinfect um our
tools regularly it's usually about 10%
bleach works very well um one of my
favorite is um uh cleaners is called
vercon um I use that on the floors quite
a bit they use that also in um in
dairies for making sure that uh animal
uh facilities are clean as well it's a
it's a commonly used
uh virus side uh mixed with other
cleaners and um we've used it in many
green houses in um over the last two
decades quite successfully um all pots
have to be bleached before they're
reused um or treated with
Veron um and then some of the new um uh
cleaners that have come out since covid
work quite well against other viroids so
you can even go to Lowe's and pick up
some of the household cleaners that are
supposed to be viricidal
um I think Jeep is one of the ones that
they talk about and that works also as
well and it's safe for
humans so I'm not a botanist or anything
but how closely similar is hops to
hemp are they like in the same
family yes of plants they're in the same
order so taxonomically uh Kingdom film
class order family so they're at the
same order yes
Ju Just to follow up on the cleanup um
when you use your 10% bleach on your
tools about how long do you do you
bleach for and have you validated any of
the timing with your PCR
assay
um uh let's see so far we've been really
we've not had any issues and it may just
be that I've been a virologist for so
long that um uh our materials stay
pretty clean just from experience
um we uh tend to bleach everything we
have a number of projects in the
laboratory as well so we really are
concerned about contamination between
projects and between different pathogens
so we do a 20-minute bleach um which is
a pretty standard um approach and then
everything is autoclaved for us so all
of our tools are autoclaved or
autoclavable so um yeah and since we're
running pcrs every day um we run enough
controls that we can pick up on things
and then we also if we feel like it we
will use uh 0.1 normal sodium hydroxide
on our lab benches which destroys any
nucleic
acid and we may do it depending upon our
situation I'll do that in our
centrifuges as well um I don't like to
use bleach in the centrifuges or some of
the lab equipment but put 0.1 normal or
0.01 normal sodium hydroxide kills
everything um without killing you or
damaging the
[Laughter]
machines so okay thank you