good afternoon and thank you for the
mckernon family and the organizers for
providing this amazing opportunity to
present today and thank you all for
listening so my name is Deb Kim Ellis
I'm the medical director of forward grow
a cultivation and processing company in
Maryland and I'm also a medical adviser
for pure green and manufacturer of the
tablets I'm about to talk about and I
usually talk about nutrition microbiome
and ruining everybody's lunch but today
I'm going to talk about pain so I'm an
anesthesiologist by Board Certification
and the fact that there are over 110
million people in our country suffering
with chronic pain is troublesome
that's a third of our population and
people are also suffering with
comorbidities associated with chronic
pain including insomnia anxiety and
depression which of course leads to more
pain and the interesting thing about
this is that even though 110 million
people are a lot of people
Big Pharma has really not come up with a
novel pain medicine since the
development of Nappers naproxen sodium
and that was in the 1970s yes there's
modifications of this molecule but there
really has been no new pharmacologic
medication that's safely and reliably
addressing painful conditions and so in
this month's Consumer Reports hardly a
medical journal they tried to summarize
specific pain relieving target options
which they broke down into four
categories acetaminophen NSAIDs opioids
and muscle relaxers and interesting you
know consumers is not a medical journal
they they neglected to mention that
there are some fda-approved medicines
for painful conditions so for
fibromyalgia pregabalin duloxetine and
Milne a sopran and for neuropathic pain
pregabalin and duloxetine however the
rates and successes of this pain
relieving medic
Chin's are variable at best and that
pretty much everything else we prescribe
for pain relief are off-label uses and
what does that mean the anti-epileptics
and the antidepressants that we write
for have are associated with no
double-blind randomized trials
supporting their use nor they
fda-approved for the indication of pain
but we still prescribe them and in fact
one out of every five prescriptions that
we prescribe as physicians are for
off-label use fun fact and commensurate
with the fda-approved medications as
well as the off-label there's a whole
host of side effects and for some reason
they're never good thank you and we
should never underestimate the fact that
patients who take over-the-counter
medicines actually believe that they're
safe and have either minimal or zero
risk which is why of course they believe
it's over the counter and not
prescription however I read a recent
study that said that there's 50 to 80
percent of patients do not take their
medications as prescribed and this is
for prescriptions not over-the-counter
stuff and so I can I can almost
guarantee that nobody reads a label as
evidenced by who here only takes one
ibuprofen for a headache ever right
however there are risks and so we all
are aware of the risk of liver failure
commencement with an overdose of Tylenol
and NSAIDs causing cardiac dysrhythmias
including ibuprofen because most people
take it in prescription doses as well as
the risk of NSAIDs even as taken as
directed on the label of which of course
no one does associated with an increase
in myocardial infarction and now the NIH
has come out with the overdose death
rates from all prescription medicines
and they continue to increase
and then when you take out opiates again
they continue to increase over the years
and these increases in opioid related
deaths is in spite of our country's
leadership declaring that opioid crisis
as a public health emergency so I don't
think that declaration is really doing
much because as the CDC has written that
every day more than a thousand people go
to the emergency room for not using
prescription opioids as directed and so
if we do some math which I'm not a fan
of but if we do anyway
the average visit costs about $1,900
across the country which means that
we're spending 2 million dollars a day
for this indication only and yet a
hundred and fifteen people die each day
from opioid overdose and interestingly I
call this under the category of
unintended consequence beyond all of the
other reasons why there's a rise in
opiate addiction and overdose I found
this in JAMA surgery that basically said
that when they rescheduled hydrocodone
to a schedule two physicians were
writing for more not less pain pills and
so with the exception of bariatric
surgery for every other surgery there
was a statistically significant increase
in pill writing and the reason was
because they couldn't call in
hydrocodone and they didn't want
patients to have to go to an ER or have
to go back to the office to get pain
relief or also to make them so that they
don't look bad because they don't want
to look like they didn't know what to do
so back again to Consumer Reports in
that magazine they said that they're
addressing the possibility of cannabis
as a novel medication for pain relief as
the medical community we should be
ashamed that that consumer reports
actually addresses us first and so I was
troubled as we all are about the opioid
crisis as well as needing solutions for
patients who may or may not have access
to every iteration of cannabis medicine
due to their geography and so I figured
what is it that we can do that is needed
so we need something that's a
give reliable and safe something that's
easy to use to improve compliance so
people take it as directed a reliable
composition so everybody feels
comfortable taking it something that can
be titratable non-intoxicating because
most patients don't want to be sidelined
by their pain but they also don't want
to be sidelined by their pain medicine
and ideally something that's affordable
and so I was given the opportunity to
create a novel pain reliever so I
formulated this CBD at five milligrams
palmitate ethanol um I'd which from now
on will be called peña because that's
too difficult to pronounce
and then terpenes four iterations which
are going to in a sec total of 0.1
milligram in a rapidly dissolvable
sublingual tablet and so why PA well I
believe in the entourage effect and as
an anesthesiologist we use medicine
synergistically we administer a little
bit of many drugs to try to enhance the
positive effects and minimize adverse
effects and at a can med conference in
Boston a couple years ago doctor
Michonne showed a slide of molecules
that he called endocannabinoid like he
said they were naturally occurring that
they are a bioactive and he wondered why
no one was studying them so I quickly
wrote them down in a notebook because
I'm a bit of a geek and I began my
research and what I found was with peña
an endocannabinoid like molecule really
isn't something new it was new to me but
it wasn't new always discovered the
1950s and actually has been used for
pain relief by itself albeit at higher
concentrations and for those of you that
don't know PA is a fatty acid amide like
it's endocannabinoid relatives has a
complex multimodal mechanism of action
it activates intracellular nuclear and
membrane-associated receptors and
regulates many physiologic functions
related to the inflammatory cascade and
chronic pain states so for example it
directly targets people are alpha GP or
55 GP you are 119 it indirectly affects
CB 1 and 2 receptors through enhancing
and and
through the entourage effect by
competing with Fah pe a down modulates
math cell activation inhibits release of
inflammatory mass L mediators histamine
and TNF alpha and mast cells are often
found near sensory endings sensory nerve
endings and their degranulation can
enhance the nociceptive signal and the
reason why peripheral mass cells are
considered to be pro-inflammatory and
pro nociceptive so this just skims the
surface of PE A's magical and
complicated mechanism of action and how
it can play a role in mitigating pain
however I found this incredibly
interesting so we combine PE a CBD and
for terpenes beta carefully and humulin
mercian and little all in a rapidly
dissolvable sublingual tablet the goal
was to treat mild to moderate pain to
compete with tylenol and ibuprofen
I actually didn't believe this was gonna
work i trialed it first on me and then
on 16 patients nine females seven males
a meaning age 50 3.2 patients had a
variety of painful conditions back in
neck P North rightous musculoskeletal
neuropathic dysmenorrhea in one person
had a hangover during the trial and then
we used the Wong Baker of pain scale for
easy reading and so the average
pretreatment pain scale score was five
point one three after one tablet the
average pain score dropped to two that's
more than half in 20 minutes or less the
score dropped again to omotte but almost
by half to one point two five in another
20 minutes and then again to 0.44 after
an hour and then two hours dropped to
0.25 and this was statistically
significant and this is a graph of the
individual pain scale scores for every
patient and this was the average score
over two hours and this formulation
approximates the onset of traditional
mild to moderate pain relievers hours a
little bit faster we didn't officially
check beyond two hours because it
and I really didn't think this was going
to work but we did ask patients to take
down notes as to when their pain
returned most documented somewhere
between four and six hours and two
people claimed that with a single tablet
it lasted 24 hours and so of course we
worry about side effects right so we
want to make sure everything is safe a
survey of the literature looked at the
side effects of peña and there are no
reports of severe adverse reactions and
in fact the rate of adverse events are
even less than placebo in a double-blind
study and so we're all understanding the
favorable safety profile of CBD and
right that's why we're here today so now
we're actually looking at this with an
expanded study multi-site and if
anybody's out there in a legal state
that wants to participate please see me
afterwards and the preliminary results
seemed to mirror the prior study and so
the medical statement has always been
first do no harm but the question is how
so perhaps dr. McCollum Consumer Reports
and all of us here today have
illuminated a path and I thank you and I
really beat the clock it's I'm from
Jersey so I speak quickly and if anyone
has any questions I'd be great yes sir
when use the pain the reason the number
of pain patients the United States do
you know if any of a lot of the states
that allow for medical marijuana
classify pain as a kind of catch-all
condition and I'm wondering if that
affects that statistic I think they do I
actually think they do classify it as a
single like pain I don't think they
break it down in neuro Pathak or
whatever although I did see Studies at
the majority of the pain conditions the
top two or back pain and the second one
is neuropathic pain thank you I just
wanted to ask if you could suss out the
neuropathic pain responses from others
other types of pain so we didn't do it
we had a couple patients with
neuropathic pain and their pain was
reduced significantly didn't go away
completely but theirs was the less steep
of the curves but we are going to do
that study there's somebody you
mentioned for terpenes very quickly
could you please repeat those and then
my second question is is this tablet and
a CBD isolate is it derived from
industrial hemp or is it derived from
therapeutic so the four cannabinoids or
beta carry awfully no Moline little
immersing the CB is CBD is isolated from
a cannabis plant so not hemp I'm
wondering what if any are previously
known uses of PE a that may have
inspired this at all so pain
predominantly and works in metabolic
issues as well but the studies that I
researched it's quite the comprehensive
but they use PE a lot for for pain
mitigation and inflammation and then a
follow-up are you guys working on any
alternate formulations absolutely thank
you thanks for your talk Deb is this
available to patients now it is so the
companies out of Michigan and
we can talk about that another time but
yes absolutely the CBD iteration they
ship across state line and is the DEA is
that something you can eat is it enough
food so pH but we make it and plants
make it and people use it as a
nutritional supplement and you can eat
it and you know take it as pain medicine
three minutes so the the study you were
talking about the multi-site study that
you're doing yes I might have missed
something but is it do you have a
control is it randomizers it's just like
a single arm study where you're just
right now it's a single arm study to for
real proof of concept I mean sixteen
patients is you know is interesting but
doesn't really speak to everything so
first step is to to do a proof of
concept to expand that one and then
ultimately will develop a placebo which
should be pretty easy and then do a
double-blind randomized trial and what
is the advantage of deriving your CBD
from marijuana rather than hemp without
so the advantage is that the company in
Michigan has access to a lot of cannabis
Drive CBD and so therefore that a lot of
people who clapped here probably believe
that there are molecules that go along
with it that when you do extraction and
so from the cannabis plant is a little
bit different from the hemp plant if
it's a complete isolate CBD is a
molecule CBD CBD but thank you for your
work thank you have you done the pain
test with adjust PA tablets without the
CBD to see results I have not but there
are lots of studies out there that have
shown it but it's at 300 milligram to
1200 milligram a day again this is why I
didn't think it was going to work
because it ours is just a hundred
milligrams but I again I'm I thinking
about the entourage effect with the CBD
in combination with the PA in the
terpenes speaking of the entourage
effect how many different strains of
cannabis are you Carol
testing these with I'm sure I said it
again are you using one strain of
cannabis to test this with your
medication or multiple types in it too
hominy right so know that they had one
purveyor of cannabis and it was one
strand that the extraction was made from
good question and good thought I like
where you're going with that there's
there's major differences absolutely
anything else great thank you so much
for your attention