foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the cam Med conference
have you gotten your invitation to cam
med23 yet if not then head over to
canmedevents.com now and request your
invitation
yes cammed 23 is an invitation only
event this year due to the limited
capacity at our new location the
Marriott Marco Island Beach Resort
that's not to say it'll be a small event
cam Med 23 will feature three full days
of cannabis science content including
more than 30 presenters and instructors
representing our key Focus areas science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
and new for cam med23 we will also
explore psilocybin and psychedelic
mushrooms check out all the latest
information about cambed 23 at
kammanevents.com and I hope to see you
there
this episode we talked to Dr Allison
Justice Allison is founder and CEO of
the hemp mine a 30-acre hemp Farm in
South Carolina that supplies premium
hemp genetics bread in-house across the
U.S
the hemp mine produces a wide array of
consumer products ranging from smokable
flour to topicals to tinctures of
different concentrations for both humans
and animals
Allison also co-founded the Cannabis
research Coalition a professional group
dedicated to addressing the cultivation
and post-harvest issues that challenge
today's cannabis industry
Allison recently co-authored an article
in cannabis Science and Technology
titled reading the leaves adventures in
the leaf level physiology of cannabis
which takes a deeper look into how
cannabis plants respond to light and CO2
during our conversation we discuss the
difference in cannabis photosynthesis
rates during vegetative and flowering
stages the possibility that during
flowering leaves in the Cannabis flower
take over photosynthesis from the fan
leaves
why cannabis Growers may want to reduce
light intensity and duration six weeks
into flower
and conversely how maximizing light
during flour can increase yield but
reduce quality
and possible varietal differences in
photosynthesis rates
before we get to my conversation with
Allison I want to thank this episode
sponsor cannabis Science and Technology
cannabis science and technology is your
educational resource for all things on
the legal cannabis industry it covers
the latest developments and Trends in
analytical testing quality control and
Assurance extraction cultivation and
processing and Manufacturing
the brand furnishes all this information
into a monthly print magazine and also
on their website that includes webcasts
ebooks podcasts and more
you can subscribe for free on cannabis
sciencetech.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Allison
Justice
[Music]
good afternoon Allison thanks so much
for joining us on the podcast
course of course so I came across your
article that you co-authored in cannabis
Science and Technology titled reading
the leaves adventures in the leaf level
physiology of cannabis and I also saw
the conversation that took place on the
LinkedIn post that you did to share that
article and I thought it'd be a great
topic to discuss on the podcast not only
because the research is valuable to
Growers but also because it's a good
example of something that we've talked
about a lot on the podcast and at can
Med which is this whole idea of
we're seeing researchers use the science
to explain some things that Legacy
Growers have learned through experience
but before we get too deep into that
please explain what it is you did with
this project and some of the key
findings that came out of it
yeah so
a project
would like
like lycor is a bioscience company that
makes all sorts of really cool unique
tools to
you know take a plant and understand
what's going on on the leaf level or
even sometimes on the cellular level
they have tools that do plants they have
tools that even go underwater and uh and
measure photosynthesis for underwater
plants and and so
you know this was a project I was
extremely excited about
um
when when Jason and Rod called me and
you know they wanted to
to get some measurements on cannabis
um I was completely excited
um you know using one of these tools you
know you could totally say that's a grad
student's dream come true
um because it really takes you know the
theoretical and let you see on a science
level with math and equations and you
know being able to understand what goes
in what comes out and make
conclusions from there is just really
exciting you know these tools are very
intricate you know they can be difficult
to use
um not difficult to use just uh tricky
and you really have to understand what
it is you're looking for so you know
it's not a tool for every grower it's
not a tool for every large corporation
you know this we tried to make it very
clear in the article it wasn't a sales
pitch by any means because these tools
are
mostly made for researchers
universities and and people that that
take it a a step further you know people
that really enjoy plant physiology and
and understanding uh photosynthesis but
the thing is you know the conclusion
here is taking
all of the information we find as
researchers
and applying it to
um you know everyday learnings of what
happens in a grow room
um and I you know this is a very very
you know high level for this type of
research because you know it was done
with data collected you know only for
two days
tons more needs to be done for this and
in different ways and we can talk about
some of those different methods that I
would like to do on a repeat trial
but I think this just kind of brings up
some topics that
we can take and and and further further
do research but then also start to
compare to you know what of what of the
Legacy growner Growers done for so long
and why you know everything from
um you know increasing CO2 levels you
know that's not it's not done just for
fun we understand that that goes to
speeding up photosynthesis and which
ultimately increases yields which
ultimately increases dollars so it all
plays together it's just not necessarily
a tool
um a grower would use it's something
that we need to take these findings and
apply it and you know bring science into
the community
excellent so in looking again looking at
your LinkedIn post there were like three
bullet points that were sort of the key
points that came out of your research
and if you don't have that in front of
you I have it written down so I can read
it up
um but the first one being
um that cannabis has one of the highest
rates of photosynthesis and you said
it's up there with corn so
um was that a surprising finding was
that something that you kind of expected
and you know and what does that mean
practically for a grower
so corn corn and I believe sunflower two
of the
um
two plants that have the highest rates
of photosynthesis
um and you know everybody driving down
the road you can see how fast the corn
grows how aggressively if it's watered
um
you know these plants are just monsters
and very good at assimilation and and
understanding or or the capability of a
you know turning CO2 into plant material
basically a biomass
um and you know cannabis is a tricky
plant
um you know I've always known that as a
as a vegetative plant it can handle
great extremes
um you know our Greenhouse there's been
times it's the fans have failed and it
gets you know 150 in the greenhouse and
the vegetative plants are just fine as
long as they have water
um
you know I've seen cold temperatures
under freezing and the plants are okay
but when you talk about a flowering
plant they're a lot more finicky
um and and what this data shows is
is kind of why and puts uh puts data to
me just saying they're finicky
um
because they can't they can't handle the
the extremes as much as the vegetative
plants do
so I think we all know that that
cannabis in general is a is a beast you
know it grows very fast very
aggressively
um
so this just shows yeah it's up there
with corn
yeah and that's interesting so is the is
the hypothesis that the plant is using
so much energy or so much resources into
creating flour that it becomes more
susceptible to stresses
I believe so
looking at the data
I imagine you'll put the the link in
where people can read it themselves but
so you know if you were to look at
figure two and three both of these
describe
you know two different processes of why
the flowering plants are
are less suited to deal with
problems than vegetative plants
um
so as far as looking at photosynthesis
carbon allocation so you know taking
taking the CO2 and the air and turning
it into biomass again
um and then looking at different light
intensities even though that light is
there the flowering plant
basically throws it away and so you'll
see in figure two non-photo chemical
quenching and all that means is that
when the plant takes it in
or when the when it comes to the plant
instead of absorbing it to to go through
photosynthesis it basically throws it
away in a form of heat
and so
um you know looking at these graphs the
flowering plant
has a much higher level of
non-photochemical quenching than the
vegetative plants
so
um plant basically all it says is
vegetative plants can take up just about
as much light as you could give them
whereas the flowering plants throw it
away
in layman terms and so you know this
really makes you think about well for an
indoor setting where you can control
what's going on because this was done on
on a field crop you know it makes you
think well is there is there reason at
certain points during the flowering
cycle to provide less light because it's
not actually using it
um
and you know
I I know a lot of Legacy Growers at the
last couple of weeks of flower they they
turned down the lights turned down the
temperatures
um and this could act absolutely be one
aspect of that
um
but then as was brought up on LinkedIn
well maybe this is just
considering that the leaves because keep
in mind this measurement is done on a
leaf
you know it's one
basically centimeter spot on a leaf you
know a point in time
um or maybe those leaves
are not photosynthesizing as much
during those later times and flower but
the the leaves within the uh the flower
material is actually taking over from
there
um and you know you kind of if you think
about the life cycles and what you
notice and especially in the field where
nutrients you know we we amend the soil
we add you know flowable liquid
nutrients through the irrigation system
but still it's hard to really provide
everything the plant needs in a field
setting
um and so
so especially in in a field setting
where you do not have adequate nutrients
or quite as much for the most part
towards later and flower you'll notice a
lot of leaf yellowing and so it's the
it's those older leaves that are are
yellowing you know eventually fall off
well you know there there's a reason for
that and that's because it's the leaves
then are becoming a a source for that
floral material so you know basically
just uh moving those nutrients out of
the old leaves and and moving that
energy towards the flower
um
and so
you know even indoors I've seen this
happen
um and you know the most likely that's
an effect of of nutrient but
what it really tells me is that it's a
shift then from
photosynthesizing potentially
potentially from photosynthesizing in
the leaf to that floral material really
taking over
um you know another way to kind of look
at this and kind of conclude that
um again a lot more work needs to be
done to have this as the exact
conclusion but if you think about the
folks who really stripped the leaves off
the plants yeah
I was going to bring that up I wrote I
wrote down lollipopping because yeah
yeah yeah so those who lollipop or you
know the the old two node what node and
Flip or where they really strip the
plants you know coming into the industry
um a while back I saw that and I was
like oh my God you know you're you're
pulling off its solar panels to an
extreme but you know I have seen an
incredible yields
when when plants are stripped you know
just as good if if not better than some
that are not stripped
um and so this definitely could
contribute to the leaves not doing as
much work than as as the flower and
cannabis is a is an interesting plant
because you know the flower is green
when you think of other plants there's
not a lot of photosynthesis going on I
mean there's no chloroplast there so um
I think that all kind of jobs together
to lend towards you know one you you
certainly could could cut the light down
but two you know is it really that
flower taking over and this kind of
leads to you know the desire I have for
another experiment
um
hopefully not too long from now is
basically taking
um doing these sorts of measurement in a
chamber
um so where everything that goes in is
measured everything that goes out is
measured what's changed inside is
measured and you can
um really really understand what's going
on with the flower not just this one one
leaf on one plant
interesting
yeah and you know one of the things that
stood out too when you were taking us
through figure two and talking about how
when you get into flowering that the
leaves not absorbing that light anymore
it's sort of giving off heat and I
wonder in an indoor setting is that
something that's more commonly seen like
when you have plants that are in
flowering is the room warmer
that's an interesting thought
um
hmm
so if you're maximizing
the light that it can take up
is it actually enough to heat the room
that's a good quite you know I would I
wouldn't think so uh okay
that that would
this is such you know micro units that
these plants are putting out I would
guess not but that's definitely
something I'm going to double check all
right sounds good and so yeah in you
know one of the conclusions that could
be made from this and you mentioned that
some of the Legacy Growers may already
be doing it is that it's it sounds like
and based on your your paper in the post
too that after six weeks of flowering
you might be able to either back off the
intensity of the light or just even
shorten the duration of the light or
both is that the idea
yeah yeah and you know again because the
plant is throwing away
um these photons that that you're paying
for in an indoor setting you know it
would it would make a lot of sense to do
that
um
you know even if the floral material is
taking over for a lot of that
photosynthesis that's happening
happening
um if you think about I guess square
footage of the leaves versus square
footage of the flowers
um if you were to take the leaves off
there's less less square footage if that
makes sense
um of the flower material so they would
have to really be making up for the
leaves so I I would my theory would be
that you could back off you know it's
still photosynthesizing but I think you
could certainly back off those last
weeks
um but but other things I've noticed
you know they kind of give a thumbs up
to backing off on the lights is is
really the quality
um
I've seen people gosh I've seen people
in the last two weeks actually go to 24
hours light
and just you know pump them full pop
them full of photons
um and in certain settings I have seen
that increase yield
but the flowers look terrible you know
they start throwing out little fingers
and as far as being a nice quality for
smokable flower you know it pretty much
ruins it but if you were just growing
these for extract which I'd imagine not
many people are indoors at least those
those top nice flowers
um you know it would make it unsellable
um you know the other thing is the the
really high light intensity
I I have seen that really and one thing
we should look at is looking at the
trichome heads and is that highlight
intensity
basically speeding up uh
the the process of going from the clear
to the Milky to Amber is it just
speeding that up or is the high light
intensity causing that color change
um because like I said I've seen people
be applying 1200 micro moles like
and you know the plants almost look
burned especially you know the the
higher the higher colas that are closest
to the light so you know there certainly
could be
there certainly could be Merit to to
cutting the lights off the last couple
of weeks oh and then to add to that the
the last thought for
um that procedure would really be you
know are you whether you're cutting
lights off or or providing low
temperatures you know are you are you
sending this plant earlier to
um
to ripeness you know is it doing
something in the flower that we
certainly haven't measured yet but that
contributes to a to a cure or to an
aspect you know decreasing chlorophyll
something that makes the plant taste you
know taste better
um the you know I I can't say I doubt
that definitely could be right
no and do you think that this whole the
do you think the idea of the plant
needing less light later in the later
stages of its life it's I mean that sort
of mimics natural conditions right it's
an annual plant and they're finishing in
the fall like like it is now where the
days are shorter and there's less light
to to use right yeah I mean in nature
that's that's what they get you know
between the the daylight and
temperatures you know that all lends to
the plant
basically saying let's hurry up uh
Winter's coming we need to flower and
produce Seed where our species keeps
going
so yeah I mean
it certainly makes sense to me
um and and this data
suggests it so I think with
with some other universities other
experiments jumping in we can we can
definitely say at least in the varieties
we test
because there's certainly varietal
differences um
I haven't seen that with with many
aspects whether we're talking nutrients
or like you know CO2 all other things
yeah and that was one of the things
mentioned in the paper I think it was
with the uh your co-author there Jason
was was mentioning that in other crops
that
this sort of this sort of study in this
sort of data has been generated not just
on the species level but on the varietal
or in our case The Strain or the
cultivar level because there are going
to be differences throughout so
um yeah that's that's a great point that
you know this was just done on one
variety over two days so there's a lot
more that that we can learn
absolutely yeah these tools are used for
breeding projects you know
whether Monsanto or whoever out there is
breeding corn
um those scientists definitely use these
tools
um
because you know when you're breeding
you can certainly measure yield versus
the inputs you give it
but you can't necessarily
you can't necessarily tell how how
strong photosynthesis is without these
tools I mean you can have an estimate
again based off of yield but this this
certainly gives a deeper insight and a
good tool for breeding
yeah and to that point about sort of on
the varietal level I I know that in the
paper that
you also identified a phosphate
limitation in the plants that you were
looking at now is that something that's
sort of specific to the strains that you
were looking at or is that something
that can be more applied broadly
yeah so that was an aspect of my field
a minute as best we can
um and and each year it gets better and
better you know making acres and Acres
just right absolutely takes time
um but no that that's certainly an
aspect of my plants being uh phosphorus
deficient
um and so that showed up it certainly
showed up it shows up on my uh my
Elemental Leaf tests it shows up in the
the soil tests and this absolutely
concluded that
got it so okay
um and so
I guess kind of in general
is there anything that stood out to you
or really surprised you
um with the data that you collected with
this project
yeah the the the phosphorus aspect that
was that was something else you know uh
when when the lycor team told me this I
was like well that's probably right but
you know I I need to jump back into the
literature you know it's been a long
time since I've had to sit down and
remember all of the pathways
um for photosynthesis and you know why
you know put together the pieces of you
know
um phosphate limitation and where that
plugs in in the photosynthesis cycle
um but yeah I mean it once I dug back
into it it absolutely makes sense
so I I can give the uh the the Layman's
description of of why why phosphorus in
general
is needed to produce good flowers or or
good flowers
because
the more photosynthesis the greater
yields
um but also just in in general with with
a good growing plant
um so you know the takeaway there is you
think about go back to biology and and
high school or whatnot you know CO2 goes
in
um the plant deals with that through an
enzyme
called rubisco
from there it's converted to sugar
to do this sugar conversion process
there has to be a phosphate attached
well if the phosphate is not there
the plant is continuing to bring in CO2
but there's a backup so there's a
traffic jam and so you know your plant's
not getting those sugars that they want
to grow and to thrive and so instead
instead of photosynthesis it turns to
photorespiration where
um it's not taking up CO2 anymore it's
taking up O2 and so O2 plugs in there
and basically it it wastes
um so the the energy the CO2 is
converted to something else
um instead of going through the cycle it
won't it should go through which makes
those sugars
so it creates oxygen instead is that
what you're saying well it takes up
oxygen instead of super two okay yeah so
it plugs in there instead of the CO2
interesting no and that's I mean again
going back to Layman's biology we're
always taught you know the plant it
takes sunlight and converts it into
energy but you forget that there's other
nutrients that are that need to be
involved to make that process happen too
and that's that's coming from your soil
or if you're growing from Hydro the
nutrients that you're adding in there
exactly yeah I mean me as a
non-scientist I've only recently come to
that conclusion after attempting to grow
cannabis myself with
with so-so results
so
so we started talking about this where
you know we were hoping to
through this research give some some
practical information to Growers that
that they can use so I guess as we're
winding down what are some of those
things that they can apply based on on
what you've learned here
understanding
everything you do to these plants are
inputs and if it's not balanced
one input would be a waste all right so
let me give an example of that
if you have a grow room
and
everything is perfect except fertilizer
say you you have a you have a organic
fertilizer you have an organic soil and
maybe you haven't supplemented it
properly so you're you're limiting
something well
let's say your temperatures are right
your humidity is right and you're giving
it 1500 parts per million CO2
well because of those nutrients being
off
you're basically just wasting your CO2
because
going back to the phosphorus and then
there's other processes in the plant
that you know it won't be the same cycle
of photosynthesis process and phosphorus
processes but there's other processes if
you don't have those individual elements
um or 16 essential nutrients then all of
that CO2 you're adding is just wasted it
might help a little
um but levels you know well over ambient
like 1500 1800 it's just a wasteful
input
um so understanding that you need all of
these pieces
to be optimal to really increase your
yields and and put out a good plant
yeah and that comes back to the to the
light too right like you said that's
it's very expensive running these lights
especially of course indoors it's what
we're talking about but you know and if
that's being wasted and you would
actually be better off dialing those
back then that's I mean that's a win-win
exactly exactly all right Allison so
again winding down before I let you go I
did want to give you a chance to plug
any
um any other Publications you have out
there that you want people to to be
aware of or check out or any you know
social media or websites that people can
check out to learn more about you and
the work that you're doing please plug
away
hello
of course from on my LinkedIn you can
see a lot of the Articles I've put out
um
you can follow me on Instagram
[Music]
um it's Dr dot Justice underscore grows
um I usually at least give some sort of
reference to to new work we put out
and then of course we'd love to have you
join the CRC the Cannabis research
Coalition this is a a farmer industry
funded group to support the hemp mine
and Clemson University put out
um really important grower relevant
research so nothing we we may include
neat tools like this in our research but
our goal is to then take that research
and and put it to something that can be
immediately used by The Growers so
um you know everything from looking at
different types of oxen for rooting to
understanding well you know with a
certain variety what happens if instead
of being just 12 12 you move to 13 hours
of flight you know that's one extra hour
of all of those photons you know
you know how can that benefit you
um so research like that that's that's
extremely relevant
um we have a website we just Google
cannabis research Coalition and it'll
pop right up
excellent yeah I'd love the CRC and
hoping to see a good representation from
the group uh at can Med absolutely we'll
be there yeah it'll be fantastic I know
you're helping out on The Advisory Board
and we're very happy to have you and um
again happy to have you on the podcast
as well so thanks again Allison and um
if I don't talk to you before then we'll
see you down at Marco Island all right
see you there
foreign
[Music]
Justice check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor cannabis Science
and Technology our next episode drops
November 9th that's two weeks from today
in the meantime please do check out the
new and improved canmanevents.com the
team really did an exceptional job
updating the website with all the
information about our camid 23 event and
of course you can still find videos of
all the previous can Med presentations
and panels and the can bed archive you
can also find all the previous episodes
of the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this Innovative industry-leading
event I also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on Instagram Facebook Twitter and
Linkedin just search for canvid events
and lastly please leave us a review on
Apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us on
the next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]
foreign