[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud M of the
team that puts on the camed Summit the
camed 25 speaker lineup is up on camed
events.com along with our preliminary
schedule we do have a stellar lineup
this year including some familiar names
some returning presenters and some new
faces as well they'll all be in Puerto
Rico this June for the camed 25
Innovation and investment Summit and you
can join them for a fraction of the full
price if you register before February
19th which is our early bird deadline
all the information is up at camat
events.com and I hope to see you this
June Our Guest today is Dr Michelle
peace Michelle is an internationally
recognized forensic
toxicologist and a full professor in the
department of forensic Sciences at
Virginia Commonwealth
University she has been funded by the
National Institute of Justice to study
the proliferation of semisynthetic THC
analoges in the unregulated market and
Define their relevant
biomarkers her work impacts public
health and Public Safety policies and
initiatives at caned 25 Michelle will
present why some people green out the
analysis of unregulated hemp derived
cannabis
products her team study uses a liquid
chromatography tandem spectrometry
method to analyze unregulated hemp
products and she found that all products
that they analized were mislabeled in
some way either misrepresenting the
cannabinoids contained therein or their
concentrations during our conversation
we discussed what has caused the rise of
semisynthetic cannabinoids in the
marketplace how Michelle got involved in
testing unregulated hemp and cannabis
products some of the Adverse Events that
have occurred from consuming
semi-synthetic
cannabinoids how the lsms method allows
Michelle's team to see compounds other
labs can't how consumers can protect
themselves from mislabeled products and
whether Federal legalization of cannabis
would eliminate the semisynthetic market
before we get to my conversation with
Michelle I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor preach
biotech preach biotech Corporation is a
vertically integrated company dedicated
to the cultivation manufacturer and
dispensing of medicinal cannabis in
Puerto Rico with over 500,000 square fet
of state-of-the-art facilities preach
uses the highest standards of
agricultural and Manufacturing practices
to guarantee the highest standard of
medicinal cannabis their mission is to
offer a natural and unique experience
through medicinal cannabis that raises
the patients well-being and quality of
life learn more at preach biotech.com
and preach is spelled p r i
c okay and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Dr
Michelle peace
[Music]
good afternoon Michelle thanks so much
for joining me on the podcast I know
thank you for having me Ben I'm really
excited for the conversation I'm excited
for the conversation and I'd like to say
that we're excited to have you as an
oral presenter at camed 25 we announced
the lineup just last week and I might be
biased here but I think it's one of the
strongest lineups we've ever had it's a
great mix of familiar names and new
faces and if I'm not mistaken you are a
new face have you attended a canmed
event before I haven't I'm really
excited to uh to be able to attend so
that I can learn from you know this this
side of the community um and also be a
part of the conversations about you know
how do we help consumers uh be safe and
still address health issues along the
way so um I'm really excited to be able
to attend and present so thank you
absolutely and I expect that your talk
is going to be well attended since it
covers a very Hot Topic in the industry
right now which is semisynthetic
cannabinoids or hemp derived
cannabinoids there's more than one
presentation touching on the topic and
we're also working on putting together a
panel discussion about it which I'm
hoping you can participate on as well so
per perhaps for those who aren't
familiar could you give us a quick
primer on the current situation with
semisynthetic or hemp derived canabo
what are they how are they made and why
are they seemingly everywhere these days
why are they everywhere yeah so um we
the hemp
derived semisynthetic compounds that we
see that are so popular in the
marketplace um we believe really was
given birth uh because of the explosion
of the production of
CBD and because H the CBD Marketplace
really reached Market
saturation um you of course it lost it
then lost value it's a it's a pretty
simple supply and demand uh business
model so to speak um and so when you're
not making as much money with that
product or you've got excess stores of
it sitting around that just gets harder
to um to sell then you know then we
believe that manufacturers thought about
well what can we do with what we have um
to then also push the marketplace
because the uh the
2018 Farm Bill the agricultural
Improvement act um you know has a lot of
very broad language in it
and so um because of that broad language
uh it
manufacturers had the space to be able
to um produce these other compounds from
CBD uh and so through fairly
straightforward chemical processes you
can make an array of analogues that look
like CBD or t delta9
THC uh and and so you know there was the
scientific literature actually
explained how to do this how to um how
to make some of these uh chemical
reactions to make um other kinds of
cannabinoids uh and so um just slightly
tweaking some of those
foundational uh chemical reactions can
lead to an array of different products
uh and so what we wind up having now is
um there are you know places on that
molecular structure of tetrahydro
canaban uh that can be
modified and let's say that's three
different regions on that molecule well
if you've got you know um any any
Arrangement that is in those three areas
you you are going to be able to create
hundreds of different kinds of analoges
from that right because there's three
places that that molecule right now can
be modified so and modified easily so
you know so when you take a look at
those three areas and you modify each of
those sections you've got um uh an array
of compounds that can be manufactured
from that uh and so because there is
looseness in the Farm building language
um and because uh there has been some
confusion as to what these compounds are
um from a regulatory perspective from a
legal perspective um that has just
allowed while we lay in that confusion
then the marketplace has just been able
to um be as creative as they possibly
can be nobody's really uh
monitoring the the um the quality of
these products so um so there's a lot of
space and when as a forensic scientist
what I know is that when there
is um space left in regulatory language
uh then nefarious activity will take
place you know and I'm not saying
everybody who has entered in this space
is has nefarious intentions I'm not
saying that there are certainly some
players in this industry who
are generating maybe quality
products uh for reasons to help
consumers um but at the end of the day I
still don't believe from my perspective
in the hundreds if not thousands of
products that we've
evaluated that we can still trust what
is in these
products so um so I think at the end of
the day you know I think that there's a
lot of Nefarious activity because you
know it's an easy way to make money uh
without
oversight right so now you mentioned the
broad language of the farm bill has sort
of opened the door for for this to
happen now if I understand correctly is
it the fact that it only specifies Delta
9 THC as being being sort of the um sort
of the band canav or or the one that's
um that determines whether it's it's
hemp or cannabis yeah I think that's
part of the problem certainly is uh you
know that at the time that the farm bill
was written you know there was just
concern about that singular compound uh
and it's placed in uh the dea's control
Substances Act on schedule one right uh
and so because that is the named
compound um then uh it's it's you you
there's place for other compounds to
exist right and so like you said you
have all these manufacturers or farmers
are sitting on this glut of CBD which
was really what seemed to be um the
intention of the farm bill was to kind
of you know create a Marketplace for CBD
D um which then got saturated and so
they had to get creative with how do we
turn this into a different compound or
well I would even say was that really
the intention of the farm bill probably
not the marketplace no the intention of
the farm bill was to allow people to
grow hemp and to grow hemp for non
pharmaceutical purposes right uh right
because you know I don't know from
t-shirts to bed sheets to animal betting
right so um you know so I think that was
the original intent of the of the
marketplace um you know we certainly
have seen Nationwide we definitely have
seen it here in Virginia where the
language was used in the process
of of of
Virginia wrestling with uh the Virginia
code and what are we what are we going
to um legalize or not how are we going
to do that you know there were
definitely lobbyists who got up and said
we want to do this because we're making
rope not dope and you know at the end of
the day everybody really knew that they
wanted to goow hemp to be able to
extract CBD from it so you know so I I
think that uh the intention of the farm
bill was to allow Farmers a pathway to
grow another kind of crop um and uh and
you know we need to close up those
loopholes excellent okay so I was hoping
you could you explain sort of what
motivated you to start studying these uh
these cannabinoids in these compounds
and their their implications yeah so um
there's actually um a long Arc to it uh
so I'm funded by the National Institute
of Justice I've been funded by them
since 200
14 uh to evaluate electronic cigarettes
and how they can be used and manipulated
to um Vape drugs other than
nicotine and you know I'll be honest we
always thought that THC and cannabis was
low hanging fruit we thought somebody's
going to do this we don't really need to
be in the space um we were really
concerned originally and still are about
people putting methamphetamine and
cocaine and fill and you know um their
anti-anxiety medication we were
concerned about how they were going to
use ecigarettes to bake those kinds of
compounds um and what implications it
had in the criminal justice system uh
and so what we really began monitoring
was the nature of the unregular Rel ated
nicotine ecigarette Marketplace so we
came uh we came to
really
um paint the picture of what was
happening in that unregulated space and
how it was creating problems for
consumers uh in addition to how do you
use them to vape other drugs and
somebody sent us
a um a
THC uh vape and they said surely this
isn't
THC so uh and it was labeled as 75% THC
something like that and when we analyzed
it it was really more like 40%
THC that's still a lot of
THC but we thought oh this is the same
thing is going to happen in the Cannabis
industry is what we're seeing in the
nicotine industry because we had
already published on and was
characterizing nicotine Vapes so the
unregulated ones you can't trust what's
on that package either in terms of the
nicotine concentration so that's really
what set us off to uh now we're now now
the industry has my attention right so
we started monitoring the quality of
those products and we saw sorry not not
to cut you off the these are the
unregulated products yeah unregulated
got it so we saw the Cannabis
industry use the consumers as their test
market for products so we saw the
chemical profiles of vaping products
evolve pretty
rapidly um and uh and then you know
we're watching the CBD Marketplace as
well and analyzing those products too
which also you couldn't trust the um the
quality of those products either and
then we received a a product from
somebody who said listen I can I I
consume a lot of canvas and this Vape is
not
canvis they sent it to us and we found a
really dangerous synthetic canavan oid
um five floro
ad and so we that was the moment we
realized Yep this nobody's monitoring
this it's not regulated um enforcement
is awful uh in the states that do have
regulations um so now the industry has
our full attention and uh and so we I
there was a pretty
public um
debate uh after we published that paper
where we found the five floro ADB in a
CBD product um that was marketed as safe
for
children and so we didn't re what was
the unintended consequence of that very
public debate right in the media
from uh the New York Times to Consumer
Reports AARP re etc etc um we started
receiving products from people who were
having Adverse Events from taking a
cannabis product so we started analyzing
those and realizing that um a that for a
certain period of time all of the
products were either mislabeled or
contained a synthetic
canav
so we're watching the CB Marketplace in
terms of you know what's happening with
this now over Supply that's being
generated
and uh we we saw the Delta 8 THC hit the
marketplace and we do a lot of
surveillance shopping and secret
shopping so I went into a
store uh to see if Delta 8 phc was in my
community commun and so I walked in and
there was a there was almost a line out
the door by Delta 8
THC and um in order to manage the crowd
uh the store clerk said we need you to
read this this document that was taped
to the display case and it had an
outright lie about the nature of delta8
on it and this say Delta 8 is like CBD h
and uh and I thought that's
fantastically dangerous uh and right
because it
underscores uh the ability of the
industry to outright lie about the
compounds so we started then uh
acquiring the Delta 8 products and then
we saw Delta 10 in the marketplace and
and 6A 10A so we started seeing some of
these and then I received a
case um that in which the consumer
had
such strong adverse event I mean
outright disassociation and
hallucinations and
paranoia that he committed a egregious
fing and now he's facing criminal
charges and life in prison
and uh and so uh the the I received the
product that he consumed and that's when
we
identified uh thco
acetate and then started seeing all of
the misinformation and disinformation
about phco acetate so now I am
fully I am fully committed now
to monitoring this emerging
Marketplace so um we are uh now funded
by the National Institute of
Justice to monitor the
marketplace develop methods to analyze
for all of the analoges that are in the
marketplace
currently and uh and then also assess
you know how do how
Prime labs and hospital clinical labs
and like for people who are having
Adverse Events you need to properly
attribute what that adverse event is to
so um so now and we do surveillance
shopping so that's why the ni has
currently funded us to specifically look
at these THC analoges and how they
penetrated different Market places um
and how do you analyze for them so
that's a long story as to how I got
invested but um but I think there are it
has points in there as to what happens
when nobody's
watching yeah for for sure and I did
want to ask you more sort of about these
Adverse Events that folks are
experiencing before they sort of reach
out or send those products to you uh for
analysis so you mentioned the
thco acetate as being one of the more
harmful cannabinoids as well so so me
you might be able to you know shed some
light on what are sort of the most uh
concerning of these canabo and what sort
of Adverse Events are they
producing um well so let's start with
the kinds of Adverse Events that we're
seeing um you know from a physiological
perspective you know from the point of
view from what's Happening to the body
and the body
organs um we're definitely seeing
you know um respiratory problems cardiac
problems um you know that are uh
certainly
disconcerting at best and
life-threatening at
worst um we from a this cognitive
behavioral perspective you know we see
where um you know people are
they have extreme
paranoia um they are dissociating from
their body uh they're having severe
hallucinations um terrifying
hallucinations um so you know when you
take all of that into
consideration um you know these can be
life altering um you know we've
certainly had cases in my lab in which
the person is affected has been affected
after consuming one of
these years later are still having
significant problems had have had two
cases in in which somebody reported
having
seizures um you know there was one case
here in Richmond Virginia where um a uh
somebody purchased a product and was at
an outdoor comp concert uh and had a
seizure uh and they had to stop the
concert and get her um medical attention
uh and took her to the hospital so um
you know and this was an unregulated
product that she purchased in a
shop and you know and you know to to
paint the you don't know what's going to
happen you know the claim was that that
same joint
was shared with two other
people and the other two people did not
have a
seizure so you know so this is part of
the difficulty with uh these compounds
so in terms of the adverse effects that
they can have W no and this is um I
guess to reiterate this is from the
unregulated market and largely
because
um the are people in in certain places
that do not have access to um Delta 9
THC because it's it's banned in that
state or or whatever so they're they're
looking for it elsewhere and are you
know kind of at the mercy of the the
actors who are are producing these
products absolutely I you know I think
some of the other challenge is that you
know we can't say that
um at with any certainty I would say we
can't say at all we can't even hint
to uh that this list of canono analoges
is more dangerous than this list um and
the the reason for that is that there is
very
little scientific research that has been
conducted on the safety or the efficacy
of of any of these
compounds uh and so you know that's
something of the challenge the other
challenge is that you can't you don't
know how much somebody is
consuming uh so that's the other
challenge in all of this is that you
can't believe how much the package says
that's in it and you don't know what the
list of compounds is that's in it right
so you know we have found that you know
there are some there are some products
that maybe list two compounds on the
package and contain seven compounds in
it well what's the accumulation of
effects from all of those compounds
right right and now I mean I obviously I
you you can't speak for the manufacturer
but do you think that that's intentional
in terms of you know they know that
there's these additional compounds or is
it just such a messy process to create
them that there are you know additional
compounds being created that you know
maybe weren't
intended I think it's both yeah
right
um yeah I think it's
good I think there are you know some
manufacturers that because nobody's
looking nobody's watching nobody's
enforcing anything honestly nobody's
analyzing the the products there's only
a handful of labs in the nation that are
able to analyze these these compounds my
lab is one of them uh and so uh when
when you can't even attribute you know
uh an event to a particular compound you
know then the conclusion usually winds
up being well it was a cannabis product
or it was it was a THC product when it
probably wasn't
or uh you know probably contain
something else or had way too much in it
write the list is this point right now
and now you mentioned um being able to
test for these and I know that you used
a specific technique for for this study
I was wondering if you could speak
briefly about kind of what that method
is and um why it was chosen for the
study sure so uh we use our primary
instrument for analysis is a liquid
chromatography with a tandem M
spectrometer attached to it um and
we use that instrument for uh almost
every analysis we do in my lab anyways
um and the reason for that is that uh
one it is very
sensitive uh right so when you've got um
analytes compounds that are in Trace
Amounts in products then you need to
have an instrument that's going to allow
you a really really low limit of
detection right meaning you can look at
things at very very low
concentrations so the lcms allows us to
do that the second reason why we use uh
the LC tandem aspect um is because we
can get uh we can
identify the
the molecule itself meaning the
molecular structure of a compound um so
right we break that compound into
fragments um and we analyze those and
then we break those fragments up again
and we analyze those and we can assemble
all of those fragments uh and uh
determine what the original chemical
structure is so for most of the canono
we're able uh to identify them that way
there are some of the canabo we can't so
um and that's just because uh you know
if you take a look at let's say Delta 8
and Delta 9
THC um you know those the difference
between those molecules is just a shift
in that double bond the location of that
double bond so for some of those we call
those isobars for some of those
compounds we can't tell the difference
between them so if that's the case then
we have another instrument that we use
uh that can separate them so so um so
the LC tandem MPC is our primary
instrument um and then we use a gcms as
a support instrument so that we can
determine you know what the exact um
cannaboid profile is in a
product and so how does that method or
technology compare to your standard
Cannabis Testing Lab well standard uh
Testing Lab uh is using uh what we call
an hlc
with um it's like a UV it's like a UV a
UV detector um it's a hplc dad or PDA um
it's a UV detector and so the challenge
with that detector uh is that you cannot
assess the the structure of the
molecular compound so that
detector um essentially absorbs energy
and emits energy from the comp compound
will absorb energy and emit energy and
you're able to um you know separate
those through the chromatography and so
because it's it doesn't give you any
kind of structural information then if
compounds are really similar then you
can't you can't really and they're
coming out at the same time you you
don't know that you have two compounds
in there you can't uh you can't
ascertain what those are so at least
with the tandem aspect you know we're
able to determine the difference and so
I'll give you an
example so uh several years ago uh me
and several of my colleagues uh we
started a quality assurance testing lab
for the Cannabis industry here in
Virginia and um and we were uh you know
we were we were doing well we were you
this was our side hustle you know this
was a you know we're going to we're
going to build it we're going to be you
know uh you know we're going to be a
scientific voice in this and we're also
going because we're forensic scientists
we're going to use the instruments that
give us the best
information so that was going to be the
LC tandem ASPC to do potency testing
knowing that the rest of the industry
was using this this
hplc so um we had a client come to us
who had three different lab results for
the same product and they
were vastly different in and of
themselves those three results and they
said we don't know which one to believe
so when we ran the product it
was it it was light years different from
what is now the cluster of the original
Three and it was because that prod we
were able to see on the lcms we could
differentiate between Delta 8 and Delta
THC and the
hplc at the time you could not
differentiate it so right so we knew uh
early on in uh in the nature in the uh
in the emergence of these compounds that
lcms gave us the ability uh to
differentiate between the different
canono um and
uh but you know that also made us a um a
unique voice uh and so the industry was
not happy with us you know because you
know we came out very strong right
because remember that's a that's a a
for-profit laboratory my research
laboratory at the time is investigating
all of these emerging
analogues and so we're seeing not only
that the concentration of all these
analoges are not what's on the label and
that there's more of them in there we're
also finding residual solvents we're
also
finding uh contaminations like hair and
dirt in products we're you know High
microbiological counts um and so I came
out really really strongly against Delta
eight uh in Virginia uh when it first
emerged and as a result our business
dried
up so uh you know so we we had to
shutter the lab um you know I don't
regret it not one bit yeah right because
uh we always said we were going to stand
by the science we were going to stand by
quality and we took very seriously our
job to protect consumers absolutely no
and that's it's the way it should be so
for the example that you just mentioned
with the the producer who was getting
different results from the labs to took
it to you and you were able to kind of
see the difference between Delta 8 Delta
9 was that a flower
product uh no that was not a flower
product okay
yeah and okay because um yeah I was
going to be surprised because it was my
understanding that Delta 8 is made only
in very very Trace Amounts by the plant
itself correct but you know I'll be
honest uh we see uh we see that flower
products are sprayed with Delta eight so
you know it wouldn't have been
surprising that wouldn't have been a
surprising result even it even if it had
been a flower product but that wasn't a
flower product yeah and then the other
thing is you were mentioning or you know
one of the the key findings in your
study here is the mislabeling of the
different products um I was curious how
much of that do you think could be
attributed to the fact that folks are
using um different equipment than yours
and are not able to see sort of the the
differences um that you are able to see
yeah I think definitely some can be
attributed to that if you happen to have
somebody who is you know cares enough to
maybe send their product out for
analysis um then that's big
F uh then the challenges going to be
that you there the lab is probably not
going to be able to analyze for all of
these analoges um but you know we don't
think the labs are act the manufacturers
actually sending these products out for
a real analysis yeah you know they're um
you know they're manufacturing the
certificates of analysis um we have one
product uh we received where you because
not only are we getting the products we
also go to the websites to see being
said about these compounds uh in these
products and so we have one product in
which the website literally
says guaranteed these compounds are in
this product but because the labs uh
can't analyze it we can't tell you how
much is in there but we promise it's in
there and it it
wasn't there was a bunch of other stuff
in there but uh you know so I mean
that's the landscape we live in so right
and I guess with that sort of you know
what are the implications of these
findings on sort of the the broader hemp
industry or even for consumers you know
what's sort of the the takeaway here
yeah so I I think there are
um a couple of implications here and and
again I mean I get it there are probably
some
um hemp manufacturer CBD manufacturers
analog manufacturers whatever they're
calling themselves you know who might
care and uh
and have the intention of creating these
products for consumers who don't have
access to Delta 9
THC um uh in their
states
but they are still comp licit
in the Adverse Events that people are
experiencing right you have an industry
that uh is so far not been held
accountable for people dying for people
having s significant Adverse Events that
have affected their lives for
years uh you know so I think that's some
of the problem with um you know the the
lack of oversight and and of course some
of that is an it's an analytical problem
right because there's not many Labs that
can actually analyze these I think it
complicates from a state perspective and
even the federal perspective I think it
complicates
the the state of
legalization uh and you know
because uh most of the Adverse Events
are not being adequately
attributed right so we don't
know if the product they consumed was
just 10 times the the THC concentration
or contained seven or eight analoges we
don't know that but usually what gets
reported is that it was a canabo product
or it was a THC product and you know and
so when an adverse event gets attacked
to well it was a THC product you know
then that becomes difficult language to
ignore um and so right so we need to be
able to uh from a public health and
Public Safety perspective be able to
properly attribute uh the Adverse Events
so I think you know those are a couple
of the bigger impacts of having an
unregulated uh hemp industry
yeah no and then there is sort of
another side of sort of the hemp
industry too where there are some
manufacturers I know who are producing
not analoges or semi- synthetic but you
know
THC Delta 9thc but in what they what
they interpret as a low enough
concentration to be deemed hemp
yes
correct and
I we've analyzed some of those compound
those products okay
and
in almost 100% of the products we've
analyzed they contain over that 0.3%
THC Absolut so what is a consumer to do
um just say no now I think it's buy or
beware right I think the first thing is
is is um is the consumer has to realize
that if it's if they are purchasing a
product in an unregulated market right
um meaning that you are buying it at a
smoke and vape shop or right or online
online if you are in a convenience store
um that just because it's in the
marketplace doesn't mean that it's safe
right we have
um
we as a culture believe that well surely
if it's in the if if it's in a store and
I can buy it in a store then somebody
has said this is safe and reasonable for
me to consume and so they don't really
appreciate the difference between
unregulated and regulated marketplaces
necessarily so I would say that for all
consumers is that you should should
despite the taxes purchase your products
in a regulated Marketplace MH um I think
that is the safest path forward for
consumers and I get it that some people
have said well we don't want to pay the
taxes and the taxes are too high and I
just read a a a scientifically published
manuscript recently that said that well
consumers really don't care about the
high PR
they care about how much product they
can buy for a price
point that's a very important
distinction
so needless to say I think that it is um
important for consumers to be very
cautious about what they're hearing
about all of these analoges um and uh
and the quality of the products and the
safest the safest place for them to
purchase their products is going to be
inside of the regulated Marketplace
despite some of the challenges in the
regulated marketplace right and where
that's available right sure so hard in
in states that haven't that don't have a
uh regul legal regulated Marketplace um
it's hard for the consumer right
so or has created hurdles right so I
mean how hard is it going to be for some
people to actually get you know their um
their note uh saying that they can have
medical marijuana you know so um so I
think states have to think about that if
they really care about you know consumer
safety uh then they have to make it
easier for
consumers to acquire regulated products
right yeah I mean it seems like and of
course this might be a bit up istic but
you know if cannabis were federally
legal and
regulated seems like a lot of these
issues go
away yeah they're not I'll be honest
they're not really all going away I I
get asked this question a lot in terms
of and from a lot of of state
legislators is like well if we if we
create a
regulated uh
Marketplace uh then all of this stuff is
is going to disappear right and I'm no
it is never completely going to go away
because there's there's always going to
be a Marketplace for people looking for
alternative
experiences no matter what the drug is
right so so this is I think some of the
challenge will it it won't all go away a
lot will go away right
because you know you've got a lot of
consumers whether they're cannabis naive
or are in pain or whatever
who or just want to experience it and uh
and they're and and so just for those
kinds of consumers you know you got to
create a pathway for them but I think
for the nefarious the really nefarious
types um there's always going to be
Marketplace well Michelle this is a this
is a fascinating topic I think we could
we could probably do a whole another
hour but we'll we'll save it for canmed
and folks should definitely come out and
uh continue the conversation um but
before I let you go I did want to give
you an opportunity to share any um
additional resources that you think that
folks who are listening who want to
maybe read up more uh might be
interested in and then of course where
they can find you and your work as well
sure um I have uh so we're building out
a web page for the lab uh that's going
going to have links to our uh
manuscripts um and we're also developing
some um documents right because a lot of
like School administrators like don't
know they they don't know and they're
trying to protect the children in their
marketplaces and so we're generating uh
products uh like reading materials um
one page reports uh that are easy to
digest uh with that information so I'm
happy to share with you uh the link to
that and links to the manuscripts that
people might be interested in Reading
excellent yeah if yeah send the links
I'll put them in the show description so
it's easy for folks who are listening to
to check that out right all right
Michelle thanks again for joining me on
the podcast and I look forward to seeing
you down in Puerto Rico I sound good
thank you so much Ben
[Music]