[Music]
welcome to the can Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the caned
Summit okay a few updates to share first
registration for the canmed 25
Innovation and investment Summit is now
live check out canmed events.com to see
details about next year's event and the
new location the Windam Resort in Rio
Grande Puerto Rico purchase your ticket
package today to take advantage of early
bird pricing second our CED 25 Advisory
Board is now up on the website this year
we have a great mix of familiar faces
and new names who will help shape the
event and assemble our best program yet
lastly the camed 25 abstract submission
portal is now open so if you have novel
research or Innovations in the areas of
cannabis science medicine cultivation or
safety testing we want to hear from you
use the link in the show description or
visit canid events .c to learn more and
good
luck Our Guest today is kevn Barbosa
chavier kevyn is a PhD student in plant
biotechnology at
uef where she conducts research under
the supervision of Thiago mat venancio
she is a computational biologist
investigating the genes and Gene
networks involved in secondary plant
metabolic pathways and fiber production
specific specifically in the Cannabis
sativa species kevn and her team
recently published a study titled
cannabis expression Atlas a
comprehensive resource for integrative
analysis of Cannabis sativa gene
expression along with a free online tool
to help researchers analyze genomic
sequence data during our conversation we
discussed the team's main objectives in
creating the Cannabis expression Atlas
how our understanding of the Cannabis
genome compares to other commercial
crops how gene expression data can
advance plant breeding and genetic
engineering potential applications of
the Cannabis expression Atlas in
commercial cannabis cultivation and more
before we get to my conversation with
kevn I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor medicinal
genomics medicinal genomics uses its
unmatched knowledge of the Cannabis
genome and the microbs affecting
cannabis plants to create diverse
testing solutions that improve crop
yield accelerate breeding programs and
ensure product safety Growers and
breeders use mgc's cannabis genome
sequencing services to identify novel
traits stabilize genetics and protect
intellectual property additionally
canopia Donnet provides bioinformatics
and blockchain certification for
cultivar authenticity
learn more at medicinal
genomics. okay and without any further
Ado please enjoy my conversation with
kevyn Barbosa
[Music]
chavier good morning Kevin thank you so
much for joining us on the podcast good
morning thank you for having me here I
am excited to be here excellent yeah and
I'm excited to talk with you today about
a new resource that your team has put
together has put together to advance
cannabis genomics research um and it was
in a new study called cannabis
expression Atlas a comprehensive
resource for integrative analysis of
Cannabis sativa gene expression it's a
it's an effort and it's research that's
near and dear to our hearts here at
medicinal genomics so I'm definitely
excited to talk with you about
it so I think to start it would be great
if you could tell us what inspired you
to undertake this study of cannabis and
focus on developing a gene expression
database okay um
W I would say that the recent changes in
the regulation of Canabis use and
cultivation around the world have opened
up opportunities to research with the
species to be
condos more broadly so this has lead to
a rap increase in the a mod information
available about
cannabis so including earna sequence
data and however these they are often in
the raw
form uh meaning that the while the ear
A6 sequence files are available in
public databases for example uh without
proper futuring and Analysis they aren't
very
affirmative so and addition to this um
not all of this um data are linked to
published scientific studies so this
this is where the idea of the Cannabis
expression Atlas came
U the goal was to create a database that
translates the earn data so speak um
transforming row sequence information
into easy to use and refined data to
anyone interested in
this great so you're you're you're
Translating that data to make it more
useful yeah excellent um so one thing I
noticed when I I was reading through the
the abstract in the paper is that you
chose to use the Jamaican lion reference
which again near and dear to our heart
at medicinal genomics our team is the
one who who put that together so how
does that reference benefit the
study um well um during my Nisha
research I realized that there was no
consensus about um which reference
genome to use in Canabis Research so
this made me want to look further to
available genom uh for these species to
choose the most suitable one for using
our
study so I found that most of other
genomes came from female plants and were
from type one or three chemotypes and
that's mean that's when the JAMA genome
called my attention because first it's a
typ two her so which means that has the
both CHC and CB gas gen active and
additionally both male and female plants
were sequenced and the researchers from
the medical genomics had identified uh
Rion corresponding to the Y
chromosome and this is uh a key feature
compared to other available genomes
because which uh as I mentioned are all
from female plan so using this genome as
reference uh allow us to enrich our
database and identify expressing returns
for Y chromosomes and genes for example
and which can be very useful for helping
researchers to better understand sex
differentiation in cannbis for example
excellent so so the Jamaican lion genome
it covers more ground because it has the
TCA the CBD and the Y chromosome so
that's great yes it's more
complex
excellent so what were your main
objectives in creating the Cannabis
expression Atlas and how does this work
address gaps in existing cannabis
research well um initially uh creating
the Cannabis expression atas was was not
our
mango uh when I began my research with
cannabis I need this R data um PR to
explore gen Express on profiles related
to specific tra of the pieces that uh we
are working but so so my initial plan
was simply to build an internal database
for this purpose uh but as we collected
and process the data we realized how
slow and laborsome and computationally
the than this person was and so that's
when we thought about making the the
process Express data available to other
researchers because not all Labs have
the staff or the computational resarch
for this this level of processing uh so
we try to develop a tool that would be
useful not only for researchers waiting
to download and use expression data uh
in other types of analysis but also for
those uh just seeking more information
on a specific ding for example and
without needing to download everything
download all the
data um showing another words it lets
users um can access gene expression
directly from the tool itself and I
would say that's the
the core of the Canabis expression Atlas
and making complex gene expression
information accessible in a clear and
interative form for
anyone excellent
so kind of taking a step back and just
talking about cannabis genome research
in general how does our understanding
our Collective understanding of the
Cannabis genome compared to other
commercial
crops
well I think that our understand of the
Cannabis genum is advancing quick
rapidly uh for other species knowledge
was developed Bradly as new technologies
were created but now that cannabis
research is more rly
accepted these Advanced Technologies
already and well established so it means
that the research progress that took a
decades for other crops like corn or
soybeans can be achieved much faster for
cannabis uh that said um there is still
a lot uh to uncover about this
pcing but I believe that in just a few
years we reach a level of understanding
comparable to what we current have for
major commercial crops
so I think that W that's that's great
that's encouraging to hear um now from
the Practical side in in your experience
to what extent have cannabis cultivators
embraced using genomics and genomic
tools well I think that uh it depends on
whether we are taking about um is
cultivators or big farms MH because I
believe that big farms are already using
genome tools to guide breeding process
but I believe that in general the for
cators itself the use of gamic tools
it's um let's say indirect so through
for example SE of newly developed C
so I think that it depends of the small
C ver or big farms yeah that makes sense
okay so I want to dig in a little bit to
um to the study that your team published
um and so it excuse me so it revealed
substantial variability in gene
expression among different tissues and
chemotypes so what were some of the most
surprising things that you found in that
analysis I think that the first thing
that c our attention was that we
initially expected that the Y jeans to
show more specific expression in sample
in samples from male
flowers but only a small proportion of
the genes on the white chromosome are
expressed exclusively in the
flow while many other genes were
expressed in samples from other Jesus
including those from female
PLS and so searching about that uh I see
that this PO can be explained
by some researchers indicating that only
a small proportion of the white
chromosome is unique with the majority
being shared with the X chromosome
so uh but it's still a thing that need
more deep attention um another notable
finding was uh the clustering of the
Tricom samples because as you know troms
are where the synthesis and storage of
the medicinal compounds are in the plant
and we observe that the triom samples
showed um very similar expression
profiles regardless of chemotype
indicating that it's likely that only a
small number of Genies that
differentiate these
chemotypes but again it's something that
need more deeper um
interpretations wow that's surprising so
so you're saying parts of the Y
chromosome can actually be found in
female plants
yeah genius prant from the the Y region
also have expression in other cheers
including in female um chees in the case
flowers interesting very interesting um
so could you discuss the significance of
these and other findings for cannabis
plant biology and you know practical
applications
yes uh I would say that understanding or
subject of study in this case the the
Cannabis is the most crucial step to
cultivating and utilizing this plant as
efficiently as possible and with that in
mind I believe that um or two will
significantly aiding generating
knowledge about the plant in a in a
broad sense
uh because it can be useful to those
focus on Industrial properties as well
as those interested in the medical
attributes uh and by providing clear and
accessible gene expression data we
believe that we are helping to PVE the
way for better informed research and
applications in this area excellent and
more specifically how might this gene
expression information support advanced
in areas like plant breeding or genetic
engineering okay uh as I mentioned
earlier uh our understanding of the
subject of the study is the key and gen
Express information can be used
to
identify genus directly associated with
traits of interest for example such as
kabite synthesis fiber produ
or SE development so knowing what genis
are involved and how they are their
expression profiles influence these
traits uh is crucial for making
decisions about genetic modification for
example it could help in modifying
variety by adding or silen in je uh to
control the presence or the intensity of
the certain traits so a practical
application might be ensuring that hemp
vares like chemotype 3 for example don't
produce an THC if it was the
interes excellent
excellent all
right so getting into more specifically
the uh cannabis expression Atlas could
you walk us through some of the main
features of the tool and what types of
users do you envision benefiting from it
certainly uh this to was designed to be
as comprehensive as possible so that
users don't need
to rely on multiple platforms to GA the
information they need about Genie so we
integrated ER n express data with
functional information about the
genus um so for example we have an
interative
table where users can explore cannabis
genes even if they don't know the Gen ID
because users can search for Genies by
name SE ATP int and find our related
Genies in this
database they can also search by
transcription Factor family names by
genology terms by Express and PS
categories so if someone is is
interested in identifying housekeeping
Genies or chy specific Genies they can
easily find the information as well for
all the the expression classes that
have and additionally we included a hit
map to visualize expression Gene of
Interest with
Will which will help to uh interpret
some
results and beside that given the lack
of organization in gulture across Canam
genom and in another
pled in can
genom uh we included a bus too in the
kabus express outlas and this means that
if the user is interested in a specific
joury but doesn't have have enough
information to search for it through the
order tools in the in
Theos they can simply input the Gen or
the protein sequency and do a blast
search again blast again the atos to
identify the genu in the database and
access the related
information and I believe that this two
will be especially useful for
researchers perhaps not directly for
catas because while it's easy to use and
intuitive of basic understanding of gen
nenat and how to interpret genomic and
transcript to data is necessary to fully
Leverage The Tool are there any
limitations in the Cannabis expression
Atlas that you aim to address with any
future
updates well um in the future we plan to
make some Visual and navigation
Improvement to the tool such as
enhancing the mobile version and making
the interactions between different pages
and internum tools more
simulus and another feature we didn't
include in this version but plan to
implement in the future is the ability
to search for information based on
YouTuber names because I believe this
could be useful for some users who are
more focused on specific
varieties and we are also open to
suggestions excellent okay and and
wrapping up how do you foresee this
database influencing Global cannabis
research well I really hope that this
database will play a significant role in
ADV in global cannab search um by
providing a comprehensive uh sess
resource for Gen Express data um by
making this information freely available
and easy to use and we hope to
accelerate research across various
fields from additional to Industrial
applications and because this database
can serve us uh
because I believe that this database can
serve as a foundation for new studies uh
enabling researchers to quickly access
and analyze data without need for
extensive
preprocessing so in the end in the end
of the day uh this two will help unify
and streamline the global research for
leading to to a more efficient and
collaborative approach to understanding
Canabis
biology yeah that's that's excellent and
again that that very well aligns with
our company and our ethos of trying to
put as much data public and um easily
accessible to to enhance the
understanding for everyone so that's
great that's great to hear um all right
kevn thank you thank you again so much
for for joining me on the podcast um
anyone who wants to check out the uh
cannabis expression Atlas I'll put a
link in the show description so they can
easily get to it and a link to the study
as well so they can read up about more
about how you put that together okay and
um again thanks so much for joining us
keep up the good work and hopefully we
can do this again soon yes me
too thank you
[Music]
a