hi everybody Welcome today to my talk my
name is Lauren Sands I am a senior
technician at safe Diva labs in
Westfield Massachusetts but today I'm
actually presenting on my grad school
work that I was so lucky to conduct at
the University of Connecticut under Dr
Gerald Berkowitz
I don't have the clicker
and as said the title of my talk is the
analysis of hormonal regulation of
promoter activities of Cannabis sativa
Primal transferase 1 and 4.
so the research goals for this my grad
school work was to one develop a better
understanding of the enzymes that
produce cannabidrolic acid cbga in terms
of functionality location and importance
in Cannabis sativa and in addition we
wanted to conduct studies involving
hormone treatments to gather information
regarding which hormone signaling
pathways are actually involved in
cannabinoid production
so cannabinoids are obviously produced
in trichomes and there's different types
of trichomes on the cannabis plant but
we're specifically interested in the
glandular stock trichome these are small
hair like projections that are made up
of stock and head tissue most commonly
found on leaves and flowers on cannabis
plants and of course on unpollinated
female flowers
these trichomes are the cannabinoid and
terpene factories that we're also
interested in so the center image you
can see a quick little diagram of this
trichome you can see the base of a stalk
and at the top the secretory vesicles
and cells the top this base this is what
we're interested in
so as I said we're interested in this
head of the glandular trichome
this contains the cannabinoids and the
enzymes producing them the enzyme that I
mentioned that produces cbga this is the
one we're interested in
so you can you can see on the left a
structural diagram up close this shows
the different parts of the head of the
glandular trichome and then on the right
you can actually see the cannabinoid
biosynthetic pathway
written out showing you the top the top
on the right of this cannabinoid
biosynthetic pathway shows you the
plastid and you can see in blue it's
connected to the diagram on the left
this shows the rosette of gland cells
this is the bottom of the head of the
glandular trichome so this contains the
enzymes that produce cbga and cbgas
actually produced in the rosette at the
base and it is exported to the secretory
reservoir which you can see in red this
is indicated on the left and right so
you can see CBJ is produced in the base
exported to the reservoir and we're
trying to figure out why the enzyme is
making cbga
and you can see the star
this star indicates the cbga synthase
enzyme
cbga synthase has been referred to as
many different things in literature it's
been referred to as cbga synthase or got
general diphosphate olivotolate
transferase or in my case pt4 penal
transferase4 so we
were just really interested in this cbga
synthase enzyme and we're going to get
more into that now
so the main reason why our lab decided
to focus on this prenal transferase
enzyme cbga synthase it's because we
initially did a research study over the
course of a flower flowering period
we took
we took the flowers and we measured cbga
synthase in this case pt4 we measured
this gene expression over the course of
the flowering period as well as we took
the cannabinoid content and we measured
the cbga in the plant we saw at week
four cbj's peaking and at week four this
pt4 gene expression level it's peaking
as well and then you can see a positive
correlation increases then decreases and
then
you can see on the right we also did
this with thca and thca synthase we saw
that thca contents peaking at week six
but there's no positive correlation with
thca synthase so we wanted to put less
focus on this thca since enzyme and more
focus on the prenal transferase genes
and these precursor enzymes so we want
to understand cannabinoid synthesis look
at the enzyme that's producing the
cannabinoid that's needed for conversion
towards endpoint cannabinoid synthesis
and as we know cbga is the mother of all
cannabinoids
foreign
these are membrane-bound enzymes
localized to plant plastids and in
cannabis we've identified 10 of them
and literature has actually pointed to
the fact that pt4 this is the main cbga
synthase enzyme however all some papers
have reference that pt1 is capable of
producing cbga specifically in a patent
done by Jonathan Page and his group in
2011.
so
there are there's a lot of research
literature review showing that is it pt1
or is it pt4 so both have shown cbga
synthesis capability however yeast
assays have revealed that pt4's only
substrate is all of atolic acid
but pt1 is promiscuous so pt1 is able to
work with different substrates all of
italic acid all of it all narengine Etc
pt1's affinity for this substrate
ovatoic acid was shown to be
sorry P2 almost 60 millimolar well pt4
was 6.27 micromolar so this is the
affinity for this substrate so pt4 was
shown to have a 10 000
stronger affinity for this substrate
elevatoric acid
and lastly when put into this yeast
system and when pt4 and pt1 were put
into the yeast systems and fed all of
italic acid it was shown that pt4 invert
in a variety of studies pt4 was
producing this cbga while pt1 was
showing little to no production of cbga
so while literature points to pt4 being
the main cbda synthase enzyme we figured
with all this literature maybe let's
just look at both renal transferases
and to understand why these perennial
transferase genes that produce the
enzymes are producing cbga we decided to
look at their promoters so promoters are
the sequence Upstream of the
transcription start site that regulate
DNA transcription and basically tell the
gene whether to turn on turn off not
work at all and so these promoters have
responsive elements throughout the
region and
promoters can be anywhere from five
thousand to two thousand base pairs
upwards of that and throughout these
regions there's responsive elements that
respond to various stimuli so stimuli
such as hormones specific transcription
Factor families and more so these
regions are actually highly conserved
across promoters so it's really nice you
can look at other organisms in these
databases such as place and plant care
to see if maybe your promoter also has
these responsive elements and maybe they
also respond to these diff specific
stimuli
and um
yeah if they're responsive to these
stimuli this can activate an increase
expression or repress the expression
so while there's all these different
responsive elements that are contained
in the promoter we decided to focus
solely on hormones
and hormones are chemicals produced by
plants that regulate their growth
development reproductive processes
Etc and actually hormones are known to
be super involved in flowering in
different plants especially it's been
shown in hops so we've decided to focus
on this because hormones are definitely
involved in secondary metabolite
production and plants likely in cannabis
there have been too many studies on it
but it's pretty clear that they're
involved in secondary metabolite
production and cannabis
so these hormone responsive elements
they are long stretches of DNA that are
going to bind to proteins that are
activated as these hormones are released
in the plant as the hormone signaling
Pathways get active
and so these hormones shown on the slide
of course there's many more in Plants
these are the ones that we focused on
for our studies and so we use these
databases and these are the um these are
the hormones that we discovered are
likely responsive in our promoters of
penal transferase one and four so we
have ethylene abscisic acid gibberellin
cytokinin salicylic acid and oxen
and um we predict that these hormones
not only a few of them are
interacting with these perennial
transfers promoters we predict that
they're all working together in this
orchestra that is cannabinoid synthesis
in the plants
so we were able to clone the 600 base
pairs Upstream of the prenal transferase
for transcription start site shown here
on the screen
we identified this using ncbi and of
course the responsive element databases
provided us with these hormones for
penal transferase Forest promoter so
these hormones some of them might
activate the promoter some might not
they might work synergistically
antagonistically or not at all so we
were actually able to clone this
promoter and we used it to examine the
hormone of
we used it to examine sorry
to examine the effects of hormone
treatment on the promoters as well as a
variety of assays for promoter activity
localization in cannabis plants using
Gus assays
and we were also able to do this with
prenal transferase one we were actually
able to clone more of the promoter of
this Gene we got 1500 base pairs you can
see on this screen there's a little bit
more responsive elements we have
gibberellin salicylic acid auxin and
abscisic acid
so we were able to clone these promoters
from genomic DNA from Cannabis sativa
hemp in our lab at UConn we cloned them
and we inserted them into vectors either
tagged with luciferase or Gus reporters
so these constructs with our promoters
were utilized in duluciferase assays or
gas assays so luciferase assay's report
luciferase reporter assays investigate
whether stimuli can activate or refresh
transcription
using the Gene luciferase and Gus essays
are used for localization and the
functional gush Gene that's produced can
it makes blue coloration in the plant
upon integration to the plant hormone
plant genome sorry
so first we wanted to confirm the
location of the greatest activity of
prenal transferase genes and promoters
in the plant on the left you can see we
performed quantitative PCR on our
flowering plants in the sixth week of
flowering and we saw that the MRNA
expression levels of both prenal
transferase 1 and 4 were highly the gene
activity was high much higher in the
flower and leaf compared to our root
control and after confirming the
location of genescript Gene transcript
location activity we wanted to visualize
these genes in the cannabis plants so we
used our promoter Gus constructs and we
took cannabis seedlings and sugar leaves
and we were able to visualize these
promoters in
in the dark blue you can see this is
where the promoters are active in the
plant and so you can see seedlings on
the left and sugar leaves on the right
so you can see in the sugar leaves which
are the leaves that form around the
flowers as the plant matures we saw
greater activity in the dark blue for
penal transfers 4 and there's actually a
really cool picture
this was our prenal transferase 4
promoter tagged with Gus you can see in
the sugar leaves in the dark blue and
the trichomes we were able to confirm
that our promoter was very active in
these regions and not only did this
confirm that this is where it's active
we also confirmed that these promoters
were capable of driving different
reporters
so to read the activation of our
promoters in vitro we utilized protoplas
which are cells without cell walls and
without these cell walls they can accept
DNA and transiently express this DNA and
so using dual luciferous assays we can
measure this DNA expression
so we enzymatically isolated protoplasts
and prepared them for transient
expression of plasmids containing peachy
promoters driving the luciferase
reporter overnight transfection hormone
treatments were completed following that
of hormones at concentrations of 10
micromolar
and we also used pop we used negative
and positive controls in this experiment
and the cells were then collected for
five hours following this hormone
treatment and the protoplasts containing
our plasmids were frozen and used in
further duluciferase assays and as you
can see on the right here this is an
experiment done on arabidopsis it shows
that the promoters are active following
hormone treatment
in the five hours post hormone treatment
and this is why we use these few hours
afterwards
we measured this promoter activity with
the luciferase assays as said and so in
this case we're investigating if our
stimuli this hormone can activate our
promoter to initiate transcription of
this luciferous Gene located Downstream
of this promoter so this is actually
using the luciferase gene found in
fireflies and in Sea pansies
and so their protoplasts their
transfection with renal transferase
Firefly luciferase constructs that's our
promoter of interest and we also
co-transfected it with a 35s
constitutive promoter which is tagged
with our vanilla elusive race
so these Frozen protoplasts that we
collected previously are lysed mixed
with reagents either luciferin for our
Firefly luciferase our promoters of
Interest or mixed with Cowell and koala
and Terra Zion for our vanilla
luciferase
so this reaction creates luminescence in
our luminometer this ratio is created
considered relative luminescence and
this to this directly correlates with
the activation of the promoter following
hormone treatment
foreign
so here are our results for prenal
transfers for we're presenting the
response towards hormones hormones that
did result in promoter activation we did
see some hormones that did not activate
the promoter that's all in the paper we
used methylgasminate this did not have a
hormone responsive element predicted in
the promoter we saw no response from
this so these graphs they show relative
luminescence the ratio created from fire
apply to vanilla luciferase in our in
our protoplasts following hormone
treatment so some hormones were
administered as either a synthetic
hormone or a precursor depending on how
these hormones exist in nature so
firstly exogenous ethylene administered
as one Amino cyclopropane one carboxylic
acid this is the precursor as ethylene
is gaseous
led to significant promoter activity
five hours past treatment
exogenous hypocisic acid led to
significant promoter activity at three
and five hours past treatment
exogenous gibberellin the administered
is gibberellic acid three led to
significant promoter active in
activation at hours three and five past
treatment and lastly exogenous cytokinin
administered as transient riboside led
to significant promoter activity
activation at hours three and five past
treatment
so we went a little bit more in depth
with salicylic acid's connection to
prenal transferase4 we predicted that
salicylic acid is likely involved or
very involved in cannabinoid synthesis
because salicylic acid is a plant
defense hormone and cannabinoids among
their many purposes they are produced to
play a role in defending the plant from
pathogens including insects fungi
viruses and bacteria
so in a previous experiment we saw an
increase in gene transcript levels in
Penal transferase 4 following a soil
drench treatment containing one
millimolar of salicylic acid so you can
see it's a very tiny graph at the bottom
we actually saw a hundred-fold increase
in Penal transferase 4 gene expression
three days post sa treatment so we saw
already that the gene transcript levels
are affected by this hormone so of
course we expect it to be affected in
the promoter
so we can see that cspt4 promoter was
activated at hours three and four past
treatment for salicylic acid and pt4
and I actually decided to perform site
Direct immunogenesis on this salicylic
acid responsive element in the prenal
transferase4 promoter
so I was able to create point mutations
in this response development
shown in red the red base pairs were
switched and I repeated this promoter
hormone treatment with this mutated
promoter and I then saw no response to
salicylic acid so we're essentially
confirming that this putative responsive
element is a Bonafide CIS acting element
that is involved in salicylic acid
signaling
so we think salicylic acid is a great
hormone to look at in the future for
cannabinoid synthesis and its effects on
that
so while we saw many effects from prenal
transferase4 we also looked at renal
transferase 1 as I mentioned we didn't
see as great responses or higher
responses more hormones in the response
of renal transferase wands promoter we
saw we did see a activation at hours one
three and five for salicylic acid at one
three and five for oxen and at hours
three pass treatment for abscystic acid
so there's different hormones affecting
each prenal transferase promoter there's
different sets of hormones affecting
each promoter so we're thinking maybe
there's different functionality in these
perennial transferase genes it's
basically it's giving a little bit more
insight into how these different
transverse genes act in the cannabis
plant
so I'll wrap this up really quickly our
conclusions so we think plant hormones
are almost certainly very involved in
cannabinoid synthesis and signaling
Pathways affecting the cannabinoid
biosynthetic pathway
the hormone networks in cannabis as seen
in other plants are very interconnected
we're seeing multiple hormones working
on the same promoter
there's definitely needs to be more
research involved in how why and when
hormones are produced in the cannabis
plant during flowering how they're
affecting perennial transferase genes
and the effects on one hormone on
another is really interesting so as you
can see again these hormones on the
bottom left are ones that we saw
response in the promoters for these
genes
both promoters respond to Celica acid
and the cystic acid and these hormone
networks and plants have been shown to
work together in many different plants
or against each other
and lastly we should conduct more
studies on these promoters and hormones
in the actual plant throughout flowering
to understand how cannabinoid synthesis
is actually happening and this can help
a lot in the future one if anybody ever
decides to do growth promoter growth
Regulators as hormones and just
understanding how cannabinoids are
produced in the plant it's really good
to get a good understanding on how it's
made and so then we can further
understand how cannabinoids are produced
in the plant for medical purposes
growing purposes and just to better
understand our plants
here's the sources for anybody
interested in them and yeah thank you
all thank you Cam and medicinal genomics
and Advanced Nutrients
[Applause]
a great talk Lauren um thanks I've got
uh one question on the these hormone
sequences that you're highlighting um
they're fairly short in sequence which
means if you scan the whole genome
you'll find them somewhat everywhere
um I I noticed from some previous
methylation sequencing that we've done
before that at least not on the parental
transfers for being Gene but on the GC
synthase genes there's all types of
weird methylation happening on the five
Prime uh promoter of that of that Gene
and I noticed you made a mutation up
there that introduced a cpg is it
possible that there's uh an epigenetic
component here of how these hormones are
are regulating these sequences
what's the mechanism of the sequence
sites is there a protein that's like
binding to it you think that's true in
the responsive elements yeah the
responsive elements yeah definitely I
think
um I think I understand your question
um these short DNA binding sequences
they're specifically somehow binding to
the transcription factors that are
activated through the hormone signaling
pathways
obviously I don't have this data with
the types of hormone treatments you did
but I can share through a bunch of
bisulfide sequencing we did on Plants
before and after flowering and I don't
know it might show some cpg methylation
that might be playing a role in those
signatures so I'll connect after yeah um
actually this data was accepted this
morning for publication so if anyone's
interested please check it out in
scientific reports
[Applause]