thank you very much um good morning SL
afternoon um thank you for having me
here first time fall in love with camm
uh thank you for still being here we're
closing to lunch um I often hear people
saying that um nutrical and uh
cosmetical are the lower handing fruits
compared to medicine to drug is that
true absolutely if we talk about the
regulation we talk about uh the the
approve uh the the requirement for the
approval but I do still believe that any
good products um any good cosmetic
products dietary supplement products
should be supported by science rigorous
research especially with the ones that
has functional claims so I want to use
this opportunity to share with you the
research experience we have and I want
to share with you uh the promising data
the exite excitement I have towards the
development of nutriceutical or
cosmetical ingredient based on
non-cannabinoid uh compound from from
hemp all right most of the fundamental
basic research are done in in the lab in
my lab at University of Rhode Island um
some of them are supported by industry
Partners um uh from different companies
and I in addition to that I also have a
a startup very early uh stage startup
called Ocean State bioactives OSB to
further develop potential cosmetic or
nutriceutical products with different
natural
products um so in the past few years the
capacity at our University for cannabis
education and biomedical research has
been sign signicantly increased uh we
have a group fascinating awesome faculty
members that we do together on the
research of cannabis in addition to that
I lead a Research Unit that is
specifically focused on the potential
application of uh uh natural products on
their neutral and cosmetic uh
applications um sometimes I take a step
back thinking that this is not about can
this is not about hemp it's about any
natural products how do we use our
platform how do we rationally design
good products so comes to me it always
comes uh from two angles the strategy to
develop a natural products based neutral
or cosmetical ingredients are always
come from two angles of course one is
the chemistry uh especially the phyto
constituents of natural products and at
the second one is of course their
biological activities uh for hemp I feel
like this is very promising very
interesting especially for Di dietary
supplements and cosmetic industry why uh
think about the hemp root it's it's
sometimes called waste products from the
industry I feel that's B I think it
never need to be called as a waste
product it's a byproducts from the hemp
or cannabis industry but it has has a
great potential to be further developed
into neutral or
cosmetical uh another example is the
spend biomass to a lot of people it's
just spend waste material but as a uh
natural product chemist I think that one
the spent hemp material still has a lot
of bioactive compounds inside for
example this is another side project we
have we have extracted uh a lot of
bioactive compounds from spent hemp
material and especially for the
phenolics and the
polysaccharides those polysaccharides
are uh closely associated with a lot of
uh applications for dietary supplement
for example it it has been studied that
polyphenol are good for the gut health
uh especially as prebio U
prebiotics uh in addition to that we
have set up a library uh of cannaboids
and we use those cannaboids for our bio
acids uh we set up a in-house panel uh a
panel of In-House acid that could
evaluate the natural products in our
library uh the the the central of that
library and also for that bio acid
platform is inflammation and from
inflammation we can derive to gut health
we can derived to uh skin
Health um for today's talk I want to
spend some time on the on the background
of our research using CBD as a
representative compound from Cannabis
and I want to introduce you how we set
up our bi biological evaluation systems
for our further studies although the
focus for this talk is on non-c noise
type of compound but I do think CBD
could be a very good chemical Pro to
study those uh the the the chemistry and
biological activities of of this
compound then I will move to the
chemistry study of the hemp roots and
their anti-inflammation activity as well
as their skin protective
effect so I do want to spend some time
on the first part int introducing you uh
the the research we have done on CBD on
um cannaboids the reason is that uh most
of those studies are published I won't
go to Too Much details on this on the on
the data but I want to spend some time
on how do we set up those assets what
are the rationale behind the the
Publications share with you some of the
workflow some of the stories behind what
you don't you don't see from
Publications uh the first step we had
was that we set up a library of uh
cannaboids this include CBD and a a few
of those rear minor canab noids we have
about over 30 different um min canab
know it in addition to that we did
chemical modifications and we use
synthetic chemistry to build up another
separate Library as the CBD derivatives
as you can see here um many of them are
showing even better biological
activities in different
applications uh we have studied all
kinds of different biological activities
of minor canab noids this is for us is
kind of like we understand those
compound better and we understand the
bio acid system better just like machine
learning you feed the machine with data
and they can improve getting better
although we are not that fast but every
time we we carry on a study using
different natural products different
canab noids in different bio acids the
understanding of those bio acids and
chemistry are get profound and profound
every time so that's the the one um
starting point we we
had so here you can see initially we
test CBD in infl cellular inflammation
model specifically this is a
anti-inflam uh model I will give you a
little bit more details later then we
pivoted from the monoy the imuno cells
toward skin cells in this case we use uh
skin cinos site as the cell cellular
model and we can kind of like shifted
from the inflammation stress in the
monoy human monoy towards the
inflammation stress in skin models and
especially for uh inflammation mediated
cell death in this case is pyro
pyroptosis and we also study another
type of cell DES in skin cells which is
ferroptosis so this is the full cycle of
the de development the evolution of of
our bio acids uh let let me give you
some of the the details so the first
step is set up different bio acids uh
those bio acids include one biochemical
based acids could be enzymatic acid then
depends on different outcome or end
points we design cellular based acids
this is this is very important because
it helps us to understand uh uh uh the
mechanism of action of those canab noids
better then dep depends dep on if it is
necessary we can move to animal based
studies we can use different animal
models for different diseases models
um in parallel to that I feel very
excited that we also set up a new
platform that utilize more Advanced
Technologies such as proteom miix or uh
Advanced biing biing aets to understand
better the biological activity of Those
comp compounds as you heard from last
talk Hunter bring a very good point when
you do biological acids especially for
cell-based AES you see the statistic you
see the stars you know it's working or
not if it is the p uh uh less than 0.05
yeah sometimes it tells you if it's not
it's working or not but you don't see
the information the dynamic change from
the complexity of the biology behind the
values the the P values so that's why we
want to utilize more advanced technology
to understand better the mechanism of
action of those compounds as you just
heard from Dr goldenstein that uh
multiomic is is very uh uh rapidly
adopted by the the the the field study
the biological activity the mechanism of
action of cannaboids here similarly to
met metabolomics we have a platform
approach set up uh it's it's about the
proteomic uh to to look at the the
landscape of the change of proteins from
cells from animal tissues from human
biological fluid samples to understand
what's the impact of those cannaboids on
specific diseases models um in addition
to that we also set up this acid this
biing acid so once you have a specific
Target from the proteo mix you want to
validate if the compound can actually
bind to that MO ular Target in this case
we use a technique called spr surface
plasma resonance to confirm to validate
if the compound could directly bind to
the protein to the
Target um so we started the
anti-inflammation assd with this model
called inflammasome so what is
inflammasome and why it's important INF
flamon it's a group of proteins that
could be assembled for the purpose of
sensing infection stress so in the
normal status there are just proteins
protein group of proteins but when the
human body uh sense the stress from in
uh in infection those proteins they will
assemble together and the further uh
activate the downstream prote protein
secens for example they can activate one
pro one protein called caspace one which
is a very important uh enzyme that could
further activate the secretion of
pro-inflammatory cyto kindes such as ir1
beta so the point is that if you through
any natural products you more or less
see anti-inflammation activity very
general anti-inflammation activity if
you search a certain natural products in
in pop matat in Google Scholar you
always see it has inflammation activity
but sometimes inflammation is not bad
thing the root of all the diseases are
chronic inflammation and we found that
inflam is more path pathologically
relevant to inflammation to chronic
inflammation so we want to to set up a a
inflam inflam specific model to evaluate
our compound so how do we do that is
this is actually very straightforward so
in the general inflammation acid often
you do is that you uh you expose the
cells monoy microage to the inflammation
stressors like lipopolysaccharide uh RPS
then you measure the outcome you measure
the the biomarkers inflammatory
biomarkers in this case in addition to
LPS we add a signal sign secondary
signal which is known as nigeran so
after the the cells Expos exposure to uh
have exposure to uh LPS and Niger is set
up inflamation uh inflammation model uh
with this model we can screen the
library of our compounds and I found
that very interesting that we screened
over 300 different natural products not
only cannaboids many different natural
products only a few of them showing
specific selectivity towards the
inhibition of uh inflammosome in this
case CBD is one of those most promising
inhibitor for uh inflam so those are the
some of the details of the study which
are already published so I won't go to
too much but basically add the non-toxic
concentration to the celles CBD was
effectively effectively reduce the
production of i1 beta without affecting
uh TNA Alpha that's what how we can tell
it's a very specific inflam inhibitor so
after that we want to have more evidence
to support the
anti-inflammation activity of uh CBD so
we further develop different acid to
measure uh the the the receptor P2 X7
which is very important mediator for
inflam so we can say that using our uh
uh different uh uh photometric acids we
can show that inflam CBD could
effectively reduce uh the inflamation
level in the thp1
cells then we move to shift to uh skin
one the reason is that inflammosome is
actually very pathologically relevant to
uh man of those skin diseases acne and
even to aging so that's why we want to
say if that inflamm can uh the anti-infl
inflam activity of CBD could be
translated into skin so what we have is
that we have different bio acids set up
we can say CBD could effec effectively
reduce the uh the uh the cellular uh
oxidative stress in the skin U Cortino
Side High cells and we use g g uh uh
Gene plx AES to look at a panel of
different genes that relevant to inflam
and very interestingly we identifi that
caspace one the the one activate uh uh
uh i1 beta was actually identified from
this panel and which was supported by
our computational um uh analysis so
furthermore we tested the inhibition
activity of CBD on caspace one and
eventually we use spr technique to
directly measure The Binding Affinity
between CBD and CPAs one and all of
those are published data so cbase one is
the one that closely uh mediate the the
process of P pyroptosis which is
inflamation driven type of cell death
and we know that skin is more uh uh
prone to UV damage which is closely
associated with another newer type of
programmed cell death called ferroptosis
so what's ferroptosis it's a it's a a
programmed cell death and it's majorly
mediated by two biom markers one is the
ion level in the cells two is the lipid
peroxidation in the cells so our acid we
set up this a we expose cartinos side
cells to different inducers including
erastin which is a ferroptosis inducer
uh uh uh in this case and we use this
model to screen a whole liy of different
cannaboids CBD again very active and
there are more minor cannaboids that
work from more promising than CBD so
this is the data for CBD it could
effectively reduce the damage the cell
damage from erting and also reduce the
two most important biomarkers lipid
peroxidation and ion level in the cells
furthermore we use proteomic to take
look at the landscape of the protein
change in this process and we can
understand better what kind of like
proteins are involved in this uh skin
protective effect of
CBD and all of these are published data
if you have more questions I would more
than happy to answer them so after basic
research we still extended to kind of
like application research if you talk
about the dietary supplement you you we
we we in this case we measure the
stability of CBD in GI track and we also
study the skin penetration Capac
capacity of CBD using artificial
membrane based acids including Pampa
Francis division diffusion of those um
bio
acids all right to the next part is the
phytochemical investigation of hemp root
so this was very interesting if you read
Dr Russo's uh review paper on the uh uh
the Cannabis root which could be a
traditional treatment and also a future
treatment for pain inflammation so I I
was very interested in this this part of
this plant then I paid a visit to my
collaborators in China they're actually
the largest producers in China for hemp
and when I visit them I see just a
massive amount of root hemp root dumped
on the side of the road and they do
nothing about it they call it waste
products and they either either burn it
or just Landfield so for me as a natural
product chemist I feel pity because I
know there are so many good compound
goodies in this uh part of the plant so
what we did is a phytochemical
evaluation of this uh part of um plants
hemp Roots so U you can see I'm not
going to every compound that we have
isolated but you can see a part from uh
few cannaboids there's a large diverse
of bioactive compounds in hemp Roots the
CH the chem types of those uh uh
compounds are amazing you have phenolic
compounds you have TR turpins you have
phytosteroids you have fatty acids but
they are often overlooked in terms of
drug development but they could be very
valuable for neutral or kosutic
development uh just some highlight here
is that some of those compounds are
actually the first time that has been
isolated from hemp or from hemp Roots so
that's the chemistry we have done in in
in this part then we further took all
the isolate into the inflam inhibition
acid we first did the screening acid to
see their General anti-inflammation
activity then we test the uh the
cannaboids from from the roots and also
the non- cannaboids which showing
activity in the in the screening assd
showing testing if they have specific
anti-inflamm Activity one of those
compounds showing anti-inflamm activity
which is not a cannaboid type of
compound
so we took one more step further
although this one has been published but
we did one more step of study because
what we have missing is there are so
many different possibilities to get the
different type of compounds from uh hemp
root for example here we use different
extraction technology to further look at
the bioch uh the chemistry the
phytochemistry constituents from hemp we
you this one we were specifically
looking for alids from hemp roots
uh very interesting this is some
unpublished data this is our preliminary
result so we have fractionated those uh
extract from hemp roots and we further
generate uh the the the the fractions
the extracts that enriched in alids we
have so far four four fractions that has
uh enriched in uh uh alids and you can
see their anti-inflammation Activity
three out of the four has very good
anti-inflammation activity so that was
really triggered us we really want to go
deeper to see what kind of compounds are
responsible for this anti-inflammation
activity but if you think about the
aloid in hemp Roots you cannot forget
about this those compound called uh
canaban sativ those are the typical very
representative uh tative compounds from
hemp roots and that their Natural
Abundance in the root is very tiny it's
very hard to isolate those compounds
from from The Roots so now we have enr a
fraction that could have potentially
this type of compounds from the
preliminary data from the MMR from the
mass back uh uh hplc um uh TLC data we
have we suspect that there's one
fraction of those acoid enriched
fragment that is enriched in speron
which is uh uh the type of those type of
compound spermine which also showing
very strong anti anti-inflammatory
activity in our bio acids so our goal
our aim is to further look at what are
the chemicals in this fraction that
could be responsible for this um
anti-inflammation activity and if
there's a new compounds or more uh uh
representative compounds that could be
further used as the the the standards
for the future development of dietary
supplement or
neutral uh why the sperming is I feel so
excited about that many research support
that sperin is is a dietary uh dietary
compound could potentially affect the
longevity of uh uh human body and this
is supported by different type of um um
models animal models uh and uh it's
heavily associated with AutoPage which
is also a is and strateg for longevity
research uh and you can see now there
are already many this type of products
you can buy from Amazon and if you
search sper spermidine type of uh
supplements you can find many of them
but what I feel pity is that those type
of products more often you don't see the
standardization you don't know what what
exactly the spermidine type of sper
spermidine compounds are are in in the
bottle so there are so so lack of
research to support their potential
application their functional claims for
those type of supplements so I think
that's something we can do more about
this okay one last part is the skin
protective effect of compounds from hemp
Roots so again we go back to this
process in addition to isolate aclo from
hemp Roots we also look at phenolic
compounds and we were able to detect
this was only a detectable level so
meaning that the Natural Abundance of
this compound C leaving is very minor in
the hemp Roots so we were able to detect
it um and we did some biological
evaluations here too so what we have
here again we set up a cellular model
using a human Cortino site the skin
cells and we challenge the cells with
different oxidative stressors uh then we
extract the protein and analyze the the
proteo mix to see what kind of B markers
are related to this uh to this process
and this is a busy slides I'm not going
to the details but our
bioinformatics they share they they they
guide us to work through all those
biomarkers and constructed different
network to further explore the potential
biot Target and Pathways in this process
and from this large amount of data we
predict that flavinoids could be a
effect active compound that could be
used for the reduce the damage for for
the oxitive stress in the skin cells so
what we did was that we get canling a
and b we threw them into this cell based
uh acid for uh uh oxitive stress in the
skin cells and we did the biological
acid we were saying that at the
non-toxic level it could uh Camp living
A and B could both effectively reduce
the damage of the cells from from
oxitive stress it could reduce specific
biom markers that is uh related to uh um
oxitive stress in the in the in the skin
cells uh last part we also have the
mechanism of uh mechanistic study to
show that what could be the possibility
of those compounds in terms of reducing
inflame uh oxidation and also reduced
glycation in the skin cells and this
part has been published as well
so one last thought I want to share with
you is that when we talk about
development of a potential neutral or uh
cosmetical just like Pharmaceuticals CMC
is the last barrier for the drug to get
approved you heard about that from uh
the panel yesterday um so very similar
when you thinking of develop a neutral a
cosmetical ingredient from natural
products you always need to think about
Is it feasible it is commercially
possible uh even you have a lot of
strong rigorous data to support the
function in this case for example Camp
leaving C leaving a we were able to
isolate grams of campling from hemp hemp
Materia but this 30 G hempling was
isolated over from over 600 pounds of
the dry material so it's almost
impossible you can extract a fraction
from the hemp or from the root and
further use that for industrial scale up
it won't just be feasible so what could
be the Alternatives that we can produce
this type of compound as you just heard
the presentation before uh synthetic
pathway could be one route could be one
option to go so in this case OSB had a
collaboration with contract research uh
so we now establish the uh the uh the uh
organic synthesis of C fling a not only
canling a canl c flings a b c and ISO
flaven B so we were able to scale it up
to gram quantity in this case we scaled
uh those the production of those canling
in gram quantity which will enable us to
do further application research on on
the Cosmetic or neutural development so
this is what we have so
far okay just summarize here um we have
looked into the chemistry of cannaboids
we have looked into the chemistry of
hemp Roots we found that this is amazing
you have a lot a diverse group of
bioactive compounds from hemp roots and
there are so many potential compounds we
haven't even discovered them we don't
know what are they and they I believe
they do have the chance to further
developed into different neutral and the
data from the biological assay support
that support that that point so I feel
this is very promising in terms of
further development and that's exactly
why I think we should not rush it into a
products and sell the products this has
to be do more research about it toxicity
uh safety safety profile application
research formulation there are tons of
research we have to properly do do in
the right way to support its further
application as dietary supplement or
Cosmetics so that's um my last slide um
I know that I used all the time for the
presentation but I will be here all day
long so if you have any questions feel
free to come to me I would love to have
a discussion with you thank you so much
[Applause]
[Music]