thank you thank you very much and well
I'm gonna use my 15 minutes wisely I'm
gonna skip the CV part and I'm gonna go
straight to the data I am gonna present
the most recent research we have done in
the lab on the anti-tumor effects of
cannabinoids and we have been doing this
for 20 years already and it's pretty
clear to us not only for the research
that we have done in our lab but from
the research that other groups all over
the world have been doing during this
time that Cannavino it haven't eaten
more properties and they can produce
this effect by targeting different
stages of the disease they can sorry
they can kill cancer cells as it was
mentioned before they can also block the
feeding of the new to Merle masses a
process that we call angiogenesis and
they can also block the generation of
metastases but the truth is that the
vast majority of these studies have been
conducted with pure cannabinoids
not because we think this is the best
therapeutic approach but because we
wanted to understand what was going on
inside the cancer cells to understand
how can have you know it's work so it is
pretty obvious also and I don't think I
have to give you an extra explanation
today that the cannabis plant is a very
complex and sophisticated Factory and it
produces not only THC and CBD but a lot
of other cannabinoids and a lot of other
chemical compounds that have a very
interesting therapeutic potential for
example among the cannabinoids there are
more than 140 different entities and
some of them have very interesting
potential therapeutic applications some
have sorry
some have anti poor effective actions in
cancer cells groans groaning cultures
and the key issue here is that most of
them have not been studied
yeah and the same thing happens with
terpenes we know that some of them have
interesting therapeutic applications and
I highly recommend you to read the work
that Ethan Russo has published in these
regards and again most of these
compounds and we are talking about more
than 100 compounds weighing more than
100 compounds have not been studied and
studied yet and as did he mention before
when we talk about cannabis and about
other plants but can I was in particular
we have to keep in mind what we call in
pharmacology the synergistic effect or
what we call in this auditorium the
entourage effect which means that one
plus one is way more than two so with
all these things in mind the question we
try to address in this specific project
was if it was a better therapeutic
approach to use pure cannabinoids THC
CBD or whole plant preparations and to
answer this question we established a
collaboration with this company here
self therapeutics based in Australia and
we aimed at comparing the anti-tumor
effect of pure THC provided by THC farm
with that of a THC rich extract provided
by Unseld and non-profit mutual benefit
corporation based in California so we
have the analysis of a number of
cannabinoids not all of them but a
number of cannabinoids in the
preparation a number of turbines in the
preparation and because we wanted to be
sure that we were comparing the same
amount of THC in here and in here we did
not one lab test but three in different
facilities one in in the United States
and two in Spain and to corroborate this
information this data so we did this
experiments in different models of
breast cancer and my group is working on
breast cancer now and regarding this
pathology we use the same term breast
cancer to define pathologies that have
nothing to do we
one to each other in terms of molecular
markers markers treatments prognosis etc
so when doctors have to choose a
specific treatment for a breast cancer
patient they check for specific markers
and depending on these markers they sub
classify breast cancer in three subtypes
the first one is it's called hormone
sensitive because these cancer cells
Express estrogen receptors or
progesterone receptors and since the
stroke genic signaling is exacerbated
the aim of these therapies is to shut
down this signaling and we can do that
by different approaches we can remove
the endogenous source of estrogens by
removing the ovaries or we can use drugs
to interfere with this signaling and one
of them for example is I'm sure you have
heard about it is tamoxifen the second
type of breast tumors is called her2
positive because these cancer cells
express abnormally high levels of this
protein called Hertz what do the doctors
recommend to these patients well drugs
that specifically target this protein
this head to receptor trastuzumab
petaluma the names are irrelevant at
this point and there is a third entity
which is called triple negative and the
name is self-explanatory it's called
triple negative because these cancer
cells do not express estrogen receptors
or progesterone receptors or head to
receptors and unfortunately this is the
most aggressive phenotype and
unfortunately since there are no
specific markers there are no specific
drugs that we can use for these patients
and they have to receive a standard
chemotherapy that you will know that is
extremely aggressive
well we tried to answer the question I
mentioned before in the different
subtypes of breast cancer and we started
with the hormone sensitive and what we
did was to grow these cancer cells a
cell line that is called t47 d in in
this
petri dishes that did I showed you and
we challenged these cells with
increasing concentrations of THC THC
that came either from THC farm in other
words pure THC or from the botanical
drug extract from the whole plant
extract and as you can see and here what
we represent is cell viability is the
percentage of cells that remain alive in
the cell cultures and as you can see as
we increase the HC concentration these
dots go down in other words we are
killing the cancer cells and as you can
also see very easily in this graph the
tea the pure THC produces this
antitumoral action but the extract is
more potent than the pure cannabinoid in
order to see if this was an effect that
was exclusive exclusive exclusively
produced in this cell line or it was
more general and a hormone sensitive
breast cancer cells in general we
performed the second in the same
experiment in a second hormone sensitive
breast cancer cell line mcf7 and the
effect was exactly the same both
pooty-poo THC and the extract decreased
the viability of these cancer cells and
again the extract was more potent than
the pure compound we then moved to the
second subtype of breast cancer her2
positive and perform exactly the same
experiments and the response was exactly
the same both THC and the extract
decreased the viability of these cancer
cells in culture and again the extract
the purple line was more potent in doing
that than the pure cannabinoid and
finally we did these experiments in the
triple negative breast cancer cells and
I want to remind you that this is a very
aggressive subtype of breast cancer with
no targeted therapies yet
and we observed that these cancer cells
are also sensitive to cannabinoid
treatment both the buccal
in green and the extract in purple
decreased the viability of the two cell
lines of this subtype that we studied
and again
the botanical drug extract was more
potent than the pure compound so from
this part that take-home message is that
all breast cancer subtypes are sensitive
to cannabinoid antiproliferative action
and that the extract is more potent than
the pure compound so we next tried to do
something similar to what it is doing we
try to combine pure THC with the most
prominent most abundant terpenes in the
extract just to see if we could recreate
the effect of the whole plant extract
whole plant preparation by combining THC
which a bunch of other compounds and we
did that in the three subtypes of breast
cancer and I'm gonna guide you through
the graphs we represent here against
cell viability in percentage so this is
the amount of cells that we mean alive
again in the in the dishes and we want
this Bart bars to go as down as possible
and in the white bars you have the
control cells that says that the cells
that do not receive any kind of
treatment and in this line bar what you
see is the effect that the terpenes only
the five tapings produce on cell
viability which is none just using the
five connector pins you do not decrease
the viability you do not kill the cancer
cells what happens if we combine THC
with it with this terpene cocktail well
the effect is this one and if you
compare this bar with this one which is
the effect that the THC alone produces
it's very easy to see that combining THC
with a called trapping cocktail does not
increase the anti-cancer effect of a
pure compound we obtain exactly the same
effects in the other two subtypes this
is the effect of the terpenes alone in
these social lines this is the effect of
THC in the her2 positive this is the
effect of
the THC in the triple negative and when
we add the terpenes to the THC we cannot
improve the anti-tumor effect of the ATS
so combination of THC with these five
specific terpenes do not does not
recreate the effect of the potency of
THC so what about in vivo effect because
a lot of things work in vitro and we can
draw some conclusions for from in vitro
studies but we if we really want to sell
an anti-tumor tool we have to prove that
it works in more physiological settings
so what happens if we reproduce these
effects in animal models of cancer and
what happens if we combine this
Cannavino it with the standard therapies
that these patients receive well to
answer this question we conducted a
series of experiments in animal models
of the three different subtypes of
cancer and we studied with a hormone
sensitive ones and first of all we
started with in vitro studies to see to
analyze the combination of tamoxifen
this is the drug we used for this
studies so we studied what happened when
combining tamoxifen and cannabinoids in
vitro and as you can see here this is
the effect that the moxa fen alone
produces this is the effect that THC
alone produces this is a very low
concentration of THC and when we combine
THC and tamoxifen we see a synergistic
response and exactly the same thing
happens when we use not pure THC but the
botanical drug preparation what happens
if we move to the in vivo we will
observe the same thing well in this case
what we represent is tumor volume the
size of the tumors versus time and this
white dots represent how these tumors
grow when the animals receive no
treatment so the tumor masses grow grow
with no control this is the Green Line
is the effect that THC alone produces
and the purple line again
is the effect that the botanical drug
preparation produces and I think it's
pretty obvious to see that is more
potent than the pure compound and not
only that but if we compare the effect
of the botanical preparation with that
of tamoxifen which is the current
treatment that patients with this type
of tumors receive you can see that the
potency is exactly the same one we also
combine a tamoxifen with the botanical
drug preparation and we didn't see a big
increase in the antitumoral properties
of c of the preparation we perform
similar experiments in her to positive
models of breast cancer and in this case
we selected lapatinib one of the drugs
that target specifically target this
receptor and we obtained very very
similar results in vitro when combined
in lapatinib this drug with pure THC we
observed sign artistic responses
something very similar with the
botanical drug preparation and exactly
the same as we observed before in the in
vivo setting the white line again is the
control animals if we treat the animals
with pure THC we get modest antitumoral
response but if we use the whole pram
plant preparation the anti-tumor effect
is much much higher much bigger and if
we compare the antitumoral potency of
the whole plant extract with that of
lapatinib again we see that we have a
tool that is as potent as the current
medicine that these patients received
and what about the triple negative and I
remind you again the most aggressive
type of breast cancer that a woman can
have
well we observed exactly the same thing
when we combined in this case we used
chemotherapy agent cisplatin and this is
the effect that cisplatin produce alone
this is the effect that THC produces and
when we move to the in vivo again this
is THC
this is the botanical drug preparation
and as you can see it's more potent than
in the pure compound remain asleep the
rest of the lines because I don't have
time and the take-home message from this
part is that the THC rich extract is
more potent than pure THC both in vitro
and in vivo the THC rich extract is as
potent as the standard therapies that we
tested that are the standard treatments
that these patients are receiving and
unfortunately the combination of
cannabinoids with the tested and the
cancer treatments didn't improve the
potency of either one of them I don't
have time to discuss discuss why we
think this is going on but that's what
we observed and as a conclusion we have
more than enough evidence that
cannabinoids are effective 22 more tools
in preclinical models of cancer all
breast cancer subtypes respond to
cannabinoids whole plant preparations
are more potent than pure cannabinoids
and whole plant extracts are as potent
as current therapies I don't want you to
go home with a conclusion that the
extract we used in this paper is the
extract you have to give to your
patients the only point we wanted to
make is that it's better to use whole
plant preparations than pure compounds
and I want to finish by thanking the
people that did the work I'm just here
presenting it but these are the guys
that did it and here there is my small
team and I want to thank of course the
team of Unseld s that was absolutely
necessary for the performance of these
experiments thank you very much
you have time for one question if you
like what one minute left
Christina very nice there were small
amounts of Canaveral and
tetrahydrocannabinol a gas 'add have you
had the chance to test those to see if
they were the ones that made the
difference yeah that's an excellent
question
yeah I didn't point it to in in this
light but the extract had a little bit
of juicy VG and a little bit of another
cannabinoid THC a and we did check if
CBG combining THC and CBD we could
reproduce the effects and we were not
able to we haven't done the experiments
with THC a but that's something we want
to do a first very good question thing