all right I think I'm going to get
started so as you all know I work with a
lot of uh children with epilepsy and
autism and is often the case with uh
Canabis medicine we see all these
significant improvements but yet these
improvements are difficult to measure
objectively and so uh you may ask me
well if a child's doing well and the
parents are happy and the school is
Happy why do we need need objective
measurements and uh I think part of it
goes to what Dr meckler was just talking
about which isep the ongoing skepticism
within the medical
community uh they uh uh are still
somewhat resistant uh to patients using
cannabis especially children still
considered very controversial uh I don't
think so but many others do but the
other thing too is wouldn't it be nice
if somebody was spending $1,000 a month
and seeing great benefits in their child
that was covered by insurance and we all
know and I definitely see this that
insurance
companies um are are are not interested
in paying for this but I think we're
saving the insurance companies a huge
amount of money because these kids have
much uh lowered Health Care utilization
needs I definitely see it in my
pediatric epilepsy practice where these
children are not ending up in the ICU
every other month with status uh so it
would be nice if their insurance
companies would pay for some of these uh
medications for them um so I'm going to
talk about my research in uh using uh
phaco metabolomics which and measuring
salivary
biomarkers uh in uh to measure the
impact of medical cannabis in uh
children so I think we all know about
autism spectrum disorder as being this
heterogeneous condition with increasing
prevalence right now the CDC says one in
36 children
uh this is 241 per higher than what was
reported 24 years ago there's clear-cut
evidence of inflammation in both the gut
and brain and currently there's only two
FDA approved medications both anticho
discs which have a very serious short
and long-term side effects I have an
11-year-old patient in my practice who
gained 40 pounds in about 3 months on an
anticho and so it didn't help his
aggression it just made him bigger and
stronger uh and that's not really
desirable
um but if you're um looking at really
what what are the issues with autism we
talk about the three uh core symptoms um
that are listed here at the bottom and
no Pharmaceuticals address these so
communication difficulty and I say in
some because some people with Autism
communicate just fine uh impaired
reciprocal social interaction and
restricted repetitive and stereotype
behaviors of pattern we know boys are
more affected than girls uh we also know
some of the these patients have a very
significant above average intelligence
um but some have intellectual
disabilities uh there's numerous uh
clinical trials yesterday I I talked
about this in the medical practicum this
uh one particular uh review looked at 13
studies and uh what they found it's kind
of hard for me to see this uh four
observational studies that showed that
70 to 93 uh percent of participants had
Improvement it's a very high number
especially in this refractory uh
condition that's somewhat it really
doesn't have very many options uh two
retrospective reviews showed 61%
Improvement rates and behavior
67% improvements in those core symptoms
which Pharmaceuticals do not uh treat
three studies show there's uh they're
able to decrease uh dosing or
discontinue other medications and all
studies demonstrated a very acceptable
safety and tolerability and I don't have
a slide on this I talked about it I
think yesterday uh it appears that
children with autism have an endoc
canabo deficiency there's two studies
one from Israel and one from uh Stanford
University showing that uh they have
lower levels of anandamide and so
remember what anandamide is involved
with is uh pretty much everything that
we need in ter terms of regulating
emotional Behavior Uh also uh endoc
canabo are involved in immune function
and uh we know that there's a lot of
connection uh in terms of treating this
underlying likely endoc canabo imbalance
in these patients so I've treat hundreds
and hundreds of children already with
who have autism some of them have
comorbidity with uh seizures uh but this
is what the parents report and this is
fairly routine it's not every patient
but many of them less anxiety and by the
way anxiety is a number one condition
that uh parents come in for at these
kids like they just are so overly
anxious I I can't tell you I've actually
met met with patients like outside my
building cuz they wouldn't come in the
building or go up the
elevator less aggression towards others
and self better sleep less rigidity
improv socialization speech
communication better focus some patients
do have some improvement in the
repetitive behaviors what's interesting
is that you can see patients improve in
certain areas and not in others what I'm
finding difficult to treat in some of
these kids are some kind of OCD hoarding
behaviors which are really interesting
and I've had to kind of really try try
other things with those patients uh to
figure it out so the current approach is
trial and error and don't let anybody
tell you otherwise uh you start a
patient on um either combination CBD THC
or CBD dominant product the studies uh
mostly from Israel show that CBD
dominant will treat about 50% of your
patients and then you can start
tailoring it down if someone's
aggressive or has severe insomnia uh or
severe anxiety I'm I'm always uh
interested in using some THC in the
beginning but anyway the point being
here is that it's a really difficult
process to figure out these kids are all
different um and it's trial and error at
best and it's based on Parental feedback
it's time consuming it is incredibly
labor intensive for the clinician and
for the parent I make sure parents keep
notes
because one day can vary from the other
and sometimes you have to just look over
time how many days were better and how
many days weren't better because uh
there's just a lot of variability in the
response so the big question is who
might benefit can we pre-select who
might benefit and save
people uh uh time and energy and
resources also uh can we pre-select
cannabinoids and products and how do we
assess the outcome objectively and so
this brings me to the research I'm doing
with a company called can formatics and
all of our papers are open uh source so
there's three of them online if you just
Google my name and write put autism
research you'll find the papers so this
technology uses phico metabolomics which
is basically the systematic
identification and quantification of
metabolites in an organism or biologic
sample so we collect U metabolites which
are compounds that make up what we call
the metabolome and this is just these uh
compounds that reflect chemical Pathways
they allow you to see uh what is
happening in the brain and it looks at
phenotype versus genotype so you can do
the DNA studies but DNA remember just
gives you predictive if the gene isn't
turned on it's not being expressed it
may not necessarily help you in
determining uh how you should treat a
patient but when you're looking at the
the metabolites the metabolome it tells
you what's going on in that human right
at the moment that you're collecting
that uh
information and this is just the way
that the samples are collected and you
can do pharmacom metabolomic or metabol
testing really on any biof fluid any
tissue uh cultured cells and then what
we do is we uh collect the samples and
we send it in for nuclear Ms or a mass
speec and then uh you look at your Peaks
and you kind of uh scale your raw data
and then you have uh reports that you
can generate including heat maps and
also um you can uh put out pathway maps
and I'm going to show you examples of
those as we go through this and so this
was the first paper we put out and this
was um uh looking at the metabolites
that we collected and I'll go through
how we did it but really what we're
looking at is metabolites that reflect
the pathways that are involved in
inflammation bioenergetics amino acid
metabolism neuronal activity and the
endoc canabo system trying to see and
really ultimately just to make it simple
before cannabis we collect uh a sample
after their dose we collect a sample and
we see what changed what moved did it
correlate with behavior so we had 15
children with autism these are children
who were all on stable doses of medical
cannabis customized through my Care at
least for one year and we weren't
changing anything so that we could
see uh leave them on those stable doses
for at least 3 months prior to the uh
collection two saliva um samples were
collected and it wasn't a swab they
actually had to spit into a tube uh we
did it before they got their medical
cannabis dose in the morning and then
anywhere from an hour and a half to 2
hours after they got their medical
cannabis dose in the morning and so um
about midm morning and by the way this
was during Co we started before Co so it
got a little bit different during covid
where we just had to be like on the
phone with the family while they were
doing this um and then we did Behavior
surveys and we taught the parents how to
do the behavior surveys and they did the
survey at the same time as the first
saliva collection and the second saliva
collection and then we had a sample of
nine children typically developing no
evidence of any uh neurologic issues uh
no medical cannabis we just uh grabbed a
saliva sample in the morning and they
established our physiologic range which
you can see here so I just want to show
you this this was kind of how we set up
um how do we know what's um in that
physiologic range so here's um the
patients 1 through nine who are neuro uh
typically developing TD and here's their
average and then we figured out standard
deviations and what we decided for our
our um study was that greater than or
less than four standard deviations away
from the mean was considered um uh uh
out of the range and significant and was
um actually correlated with symptoms and
what you can see here this is this is
just uh what the uh before cannabis and
after cannabis that was just our
hypothesis of what it would look
like this is the um characteristics of
the patient so I'm just going to show
you here uh we started with age six
because under six is kind of hard to
collect saliva uh we needed one 1 ml of
saliva and so we went up to age 12 we
were trying to minimize the effects of
puberty although we did see some effects
of puberty you can see mostly boys this
is how many doses a day that they were
taking so one dose would be in the
morning if it was three doses morning uh
afternoon and evening now I just want to
point out Edibles and tinctures these
kids were all on tinctures nobody was
actually taking a gummy it's just we
called it inedible if it the parents
were putting it in food and then you can
see each child's cannabis uh regimen and
you can see that there's nothing um
consistent it's based on their own uh
response um working very hard with the
family to try to dial in using my rouet
in or rulet out and some of these kids
it took 2 years to find what worked for
them and remember that during the time
that you're taking care of these
patients new canabo are coming out and
then you want to maybe introduce
something new after somebody's um been
on something for a
while now here's the behavioral ratings
before cannabis and just to cut to the
chase red is severe Behavior Uh the
lighter colors are less severe and we
use three validated scales to assess
this uh the parental ratings of symptoms
before cannabis so so 11 of the children
were severe one child was moderate two
children were mild and we actually
missed data on one of the
kids and then this is after so you can
see that this improved 11 children were
considered um much improved uh two
children had mixed response so improved
in some areas but not in others and two
children actually had increased
difficulties at Peak and it's quite
possible that they were not happy about
having to give another saliva sample and
got you know again with the rigid
behavior and so on it's everybody's I
always say everybody's allowed to have a
bad day so uh these are the behavior
ratings and what you can see here is
under this Improvement these are pretty
high numbers here and then no change and
then you see on the end some uh actual
worsening for some of the
kids and so we detected 484 known
metabolites in the saliva 65 were
identified as cannabis responsive which
means that we found that they moved
after the Cannabis dose towards the
physiologic range and at least eight uh
to um 15 of the in at least eight of the
participants 31 of the metabolites were
detected in all the participants and 21
exhibited statistically significant
shifts and I'm not going to go just cuz
TimeWise I don't have that much time
into how we calculated but these are
algorithms they're explained in the
paper but it just gave us a way to
measure the change and kind sort out the
zc
scores and so here and I showed this
yesterday I think I can't remember now
um uh anical aspartate which is one of
the most abundant neurochemicals in your
brain it's the second most abundant
after um glutamate and what we found and
and there's already research that exists
that shows that anical aspartate which
is involved in neuronal function and
density and can reflect neuronal
dysfunction um this particular compound
has already been document mented to be
low in some individuals with autism or
elevated in some individuals with autism
and the elevation was Associated more
with high functioning Aspergers type um
uh symptoms um but what you can see here
so these are the patients along the
bottom A1 A2 A3 A5 so let's just look at
A2 so A2 had very high
NAA uh prior to their medical cannabis
and what you see after they take their
Med medical cannabis is it as much lower
and it's towards this is the physiologic
mean here established by the typically
developing groups you can see here
they're all kind of tightly uh clustered
around this average here and then this
gray line is the um uh plus two or min-2
standard deviations away from the mean
so what you see though is that look at
A3 there's basically no NAA measurable
and then it comes up towards the mean
when it's um high as you can see in the
older kids they all kind of had high NAA
that all came down towards the
physiologic mean so here's some
objective evidence of the homeostatic
nature of cannabinoids as well as
shifting those compounds towards that
physiologic range that was established
by the children who don't have autism so
I was really excited to see this I
didn't think that we would see such uh
great results and then I showed this
yesterday and if you haven't seen this
this is just three of the older
boys this is uh plotted out go on this
side uh here's your mean that goes down
from the arrow the minus 2 to plus two
in the green column these are all the um
U metabolites listed on the left hand
side and you can see kind of how they're
all out of range and then uh after
medical cannabis you see this is very
crystal clear that what's happening and
what the parents are reporting what the
parents are reporting is we're seeing
this incredible shift of these various
metabolites remember they reflect
inflammation neuronal function uh they
are correcting now it seems to be a
temporary correction cuz if these are
kid kids on cannabis uh around the clock
or all the time why are they having this
initial and this was 8 hours at minimum
of 8 hours without cannabis so it's a
temporary cor correction so I don't ever
want anybody to think that quote we're
curing patients but I do think what
we're doing is giving them a natural
non-toxic option to have a decent
quality of life
and to live in a more physiologic
balanced
State and so what we did was we decided
to see if machine learning could help us
understand more about our findings and
this was a report that we published in
August 23 there was a second report
which I'm not including here where we
looked at just the lipid based um uh
metabolites uh but then we took all this
data and we decided to see what machine
learning could tell us and so we had a
lot of data you see three categories of
children so we had typically developing
children and their saliva metabolites
and then we had the category of children
before they took their cannabis and
those metabolites and then the category
of of the same children but the
metabolites after their cannabis and
then we had lots of metabolites to look
at as you can see in the corner down
here and then we looked at the
correlation of these metabolites in
these categories of
children uh with just the three of the
main cannaboids the other cannabinoids
that you saw listed on that chart
including thca cbda and CBM we just
didn't have enough data and there
weren't enough children on those uh um
canabo to be able to assess it and so
what we did was we created numerical
scales for the dosing and you can see
here uh and it was somewhat arbitrary
but we had to create some type of
scaling so that we could uh feed the
data in and what you can see here is the
dosing uh each dosing range uh got a
number each behavioral response got a
number and that was what uh uh we gave
um uh along with all the uh metabolite
um data
sets and so I can't include every
finding but um I'm going to highlight
kind of the most exciting findings here
so this is I'm starting kind of
backwards than what's in the paper but
basically we looked at differentially
expressed non cannabinoid plant
metabolites and we found seven
phytochemicals including uh flavone uh
Rootin rutin is a type of
coratin um vexin which is um
apennine uh naringenin zanthin corosolic
uh acid and uh cyto sterol and they were
all associated with Shifting the
Cannabis responsive
biomarkers excuse me from large standard
deviations away from the mean towards
that physi logic mean so what does that
mean and so all of these compounds are
have some evidence of being uh acetool
and esterase Inhibitors which are
involved in you know memory learning
attention motivation Dr um meckler
mentioned acetool and esterase um and so
what we found though and if you look
here um what you can see is this gray
bar is pre so this is your just um you
can see that here so before Medical
canab this is chyc acid uh this is where
the kids sat with their um uh
metabolites and that for corol acid and
then the second bar is after cannabis
and the third one is in the children who
don't take cannabis so why would it be
there well remember it's a phyto
chemical so it's maybe in salad or some
other uh plant material that the child
was taking but notice that none of the
others here were found in the typically
developing uh patients um but the point
being that these compounds were
associated with improvements and um we
hypothesized that this um contributes to
the idea of the Entourage effect that
it's not just the canabo it's also these
plant compounds because these were found
to um stand out uh in the patterns that
were discovered now here this ven
diagram documents the identification of
the autism um cannabis responsive
biomarkers that distinguish categories
of the patients and so U machine
learning found one particular compound
that stood out to be different between
the diagnosis of autism and the children
without autism and that's the one that's
Landing right here in the middle and
what you can see here is that before
medical cannabis it's this very wide
variability this wide range and then
with medical cannabis it corrects
somewhat closer to the typically
developing but it never
achieves uh that kind of uh tight range
and so it seems that this particular
compound called lysop pe18 to1 can
distinguish between Autism and uh and uh
basically make the diagnosis so we're
hoping to do further research on this
because currently as we know there is no
test for uh autism and we're hoping that
just by collecting saliva we might be
able to uh have some support of the
diagnosis again remember it's a clinical
diagnosis where you answer questions and
it's somewhat
subjective uh Additionally the uh
machine learning documented that there
was no evidence of any negative impact
of cannabis that no biomarkers moved
away from the physiologic range but this
may be due to the fact that all of these
patients were on canabo that we knew
were helping them right this was already
personalized data and I suspect that if
you were get to get a baseline before
somebody started medical cannabis and
you started some type of uh regimen and
then you checked the metabolites again
you actually might especially if you saw
unwanted behaviors or worsening sleep or
something like that we might see a shift
away from the physiologic range um but
the whole idea here is to try to
understand these metabolites and use
them as a tool to follow treatment and
design
regimens and uh this is uh the last um
um uh finding that I'm going to share
and to me it's the most exciting is we
discovered a number of biomarkers that
were impact by the specific cannabinoids
and so this is truly the understanding
of the mechanisms of action so we
understand um which receptors which
Pathways CBD might affect for instance
but we don't have the information of the
underlying chemical status of the human
being we're treating we're making an
assumption and it's trial and error and
so this data can tell you about the
Baseline characteristics so for instance
I'm just going to share a quick story my
parents live in Upstate New York it's
dark most of the year it's like not nice
weather and um the doctor there I had
asked her to check their vitamin D
levels and she said well we don't check
those we just give everybody vitamin D
but wouldn't you want to know I know
everybody's shaking their head you kind
of know where you're starting and where
you're ending up I mean that's kind of
how we we practice medicine so needless
to say we don't go to her anymore but um
uh point being that I want to know the
Baseline chemistry and I want to know
what these cannaboids are affecting I'm
very happy with the fact that when a
parent tells me the child is doing well
that's great but what about the kids
that I'm struggling to treat because not
everybody responds the same way be like
to understand their chemistry and so um
THC we found was associated with 11
different uh cannabis responsive
biomarkers CBD was associated with seven
cannabis responsive biomarkers but
really interesting there was no overlap
so anybody who we've heard over and over
the past two days THC plays a very
important role there are some people who
are sensitive to it but in general if
you are only using CBD isolate you are
missing out on some of these Pathways
and may not be achieving uh that full
treatment that the uh Pat patient might
benefit from CBG was associated with 15
cannabis responsive biomarkers more than
THC and
CBD and there was
um uh overlap okay so three biomarkers
overlapped between uh THC and CBG and
only one overlap between CBD and CBG but
what's interesting is there's been some
uh two reports in the literature
reporting that CBG plays uh may have a
uh reside far sorry reside
pharmacologically between TC and CBD I
it it has the and and I think it was Dr
Russo who mentioned yesterday that CBG
has overlapping effects with both you
can use a lower dose but it's non
impairing and so that gives you a nice
tool to be able to use in these patients
and I definitely see benefits with CBG
in these kids if you're treating kids
with autism do not ignore you could
start with CBD and THC but definitely uh
try CBG I've seen a fair amount of
improvement in speech verbal abilities
and
focus all right and then here my
research Partners who are brilliant say
this is simplified I don't think there's
anything simple about this um but we
combined the U machine learning data
plus the information we gathered to
create this metabolic uh
pathway and THC is in the green color
and you can see it's strongly linked to
endoc canabo metabolic pathways
including uh interacting with anandamide
and
2ag uh CBG which is in like the mauve
color was associated with 2ag
arachidonic acid and ethanolamine which
is a phospholipid THC and CBG were also
associated with a variance of e
ethanolamine which are also
phospholipids you can see those in the
green with the red border and CBD is in
blue and was really associated with
numid uh numerous lipid-based Pathways
uh in that are involved in influencing
oxidative stress and up in the corner
here what you see it says ASD and
depression what's interesting is we
found some overlap in the scientific
literature of these various compounds
that changed quite a bit in response to
uh cannabis medicine um that were also
involved um in
depression and so how can we use these
uh biomarkers so we can use them as I've
mentioned for diagnosis does this
individual have the condition they can
be predictive will this patient um
benefit from medical cannabis what if
you get back you do a a saliva test
before you treat and everything is in
the optimal range is that a person that
you necessarily need to treat I would
still always offer treatment if there
were issues but at least it gives you
that Baseline status to and and have
expectations pre-dosing which I'm going
to show you a slide what about dosing
and cannabinoid profile what should we
pick first um response how well is the
individual
responding and also what's the response
over time is it maintaining I will tell
you that puberty really rocks this
community uh they become uh much uh for
many of them they become much more
aggressive they have more sleep issues
they can be perfectly dialed in on their
cannabis and then they hit like 13 and
all of a sudden it all falls apart and I
always call kids moving Targets in the
Cannabis World cuz you're const
constantly changing things um but here I
want to just show you one last slide I
have a perfect minute and 40 SEC uh 40
seconds so here is the unhappy child
that comes into my office and this is
their heat map this shows you and again
red is symptomatic the dark blue is
physiologic and the light blue is
optimal so this child really does not
have anything in the optimal range uh
and all that red there and by the way
you can look at this and then when you
repeat the test you can just compare the
p
individually but if we have a database
and here I have another patient who has
a very similar profile that's already
being treated you could see I think
they're happy over here and you can see
that these uh you get correction
shifting towards that physiologic range
that gives us a chance to kind of dial
in treatment and not have to be so trial
and error and not have to look for every
cue and so it gives us a chance to
follow these patients so I'm really
excited to do more research
um this um uh technology can be applied
to we're looking at doing some research
um with some uh people in New York for
dementia uh we're trying to work with
some people in Canada to look at this
for epilepsy as well and then Ethan and
I have talked about using this to see if
there's any
metabolic uh changes in patients with
CHS and so uh and uh there's a fair
amount of application and this at least
is by the way you can send a kit to to
somebody's house they can collect Sal
saliva and send it in it's
noninvasive and um uh very easy and also
lowc cost so uh thank you very much I'm
happy to answer any questions
[Applause]
[Music]