[Music]
all right
so
um let's let's talk about the result
results of your research so how many
different studies were you able to to
look at and what were sort of the the
main takeaways there
yeah so as you said our review looked at
the what we consider to be next day
effects of THC so basically we were
looking to identify any Interventional
studies so studies where either cannabis
or THC had been administered in some
form and their participants have been
required to undertake or perform some
kind of either simulated safety
sensitive task for things like driving
or are there some studies on simulated
airplane flying or some more sort of
standard and sort of common I guess
computerized cognitive tasks and there's
a wide variety of of those sorts of
activities and so to be included in the
review the studies had to have done this
and measured performance at least eight
hours following cannabis use because
that's sort of what we consider to be
um I guess your typical overnight
recovery period And so studies most of
them administered the tasks between sort
of 8 and 12 hours following cannabis use
and and some administered all the way
through
often they conducted testing at multiple
time points they might have measured at
12 hours and then 24 hours and sometimes
all the way up to 48 hours so we found a
total of 20 studies that had done this a
little published quite some time ago
there was a little bit of recent work
but largely historical and they measured
quite a number of different outcomes I
think it was several hundred uh
different sort of organists sorry
several hundred different tasks and
that's across all the studies at all the
different time points and um under all
the different cannabis conditions so
often the studies would administer one
dose of THC on one study and and a
different dose on or sorry one dose of
DHC on one arm of one study and a
different dose and a different arm in
the same study so you end up with like
you know the amount of data sort of just
increases exponentially as you start to
include these different arms and
different time points so yeah it turned
out to be a reasonably large undertaking
um but yeah
what we included in our review
okay and what were the results are were
you finding that people were impaired
after eight hours or or no
um so the vast majority of studies
showed no next day effects of THC so
that was across a variety of different
cognitive tasks and safety sensitive and
safety sensitive sorry simulated safety
sensitive tasks there were a small
number of studies that detected next day
effects but I guess an important element
of this review is not just to look at
quantity although there were overming
majority showing no next AFX but also to
look at the quality of the studies and
what they're sort of showing and when we
looked closely at this sort of small
number of studies showing subtle next
day effects they tended to be not such
good quality so
um none of them were randomized
controlled trials for example which is
our most rigorous form of Interventional
study and they often
um and they didn't tend to have the
um employ the best sort of
standardization procedures so what I
mean by that is we're really interested
in making sure that the studies we
um were sort of reading into used
um but didn't allow their participants
to sort of consume alcohol 24 hours
prior to you know undertaking tasks
caffeine stay up all night all of those
things that can go on to affect
cognitive function we wanted to be sure
that they had been controlled out of the
sort of context so
um basically the gist is the studies
that did show next day effects which
there were very few of
um tended not to be great quality
um whilst there was a couple among those
showing sort of no next day effects that
were quite good quality so that seems to
be whether the evidence is at the moment
[Music]
thank you