[Music]
Now, is that a a common finding that
these rare canabonoids in the low
concentrations are find are offering
more promise perhaps than the ones we
know and love like THC, CBD, CBG?
So I will say the 50% in the cases.
Sometimes it's CBG, CBC, CBDV, the more
known ones. Yeah.
But in half of the cases is the rare
cannabonoids. But I want to say
something, okay, which is
important. If you didn't see it and
never heard about it, doesn't mean that
it's rare, okay? Doesn't mean that it's
low concentration.
So the the molecule that we saw that
killing the leukemia it's unknown
cannabonoids it's a new one whatever but
it's the third more expressed in this
strain so it was 2.3%
oh really it's not really minor it's not
really rare it's not low
percentage if the the the regular
equipment of or the HLC and we don't
have standard so we don't see it usually
doesn't mean that it's rare or or very
in low concentration. Okay. So, usually
these are not, you know, a a a very
extremely low concentration. It's not
0.001%. It will be
0.5%, 1%,
1.5%. But it's an
unknown molecule. So,
so it's a so it's sort of a limitation
of
Sorry for cutting you. If you look on
other plants, okay, even you know today
people talk about a lot of mushroom
functional mushrooms so mushroom if you
look on the concentration of the
molecule there which consider active it
will be 0.2% 0.5% 0.1%. Mhm. In cannabis
when you saying 0.3% you you think it's
it's rare or minor but if you
translate if if if if a patient using
one gram just for it will be easy to
calculate you know the average amount of
a patient in Israel it's
32.5 gram a month so it's an average of
one gram okay so
if if if a molecule is expressing
0.5% in
this flower. It will be 50 milligram a
day. 50 milligram it's drugable. 50
milligram it's it's it's not low amount
for a drug or a molecule to affect your
body. So it's not really rare or minor.
We are wrong to call them like that.
Interesting. So you're
saying with the testing labs or the
equipment or sort of the methods that
they're using, there could be these
unknown canabonoids that are are there
in concentrations, but they're just not
seeing it with the equipment or not
reporting it on the on the COA. I'm not
saying maybe we know that like it's
after 10 years I can tell you exactly.
Yes, sure.
A lot of the cannabonoids which express
in quite high amount you don't see or
you don't
read. Usually the laboratories have the
ability to do that. But because it's not
interesting to anybody and it cost more
money it will cost instead of you know
$50 or 40 $40 for for the test it will
cost $300. Usually the grower not asked
for these
readings and and usually the
laboratories not developed method to
look on them. Right? Every good
laboratory in the US that have masspec
or GCMS can take my paper read it and in
one day be able to see that. Okay. It's
not something that it's difficult.
there is no economic demand for that,
right? And and that's that's the reason
[Music]