good morning and thank you very much for
the opportunity to be here my name is
Jeff friggin rather I'm a physician in
California I have a private practice in
California doing cannabis consulting for
the last 20 years this has been a really
enjoyable change from family or from
general practice and from ER medicine to
go into cannabis medicine I take this
practice very seriously I've I'm kind of
an old-style physician I I request
patient records before I see patients I
usually a set up an appointment for
about 90 minutes for my initial adult a
consultation two hours for children so
in California we can see anybody from
you know of any age group with any
conditions so I want to know if that's
in the record the problem that they're
coming to me about and and then
basically tailor a treatment plan to
work with them I am president of the
Society of cannabis clinicians this is a
group that started in about 2000 and
I'll talk a little bit more about this
as we go along so we all choose our
evidence as it meets our needs and there
are ancient sources of information that
are very interesting they're burial and
tombs that are you know where cannabis
has been used in the past we have
evidence from William o Shaughnessy back
in the middle of the nineteenth century
he was spoken of yesterday going from
England to to Calcutta back in 1833 and
working there for over a decade
learning about cannabis and writing
about it and eventually bringing it back
to England as a medicine in 1844 some
cling to the reefer madness level of
information and you know that's just
something we have to deal with
doctormick areia the founder of this
society of cannabis clinicians wrote a
book that wasn't published at ni MH he
was there as a as a doctor studying
cannabis in the 1960s and 70s and when
he was asked to go to California and and
spy on the college students smoking
cannabis he realized they really were
that interested in the medicinal uses of
cannabis but his book was about the
English language literature on medical
marijuana from 1839 until 1972 of course
we have the LaGuardia reports in 44 and
the Schaffer Commission in 72 both these
documents exonerated cannabis as being a
problem they basically said that
cannabis users are indistinguishable in
our society from those that don't use
cannabis and then we have the IND
program that the government was really
forced to get involved when got involved
with because patients who weren't
getting adequate treatment with
conventional medicines basically sued
the federal government and the federal
government was then forced to allow them
to use cannabis as medicine then they
about a year later they forced the
government to actually supply them with
the cannabis so there's are still a half
dozen or so patients using cannabis from
the federal government there were at
least 19 that were using cannabis over
the years and then George Bush senior
came along and in 1992 closed the
program saying there was no scientific
value to marijuana
well it's interesting to note that the
feds never looked at any of these
patients or their experiences or what it
was doing for them that's just the way
it is the federal agenda was to keep
cannabis down so the feds parental
perennial e refused to reschedule
cannabis and they continued to put out
misinformation to the public and to the
physicians basically scaring people from
the use of cannabis and even as early as
just a month months ago in January we
had an update from the National
Academies of Sciences talking about need
for greater research well this is kind
of a problem because we can't get the
research that we want certainly not in
terms of cannabis as a medicine we can
get it as cannabis as a drug of abuse
those research projects are approved and
done by NIDA but as far as the medicine
it just doesn't happen for the
physicians doing cannabis work we have
our clinical evidence so cannabis as you
probably well know is one of the most
studied therapeutically active
substances in history far exceeding
almost all pharmaceuticals the pubmed
literature and the Google Scholar
literature is full of tens of thousands
of papers on these subjects of course
you already know that the cannabinoid
receptors are in the animal kingdom
accepting insects from Hydra to humans
so it's there as a modulating system to
keep our bodies in balance you've seen
this already today this is the presence
of the cb1 receptors in their brain so
the receptors are their modulating the
way the nervous system works and in the
peripheral nerve endings throughout the
body as well as in the immune system
also modulating the immune system in the
tonsils and the adenoids and the liver
and the spleen and the T cells and the B
cells so it's not that the federal
government doesn't understand this
modulating endocannabinoid activity may
have therapeutic potential in almost all
diseases affecting humans including this
laundry list of conditions this came out
of NIH four years ago so they understand
this it's just that they're not thinking
of cannabis as the way to get there
they're looking to protect the interests
of the pharmaceutical industries to
bring us new generations of medicines
this is just an incomplete but longer
list of the pharmacologic effects of
cannabinoids that we saw in part
yesterday and you can scan through them
to see the kinds of things that
cannabinoid activation is known to do in
the body but what do we hear from the
government their health assertions of
harm in the pulmonary tract possible
smoking cannabis causing lung cancers
brain injuries addiction psychosis
schizophrenia and impairment short-term
memory loss and driving as well as fetal
and neonatal harm are all asserted and
we continue to get really bathed in this
misinformation that comes from the
government let's start and pick apart a
little bit of this
Donald tashkin
professor emeritus of pulmonary medicine
at UCLA and he's worked for NIDA for
forty five years in an effort to find
harm in smoking cannabis well he does
show that smoking cannabis causes
irritation of the airway some
inflammation some edema and some
increase in mucus production but there
is no evidence of clinically significant
alterations in pulmonary function
studies
this means no COPD no emphysema even in
the heavy cannabis users and going on to
do a large epidemiologic study he showed
that there is no substantive evidence of
any increase in the incidence of cancers
of the lung trachea larynx pharynx or
esophagus even in the heavy cannabis
smokers if you pick at his data a bit
you'll see that those that are smoking
cannabis and smoking tobacco had a 37%
decrease in the incidence of developing
any of these cancers
what about marijuana studies at Kaiser
Stephen Sydney is a doc epidemiologist
in kaisers Oakland a division and he
looked at nearly 65,000 patients and
divided him into cohorts of non-smokers
marijuana smokers and tobacco smokers
and just looking at the cancers of the
lung the tobacco smokers went on to
develop 46 cancers over a short period
of time the non-smokers had two lung
cancers in the marijuana smokers none so
getting these cannabinoids into the
lungs when we're irritating the lung
seems to actually be responsible for
extinguishing these cells and causing
them to not become a problem brain
injury we know that short term memory
impairment has been observed after heavy
chronic recreational cannabis usage but
it virtually disappears after abstinence
and more recent studies are similarly
encouraging with regards to
reversibility of any cannabis associated
cognitive sequelae hippocampal volume
changes are asserted by the government
but the most recent studies there show
that there's no significant gray matter
changes observed in cannabis users and
then lower grade point average
and IQ and performance differences are
asserted in teens using cannabis but
these two are insignificant when
controlling for tobacco and alcohol use
the knight of director often quotes they
surmised neurotoxic effect of cannabis
on the developing brain that permanently
lowers IQ this study was reviewed at the
University of Oxford and finds the
conclusions premature in light of likely
confounding from socioeconomic status
what about addiction we've talked about
this a bit already
and it's postulated that and there's an
often-quoted
incidence of 9% of ever cannabis users
becoming dependent at some point on
cannabis well we have to temper this a
bit with it facts that this is based in
part on substance abuse treatment
programs and so as these people come
into these programs the majority of them
don't really have a substance abuse
program a problem they're there because
it's mandated that they either go to
jail or to court or take the substance
abuse program so this is more or less a
laughable condition for my thousands of
patients that I've seen over the years
they don't have any trouble coming and
going from cannabis use they may like
cannabis use and you might say they're
habituated to it but they're not
addicted to it and there's no
significant withdrawal and they can come
and go from cannabis use quite easily
what about psychosis and schizophrenia
well this is really depending on your
viewpoint your perspective if you have a
child that's gone on to develop
schizophrenia and he or she may have
smoked pot as a teen you may very well
feel that this has been responsible for
your teens change
well causality is unsupported by the
literature if you look at the Keele
University study this is the largest
study that I've seen done came out of
England it studied cannabis use in the
clinic system in the UK for 10 years
from 1996 through 2005 and over that
period of time 2.3 percent of the
English population came through the
clinic system and of those during that
time there was
an increase in cannabis use in the
general population by four-fold and in
the 18 and younger population they had
an 18 fold increase in the use of
cannabis and when they looked at the
population and the incidence of
psychosis and schizophrenia they found
that the incidence and prevalence of
schizophrenia and psychosis were either
stable or declining during this decade
when cannabis use was increased so much
fetal and neonatal harm again assertions
of harm and doctors are quite afraid of
its use in can opinion in nursing
mothers mothers and in pregnant women
but the evidence isn't there either
maternal marijuana use during pregnancy
is not an independent risk factor for
adverse neonatal outcomes after
adjusting for confounding factors and in
a study a little ways back marijuana use
was relatively common in pregnant women
and was not related to adverse pregnancy
outcomes it was the tobacco and tobacco
is still the most commonly abused drug
during pregnancy and responsible for
adverse pregnancy outcomes probably the
most important study is one from Melanie
Dreier when she went to Jamaica and
studied pot smoking pregnant women she
had 30 women that were heavy pot smokers
and she got thirty others that were
there they're a group of non-smoking
women that they compared to and she
followed these people through their
pregnancy their labor delivery and and
through the first neonatal month of life
and without reading the the fine print
basically she said that the kids that
came out of these pregnant pregnancies
from pot smoking moms we're actually
doing better at the end of the first
month of life they were more alert they
didn't need as much arousing and they
just seemed to be doing well she got
this paper published in Pediatrics in
1994 then went back several years later
to see how these kids were doing later
on in life and she found again that they
were actually doing better than than the
control group she went back to
Pediatrics magazine with her evidence
and asked to prep
her information they said no this is the
earth-mother syndrome they explained
it's just that these pot smoking moms
were better mothers so what about the
future
cannabis is making a difference and is
likely to continue to play a role in the
world of mainstream medicine with or
without the federal government's
prohibition we know that we have to have
clean medicines available in that to
have any product approved as a
pharmaceutical it must have proof of
biochemical uniformity and stability
along with safety and efficacy as proven
by the randomized clinical organ
controlled trials this is the problem
because the federal government does not
want to see these studies so they're not
done so we don't get the evidence that
we're looking for basically you have to
have approval by NIDA DEA FDA I think
maybe PHS is off the hook now Public
Health Service but Health and Human
Services all have to approve a study
before it can be done in the United
States as a randomized controlled study
of cannabis so basically the federal
bureaucracies and the influence from the
pharmaceutical industry and what I would
call the drug war industries effectively
prohibit cannabis studies but the public
has changed the world here because word
of mouth from person to person now has
it to where we have changed the laws in
many many of our states the darker green
states are those where we've approved
adult use of cannabis the pale green
states are the ones where we have
medical marijuana and not even shown or
17 more states where we've where states
have approved the use of cannabinoids
that are not psychotropic mainly
speaking of CBD so what about the
evidence
there's valid you know randomized
controlled studies that we basically
can't get and then we have our clinical
observations the founder of the SCC dr.
Tod mikuriya years ago said we have a
problem with this gold standard stud
because we can't we can't use it we're
not getting the opportunity to study
cannabis in controlled studies this
randomized controlled trials were
ushered into medicine in the 40s while
the time modern honored clinical
observations have a have been assigned
to anecdotal and really invalid evidence
which I would argue with it is valid
evidence the value of the randomized
controlled study depends upon the study
design and who's funding the study and
what they intend to show and the value
of the clinical observation hinges to
upon the expertise and the reliability
of the observer they both have
opportunity for institutional or
personal bias
you know we had Vioxx some years ago a
great anti-inflammatory drug it went
through our CTS but 55,000 people died
of cardiac deaths even though it had
gone through the the studies of being
able to show that it was supposedly safe
and effective so just because it's an
RCT doesn't really show that it's safe
so the feds continue to refuse medical
cannabis research we this is an
interesting little bit that Kant has
come out of the American Academy of
Ophthalmology in 1992 basically saying
marijuana safety and efficacy or safety
hasn't been demonstrated through the
federal regulatory process I would say
that it never will get the federal
regulatory process so what they had said
was that there is no scientifically
verifiable evidence that the use of
marijuana is safe and effective in the
treatment of glaucoma they had studied
it back in the 70s it does lower it to
ocular pressure what they never looked
at was the neuro protective qualities of
cannabis that are exceptional and for
which the government has patented the
use of a patented cannabinoids I should
say and then in 1997 the the National
Eye Institute in the NIH concluded that
none of the studies demonstrate that
marijuana or marijuana or any of its
component
because safely and effectively lower
intraocular pressure get this any more
than a variety of drugs on the market so
they don't want it to be studied they
don't want the competition so cannabis
is effective for her glaucoma and I've
been watching it for years in my own
patients with stability in their
glaucoma but again this is problematic
when it comes to research because we
really can't get it with the embargo on
cannabis clinical studies what the
Society of cannabis clinicians did was
reformed our own journal o'Shaughnessy's
was published in 2003 we put out a
couple issues a year or an issue a year
since that time and it gave us an
opportunity to publish our clinical
findings without the requirements of the
RCT the IRB and the peer review that
would be required in order to try to get
a controlled study and so the journalist
called of Shaughnessy's again named for
William o Shaughnessy the English
physician who went to Calcutta in 1933
stayed there over a decade observing and
writing about and studying the use of
cannabis and he was quite influential as
he took this in Furman information back
to the English in 1844 here in 1843 his
paper led the paper his article on
Indian hemp or ganja and how to prepare
it so he was preparing cannabis for use
as an anticonvulsant and for other
medical uses well I know Shaughnessy's
in our first issue we also put up
doctormick areas cannabis as a
substitute for alcohol and really
throughout our journal every issue we
have our clinical studies and we have
our observations that we show which are
very useful for clinicians and for our
patients as long as we give it to our
patients for free we can get it for a
very low price this is just a case that
appears in o'Shaughnessy's this is a
baby that came to me 16 months of age
you'll see a large tumor deep in the
brain on the left-hand column
we he was advised chemotherapy and
radiation therapy
the parents said I'll get back to you
and they came to me we started putting
the full extract cannabis oil on his
pacifier you see three months later the
column shows the tumor fading and in the
middle column five months after we
started putting the cannabis oil on his
pacifier the tumor had virtually
disappeared this yes thank you this
kiddo is now in first grade he has gone
through some IQ testing to just see how
he's doing he measured it a hundred and
thirty five so no one's worried about
this little guy and then Crohn's disease
this is a subject that I'll briefly
review because I really am running out
of time my first publication on our
pilot study was in 2005 on a dozen
patients with Crohn's disease all of the
early docs in the society reported our
benefits with using cannabis in Crohn's
disease we went on to study what is Oh
put out of Italy for years showing all
of these pharmacologic physiologic
effects of cannabinoids in the gut on
the cb1 and cb2 sides and then we had we
got 38 patients with Crohn's disease to
come into the study and we asked them
about with and without cannabis what's
your paying your appetite nausea
vomiting fatigue stools per day
depression activity level flare up
frequency and severity and what's their
weight and so these columns here each
pair of columns represents each
patient's response stools per day were
down from 5.3 on a mean number of stools
per day to 3.7 with smoked cannabis pain
was markedly down regulated appetite
markedly up regulated nausea down
regulated you see the p-values over on
the right side as well vomiting markedly
down regulated fatigue down regulated
depression significantly down regulated
and the psychiatrist that I've seen
showed this to say this oughta be
published independently commonly drugs
don't work this well for depression
activity level up regulators so in spite
of what you might think about people
smoking pot all day they get up and go
when they're using cannabis for Crohn's
disease their weights are up about 12%
their flare-up frequency is markedly
down in their flare-up severity
similarly is markedly down so in
conclusion the clinical observations and
findings are valid evidence of the
safety and efficacy of cannabis where do
we go from here well with the industry
coming along as it is I think it's time
to buy our legislators like the
prohibitionists have been doing for so
long
[Applause]
you