[Music]
welcome to the cbag Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on the camed
Summit okay we just announced our first
round of poster presenters who will be
sharing their work at the camed 25
Innovation and investment Summit this
June in Puerto Rico you can read all
about each of them on our speaker page
at canmed events.com along with our
confirmed oral presenters and panelists
who will be participating in the
Cannabis genomics workshop and the
compliance testing Workshop
you can check out the caned practicum
instructors as well and don't forget
that doctors and clinicians can earn six
continuing medical education credits by
attending the
practicum all the details are at camed
events.com be sure to sign up for email
alerts so you get all of our
announcements delivered directly to your
inbox and please subscribe to the
podcast so you don't miss an
episode oh yeah and don't forget to
register to join us at
c25 we've gotten a great response on our
early bird promotion which did expire
last week but there are still great
ticket packages available we'd love to
see you in June check out the details
again at camet events.com
our guest today is Dr Shauna vek Shauna
is head of research at true Turpin where
she is instrumental in developing and
maintaining the rigorous safety and
quality protocols the brand is known for
Shauna is an active advocate for
science-based safety parameters to
protect consumer health and has worked
with policy makers to implement sensible
regulations to protect public health and
maintain access to regulated cannabis
products she has multiple peer-reviewed
papers on Vape safety and most recently
her work has been adopted into two ASM
Global standards
at CED 25 Shauna will present
toxicological risk and cannabis Vapes
exogenous additives and their
implications on consumer safety it will
highlight specific higher risk
ingredients and identify how prevalent
they are in vaporization products
currently in the Cannabis
market during our conversation we
discussed the main components of
cannabis Vape products how and why
exogenous ingredients are added to vape
products how toxicological risks are
evaluated based on Hazard and exposure
level why one can't assume that safe
food ingredients are also safe for
inhalation why risk assessment based
regulations are a better approach than
outright bans on flavors and
more before we get to my conversation
with Shauna I'd like to thank this
episode sponsor mckin
RSA mckin is made up of regulatory
science veterans who apply Lessons
Learned in the nicotine space to help
cannabis manufacturers better understand
the toxicological and societal
implications of their product they do
that by identifying base compounds
extracts flavors and
tpin understanding how they interact and
ensuring Effectiveness for the intent
use they also provide dosing
recommendations and establish guidelines
for product
consistency learn more at mckin
rsa.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr Shauna vek
[Music]
good afternoon shaa thanks so much for
joining us on the
podcast hey Ben thanks for having me
here I'm really excited I'm excited too
first of all I'm excited that you're
going to be joining us at caned 25 in
June down in Puerto Rico uh your the
name of your talk is going to be
toxology risks of cannabis Vapes
exogenous additives their implications
for Consumer safety um as we were saying
before we started recording here um
cannabis Vapes are very popular so I
think this is a very popular topic um
but before we dive into it too deep I
wanted to just ask you off the top what
motivated you to conduct this study on
the toxicological risks of cannabis
Vapes yeah that's a great question um
what really motivates me and like
everything I do here at true Turpin is
always about consumer health and safety
safety um so with Vape products it's a
unique product in the Cannabis space
because it allows the manufacturer to
add or adjust levels of different
ingredients um that's going to be
different than say a flower where you
can't really adjust how many canabo or
tpin or other additives that go into it
so because you have this ability to do
that with Vapes we were curious to see
what types of ingredients are being used
when they're creating these vape
formulations and to compare where true
turfing stands within the
industry excellent so all that's a
that's that's a great segue because I
was curious so you mentioned different
ingredients so what are sort of the main
components that we find in cannabis Vape
products and how do they
vary so cannabis Vape products there's a
few different categories I would say the
most common ones are going to be made
with a distillate and a distillate is
like a very refined canabo extract from
the flour and when you go through that
refining process you oftentimes will
lose all the volatile Turpin and other
flavor molecules that are naturally in
the cannabis plant so to kind of
recreate that natural composition of the
plant manufacturers will add ppines and
other flavorant back into this
distillate extract um like I said those
are probably the most common types of
formulations but you also have live
resin which is going to be a more
broadspectrum
extract um or you're going to have like
a live rosin which the live rosin is
going to be the most like delicate way
of extracting so those will oft times
carry the natural Tarpin into the
extract but in regards to these like
tpine additives there's a lot of
different compounds that can be included
and I'm going to use the word tpine as
an umbrella term going forward just for
ease of conversation but that also
includes terpenoids Esters flavonoids
ketones alahh lots of these really high
volatile High
aromatic um compounds that are often
naturally in the cannabis plant but but
we can also add some other ones to kind
of increase the aroma create new and
unique flavors that cannabis consumers
really enjoy excellent so you said that
it's most common for it to start with
sort of the distill it as you said so in
what form is that is that like a powder
or is it sort of that oily viscous
material that we actually see in the
vape pen what does that look like yeah
it's usually that oily viscous material
um if it's really refined it can be a
more clear amber color uh or if it's
more closer to like a live rosin
material it's going to kind of be a more
like a darker Amber like a golden kind
of extract but it is very viscous so
without any tpping at all it can be very
challenging to like aerosolize it in a
vape device because it's just so thick
so the tpin also help to liquefy it a
little bit so that it can be you know
efficiently efficiently aerosolized in
The Vape Pen excellent explain a little
bit more about the methodology behind
your uh toxicological risk assessment
that you're
performing yeah that's a great question
so toxicological risk is a component of
the the unique um hazard risk of each
ingredient coupled with the exposure
level so I always like to describe this
in terms of alcohol most of us are all
very familiar with alcohol so for
example ethanol that is the compound
that has the inherent risk in
alcohol and so we understand the
toxicity of ethanol then you compare
with with the exposure level so for
example one glass of wine you're
probably going to feel totally fine um
you'll wake up the next day feel totally
great go about your day no problem so
that is a very low exposure to ethanol
so the risk is very low but then let's
say you know after I do my presentation
I'm really excited I'm going to
celebrate and I drink a whole bottle of
wine so that's a much higher exposure
and while I'm drinking that bottle of
wine I might lose a little bit of
balance right I might say things that I
think are really funny but maybe not be
so funny um and then the next day when I
wake up I'm probably going to be very
dehydrated I might have a headache but
ultimately I have a really great
breakfast and by the end of the day I
feel totally fine again so the risk
between you know a glass of wine and a
bottle of wine is a little bit higher
because we're doing we're getting
exposed to a higher level of that
ethanol so that's the idea behind a risk
assessment because nothing and I mean
nothing in this world is 100% safe so
it's really important to understand the
inherent risk of that individual
component but then also to understand
how much of that component how much of
that ingredient can a consumer be
exposed to without having any risk or
without having any like you know the
risk is at a negligible
level so the methodologies that I employ
here at true
tping um includes surveying all of the
publicly available data on each
individual
ingredient compiling all that reading it
understanding the
conclusion and then I perform a set of
calculations which is very standard in
toxicology um and so the these
calculations do things for example if it
was a study with a rat we need to
understand what that means in a human so
I do a calculation to put it into the
levels that a human would be exposed to
then I need to put it into the exposure
of a cannabis consumer right so I
understand how much is a cannabis
consumer vaping every single day how
much of this extract are they being
exposed to every day so that's a really
important
calculation then once I get that calcul
or once I get that answer from the human
exposure
level I apply a set of uncertainty
factors or safety factors there are
sometimes called and so what that means
is we found this limit from a study
where there was no Adverse Events to the
rat but we're not 100% sure if a rat is
totally equivalent to a human so we're
going to apply this uncertainty factor
which brings this No Effects level down
let's say 10 times so now it's 10 times
smaller limit so it's going to be more
conservative limit so we can be more
confident that that limit is not going
to cause harm to our cannabis consumers
in the final product so that's kind of a
brief overview of you know what a
toxicological risk assessment is and how
I perform that excellent excellent so in
your example with alcohol you're
mentioning how ethanol is sort of the
the compound um that can cause harm I
guess for lack of a better term so when
you're looking at cannabis Vapes what
are sort of the ingredients that that
are kind of of
Interest I try to look at every single
ingredient that's in there um even uh
impurities are important to look at
so you know you can do this work with
canabo but there's been a lot of studies
done on THC and CBD and the commic
canabo that are going to be in these
extracts so I try to focus on these
other additives that are in there um
like the tpin right I work at true tping
so what we really care about are these
like tpine Blends that being added into
this
distillate so I look at every single
ingredient within this tarpine blend and
some tarpine blends can have upwards of
40 different components in it so I
perform a risk assessment on each
individual
component excellent excellent and yeah
no it's it's great that you mentioned
tpes because especially in Vapes and
them being added back in they can
sometimes be at unnatural levels right
so that would be a concern or at least
something to look at exactly they can be
in unnatural levels or they can be at
level s that are a different ratio from
each other than what's found in the
natural
plant excellent excellent and before too
you were talking about as you were
analyzing sort of the exposure risk um
you taking into account how much of a
consumer typically Vapes every day um so
so what is that figure or what is that
range yeah so here at true Turpin we
like to do a range from like 75
milligrams a day to 100 milligrams a day
um and this is based on a few different
studies that I've done I done a study in
partnership with Pax when Pax had the
smart pods and so they were getting real
use data so we analyzed you know
probably over a thousand different data
points and we were able to come up with
the consumption of
95% of users and the reason why we
choose 95% instead of say the median is
because we're really trying to protect
most cannabis consumers out here if you
pick the average use then you're only
protecting 50% of consumers um so we
just felt like you know that wasn't
really the best use of this program um
and then there's been other studies that
have been published um in peer review
journals that looked at consumption from
Vape products and so we compiled all
those and that's how we get this
range excellent so I know that you don't
want to reveal uh too much of your
findings you got to save that for canmed
which I completely understand and
appreciate um but can you explain how or
how and if you identified some more
toxic additives in some of these Vapes
and sort of what are the implications
there for consumer health
so we first analyzed um a variety of
different tping blends that are sold on
the market uh internally we have a gcms
inhouse that can do tpine analysis so we
first ran all the products inhouse to
analyze kind of the total composition of
these Blends then what I did is narrowed
down our Target list of compounds to a
select View
that at true tpin we choose not to use
at all because I think the safety
profile um is just not not there it's
more hazardous than it's worth using um
so that is kind of the target list that
we uh started with then we sent out a
select of these samples to third-party
lab so we tested them by two thirdparty
labs to validate and verif verify the
results that we found in
house so you were analyzing products on
the market for sort of a hit list of
compounds that are sort of known to be
um
risky yes more or less excellent okay um
and so you you mentioned that you at
true chines you guys do not use those
for obvious reasons um why I mean I know
you can't really necessarily say why
others do but um you know is it because
it's a flavor enhancer or some other
some other reason for maybe some of
these additives yeah that's a great
question so a lot of these ingredients
are really commonly used in food so they
have a safe history of use they are
approved by the FDA for you food most of
them are grass we've heard that a lot
generally recognized as safe however
none of those accounts for inhaling
these compounds so when I do the risk
assessment I go beyond just oral
application and I assess what would it
do if we inhale these compounds and
that's where we see a higher risk factor
and I will stress that none of these
compounds do I believe are going to
affect your consumers today right
consumers are not dropping like flies
using these Vape products so they're not
so extreme that I'm like oh [ __ ]
cannabis consumers are in like deep [ __ ]
right now what we're looking at is you
20 30 40 years from now we really want
to see the longevity of the Cannabis
industry and so we want our clients that
use our products to be able to sell
these materials to Consumers for as long
as consumers want to use these products
so like I said I don't think we're going
to see problem with these ingredients
today or tomorrow or next year but over
20 years that's where we're going to see
these negative effects start adding up
and so we're really cautious about that
because like I said we want to see the
Cannabis industry Thrive for generations
to come yeah and when you consider that
a lot of uh younger the younger
demographic is really drawn to Vapes too
they probably use it more than anyone
else this long-term effect is even more
important
exactly so based on your results do you
see regulatory bodies kind of adopting
stricter guidelines or requirements for
testing for these
products so my hope is that
regulatories bodies don't start Banning
things right we don't want to see flavor
bands we've already seen that in some
states and really that doesn't lead to
safer products um it just leads to much
more restrictive products much more
expensive products and consumers are
oftentimes going to just travel to other
states to get these products that they
want or they're going to start buying
them again from the black market and
that's worst case scenario we do not
want to drive consumers to the black
market so my hope is that Regulators
will start
adopting um standards so I've uh drafted
and we got two ASM standards approved
and ASM is a global standard
organization um they have sectors in
pretty much every single industry
including you know shapes of stop signs
um you know safety
glasses even even sex toys have ASM
standards to apply to so I authored two
ASM standards around performing a risk
assessment for these exact types of
ingredients that go into cannaboid
products that will be
vaporized so my hope is that Regulators
will start adopting these standards and
say if you're going to use these
exogenous ingredients they need to have
been performed this risk assessment or
they need to follow these two ASM
standards and then what can happen is
regulatory bodies can can go to these
manufacturers and audit their risk
assessment
program so that's my ultimate goal
instead of saying this ingredient is
banned this ingredient is banned they
just say okay they need to comply with
these two ASM standards which it is how
it is in many Industries already today
yeah and so would that risk assessment
be performed on you know individual
ingredients or an entire formulation or
both it could be performed on both MH um
so if you perform it at the ingredient
level it's a little bit easier because
we know like true tping and other
tarping companies know exactly what
individual ingredients are in the blend
since we build it compound by compound
so it's easier to perform the risk
assessment at that level but if you are
say a vape manufacturer and you are
creating a tarpine blends yourself or
you're adding Tarpin isolate by isolate
as well you can perform this risk
assessment um or you can send your
extract to a lab that can do um analysis
on the chemical composition of it and
then you can perform the risk assessment
on the individual components that uh
show up in the lab
result excellent and you and I guess
just to clarify here too um this risk
assessment is being performed on
ingredients that you know the
manufacturer the processor knows they
are putting into the product it's not so
much for you know um contaminants that
are part of the the processing um the
the processing the processing process
like um you know residual solvents and
things like that correct yeah that's a
great question and I'm really glad you
brought up because we do want to clarify
in the ASM standard it does specify that
contaminants and impure ities are not
within the scope of the standard because
most of those are already
regulated by the regulatory bodies um so
it's you know really important to
continue doing those impurities uh you
know residual solvents heavy metals Etc
do that testing by your third-party lab
follow the action limits that are in you
know the regul Regulatory Agencies uh
that you're selling the product into um
that you know first and foremost you
need to have compliant products right um
but yeah this these standards are
specifically for you know exogenous
ingredients that are being added back in
you can perform this risk assessment on
for example like a live rosin product
that's a natural extract of the cannabis
plant but I always like to stress that I
am not here to police the plant if the
plant creates x amount ount of lemoning
and you have you know efficient
extraction and so that's how much loning
is in your final product then that's
great I'm not here to tell you that's
too much loning if the plant makes it
you know humans have been smoking the
plant for hundreds of years if not more
so there's a long safe history of use
there so I'm not worried about natural
extracts from the plant we're really
focused on exogenous ingredients that
are being added back in right yeah so
it's sort of like there's that that base
level of safety testing to make sure
that there's no impurities and there's
no contamination you're just going one
step further to be like okay whatever
we're adding in here let's make sure
that it's at levels that are safe for
consumption exactly excellent yeah and I
remembered what I wanted to ask you
about too because you were mentioning
that a lot of these ingredients are
generally regarded as safe but that's
more for ingestion and not for
inhalation which I think that some carry
over there with what we do here at
medicinal genomics where we do microbial
testing and a lot of the regulations
sometimes are just lifted from food
testing without taking into account the
fact that it is an inhaled product and
there are different risks for different
microbials um when those are ingested
that way so that's very important yeah
absolutely the risk of inhaling
something is much higher than the risk
from eating it for example because when
you eat something it goes through the
metabolism that's in your stomach so
that's going to change the compound it
goes through the liver that changes the
compound so by the time these
ingredients are actually absorbed into
your bloodstream and then travel through
your body they've been changed they've
been altered um you know in toxicology
we assume that it's only 50% of the
original ingredient is what's actually
traveling through your body versus when
you inhale something it goes from your
lungs directly into your bloodstream so
there is no metabolism that happens
essentially there's no metabolism that
happens within the lungs so we in
toxicology assume that 100% of the
active ingredient is being um you know
is being exposed throughout your body so
that's why it's a higher risk factor
interesting great so what is sort of the
key take way that you hope that the
industry professionals and Regulators
kind of gain from this presentation in
this
work yeah I really just want the whole
industry to be safer I really want to
lift up all
products um and you know a big thing is
like there are ways to substitute some
of these ingredients with ingredients
that still impart the same flavor but
have a much higher safety profile and
then if we can't do that if we can't hit
a flavor and make it safe you know maybe
that's the best step forward for the
whole industry do we really need coffee
flavored cannabis Vapes if they're gonna
be you know potentially toxic to our
consumers I don't think so like I really
want to push you know product
development teams to challenge
themselves to create these flavors with
safer ingredients or you know let's just
all band together and agree not to
create certain flavors at all because
really consumer safety should be top
priority it shouldn't be on the
shoulders of consumers to understand if
their product is safe or not to make
that risk versus reward Choice that's a
lot for them to burden so I would like
the industry to take on that burden and
we can still innovate I mean true Turing
still makes awesome super strong
Innovative flavors even with this
program and we've had this program for
four years now so everything that's on
the market today from True Turing is
going to comply with these toxicological
assessments and I still think we have
you know the best flavors out there so
this is not going to stifle creativity
your consumers are are still going to
love your products and they're going to
feel more confident using these products
you know for as long as they want to use
them because really consumers clearly
find these products
beneficial so for them to be able to no
questions ask take a product that they
know is beneficial and have that
confidence that it's only going to
provide benefit for them that's what I
want to see excellent no and you don't
have to name names or or or name flavors
but you in that example that you gave
are there certain flavors that you've
sort of identified like yeah we really
can't make this flavor safely I mean
again you don't have to say exactly what
that is you probably save that for
cannmed but but has that come up has
that happened there are flavors that are
really challenging to make with
ingredients that have high safety
profiles um but we've done really good
with you know skirting around that and
finding a way to make these flavors it
is a challenge but you know if you got
the best PD team out there you should be
confident in your product development
team they can find a way that's awesome
great all right so winding down here a
bit Shauna we've mentioned that you're
going to be down at camed and we're
excited to have you are there any types
of um Professionals in general that
you're looking to connect with down
there so that if they're seeing this and
they know that they that you're looking
to connect with them they can make the
trip
down yeah I mean there's some like
really fantastic speakers there that's
why I really love canmed because I think
it brings in you know the top tier
scientists in the Cannabis industry with
like the most Cutting Edge research um
but one person I'm really excited to to
collaborate with is uh Bonnie
Goldstein we've talked a little bit
about creating products um for Pediatric
patients that she works with and
utilizing Tarpin to create really
effective Blends for them um and I think
the work that she does is super
fantastic and I mean she is just awesome
to be you know providing these products
to Pediatric
patients yeah no that sounds that sounds
like a great collaboration and hopefully
we can make that happen um all right so
winding down I didn't want to give you
the opportunity to share any other
resources or links that you think might
be of interest to anyone who's watching
or listening to learn more about you and
the work that you guys are
doing yeah so if you go on the true
tping website we have a few blogs that
go over the toxicological
program um we have a
few u news articles that go over the ASM
standards um the toxicological review
and if anyone is interested in Access
accessing these ASM standards they can
reach out to me I'm happy to share them
um I'm you know I'm really hoping
everyone starts taking this work
seriously and you know let's lift up the
whole cannabis industry excellent yeah
if you want to send me some some links
to those blogs and those resources I'd
be happy to put them in the show
description so people can easily find
them um and I'll put your contact info
in there too uh if if people want to get
those standards or they can come to
canat and meet you in person
right can man where Rico how can you say
no I know yeah we're so excited all
right shaa thanks again for uh for
joining me on the podcast and uh yeah
look forward to seeing you in a few
months awesome thanks Ben it's going to
be great
[Music]