[Applause]
good afternoon
i met with kyle turley over lunch and we
decided we're going to
try and pass some legislation about mike
heights limitations
it's an ada issue for all those of us
who are taller
we feel it would be only fair to have
mics that reach where we are
i'm going to take uh i'm going to if you
can am i loud enough out there i am
going to take a moment
um i'm going to take a i'm going to
steal a play
from dr mushulem's playbook from his
comments last night at dinner
because i think there is a similarity
between those speaking immediately after
lunch
and those speaking immediately after
dinner and
so i i do have some formal comments to
make but i
also i will be telling a story because i
thought his story last night was
absolutely wonderful for those of you
who got to
hear it and i think it's actually part
of the the documentary that was done
about him
uh the story in particular about how he
and he relayed some of it this morning
went to uh to the police to to
essentially
take cannabis that was confiscated and
use it for science i think it's just a
fantastic story
um i i'd like to echo also something was
said earlier this
this i believe truly will when we look
back in a decade from now
uh i think this day today in this
auditorium will be
considered a milestone event and i'm
just a real
um
i i'm just so honored to be part of it
and i do
i will say i do feel a little bit like
an undergrad student at a
graduate lecture so i hope you'll bear
with me
um so my story my story is
and some of you have heard it so for
those of you who heard it i apologize
for
repeating but my story is about these
two little girls this is uh
sorry uh so
this is adding cassie and they were
little kids and um
in 2005 and today they're 14 i think in
this picture they were give or take
a little over a year
they were they were hell-bent to be
movie stars
running around you know around age 3 age
4 we began to see
a little bit of notice of wobble in
their gate
a little bit of developmental delay
but we had a perfect life at that time
this is my wife chris she's sitting in
the audience with a different
style of hair um ultimately we ended up
in the hospital for testing
um it actually was initially diagnosed
by
uh their pediatric doctor dr sorenson
discovered that they both had enlarged
spleens it was initially diagnosed as
mononucleosis
which commonly uh manifests itself in
enlarged spleens but
we quickly realized that that was far
more than that
we went through a battery of testing the
diagnosis the odyssey of diagnosis took
uh well in excess of 18 months
including what you see here which is the
beginning of the
eeg process ultimately they were
diagnosed with a really horrible
and largely fatal untreatable
cholesterol disorder called neumann pick
type c this is a lysosomal storage
disorder
it manifests itself all those little red
dots on that
on that chromosome sequence are known uh
genetic defects
of that particular chromosome the mpc
gene the mpc
gene so my kids have what's called mpc
type c
which means that they do not process
cholesterol either in
or out of their cells well
particularly their organ cells which is
why they got larger in large spleens
but most importantly and most uh deadly
is the
uh the death that happens to their brain
cells
and so it's a very severe neuro
degenerative disease
from the onset of symptoms which in my
children took place
in around their third year their life
expectancy is somewhere between four and
five years
beyond that point it's an auto recessive
gene i won't
dive into this this is my you know
undergraduate work and
it'll bore most of you to tears so we
ended up at the mayo clinic as many
folks do
met with a doctor at the mayo clinic who
specializes in neiman pixie
he essentially told us that there was
one experimental drug that was improved
in europe not approved in the united
states if we could convince our
insurance company to spend the hundred
thousand a year per kid to put them on
it
we could use it as treatment for our
children and it was only expected to
make a 10
difference in the outcome wasn't a good
diagnosis and certainly wasn't a good
uh prediction of outcome we then ended
up at the nih
in bethesda there was an a natural
history study underway
uh sponsored by the nih and thank god it
was underway because it became the basis
in some ways for what we ultimately
achieved as parents
to find a drug for our kids my wife and
i immediately formed a research
foundation
raised a few million dollars and started
putting it to work
piggy backing off then already existing
research in the npc community
from very very very fine researchers
and frankly we entered into the
ecosystem of npc
at a very fortunate time so the kids
went through a full week of testing at
the nih
and our life changed immediately we
became citizen scientists
my wife and i have technology and public
relations backgrounds predominantly we
met at netscape i spent my early part of
my career at apple and
other technology companies we became
scientists
and what we discovered along the way
very quickly was
a compound called cyclodextrin
cyclodextrin is a
grass compound it's used as an incipient
as a solubilizer
in many many products it's the basis for
the product febreze it's in almost every
single procter gamble product
it's used in mayonnaise to enhance
flavor it's used in
soft drinks chewing gum you name it
you're you're surrounded by cyclodextrin
almost anywhere you go in our country
it turns out that cyclodextrin is an
active ingredient and is now
in phase two three clinical research at
the nih to treat my children's disease
we were the first my kids were the first
to see this disease so i've already
talked a little bit about this
so we became drug developers the problem
is that the drug
was only available in pharmaceutical
grade as part of another drug
it was manufactured by jansen
pharmaceuticals a subsidiary of j and j
we reached out to j j and said hey how'd
you like to share your
drug master file and your manufacturing
technology so that we can make this drug
ourselves
yeah and that was pretty much what they
said in response
you know and uh and my wife being who
she is
those of you who know know what i'm
about to say she didn't take no for an
answer
and she immediately wrote a blog that
says said
effectively does johnson and johnson
care about children
and the answer was yes we care about
children and oh by the way we've
rethought our position and we will not
we will not only share your our drug
master file for the use of cyclodextrin
as an active ingredient in your drug we
will actually set up a manufacturing
facility and make this drug not only for
your children
but for all the children in the world
that can get a
compassionate use ind approved by the
fda by their doctor
and subsequently now i think about 100
kids around the world are
on this amazing drug
and effectively what we're talking about
is translational medicine we're talking
about
repurposing an existing compound in this
case it wasn't known as an active
ingredient has subsequently become so
and we're repurposing it in the
translational medical science
and that took filings with the fda
you'll notice the pink binders those are
unique colors to our children and my
wife chose them so that they would get
attention at the fda and ultimately get
our approval so
in less than 18 months after our
diagnosis at the
uh at the han ultimately the diagnosis
took place out of testing from stanford
but
uh within 18 months out of the test with
the testing we had submitted and gotten
approval to
treat our children with cyclodextrin
intravenously
uh by the way we had tried it through
the gut initially only to find out that
that that it doesn't pass through into
the bloodstream and more importantly
once we started treating our children
intravenously we discovered through
follow-up research that we had sponsored
that it doesn't really pass the
blood-brain barrier very well either
so not only did we file an ind for
intravenous
treatment of cycloadduction with our
children we then subsequently filed
another
compassionate use ind with the fda to
get our kids treated intra-thickly in
other words a spinal tap straight into
their spinal cord
and for the last four and a half five
years they have been
receiving every other week they receive
either an intravenous infusion which
turns out does actually in small
quantities pass the blood blame
blood the bbb
but it also turns out it helps their
their systems their organs and so forth
clear cholesterol
uh and they on the off week we take them
to the hospital
they're fully anesthetized and they
receive a spinal tap to receive this
drug into their
uh csf and it has we believe
extended their life by quite a lot they
are now uh 12 years old here's uh
the initial installation of their ports
for the intravenous infusion so they get
it mainline port infusion every
every other week on thursdays and here's
the very first compounds that we made
these compounds were actually made at
our at the pharmacy
in our local hospital in reno nevada
they were
compounded by this wonderful man on the
left his name is adam porath
he's a little-known pharmacist hospital
pharmacist who
i think is part of an amazing story
that is now saving other children's
lives he was the first one to figure out
how to do all the osmolarity testing all
of the necessary
sterilization because we were actually
receiving the compound in a powder form
and it had to be turned into a drug that
would be
acceptable to the fda to be not only
infused into the
into the bloodstream but also into the
past the blood-brain barrier
here are the kids receiving their
infusions at the infusion center at reno
so 400 and plus i think it's now more
than 500 iv infusions later they get
megadoses
uh you know we started we started down
the path by the way walgreens
has been unbelievable in this process
they actually helped us work through a
third ind which got us approval to treat
our children at home so we no longer
have to take them to the hospital for
this treatment
we have a little pump that we treat them
at home
so cyclodextrin then the whole effort
took off so we worked with the nih
the nih ultimately licensed or sub
licensed all of the data that we
collected as ind patients plus a whole
bunch of data they created in-house
through a small i think n of six uh
phase one sort of safety clinical study
it's now in phase two
dash three on the fast track
phase study supported by a company
called vitesse who licensed all the
technology
and is taking over the drug as a as a
manufacturer
so it's a great story um
and our dream was a sterile solution
that was you know
available for both iv and it and it's
and it's now happening
so there it is manufactured by janssen
available in sterile bottles
and i give i have to say we just don't
do this enough i want to give public
credit
to jansen j j for for stepping up and
doing this they didn't have to do it
it was risky on their part and they were
just amazing amazing partners in this
whole process
so the twins are still alive they had
their 12th birthday last january
i think that's amazing of itself
after all these treatments we've seen no
toxicity
creeping in their plasma oxyteral
biomarkers have really improved and
especially their
seven keto cholesterol levels tau and a
beta levels are dropping
almost all the signs of of neurological
stress inflammation or degradation are
are improving as a result of this it
turns out and we've already talked a
little bit about mechanism of action and
the mysteries of mechanism of action
it turns out during this entire process
not none of the scientists involved had
any idea how cycloadduction was working
the assumption is that it was working
similar to the way that cholesterol
you know uh is that odors are captured
by febreze
turns out that that's not the case and
just this last week a seminal paper was
published about cyclodextrin and its use
in the treatment of atherosclerosis
which elucidated its mechanism of action
and that's a day that's for another day
but exciting okay so we sort of
stabilized our children with a drug
through the fda process
became aware of what's involved in doing
that
really respect those of you who are
involved in that process because it is
daunting and involved and expensive and
time-consuming
but it wasn't helpful for my kids
seizures our kids
stuff began suffering several years ago
from
nowhere near the dravet kids sort of
levels of seizures but still
an a disturbing level of seizure
activity
we did like every other parent does we
tried to treat it with pharmaceutical
meds
it basically just turned our kids into
zombies had horrible side effects for
them
and decided to chase uh cannabis it
turns out that dr
gupta's story um you know we'd won
about the stanley's in charlottesville
and so forth was just coming out
uh or had you know after we about six
months after we started looking at it
long story short
we had already been sanjay had already
been covering our story about
psychoaddiction in our kids so we had
been interacting with him and he had
mentioned to us
as had others about trying cannabis so
this is actually a picture of one of the
very first bottles of oil that we
used when we treated our kids we started
this treatment several years ago
we were this bottle is approximately an
18 to 1 cbd to thc ratio
suspended in a safflower oil
what we discovered in the process of
treating our kids with essentially
what i would largely say as a very
sophisticated home
grown oil was that the supply of this
oil and its safety
was of paramount importance to us so we
took what we had learned in our process
of
you know working with cyclodextrin and
building a drug through the fda
and formed a company that we call
strains strains
purpose in life is to be a world-class
high quality manufacturer
of cannabinoid cannabinoid and others
cannabis based
products in oil form and in other routes
of administration
as possible by state regulations so we
embarked um and have just recently
announced
eight million dollars in funding to
launch our product development
our more importantly our product
manufacturing efforts in the state of
colorado
washington state and nevada
we have facilities built and ready to
produce products in seattle denver and
soon to finish in reno as well
here's an example of the machine that we
use this is a 70 liter co2 extraction
machine
it's just one part of a complex process
of making these oils
to the highest grade standards that we
know how to make and
i i think to what the industry is making
at this time
we make a multi-ratio product 20 to 1 1
to 20 and one to one in the middle
and from these three products a parent
or a patient could
come up with a ratio of their own design
obviously capped by 20 to one at the
high end on the cbd spectrum
so i want to talk a little bit about so
that's our story that's my story and
here's
i i know that the title of my talk for
today was
was about rescheduling so out of
necessity i have become a little bit of
a cannabis policy wonk because
uh it worries me as a business person to
take
my investors money without a clear path
for how they're going to get their
returns
i want to make these medicines under the
belief that we can actually get them out
to lots and lots of people and
ultimately as
i think we all know that's going to
require some form of rescheduling
i'm not sure that rescheduling is the
answer i will say that
if i could make wave my magic wand and
convince the cannabis community
i think we should hold our ground and
insist on a de-scheduling
or or the creation of a
[Applause]
i think we or or better yet the creation
of a parallel path let's face it tobacco
and alcohol are on a parallel path
they're not on schedule
anything although they arguably should
be certainly if cannabis is
so i would like to see the there there's
already a movement afoot
the states have already said we're gonna
we're going to authorize the creation of
cannabis
let's let the federal government embrace
that idea let's let the states regulate
the product
let's layer on top of that federal
regulation which
really focuses on the gmp process our
facilities are designed to gmp cfr 111
which is the nutraceutical or dietary
supplement standard
i think that that's the minimum standard
that should be established i'd like to
see the federal government insist that
the states enforce that standard just as
they insist
that the states enforce things like
diversion or proximity to schools and so
forth so there are ways to regulate this
product without putting it into this
the drug schedule and certainly most
importantly without putting it into the
crosshairs of the fda for you know the
full monty
on on on drug approval process
there are so many incarnations of this
drug that can be delivered as a dietary
supplement
um and and we that should be allowed and
i just hope that we can figure out as a
society how to do that
okay one more soapbox cannabis belongs
to mankind
cannabis does not belong to one company
one brand one method of
action one process technology it belongs
to all of us
i come from a world that pretty much
embraced open source technology in the
software community
open source as a concept has become
further and more recognized as a viable
capital endeavor
i'd like to suggest that we as a
community
make a pact with each other to treat
cannabis as a shared asset
and not to lock it up not to put it
behind the
pharma fence not to put it in a cage
where people can't make it unless they
have a patent on it
this is uh this is one of my as a parent
and as a patient advocate
one of my worst nightmares is that we
will
you know not learn from the from the
past
finally to uh somewhat in honor of dr
michoulem certainly but
uh in honor of my children and all the
patients out there who need more
understanding
dr goldstein this morning talked about
it almost everyone has talked about it
we need far more research especially
human clinical research
so in the spirit of not having enough to
do my wife and i
got together and we asked the irs to
give us approval to
create a research foundation called
peoplecam peoplecan is now approved as a
501c3
specifically to fund organize and
orchestrate human clinical research
in cannabis worldwide we actually just
thank you
we actually just got approval and we
just hired an executive director i'd
like jason to stand up
jason smith
so we're just getting started and the
first task is to raise a little money to
to to build out the infrastructure uh
i'm of the
opinion um informed i hope and opinion
that it is possible to do clinical
research on cannabis
in the united states without the dea's
approval without even the fda's approval
this
this product is a dietary supplement in
many of its forms
and we can research it uh as such and so
we intend to
work with the irb community figure out a
way to get this done
and embrace the rest of you in that
process so
i hope you'll engage with us in that
process on on many levels
thank you very much