how is big egg and big farmer going to
alter the marketplace for young
entrepreneurs who want to get in the
cannabis business well here's the thing
big AG and Big Pharma are already here
there's a tremendous amount of
opportunity as our industry grows and
here's the thing there's a lot of small
businesses that are going to be acquired
by big AG and Big Pharma so don't wait
get into the marketplace find a good
company with some solid management and a
great vision and go to work for them
because the odds of them getting
acquired are really really good and
there's going to probably be a minimum
of a quarter million to half a million
jobs new jobs that will be created here
in America over the next several years I
want to say this I wouldn't be where I
am today if it wasn't for hard studying
and reading a lot of books and finding
great scientists to talk to and share
different ideas with and I want to
encourage all the young entrepreneurs
and business owners who want to get into
the cannabis space to pursue the science
aspect of cannabis just like I did that
is where I made the biggest gains and
when I had science behind me advanced
nutrients Big Mike's blends are able to
grow at a faster better rate science has
always been the answer to success and by
the way that's what I like about can med
because the best cannabinoid researchers
in the world are gonna be right here in
Los Angeles at UCLA October 22nd through
24th and I'm gonna be on one of the
panels they're speaking and I'm really
looking forward to it straight to the
point
I love cannabis I love talking about it
I love hearing new ideas and most of all
I love to talk about the future of
cannabis because it isn't what a lot of
people think it is all right I will
you October 22nd to 24th at UCLA