[Music]
welcome to the CB Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I am the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team team that puts on the canmed
Innovation and investment
Summit all right well registration for
canm med25 is now live check out camed
events.com to see details about next
year's event in the new location at the
Windam Resort in Rio Grande Puerto
Rico if you check out the ticket
packages page you'll be happy to see
that the price for this full Summit
package is lower than K 24 but that
package still includes three nights at
the resort full access to three days of
canmed presentations workshops and
networking events meals and Cocktails
and so much more now I know what you're
thinking the events in June I have
plenty of time yes you do but it's never
too early to purchase your ticket
package for cmed not only will you take
advantage of early bird pricing which
gets you another $500 off the full
Summit package but you'll also get the
satisfaction that comes with Crossing
something off of your to-do
list Our Guest today is Justin ESL
Justin is CEO and geneticist at Green
luster fenos and he's been an influencer
and leader in the Cannabis industry for
years Justin was the head grower and
geneticist of an indoor commercial scale
cultivation operation back in 2012 and
since then he's helped more than 100
cannabis facilities
worldwide his one-of-a-kind approach to
plasticity breeding has yielded pest in
bacteria resistant genetics in his
application of cannabis tissue culture
and selective homogeneous breeding
enable his company to bring exotic
tailored Offspring to Growers
globally during our conversation we
discuss Justin's background in
traditional a and how that applies to
cannabis how he used uses tissue culture
to store genetics and eliminate
pathogens the process for creating
stable cannabis
varieties how purposely introducing
pests and pathogens into the breeding
room helps select for resistance traits
and the application of analytical tools
such as PCR hlc and marker assisted
breeding before we get to my
conversation with Justin I'd like to
thank this episode sponsor Rare Earth
genomics Rare Earth genomics is a
dynamic partnership formed with Texas
A&amp;M agralife one of the world's leading
research institutions to accelerate hemp
research and create tools for Farmers
their mission is to increase the
likelihood of a successful Harvest for
Farmers through genetic analysis and
rigorous Environmental Testing of
vigorous
cultivars learn more at Rare Earth
genomics
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Justin
[Music]
esel good morning Justin thank you so
much for joining us on the podcast
thanks man happy to be here all right so
I'm excited to talk with you about
cannabis breeding techniques uh the
audience just heard me read your bio but
maybe to start out I'm gonna ask you to
elaborate a bit more on your background
how you got into cannabis breeding and
how you're approach is different from
other
breeders yeah sure so um you know my
background starts off in traditional a
so I've been breeding blueberries I've
been breeding strawberries grafting
Japanese maples propagating ni Blu
hydranges um and so I have an extensive
uh background with breeding in general
for all a in general um but with
cannabis I would say around 2012 is
where I really started getting my feet
in the dirt um and breeding cannabis um
you know stabilizing genetics plant
genetics uh very similar right with
cannabis genetics um but what has missed
kind of missed the curve is you just got
a lot of genetics that are cross
pollinated um sometimes poor breeding
techniques are used um but you end up
with lots of different genetics and in
seed form they're very unstable um
sometimes you've got strains that show
very high her hermaphrodite Tendencies
uh and then you've got some that you
know you might have regular seeds where
you have 70% of them are male and only
30% are female um so you run into many
scenarios Growers do buying seeds uh
buying clones um and so it really really
got me into wanting to stabilize
cannabis genetics so that we have a very
very homozygous stock of seed for
Growers to use um and so with that um
Madrid we started in Madrid in 2012 uh
we were pretty predominant in a lot of
the coffee shops in the Netherlands area
um and we started to work with CBD germ
plasm uh just to name one off hand
Lion's Tabernacle it won the 2012 CBD
Cannabis Cup in Spain um and so we
started getting involved with breeding
but not just breeding but like I said
creating homity as well as plasticity
breeding which we can get into later as
well right so so what's your approach to
creating a homozygous um strain sure so
we are also a tissue culture laboratory
so something unique that we do
everything's in vitro
so everything grows in cryo it's never
watered it's never fed it's never
touched it's never looked at for up to a
year at a time and because of this uh
we've been able to really really
maintain a large Vault of different
genetics we have about 2,000 strains
that we've hunted um from about 20
countries now the USA being one um and
so we get these um into their vessels
where they go through either
multiplication phase or a ro phase but
more importantly 100% sterile so we're
able to sterilize these genetics uh
implementing aicle maristone tissue
culture we can get them back to their
generation zero uh which is going to
return that actual tissue that plant
that genotype to its original Vigor um
so we take a sterile approach and then
when we go to create a new line we can
pull from that Vault we get that out of
tissue uh we start What's called the
acclamation phase getting it used to
being out of that 100% relative humidity
vessel and then getting it into our
inbreeding Chambers uh we then will take
that specific strain and we will inbreed
it and we get it to about an S4 when we
get to an S4 we then get it back into
vitro and we hold it in that S4 um stage
so that when we come across another line
that really really checks all the boxes
for us we then do the cross there um so
we're creating stabilized Offspring um
in seed form um and yeah I mean that's
kind of our approach but we also take
that plasticity approach um something
very very unique that we're doing and
I've done an also traditional AG is we
are taking I'll give you an instance an
example of how we do this plasticity
breeding in 35 gallon tubs we are
propagating and growing um fungus larvae
we Harvest fungus Nat larae with wire
mesh and then we practice what we call
targeted releases so we might go into
one breeding chamber and we'll disperse
this larvae and from start to finish
we're able to find that specific
genotype that shows the most resistance
towards that specific plant pressure uh
in this case being a fungus snap uh you
know they start in that lar stage but
then they evolve into that adult mobile
stage where they're landing on your
plants they eating the foliage they're
causing damage to your canopy and so
we're able to take that genotype isolate
it and then bring that over to the next
generation and breed again and again and
again and we're constantly hunting for
that genotype that has the most
resistance towards that plant pressure
wow so you are purposely
introducing uh a pest in this case right
to try to identify the plants that have
the trait that you're looking for
that's right and we're we're a
completely sealed facility so I hope so
yeah UVC filter hea filtered so we don't
really have too many past pressures that
come into our facilities but we're able
to control what does come in and then
create such such a high density of that
specific plant pressure that's allowing
us to do these inbs and we do this with
spider mites aphids uh we buy spores a
PM uh and we do this with every Garden
pressure um that a grower is going to
experience so that they have the
greatest tailored Offspring when it
comes to growing and so you do it with
all those different pathogens for every
line no so we have a Target right so
every strain there's a Target we might
do a PM Target and then we're also you
know hunting for yields or we're hunting
for Turpin or canabo so there's always a
different Target um you know you go and
try to Target everything in one strain
it it would take so much to achieve that
um and then in many cases you're kind of
fighting one with the
other yeah so in terms of of pathogens
and pests are there ones that are uh
particularly um interesting or ones that
you prioritize I should say uh we
definitely prioritize powdery mildew on
the bacteria side on the pest side it's
going to probably be thrips aphids or
fungus snats indoor Growers experience a
lot of the fungus snats they experience
a lot of the powdery mil do and then
when you get Outdoors you're seeing man
you're seeing all kinds of pest
obviously aphids spider mites um rusted
mites uh and things of that sort so we
have a different Target for each train
and now do you do environmental
pressures
too uh mainly just either pest or
bacteria um our rooms are each dialed in
so we've got breeding chambers that we
dial in for more of like uh say Texas
environment we've got strains that
Island for like main environment
compared to Florida environment um we
are East Coast breeders uh we're we're
located in North Carolina and New York
um and so a lot of what we're doing this
year last year and years to come is
going to be more so directed towards the
east coast cool now this plasticity
breeding is that something that's unique
in the
industry um it's Unique for cannabis
breeders yeah I mean most cannabis
breeders they're finding a plant that
they're growing they love it they find
another strain that they really like
they're crossing the two and they're
selling the seed um so for us it's
because we're indoors we're able to
achieve about four years of outdoor
breeding we're able to achieve that in
about two years in our indoor facility
wow but I think I think uh yeah a lot of
breeders aren't taking the time to do
Implement plasticity breeding and
creating more of a homozygous genome um
with their
genetics yeah no and I was going to kind
of circle back too because when you were
sort of talking about the process before
you mentioned
S4 um which to some folks who who are
listening and maybe some some hosts who
are who are talking to you um in terms
of like the
S4 um F1 all these different sort of uh
letter number combinations can you sort
of like walk through the process and you
know when each of those kind of comes
into play yeah so s is just selfing so
that's when you're taking um a specific
genotype that's a female um you're
reversing it and then when you reverse
it you're having it pollinate itself um
creating that first S1 and so we're
doing this over and over again until we
get to S4 uh and then when we get to S4
we're then pairing it with something
from our vault it could be something
from our vault that was bred uh with
male pollen maybe it's an F2 maybe it's
an F3 uh but at the end of the day we're
matching up two very very stable strains
and we're matching them with each other
to create um you know a new line and
then hunting from
there excellent yeah yeah yeah um so the
process of of selfing a plant um what
does that look like uh because I know
when I was looking through um your
LinkedIn posts there was some ation
about different techniques for creating
these femin seeds and how you know
they're not all equal oh yeah yeah so a
lot of people don't know this but the
first feminized seed ever in the world
ever created was created through a
process called rodelization rodelization
is a defense mechanism built into the
cannabis plant it's so that a female
plant will always produce Offspring okay
and it's like I said it's a defense
mechanism now obviously being in the
Cannabis industry we don't want our Fe
female plants to be pollinated but
that's why they have tricomes and that's
why the pistols are there so that
neighbor and pollen Blowing by sticks to
the pistol retracts down and forms a
seed that's why the tricomes are sticky
that female plant wants pollen that
blows by to stick to them retract and
form seed um and so what happens in this
rodelization phase is if you take a
plant that's supposed to reach full
maturity in say eight weeks and you push
it to 14 weeks it will it will actually
produce anthers those anthers will
mature and it will pollinate itself and
this goes for female clones feminized
seed this goes for all female cannabis
plants so that was the first way that a
female a feminized seed was ever created
now breeders we've learned over time
that this creates more um uh more of a
chance to get more of a like a
hermaphodite so it increases your
hermaphodite Tendencies substantially um
and so then you had breeders to use clal
silver clal Sil silver is probably like
the number one um product that you see
sprayed on feminized plants at home to
produce feminized seed someone like
myself on a commercial scale we use
silver thy sufate spray and something we
do differently um than any other breeder
I know of is we use an adant it's a
sticker so choal silver you're spraying
on a female plant every single day
repetitively for a long extent period of
time
with silver thy sufate spray you're
spraying about every 3 to five days
doing it our way we spray one time we've
made an Adent with the silver thy sufate
spray so that that stays active and on
the plant for longer without evaporating
and so we do this so that when we find a
genotype we want to reverse we're
soaking it once with the heavy atomizer
and then from there we leave it alone
and within a few weeks we're starting to
see that reversal take place
so what's the benefit of doing it once
versus multiple times other than you
know ease of use for for you yeah I mean
it's it's really an ease of use thing uh
another thing that we're seeing is we're
seeing more robust anther production as
opposed to spraying silver thy sulfate
spray every 3 to five days uh getting
this one spray with a very highly
concentration of the silver thigh sufate
spray uh we're just seeing more robust
uh reversals I mean I've I've had um
reversals that look like a and and it's
not sometimes with these reversals you
don't get as many pollen sacks as you
would like to and is like what you would
see on a male um but with this adant we
we see robust anther production um and
yeah I mean the the numbers don't lie
excellent so now this process of sort of
of reversing a plant is that just for
selfing or do you also use that um to
breed with another plant so uh two two
things so it's only for reversing uh
we're obviously trying to get pollen
from that plant uh in most cases it's
going to be live pollen so we'll have
that reverse plant in a sealed chamber
with other female plants um but in some
cases what we'll do is we'll Harvest
that uh that pollen and either cut it
with flour and get it in the freezer or
we'll nitrogen freeze it just depending
on what we're doing but we do that so
then we can still have that same pollen
to use down the line in a future project
excellent excellent um so I know one of
the concerns with with doing this and
know feminized seeds in general is
hermaphrodites like like you mentioned
before um is there something about your
process or are there best practices for
this to kind of make sure that doesn't
happen yeah I mean so it we we Implement
a lot of advanced tools not everyone in
the industry especially more of your
craft at home breeders not everybody can
implement this uh but we Implement
marker assist selection as uh as well as
par uh we're also an hlc lab as well so
we're able to do our hlc testing in
house um so we're able to really shave
off a lot of time that most breeders
have to go into breeding to find out
which genotype they're going to carry on
which ones have recessive traits which
ones don't um and so we're able to
collect a lot of data uh from these
third-party analytics to give us the
information we need to make sure that
we're bringing in the right genotypes in
when it's time to breed excellent so
marker assisted selection I'm glad you
brought that up so Are there specific
traits that you've already identified
that you're kind of screening for or are
you doing actually like sequencing to
find new and interesting markers and
then going from there yeah we're doing
sequencing to find new markers um and
right this is a this is new to the
industry somewhat new to the industry
and so so you know we're learning as we
go we wish I mean most of what we do is
in house but for the marker assisted
selection in par that's third party um
so we're leaning on them for a lot of
advice uh with the advanced tools that
they're they're learning and they've
mastered um but yeah we're constantly
learning constantly evolving looking for
new sequencies new markers uh to keep an
eye out for excellent so then are you
using like PCR assays to to screen the
plants based on those markers in some
cases yes awesome that's really cool um
all right so I was wondering if you
could kind of just like take me through
the process of creating a new strain um
like are you selecting the plants with a
specific trait in mind or are you just
taking two plants Crossing them and kind
of seeing what comes out and then
following the trail from there how does
that work yeah so I mean each strain is
different um I'll give you an example um
I brought back a a cut from AK-47 of AK4
7 from a family farm in Durango Mexico
um we got it back um and got it
initiated we then crossed it with a very
popular Michigan strain you've probably
heard of it Oreos um but to create our
new strain uh which we called cream 47
we had to take the Oreos get it to an F3
and then we took our AK-47 which we knew
as a land race strain and we did that
initial upfront cross when we do that
cross
when creating cream 47 we had a list of
markers we wanted to hit we wanted to
hit high triome density we wanted the
bag peel to be there we wanted some of
that creamy kind of Oreo um flavor to
come over from the Oreos uh in that
cross so in some cases it's doing a stem
rub on the mail in some cases we're
looking at internodal spacing you know
do we want a indicia dominant plant do
we want a sativa dominant plant do we
want a true hybrid um and then we're
also implementing like I said before
which genotypes and which plants are
most resistant towards certain uh plant
pressures um so I mean it's hard to give
a breeder a a rundown of an exact
formula for what our targets are um but
it's it's always changing I mean for
each strain we have a different goal um
we just developed a strain push OG which
our goal for that was to be very drought
resistant uh very very drought resistant
and to be a light feeder so yeah I mean
it it's hard to nail down exactly what
we're looking for for each strain but
bag appeal because of the way the market
is right now and the things that are
trending in the industry bag appeal is
always a box that we have to check
because at then at the end of the day
the grower needs to like what they see
in the canopy and the consumer needs to
like what they see in the bag yeah for
sure so now when you you were talking
about doing the initial cross with uh I
think it was the F3 and then the land
race and then so so how many different
seeds are you popping how many plants
are you sort of evaluating and sort of
how does it scale from there yeah so I
mean if we're doing if we're hunting
through seed we're doing about 200 um as
I told you before we're a small indoor
craft sealed facility uh we're not
Outdoors we're not in a greenhouse we're
in an indoor sealed environment that way
we don't have any worries of any
cross-contamination or uh foreign pollen
coming in that we're unaware of um but
for what we were just speaking about the
F3 and then you're taking the land race
AK-47 once we make that cross we will
hunt out about from maybe 200 seed um
we'll do that because of the stability
with both lines we're working with all
we need is about 200 seed to find that
genotype that we want to then sterilize
um again we we use um axillary node
culture so we're actually doing a micro
splice taking that node sterilizing it
and then getting it into vitro um and
then depending on how quick we need to
make seed for our new line it might stay
there for a year it might stay there for
two years um and then we're we're
pulling it out when we need it excellent
so that upfront stabilization before you
were putting it into uh tissue culture
makes it so you don't have to hunt as
many that's right that's right
awesome um so I know that you're working
with um a lot of different cannabis
cultivators commercial home growth
everything um now are a lot of your
clients are they growing from seed or
are they more sort of popping seeds
pheno hunting and then cloning from
there sure so I mean because we produce
type one type two and type three
genetics we've got hemp Farmers that are
doing 10,000 seeds at a time so they're
growing from seed um and then with our
guys that are more wck medical side of
the industry which is going to be more
along the lines of your type one or type
two they're going to buy like a 100 seed
pack they're going to hunt they're going
to pop 100 seeds they're going to find
the the phenotypes that work best for
them in their grow and then they're
going to get a mom and they're going to
turn it into a mom and cut clones from
there most Growers are running either
clones uh anyone I know running seed is
going to be mainly our hemp Farmers uh
but because of our stability with our
type one seeds we do have some Farms
that decide they're just going to run
seed um so again it really just depends
on the farm we're working with now do
you see that change in at any time where
you know more Farms will grow
exclusively from
seed well a lot of farms are hunting
pheno hunting constantly the advantage
from growing from seed is you have that
initial radical that little white Tap
Root that comes out of the seed and
there's certain hormones that are
produced that allow you to achieve the
full genetic potential of that plant so
you don't get that with the Clone you
don't get the radical and you're never
with a clone going to achieve the full
genetic potential and that's why a lot
of Growers favor seed seeds um I think
it's always going to be split I mean
you've got guys that love growing from
seed and you've got guys that love
growing from clone um I think we're
going to continue to kind of see that
Trend parallel um like I said it's it's
really a preference thing yeah no I kind
of I guess circling back to the pathogen
side and I know it's been an issue
primarily with folks who grow from clone
is hop L and vroid um any have you
worked with that pathogen at all oh yeah
so pop and vroid is is huge I mean it's
we've we've personally tested seed from
all over the place uh and I tell people
the data that we've tracked has shown
about 82% of what we test is positive
for the hotblade and vroid the best
place to test is in your roots you can
test the bud you can test the leaf you
can test the stem and it comes back
negative and there's hop and vroid it's
in the roots so the roots are the best
place to test for that um and the way it
shows itself is later in its progression
you start to see things that look like
maybe nutrient uh nutrient deficiencies
the limbs start to be a little bit more
brittle easy to fall off um and it's
very mature State you're losing
cannabinoids you're losing Turpin yields
I mean it's detrimental um it's a big
reason why we got into the tissue
culture Arena we just want to ensure
that everything we're working with is
sterile um and and it's that's huge um
back in 2009 I cultured out the Rosetta
virus out of knockout roses uh your
traditional knockout rose like you would
see in a neighborhood um and the Rosetta
virus uh transferred very similarly to
what we see with the hopl and viroid um
and so our approach with that to get rid
of it is through aicle maristone tissue
culture with a very high intensity of UV
exposure and we're actually able to rid
that germ plasm of the hopin and vroid
and get it back to its original Vigor
now the hopl en vroid you know it really
depends on how strong it is in the plant
you can test it and the efficacy is not
always going to be there so it's really
really really tricky uh to nail down you
know how how um potent is it in that
strain that you're working with yeah and
that I know that's one of the things
about hopl virid is it can affect
different varieties differently so I
mean h have you identified any varieties
that are more resistant to hop L and
vroid than others no I mean we're just
it's still so new um hopl Android's been
around for a while but on the analytical
side the testing side the R&amp;D side
there's so much there's so many more
unknowns uh there's so much more testing
and research and development that needs
to be done for us to get to the point to
be able to really lock it in per each
strain I will say like our push OG I did
uh do a small experiment in an incubator
with the HL en vroid um and we did see
some resistances but it still picked it
up and it's still tested positive um and
as we know in that earlier State plants
can still be green you can still have a
solid run but then what happens is over
time it gets worse and worse and worse
um so yeah I mean it's we're still
learning man yeah no and we're we're
learning too on the medicinal genomic
side um you know we we sell hop lat and
vroid tests for for Growers and breeders
um work with a lot of the top
researchers on it um like zamir punja
out in out in Canada um but yeah there's
still a lot to learn and I mean I know
our CSO he's doing our his own tests um
with the Jamaican lion cultivar um and
he saw that you're right where you're
gonna find it more more times out nine
times out of 10 is in The Roots but in
some varieties mainly that one it stays
in the Roots even in flowering and
doesn't even get up doesn't get up into
the canopy until much later so he is of
the mind and still a lot more research
that needs to be done um that that
potentially could be uh a way out of
this you know having the have it stay
down in the roots and not affect the end
product there
absolutely absolutely okay now circling
back to kind of breeding what your
targets are and what your customers are
looking for you mentioned bag appeal was
always kind of top of the list what are
other traits that you know that Growers
are looking for or maybe you know that
you're looking forward to for you know
uh the next few years yeah I mean tping
so I mean I'm a consumer I've been
consuming my whole life um so for me
it's the bag appal and then it's the
nose right what does it smell like
there's so many medicinal value uh so
much medicinal value that comes with
Tarpin um as well as the canabo um my
passion for all of this um is because of
my grandfather I lost an 09 to cancer um
and you know back then all they had was
the maritol pill um it was like one of
the first legally synthesized THC pills
and it helped them with radiation it
helped them keep down food now on that
end of the spectrum for us that's what
got us into developing type two
varieties is we noticed the bag appe
peel and the tpin were very very
profound with our type two varieties um
and so for us it really depends on are
we breeding a type one are we breeding a
type two or are we breeding a type three
um as I mentioned before those are the
three that we search for but bag appeal
Tarpin and plant resistance are are
three top uh that we look for yields
yields are important as well but I would
say that comes forth excellent now are
you seeing more Growers open to Growing
um you know type two varieties I mean I
can just tell you from personally
looking at at flower that's available
Where We Are are where in Massachusetts
um it's all type one um you can find
sort of the one to one in more of your
your tentures your Vapes your edibles
but in terms of flower it's just all
type one yeah no I mean I would tell you
this year our top seller were our Tios
um we've got them out in dispos in
Michigan uh they're out in dispos in New
York Florida so it's starting to Trend I
think the consumer as well you know for
a long time it's just like potency of
THC can get the highest THC potency and
the problem with that is the breeder I
mean not the breeder the grower is just
rolling it in hash and then getting it
tested and so what you see on the label
isn't authentic so I think as as the
trust and the education come come to a
plateau I think Growers are going to be
more and more interested in growing like
type two varieties um I'm a young Dad
I've got two little girls and because
I'm a daily consumer I like type twos
because I still get high I still feel
euphoric but don't have that impaired I
don't have that slowed reaction dry eyes
dry mouth because the CBD truly
counteracts that psychotrophic effect of
the THC um so for me it's amazing um
I've got guys in Michigan right now and
they're selling crops twice they're
running a type two and through
chromatography and winterization they're
pulling off the CBD and then pulling off
the THC and getting two turns of Revenue
on one crop um so it is trending it's
becoming bigger um and it's the best
possible form of cannabis medicine is a
full spectrum plant that has not just
THC but it's got some other beneficial
canabo as well yeah for sure and I think
I mean I think there's really a big
market for for the type two varieties I
can't tell you how many times I've heard
people say oh you know I've tried to get
back into smoking now that it's legal
and you know it's just way too strong
for me I got paranoid or got anxiety and
I think it's largely in part of that
it's it's just too high in the THC and
you don't have that CBD to kind of
counteract and give you a more balanced
experience like you were talking about
yeah yeah I mean there's a time in place
for everything I I love high THC
varieties too I mean but like I said
there's a time in place so there's
sometimes I want a type two there's
sometimes I want a type one um but yeah
I think as consumers become more
educated you know for a while there in
2018 the hemp industry a lot of guys
were buying hemp flour and mixing it
with their their herb they every day and
they're really enjoying the experience
um and so I like I said I think it's
kind of like the hotblade and viroid I
think we just need time the more time
the more education uh you know the more
consumers are going to realize what I
know and I'm sure many other people know
as well excellent yeah all about all
about education and and sharing
knowledge that's where we're about here
at camed so kind of wrapping up here
Justin I want to give you an opportunity
um share with the audience you know know
anything new coming up with uh green
luster fenos and um if they want to
learn more about you and what you do um
share any resources yeah absolutely so
new and upcoming uh we actually have
something really big um so when I was in
high school a good friend of mine he's
first string of the UNCC Chapel Hill
football team um they brought back some
really really nice Granddaddy Purple um
and we actually found a few seeds out of
this bat so this this is a long time ago
and uh what we did was we mixed it with
flour and froze it right away um I've
always been a genetic freak always
keeping seeds and seeds of other
breeders and from other countries and so
for me collecting genetics has always
been kind of a hobby of mine um and so
we popped um a few two years ago now we
popped these bag seeds quote unquote bag
seeds um and what we discovered was just
remarkable the females were all poor
every female we found of course right
was the flower was poor the yields were
poor but we found some amazing males
that had amazing stem rubs really really
heavy pollen producers and so we use
that um to create new varieties and
we're actually dropping three new uh
granddaddy per number three crosses this
year the number three was the mail we
used uh out of all the males we planted
and got in vitro it was just big fan
leaves really nice stem rub great
internal spacing very Hardy um so we
created three new crosses uh we crossed
our wintery fruit which was our top
seller in 2018 2019 in 2020 uh we
crossed your famous um ice cream cake
and then we crossed a Lemon Haze um
Lemon Haze was from Greenhouse
Greenhouse seats um so we're super
excited for this I mean it's an amazing
thing to experience something when
you're younger and then to be able to
bring it back grow it and it's identical
to what it was then uh it's a beautiful
thing so we're really excited for that
so that's kind of what green luster
fenos has coming up this year hoping to
release those in December uh we'll do a
breeders cut as well uh for those of you
that don't know anyone watching our
breeders cut is just when we pull one
out of vitro that's the one that I
selected personally out of hundreds and
hundreds of genotypes and so as you know
a lot of Growers a lot of commercial
operators craft cultivators they're
having to pop these seeds and spend nine
months sometimes 12 months finding the
right plant to turn into a mom with our
breeders cut we do all the work for you
um it's fully rooted and we overnight
ship for free anywhere in the USA
excellent now in terms of if Growers
want to do their own breeding project
with your
genetics is that is that cool absolutely
man I mean that's that's how this
industry exists I mean some of the
greatest varieties we have were produced
by other breeders not not by produced uh
by myself but by other breeders so
absolutely I think the more uh the more
the better you know we want more
breeders to use our germ plasm and cross
it with what they have and and vice
versa excellent and now coming back to
the bag SE because that's really
interesting you mentioned that the
females weren't so hot but the but the
males looked great is that typical with
bags seed no no I mean well we we don't
do a lot of bag seed hunting we just
have a few where I got some herb and I
really liked it and there happened to be
a seed and I kept it um so we're not
normally you know doing projects from
bag of seed that's why this is such a
big deal um but no I mean I would say
normally we find females that are great
um and then we you know we'll find some
males that are good and sometimes we're
hunting feminized seeds so then we're
not really finding males um but in this
case it was a it was a male seat um so
we we really uh won with that one that's
cool yeah awesome all right thanks again
justtin for for taking the time to talk
to us today about um about cannabis
breeding and um I hope to see you down
in canmed uh this June we'd love to have
you yeah well I appreciate it man and uh
thanks for having us on and uh yeah
we're looking to looking forward to
being out there in Puerto Rico all right
sounds good all right cheers brother
he
[Music]