hello thanks for having me here
thanks to medicinal genomics for putting
this on and really thanks for just
taking the time to stick around great
conference great speakers what I'm here
to talk to you about today is growing
from seed we have a small production
company based out of Oregon we've been
in business for about four years my
brother and I co-founded it in 2015 and
this past season was sort of a
culmination of a lot of the research and
development that we've been working on
over the over that four years that
resulted in about four thousand acres of
production across the United States for
Fito cannabinoid rich CBD CBD hemp
roughly 15 million pounds of biomass
testing at about 10% on whole plant
extraction so what I'm here to talk to
you about is a little bit of the behind
the scenes of what we do and how we do
it first off I do want to just say
thanks to medicinal genomics orange
photonics and Pyxis laboratories in
Portland all three of these companies
have radically changed the way that we
actually go about the plant breeding
process they have markedly accelerated
what we can do and how quickly we can
bring true f1 hybrids to to the market
for farmers to produce with and I'd be
remiss if I did not thank everybody on
my staff at oregon CBD and every day is
Monday Monday one Monday to Monday three
we've been working tirelessly for the
last four years to be able to make sure
that phyto cannabinoids non-psychoactive
cannabinoid could be accessed by
everybody in the country everybody in
the world at a reasonable price and
we'll talk a little bit more about how
that's come about one way to think about
cannabis legalization in the United
States we essentially have three
separate markets my background is
actually I have a PhD in sociology my
research was on the political economy of
cannabis in the way that it was
unfolding in 2013 and 2014 the way to
think about this is that we essentially
have three channels the first is the
adult use medical use recreational
however you want to describe it and its
THC dominant there's a high regulatory
burden seed to sale tracking testing
which is also a good thing but the
downside of that is that you're looking
at a fairly small user base
anywhere between fifteen to twenty
percent of the population at any given
time is consuming THC there are other
cannabinoids that are obviously being
used but that's that's the predominant
cannabinoid what's interesting about
that too and this is a now something
that came out of my research is that the
total u.s. demand for THC can be met on
about six thousand acres it produced
right in Southern Oregon so this is a
small market relative to the non
psychoactive x' and it's easily
capturable by by folks with a lot of
capital on the other aspect of this is
the pharmaceutical industry and we've
obviously heard a lot about different
compounds that have been developed and
trialed and that are coming online it's
fantastic we love it
but again the user base in this
situation is determined in part by the
FDA and insurance companies as well as
the applicability of each one of these
very specialized compounds for specific
treatments we like industrial hemp at
least from our perspective one because
it's non psychoactive - there was a very
low regulatory burden getting into this
industry and the user base is pretty big
you're talking about all vertebrates and
according to some of the research there
are some invertebrates as well we're not
sure how we're gonna capitalize on that
financially but it's out there real
quick hemp and marijuana in the United
States there's a differentiation between
them with hemp being anything below 0.3
percent THC this is obviously an
arbitrary socially constructed limit
that dates back to small and cronquist a
publication from some canadian
scientists in 1976 that we're examining
new leaf tissues on mature plants
obviously that's not necessarily the
best way to go about it today we have
better tools to assess what the
differences are and truly when you look
at the literature it says most of the
genomic data and literature on cannabis
at this point says it's all the same
there's just two very closely linked
genes eight centimorgans apart on the
same chromosome to differentiate between
these different types if you step back
and you look at this from a perspective
from a producer you're interested in
trying to have large plant numbers to be
able to do targeted breeding programs
and develop new unique cultivars
anything that's not type 1 or type 2 is
essentially fair game if you jump into
the hemp industry and with the passage
of the 2014 farm bill
we all had the opportunity to do that so
the originating question that really
drove our research was how can we make
non-psychoactive cannabinoid it's both
available and affordable picture of my
my trail running buddy in 2014 he was
about 11 years old hips were hurting he
was suffering from occasional seizures
and I found that CBD really was an
effective treatment for him helped out a
lot the problem was is it was about
twenty five hundred dollars a pound
wholesale when THC was about twenty-two
hundred dollars a pound wholesale at the
same time just seemed ridiculous
so we started to try to figure out how
to alleviate that the goal was to
essentially replicate what's already
been done this is no secret most of us
are all doing the same thing that
somebody's done before I hate to burst
everyone's bubble but we did the same
thing we tried to replicate corta farm
and GW farmers single cannabinoid chemo
type breeding program but importantly we
were not focused on just developing
individual clones for production in
sealed warehouses or greenhouses or
etcetera we really wanted to be able to
produce true f1 100% female plant
varieties that can be deployed across
the country with small farmers being
able to produce these compounds we also
needed to address some of the big issues
that come along with large-scale
production namely harvesting and drying
either using mechanization or using
music nature when when at all possible
and that required that we'd have to
develop independent lines based on photo
period sensitivity and that included
day-neutral plants which are considered
autoflowering early flowering plants
which is something that we actually
invented quote/unquote invented again
following in other people's footsteps
but these are plants that start
flowering shortly after the peak in June
of sunshine and essentially finish up in
the month of September in most locations
across the United States as well as what
most people are accustomed to which is
we call it a traditional long season
plan this is the behind the scenes this
is sort of the the in-depth breeding
program
that we operate at our facilities and
what this requires in terms of being
able to develop individual true-breeding
f1 lines is you start off with two
completely unrelated very distinct
parental lines you cross those two
planets depending on what your goals are
whether it's a chemo type chemo type
switch or increase in cannabinoid
content or creating structural
differences in the plant itself you in
Bri those excuse me you cross those and
create your f1 hybrids from there we
isolate each one of those F ones that
come out and generally this is you don't
need a very large sample size when
you're working with F ones sometimes we
go down to 20 plants in breed each one
of those collect the seeds off of those
using a self fertilization technique
described by Ram and set in 1980 1982
using silver thiosulfate the resulting
seeds that come off of those plants are
again isolated we grow those out we
spend their summers growing out F twos
which is sort of where unicorns emerge
this is a common thing that folks are
looking for in the plant breeding world
where they are just absolute
masterpieces of recombination taking the
best of both parts of the parents both
of the p1 and the p2 and creating
something unique diverse and new from
there to be able to to isolate and lock
in those traits we continue to in breed
generation after generation after
generation in isolation as long as we
can one of the biggest challenges that
we run into especially on the hemp side
is infertility tends to set in fairly
quickly in general we average about f4
the f4 generation it's a third round of
selfing basically attempting to reduce
heterozygosity
make the plants as true breeding as
possible so that when we do end up
eventually out crossing it to create our
f1 hybrids that you end up with high
levels of uniformity so again just to
highlight on the left you're seeing the
development of one line and that arrow
pointing to the circle is another
independent line that has to be
developed just to make each one of these
f1 hybrids once we've isolated these
plants before we release it to farmers
we run progeny trials so we'll have a
number of different variety
it came out of these different
inbreeding projects we cross it out to
our pollen donor and then we run our
trials to figure out which of these
plants are most stable when out crossed
and in general we usually come down to
one or two plants and those plants are
lucky enough to get put into our
breeding programs mass propagated and
end up resulting in producing seed for
farmers so the take-home message on this
is one if you're a plant breeder and
you're really looking for something
unique f2 is where it happens there's
just incredible things that pop up here
and it's a very different approach from
what we end up seeing in traditional
cannabis where you're crossing to
usually poly hybrid varieties that end
up not being true breeding when you try
to put them in the field but large-scale
field production requires a very
different approach and it's only solved
with true F once what we've been able to
do with the help of these analytical
testing companies and this breeding
process is essentially be able to create
new varieties in anywhere between 18 to
24 months depending on chemo type or the
specific terpene combinations that we're
looking for we end up with very vigorous
very uniform structurally stable dense
high yielding just beautiful flowers
that are perfect for farmers who just
need to put plants in the ground and
figure out how to harvest them to get
them to market and the really cool part
about this is that we've actually been
able to achieve 99.97% female plants in
these in these fields it's essentially 1
in 4,000 plants ends up having a male
phenotype we've actually tested it they
all have two x-chromosomes are really
female but they have a male phenotype
and if you let them pollinate plants 50%
of the following progeny will end up
having that male phenotype so they're
problematic need to be removed we're
working on trying to get it to a hundred
percent but at this point ninety-nine
point nine seven is we think it's pretty
good as I just mentioned our CBD lines
this is basically a three to four year
project we had our first lines in 2014
we out crossed those using the the
schema that I showed before and we've
conducted field trials in 2016 to 2017
before releasing those to farmers and
again we had over 4,000 acres in
production in industrial
legal states across the country yields
ranged anywhere between two thousand
eight thousand pounds per acre and
you're looking at a content of 8 to 12
percent on biomass
although the outliers and for all of the
varieties that we developed are well
over 20 percent on total CBD a content
on trim flower tops which is basically
we've taken industrial hemp and turned
it into the final cannabinoid rich THC
cultivars with great terpenes and great
structure that everybody loves but you
can produce them in a field some shots
of that the shot on the left is a 1500
acre farm in Kentucky same shot on the
right just a close-up if you're
interested in seeing more pictures of
this we have a photo contest on
Instagram hashtag best oregon CBD photos
absolutely beautiful results great great
plants and really the farmers made us
look good so that's one compound
obviously the goal is to be able to
isolate and put into production other
compounds as well our next target was
CBG we found our first pure CBG line in
the first quarter of 2017 this plant was
about nine and a half percent
CBG less than 0.1 percent THC
non-detectable CBD and it had a hundred
to one ratio for CBG to THC which when
you're looking at the industrial hemp
laws in the farm bill in the United
States a 0.3% means that you could
actually run up to 30 percent CBG on a
trim flower and still be legal for
interstate commerce in the United States
we have improved these lines over the
last year and a half and we conducted
large-scale field trials this past
season this is a picture of this again
this is no sleight of hand some people
for some reason think that when you have
a high level of CBG it's because the
plant was harvested early or you did
some sort of magic with with the root
zone these are just full-term plants
that happen to have THC turned
completely off just through a random
mutation that we happen to find the
needle in the haystack
and a regular non-functional CBD allele
so this particular plant tested at
eighteen point nine percent
CBG that's on a trim flower and again
you can see the the THCA content on that
is way below the 0.3% requirement to be
federally legal the beauty of this too
is once you start in breeding plants of
another tip if you can f2 is where the
magic happens
but inbreeding is where you can really
lock in and find incredible results with
the inbreeding on our CBG lines we're
able to attain right now that the
highest level that we've seen is four
hundred and eighty to one ratio so CB g
to THC which means that you can make oil
in this case forty percent CB g rosin
and still be below the federal the
federal limit of point three percent on
THC it's I think it's kind of cool we've
also discovered CBC Bridge plants CBC
rich plants are a little bit more
difficult in that there is a linkage
between cannabinoid content total
cannabinoid content production and the
CBC gene for some reason and we haven't
been able to get over about five percent
five percent total cannabinoid content
on those lines but they are CBC rich
anywhere between twenty to thirty
percent of the total cannabinoid
fraction there may be better ways of
going about producing CBC which would be
maybe isolating it in CBD lines or in CB
g lines but we're working to improve
that and we'll have field trials out in
2019 again just some analytical data to
back that up I'm not kidding
they're real my favorite thing that we
discovered this past summer in part
because I do like beer and I like the
hops industry but I feel bad for hops
growers it just doesn't look like much
fun
we thanks for glass we discovered
cannabinoid free plants there is
literature that describes the functional
mechanisms that make this happen its
upstream of CBG production you're
basically just turning off some of the
precursor chemicals and the plant only
bioaccumulates terpenes it is really
cool you're looking at the planet it
looks resinous it looks crazy
it smells wonderful there's no
cannabinoids so we found this and when
you look at the literature it suggests
that it takes two generations of so you
can out cross to any any flavor that
you're interested
in Sour Diesel etc etc and within two
generations you can identify plants that
have that same terpene profile but no
cannabinoids whatsoever three minutes
I'm really excited about it because it's
more agronomically efficient than hops
it doesn't suffer from many of the same
diseases in part because we are growing
from seed and they do contain more oil
on average in the same terpene
combinations as some of the the
traditional hops so we're very excited
to be able to work with the brewing
industry and being able to bring these
to fruition and put them in beers here
shortly and again just to back that up
no cannabinoids and the rock
chromatogram for that anything on the
left-hand side of that one-minute mark I
was told by Pyxis labs that there was
just something caught in there in there
HPLC machine close-up picture of these
cannabinoid free plants again the
trichomes they're covered obviously
covered they look very resinous but the
trichome heads are much much smaller in
size than then we see with with other
plant lines last little bit here we have
discovered multiple THC VCB DV and cv
g'v lines now these are lines that do
not have any of the propos as the
dominant fraction but through inbreeding
we are working to improve those and have
heightened expression ready throughout
the rest of this year and into 2019
filled productions filled production is
slated for field trials for 2020 and we
hope to have these out to farmers
everywhere across the country in 2021
the idea behind this is we know what's
going to happen with the cannabis
industry THC is an easy to monopolize
market you're going to end up with just
like the alcohol industry several
several very large companies dominating
production but if we can continue to
make each one of these novel
non-psychoactive cannabinoid available
for farmers to be able to produce we
have a chance to at least keep some of
the culture and some of the approaches
that we had in the cannabis industry
leading up to legalization alive and
well limit again looking ahead for 2019
we thought that CBD was probably going
to wash out it's not we've already got
contracts in place for over 15
Maker's it's almost a four-fold increase
over what was produced this year using
our seed so we're looking to increase
our capacity up to about fifty thousand
acres by the end of 2019 and like I
mentioned at the very beginning $2,500
pounds to get non psychoactive cannabis
to make my dog's hips feel better it
just seems wrong luckily we're down to
anywhere between twenty five to fifty
dollars a pound for equivalent biomass
at this point and that's over the course
of four years so we're very happy well
it's not necessarily great for farmers
it's great for consumers and people that
benefit from non-psychoactive
cannabinoid and we anticipate that this
is going to continue forward as time
goes on and we get better plants thank
you
[Applause]