I wanted to spend some time just opening
up some of the background behind this so
as I had just mentioned we've been doing
a fair amount of sequencing and trying
to de-risk what has been I think
affectionately termed lately
surveillance capitalism where we're all
finding our data is getting harvested by
other entities that might house that
data and sometimes being used in ways
that we're not all excited about this
certainly has happened in genomics over
and over again we've seen this with
23andme we've seen this with a variety
of companies and sometimes it's
completely voluntary and the the terms
and conditions are really clear about
this and there's there's there's
actually some informed consent that goes
on at other times there are very long
terms and conditions that people click
through and don't realize what their
data is going to get used for and so we
thought this would be a helpful
discussion to light of what we've seen
recently in the cannabis industry we've
certainly seen a few companies in the
space collect data from people under the
intent of helping them only to then turn
around and compete with them and this
got a lot of discussions brewing about
well should we be patenting our work and
should we be putting an open source and
which models are going to work for the
cannabis industry as we see in different
types of capital investment coming to
the end of the field traditionally we do
see a lot of capital investment coming
in that works on the paradigm of
patenting things and and and getting
things through the sec and that being
publicly traded and that those change is
very different than the cannabis
industry that has been around for the
last 80 years where there has been a lot
more sharing going on and sharing
thoughts and sharing genetics and
everyone working off of the shoulders of
somebody else so I wanted to spend some
time just at first just to introduce the
panelists here and let them each
introduce themselves you get
understanding of the type of people
we've collected to discuss this topic
and I think I'll start with my left here
with with Trevor thank you Kevin hi my
name is Trevor Wicky I'm the executive
director of the Calaveras cannabis
alliance I am a second-generation
cannabis farmer I've been growing for my
entire adult life for the last 20 years
and my primary passion through the
entire time that I've been cultivating
has been breeding in genetics I was
handed marijuana botany when I was 16
years old and
given that as my introduction into
cannabis cultivation and so when Kevin
extended an invitation to come down and
talk about the future of cannabis
genetics and the implications that it
has in terms of cultural resources
genetic resources and how that's going
to impact traditional cannabis producers
I jumped at the opportunity I'm grateful
thank you for the invite and there's a
lot going on in the space right now and
I think that this is really cannabis
genetics as Kevin just pointed out are
incredibly plastic there is a unique
genome that we're working with here it
is very under understood we have a
limited knowledge base here and I think
before we rush off and start tinkering
with things we should sit back
understand what we're dealing with and
understand the long-term implications
for the genome and for the people who
have produced this plant and have
dedicated their lives to it for decades
and generations so that's why I'm here
thank you so much my name is Janine
Coleman and I'm the executive director
and founder of origins Council which is
a nonprofit organization devoted to
establishing legal Geographic indication
protections for cannabis in support of
sustainable economic development for
cannabis producing regions I'd like to
take the opportunity to offer a brief
introduction to Geographic indication
systems for those of you that are not
familiar with them
Jia's or a legal standards based
designation that are awarded to products
of place products that you're familiar
with it that where geographic
indications are champagne Bordeaux Parma
ham tequila and these designations
recognize and codify regional
intellectual property rights of
producing regions and these intellectual
property rights are tied to region
specific agricultural practices
and product quality standards there's a
number of deliverables tie to Geographic
indications first and foremost they're a
regulatory framework and so the
designations are awarded by a regulatory
agency and they're therefore carry the
authority and the enforcement capability
of a regulatory agency so they're very
strong they have a lot of legal
strengths and the associated standards
are framed around product quality and
therefore they they are very strong and
building consumer loyalty and can be
very strongly leveraged for market
differentiation because the designations
are place-based there's a number of
deliverables to the region with respect
to standards protections for the
environment as well as building the
renown and reputation of the region
which can drive economic development
opportunities such as Agri tourism
Geographic indication systems have
tiered designations I'm in California we
have two designations that have been
created in state law we have county of
origin for cannabis and appellations of
origin and just to give you a sense
County of origin is technically a
indication of source and so there's
really no standards associated with it
other than it was produced in the
designated region appellations of origin
by contrast have a lot of standards
associated with them because the
designation is really awarded to
products that can that can prove that
there is a essential link between the
quality of the product and the place
inclusive them environmental factors and
also the practices of the farmers and so
as Trevor spoke to there are an enormous
tool to really protect genetic resources
as well as cultural resources of the
community so I'm very excited to present
today and talk about how this ties into
protections for cultivars and
particularly legacy producing regions
and I thank you all for having me here
I am Dale hunt I'm a plant scientist and
a patent attorney and I founded a law
firm earlier this year called plant and
planet law firm I think I'm here because
I know about patents and I think that's
why I was invited I have worked in well
a little bit of background my bachelor's
degree is in botany master's in genetics
and I did a PhD in molecular and cell
biology studying seed development then I
went to law school because I knew by
then I didn't want to be a professor and
since I finished law school I've worked
in a few different law firms
representing plant breeders among other
different kinds of companies in
connection with the work I've done with
plant breeders I have helped them
identify appropriate strategies for
protecting their genetics and for
commercializing them all over the world
I think we've probably done
commercialization agreements and
protected intellectual property in at
least 20 countries probably closer to 30
over the the 23 years that I've been
doing this I was kind of I got into the
cannabis industry by being asked if I
would consult on legal topics for a
group that was looking at IP policy as
it related to cannabis and then since
then I have gotten more and more
involved in the industry and now
consider that the work I do with plant
breeders is probably the well it's
definitely the most exciting work that
I've ever done and I consider it the
most important work that I've done I
believe that you know may elaborate this
on this later but I believe that the
kind of old-school self trained plant
breeders that are passionate about
cannabis and that each have their own
collections of genetics they've
developed and seeds and plants that they
have collected and received from others
I believe that constitutes the greatest
army of R&amp;D that the world has ever seen
in terms of really meaningful
developments on the frontier of Medicine
and I think it's one of our challenges
to figure out how to tap into that army
instead of having it become left behind
in the in the industrialization of of
cannabis and the the big money aspects
of cannabis so that's become sort of a
cause for me and it's also something
that I'm very excited to talk about and
write about and I'm glad to be here
with the rest of the panel hello
everyone my name is Christian saucier
I'm the founder and principal consultant
at crypto tech guru on this panel I'm
the only one who doesn't know much about
genetics apparently I'm here for
information science a lot of what we've
heard even this morning when we were
talking about the need for more
information more clinical research you
just mentioned all the little farmers
they have information right now that
could save lives and we just don't know
how to aggregate it my expertise over
the last five six years has been to
apply what I'll call this peer to peer
consensus protocol we know it has
blockchains
applied these technologies these new
formulas to reach an understanding
between people who don't know one
another and that's the magic of it in
the way applying that to other
industries one a more successful space
in their applied it to fruits and
vegetables having sensors in the field
following the product all the way to the
restaurant using these technologies
fisheries I mean it could be applied to
many things obviously but cannabis is I
believe one of the most exciting
opportunity for the blockchain space
forget Bitcoin this is the growing
industry
and the cannabis industry has a need to
better share or share information in
better ways and when we do that we also
want to make sure we recognize where the
information comes from you know the two
generation farmer and the lawyers the
the labs there's a lot of players and
you just can't expect there to be heavy
contracts between all the players and
the industry so that's where some of the
information technology that I believe
they can bring here to the table and I'm
looking for and looking forward to speak
to you guys about it excellent so I
think it's it's pretty apparent with
with the recent vitamin e acetate
outbreak if you want to call it that
that traceability of products is
becoming increasingly clear we it's
still unclear to me where these things
came from and how they got into the
testing or through the testing systems
that we have and one of my reasons for
wanting to invite Cristian on here with
with Jeanine is that this sounds like
appellations to me you and you know your
grower and you know what their methods
are and of course bringing bringing Dale
and and someone who's actually growing a
plant here is I think very important in
the equation to understand how do we
build these things so that they're
protectable and that the small farmer
does not in fact get gets squeezed out
of this based on the the bud light if
ocation of cannabis if you will do you
want to touch on just maybe the
background on the different flavors of
IP that are out there that that people
can consider sure if you are someone who
has a cannabis plant or cannabis
genetics and you want to protect it the
first question is how are you going to
commercialize it because there are
different forms of protection available
for cannabis each of which can be
completely ineffective if if it's not
aligned well with your commercialization
strategy so if you're selling clones
then you really really need a plant
patent a plant patent is a form of
patent protection that is like a
copyright on a plant it only protects
asexual propagation or only it it's only
infringed by asexual propagation of a
particular cultivar so if you're making
clones that's your form of protection
on the other hand if you're selling
seeds a plant patent doesn't really give
you any effective protection except
perhaps to give some protection if
you're if you have some important
parents of those seeds and you you may
well want to protect those parents with
a plant patent so the alternative is
something called a utility patent it
treats the plant as more of just any
other kind of invention and it lets you
claim the protection for the plant by
way of protecting of claiming its seeds
it's any kind of it's progeny using the
plant variety and a method of breeding
it can protect extracts of the plant and
so on so for example if you want if your
business is all about extracts and
you've got some really great underlying
genetics you would need a utility patent
to really protect that so and then for
people in the hemp space there's a newly
available kind of protection provided by
the USDA it's not new to other players
in the seed industry but it's new for
cannabis the USDA plant variety
Protection Act permits protection of
seed propagated varieties and since the
passage of the 2018 farm bill it also
protects a sexually propagated varieties
the tricky part of that is that if you
want to file a USDA PvP application you
have to submit a seed sample and those
seeds have to be seized that the
government can legally accept so that's
only applicable currently to industrial
hemp that's not available for high THC
cultivars so coming back to that if
you've got seeds you want to protect and
they've got high THC you've really got
to get a utility patent most of all just
call somebody who knows what they're
doing and they can help you out
[Music]
and how do we bring appellations into
this and that if you want to have a song
if you want to have it if you've grown a
plan let's say in humble County or
Mendocino that's you unique terroir the
Appalachians aren't necessarily a
recognized form of intellectual property
at the USPTO but they're certainly
legally recognized as something with
with with weight to them what how does
one go about choosing each of these
paths you want to take yeah it's a
journey with respect to policy and
starting you know California has an
amazing propensity to really set the bar
with respect to a policy reform for
cannabis so we do have in state law and
the California Department of Food and
Agriculture a free work to support
Geographic indications for cannabis and
so working on appellations of origin and
as I mentioned we have county of origin
there is case law with American
viticultural areas which are the GIS
that we have in the United States for
wine that GIS are very strong with
respect to the protections associated
with them and in fact take precedence
over trademarks so there are some some
pretty rigorous protections that we can
start to build upon and Pollard's policy
reform is simultaneous right now there's
work happening today in fact at the
United Nations with consideration of the
World Health Organization's
recommendations to reschedule cannabis
the World Intellectual Property
Organization is looking at some of these
protections with respect to cannabis for
genetic resources cultural resources and
also cannabis is a traditional medicine
and so I think between what California
is doing to set precedents around GIS
and what is happening on the
international level there's a pressure
that's going to really unfold with a
national level of policy reform and
there's some bills that have recently
passed
both Oregon and and being entertained in
California with respect to trade between
legalized States and so how we can start
to fold some of these policies into
those types of agreements and really
further the policy pathway for
Geographic indications for cannabis I
think what we've seen also in the same
in the same vein and the food business
which is similar when you look at labels
like organic Fairtrade and and very many
you know labels out there you never know
for sure right the package has a stamp
but really the evidence is is what you
know would prove that this is organic or
Fairtrade and today that evidence is
very very difficult to get right there's
organizations obviously that are
defending these labels right so that
organic still means something to
consumers but even the people in charge
of defending these labels and I've
talked to many of them are are little
freaked out because it's really hard to
defend these these labels the evidence
that can be brought to bear that I
cultivate this plant according to
organic or did I you know transport it
in the right you know environment right
humidity and all the things that we need
to know about the products at the end of
the supply that information can be now
captured and moved in parallel with the
product we're good moving product
obviously our supply chains can move
information it can move product but the
information gets tampered with in
between and sometimes by something that
might not be fair trade so a way to
defend these is to have a system an
information system that allows
throughout the supply chain the ability
to capture data that can be seen as
evidence that the farmer have an organic
or some some other you know
accreditation by the right accreditation
body and if not that that is a piece of
information that could be known if we
knew how to convey the information with
the product
I think we're Christians trying to say
he may not realize that no one ever
counterfeits anything in the cannabis
industry
how would how would you feel about an
Appalachian clearly you're in a district
that will probably be one right yeah
Janine and I were both on the state
working group and we discussed with
state regulators the rollout of the
Appalachia program I see this as an
opportunity for us to create
intellectual property rights that are
community property rights and not just
necessarily property rights that are
held by individual corporations or
individual private entities by having
GIS and community-based Appalachia
systems producers come together and this
is honestly the only place that
California's regulatory system actually
gives control and local control to
cultivators licensed cultivators get to
come together establish standards
procedures and cultivars now this is
incredibly important there are people in
my County in my area who have been
cultivating and breeding for decades and
generations those particular cultivars
that they have bred in these areas are
unique and specific to our area and it's
our job to try to come together and
establish these norms and procedures
around these cultivars to protect them
the Legislature's done a good job by
giving the cultivators and the licensee
is the actual opportunity to establish
these standards procedures and cultivars
and so for me I think that this is a
unique opportunity for us to be able to
preserve and protect the value that
we've created in the preceding decades
and generations before legalization came
into effect I also think that what
Christian brought up is incredibly
important one of the things that we need
to do is establish the scientific basis
for demonstrating that there is a unique
and uniform product that we are
producing in our particular geographic
regions we need to differentiate that
between our region and other regions I
live in Calaveras County it's on the
it's in the Sierra Foothills so our
environment is incredibly different
relative to the Emerald triangle it's
much more arid it's almost semi desert
we're going to have very different
outcomes even with the exact same clones
than they're going to have simply based
on the environmental effects of our area
and so a particular clone grown in the
Emerald triangle verse a particular
clone grown in Calaveras County even
though they're the exact same genetic
material produces two two different
outcomes these are ways that we can
through the data and through the science
of it doing lab testing doing genomic
testing and also collating all of this
data and aggregating it within the
appalachia system we're going to be able
to prove that there are unique distinct
outcomes that are tied to place and that
are tied to the cultivars that we have
traditionally bred this is something
that is going to essentially once we
move into a much more uniformed
commodities market the thing that's
going to differentiate products within
the future cannabis space is going to be
the ability to create value-added and
differentiation between products and a
Palacios are going to be one of the key
basis is for us to do that and the
science is going to be absolutely vital
being able to track all of it back and
to demonstrate that this plant came from
this place was grown with these
practices and we have the data to show
that this has actually happened that's
what's going to create the value-added
because if somebody's just producing a
clone and not living up to the standards
that are set and established and the
unique outcomes that are tied to those
standards and practices then we're going
to see the devaluation of these unique
areas of traditional cultivation so to
my mind the appalachia system creates
the most open and community-based system
for developing and
I pee for cannabis it allows the
consumers access and information to the
actual data and it provides the
cultivators and the traditional
producers a means and a mechanism
through which to demonstrate and
differentiate their products from other
products that may be mass-produced or
may not live up to the standards as if I
could comment it as long as we're
talking about the way things could be
done in the future one of the things
that's a real problem right now is the
utter chaos around the naming of
different strains or cultivars and
correlating that back with anything
that's meaningful and so one of the you
know as long as we're putting things on
the blockchain I would love to see some
kind of a DNA fingerprint that says this
is the standard for this cultivar this
is what it really is this is how you
know that it is what you think it is and
then you know I can picture looking at
scanning a QR code and getting
verification that this cultivar is real
some information about the appellation
these are different layers of value if
you have a genuine genuine genetics
cultivated in a certain place under
certain conditions and they move yeah
move through the supply chain in certain
ways that assure the quality then you've
got a lot more protection for the
consumer and you can ask a higher price
so a premium farmer premium genetics
doing everything right ought to get a
much higher price yeah yeah I want to
add to that because this is what really
reminded me of what Christian was doing
at a company called ripe that I oh is
that traditionally like seed to sell
tracking has become the sturdy work now
in the cannabis industry and I think
it's mainly a dirty word because the
databases are centralized and the people
harvesting that data aren't necessarily
delivering any of the rewards of that
information aggregation back to the
people who delivered the data and what
we're seeing now in many other genomic
industry is there's a company that
George church has recently founded
called nebula genomics and what they're
attempting to do is invert the model of
genomic
aggregation of information from the
23andme model which is very centralized
to giving the access and the keys that
DNA sequence information on a blockchain
to the patient's the patient's can opt
in and decide to sell that data to Roche
if they want to and the patient gets the
reward not necessarily the central
aggregator of that information
well there's ways that this can be done
in the food industry that I want to
throw the ball to you Christian because
I think you've seen this happen before
there's some challenges doing it yeah no
they definitely are maybe the first
concern about this blockchains to be
addressed as the fear of all the open
and the free and then the open block
chains are open indeed but the openness
is there for anyone to come into the
network right so the the farmer who does
not have a big brand can come into the
block chain network and say hey I've got
a unique product though so the openness
is in the accessibility of you know
collaborating on the network once on the
network the block chain and that's what
we did for food it can be very private
right you can be anonymous even in some
cases if that's what the the industry
needs so the private deals in the
exchange of information between
commercial parties the building of
commercial brands and reputation all of
that is is very available on these open
blockchain now specifically to what
you're talking about Kevin yeah the food
and even the wine business are ahead of
cannabis on in this particular space and
we're already seeing a number of
commercial players including one of my
own startups right right dot IO that
looks at the traceability problem the
trust problem is there evidence that you
know this Colombian coffee was grown
again in fair trade practices and these
questions are you know it's new
technology I'm not gonna you know
suggest that these networks are super
well-established but there's many
commercial partners right now that are
building competing blockchains for the
dissemination and the certification of
information that comes with your stake
or which you
fish or with your cannabis or with
anything so it it's really something the
industry needs to look at that there's
other industries that have faced very
similar problems this one is it's more
exciting because there is a tradition of
the small farmer doing it prior to
legalization and that tradition needs to
be preserved that tradition built this
industry so we need to have an
information system and a certification
process that respects you know these
pioneers that actually built the
medicine that were we're looking for I'd
like to speak to enforcement because and
and by that I mean enforcement of the
certifications and the standards
associated with it because that's really
where the rubber meets the road we're in
very early iterations of track and trade
systems for cannabis I would say this
cautiously that there is a benefit to
prohibition and that the rigor of of
intent behind track and trace will drive
I think more accountability with respect
to those systems developing for cannabis
but additionally with Geographic
indications what you have is you have
regional shared byun shared motivation
shared intellectual property rights and
so there's a motivation on the part of
the designated community to really drive
the enforcement of their own standards
as well to maintain the quality and
reputation of their product and so
there's kind of a very unique and I
think powerful dual enforcement
mechanism with respect to Geographic
indications because you have that
community buy-in to really ward off
counterfeit products and to really
adhere to the quality and standards that
you have communally created and so I
think it's a really kind of powerful
differentiator for Geographic indication
systems with respect to where the rubber
meets the road with enforcement of
standards I also want to throw this back
to Dale a little bit in regards to
patent pools I'm hearing a lot of terms
like community genetics and community
information and I know there's another
mechanism that you've been think
on how to create patent pools that might
be able to maleic asymmetric warfare in
the intellectual property space that's
me my parents would be so proud I'm all
about asymmetric warfare now yeah one of
the questions I am asked most often as a
patent attorney by growers and breeders
is can Monsanto make me stop growing my
own plants and of course the answer to
that is no but there's a little bit of a
yes the know is if they're your own
plants and you've got them and they
predate anybody else's patents or
whatever then then in terms of patent
protection no one can come in and tell
you to stop growing your own plants the
way it works in the real world in some
other in the commodity AG space is that
a company that has vast access to
technology and money can make better and
better seeds that it better in terms of
not necessarily taste or anything but in
terms of productivity in terms of you
know how many dollars can you squeeze
out of an acre of land or a growing
season and they can build some of those
technologies right into the seeds and if
you're a commodity farmer you end up
facing a choice of either buying the
seeds from that source and growing them
with enough efficiency that you can sell
them for less or for more than it cost
you to produce them or your other
choices to continue growing the seeds
you've always grown less efficiently and
face a commodity pricing structure where
it may actually cost you more to produce
your your product than you can sell it
for and in that way powerful technology
forces in a commodity market really can
put people in a position of either
adopting that technology or of going out
of business or losing money perpetually
so in response to those questions I
thought about that and I realized that
there's an analogy
well so obviously people want to be able
to have well one of the recommendations
is if you can stay out of the commodity
market because it really is hard to
compete in these economies of scale and
so directed to the small farmers who
still don't want to be sued for patent
infringement for some of the very broad
patents that have issued the analogy
that I drew from that is that in the
electronics industry we all hear about
the big lawsuits because they're really
really big but for the most part there
are companies that coexist by licensing
their technology to each other and just
agreeing not to sue each other because
they could sue each other into oblivion
they could be in court every day
the reason they breach these agreements
is because both parties have some
patents that the other party might
infringe and instead of just getting
stuck in patent litigation they cross
license each other and they coexist my
suggestion for the cannabis industry and
to protect the small farmer is to
establish some pools of patents and a
mutual defense organization of some sort
where anyone who gets sued for patent
infringement can tap into this pool of
all their their colleagues in that pool
the small farmers the small growers
small breeders and any patent that any
of them owns it might be useful in in a
countersuit or to assert against this
party that's it's threatened or has
actually filed a patent infringement
case that whole community's patent pool
can be tapped into to to try to
counterbalance the the force of these
really big companies there are some
challenges with that but I do think it's
viable and I and some other people who
care about this are working on putting
this very thing together that would be
fund for patent defense so that the
small the small player isn't completely
out
outgunned in terms of firepower and
mounting a defense and challenging the
validity of an overbroad patent as well
as having a pool of other people's
patents that they can draw on in a
counter suit so there's there's still a
lot to be done with that it's nothing
that any one person or law firm will do
on its own but it is something I believe
needs to be done so that the community
of small farmers and traditional players
in the industry really have a chance to
to stand their ground in the face of
some very big very aggressive patenting
strategies okay so we're gonna open up
the microphones for questions and while
folks are kind of collecting their
thoughts on on questions there I did
have a question at least four Jeanine
how do you are there cases in the past
where people have protected champagne or
protected appellation branding in the
past and how have those traditionally
been litigated are those obviously
they're not litigated through any kind
of intellectual property court they're
litigated probably more through state
law or I don't actually know I'd love to
hear more about it well because the
designation is really codified and
issued by the regulatory authority that
really is then the opportunity to bring
forward claims of fraud right and so a
lot of how it's driven is really by
producers trade associations syndicates
and in France is what they're called and
so there's an element of self policing
and then an authority with which to
bring your claim forward and then for
the designation to be evaluated with
respect to standards adhere met and so
that's really generally how the
enforcement works with an appellation
system I think I see a question from
Brent yeah thank you this is great so I
get two to brief questions the first
rights the coattails of Kevin's question
I hear a lot about
geographic gie because i can't forget
the action and I hear allusions to
science where are we with any kind of
standard protocol for looking at what
would determine what what you're I mean
because what I'm hearing is essentially
you're talking about having a
essentially a biological marker of
epigenetics so what what are you using
for that and then you know the second
question is with respect to the idea of
a patent pool what about in the other
event where we're not looking where
there's a clear patent infringement case
and where a patent defense fund could be
leveraged really to you know for the
benefit of the infringer could could
there be a backfire type situation there
okay I'll attempt to hit your first
question then hand it to they're
probably Dale for the IP side of things
but well one way of perhaps trying to
register where your genetics are is you
can get DNA sequence information fairly
cheaply now from the plant and then if
you can demonstrate a lot of photographs
on phones have geo tags embedded inside
the metadata of the image and so if you
can if you can attach that image with
the geographic timestamp of it if you
will with the sequence information on
some type of blockchain to prove hey
this was grown in a particular
appellation there's perhaps ways of
circulating that information so that
it's immutable and it's on a distributed
public ledger that nobody can change but
in terms of the second question on
patents I'm gonna pass it over to you
yeah I I hope this is responsive to your
question I'm I didn't I'm not sure that
I got the full question if you'd like to
rephrase it you could or I can just dive
in
Oh York it's really bright up here
[Music]
I saw so in a case where yeah okay
the question was in a case where where
someone in this patent pool is
maliciously trying to infringe a valid
patent would it backfire and I do
believe so I think you'd have to have
exceptions you can't have bad faith
infringement of a valid patent this is
really about maybe two things the at
least one there there have been I want
to get to jargony or anything but to
give you that maybe the hopefully the
one minute version of patent examination
when you apply for a patent the patent
examiner's job is to look at what you've
claimed and find every reason that they
can for rejecting it that really is
their job it kind of protects the public
from guilt from granting unduly broad
monopolies the way they do that in
biotech or electronics or air airplane
engines or anything is they look on this
vast body of prior academic literature
prior patent literature and they can
find things that come pretty close to
what someone is claiming to have
invented and if they find something
that's dead on exactly the same they'll
give a rejection for lack of novelty if
it's just pretty close maybe that what
they're claiming is a trivial
modification over what came before
they'll give it a rejection for obvious
'no self in the space of you're a
cannabis patent examiner and this is an
industry that has a lot of commercial
activity but basically no significant
prior literature in terms of prior
patents or prior academic research
notwithstanding the beautiful work we've
heard spoken about today that is such a
a small number of publications compared
with the hundreds of thousands or
millions of publications in some other
industries and they're pretty focused
fantastic but they're pretty focused so
if someone applies for a patent in the
space the examiner really is flying in
the dark they don't have the tools in
the literature to assess really whether
this claimed invention is new or not and
the result is that arguably there have
been some patents that have been granted
that have been unduly broad and the
place of burden on the industry because
they really cover things that are not
new if that's the case and I'm not here
giving a legal opinion but if that's the
case the community itself is the best
source of this so-called prior art
they'll be able to come especially if
they're if they consider themselves a
mutual defense organization of some sort
they'll be able to come forward with
their own evidence that this or that
chemo type has been around for a long
time and isn't really wasn't really knew
when this particular patent was filed
that's just one example but yeah I would
never want to be part of something that
would defend a bad faith infringed er of
a valid patent this is really about
patents either that are there are over
broad and therefore invalid that cover
things that are not new or not that are
obvious or in some cases it can be that
someone does develop something great
let's say somebody comes up with
technology to make all cannabis
mildew-resistant everybody's going to
want to have that access to that and
this kind of patent pool might be able
to negotiate a group license in a way
that wouldn't be available to any
individual member of that pool so in the
case of a genuine invention that has
valid patent rights there can still be a
place for this kind of a pool and I hope
we can make it happen hi there I have a
question in particular for Christian I
was that answer does it okay if I go
forward yes sorry yeah okay I come from
that the food processing and agriculture
background and we were very involved in
like using technology that came from
Europe that was regarding traceability
so forth like you could use a barcode
and know who grew your meat what they
ate what medicine they have and so forth
and so on and the United States was a
much farther behind and that in giving
that accessibility to the consumer
because of the EU and and
differences of where the sources were
coming in Apple eat all the things that
you guys are talking about and how I in
the cannabis sector in both the ahem
side and on the THC side and I'm looking
for that type of ability and I'm
understanding now that the blockchain
technology would give even a greater
under a greater depth of traceability
and chain of command so my question is
is is that something that I've been
trying to shop for this is that's
something that I can actually go out and
get like the right software the part of
the chain of command or the blockchain I
mean I how would I obtain that and use
that in my business I think I should
repeat the answer you gave earlier you
know come talk to me afterwards we can
talk about this there are a number a
number of commercial operations that
provide these services today we're all
innovators in this room right so when
you're the pioneer the blockchain space
is also relatively new to new in ten
year old industry governments you know
companies and foreigners are all trying
to figure out how do i tap into the very
few new things that blockchains do you
know blockchain is not the solution it
is part of the solution for specific
reasons traceability and Kevin said it
earlier right it's a notarization of
that traceability you can trace with a
private database if you if you trust a
company that owns a database it's it's
cheaper than blocking but the problem is
what you put if you don't trust
Monsanto's words right and that's where
that traceability can be improved with
these more open Network and again you
got to be careful with how these words
are interpreted open does not mean
there's no room for commercial legal
governmental and you have spoken
specifically and about food to the
Canadian foods you know Inspection
Agency and they were asking you know
Walmart Loblaws
some big fishery in Canada hey we need
better traceability so next time there's
a food poisoning event you know we can
figure out where it's from quickly and
at the end of the the conversation all
these companies were all freaked out
about how much it was gonna cost them
and they were telling the Canadian
government sorry we can't do this
without help and then they say hey
Christian maybe you know blockchain can
help well they'll block trains gonna not
gonna solve a hundred million dollar
problem but it is gonna be part of the
solution and the solution that it brings
is better transparency and better
notarization of the information that
you're viewing can it be conned hi can
you cheat on the blockchain yeah yeah
that happens to it if the product is not
information in this case the product is
a kind of cannabis so it is a physical
product that can be a lie about the
information put on the blockchain so
there's a lot of aspect to this it's not
a panacea but when you look at sites
like canopy dia you can start small
right you can start with a scan at the
at the farm in a scan at the dispensary
and maybe a scan of an employee and
again all of this can be done very
privately and in private systems but
when you're trying to demonstrate that
no this is the farm that's been there
for four generations and they've been
growing your good cannabis for you and
you want to differentiate your product
that's where I think these more public
networks like blockchain systems can
help yeah I'll just add to that real
quick that there has been I was at an a
OAC meeting recently where Frankie
honest who's high up at the FDA was
commenting on how it was taking in 60
days to track dirty product like bad
mangoes or something throughout the food
chain that they currently have and so
they got on board with a particular
blockchain project known as hyper ledger
and I'm not necessarily endorsing that
as the particular solution here but they
demonstrated they could get that
sixty-two days down to like six seconds
once they had everything bar-coded seed
to sale as an experiment now they only
had that running in one particular
and obviously that has to get expanded
to all foods and there's a lot of
building and and engineering that needs
to go on to scale this to multiple other
industries but it's happening at the FDA
level where they want block chains on
everything and they want genetic
signatures on everything so they can
trace outbreaks and much more rapid clip
I think the next question might be
coming through there were having a hard
time to see how people were responding
to you in the wrong direction don't take
offense right I'm on the right I have a
cyber question my background is in
physical security so dealing with act
physical access control video cameras a
lot of our solutions have been moving
towards the secure hosted phase so it's
it's up in the cloud I know with Canada
and the Patriot Act there's a lot of
rules where if we work with any of our
Canadian companies it has to be servers
that are within Canada's borders outside
of the US my question for cannabis is
because it's not federally legalized do
we do we have to consider where is that
information stored so like for example
if my organization isn't with this state
that California does does my information
have to physically reside in California
how do we deal with that secure hosted
I'll make a quick comment on the
decentralized network protocols which is
my specialty it is a it is a problem
governance are struggling with right
blockchain came about and now you can
move more than $10,000 you know across
borders without anybody knowing
governments didn't like that right and
that's why they're there they're trying
to figure out how to legally categorize
these new information networks
that said well maybe maybe it's it's a
good thing that the cost of transaction
is being reduced by the cost of storing
information in a specific place on
planet earth should not be relevant
anymore in the 20th century right
because we have all sorts of ways to
store information we can store
information in DNA so the these old
approaches are changing its changing
slowly obviously it's part of
legalization and creation of zonings
and-and-and cultivars now identification
will take time but I think these kind of
requirements will be relaxed over time
simply because they're becoming I don't
want to say obsolete but sorry so just
from like a legal standpoint you don't
you don't see worry I am NOT a lawyer so
I'm always worried about legal that's
why I call my lawyer when I need a
lawyer
you're correct no there's there's a
danger there that I don't have a
solution for it but the information will
not stay on a database in California I'm
not a lawyer but my reaction to that
would be that the information itself
isn't technically in violation of the
controlled substance act though that
information could be used in prosecution
if activities were violating the
controlled substance act so as far as I
know like the information itself isn't
the crime it's only evidence of a crime
potentially so you're worried that the
geotag to demonstrate your appellation
points to your house that might be a bad
idea
hi my name is Jason I'm with Ocana I
have a patent question I was reading
last week that Charlotte's Web got
approved for a point two seven THC level
on
CBD hemp strains and they're gonna
supposedly gonna get approved for a
utility pen here in the next few months
what does that mean exactly the point
two seven I might have a follow-up
question yeah actually I was interviewed
about this very thing by at least a
couple of reporters a couple weeks ago
this is big news I think the biggest
concern arises from people not having
clarity about what this actually covers
and at least the plant patent that I
looked at and that was the topic of the
questions I addressed a couple weeks ago
at least that plant patent is truly a
plant patent which means the only thing
it protects is if someone makes clonal
copies of that exact unit type and so
then the question is well why would they
do that it may be that and this is all
you know why would they choose to get
that kind of patent if they're in the
seed business then the only reason they
would want to get that kind of plant
patent is to protect the parent from
being copied without permission they may
be selling clones and you think wow how
would you sell clones of for hemp when
you've got a farm and on such scale it
who knows it I know that one of the
biggest problems in hemp is if your THC
level goes above 0.3 you've got a big
problem and so maybe this is so stable
so locked in at point 2 7 or lower that
it has enough value that people would
would perform this using clones but
bottom line is if the patent if it's a
plant patent it will never protect more
than one genotype if it's a utility
patent you have to look at the way it's
claimed and a utility patent
would never be able to claim every kind
of hemp that is below 0.3 because those
aren't new but it could claim a
particular cultivar that is the subject
of a seed deposit and that if you are if
you have something that that matches
this cultivar in this seed department
then you there this seed deposit then
you would be infringing it I want to add
one thing to that as well it's also
important to know that plant patents
only cost about twenty five hundred
dollars to file so that's a really tiny
insurance policy for someone to protect
against employees running out the back
door with cuts and so they may viewed
that in light of maybe security cameras
and then like this is a good thing to
add on so that if anyone grabs a cut
they know that we've got a plant patent
we can then come after them with it's
not a huge cost next to a utility patent
which might be ten times more yeah it's
it's can be as low as twenty five
hundred to file it to get it all the way
through the patent offices more but it's
still around around 10k ten to twelve K
usually is the average so so at point
two seven they don't own every man
thank you very much so many questions so
little time can we speak to him
pollen collection storage for a moment
my big quandary here is I know the
datasets there is somewhere but they're
practically impossible to find typically
what would be the moisture content in
fresh hemp pollen how far do we have to
and how safely can we di drape that down
before we do not really long-term but
safer in a few months - 50 C storage in
that fallen without degrading it or
rupturing the capsules so that it's
ready for pollination when we're when
our plants are and then what stage do we
have to re mooster eyes that pollen
before we apply it I have seen some
photos that shows that the pistil
structure itself is capable of
remoisturize in the pollen as it
produces it's to to insert a C in a
package but we've got a lot of money put
in this and we don't want to try to be
throwing shooting it in the dark thank
you that's you I don't have any of the
specifics at hand right now I do know
that there are some published studies
that address the issue of pollen saving
and from personal experience low-tech
and not doing any scientific studies I
leave my pollen out for two weeks to dry
and then I put it into fridge rated
storage with desiccant and I leave it in
my fridge for years and I've had viable
pollen up to 12 months after I've stored
it in that fashion
it's not at all scientific or what
you're asking but I do know that the
data is out there and I believe I have
some PDFs that I could share afterwards
with you thank you because the industry
is somewhat beyond
our old styles are doing that now
exactly yeah
you know this kind of information like
this this particular you know experience
practice that you you do about the
pollen which I know nothing about so
well I won't talk about that but the
information that you have which was a
question is really hard to connect you
to right there's another farmer producer
that needs to know what you know and
this is where you know little excitement
maybe we're beyond just traceability if
we want to really engage some of the new
dynamics with these peer-to-peer
networks that information you you can
put up for sale on these networks like I
don't know how much that was worth but
some of it is fractional you know you
know fraction microtransactions
fractions of pennies when was the
cannabis you know cultivated or or the
harvest date right that that's a little
piece of information and a lot of people
will want to know down the supply line
right the guy doing the oil the guys
selling the oil the customer buying the
thing everyone's gonna want to know you
know the cultivar and a bunch of
information to the extent where that
information makes the practice better
the farmer should be should have a forum
to be able to brag about it in order to
raise the value of their brand of
cannabis and if we can notarize that on
a network then that becomes money in
your new money a new stream of
information that doesn't come from the
cannabis it comes from the information
about the cannabis that you've been
drawing the channel sell I really want
to reinforce that topic because there's
asymmetric information all over the
marketplace whenever you find people who
can share like this there's value that's
created and it's like from our
perspective we would pay value or money
make micro transactions what-have-you
for people that supplied us with chemo
types in addition to their sequencing
and so instead of us trying to collect
that stuff and harvest it on you and
sell it to somebody else we'd actually
love to be able to have a blockchain
that could give people credits if the
strain they had in canopy dia was really
popular or sold a lot or had a chemo
type and we could give them more
frequent flyer miles to use more
sequencing or use more of our products
if we could actually capture some of
that information and trade it so even
though you might think of terpene
profile on a plant as meaningless and
not worth of
it's valuable to other people who don't
have access that information and if they
could get on a network that could share
it it would be it would be wonderful I
think we have time for one more question
over there before lunch breaks yeah I
have a question for Dale and then a
brief comment that and I can meet with
you afterwards on with Janine and Trevor
on the whole GI and Appalachian thing
Dale thank you by the way we had the
pleasure of meeting with you in Oregon
and thanks for outlining the difference
you've answered some of my questions
already basic outline of plant pattern
versus utility patent could you take a
moment and just dive into the PDP and
why it's good for him you kind of ran
through that kind of quickly first of
all what does that acronym mean again
plant variety protection plant what
plant variety protection pvp pvp yep
I didn't enunciate well okay so the USDA
to put a little bit of historical
context on it the the Congress passed
the plant patent Act and I think about
the 1930s but for some crazy reason it
only covered a sexually propagated
plants trees vines things like that it
did not cover seed propagated plants
later on in about the 60s there was a
worldwide movement for protection of
plant breeders right or establishment of
plant breeders rights and something
called you paav was created which is a
French acronym that basically means the
Union for protection of plant varieties
and/or of new varieties and eventually
the u.s. joined you paav in gosh 70s I
think maybe 80s doesn't matter we're in
the were in the next millennium anyway
but in joining you paav the u.s. limited
its protection unlike the rest of the
world that limit its protection just to
seeds and that was to kind of fill the
gap created by the plant patent statute
it was only last December that that gap
was or that that limitation was removed
and
the USDA PvP can protect case actually
propagated varieties although that's
only theoretical for now because the
plant writing protection office hasn't
yet figured out how to handle the
deposits of a sexually propagated plants
seeds are one thing getting whole plants
or some kind of tissue culture or
something that's another thing it's a
whole big administrative challenge but
the main differences are between PvP and
a utility patent on a plant that would
claim a seed is plant Brady protection
as it currently exists with in usable
ways you can use it for him you have to
make it a positive about 3,000 seeds I
think it's exactly 3,000 seeds to be
precise you have to pay quite a few fees
but the examination process is quite
different from the US patent and then
I'd say the biggest differences are that
the that plant variety protection the
whole you pod system has two exemptions
that don't apply to utility patent one
is called the breeders exemption which
means that it is not an infringement of
a plant variety protection certificate
to use a protected variety in breeding
other varieties there's also called
breeders rights breeders rights yeah
well sometimes when they talk about
breeders rights they talk about the
rights that accrue to the owner of that
of that registration no this is
specifically on the PvP right yes but
then the other exemption is the farmers
exemption which means that a farmer who
buys registered seed can save enough
seed to replant the same acreage season
after season and that that's not an
infringement the farmers not allowed
into that exemption to sell the seed or
to make more seed than then enough to
replant that field or that acreage but
that that's an affirmative right that
that is carved out of the plant variety
Protection Act that is not doesn't have
an analogy in a u.s. utility patent so
if you want to have the maximum control
over how you help people use the seeds
that you sell the right way to do that
would be with a US utility patent we can
talk a lot more of the laughs yeah thank
you yeah and there's a lot more and just
a comment because one of the organize
that Oregon is really taking a lead in
certified seed hemp seed right now
they've been certifying seed in Oregon
for over a hundred years largest
producer of grass seed on planet earth
so they're pretty far ahead and actually
working on that state board with a
couple other breeders but the comment I
wanted to make another organization I
mean this is for Janine and Trevor this
is the like in a VA you called it a GI
or an appellation the one thing that I
don't hear talked about sometimes I
think is it a weakness in that for
high-end cannabis is number one it's an
annual plant so it's not the same as a
vine that's going to get the terroir
number two we had a guy a geologist from
OSU which is our premier AG school in
Oregon it's like the UC Davis of Oregon
and he came down and wanted to
investigate bringing forward exactly
what you guys are talking about the GI
the Appalachians so he gave clones to a
lot of people through our Sun grown
growers guild and the one thing that
people haven't thought about is most
high end cannabis is not grown first
annual plant number too often not grown
in native soil grown in big bags of
imported soil so you're not going to get
the terroir of the flavor so I think
it's a good play for us as an industry I
just want to make that point it doesn't
necessarily require an answer from you
at this time I don't want to take any
more time but I think it's a longer play
the Appalachian versus protecting our
genetics through other means it could be
more effective now and that's something
we have to think about it's not grown in
native soil by and large
those are excellent points and I would
like to respond briefly there are
geographic indication protections for
annuals and also products in general not
just crops and to your second point
which is an excellent one with respect
to terroir and native soil one of the
things our organization is looking at
from a research perspective is the
microbiome because we feel like that is
an array that creates a bridge between
the the native soil and essentially the
native microbiome of the region that can
populate and integrate with soil mediums
to such an extent that there is that
localized influence particularly with
respect to the exudate relationship and
then the metabolome a expression of the
plant and so that's something we're
really specifically looking at with
respect to how this might be relevant
for cannabis as an annual that is
frequently cultivated in aggregate soil
so I'd love to speak more with you after
the panel all right I think we're gonna
wrap this up so folks and get some lunch
before disappears but I want to thank
all the panelists here thank you very
much it's great