I'm here to talk to you today about
something that medicinal genomics has
developed and I think it's going to
revolutionary revolutionize testing
using qPCR methods so I've been working
at medicinal genomics as an R&amp;D
scientist for the past five years and
over those past five years we've
developed a lot of tools to help the
cannabis community particularly in in
the genetics of cannabis as Kevin talked
earlier about Jamaican Lyon and in
microbial testing so um
microbial testing while it's not the
most glamorous idea is very important
every state that is legal to sell
cannabis has potency having met have
heavy-metal testing and microbial
testing and like I said it's not the
most glamorous but it is the most
important because the only confirmed
deaths in cannabis have come from
microbial contamination
Aspergillus in particular although with
the recent controversy with vape pens
that might be up for debate and I think
there's some talks on that maybe
tomorrow
so as we've just heard cannabis is used
as a medicine and there are
immunocompromised patients out there
some that don't even realize that
they're immunocompromised so it's really
important to make sure that the cannabis
that that are receiving is free of
microbial contamination so it's
imperative that the testing labs have
the ability to accurately detect for
harmful harmful microbial contamination
on cannabis and there's generally two
methods that are out there for microbial
testing molecular methods and we have
medicinal genomics have qpcr testing and
culturing methods which is your
traditional does it grow on a plate and
they both have as you can see there's
qpcr methods have more pros than
culturing methods in that it's more it's
faster it's more accurate you can
specifically target the contaminant that
you're looking for and it's scalable
whereas culture methods are slower
they're more inaccurate they're not
specific and it's harder to scale but
the one thing that
qpcr lacks that culture methods has is
that can I go back is that if the DNA
DNA is present and a qPCR a site is
going to be detected it doesn't matter
if it's live or if it's dead so there's
two types of testing in in the in
cannabis microbial testing qualitative
or presence/absence testing and this
requires that no amount of the target
organism be present in one gram of
sample so these are your four
Aspergillus species Aspergillus flavus
from a goddess schneider Tereus
Salmonella stackin e.coli and then you
have qualitative or the total testing
testing and this allows threshold limits
of the of their to be microbial
contamination so for example total usin
mold most states have a 10,000 CFU limit
a total aerobic bacteria 100,000 CF
either way so like I said before qPCR
detects all DNA whether it be live or
dead and this can be a concern in the
cannabis industry because there are some
cultivators out there that want to make
sure that their cannabis is free of this
microbial contamination so that will it
will pass and so they're doing
techniques like a radiating they're
killing the microbes but killing the
microbes still leaves behind their DNA
and qpcr methods will pick up that did
DNA but we've developed a method to
solve this problem and it's called Grimm
reefer so like I said before the pro of
qPCR testing is that there are primers
and probes specific to amplify that's
the DNA that you're targeting however it
cannot distinguish between live or dead
DNA and the solution that we came up
with is eliminate the contaminating dead
DNA again by this method called grim
reaper so I'm just gonna go over
see how this if I pointed it sure so
it's a simple upfront 10-minute
incubation at 37 degrees Celsius what
you do is you add in your Grimm reefer
enzyme along with a buffer into your
sample this all happens before DNA
extraction and lysis the grim reaper
enzyme comes in and it chews up any of
your free-floating or dead DNA after 10
minutes at 37 C you add in the mg C
lysis buffer that lysis buffer
deactivates the enzyme the lysis buffer
while deactivating the grim reefer
enzyme also opens up the D the cells of
your live organism thus now you have
only your live DNA's you live organisms
DNA present and then what we've added is
we've added a positive control into this
mix and this positive control is a DNA
template that you add in to ensure that
your enzyme is in fact has been
deactivated and that will later down the
line be tested in your q PCR reaction so
after the positive control after you add
in your lysis buffer you had any
positive control and then you proceed
with the mgc DNA extraction procedure
and that positive control is in there
because if you have your original method
versus your Grim Reaper method you
expect that that positive control DNA is
not going to change it should be exactly
the same CT value as the original method
versus the grim reaper method so so to
test this theory we took any alive ecoli
culture and this was an e coli culture
that had only been growing for four
hours to ensure that the majority of the
culture was in fact live and we split
that into we put that in in the presence
of ham and put it into twelve different
tubes six of the tubes
and that was the wrong button six of the
tubes were treated with the original
method six of the tubes were treated
with the grim reaper method and
increasing copies of salmonella DNA were
spiked into each tube they were treated
10 minutes 37 degrees and then after the
10 minutes that mgc lysis buffer was
spiked in to kill the to stop the enzyme
and the positive control was added in
DNA DNA extraction happens so 12 samples
it was running triplicates of a total of
36 q PCR reactions were run so these are
the results for e.coli and so the
hypothesis is is that due to the
presence of e.coli there ecoli results
for the groom Reath reefer method may be
lower than the original method but since
ecoli was fresh it freshly cultured
ecoli results will be more similar
between the methods and the internal
control results and again like I said
this was only a 4-hour equal eye culture
and as you can see there's no
statistical no statistical significant
difference between the e.coli results on
the grim reaper results so on your
x-axis you have the increasing amounts
of Salmonella DNA and on your y-axis is
the cycle of Q PCR cycles of qpcr goes
to 40 and the results are consistent
with the hypothesis that the Grim Reaper
met the Grim Reaper method does not
interfere with DNA from live cells and
both methods demonstrated robustness and
that there was no impact from the
increasing amount of Salmonella DNA and
so these are the Salmonella results and
the hypothesis here is that free
Salmonella DNA will not be detected for
the Grim Reaper method until the amount
of free DNA exhausts the enzyme and as
you can see the Grim Reaper method
consistently deactivated this element
Ella
until you got to the 4.0 2,000,000
copies and you see that purple bar there
is the Salomon Ellis
like no in qpcr results the higher the
signal value the less DNA is there and
so the results for the Grim Reaper
method are exclusive of free DNA as long
as DNA is less than 4.2 million copies
and just to give you an idea a tenfold
dilution is represented by a 3.3 CT
shift so for the 6.0 3 million copies
there was an approximate 12.9 3 CT shift
was which is about a 75 hundred fold
reduction in free DNA so now here's the
Grim Reaper positive control and as I
said earlier that the hope here is that
the enzyme is deactivated with the
addition of the mgc lysis buffer and
therefore you should not see any
difference in your Gremory for positive
control between the two methods and
that's exactly what you see here the
null hypothesis cannot be rejected in
the 95% confidence interval since the
p-value was 0.16 one so there is no
significant no statistically significant
difference between the Grim Reaper
control and the Guru Murray in the
original method and this result is
consistent with the hypothesis that
river e4 enzyme is no longer digesting
free DNA after incubation and after
lysis buffer is added and both methods
demonstrate robustness as there's no
impact from the increasing amount of
Salmonella DNA and so another feature
that the M gcq PCR assays have is we
have built in an internal control and
that's targeting the Cannabis DNA and so
due to the inherent presence of free DNA
in the plant material you would expect
that a dried sample is going to have
some dead DNA so you would expect to see
the internal control shift between the
original method and the Grim Reaper
magnet and that's exactly what we see
here the null hypothesis the Grim Reaper
in original method internal control
result results are the same can be
rejected at a 99% confidence interval
since the resultant p-value is 2.4
five times 10 to the negative 25th so
there is a statistically significant
less hemp DNA detected in the groom
reefer method verse the original method
and the results are consistent with the
hypothesis
so these are some qPCR curves this is
utilizing four different channels in the
instrument the fam hacks sy5 and rocks
channel and let's see if I can get this
to work so so the orange signal that you
see here is the Salmonella signal and
this is at four hundred and two thousand
copies and as you can see with the Grimm
reefer method that orange signal goes
away and then when you get down here at
the eight million copies you see the
cell Mennella signal very strong here in
the orange and it decreases after the
Grim Reaper method so this is an
approximate I believe it's a 12 C T
shift here so here's some conclusion
summaries the Grim Reaper method is not
metabolizing DNA and viable cells it's
not metabolizing DNA after deactivation
the Grim Reaper method is capable of
metabolizing free DNA up to 4.2 million
copies
both the original and group Grim Reaper
methods demonstrate a high level of
precision both methods demonstrate
robustness for 'allah analytes observed
as there was no impact for the
increasing amount of Salmonella DNA and
the original method results are
proportional to the amount of free DNA
plus DNA and viable cells and I
apologize for the numbering being wrong
there so now that we had shown that this
worked in the lab we wanted to see what
would happen in real cannabis samples
because we're not a cannabis testing lab
so we don't have access to actual
samples so we asked for independent labs
if they would be interested in beta
testing this
and they said yes and so now I'm just
gonna take us so there's a lot of
results I'm just gonna go over our snap
shop I kind of picked some from the
total aerobic assay and I just wanted to
point some things out here so lab one
what you can see here is that there is a
shift in the TAC signal it goes from 25
point two to twenty seven point nine
five there is also a large shift in the
SEC G signal that's that internal
internal cannabis control you see it go
from a twenty six point two one all the
way to a thirty two point three six and
the grim reaper positive controls are
very similar for the two and that's what
you would expect lab to without with the
original method there was a detection at
25.87 but with the grim reform method
none was detected and this indicates
that most of the DNA that was present on
this sample was in fact dead and you can
see that there was a large hacks s ECG
signal shift here yet the grim reaper
method is positive control remains the
same so I don't know what this sample
could have experienced both the large
shift in s ECG signal this could have
been a sample that had been heavily
irradiated lab three you can see that
the tach signal isn't really changing
all that much so this is indicating that
most of the organisms present on this
sample are in fact alive as you're not
seeing that CT shift and there's a
threesome we are about a 3 CT shift and
the SEC G signal and again the the
positive control and the size 5 is is
similar and finally lab 4 you see a very
large shift again in that tach signal 26
to 30 7 the HEC signal there's also a
shift and again the internal control
signal I mean the positive control is
similar so there are other free DNA
removal products out there
one is PMA and PMA is a high of affinity
photoreactive DNA in Turkey
by and what that basically means as is
that the dye goes into the
double-stranded DNA and it becomes
activated when it's exposed to light
he's in my way and this results in a
permanent DNA modification which renders
the DNA and soluble and therefore can't
be extracted through your standard DNA
extraction methods the dye the dye is
cell membrane impermeable so that means
that it can't get into the cells of live
DNA there's also other enzymatic
treatments out there and they require a
fifteen to thirty minute
digestion but they also require a
fifteen minute in the activation step at
95 to 100 degrees C and that
inactivation step at such a high
temperature is gonna cause the live
cells to start to lyse and then you're
gonna have a competition happening
between those cells that are starting to
be lysed and the enzyme being
deactivated so these both have have
their faults PMA it requires an
incubation in the dark followed by
exposure to visible light either through
an LED device or a halogen lamp PMA does
not work equally across all
microorganisms and different
microorganisms may require different
concentrations of PN ma and different
exposure to light and PMA is toxic which
creates a biohazard waste stream as for
the other enzymatic treatments I the
product literature that they claim has
an average signal reduction of two labs
or about six CTS which isn't as good as
what I had just showed you and again
what I had just stated before the
heating the sample 1095 for enzyme
inactivation will result in the lysis of
live organisms so some final thoughts
Grim Reaper offers a simple 10 minute 37
C upfront
incubation that is non-toxic and easily
devack deactivated without causing harm
to viable organisms the result it
results in a three to four log or 12 to
13 CT reduction signal from free DNA the
method includes an added added positive
control to monitor deactivation of the
enzyme it can be easily added to the
current mgc DNA extraction protocol and
provide qPCR results that are void of
dead DNA and this can be used to guide
sterilization protocols that grows I'd
like to acknowledge our collaborators
that helped us work on this project and
of course the team at medicinal genomics
anyone have any questions
[Applause]
thanks for the talk I actually have a
quick question which might be obvious to
folks that are in the industry here but
I was wondering if if it sounded as if
the microorganisms are dead then it's
not a concern anymore
but I was just I mean if you had like a
massive mold infestation on the on the
product and then killed it with
radioactivity would there still be
toxins and other things associated with
it I'm just curious why the distinction
between living and dead so it depends if
you had a major
Aspergillus contamination which produces
market auction micro toxins then yes I
think it would be a concern I'm not sure
every state has different rules and
their regulations as whether they if
they fail can they go back and be remate
remediated and tested again I was under
the impression that in California it
doesn't matter if it's live or dead but
I could be wrong so I think it depends
but there are other regulations that do
you test for micro toxin testing so if
it was dead and left something behind I
would think it would come up positive
there
yeah those this is a really interesting
talk
III not working in this field I was a
little confused at first when you
describe this as dead DNA isn't it that
your test is detecting any free DNA
attached to the cells and if for some
reason there was cell lysis that
occurred during the preparation of the
extract would that skew your numbers
yeah it could and we call it so a lot of
is it's basically viable verse
non-viable so in culture methods you're
only detecting living organism cells
that are able to create colonies on your
plate we're in the qPCR it does it
doesn't distinguish between the two yeah
yeah yeah it's agnostic okay thank you
yep
great thanks guys
[Applause]