well first i'd like to thank the
organizers of canmed and thank you so
much for the gracious invitation to
present this year and i'm so sorry and
so disappointed i can't be with you in
person i'd much rather be there
trust me perhaps next year in the
meantime i'm uh honored to share some
data with you from basically a first
look if you will at open label data from
a cbd clinical trial for anxiety or what
i like to call high anxiety question
mark
when we think about anxiety disorders
it's important to remember that they are
the most common of all mental health
conditions according to the world health
organization
one in 13 globally suffers from anxiety
lifetime prevalence of anxiety disorders
does vary across age groups there are
different examples for for instance
within the united states it appears that
between the ages of 30 and 44 we have
the greatest
likelihood of having an anxiety disorder
interestingly and perhaps not
surprisingly the coven-19 pandemic has
not helped the situation
u.s census data revealed 42 percent of
people reported symptoms of anxiety or
depression in december of 2020 that was
an increase of 11
from the previous year that was that's a
that's a pretty big jump a 31 increase
so important to keep these things in
mind um anxiety disorders are generally
under-reported and under-treated and
lost productivity as a result of anxiety
and depression cost the global economy
somewhere in the neighborhood of about a
trillion dollars every year
so it's not as if there aren't
treatments for anxiety disorders there
are plenty of available pharmacologic
approaches including but not limited to
things like ssris snris benzodiazepines
maois tricyclics
5ht1a receptor agonists anticonvulsants
atypical antipsychotics
that's not the issue the problem is that
despite a number of options with regard
to conventional medications response
rates remain somewhat limited and
residual symptoms are often present
that's a problem
in addition adverse effects also limit
tolerability and adherence i don't know
how many times we've heard people say
yeah i took the medication but the side
effects were so hideous i had to stop
so limited efficacy of current
pharmaceuticals and
you know people's unwillingness to
continue with something that causes uh
side effects underscores the need for
alternative treatments for those
suffering with anxiety
the growing availability and popularity
of legal cannabis uh products combined
with higher rates of anxiety globally
further exacerbated of course by the
covet 19 pandemic has reignited a
long-standing conversation about the
potential effects of cannabis on anxiety
it's important to remember though that
when we think about cannabis we again as
i'm very fond of reminding people we
have one word um and we use it to
describe lots of things almost anything
at all from the plant um when we think
about products cannabis or
cannabinoid-based products uh very
important to remember that they can
either be plant-derived or
non-plant-derived so
in terms of plant-derived products you
can have full-spectrum products which
contain a host of cannabinoid
constituents delta nine thc cbd a host
of other cannabinoids as well as
terpenoids the essential oils that give
cannabis its characteristic scent and
flavor profile and have their own
biobehavioral effects flavonoids etc you
name it then there are broad spectrum
products which contain all of the above
except for delta nine thc
interesting uh and a completely separate
talk probably in terms of how we quote
get to xero because it's an interesting
approach
but broad spectrum products are designed
to capitalize on the the full spectrum
aspects of of having everything from the
plant that may be beneficial without the
potential intoxicating issues related to
thc you can also have plant-derived
isolates for example things like
epidiolex a single extracted compound
cannabidiol from the plant that's
purified so it has no other cannabinoid
constituents no terpenoids no flavonoids
etc
isolates can also be non-plant derived
so things that are
more conventional medications for
example the the we would call a
synthetic cannabinoid like an avalon so
it's it's not just one thing
cannabis and cannabinoids can be used
for multiple reasons in many ways and in
countless combinations so it's important
to keep that in mind single compounds
like the single isolated cannabinoid
compound that i talked about
basically
works very differently from a full
spectrum product right where you have
the broad range of naturally occurring
chemicals in cannabis including thc
and the entourage effect or the
synergistic action that occurs in the
presence of multiple cannabinoids
terpenoids and flavonoids is something
that can be leveraged
there are many who question the presence
of things like the entourage effect i
think it's becoming more and more widely
accepted at this point
especially since lower doses of full
spectrum products may in fact have
therapeutic
effects relative to single extracted
compounds there was a meta-analysis in
epilepsy patients conducted in 2018
that basically looked at patients using
cbd rich products these were
full spectrum products and and the
meta-analysis basically reported that
lower doses were required to retrieve a
therapeutic effect and fewer adverse
events reported compared to those
patients who were taking purified
products or single extracted compound
products so important to keep in mind
the relationship between cannabis and
anxiety is also a complicated one
there's been research suggesting that
cannabis use is prevalent among
individuals with anxiety disorders and
so the question becomes what are we what
are we really looking at relaxation and
relief from anxiety are among the most
commonly reported motives for cannabis
use and to date very few studies have
examined the causal nature of the
association and those that have have
failed predominantly to control for what
i would call related factors which has
led to mixed findings
most at this point believe that the
etiology of anxiety disorders is
multifactorial and not likely caused by
a single factor including cannabis use
so that's very very important to keep in
mind but there are still plenty of
people who are convinced that that is
probably the cause and not a solution
there have been several reviews that
have looked at the effects of cannabis
on anxiety
going back to 2012 there was a review
that looked um and basically reported
that outcomes were highly variable
cannabis may have a bidirectional
influence on anxiety response responses
as a function of dosage
uh
not incomprehensible certainly a later
study noted mixed findings with regard
to impact of cannabis on anxiety in
recreational consumers and i should say
right here
it's a very very big um sort of a big
part of the picture whether we're
talking about individuals with anxiety
disorders who are being treated as those
using recreationally and those using for
medical purposes with regard to how
they're considered and how the
approaches may vary in a systematic
review in 2017
uh there was a report that concluded
that cannabis use is no more than a
minor risk factor for the development of
elevated anxiety symptoms in the general
population and in fact the national
academy of science engineering and
medicine report in the same year
reported there
was limited evidence that cannabis or
cannabinoids would be effective for
improving symptoms of anxiety and ptsd
so
why so mixed
individual factors including but not
limited to things like your genetic
profile physiology other substance use
and previous experience with cannabis
are very likely to play a role
the impact of cannabis and cannabinoid
products on anxiety appears to be
related to the very specific and very
different
impact and effect of individual
cannabinoids for example research
findings suggest that delta 9 thc and
cannabidiol have different effects on
anxiety and that dose is absolutely a
critical consideration
when we think about thc we know that thc
can be anxious at low doses that is it
can reduce uh symptoms of anxiety but is
often anxiogenic at higher doses so it
can either exacerbate or perhaps even
cause anxiety at higher doses
there have been a number of studies
demonstrating this with regard to acute
administration i think the earliest one
that i have on this slide goes back to
2012 where healthy males administered 10
migs of thc exhibited increased anxiety
as well as dysphoria and some psychotic
symptoms sedation and subjective
intoxication
as well as increased heart rate
some later studies found that daily use
was associated with anxiety disorders
even after stopping the use of cannabis
acute subjective effects following
smoking
joints that contained up to 60
milligrams of thc and recreational
consumers demonstrated that thc
decreased calmness alertness and
contentment and
thc induced increases in anxiety
actually lasted up to eight hours after
smoking
among cannabis users female users report
increased anxiety symptoms relative to
female healthy controls there may be
some obvious gender differences
on the other side cbd um it appears
perhaps has anxiolytic properties there
have been a number of studies going back
um into the 80s actually our
our folks outside of the us have done
some really compelling work the very
first one looked at thc induced anxiety
cbd was able to mitigate the anxiogenic
effects produced by thc
the same group actually also reported
that cbd reduced anxiety induced by the
simulated public speaking test and
healthy controls and in patients with
social anxiety disorder and there was a
recent a more recent
clinical trial a double-blind clinical
trial in japan that looked at the
efficacy of 300 milligrams of hemp
derived cbd isolate so single extracted
compound
in teenagers with social anxiety
disorders and avoiding personality
disorders the cbd treated group
exhibited significantly decreased
anxiety relative to the non-treated
group so again rather compelling
with regard to dose investigations of
all you study products containing single
extracted compounds cbd only purified
cbd which exhibits an inverted
bell-shaped dose response curve with
limited dosage range for therapeutic
response that's important remember that
whole plant full spectrum products have
been shown to yield therapeutic response
potentially at lower doses relative to
single compounds likely the result of
the entourage effect or this synergistic
action
of the cannabinoids terpenoids and the
other players so
really really interesting just keep that
in mind everything that's been done so
far has been using single extracted
compounds
so
in 2014 i started a program called mind
or marijuana investigations for
neuroscientific discovery and we have a
number of observational longitudinal um
cross-sectional survey and clinical
trials underway
um the very first clinical trial we
launched some years ago
is a cannabis derived high cbd
formulation for individuals with
moderate to severe anxiety we have a
number of other trials ongoing for
anxiety as well which i'll tell you a
little bit about but this is the one i'm
going to show you some data from
this is basically a custom formulated
study product that i sourced the
original story is actually much more
interesting than the
than the final story but um the study
product wound up being formulated with a
naida based extract uh we've completed
the open label phase of the open label
to double blind double blind is now
underway and we actually have added a
third arm so it's uh it was an open
label phase
the double-blind phase includes placebo
the same product that people got in the
open label phase and a single extracted
isolated version of the study product so
study product removed everything except
the cbd that's underway i'm going to
show you data from the open label phase
in just a minute
we also have cbs cbd related project
focused on patients with anxiety and
agitation
basically i formulated that product with
some industry partners the open label
phase of that study is underway i also
have a hemp derived high cbd formulation
for folks with anxiety who don't quite
need the same level of severity
for the very first trial again
formulated in partnership with some
industry collaborators and that open
label phase is underway i just got
another ind approved
for patients
with a mood disorder so
in terms of the anxiety realm we have a
lot going on
so in terms of clinical trial product
formulation uh the products are custom
formulated uh by myself
and my program in collaboration with the
knight of drug supply program as well as
some industry partners and
chemists with what i would call
significant campus experience it's
basically how you go from taking an
extract that looks like that which is
this very very gummy rather unfortunate
looking and smelling um
product
that patients are definitely not going
to be able to use turnkey and turning it
into something that looks like that what
you see in the dropper it doesn't taste
too bad actually i have to say
um so this very first ever clinical
trial of a whole plant derived high cbd
full spectrum product for anxiety is
like i said open label to double blind
custom formulated solution four weeks of
active treatment and the basically the
study product consists of approximately
10 migs per ml of cbd which doesn't
sound like a crazy high dose it's
administered three times a day it also
has somewhere in the neighborhood of
point two four to two six or so things
of uh thc so at a three time a day
dosing you're under just one milligram
of thc per day under one milligram of
thc per day keep that in mind it's
sublingual administration and patients
are taught how to do it in the lab and
then they do it on their own at home
this is a quick
overview of the study timeline basically
we have a screening visit where everyone
gets a full clinical and diagnostic
assessment they complete a series of
anxiety and mood rating skills um sleep
quality of life and other scales a full
neuropsych assessment
obviously urinalysis and for some of our
folks early on we did a blood draw for
pkpd work
we then assess them every week with
regard to
anxiety and mood scales as well as
clinical
check-ins and side effect assessments
and urine screens
the pandemic shifted this at the very
end of the trial i will tell you
um neuropsych assessment is done again
at the end of the four week
clinical trial
and
basically at the end of the five weeks
we're
able to verify how much they took
and sort of back calculate every week
that they come in or every other week
oh sorry an open label phase they came
in every week um we actually weigh their
bottles on the way out and on the way in
so it's not just us telling them take
one mill one mill three times a day and
and then reporting um having them report
how what time they took it etc we
actually weigh the bottles out and weigh
the bottles in
we assess their clinical ratings and
their cognitive performance and we're of
course interested in the safety profile
potential for serious adverse events
uh urinalysis
was completed to look for thc positive
status over the course of treatment
which is another really important and
rather interesting finding from this
study so what do we do in terms of
anxiety measures
the back anxiety inventory is a
self-report measure it's a 21 item
[Music]
tool that can be used to screen for
anxiety and each item is rated on a
scale of zero to three it's a
descriptive of subjective somatic or
panic related symptoms of anxiety then
there's the oasis which is also
self-report it's only five measures that
can be used across anxiety disorders to
measure what we call functional
impairment caused by anxiety and it
measures both frequency and intensity
anxiety as well as the degree of
avoidance and interference with work and
social function
finally there's the hame or hamilton
anxiety scale it's
clinician-administered scale a 14-item
um metric that is basically administered
in the form of an interview this allows
for information for multiple sources to
influence ratings so we have the
subjective report we have the examiner's
observation
and it's been shown to be one of the
most if not the most reliable index of
clinical state
with regard to anxiety
so in terms of
this particular cohort this was a group
of 15 folks that's we set out to
complete open label
data or collect open label data from 15
folks we stopped at 14.
um
oh sorry actually we set out to collect
data on 16 people we recruited 15 and
one was discontinued which i'll tell you
about in one second
average age was about 41 16 years of
education and as you can see from their
scores on the oasis the bai and the hama
they all had moderate levels of anxiety
overall
of the 15 patients we enrolled we
discontinued one for the use of another
cannabinoid product one time with their
partner that was enough for us we had to
let them go um overall the study drug
was well tolerated and there were no
serious adverse events reported at all
interestingly and very importantly no
patients reported intoxication on
average patients used not three meals
per day but 3.48 meals per day
the daily equivalent to that is about
34.7 milligrams of cbd and uh just about
0.8 megs of thc so that's why it's so
important for us to weigh the bottles
not just take their word that they're
taking about a mil again they have a
marked dropper but still people tend to
administer slightly
different levels over time
so what do we have in terms of our open
labels results when we look at
the bai what we find is a 79.9
decrease
in self-report ratings uh so this is a
significant improvement in ratings of
anxiety they go from about a 20.3 at
baseline to a
4.07 at the end of the four-week trial
on the oasis we see a 70.2 percent
decrease the scores go from 11.3
approximately to 3.3
and on the handmade that's the examiner
driven scale they go from just under 20
or 19.8 to 3.3 and 82.9
degrees so these are rather striking
decreases in self-reported
anxiety
at some point this will move forward
when we look at other ratings of mood
the bec depression inventory for example
a very commonly administered metric
designed to measure self-reported
measures uh or symptoms of depression
our subjects go from a 20 approximately
a baseline to a 4.4 that's almost a 78
decrease in self-reported depressive
symptoms profile of mood state
which allows us to look at
differences over time total mood
disturbance that's sort of your grand
total goes from 65.8 down to a 23.9
between baseline and four weeks of
treatment that's almost a 64
decrease so pretty striking
as i mentioned we also look at other
domains so in terms of sleep and quality
of life the pittsburgh sleep quality
index very commonly administered metric
looking at sleep quality here lower
numbers are better folks go from a 9.2
to a 5.8
it's uh 36
change and when we look at the short
form health survey or the sf36 the basic
measure of quality of life
we see some rather compelling and
striking
significant improvements in areas like
physical function
[Music]
energy emotional well-being social
function and
pain this is interesting again baseline
to four weeks of treatment um these are
these are pretty striking differences
over time
the only thing we didn't see and that's
pretty interesting actually because we
think of them potentially as control
areas role limitations with regard to
physical
the physical role that someone has to to
perform
and general health
so in terms of some of the other areas
where we might expect to see some change
we do
and then those two we don't between
baseline and four weeks
when we turn to cognitive performance
this is very similar actually to data
that we've been collecting for some time
in our longitudinal observational study
that's been going for several years we
basically look at people
who are interested in using medical
cannabis for a range of medical or
psychological or psychiatric symptoms or
conditions we look at them before they
begin using cannabis and again over time
we go all the way out now for several
years but we published a paper looking
at cognitive change over the course of
one year so we look at baseline to three
months six and twelve and what we found
was basically some improvement over time
again those folks are choosing their own
regimen
in this case this is a clinical trial
and what we see see is exactly the same
patients are basically demonstrating
stable or improved performance they're
not demonstrating decrements especially
in measures of frontal or executive
function this is just an example of some
of the measures uh the trail making test
part b not significantly different
they're certainly not getting worse
for stroop interference time or time to
complete a task requiring active
inhibition over overlearned response
tendency and we see a statistically
significant improvement with regard to
time required to get the job done
uh the wisconsin card sort it's
considered a gold standard measure of
frontal function total correct what we
see is a statistically significant
improvement between baseline and four
weeks uh we also see the same thing in
the number of categories achieved on the
wisconsin card sorry so they're getting
better they're not getting worse over
time that's important especially when we
consider what we know to be the case in
recreational consumers very often we see
decrements in areas of executive
function
we have some other measures of executive
the letter number sequencing task and a
task of phonemic fluency
again we're seeing either stable or
improved performance patterns not
decrements here improvements after four
weeks of treatment folks are going from
a 12.5 to a 13.4 that's a trend uh
that's that's that's pretty interesting
again you know alternate versions of
tasks are used so
we're not really thinking this is a
practice effect especially after four
weeks but certainly something to to
watch over time
i think that the expectation perhaps
when we introduce something that's
cannabis or cannabinoid-based is i'm
sure it's not necessarily going to make
people better i hear that a lot
and that's just not what we're seeing in
the case of this particular clinical
trial
so to conclude the cbd open label
clinical trial
data so far findings suggest that use of
this custom formulated whole
plant-derived high cbd sublingual
product results in less severe anxiety
as measured by the oasis and fewer
anxiety-related symptoms as measured by
the bai and the hama after four weeks of
treatment relative to their own baseline
self-reported improvements and other
mood symptoms like sleep and quality of
life were also noted which may be
related to reduced anxiety
it's funny these things often coexist so
it's hard to disentangle them i have
often noted that sleep disturbance tends
to happen in lots of different
conditions so
it's not surprising that when we see
sleep improvement we also see other
things improve and vice versa
improvements on tasks of executive
function were also noted we certainly
didn't see any worsening of task
performance which is really the
important issue here and no significant
adverse events or intoxication were
reported at all over the course of the
trial a definitive assessment of the
impact of this novel treatment will
certainly come
from the double-blind placebo-controlled
phase which is as i mentioned currently
underway and we have this additional
study arm that will now allow us to
compare the full spectrum product to a
matched cbd isolate which i'm very very
excited about
um one thing that i mentioned sort of in
passing is that we did monitor people
for thc positive status over the course
of the trial and the reason for that is
that many many people are taking what
they call quote cbd products they say oh
i'm just taking cbd uh what they really
mean is they're taking a product that's
either high in cbd or marketed as such
or contains cbd primarily hemp derived
products and the big question is am i
going to fail this random drug test
since i'm taking cbd which i think is a
great question
there have been very few studies that
have directly assessed whether the use
of a full spectrum high cbd product
could yield positive results on a
urinary drug test
and you know assessing cannabis use
through the detection of thc metabolites
it's really really important so we
monitored this status in this open label
trial and we used in-house or you know
in lab drug assays and we then confirmed
those data using gcms quantification in
pre versus post-treatment
we also looked at the relationships
between thc positive status and
demographic variables as well as things
like creatinine [__] is typically
reflective of kidney function and
hydration
so after four weeks remember our final
sample was 14 not 15 folks we had to get
rid of one of them um exactly 50
of our subjects or our patients seven of
them were positive for thc metabolites
after the four weeks gcms confirmed the
assay findings but indicated that the
drug screen was actually more sensitive
than its stated lower limit of detection
that's probably because of some
cross-contamination from other
cannabinoids thc status was only
significantly associated with creatinine
there was no association with any other
demographic variable for example
bmi
there was also no association between
thc status and how much product people
actually took remember i mentioned that
we do bottle weights out and bottle
weights in and the actual amount was
somewhere around 35 migs of of cbd that
folks were getting every day not 30. so
you would think that people who had more
might have had a higher chance of
testing positive that wasn't the case so
it's not amount of product it's not bmi
it's not there any other demographic
variable the only relationship we saw
was with creatinine the measure of
hydration
patients consistently using full
spectrum hemp derived products then they
test positive for cannabis use on
urinary drug screens which is something
that people need to know
we definitely need studies with larger
sample sizes to more thoroughly assess
which variables like how much product
people are using bmi age sex race
other medication use for example
how those things contribute to positive
thc status in only some individuals
particularly those with higher
creatinine levels importantly and this
is something i can't stress enough this
study product if you look at the math
contained
0.02 let me say that again
0.02 percent thc by weight remember that
hemp derived products can contain up to
that's right 0.3
thc by weight that's more than 10 times
the amount of thc as in my current study
product and half of my sample was
positive after four weeks of treatment
so
um it's often assumed that individuals
who are using hemp derived products will
be negative for thc but this may not be
true
especially if assays are more sensitive
than advertised or they're
being impacted by what i would call
cross-contamination from other
cannabinoids those assays are designed
to look at the thc metabolites but the
presence of others may in fact create a
little bit of a change
these findings certainly underscore the
potential for adverse consequences
uh loss of employment for example legal
or treatment ramifications despite the
legality of hemp derived products
they're legal but that doesn't mean you
won't test positive for thc depending on
what you're using
and if i had a dollar for every person
that said but i'm only using cbd and
they hold up this model and it's not cbd
it's a it's a broad spectrum product or
a full full spectrum product i've also
seen them turn positive with broad
spectrum products
uh we have a number of other ongoing
clinical trials at the mind program
um some of which are pending we have
inds received for pain
we were just approved for anxiety in
patients with glioblastoma and in
patients with bipolar disorder which is
very exciting
we have some ieds pending for
indications like sleep and so many more
what do i mean when i say many more
a number of a number of different
indications so the mind program will
continue to support a range of studies
that will generate ecologically valid
empirically sound data examine the
unique synergistic effects of cannabis
and its constituents to determine the
efficacy of cannabinoids for specific
conditions and disease states clarify
the overall impact of cannabinoid
treatment on physical and mental health
invest in studies designed to improve
patients overall well-being and assess
potential risk and harm as well as
patterns of misuse it's not all about
just the good we also have to look at
the potential quote bad or downside
ultimately we'd like to harness the
therapeutic potential while minimizing
risk and harm of cannabinoid-based
treatment and exposure
we need to overcome barriers and conduct
empirically sound research to draw clear
conclusions i always say it's not one
thing or the other it's the good the bad
and ultimately the truth
without vision we have no ability to
move forward so very often we're forced
to think outside the box in order to
move the field forward and with that i
would thank you for your time and
attention
acknowledge my extraordinary staff
without whom i could not
i couldn't do any of this work they are
the most dedicated people ever and i
would again wish you a wonderful rest of
your conference and be safe thank you
again