[Music]
So you know researchers they could
develop their own sort of their own
trial.
That is exactly right Benjamin. We
created some let me call it standardized
master EEG research protocol that has
been approved by health Canada and have
been approved multiple times by
different independent ethnic research
boards. But the beauty of our
standardized research protocol is that
it enables our partners because we don't
only do research in our lab. we are
implementing this technology in other
labs and research hospitals is that they
can customize you know this this
protocol. They can typically what we do
is EEG's recordings before the
intervention or consumption of a product
and then after the consumption of the
product. So after the after consumption
recordings are completely customizable.
You can do many EEGs scans or recordings
right at the beginning, the first 30
minutes if your objective is to capture
the the onset time as accurately as
possible. Think about as resolution,
right? The more samples, the higher the
resolution to see how that evolves. But
also you can do it, you know, you can
just record the EEG of a study subjects
and map that product experience for up
to 30 minutes or 45 minutes or 1 hour or
3 hours or up to five hours etc. Right?
H you you can you
know customize that according to the
needs of the needs and objectives of the
company or research organization that is
conducting research in this in this
field. Yeah. And I have to imagine this
being you know AI and machine learning
the more data that folks are generating
it's just going to feed into the system
and just improve it. Correct. Exactly. I
mean it's it's just it's just like a
snowball because the more data we
collect the more AI will continue
learning and and and I think that we
will get to a point where the PL metric
will not only measure you know the high
and you know how strong is that effect
etc. It will it will also tell us what
type of high you are experiencing. Are
you experiencing the body high or the
head high or what hallucinations I don't
know etc. I think that it will get to
that level of accuracy and even better I
think that it will get to a point where
we will be able to personalize it. So
imagine that at a certain point and I
want to be one of the first ones to say
it because I really think it will happen
is that these devices will become you
know gadgets for consumers where you
will be able to wear it. It will read
your brain waves and will know who you
are what type of what type of brain you
are and based on that you will tell this
app hey you know I I want to relax
today. Okay, you are this type of brain,
you want to relax. These are the type of
products that you should consume and
this is how you should consume them. I I
think that that that will be the one of
the late latest stages of adoptions uh
of adoption of wearable EG technology
and AI for for these types of consumer
package good markets like personalized
recommendations of product used to
accomplish an experience. Yeah, I mean I
can definitely I can definitely see a
future with that.
[Music]