[Music]
Welcome to the Canad Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science, medicine, cultivation,
and safety testing. I am your host, Ben
Amaralt. I am the senior marketing
manager at medicinal genomics and proud
member of the team that puts on the
CANMED summit. Well, we are getting
closer and closer to CANMED 25, which is
taking place at the Windham Resort in
Puerto Rico June 17th through the 20th.
If you are planning to join us in Puerto
Rico this June, don't wait to register.
Our room block at the resort is filling
up fast and you don't want to miss out
on this year's event. If you're still on
the fence, I invite you to go to
cammedvents.com and check out our
speaker lineup, our schedule, and our
unique networking events designed to
connect you with the leaders who are
shaping the industry. We really do have
something for everyone at CAMED2 this
year. We have the medical practicum
where doctors and nurses can earn up to
six continuing education credits. We
have the cannabis genomics workshop
featuring more than a dozen of the
world's leading experts on plant
genomics, breeding, and pathogen
resistance. We have a lab compliance
workshop covering lab shopping,
remediation, and other hot topics. And
we also have 20 curated oral
presentations from the top researchers
in cannabis science, medicine,
cultivation, and lab testing, and so
much more. And the great part about
CANMET is that all of these people from
the different areas of the industry come
together with the goal to advance
cannabis medicine and the industry as a
whole. And we really hope that you'll
join us this
year. And since you are a podcast
listener or watcher, we do have a
special offer for you. I have a promo
code that you can use to get $300 off
your ticket
package. That promo code is coffee talk.
All one word. If you put that in the
promo code box, when you buy your full
summit package, you will get $300 off.
So don't wait. Pause this episode. Use
the link in the description to go
register. Pop in the promo code, get
your discount, and get ready to join us
at
KMED25. Our guest today is Dr. Daddy
Meri. Daddy is the associate professor
at the Techneon Institute where he heads
the laboratory of cancer biology and
canabonoid research. His lab
investigates the vast therapeutic
potential of secondary metabolites from
cannabis and other herbs, algae, and
psychedelic mushrooms and reveals how
these naturally occurring metabolites
affect various types of cancer,
inflammatory disease, and disorders of
the nervous system. Daddy is also highly
involved in governmental regulations and
is a residing member in several Israeli
Ministry of Health committees that seek
to advance the fundamental understanding
of optimal cannabis and other
psychedelic plants usage and curtailing
adverse effects. During our
conversation, we discuss the wide range
of clinical applications for cannabis
medicine, including cancer, epilepsy,
sleep disorders, Alzheimer's, and
women's health issues like
endometriosis. How cannabis's entourage
effect challenges the traditional one
drug, one target
model. The fact that many powerful
canabonoids are often overlooked by
standard lab testing methods, even
though they exist in significant
quantities. and show therapeutic
potential. Israel's medical cannabis
model, which treats cannabis like a
pharmaceutical with prescriptions,
clinical oversight, and growing
physician
acceptance. Dedi's goal to provide
evidence-based, accurate treatments that
tailor cannabis therapies to specific
health conditions and individual needs,
and more. Before we get to my
conversation with Daddy, I'd like to
thank this episode sponsor, Trusted Cana
Nurse.
Trusted Canon Nurse was founded by Megan
Bang and Arian Williams, two nurses that
are dedicated to bridging the gap
between traditional medicine and the
world of cannabis and
psychedelics. They specialize in
creating evidence-based treatment plans
for all ages that address chronic
illness, treatment resistant conditions,
mental health, autism, and more. Learn
more at
trustedcanurse.com. Okay. And without
any further ado, please enjoy my
conversation with Dr. Denny Mary.
[Music]
Good afternoon, Daddy. Thank you so much
for joining me on the podcast.
Thank you for having me. It's always a
pleasure. Yes, it's always great to talk
with you. You're one of our favorite
guests. You're one of our favorite CAM
Med presenters, and we're thrilled to
have you back for CAM
Med. Uh the title of your presentation
this year is Cannabis as a therapy
across diverse cancer types, milestones
and insights from a decade of research.
So, first of all, congratulations on
that milestone, a decade of research.
That's that's makes me not younger and
not young anymore anymore. You know, I
was young and promised. I I left with
the promise. Yep. Well, we'll never be
this young again, right? We're always
we're all getting older.
So, it's all about your lab's work
investigating whether cannabis can serve
as a primary pharmaceutical treatment
for cancer. But before we really dive
into that, um I I am interested in kind
of exploring this past decade. How has
perception of of cannabis and medical
research evolved since you got started?
So I think it's a it's an amazing
journey and I started very skeptical.
you know cannabis like everybody that
started and I think you know people said
that cannabis is not addicted try to do
a research with cannabis you will learn
that it's very addicted
and it's phenomenal the results that you
get working with cannabis it's something
that a scientist usually don't see in
the lab in many indication
so I think it it's quite a journey and I
would never dream to have such a result
so phenomenal in so many illnesses
different you know usually scientists
it's somebody that know everything about
nothing you know we're going very deep
but cannabis caused my lab to be open
and and to work in such a variety
indication epilepsy Alzheimer's sleep
disorder and multiple sclerosis
inflammation cancers different types of
cancers. So cannabis is touching so many
systems in our body and every time we
discover something new very exciting and
it's taking the lab or part of of my
students to a new area which is just
phenomenal. It's I'm feeling I'm feeling
so lucky that I choose to work with
cannabis. First of all, I think we are
helping a lot of patient. It's a very
good feeling. Second, it's create my lab
to be so you know diverse and and so
interesting for me which is you know I'm
I'm grateful for that. Can it be
difficult to focus though if you have so
many different indications that you're
investigating? Oh, this is the criticism
that I'm getting in the academia and
this is the criticism I'm sometimes on
myself. You can't be expert for
everything. So maybe I'm expert for
cannabis or the endocanabinoid system
which you know I'm working with other
plants also but
I I will never be the best scientist at
doing epilepsy or the best science at
doing multiple sclerosis or sleep
disorder but I'm usually collaborating
with expert I'm bringing the the
knowledge on the cannabis the
endocanabinoid system and whatever and
and collaborating with expert in the
field and then you
know jumping on their back and then
riding with them.
So again it's it's it's in personality
issues you know I enjoying this diverse
I
was as when I did my post and I want
work on one protein in one
phosphorulation in one area you know I
could commit suicide it's not for me I
need to look on the big picture to see
the big picture it's more interesting
for me and I cannabis was
I was lucky to touch it because of this
diversity. Yes, there is a penalty about
how deep you going in each indication.
Is there a favorite though? Is there an
indication that's uh top of the list for
you?
Sleep. We we were talking about that
earlier. I'm not sleeping much. I don't
have a sleep problem, but I think it's
sleep. It's extremely important. And
cancer. You know, I'm my laboratory is
lab for cancer research. I'm coming from
them. But
also I I I think cannabis can be a
promise or or can be a treatment to some
types of cancers and and I
think it's nice to find cannabis is
helping in sleep and whatever but when
you succeeding to eliminate tumors and
things like that it's it's a different
level of science and and and feeling
about you know what you're doing. I will
say another things in the last three
years the lab is working around women
health and and endometriosis. It started
for breast cancer but move for
endometriosis and the results there is
are
phenomenal and very interesting the
field is very interesting you know I
don't want to say that women are very
interesting for me but in general I
think the field the
hormone you know all all
these system is in the last years are
very exciting for me yeah that seems to
be an emerging topic. I know that we did
have a presentation about it. I believe
it was last year about
endometriosis and we have another one
this year. If it's not a presentation,
it's definitely a poster presentation.
Um, so yeah, those those women health
topics are definitely gaining more
traction. At least we're seeing it.
Yeah, it's very different. It's working
in a very different mechanism that the
endocan the regular endocanabonoid and
CB2 and CB-1 and that and again as a
scientist it's fascinating me and and
it's open new gates to new you know new
windows
so it's interesting but you know I can
talk now 10 hours on on the new
indication and findings that we found in
the last year or two I I think what we
calling the entourage effect okay
is something that I'm putting a focus on
him on it but not in as a classic what
we called in the conference entourage
effect but as a
concept that what we call
polypharmacology that few compounds
using few compounds as or or you know
combination of treatments in order to
attack a disease And cannabis is coming
within like the the the because the
endocanabon system is so wide and
cannabis have so many active compounds
it's bringing it within but as a concept
for medicine in general but plant
medicine in in
particular I think I'm I'm fascinating
and I'm you know trying to hold the flag
and and wave with
that to say that if we will understand
the complexity that plants bringing with
with them and and treating with this
complexity we might
solve diseases that for hundred of years
we are hitting our head to the wall like
Alzheimer ALS cancers that a single
molecule like pharma that trying to
attack with single molecule is not
working but if you coming with three
four molecules So that each one of them
affect different system, different
mechanism, whatever. You might achieve
something that is is is bigger and
cannabis is presenting that it's easy
to to show that with the cannabis, but
it's a it's a whole concept for herbal
medicine in general. You know, I have a
pitch that I'm saying in the last three
years. So if you already heard that, I'm
sorry for that.
Um people use plants as a medicine for
thousands of years. In the last 100
years, every time that we succeed to
isolate a molecule, we did kind of
modification whatever and it's become a
medicine. But every time that it was
more complicated, it was few compounds
or we didn't succeed to isolate. It
stayed as a herbal medicine and and
there is a gap
between accurate medicine that we know
exactly the molecule safety dosing and
herbal medicine doesn't matter if it's
cannabis or are there herbal medicine
you know ginsan or whatever you said
take you don't know what is the active
compound you don't know do nosing maybe
it will help maybe not we have the
ability today with analytical and and
computers to understand this complexity
it's quite easy
Okay. And I think this
complexity can solve diseases and and
problems that we didn't succeed to solve
this till today. And I use cannabis give
me the tools to understand that and to
open you know a a new with herbal
medicine. Cannabis is a a perfect
example for this complexity. So I'm
using that and and this is exciting me
bigger than the cannabis bigger than the
field as as something con new
concept in in research and in medicine.
So this is something that I'm showing
with the cannabis in the last years you
know I'm taking a disease like
inflammatory bald disease like chron and
colitis and showing that few molecules
from the cannabis blocking the colon
cells to call the immune cells and few
other molecules affecting the immune
cells and few other cell compounds
affecting the third cells and all
together you get complex action that
treating the the the the chrono colitis
better than one molecule. So I'm using
the cannabis to prove kind of a bigger
concept and I'm very excited about that.
Sorry for very long answer. No, that's
interesting though. So you're basically
saying that the whole idea of single
single molecule single indication is a
bit of a fool's errand or it's
restrictive or that you're sort of
missing out on it's it's restrictive.
It's working sometimes but right there
is a limit and and and you know when I
started work with cannabis few years ago
10 years ago actually it was already 10
years ago and I realized there is many
compounds for for many indication I came
to one of the people you know I'm I'm a
professor in the technon it's kind of
the MIT of
of you know the US it's the technology
institute and we have few genius there
you know that you know finish high
school when they've been 11 and got a
lab when they're 15 these kind of
people. So I went to one of them and
said hey look I need your help you are
computer science bioinformatics and
everything look there are 100 compounds
and many indication he looked at me and
said I will teach you Excel you know
like this is not complex
okay you know the complexity that we can
understand today with computer AI
bionformatics proteomics metabolomics
whatever to understand how three
molecules working
together. It's it's a joke in the
abilities that we have today. But the
regulation is very or the physician, not
the physician, but mainly the
regulation, take the FDA as as an
example, is very still narrow. You know,
even though we can take a blood sample
today, run it on equipment, after 40
minutes, look on 5,000 different
molecules, still we need to use just one
because that's what we used to. Okay.
And I think it's we need to educate and
and to lead that and this is this is one
of scientist you know job to lead that
to to show that to present that to
explain that but I think we will see the
future of
medicines are more complicated drugs and
and plants in general and particularly
cannabis coming within it's in them this
complexity.
So that's interesting. So you started
off talking about how you're studying a
lot of different uh indications with
cannabis and how it's a combination. So
I'm curious when you're finding success
with treating these different
indications, is there ever an example
where it is a single molecule or is it
always a combination? No, no, there is
there is there is examples that we
found. I I gave this example. We found a
a new cannabonoids like new unknown
cannabis canabonoids we call it
3315 but it's a little bit similar to
CBG but with three oxygens. the the
structure is a little bit different
which these canabonoids
reduce the estrogen expression estrogen
receptor expression in in
in ovarian or breast or tube
cells which I don't familiar with any
other drug that reduce estrogen in
ovarian or tube cells and this can be a
a treatment for endometriosis and other
diseases and this is a signal
single molecules
but in most cases it it we found things
that are more complic.
Yeah. Yeah. So circling back to cancer
since that is going to be the topic of
your talk at KMA2
um and sort of talking about clinical
applications or maybe you know future
research. Has any of your findings led
to any clinical trials or real world
applications yet?
So yes and and both both questions are
the answer is yes. It's lead to clinical
trials and it lead to real world
applications. So in three cases first of
all I want to take one step back okay
and to explain cannabis is a given name
to hundred or thousands of different
chemovs each one of them contain
different combination of molecules and
we just talked that this combination is
important for the effects okay cancer
it's a given name to thousands of
different diseases we have in our body
220ome different types of cells. Each
type of cell have different types of
cancer. Our you know lung cancer, breast
cancer, skin cancer are totally
different. It's a different diseases.
But even in one type of cancer, breast
cancer, we have 20ome different types.
So altogether you're talking about
thousands of different chemovirus of
cannabis and thousands of different
diseases. And now my goal in my lab or
my what I'm trying is to
match a specific cannabis to a specific
cancer. So it's not that cannabis can
cure cancer or cannabis can treat
cancer. There are specific types of
cannabis or molecules in the cannabis
they might help or cure specific types
of cancer. So that's first of all let's
bring it back to earth. Okay. Right. But
if at least in three cases, three types
of cancers and mutation, we already know
which cannabis, which which combination
of
molecules can kill this cancer when you
have this mutation. So in leukemia with
a specific mutation called notch one
mutation, I already know what are the
molecules in the cannabis that will
always kill the cells. So if a leukemia
patient have a mutation called notch one
and 50% of the leukemia patient it's not
all the leukemia but it's around 60%
actually okay so this type of cancer
will treat as a chem chemotherapy or
radiation without all the side effects
and everything right but the idea it
would be the same it's killing the
cancer cells so we have three types of
cancers like that and and we are in two
of them we started the process I open a
company raise money we started the
process to go to clinical trials that's
one and on the other hand we created
products cannabis product extracts or or
flowers that we aiming the specific
patient not to take a general cannabis
to take this cannabis and usually I'm
very gentle on that. I'm I'm saying if
you have leukemia and you have this type
of leukemia and you're already going to
take cannabis and you don't know what
you're taking and you don't care, why
won't you take this? Okay, that we have
science on that and research and we know
it's no I'm not coming to the patient
this will cure you. I said if you're
taking it arbitrarily and you don't know
what you're taking and it's just you
know trial and error start with this.
Mhm. This I can think can help you and
then we are following on the p following
on the patient they're taking looking
the improvement and and and so and
so we are doing that. Yes. Excellent.
And it's again phenomenal. It's it's
amazing feeling you know a scientist
usually like me even when you finding
something and you have amazing findings
in the lab until a patient will touch it
it's 10 15 years something like that you
know when I did my posto in Toronto
father of one of the PhD student that
was that works with me and she's still a
good
He was a very important scientist in in
Vancouver
[Music]
and he was the ones that invent the the
Fiser COVID
19 vaccination. Okay. So he won you know
all the prizes in the world after that
he become a billionaire but this is a
different story. um he he came to give a
talk in my university a few months ago
and he he stand and he
said it's it's amazing how we succeed to
create a medicine in in eight months to
this virus but now in my talk I want to
show you that it took 40
years that it took me 40 years okay so
I'm coming back to what I meant to
say usually to a scientist in the up to
have a results and to affect a
patient if he's lucky and if he's you
know amazing and then got a Nobel Prize
it's 15 20 years in my field in my work
sometimes we finding something and two
weeks after it can already be in in I
can already recommend the patient or
help a patient with that because the
product is on the shelf I just need to
point him to what we found and think and
and this is very unique situation very
unique feeling I'm very
very careful or you know I don't know
how to say that very I'm not saying
things that I'm not
100% sure about them when I not 100%
sure that it will help and not make do a
damage but when you know something and
you help. It's really good feeling. So
that's interesting. So it's a unique
situation that patients kind of have
access to this medicine um early on
where that's not typically the case with
other other compounds. They have they
have an access to the medicine before
you pure you prove it's really a
medicine. So yeah, they have the access
before they have the knowledge. Right.
Exactly.
Interesting. So you talked about
canabonoids and you talked about rare
canabonoids. um one that you mentioned
that was just numbers instead of instead
of letters the alphabet soup that we
typically deal with. Um now is that a a
common finding that these rare
canabonoids in the low concentrations
are find are offering more promise
perhaps than the ones we know and love
like THC, CBD, CBG.
So I will say the 50% in the cases.
Sometimes it's CBG, CBC, CBDV the more
known ones. Yeah,
but in half of the cases is the rare
cannabonoids. But I want to say
something, okay, which is
important. If you didn't see it and
never heard about, it doesn't mean that
it's rare, okay? Doesn't mean that it's
low concentration.
So the the molecule that we saw that
killing the leukemia it's unknown
canabonoids it's a new one whatever but
it's the third more expressed in this
strain so it was 2.3%
oh really it's not really minor it's not
really rare it's not low
percentage if the the the regular
equipment of or the HLC and we don't
have standard so we don't see it usually
doesn't mean that it's rare or or very
in low concentration. Okay. So, usually
these are not you know a a a very
extremely low concentration. It's not
0.001%. It will be
0.5% 1%
1.5% but it's an
unknown molecule. So,
so it's a so sort of a limitation.
Sorry for cutting you. If you look on
other plants, okay, even you know today
people talk about a lot of mushroom
functional mushrooms so mushroom if you
look on the concentration of the
molecule there which consider active it
will be 0.2% 0.5% 0.1%. Mhm. In cannabis
when you saying 0.3% you you think it's
it's rare or minor but if you
translate if if if a patient using one
gram just for it will be easy to
calculate you know the average amount of
a patient in Israel it's
32.5 gram a month so it's an average of
one gram okay so
if if if a molecule is expressing
0.5% in
this flower. It will be 50 milligram a
day. 50 milligram it's dragable. 50
milligram it's it's it's not low amount
for a drug or a molecule to affect your
body. So it's not really a rare or
minor. We are wrong to call them like
that.
Interesting. So you're saying with the
testing labs or the equipment or sort of
the methods that they're using, there
could be these unknown canabonoids that
are are there in concentrations, but
they're just not seeing it with the
equipment or not reporting it on the on
the COA. I'm not saying maybe we know
that like it's after 10 years I can tell
you exactly. Yes, sure. A lot of the
cannabonoids which express in quite high
amount you don't see or you don't
read. Usually the laboratories have the
ability to do that but because it's not
interesting to anybody and it cost more
money it will cost instead of you know
$50 or 50 $40 for for the test it will
cost
$300. Usually the grow not asked for
these readings and and usually the
laboratories not developed method to
look on them right every good laboratory
in the US that have masspec or GCMS can
take my paper read it and in one day be
able to see that okay it's not something
that it's
difficult there is no economic demand
for Yeah. Right. And and that's that's
the reason it's a mistake in my opinion.
You know, that's how I work. But well,
that's why for sure I want to know.
Okay. Well, that's why we bring all
these different people together for
Canmed, right? That's why we bring the
researchers, the doctors, the testing
labs, the cultivators all together. So,
um, so that they Yeah. And this is why I
love Canad so much. You know it's very
scientific from one hand but very the
variety of people the the the pe
the the you covered so many areas you
know from cultivation analytics the
medical even recreational all of that
coming together from very good
scientists researchers physicians you
know activism And it's it's an amazing
venue to to learn and to show the the
new data.
Excellent. Um so winding down here,
Daddy, we we open by talking about your
last 10 years in in cannabis research
and where we've come. Where do you see
cannabis based cancer therapies in the
next 10 years?
So again, I will divide it to countries
that have medical cannabis mainly to
countries that it's legalization and
something like that because it's a
different point of view. Okay. In
Israel, cannabis it's a medicine. It's a
medicine being prescribed by a
physician under healthcare and you get
it in pharmacy like every other drug.
It's actually one of the most prescribed
medicines in Israel, but it's a totally
medicine and we succeeding. I'm saying
we because, you know, I'm the adviser
for the Ministry of Health for
psychedelic plans and and by that
cannabis and I'm parting the of the
regulation and I'm, you know, I'm I'm
feeling part of the the movement in
Israel that doing that. We
succeed to bring it to the mainstream of
treatment. A physician eight years ago,
nine years ago when I started said on my
on my dead body that somebody will
prescribe cannabis in my department and
today there is no physician that not
prescribing cannabis. It's become
common. Okay, first of all, second we
succeed to bring the cannabis or to try
to take it to the next level. Okay, to
bring cannabis which is evidence-based
already. Okay. So we doing branding now
with the biggest pharma company in
Israel and with the healthcare in
Israel. A branding said evidence-based
and the meaning we said every cannabis
strain then being tested. We know the
molecule. We know that it's good for
that indication. We we we did a clinical
trials on on patient not FDA approved
clinical trials but test it on real
patient. It's evidence-based and now a
physician can prescribe it like a
medicine. He can prescribe when he knows
what are the active molecules, what is
the mechanism of action. So if you know
the mechanism, what is the drug drug
interaction with other drugs, how it's
work and then dozing the side effect, he
can he can treat it as a medicine. You
need to understand a physician that come
to prescribe a physician study in Israel
seven years and then you have another
five years of kind of you know before he
become tenure and whatever like 12 15
years he's studying and now you ask him
to prescribe something that he had no
clue about it. Mhm. He said what the
[__] why I study 15 years you know if if
I know nothing but if you give him the
tools he said okay this product this is
the mechanism of action these are the
molecules this is how it's act this is
the dozing this is the side effect you
need to be careful then that then you
become a physician
and giving these tools bring cannabis
and the treatment to the next level that
I believe that is extremely important
okay and and I see how It's open gates.
How it's open the mind of the physician,
the
regulation, the health care. You bring
it to something more accurate, more
professional and and most
important, you help the patient to get
better treatment. you know, we we we
started treating cannabis in a trial and
error, you know, with sentences or a
phrasing like start slow, you know,
start low, go slow, you know, and think
about that you have a migraine and
you're taking a pill and you
have 20 pills and the physician said
every time that you have a migraine,
start low, go slow. No, you know the
dozing, you the migraine is off. Okay,
this is accurate treatment then you know
a patient know on his body the best or
sentence like that the meaning that we
don't know how to
recommend that's the meaning of you know
trial and error and bringing to more
accurate will
reduce you know this trial and error
increase the success
rate and and having a better treatment
to patient I hope so. This is I think
the next generation, the next three,
five years in in medical cannabis. Make
it a specific treatment, accurate
treatment, not anymore. No try 10
strains and then decide which one is
helping you to sleep and then to take go
to this strain. This is go to sleep
because it's good to sleep because of
this molecule, these combinations, this
complexity, but we will
know to direct the patient better.
Yeah. So I mean I would imagine in order
for that to work there needs to be
accuracy in the testing and consistency
in the product. Correct.
The the product is very consistent in
the last I would say five six years. You
know when we started to work 10 years
ago cannabis grow outside and then there
was a different between summer and
winter and you can said white widow but
then you test them genetic and 10 of
them were different strains. Okay. I
don't see that anymore. Not at least in
Israel and in the areas that I'm
working. It's very consistent. It's
growing mostly indoors in very
controlled way.
you the level of growth and the the
product
is you can't compare to what was you
know few years ago and I think it's
consistent and accurate and and now it's
easier to do the work and and and again
if we we want to treat it as a medicine
you want it to be consistent you want it
to be
accurate
excellent all right Daddy I do want to
be mindful of your time but Before I let
you go, I want to give you a chance to
share with the listeners or the viewers
um any way that they can read up more on
you and the work that you're doing or
possibly connect with you. Uh please
plug any links. I'd be happy to put them
in the show description uh so people can
read more.
So I'm a scientist. I'm publishing my
papers and then there is you know all
the papers is out on PubMed but there is
Google Scholar then LinkedIn and all of
these you know ways to reach me and to
read about my science and there are
previous talk in canmed and
other you know
other conferences and things like that
which I don't like people to show that
because I'm repeating my jokes. So now
it's a problem. Need to work out some
new material. Yeah, exactly. Yeah. And
absolutely people should check out those
links and join us in Puerto Rico for
KMAD25 and meet Daddy in person. Thank
you very much for having me here and in
Puerto Rico. It's always a pleasure.
Always I'm always learning a lot and
meeting a lot of friends. I hope to see
you and all the people there. Yep. We'll
see you soon. It's right around the
corner. Thank you very much. Bye-bye.
[Music]