[Music]
welcome to the caned Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the the team that puts on the camed
Summit all right the camed 25 abstract
submission portal is now open and will
be until November 15th so if you have
done any novel research in the areas of
cannabis science medicine cultivation or
safety testing we want to hear from you
if your abstract is accepted by our
Advisory Board you will receive a 50%
discount on the camed 25 full Summit
package which includes three nights at
the Windam Grand rainforest Beach and
Resort with all the associated
amenities full access to the caned
medical practicum industry workshops
oral and poster presentations and
networking events and all-inclusive
meals which include a welcome reception
lunches and themed Beach dinners not
only will you get to present your work
on the stage at camed 25 but a video
recording of your presentation will be
added added to the canmed archive and
the medicinal genomics YouTube page for
additional exposure after the event and
let me tell you more than one of our
caned videos have reached up to six
figures in
views use the link in the show
description to submit your abstract
today or go to camed event.com and click
the button Our Guest today is Elizabeth
Thompson with a bachelor's in molecular
biology and a master's in physiology Liz
has has studied the human body through
many lenses the focus of her PhD program
in Pharmacy is to explore disorders that
have directly impacted her life in the
world of professional contact Sports and
how cannabinoid products could
potentially play a role in them as a
member of the clinical trial team that
was recently awarded funding from the
NFL to study canabo and concussion and
pain she is excited to bring new data to
the literature exploring cannabinoids
andth a letics Liz and her team recently
published an extensive literature review
titled cannabinoid therapy in athletics
a review of current cannabis research to
evaluate potential realworld cannaboid
applications in sport which establishes
a foundation for their future research
during our conversation we discussed how
Liz became interested in the therapeutic
potential of
cannabinoids the published literature
that supports using cannabinoids for
neuroinflammation and neurod
degenerative
disorders her team's collaboration with
the NFL in ongoing clinical trials
focused on neuroinflammation and
Recovery in athletes particularly after
concussions the current use of cannabis
in athletics and how Sports
organizations are changing their
policies future directions of research
and
more before we get to my conversation
with Liz I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor the dent
Institute with more than 300,000 patient
visits per year the dent neurologic
Institute ranks among the largest
Neuroscience centers in North America
its 24 subsp special D clinics often
treat the most challenging neurologic
conditions including but not limited to
migraine chronic pain ALS Ms Parkinson's
dementia neurooncology and more with
their mission of advancing Neuroscience
they established a cannabis clinic in
2016 to Aid in the treatment of these
chronic conditions seen throughout their
Institute for more information visit
Dent institute.com
okay without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Liz Thompson
[Music]
good afternoon Liz thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast for sure well
thank you so much for having me I'm a
big fan of your podcast so I'm honored
to be here oh well that's that's great
thanks uh well I'm excited to talk with
you today about the work that you and
your team are doing to better understand
the therapeutic potential of
cannabinoids in athletics so I think a
good place to start is why don't you
tell us how you got involved in
researching cannaboids and Athletics
yeah for sure um so it was not a linear
path as I don't think anybody's ever
really is but my undergraduate degree is
in molecular biology and then I have a
master's degree and applied physiology
and I was always athletic and so with my
uh physiology degree we were always
looking at you know training principles
or just basically principles of
physiology of how can you really push
the human body to do things that you
want it to do essentially using
non-pharmacological agents so looking at
you know training principles or
nutrition or even supplementation
whatever so um I worked with athletes
and I also worked clinically so I had a
patient population um but the the
biggest driving Factor behind it was my
husband's actually was an athlete a
professional athlete and we've been
together since we were 17 years old and
I would watch him play and I was like
man this is not going to end well if you
keep on you know the head contact and
the contact and the contact and so just
knowing having a background really of
molecular mechanisms and understanding
what was happening all the time I
started to really look for ways to
reduce the neural inflammation just
thinking like I don't want to be feeding
you with a straw when we're 80 years old
so let's see what we can do there's got
to be things and there are a lot of
things you can do which is the
empowering part about understanding
physiology is there's a ton that you can
do to really help support your system to
reduce those things and so um I I
started looking specifically so when he
was playing really was in the 2000s so
I'll date myself here but it was really
the height of the opioid epidemics in
athletics like there was a lot of
exposure of opioids and you know we we
had teammates that ended up with opioid
problems we buried some teammates and I
was like you know there has to be
something better than this and so in
order to understand that I wanted to
understand the mechanisms of how opioids
worked and so I started to look at the
molecular mechanisms in the brain of how
opioids were actually working and
physiologically like why are people how
does it kill you what is happening here
and so I came across research that
suggested that using canono you could
actually reduce the required amount of
opioids to have the same pain efficacy
and I was thinking like that's crazy how
would that even work and I didn't really
know anything about cannabis at all you
know I mean I was a downhill ski racer
and I I played rugby I was always like
you know an endorphin junkie and so we
understood cannabis from like a
recreational cultural standpoint I grew
up in Canada it's always around but I
didn't really understand anything about
the molecular mechanisms which was
shocking because I'd already finished
two degrees that were focusing on
molecular mechanisms and I had never
seen anything about the endocannabinoid
system so anyways I started looking at
that and um I kind of went down a rabbit
hole and I have been there for probably
the last 10 or 15 years just looking at
the different ways that the endoc canabo
system can work um really a
neuroinflammation but it really goes
everywhere throughout your whole body
and so it was looking at things like
that and and um so then I applied to you
know I thought okay well I I think this
I saw the mechanism that I really wanted
to look at and it was the calcium
channel so just getting like super nerdy
here but it was the the calcium channels
in the neurons and I thought well like
who's looking at this and so I looked
for any supervisor anywhere that was
actually studying that and of course
after having a couple people tell you
you're totally crazy because it's like
hey have you ever looked at using
cannabis to reduce neuroinflammation and
most people are like yeah okay next I
don't know what you're talking about but
my supervisor now um he he was one of
the first people he's like the only
paper that I actually found at that time
that was published specifically talking
about um some of the cyto kindes and
chemokines that that happen you know
when you have neuroinflammation and the
potential for maybe some things that
cannaboids could do to reduce those and
so I contacted him
um and he knew exactly what I was
talking about and so I was like so
thrilled and so I thought I was going to
have to beg him to take me on as a
graduate student but he said oh oh yeah
like I would love to have you and so um
I applied and so I I wanted to look at
concussion specifically it was
concussion and neuroinflammation in the
brain and um you know he was happy to do
that and right after that we saw the
call from the NFL I was actually outside
watering my first cannabis plant that I
ever grew and it was in 2021 W and it
came across my phone and I was like
Patrick check it out like the NFL is
actually putting up money to study the
thing that I just said like I I this why
we want to look at and so I didn't
really think we would apply I thought
that he'd be like he cool like we're not
crazy you know we're this is not some
you know people think that yes someone
else thinks this and so he would but
instead he was like okay yeah we're
gonna apply and so he went and he
gathered and he's wonderful so he
gathered people that he had worked with
over the course of his career look at
like we're looking at so many different
metrics but um we had to put in for it
was an NIH adjudication to go through
you know all the different researchers
that applied for the funding and um and
we were selected as the group that the
NFL would fund to look at all the
different metrics um for using
cannabinoids for neuroinflammation
concussion pain and then opioid sparing
so he's my one supervisor that took me
on and then I'm actually double
supervised um my other supervisor is the
de a pharmacy so my PhD is in pharmacy
at the University of Saskatchewan so
those two are my supervisors and we have
a team an amazing team of people that
are looking at so many different metrics
of um yeah how we can use canabo to
potentially reduce so some of the things
you know so for me it's very personal I
have people in my life like we are
surrounded by athletes I grew up in
sports and you know you can only change
so many rules and redesign a helmet and
a mouth guard so many ways but unless
you're actually
focusing on the molecular things inside
the skull you're missing a massive
opportunity to do something um that I
believe you know we need the data and
that's why we're getting it um to prove
that what what we believe to be true is
actually happening in humans and we have
a ton of preclinical there's a ton of
animal models that show it but because
of the laws and the prohibitor you know
the prohibition and the inability for
researchers to put this substance in a
human and actually draw data which in
Canada now is even doubly ridiculous
because people can walk down the street
and buy it anywhere they want and it's
still actually very hard to do research
in Canada even though at the federal
level it's legal we're we've been legal
there since 2018 and so it's accessible
to anybody in our country that's over
the legal age but to do research was
actually still very difficult that's why
it's taken us so long you know that was
in 2021 and we just finished um the
first portion of the clinical trial so
it's yeah I mean I feel like there'd be
a lot more human data if the policies
would have allowed researchers to do the
research that they've been trying to do
for a really long time yeah no I guess I
didn't realize that that that Canada had
those restrictions on Research I mean
here in the states we're familiar with
it because cannabis it's a schedule one
drug and you know that has a lot of
limitations and now there's talk about
rescheduling uh we' prefer descheduling
but I think we'll take rescheduling just
because it will open up some of that
research but I didn't realize that
Canada uh had the same issues well you'd
think that it would be easier than it
really was and that was you know our
ability to do the clinical trial at all
were definitely at an advantage in
Canada like the fact that we were able
to you know we have the Cannabis
research licenses in our Labs like we're
actually able to do it but it's you know
the requirements and it's it's really
probably no different than any other
like natural product research you know
it's just your ability to source things
that you want to Source because you
still have to have the stability tests
the investigation brochures and so like
you have to find people that actually
have that quality and that grade of the
cannaboids that you want to use because
in order to do a clinical trial you have
to be sure that any of the effects that
you're seeing aren't coming from some
other reagent or something else that's
in the product right so it's the same as
other things it's just that the
accessibility to the product that you
need in order to do it and then that was
very restrictive too because in order to
go through to get a no objection letter
you have to have that on every single
molecule that you want to study and so
in cannabis because it has 500 bioactive
molecules you would need 500 different
brochures and investigativ and talks on
everything and so it really kind of
handcuffs you to what you can actually
do and progress with because to get so
we had to start with a CBD isolate
because in order to do anything more
than that which you know most of us of
course would want to do something more
full spectrum or you know there's
reasons you know of course it makes
sense to do a clinical trial with just
the one so you can see what is changing
in association with just that one
molecule but if you were looking for
better outcomes you could design it
better I think but yeah I know that's
that that's tricky like you said so many
different compounds in the cannabis
plant um probably even many that we
haven't even uh identified yet yeah so
that makes things tricky right and and
that's the thing is you can't do a
clinical trial if you can't identify
exactly the mechanisms of what it is
you're studying and so if you're study
you know but I think that that's where
there's a real place for real world
research and like you know because
really at the end of the day what is the
point of this research if it's not at
least in parallel or mirroring what
people are accessing in real life right
I mean there are some CBD products of
course that are isolates you know but if
you were going to preferentially pick a
product it like wouldn't be an isolate
you know if you know how canabo
pharmacology works you would try to
design something better but it's just
for the sake of a clinical trial so of
course you know some people are like
well why are you using an isolet well of
course it's not by choice it's because
we had to you know and then you progress
from there so um in the next couple of
steps we'll be able to hopefully add in
some more canabo but first to have there
is no data right now at all even on the
CBD isolate like that doesn't even exist
in a healthy population yet so what
we're doing by putting it into a healthy
population is still the first time it's
ever been done we have you know the
metrics on epidex which is a CBD you
know but that's not a healthy athletic
population that's in a population of
epileptic children and so I think one
thing in cannabis research where people
really need to be careful is to identify
the population that whatever you're
looking at was actually studied in
because you can't take metrics from an
epileptic child population and think
that that equates to a healthy athletic
male population those two aren't the
same right as in same as an epileptic
brain it it's not the same as a
non-epileptic brain and that's not the
same you know so I mean we have to be
really careful at what are we looking at
when we're looking at these studies and
the studies that do exist and so in
athletics I think that makes it really
complicated because there is you know
there are we do have research that
exists in certain things humans not so
much there's lots of pre-clinical data
lots of animal data but we have to be
really careful in the interpretation of
and that was one of the points in the
recent publication that I put out in
sports medicine was we have to be
careful with our interpretation of
research that does exist and not to take
that research and apply it to
populations that it wasn't actually done
on yeah for sure now I so I wanted to
kind of just circle back to the NFL
because I know that that's U um that's
an important part of your research and
you know kind of getting that approval
from them and you know it was funny cuz
I was looking back and so our first
event our cam first cam at event in 2016
was at Harvard Medical School and Kyle
Turley former NFL player actually
attended and spoke there and a
documentary film crew followed him uh
for vice and so I was going back and I
was um and I was watching some of that
and there are clips of the NFL
commissioner talking about you know
cannabis in the NFL and their policy
around that and his stance then was
there's not enough evidence to um
support changing anything at that point
so that's 2016 eight years later here we
are um I guess it's better late than
never but um speak to kind of how
attitudes from the major sports
organizations have changed when it comes
to cannabis and do you have any thoughts
of kind of what was the Tipping Point
yeah I do have I got a lot of thoughts
on a lot of things but um yeah so that
you know by them saying that there we
don't have enough evidence to change our
policies that is true and they stuck
with that the NFL did and it was
actually the players that were
pressuring them saying okay fine like
you keep saying you don't have the data
get the data then like figure out how to
get the data because you can't just keep
saying you don't have the data you know
that's kind of sometimes people will say
that as it's like an excuse to just keep
bad policies in place it's the same as
people saying there's no research
there's tons of research we have tons of
research that is already in the
published literature you just look like
that it's the it's excuses or these
talking points right to just kind of
leave things status quo because it is a
very disruptive space because it's very
misunderstood because we have that
commercial industry too right a
recreational industry um but the NFL it
was the players that kind of pressured
them and again why are we so many years
later and we don't have the data and
that is true and I think one of the most
complicated things with cannabis and
getting that data is the funding because
really clinical trials are expensive and
so the people that are going to fund
clinical trials would be the people that
ultimately somehow would have some
benefit from seeing the results right
one way or the other now the NFL truly
does want the data what they do with it
is up to them we're just you know we are
just here to get the data um and it'll
be really interesting to see what they
do with the data because you know you
still have other people that are well we
need more data we need more data so so
it's hard to say but I think that
ultimately right now because of the
shift in the laws of our countries the
society is Shifting and so the policies
that they have in Pro Sports and even I
mean the NCAA just removed cannabis from
their prohibited list because those
policies no longer align with Society
like Society is changing their laws and
so in order to have fluidity amongst the
game and the place of the game in
society dysfunction it it was starting
to become too much and so I think that
was one of the reasons why they were you
know they got interested in okay well
let's see maybe we can put up some
funding and find people to get the data
then because you
know it's the amount of money you know
and yeah and there's a lot of drug
design for sure being done with
cannaboid molecules because the
scaffolding of how they work will it
will I mean we have data already to show
in animal models that there there is a
ton of effect there in neuroinflammation
neurod degeneration you know we know
that they are active there those
molecules are active there we know that
we now drug design has some complicated
things like you know bioavailability you
have to have reproducible dose you have
to have reprod you know and then the
canono system itself is very complicated
and so that's a whole different thing
but when you look at funding the
clinical trial it's who would put money
into that because with a product that's
available to everybody right now with no
prescription needed and it will continue
to be like that industry is not going
away so whose benefit is it to put the
money up to do the research and even in
the commercial industry they don't
actually need any data whatsoever to
shelf a product they don't need to show
pharmacokinetic data they don't need to
show bioavailability they don't need to
show anything they can package a product
and sell it as long as they're following
the Food and Drug compliance but it's
not an FDA approved thing so like
there's no incentive for them to fund it
because they actually don't need it they
can make an edible product and just put
it on the shelf and so It's tricky to
find anybody that it would even would be
interested in doing it so I think the
NFL like I applaud them really for doing
it because it shows that their minds are
at least Progressive and they're not you
know for a long time the conversation
about cannabis as a medicine just had
the brakes on like nobody wanted to talk
about it or try to understand it you
know and it's no different than any
pharmacological agent it it is bioactive
and it should be treated that way it's
just that in society we've chosen to
make it available to everybody and
that's a different conversation but it
is a plant and perhaps should never have
been prohibited in the first place right
right so why we are in this place right
now is a different conversation but it's
like how do we get out of it and so I
applaud the NFL for wanting to actually
see the data and putting up you know the
call for research because it is not an
easy space to get funding for sure yeah
yeah so how do we get out of it so it
seems like at least the first step is
the uh the publication that you
mentioned earlier um and the title is
cannaboid therapy and Athletics a review
of current Canabis Research to evaluate
potential real world cannaboid
applications in sport so um i' I've
looked through the paper and there's
there's a lot in there about a lot of
different uses for canabo and Athletics
so
I guess in your opinion or in your
research what are some of the most
common or most promising applications of
of cannaboids in athletics well for me
personally like where I think they can
make the best difference or the biggest
difference for me for sure is in
neuroinflammation like I think right now
and and I might be biased because that's
what drew me to be interested in it in
the first place but I think right now I
mean there's there's a difference I
guess for where I think it should go and
where it is being used as athletes those
are things like athletes currently right
now in my experience another part I'm um
Gathering data to research athletes
themselves like by talking to them and
interviewing them and also their medical
training staff and so I have some
Publications coming out on that but
athletes themselves have are using it
for primarily uh pain inflammation sleep
and somewhat anxiety you know mental
health things now where do I think for
sure those places will be beneficial but
the one place where I think it could be
very applicable is in neuroinflammation
in the brain and concussion and there's
a few reasons for that molecularly it it
makes a ton of sense why we could
actually use these molecules to invoke
the same Downstream effects as we would
have by our naturally secreted endoc
canabo but secondly we don't currently
have any pharmacological agent that does
anything for concussion or TBI it is a
space where we're just sitting there
like there isn't any that anybody can do
to help somebody right now other than
you know Physical Therapy occupational
therapy those types of things like
vestibular training you know balance and
those things but as far as a
pharmacological agent goes there isn't
one and so for me it's like why wouldn't
you want to investigate this when it
could and we know statistically like con
you know contact sport athletes they die
from neurodegenerative disorders at a
three times greater rate than the
population that doesn't play contact
Sports so we know that there's something
happening there with neuro degeneration
and contact for the mechanisms of that
you know of course biology is a network
it's never linear so there's a lot of
things going on there but we know from
the statistics when you look at the
neurod degeneration that absolutely they
have a higher rate of it so for me the
focus to focus on something like that
which is your brain it just makes a lot
of sense because if you could and so the
metrics that we're looking at in our
clinical trial we are looking at you
know cerebral vascular changes in your
brain like how does the blood flow
actually change in your brain using
cannaboids we're looking at the
oxygenation concentration so how does
the oxygen concentration changed in your
brain when you're using canabo because
it comes down to really the question of
you if you can reduce that neural
inflammation you can reduce the
secondary effects of that Cascade and
domino effect that ultimately leads to
neurodegenerative disorders um which is
starting at you know the secondary
effects of what happen Happ s when you
smash your head together or you know
what whatever and then I do think also
there's some things with the peripheral
you know peripheral inflammation also I
believe plays a role in it because you
have so many circulating
pro-inflammatory signaling molecules
that everything and really that's what
inflammation is Right inflammation is
everybody thinks of it as a thing it's
not a thing it's a process inflammation
is a process of signaling molecules that
are calling in your immune system to
Signal them to either you know come in
we have a problem we got to fix this now
we got to clean it up now we have to
reduce now we have to shut off and now
we're back to homeostasis that's when
inflammation is working correctly and
and it should work correctly your body
is designed to do that inflammation only
really is a problem when it doesn't shut
itself off or when it's you know it's
chronic and that's what happens I think
in the brain if you can't shut off that
inflammation in your brain and it
continues to be inflamed then you end up
with neurodegenerative disorders a long
time down the road so if we had the
opportunity to use these molecules as
pharmacological agents to get in there
and reduce that neuroinflammation at
that time I think it would be such an
advantage to athletes particularly but
also military and then also it just
ripples out into like the Aging
population and then all of these
neurodegenerative disorders because it's
all stemming from the same thing right
like there's a setup in your brain and
all these cascading things they're just
different flavors of the same
kind of right like it's all on the same
mechanisms it's just different portions
are being broken for lack of a better
word yeah all right so yeah let's dig
into that a little bit so how I mean how
ideally would canono be used for
neuroprotection is it sort of like a
preventive thing that would be taken for
anyone who's kind of participating in
these types of sports or is it sort of
okay I've had a head injury now I need
to take canono to like you said cool
that inflam
how does that work yeah so that is the
million dooll question and um there
there has been research done to look at
that and really the the short answer is
both I mean you can so when you look at
neuroinflammation in the brain you have
to first look at your endocannabinoid
system which is why and how cannabinoids
work in your body at all so your endoc
canabo system is um when you get conked
in the head you secrete endoc canabo
yourself like plant aside this isn't
even talking about cannabis but like you
secrete endoc canabo and so when there
is an injury a neural injury your body
will secrete those endoc canabo to go
and hit receptors to essentially break
the circuit of inflammation and calm it
down and so in concussion if you at the
time of an acute injury one approach
would be okay well you could take
canavan oids right there and there are
some places like I think the Israeli
military I read uses it on impact if
they get injured they actually have a
nasal spray of a THC CBD that they they
nasally inhale because at that time you
can hit the CB1 receptor which
essentially shuts those calcium channels
and it'll reduce the amount of exy Talk
Like excitatory neurotransmitter which
is glutamate if you hit that CB1
receptor you can actually reduce that
outof control secretion that we know
happens in concussion so if you take THC
which is stereochemically basically
identical to anandamide which is what
you secrete yourself if you can't
provide enough anandamide yourself like
you can't keep up with the amount of
excitatory neurotoxin that's being fired
by your neuron if you can't put out the
fire yourself you can bring in an
exogenous molecule such as THC to hit
that same receptor and it would actually
cause the same Downstream results for
all intents and purposes and it itself
will reduce that firing of the
excitatory neurot transmitter so that
would be on impact but CBD does
something completely different and it's
like it's very promiscuous and you have
to remember that every molecule in
cannabis functions differently than the
next like they don't all hit the same
receptors which is why it's so
fascinating to study but also we could
be here for another 300 years like
studying it to figure out what's doing
what
but there's certain approaches of
thinking of taking CBD you know
prophylactically to maintain because CBD
does some things basically for your own
endocan avonoid system where it helps
you
maintain um healthy and Hearty endoc
canabo system where you would it would
help support your ability to secrete and
use your own anandamide and 2 a so
there's a lot of receptors I won't go
into all of them but one of the big ones
really CBD does is it inhibits the F
enzyme which is the enzyme that breaks
down your own anandamide which is the
thing that hits that CB1 recept
so there are some thoughts that taking
CBD um prophylactically you know on a
consistent basis will allow your own
endoc
canabidol canabo at the time that the
injury is going to happen and in sports
you can pretty much Bank on the fact
that you're going to get slammed like in
contact Sports you know the hit's coming
it's not an if it's when like and it's
you know small hits big hits whatever to
your body to your brain you know that
those pro-inflammatory cyto kindes are
going to start firing and the reactive
oxygen species you know that that's
coming and so the approach should be to
do everything that you can to give your
body the ability to reduce it when it
does happen and so using cannaboids um
and also you have to remember in sports
too THC is cognitively impairing and so
you have to be careful with how things
affect your decision-making or your
reaction time or things like that right
whereas CBD is not cognitively impairing
and so you can take it and it wouldn't
affect you're outputed as an athlete so
um there's two schools of thought there
but personally for me I think and and
again that's why a lot of the research
that does exist you have to be very
careful because the devil's in the
details like there are some studies that
were looking at CBD and how effective
CBD was at reducing inflammation but
they only looked at it for you know for
three hours post inflammation so I think
they were doing they were doing a
workout protocol I think and so they
looked at it and you know it didn't do
much well in my opinion I think the
prophylactic approach is going to be
better because I think if you're taking
it leading up to whatever you're doing
and that has been shown in the research
that yes having it on board before does
seem to help when the impact does happen
or the inflammation does happen but CBD
seems to work better when there is
inflammation in play already so if your
cells aren't already in the process of
inflammation CBD is you know it doesn't
really have a lot of activity but for
inflammation I mean but when things are
inflaming you upregulate a lot of your
endocannabinoid receptors which means
the concentration of available receptors
to hit has increased so now CBD has
something to work on right so it's again
you have to look really at what was the
population and what was going on at at
what we were studying or what was that
research done on and then H so and then
you can't really apply what was found in
that to a different situ a so for me I
think for athletes taking it I think
take it before and then if you did have
a a head contact then there would be a
place for sure to take it immediately
after that's only in my opinion that
hasn't been proven out anywhere because
we can't you know we haven't done it in
humans yet but we do have anomal models
we have mice models you know looking at
what happens in their brain when we honk
them in the head and and they they have
a massive secretion of 2 Ag and
anandamide which are your natural
endocannabinoids and they also have a
big op regulation in the CB2 receptors
um which are the receptors that are on
the microa which are the immune cells in
your brain and so in that experiment
with the mice if you gave them an
exogenous source of 2ag the inflammation
reduced quickly and you could save the
neurons and you could save the tissue
and it recovered and so in theory you
know mice aren't humans but in theory
that would be what you would be looking
at now again to make it pH phag grade
you'd have to have you know a pharmag
grade product to do that but in my
opinion we we have a product that does
it right now you know we know the
cannabis plant can do it in some degree
so it it's just like we don't have
anything so why if you know you have
something that might have a benefit why
wouldn't you try it rather than sit
there and do nothing and let the
inflammation just Cascade out of control
because if you do it correctly we know
that CBD has a really High safety um
safety profile it's very safe CBD is as
long as it's made in the right way
because these days these days you have
to be careful where you're sourcing it
but you know if if you get good quality
CBD we know that it's safe
so I just think you know why wouldn't
you try it right no and I mean that's
it's a common refrain when we talk about
sort of cannabis as a medicine is
there's a lot of upside and not a whole
lot of downside um why not try um yeah
and so and so you mentioned that you
know perhaps the Israeli military is
sort of using a nasal spray um for um
for treating head injury to your
knowledge are any sports teams or
Athletics are do they use CBD do they
kind of have it as a protocol are they
experimenting with it no well well again
loaded questions so Protocol no and so
really when it comes down down
to experimenting with it yeah athletes
yes because I think that athletes
themselves do anecdotally or from each
other they have heard and they have
learned but that's a separate thing from
then looking at league and League
policies and so a lot of leagues even in
Canada like I mean in 2018 cannabis
became federally legal so now okay if
you're an adult you can use it the same
way you use beer like this is not an
illegal substance and so in use for
which is the equivalent of the NCAA in
2020 it was actually stated that like we
will no longer test athletes for
cannabis anymore it's just it's not a
thing right but then the progress isn't
made to then all right now are you going
to develop Protocols are you going to
teach your medical training staff how to
use this or how to inform the athletes
how to use it properly and that's the
portion of my PhD that I'm working on
right now is really informing the
medical staff because so what I was
gathering was data to see like how much
do they even know about cannabis or or
what do they think about cannabis right
and so you know in Canada we had an
opportunity because we made it legal
five over five years ago to really
create teaching opportunities for
medical professionals and this isn't
even just for athletics it's for all
medical professionals there is still a
massive lack of Education in our doctors
and when we asked our doctors when we
gathered statistics just from a general
population standpoint are doctors okay
how many of you have had a patient come
to you and ask you for advice or maybe
some sort of guidance to use cannabis as
a medication or you know authorization
to use cannabis instead of something
else how many of you guys have had that
because we wanted to know like is this
common 92% of them have had a patient
come and ask them that's like almost
100% okay so then we looked at well what
are the barriers to like proper care
well only 6% of them had ever had any
kind of education on using cannabis or
canid molecules so the barrier is
obvious it's that it the educa they are
not taught so they don't have confidence
to provide any kind of guidance um but
that creates a problem right because the
product is available there so now you
know rather than using a medical
professional to maybe help you guide
them they're just going straight to the
bud tenders so because they don't need a
doctor so what you've done now is you've
actually taken the patient out of the
healthare system rather than keeping
them in the Health Care System right and
it's a it's a pharmacologically active
agent like if anything you should want
to have somebody there to guide you but
then you have to remember our doctors
are very busy we don't have enough
doctors they have like three minutes
with every patient so like they don't
have a lot of time and cannaboid as a
therapeutic it takes an interaction with
your patient you have to spend time with
them and the patient has to be willing
to toy with the levels that they're
taking in the amounts because everybody
has a different optimal dose and so I
personally think that we could have an
entire undergrad degree just teaching
people how you know the endocan aoid
system and how to use it as a
therapeutic and I hope one day that we
can do that um because the doctors
they're too busy like that I think we're
aiming at the wrong people there and so
in athletics when I went and was
interviewing medical staff they they're
busy same thing but now you have a
different population because your job is
to keep these athletes which are million
dooll athletes safe and so if your
million-dollar athletes are interested
in this substance and they're able to
access it and you don't have any kind of
rules against it which the NFL still has
rules at C just in preseason I think and
then but it's like if they can access it
then your responsibility as a healthc
care provider is to be able to provide
them with information and guidance about
it it's not okay to just be like uh
pretend you know like look the other way
and pretend we don't know what's
happening which is pretty much what's
going on like but everybody is scared of
the hierarchy and of who sets the rules
and who you answer to including the
athletes they don't necessarily want to
talk to somebody in their team about it
because they're worried that they're
going to get in trouble and then the
medical staff are worried that they're
going to get in trouble if they were
giving them sort sort of guidance on it
and so the NCAA removing it as a
prohibited substance has created a space
in my opinion well okay then if you're
going to remove it then you have to
teach them how to use it responsibly the
same way that you did with alcohol you
know the the this whole punishment model
that's ridiculous the abstinence thing
doesn't work all the athletes say that
it it's offensive to the medical staff
when they're learning this message where
it does not align with what we see in
society and so athletes and a lot of
them are actually gravitating towards
cannabis um for different reasons you
know they're choosing it over other
things for different reasons for example
alcohol alcohol you know there's a next
day effect in athletics that takes up
time they they're dehydrated they're
hung over they can't train they lose a
day when they spent Saturday night
drinking 16 beer if they spent Saturday
night they ate a gummy just is just
totally recreationally well the next day
they they probably sat at home ate
something went to bed and then the next
day they can train they're not
dehydrated they're probably have their
inflammation reduced and they can carry
on and so the dysfunction now that we
see is like the regulations aren't
lining up with reality and so it's to
find a way to correctly and put in place
the policies that align with these
things because if you don't you're
fractioning the trust of your athletes
towards their team and you're
fractioning you know the trust that they
have that you're able ble to actually
care for them in all capacities because
if you can't answer their questions
about this one thing they're just going
to bolt and go find their information
somewhere else and you don't want that
right no and I would think in an an
athlete population too um these are
people who are very hyperaware of their
bodies and how they perform and they're
always trying to get an edge that's why
you have people jumping into cold
plunges and having different diets and
things like that I would think that you
know uh canabo as a way to reduce your
inflammation or maybe you know reduce
your anxiety so that you can perform
better like I would imagine a lot of
athletes are are very interested in that
and are experimenting with it yes and
that's the thing is they are
experimenting with it they are training
with it and they have found results and
so these guys you know and they learn
from each other so if one they're like
ants like if one guy has a good
experience they'll tell the next guy the
next guy you know before you know it
then they're all trying it but they're
not wrong there are things like it does
legitimately molecular mechanisms that
do reduce inflammation and so that can
help you recover we have to prove that
out in humans but in theory so if
they're feeling that you can't tell them
that what they're feeling is incorrect
if if they're feeling you know if it
does reduce their inflammation and stuff
and so that's where the dysfunction is
between research and the real world and
I think cannabis is one of the places
where I mean I can't even think of
another one where research is further
from Real World I mean the real world
they're doing stuff like I mean athletes
because I work with athletes they'll try
exactly like you said I mean they want
an advantage and they want ways to you
know Advantage their body because their
body is their most important tool it is
their most valuable tool is their body
and they're very intentional about what
they put inside it they're not messing
around with things that they think are
going to hurt them so if they try
something once and they're like yeah I
didn't feel good they're not going to do
it again but if they try something and
they're like okay w i you know whatever
hurt before doesn't hurt anymore or I
was able to recover faster you know but
then they're at a loss for you know
they're going on Google or whatever to
get their information there's no place
for them to find they don't know how to
find good information and then the
question is like well would they even
ask their team anyways and then if they
did ask their team what could the team
even offer them as far as answers go and
currently not much like it's and now the
NCAA is in the exact same spot because
they've removed it as a prohibited
substance which I applaud them for doing
that because it it didn't make any sense
to have it prohibited anymore um because
there are valid places where athletes
should be able to use cannaboids and and
one place that comes to mind because it
came up a lot was female athletes and
they use it for once a month they are
doubled over in pain with menstrual
cramps and canono work amazingly for
reducing because menstrual pain is both
neurological and it's no receptive so
you have neurons firing and you have
tissue inflaming and canono can get at
both of those to reduce them and it does
work really well in female athletes and
so you had female athletes that would
prefer to use that instead of an nsid or
any other type of drug but if they did
they were at risk of losing their
scholarship and that was wrong in my
opinion like they shouldn't have to
worry about that and then have to take
whatever prescription or other drug that
you say is good when they would prefer
to use something else so the autonomy
over their own choices I think is also
making it you know I think athletes are
voicing that more now than they did
before so I I definitely think um yeah I
think the athletes for sure are you know
they're trying different things as they
always do that's not new a lot of times
athletes like we call it bro science
right like Bro Science is always about
10 years ahead of actual science and
half the time they're right and half the
time they like harm themselves but I
mean a lot of the times they come out
with like these guys just do it because
they're like okay well I'm just going to
try it and then like then science
catches up right but Bro Science there's
something to that like it's you know so
yeah no and it's funny you see it in in
C cannabis cultivation too where you
know the Growers they're not trained
scientists or or whatever but they they
know it works and they've been using it
for a long time and only now the
researchers are coming along and
understanding like okay well this is the
mechanism and that's why that works
exactly and I think that cannabis
honestly like I laugh all the time
because it's it's backward it's been
backwards since the beginning of time
like what other substance like you know
mulam wanted to know why people were
getting high and so in 64 like he
isolated like the THC molecule but it's
like we went completely backwards as far
as like usually in Pharmaceuticals
you're looking for an agent to cause an
effect and in this place we already had
the effect and we were trying to look
for the agent like it's backwards and
then we had no idea how it worked and
then we discovered this enormous endoc
canabo system because we discovered this
molecule in a plant like normally you
know what system you're working in and
you're looking for like it's completely
backwards so we discovered like isolated
the molecule and then happened to
discover the biggest neurophysiological
receptor system in your body because we
were looking at what like it's just it
was completely backwards and so I think
you know I laugh because it's like
almost everything is backwards in it in
cannabis like it's it's yeah but I mean
I I think it's an opportunity really for
people to learn so many things about so
many things by studying it yeah so I
mean instead of going backwards let's
look forward so what new studies are are
you working on or are you excited about
that you know are in the works when it
when it comes to uh canabo and Athletics
so I'm really excited we just finished
um the first part of our NFL clinical
trial so what we were looking at um
before we could go into the next part is
we really wanted to see what is the
optimal dose of CBD in an athlete like
nobody knows right and you hear it all
the time in people arguing over like low
dose high dose what you know nobody
really knows and so um we have a group
of athletes that these poor guys gave so
much blood every two weeks but we um had
an escalating dose and we got them up to
a pretty high amount and so now we're
going to calculate out what would be
what would appear to be the optimal dose
just based on you know the serum levels
and stuff like that so with that then
the next part is we're going to use that
optimal dose and we're actually going to
do a double blind crossover in a season
of football and we're using um athletes
in Canada in in the football season and
we're going to use the product that we
have and this is where it's going to get
really exciting because we're going to
be able to compare the group that's
using the cannabinoids compared to the
group that isn't and the metrics that
we're looking at in that is like so
exciting to me because we're looking at
you know a couple of things I mentioned
before the things that are happening in
the brain like the cerebral oxygenation
and the cerebral blood flow but we're
also looking at the bioinf flammatory
markers to look at what the changes are
in that when you're taking cannabinoids
versus when you're not um and then we're
also going to look at of course the pain
scores we're going to look at the
concussion scores we're going to look at
um the contractility of their heart
because we want to look at the uh
because your heart is electrical endoc
canabo system functions on ions
essentially so we're going to look at
the heart and the differences in the
contractility and blood pressure like we
have we're looking at sleep scores we're
looking at their mental status so like
we're going to be able to pull so much
data out of this specific to athletes
which hasn't been done like athletes
just haven't really been studied because
you know they're a healthy population
right but for me you know they really
are representative of a great number of
people in the world you know like
Weekend Warriors or people that are
generally healthy you know like people
that want that are looking for you know
you could consider it a supplement
really like a supplement agent and so
that is really exciting to me and um the
other thing that really excites me is
the progress that's being made right now
in um biophysics which is looking really
at the ion exchanges between like all of
your cells so usually when you're
looking at ion movements it's you know
brain waves because we know that your
neurons function on electricity and your
heart functions on electricity but with
Recent research we've been able to see
that the ion movements between all the
cells so there's a lot of um
communication it's a communication
system and so it's a communication
system that typically you know we know
your body runs on biochemistry so that's
looking at the chemistry of it but above
that it's actually physics it's ion
exchanges and so when you look at um
that's one of the things we're looking
at in the brain is the brain
oscillations also using the cannaboids
because um there's a lot of information
there I think and I think that uh the
future for that is is really bright I
think and I think that it'll develop a
whole new way to treat bodies um you
know sick bodies too because right now
we treat them with you know medication
or things that are targeting receptors
but if we could develop the ability to
um like a quick example of cancer cells
like you can see uh cell that's about to
turn cancerous because there's a change
basically in the it's basically in the
bioelectric frequency of the cell so you
can you can see it by the change in the
ions if you could in theory use that
information to then reverse it by using
ions and electricity rather than
chemistry you could potentially find
ways to actually push physiology again
just using a different mechanism and so
for me I'm always looking at how do you
push physiology without drugs really you
know and so that and that really was the
endocannabinoid system to me is I think
there's a lot going on there and you
know it started with me looking at it
because you can push that system without
the cannabis plant you know you can
invoke it with exercise you can invoke
it with meditation the cold plans that
you just talked about before when you
shock it you secrete endocan aboid and
so singing you know youed to create them
when you sing you used to create them
when you dance and so it's like a lot of
the things again that historically and
traditionally and culturally were used
for therapeutic reasons and again it was
like Bro Science culture mode like they
were doing it and they were doing
dancing and chanting and nobody knew why
it worked but now we come to find out oh
wow they're secreting a massive amount
of anandamide when they're doing that
well that makes perfect sense because
anandamide is named that because it's
the Bliss molecule so it makes a lot of
sense right so what they always knew to
be true now we have the technology to
actually prove out molecular
why it is true but they always knew that
it was working you know way back when
and so um yeah so I think that for me
it's an exciting space to be in because
you're looking at your neurons and
you're looking at your like the immune
system which to me really I mean it
touches everything in your
body absolutely yeah that that is
exciting um lots of work to do yeah y um
so wrapping up Liz I want to give you
opportunity to share any other resources
or papers that you know of that you
think the listeners might be interested
in reading up on if they're curious
about some of these things and then also
any website social media or ways that
people can connect with you to to learn
more yeah uh so the paper that I
recently published the one that you
mentioned is in the sports medicine
journal and then our protocol for what
we're doing for our clinical trial was
just published in BMC neurology and so
that lists all of the different metrics
that we're going to be looking at in our
athletes so if that's of interest to
anybody they can search that one up too
and then um I don't really have a lot of
social media so I have uh there's a
website a research website basically
that just kind of updates what we're
doing and it's trainwith Mar jane.com um
and then on Instagram it's just train
with. Mar Jane and there's not a ton on
there but there's you know just updates
brief
updates excellent well I'll put links to
all that stuff in the show description
so people can have an easy way to find
it and um Liz thanks again for taking
the time um this is fascinating stuff
that you're working on uh we're excited
to see where it goes and uh hopefully
we'll see you down at canmed real soon
yeah I hope so thanks so much for having
me on I appreciate it all right
[Music]
a