welcome to the canmed coffee talk lounge
here live at canmed2022
in pasadena california i'm ben amaral
host of the canmed coffee talk podcast i
am here with ethan rousseau our science
keynote presenter here at canmed2022
ethan great to see you well it's lovely
to be here i regard this as my coming
out post pandemic
yeah and with that said how nice is it
to be back
um in person at a meeting like canmed
and what are you hoping to get out of
this event well it's familiar but novel
at the same time we've all been cooped
up for a couple of years this would be
my first in-person presentation although
we've made good use of zoom
for presentations all over the world
so you know i found out i don't have to
be there but i certainly wanted to be
there for this yeah and again what is it
about an in-person event that
makes it better than you know zoom which
we've been living with for the past
three years well you don't have the
ability to network
on zoom
the same way you know it's not just the
meeting it's the uh little get-togethers
in a
quiet room afterwards or dinners
together
uh the chance to really get to know your
collaborators
all that you know that's irreplaceable
right yeah the business really takes
place between the talks sure
excellent and now are there any
presentations at this year's event that
you're looking forward to oh there's so
many
uh of course professor mishulam
my spiritual uncle and all this
um
dustin sulak bonnie goldstein
yeah stacy gruber
so many yeah no i didn't mean to put you
on the spot if she's curious and um so
your keynote presentation it's titled
cannabis and psychiatry the final
frontier and um i have to admit i'm a
little curious about the final frontier
part
because certainly there must be some
additional frontiers that we've yet to
conquer with cannabis medicine yeah
there are the other notable one would be
the area of obstetrics and gynecology
now what they have in common is these
were
very
commonly
indications for cannabis-based medicine
in the past
historically the literature from the
19th century and even before pointed to
those areas as
being ones where cannabis-based medicine
was very effective
particularly for psychiatry though
it's sort of a forbidden territory yet
same with obstetrics and gynecology
most psychiatrists are extremely
conservative
particularly about the
idea of a drug of abuse i.e cannabis
that can be used therapeutically but i
think many of them are unfamiliar with
the history
and they're also thinking in terms of
what they've seen
which is really abuse
related to thc
but
there's more to cannabis than just thc
right and the real
contributions are going to come from
additional components
with maybe just a touch of thc yeah i
was going to ask you that i mean because
obviously thc is the the known
psychoactive compound so is that sort of
essential to be
used here no they're preparations for
instance there have been a couple of
randomized controlled phase 2 trials
of cannabidiol as an isolate
in
treating schizophrenia quite effectively
but the doses were so high eight hundred
to a thousand milligrams i think that we
could do a lot better with less making
it more accessible and less expensive by
having other components particularly
cannabidirl which i'll be talking about
in the keynote
that's a component of great promise
most people really haven't had access to
it
let alone knowledge of its potential
yeah so is that an example where you
know these additional compounds can sort
of
um when i talked with kevin spellman
about some of the pharmacology of the
different compounds he explained that
some of them are almost served as an
icebreaker where they can sort of help
with the penetration of the medicine so
is that an example of why you know the
entourage effect is so important well
it's just one factor among many yeah
but
you know i i named my paper taming thc
back in 2011 because
that really describes a lot of what
some of the minor cannabinoids and
terpenoids will do is increase the
therapeutic index of thc making it a
better more tolerable medicine
excellent okay and so i wanted to quote
from your abstract here you said that
the endocannabinoid system has a
critical
role in neurotransmission and
homeostasis of the limbic system can you
speak more about how endocannabinoids
and phytocannabinoids help regulate this
important area of the brain sure so the
limbic system are the emotional centers
of the brain of course
and what we find is there's a very high
density of the cb1 receptor where
thc
and the endocannabinoids and nanda mine
and two eric adonal glycerol work
so that that was a hint i mean when this
was established back in the 90s it was
obvious to some of us that boy there's a
real target there and this explains why
cannabis could be so effective for a
variety of psychiatric conditions
and really that's the foundation
then it just becomes a practical matter
of what do you use what's in it what's
the dose
on where is it going to be most
effective
that's what i'd like to be working on
you know for
the rest of my career right you've got
to conquer that frontier right hopefully
and i did want to bring up since we're
talking about psychiatry it's becoming a
bigger topic kind of in our circles and
we have a few presentations about it
here at this year's canmed
psilocybin and psychedelics
what role will they play in psychiatry
again great promise
there's been a resurgence of interest in
the psychedelics
just analogously to cannabis it's been
submerged for some decades because of
prohibition
but again i'd like to be a student of
medical history
back in the 50s and 60s there was some
tremendous research on psychedelics
for a variety conditions treating
addictions particularly alcoholism
uh intractable depression end-of-life
things the same kinds of things you're
here now
um
so it's interesting how there's been
sort of a transition uh from cannabis to
psychedelics uh and it may be that we've
got
psilocybin or mdma available
as pharmaceuticals
before there's better access to a wide
range of cannabis based pharmaceuticals
it's not a competition i'd like to see
both um
something i'd like to emphasize is most
of the current research on psychedelics
is focused on synthetics
or sim single molecules um i think that
there's synergy in the philosophy
mushrooms and many of the other
botanical sources of psychedelics and
i hope to focus more on those
uh rather than the isolates right so
again the entourage effect uh yeah if it
works for cannabis it should work in
this realm as well
excellent um and so in your abstract you
also mentioned you mentioned it here um
answering one of the earlier questions
of there being a long history of using
cannabis to treat mental conditions what
are some good examples of that
well it only goes back about 4 000 years
you know the sumerians uh there was a
listing of the attributes of what we
believe is cannabis i'm sure it is
but one of the the lines about this
plant was for
or against panic
and
that is the 4 000 year old demonstration
of the biphasic dose response curve of
cannabis meaning
at very low doses it's great for anxiety
a dose that's too high and induces
anxiety right there it is right there
so um that's a blueprint for everything
that
came before and hopefully will come
subsequently
another highlight would be um
jean-jacques monroe de tour in france on
the 1830s wrote a whole book
about the promise of cannabis
for treating
schizophrenia and other psychiatric
conditions
unfortunately the tradition didn't carry
through
to the modern day but we have a chance
to write that historical wrong
excellent okay and just in closing
before i let you go um
just curious that you know given that so
much of the research that goes into
medicinal cannabis
is done by privately funded companies
like your own
how important is it to come to events
like canmed and share that information
with the community because
not all companies are going to be as
forthcoming as as you and others well
again you have to keep some things close
to the vest in terms of development uh
like it or not one has to have
intellectual property attached to be
able to continue the work
as it is now
we have found ourselves at credo science
going uh into a few tangents to try and
support the operation
but we've got a lot of proverbial irons
in the fire
but the chance to network
again is fundamental here to see with
whom you want to collaborate on whatever
level who's got the novel extraction
technique that might be ideally suited
to the medicine that you're trying to
develop right um
seeing what the markets are
it's always a matter of what what are
other people doing
how can we either work with them or
maybe it generates a new idea we can
take in a different direction
so again it's that intellectual
interchange that's just fundamental to
how
science advances yeah no and that's one
of the things we've noticed in the last
few years there being more sort of
announcements of novel technologies or
novel methods that that go on at the
event so
we like to think that's the strength of
the event
hopefully
all right ethan well thanks again for
taking the time hope you enjoyed your
time in the cam ed coffee talk lounge
and look forward to having a great event
with you a pleasure thank you
you