[Music]
and one of them being that there's a
number of different fluids that can be
tested and I know that your your paper
kind of looked at this kind of saliva
versus urine versus uh blood so what is
sort of the the best one to use so right
now at the side uh what is happens I
know in Canada for sure I I think it's
similar in the US is if a a officer is
suspect somebody of being impaired they
they pull them over and they do a a
standardized field sobriety test which
is the you know touching your nose and
looking at uh the stigmas and and your
ability to walk in the one leg stand uh
you know your balance and things like
that which we've all seen on TV I'm sure
we're a little bit familiar with what
that looks like uh and then they're also
able to do at the roadside and I know in
Canada we use this it's a saliva test
that measures it gives you a reading
that says positive or negative if you're
above a certain level or not and then
there's the blood which they can take
you back to the lab and they can look at
the blood levels of THC as well then
there's urine of course um which is a
bit of a different Beast because with
urine you're measuring the breakdown
products of cannabis you're measuring
what it comes off the Cannabis whereas
with saliva and blood you're measuring
uh THC uh directly so for that reason
urine probably isn't a great indicator
of recent use also as we know the these
breakdown products of cannabis of THC
can last in the urine for days weeks
very a very long time so it's not a
great indicator of very recent use it
just says that somebody has used in the
past few days or potentially longer
whereas Salva tells you more of a short
time window in the past 12 hours and
blood can give you a more definitive
timeline um you know if somebody has
very high levels of blood THC then you
know they've used fairly recently or
smoked fairly recently um and and if
they're lower than they would have used
at some point in the past day or so so
that's more of an accurate time window
for blood and saliva
right and now is it fairly easy to kind
of look at the concentrations in the
blood or saliva and sort of Trace
backwards how much cannabis the person
could have ingested again I'm I'm sorry
I'm GNA keep doing this I'm Gonna Keep
kind of doing the comparison to alcohol
but you know if you're at like a 08 um
alcohol level you can kind of kind of go
back and be like okay they've probably
had a few a few drinks at least in the
past hour or two can you do a similar
thing with cannabis it's really uh to to
estimate the last time of use and the
exact amount of use is quite challenging
with cannabis because the amount of THC
in blood and urine is really dependent
on a lot of factors including age sex
how often you use cannabis what form of
cannabis you've used so we know that
smoked and Vaped cannabis produce very
much higher levels very quickly in Blood
and saliva than with uh Edibles for
example but Edibles last very a lot
longer than smoked with smoked or Vaped
it's gone in five hours with Edibles
that's much can last much longer so if
somebody comes up with 10 nanograms per
Mill of
THC uh it's really hard to know what
kind of cannabis they used and when they
last used it also um people who use
frequently the Cannabis might stick
around longer in the blood urine than
people who use infrequent
so it's it's it's very it's very
challenging but we we can tell you've
used recently but we don't know exactly
how much or when that
[Music]
was