welcome back to the canberra coffee talk
lounge here can med 2022
i'm here with bonnie goldstein she is
our medicine keynote presenter here at
canmed bonnie welcome to the kim at
coffee talk lounge thank you for having
me it's great to see you in person again
it is so nice to be back in person it's
been a long two and a half years
and it's just great to see everybody
here
yeah and so in particular coming to an
event like canmed and being here in
person what is it that you're looking to
get out of the eye
well you know we haven't really had a
huge amount of education over the last
two and a half years because we've all
been home
and so i'm really excited to see
my fellow cannabis
uh scientists
um
and hear what they have to say that
they've learned over the last two years
their latest publications where the
cultivation site is going where the
medical side is going and just looking
um
really to get more information
yeah and
and to that point are there any
presentations in particular that you're
excited to hear
well i'm always excited to hear dr ethan
rousseau he's like our medical cannabis
guru and he's doing a talk on the latest
in um
for cannabis and psychiatry so i'm
really excited about that yeah yeah i
spoke with him a little earlier today
yeah i'm looking forward to that one too
it's great to have a full hour of epa i
think it's a treat for everyone
um so you're participating in the
medical practicum you're giving keynote
presentation as we mentioned and you're
participating on a panel so thank you
very much for everything that you do for
here right so tell us a bit about what
you're going to be presenting about in
your keynote though i know it's about
pediatrics
that's right so i'm focusing on uh two
conditions that are
very commonly treated now with cannabis
so one epilepsy
and uh certainly we're seeing great
results and very i'm very excited
because there's a ton of new research
that just came out in the last couple
years because this is still new
and now we're finally getting some
long-term results so i'll be talking
about that
and then also with autism i'm going to
be talking about some research that i've
done where we published two papers in
the last six months looking at uh
biomarkers collected in the saliva
that help um document the impact that
medical cannabis is having on children
with autism yeah
no it's good that you mentioned that you
know epilepsy that's sort of i mean
that's pretty well established right in
terms of using cannabis for epilepsy but
autism that's one that's really starting
to gain steam so it's great that you
have
this data now that's that's showing the
biomarkers you can really quantify that
really
that's right and what we're finding is
that the biomarker improvements
correlate with what the parents are
reporting
so it's no longer anecdotal report we
now have
uh objective data which
you know really we don't have for
pharmaceuticals nobody's doing that so i
would say that this actually puts
cannabis on a even playing field with
pharmaceuticals to treat autism
excellent excellent
so let me speak a bit about the panel
that you're going to be on as well what
are the goals there
so i think with the panel i'm going to
be sitting with other clinicians
and we're just going to share our
collective experience treating thousands
of patients with medical cannabis and
what's interesting is that we all come
from different parts of the country
we're all working in our practices and
we're all finding very similar results
for people with dementia for people with
chronic pain for people with anxiety
depression
that cannabis is this unbelievable
um and
useful tool
for doctors to start incorporating
really you can't be a doctor anymore and
ignore the endocannabinoid system you
have to understand that this plays a
major role in human health and that
by not offering cannabis as an option to
patients especially to those who are not
finding good results with conventional
treatments you're doing a disservice
yeah
no and i think it's important too that
even if physicians aren't going to
necessarily be recommending it to at
least be knowledgeable enough that if
your patient comes to you with questions
you can answer them right you want to
have a conversation and this idea of
there's not enough research well one
could say that but i just had to race
through a presentation because there is
so much research that i i wanted to
share and again it's not a panacea for
everything this is just another tool in
the toolbox of uh that physicians and
other healthcare practitioners uh should
be including in their practice yeah and
one encouraging sign that i noticed when
i was sitting in on the practice
earlier was when eloise was welcoming
everyone she had asked people to raise
their hand if this was their first
experience getting a medical cannabis
education a good amount of people raised
their hands
absolutely
when you're sitting in a room and a
patient asks you about something and you
don't know about it and then that
happens over and over again
as a scientist right doctors are trained
scientists we should know about this so
that we at least can have a conversation
with our patients that's meaningful to
them
so that we can help them and again not
everybody should be taking cannabis but
at the same time you want to be able to
be discriminating in those when you have
these conversations with patients who
might it help who might it not help
that's what you are are there to do with
your patients is to help them sort out
all of this scientific data yeah
absolutely
one thing that you you mentioned too is
called the research
and you know one thing that we find
especially you know with the
prohibitions on cannabis there's only so
much research that can be done and a lot
of it has to be done by these private
companies um much like you know
informatics and the study that you had
talked about earlier so
with that said how important is it for
these companies that as they're getting
new data to come to events like him and
share that because i mean obviously they
are privately funded companies they are
putting up their own money and they
might want to withhold that but you know
it is important to share absolutely and
you know there's a statistic that says
that something published in the
scientific data takes 17 years to
trickle down to the clinician that's a
long time so conferences like this
are so important because
one
there's camaraderie and all of that but
at the same time we're all learning
about what other people are doing in
this um
very uh important field of cannabis
medicine
absolutely
all right bonnie i know that you're busy
as we mentioned with your your many
responsibilities here at camden but i
appreciate you taking the time to talk
with us
and um have a great event thanks so much
ben
you