[Music]
all right
there's there's different oils have
different viscosities A good rule of
thumb is that distillate is is is pretty
viscous in terms of CPS where we're
looking at anywhere between 50 and and
100 000 CPS
and when you sorry what's CPS Center
Poise it's the measure of a viscosity of
a fluid got it
um and when we are looking at live resin
we're usually on some lower viscosities
because we've got some either recombined
terpenes in there or the terpenes have
been re-added back so we're on a product
that's a little bit more liquidy and
then when we look at live rosin which is
solventless which is pressed uh we go
back to something very very thick so the
the mathematical process of vaporization
is a mix of chemistry thermodynamics and
fluid mechanics
so you have to understand all three of
those to understand which Hardware can
work better with which oil the added
complexity of cannabis is that it is a
plant it's a natural product so from one
batch to the other of the exact same
strain when you process it you will have
different inputs so the trick is really
to figure out which Hardware suits which
oil the best we have we have a great
rule of thumb that are are uh our
run-of-the-mill basic cartridge the V12
is something that would work very well
with distillate and live resin for rosin
because you have more of that full
flavor because you have more of that
terpenes we need to use a different
device to make sure the client or the
patient does not heat it too much so we
increase the resistance for instance to
be usable on the run-of-the-mill
batteries that you'd be buying
um now that's just an example we can
also look at the intake hole size
because that will measure the rate at
which the oil is going to feed the coil
to turn into vapor so obviously the
thicker the oil the bigger holes you
need to allow more of that to seep in
there's there's a lot more I'm trying to
hit it really high level but there's a
lot more that goes uh that goes into
this and really the the the performance
of The Vape cartridges on the market can
literally be divided by 10 or multiplied
by 10 by changing one of those variables
right and given that that fact and that
you were saying you know some processors
they're just buying kind of cheap
Hardware from Alibaba
um I imagine that the performance and
quality of Vape carts in the marketplace
can vary widely
immensely we've done some testing
um with different viscosities so let's
say you take a very very thick liquid
you know like like like honey like
molasses
if you use a battery for instance at a
3.7 volt setting with smaller intake
holes you're essentially not going to
allow enough oil to penetrate the coil
um fast enough when the coil is heating
up so basically the little that has made
it into the coil is going to be burning
immediately and not only are you getting
bad flavor but you're also getting toxic
emissions because burning in essence is
the same thing as combustion so you're
degrading the terpenes and the
cannabinoids in there and uh potentially
ruining the The Experience now on the
other hand if you have too much oil that
goes in
um it and and too much of an intake hole
and too much of a big porosity on the
ceramic itself of the coil you are going
to see saturation which means which
leads to clogging which means leads to
leaking and potential spit back through
the mouthpiece so it is very very
important to really match the hardware
to the oil or vice versa and make sure
you have a consistent Supply I think
that's really the other the other side
to this is the consistency of the
quality of the
[Music]