hi welcome to the cannabis safety
testing panel I'm the my day job is
director of Clinical Research at tilray
but I also serve as a member of the
cannabis Advisory Committee to the state
of California advising them on their
regulations in California and this issue
of product quality safety is really
maybe not very interesting to a lot of
you but it's actually critical to
elevating this industry and it's a very
difficult topic to cover so I have with
me here for chemistry experts and
they're gonna help us kind of discuss
this topic and choose apart some of the
most important issues that we need to be
thinking about and I'll let them
introduce themselves hello my name is
Kyle passion I'm representing madman
Enterprises LLC we own managed to
operate a slew of licenses for the
cannabis industry across the nation I
serve as their laboratory director for
compliance specifically ISO 17025 for
our in-house analytical testing
facilities that are built within our
facilities my background is in
biochemistry and laboratory diagnostic
assay development and I am coming here
by lieu of Doug Kennedy to speak to
compliance and regulations for
analytical laboratories in the cannabis
industry my name is Kyle Moyer and I'm a
field application scientist with
medicinal genomics I received my
bachelor's degree in neuroscience and
behavior from the University of
California Santa Cruz and I currently
serve as the vice chair for the American
Chemical Society's cannabis chemistry
subdivision as well as their scholarship
chair and my background is mostly in
cannabis testing I've been doing it for
about six years now and I got my start
at one of
first independent analytical
laboratories in the state of California
and in those six years I've tested about
a hundred thousand samples of medical
cannabis at this point hello everyone my
name is Andrew Pham I currently serve as
the scientific director at Bell Costa
labs the first licensed and accredited
lab in Long Beach California I am also
the chair of the cannabis chemistry
subdivision at the American Chemical
Society as well as a court qualified
expert witness that testifying in over
two dozen cases involving cannabis and
I'm right flora noia president urines
friendship global sciences been in this
analytical world since 1989 I feel
pretty old but been really grateful and
going through all of the cannabis
documentation and with all of the
sciences going on with it and I'm here
to hopefully help navigate through some
of the quality pieces because this is a
really infant type of industry and
there's a lot of information that can be
learned from the past that we were
hoping to put together with this thank
you okay so I'm gonna set the stage a
little bit by telling you what I
currently see as a cannabis you know in
the state of California so so full
disclosure I have a son with very severe
treatment-resistant epilepsy and have
been looking for products that are safe
to give him for the last six years even
today if I walk into a dispensary I'm
not comfortable with the product quality
standards of any product that I find it
is Spencer II at least not in where I
live in Northern California I honestly I
don't know whether the product will be
contaminated I don't know whether the
potency is correct right whether the
labeling for THC and CBD content is
accurate and I think this is a real
problem and I'm a very educated consumer
because of my my background and I think
we're we're at a place where a lot of
consumers are not as educated and really
don't understand that nobody is
overseeing these cannabis products being
sold in dispensaries because right now
it's the industry itself that is
kind of paving the way and one of the
things that I wanted to talk about with
you guys today is how do we ensure that
the testing industry you know with with
lack of federal oversight and I think
the speaker from medicinal genomics gave
a good overview of how the regulations
differ state-by-state and how the states
apply different standards are different
they reference different pharmacopoeias
to establish their regulations but if
there's going to be no federal oversight
how can can we as an industry raise the
bar in testing to make sure that a
sample that is being given to two
different labs in let's just say in
California would return the exact same
results I mean that's the goal that
we're going for and so let's start with
Kyle you yeah you guys what are some of
your suggestions for you know rates for
the for the testing industry itself to
raise the bar I know you guys are all
for part of different organizations and
maybe you can speak a little bit to what
the different organizations do and and
which one might be the best suited to
set you know third-party standards for
all of the testing labs so for my case
example we're not an independent
laboratory testing facility we do have
laboratories within our vertically
aligned facilities and with that being
said we have to take into account local
jurisdictions across many different
states from my background in both pharma
and biotech and even in clinical we
follow strict regulations specifically
iso international standard organizations
and even more so specifically iso 17025
with my experience going from state to
state and dealing with local
jurisdictions is that a lot of the
authorities there for example fire
marshals if not County authorities rely
on people like us people in the industry
to educate them on how to build a
regular
system how to apply that on us so in
terms of moving the compliance and
regulation forward to make sure that it
is moving towards a federal legalization
madmen we imposed local jurisdictions
and local standardization and also ISO
as a prerequisite for a lot of our
facilities and a lot of building
analytical labs and also developing more
methods it also speaks to teaching a new
generation especially with this new
version of ISO 17025 which takes out a
lot of the details from 2005 and leaves
a lot of things generalised but in a
sense this opens a door for innovation
to allow more creativity that still
follows compliance and regulations so
with that being said it gives an
opportunity for perhaps legacy growers
or people who have been growing and
things for 20 years in their garage who
say that they can honestly grow this
with a certain distance or whatnot but
unable to teach them to use objective
evidence like using an analytical lab to
actually track and monitor chemicals and
whatnot so it's important to use
regulations and compliance to not only
help this industry move forward but to
also help the people within the industry
to be more familiar with the progression
of regulation and compliance okay I'm
gonna ask Michael a question because you
come to this with background from other
industries so environmental testing food
testing what are some of the so given
your extensive background in these
industries which are well regulated what
can we take from each of those you know
regulatory standards and apply to this
industry and you raise a really good
question and technically this particular
chemical this particular plan this
particular food could
transcends a lot you know it's not a
drug
Marshall it is a drug it's not a food
what should you put it in food you know
it's really not something that it's like
a tobacco but it is because you can
smoke it so it goes across many
different mark as many different fields
that you know really puts it into a
different category so you don't really
look at it as a drug but FDA is there
DEA is there and they do look at as a
drug but we don't the DEA
really puts the clamp down even on the
deal T so being able to move things
across really makes it very very
challenging
and I know kind of looking back at the
past working with the EPA and the FDA
back when they were developing methods
back in the 60s 70s 80s it was kind of
like the Wild West kind of like it is
today
specifically on the analytical set on a
testing side you know if I recall you
know we were able to do one-point
calibrations back then we were able to
hold the calibration for as long as we
wanted to you know all of those change
because it was a very big need for
getting accurate data and so using some
of the lessons learned from those
industries from the past and we can
certainly use that information today to
make this particular process much faster
to the endpoint as possible and being
able to you know kind of distill
everything that we've done it all comes
down to validation that's what it all
comes down to um so if you're able to
get a good validation protocol with the
intention of having good limits because
that's also part of it that will
definitely get you to a point where it
starts defining what type of
instrumentation you'll need what type of
chemistry analysis you'll need what type
of processes you need to be able to make
things move forward but it also gives
you an opportunity to be able to let
technology help you grow fast or help
you get better over time because if you
start to constrain everything because
you've made it too constrained through
your methodology then it's really hard
to help technology grow so I think
that's kind of the basically striking a
balance between allowing innovation to
occur in a very nascent industry but
still superimposing some of the the
standards that are common in other
industries and and one example for the
audience is common reference standards
don't exist right so a reference
standard is by definition the same thing
every time any lab uses it and currently
in California there is no reference
standard for any of the cannabinoids
which means that you can't call it a
reference standard right and in Andrew a
question for you might be what is your
experience been you know serving
customers in what are some of the issues
that have come up because of the lack of
a common reference standard well it's
the same complaint that pretty much
every one of our clients is saying well
we we're a distributor we take a same
sample to ten different labs and we're
getting ten different results and there
are so many technical difficulties to
overcome in order to fix this but yeah
an actual common reference standard
would be extremely helpful in really
getting everyone on the same page it's
honestly in my opinion if this can't be
done on the federal level I think the
burden is actually on the state states
have established reference testing
laboratories so if the state has a
reference testing lab they can act as
the referee you can present your
validation data to them and then you can
actually compare your data to other labs
who anonymously and I really think
that's the really the best path forward
because the state reference testing labs
won't really be motivated by churning
out results in order to make money the
resources are going to be from tax
revenues so they'll actually have
resources of equipment in order to
really get these methods together down
and be able to share these with the
testing labs that are doing this
commercially that's great
so a another problem we see is that
people use different equipment to test
products right and and and the equipment
has to be calibrated a certain way it
has to be cleaned a certain way these
are all called standard operating
procedures and so I'll I'll give this
question to kyle Boyer what is your
experience been when you see the
different types of equipment being used
in different labs
and do labs have standard operating
procedures in place that are relevant to
the types of equipment that they use and
how can we standardize that process a
bit more would it come from an external
regulatory body would it come from the
manufacturer of the equipment you speak
a little bit to that certainly yeah and
I think really what it is is we all need
to agree on you know what is the
appropriate instrumentation to quantify
or detect a given analyte or I guess
indicates microbiology pathogens or
species of interest and really what it
comes down to is the states need to all
come together and establish some sort of
consensus as far as okay here's what we
need to be looking for and then here's
the appropriate methodology to do it a
good example of this that I see is
Canada's microbiology my colleague
Yvonne spoke to this quite a bit we have
a kind of scattered mismatch between the
states some states are doing total count
tests some of them are doing species
specific pathogen tests some of them are
using platings some of them are using
quantitative pcr and in all these
systems they vary in their results and
their methods and I think really what it
is is it's hard to establish any type of
consensus when there's so many people
doing so many different things and so I
think it needs to come from all these
labs they really need to come together
and collaborate and speak with each
other and all these states they also
need to collaborate and speak with each
other what do you feel is the most
important in terms of patient safety and
what levels are appropriate and that
will then dictate you know what
methodology is used and what type of
instrumentation is used and as of right
now I don't think that there is that
consensus right now we're all scattered
doing our own thing and I think
California is doing a good job of paving
the way for establishing some consensus
because they've really done a lot of
diligence and figuring out what is
important for patient safety and I think
that you know we just all need to have
this conversation in order to arrive at
what is the appropriate methodologies in
order to keep patients safe so let's go
back to so I think we've we've talked a
lot about the problem and it's a huge
problem and it I think it's
gonna take years to address but let's
focus a little bit on the solution so
you you have mentioned different Pro
like different societies that you belong
to which would be the third party that
could take on establishing you know SOPs
or common testing methods in the
cannabis industry that are specific to
the cannabis industry and address some
of the issues that we see that that may
not be seen in food or Pharma or
environmental arenas um one of the
bigger areas that's doing a lot of
there's a lot there's a lot of a lot of
science going on a lot of research going
on a OEC is working really diligently on
developing methods that could do a
majority or a large amount of the
testing for different products and you
know being able to validate every
product it's almost impossible but you
know there's certain things certainly
the ways you can group things into
categories and you know if the AOA see
and some of these other organizations
can you know kind of push sorry Michael
what's the AOA see it's the Association
used to stand for Association of
analytical chemists but recently they
just changed it to AOA see so now just
answer AOA see yeah yeah you know but
looking at just the methodology that
they're putting together a a set of
criteria as a set of quality criteria to
be able to do the process of digesting
or extracting and analyzing samples for
results to be able to mitigate
interferences and be able to mitigate
the processes so that you're getting
better quality data and not having huge
biases one way or the other but again
there's there's lots of different areas
and like I said this is actually going
to transcend just one market and you
know right now that we're looking at it
as more of a food drug type of thing but
it's going to get environment it's going
to get into the environment we're going
to test it in the environmental space um
so we have to start looking at exactly
what that means and then that'll go into
more APA style methods
and it'll be in the permits and all this
other stuff so you know kind of looking
at it from a standpoint of what do we
need to do as an organization and we as
a community we have to really engage
with you know some of the organizations
that you may belong to so that we can
try to come together on some of these
things there's other advocacy
organizations that are out there a CIL
the association of independent lab or an
independent or Association and I'm on
the board too what the heck
but anyways but looking at some of these
other organizations that are out there
we should all come together and be able
to help the government be able to put
together something that we can all live
with if we go back to the past that was
when the EPA developed the methods that
the labs were supposed to use and it
worked for a while but it didn't work
later the same thing with the FDA they
developed these methods and then the
Liao's were supposed to use those
methods well kind of it so happens that
some of these companies that are doing
the testing are pretty darn smart and
they're able to do a lot of these
developments on their own so you know
kind of looking at how we can put all of
this together we should we all need to
come together as a group and almost a
man we have to kind of demand on what we
think is gonna be best for the consumers
because the reason why we're all here at
the testing level is to make sure that
we're you know making our communities
safe at the EPA is community safety FDA
community safety even d-o-t community
safety so you know at every level this
is all about safety for consumption
safety for the community safety for our
children so I think we all need to come
together and put together something
that's going to work for this particular
product right and so you brought up
something important which is this comes
in a lot of different forms like gummy
bear could come to the lab a brownie a
candy and dissolving all of those and
then being able to run a test that's
accurate is and coming up for a method
for all of these different ingredients
is going to be difficult so where do we
so I see you know the end result what
the ideal would be but if we're going to
tackle it step one step at a time
what are the
important things to test for right now I
mean we heard that certain forms of
Aspergillus are much more harmful than
others and currently very few people are
testing for those you know what what's
the first step in Stanton in looking at
safety what would be the very first step
and the minimum standards and then we
can go from there so I think when it
comes to at least with microbiology you
definitely hit it with Aspergillus I
mean this is like a it's it's an end to
fight in the cannabis plant and it's
commonly found and it's it's one of the
actual pathogens that can kill people
that it's documented well-documented it
can kill people when it comes to
pesticides I think we need to understand
okay what what is commonly being used
and at what levels is it actually okay
to have them in for example things like
Michael butanol are constantly being
used and there's of course some research
that's was done to show you know that
produces cyanide when it's combusted so
that's clearly an unsafe product for any
type of smokeable product but but we
know what what is being commonly used
and established these limits based on
science I think that's what's currently
happening right now is no one's really
basing these regulations on scientific
research they're just taking their best
educated guess as to what is going to
keep people safe but that also puts
people in the testing labs in a really
tough position because you set the bar
extremely dear detection limits
extremely low and what's allowable to
extremely low levels it becomes very
difficult to actually comply with these
regulations because it again it's not
based on science but it's based on what
they feel is keeping people safe so I
really think that a lot more research
needs to go into what is an acceptable
level of certain contaminants in
cannabis of course there's also heavy
metals as well that need to be tested
for and of course that's something that
you know we should be absolutely testing
for all across the board
and I think no levels of heavy metals
you know they're very low levels are
gonna be tolerated but we need to
establish consensus as far as what is
okay and what is not okay and then as
far as micro toxins go that's
another contaminant that I at the moment
I just don't think we have enough data
to support you know how rigorously this
mycotoxin testing needs to be done of
course we see that there is Aspergillus
there but are the conditions sufficient
enough to produce these types of micro
toxins that could be deleterious to
human health I you know I think that
it's just there's a lot more research
that needs to be done in order to
establish what these limits should be
and right now we're just taking our best
educated guess at it but I think we need
to see more data in order to actually
establish proper limits I have one thing
way back in the 60s 70s 80s they did
lots of studies that determine what type
of chemicals specifically in the
environment what kind of going back
we're going to be harmful at what levels
which is how they've developed these
permanent levels I think we do need to
do that for these because you know at
the contaminant level you're absolutely
right no do you have to speciate
something to be able to determine which
one is gonna be harmful for example
arsenic do you have some forms of good
arsenic there's some forms about arsenic
that that arsenic is really really bad
you don't want to take that but the good
are saying yes you can take a quite a
bit of it you'd be fine but as these
limits are progressing you have to be
able to determine what is going to be
important to the consumer might just
heard today that you know from a friend
I just met that North Carolina is using
an F fighter it's an instrument that is
not very capable of being able to
determine which is the bad portion of a
chemical that is trying to is trying to
do then that's we know basically THC and
T she's not really that bad but but
you're kind of looking at how much of it
is going to be the right amount is gonna
really be determine what cup type of
instrumentation you're going to be able
to need to do that particular analysis
or the species of that chemical so I
think there needs to be some Studies on
what it is that we're gonna be calling
important and understanding that that's
gonna change because over time you're
going to have different technology
that's gonna be able to do other things
but you know being able to determine
what is going to be important to the
consumer is super important you know
some of the levels that I've seen just
in California you know to me those are
high numbers based off of the cup type
of testing that we do you know for
example for arsenic as you know Quentin
1 and 4.1 ppm and then
or mercury mercury is bad but there's
someone working that it's not horrible
but methyl mercury is super bad for you
and if you have point zero five
micrograms or milligrams ppm of methyl
mercury that's not really good for you
not good at all so you know we have to
come together with what these type of
limits need to be based off of the
science absolutely right and just
because it's called arsenic doesn't mean
that's part of the science because
there's many many forms of arsenic so I
think that's the important part so I'll
just throw this out there because I
don't think you either of you answered
my question
which is what do we start with so so we
know that a lot of research needs to be
done but we need to start somewhere so
so what do we start with right now I
really think it starts with
toxicological studies basically making
sure and seeing studying exactly how
much to me its pesticides is the largest
public health danger right now because
we don't have a great idea on how much
is dangerous to human health in terms of
inhalation routes obviously a lot of
these pesticides have been used in food
for decades but we don't really know how
dangerous it is when you put it to a
flame and inhale it so I think that's
really what's more important here I also
want to bring up a heavy metal testing
is obviously going to be important a lot
now that a lot of these vape carts are
being filled with oil the carts
themselves are being produced from China
which doesn't really have a lot of heavy
metal testing so contamination levels
that we're seeing in vape cars I mean
there's just not a lot of data right now
and I think it's an extremely big risk
well it's interesting that you bring up
vape cartridges because they're they're
putting substances in the in the vape
cartridges like peg and we don't know
what the long-term risks are of inhaling
peg I mean it's it's not a good chemical
and there's nobody overseeing that
anywhere which is really scary to me so
that's a separate issue though so if we
were to put in place certain standards
right now I mean clearly we need to know
accurate potency right because we want
to avoid overdosing as far as
contaminants what would be so the the
0.1 parts-per-million for arsenic
Michael is I think that's in the a HP
and the USP and it's it's okay with them
but now I'm hearing you say that that's
too high it's pretty high I mean based
off of some of the food studies that we
do is once you get into prop 65 went to
buy that out props to c5 once you get
into serving size you know people are
eating grams and you know mini grams of
this stuff it adds up pretty quick
that's why you need to see lower that's
the reason right so I mean that's that's
actually pretty scary to me because
that's the standard that almost everyone
everywhere follows the 0.1 parts per
million for for arsenic yeah where we
look down at point zero zero one okay
that's our MDL okay so in Canada we we
can't use pesticides because the
government can't regulate the pesticides
right they haven't decided what's an
acceptable pesticide to use on cannabis
so we use none here the EPA has not
really put out a list for which
pesticides are okay to use in at what
levels so does that mean we should be
not be using pesticides at all I don't
think so there's some naturally derived
pesticides that have definitely been a
readily widespread and available I think
you in California put out a list of
acceptable pesticides are they not
California did yeah so really in the way
okay um I have something to contribute
to your previous question of where shall
we start and I think it follows back to
Mike's answers we should just all start
with validation proper full validation
because there aren't any standard
methods available to use and to be
accredited for in in the nation and so
we have to develop our own methods
in-house and yet those validated and a
third-party body to oversee that would
be going for accreditation to get
accreditation to get an international
standard accreditation you have to go
through an accredited body that
accreditation body
a part of a bigger national body that
oversees competency that oversees
accuracy precision of of labs of testing
labs including cannabis labs and so if
we start with a robust validation
program for any of our methods
pesticides heavy metals even potency and
then we a part of that validation is
also a robust proficiency test and that
feeds back to your certified reference
materials that need for that then that
would get the ball rolling with all of
us at least measuring the same thing the
same way all together right so you're
talking about proficiency testing which
the state could even oversee
theoretically because you're allowed to
develop your own methods you just have
to show that you get the same result
every time you use your methods but for
the common so how many of you have a
schedule one DEA license or do you need
one in order to get the you know there
are commercially available reference
standards and and are you using those
you see anyone using those do they
require a Schedule one DEA license so
there are actually commercially
available reference standards that you
don't need a DEA license with as long as
it's in a concentration of a thousand
milligrams per mil or less so that's
what most of the testing laboratories
are using right now there's also the
Emerald scientific has also started
putting out reference standards that are
in a hemp bud matrix so basically if it
has less than 0.3 percent THC it's not
technically unlawful to ship across
state lines although it's a really big
gray area but I think that's a really
good step forward because of proficiency
tests in the past basically only just
been these vials of reference standards
at certain concentrations and at that
point you're really just testing out
where your machine is all you have to do
is dilute it and put it in but it
doesn't evaluate your sample preparation
method at all which is probably more
than half of the reason that there are
so many disparate results so it's among
labs not only that a sample collection
is a really big deal if you're not
collecting the sample and a
statistically valid and representative
manner
then you're not going to get the same
result so we have about ten minutes left
and I think I'll open it up to questions
hi there I would my name is Dianne
Strauss and I'm a part of the a member
of the hemp roundtable I'm not sure if
you guys are familiar with the hemp our
own table or not but the hemp roundtable
has put forth a great great amount of
resources to produce a hemp
certification program that has been
created by where food comes from where
food comes from is a an agency that
developed the USDA Organic Standards and
has developed many organics and many
other standards and certification
programs for a lot of the food industry
and it is going to be validated by
validus they are going to be the third
party audit on this program for hemp
producers growers and processors it is
going to be unveiled at HIA in Los
Angeles the HIA show starts I think on
November 2nd or 3rd of this month and it
does address a lot of the things that
we're talking that you guys have been
bringing up and in the hemp industry we
felt that it was imperative that the
industry itself started studying
standards so that people could have
confidence and safety and the testing
and in the Processing's of which what in
weight things are being produced and
being offered to the public so soon you
will be able to go it's not quite up yet
the URL and the website for our landing
page to see the standards I'm sure that
they would love to get feedback from any
people on the certification method that
was created it will be an ongoing and an
improving certification program and will
be available January 1st and again my
name is Diane Straus and it'll be I
think it's gonna be it's us hemp
Authority org
u.s. hemp Authority org will be the URL
that will be or you could also go to the
OSM prone table I'm sure there'll be a
link but
you hopefully in those standards can
also be used and the cannabis industry
mean in the THC industry as well even
though this is specifically certifying
to show that it is less than 0.3 and it
has the GMP standards that are going to
be needed from from grower all the way
from seed to processing thank you you
sure hi my name is David sure I own a
specialty chemical company dealing with
chromatography so we work with you know
you want to know about the process and
the best way to to deal with that I
think it's the stationary phase people
that make sample prep products that you
need to work with those who make us b'e
cartridges those who make the analytical
instruments such as shimasu and working
with them to define the best methods for
sample prep because that is right now
one of the biggest problems that we've
seen in trying to determine proper
concentration of pesticides etc but my
company right now is defining a true
method for decontaminating pesticides
from cannabis extracts so we're
currently in an alpha stage with that
and currently go into a beta stage so
I'd love to speak with any of you to
talk about that but right now you've
made a good point you've got the highest
quality of analytical testing equipment
and consumables for you guys to do the
best work the challenge is how to
successfully use them and you brought at
a great point about sample prep I mean
right now we're sending samples to
different labs the same sample getting
different results so when you have that
just as something for pesticides besides
concentration of THC CBD and other
compounds within that it is it is a
challenge but I go to the state the
people that make chromatography products
we're one of them so we can help you in
defining those methods so anyway I just
want to bring that up but there is a
process that we're making for you to
understand for total decontamination of
pesticides from the extracts while
maintaining the integrity of the
cannabinoids
so I'd like to talk with you guys after
thank you thank you hey thanks guys for
mentioning method validation I think
that's really important in the interim
until we get some actual standards in
this industry but I had a question about
if you see any usefulness in round-robin
testing as a way to you know compare
labs either within a state I guess it's
difficult to do that across states at
this point but could you just comment on
you know the the role you might see or
not see for round-robin testing I think
it's great round robins are a great
exercise it really shows Delta's between
you know different results and kind of
going back to is a result your his eye
response on you know getting good sample
prep you know doing that size or even
something as simple as metals you know
if you have o oil you have to get it
into like an aqueous form and being able
to do that is not very simple but yeah I
do think there there is something there
yeah but we have to have someone who's
run round robins before to do this the
trick is that you have to somehow do
something similar across state lines and
then be able to bring all data together
or be you know just you know if you're
okay with just having a state round
robin I you have to kind of make that
decision if you're okay with it
but Timmy I think is great to be able to
do that
the good thing about the hemp thing
though is if we're able to ship across
state lines because we've been doing it
but the good thing about him is that
point three percent is a lot you know in
terms of instrumentation you know humans
can see so much lower than that so you
can make tons of standards at point
three percent so no there is something
to that to be able to do a round robin
even at that level to be able to show
even on a difficult matrix that
laboratories can see similar results or
not and then based off of that
information be able to know exactly
where you need to target for improvement
I think there's also a technical
difficulty in doing a round robin it's
that basically having a single reference
material that's fully homogenized and
can actually be shipped across state
lines it's really hard like how do I
find a butane hash oil sample with exact
same amount of butane and how can I ship
that to other labs to
among my results so it's definitely
going to be helpful but there it's
definitely challenging right now I think
the round-robin testing or ring test is
I'm used to calling them is definitely a
really good idea the thing that is that
we're seeing at least in within certain
states like I know that recently there
was a publisher publication out in the
journal Nature that took a look at all
the Washington State labs and took a
look at the potency results and you saw
quite a bit of variance between the labs
and you could always pinpoint you know
where a certain result came from and I
think that comes down to you know well I
was a sample of being prepped how how is
the instrument being calibrated what
instrumentation are you using and being
able to see you know the distribution of
how people report the results is
definitely very important and I think
that should be implemented that was just
a sample of Washington state cannabis
testing laboratories but I think
something like that should be
implemented across nationally to take a
look at you know how our state's
performing between each other and who's
reporting the more accurate result as an
internal auditor I would say yes do a
round robin the standard for ISO says
for in-house develop methods you either
had to partake in proficiency testing or
inter lab intra lab professor
proficiency testing where appropriate so
going for accreditation you really have
to plan this out if you're doing round
robins especially with your accrediting
officer for them to understand that this
industry does have a lack of resources
like reference materials we are strapped
with our hands around our back when it
comes to shipping samples even within
state and so it has to be very robust
and for proper validation do not skip
out on proficiency testing no matter
what no matter how you can do it one
minute okay so my question is well it's
more of a suggestion I would say you
talked about MIPS and how they come in
all different forms whether they be
gummies candies I mean basically now
they're putting it into anything they
can find why not test the starting
product whether it
the oil or what-have-you that goes into
the mitt instead of the final product so
then you don't have to develop all these
different methods for all these
different matrices if you were to test
what's going into it at the start and
then know if it's contaminate it's a
free of pesticides or microbials just
that's one way we could do it and then
you would have to have a two-part
testing setup right so you could test
the oil for contaminants but then in the
final product you still have to go back
to testing for potency yeah and then you
don't actually know if the other
ingredients that they're putting in in
it is also safety tested so either way
you'd probably have to test it again I
mean there could be pesticides and the
non cannabis ingredients they use which
is something we've seen a lot in other
products it's as for a company with our
vertically integrated labs it's
important to test from conception of a
product all the way to the end result
especially when you're in getting
materials from vendors question of
Enders China and whatnot it's important
to test from the beginning you go
through such a strategist process of
getting to your gummy bears or whatnot
which does require heat and require a
lot of manipulation it's advantageous to
monitor your whole process through
manufacturing production using objective
evidence by testing at every step to see
if there's a part here you need a
troubleshoot but at the end of the step
especially depending upon which state
state regulations require you to also
provide information on the final product
so it's important to not only do
beginning and end
but advantageous to do throughout the
whole process thank you very much