[Music]
hey everyone Ben here with a quick
announcement the CED Coffee Talk podcast
is currently on Hiatus so the team can
reset and recharge following the camed
24 Innovation and investment Summit we
will be back with brand new episodes
starting July 10th so hang tight we
already have some great guests lined up
that I think you're really going to
enjoy but in the meantime I invite you
to check out any past episodes you may
have missed they are all available at
camed events.com as well as your
favorite podcast app and please be sure
to check out all the video recordings of
the past canmed presentations in the
canmed archive at canmed events
we will be adding the videos from the
CED 24 Summit to the archive very
shortly so be sure to sign up for email
alerts to get the notification when
those go up and be one of the first to
know when we announce details about
camed
25 so that's it we'll see you back here
in July
[Music]
a