foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can Med conference
Happy New Year I hope you had a safe and
happy holiday season and I hope you were
able to have some time off maybe get
recharged and you're ready to take on
2023. I know that our team is excited
for this year as I record this we are
just over five months away from the can
Med 23 Innovation and investment Summit
it's an invitation only three-day event
that will feature intensive industry
workshops and more than 30 presenters
covering the latest Innovations in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing
it all takes place at the Marriott Marco
Island Beach Resort in Florida May 15th
through 17th that's a new venue for us
and with it comes a lot of outstanding
amenities including three miles of white
sand beach world-class spa and golf and
much more
head over to Kim and events.com now to
learn more about Cam med23 and request
your invitation
and while you're there be sure to also
sign up for email alerts we will be
sharing the first round of Cam Med 23
oral presenters very shortly as well as
some additional information about our
industry workshops so stay tuned
my guest today is Dr Addie Ray
Addie is a neuroscientist known for her
extensive expertise on cannabis she is
an assistant scientist at Legacy
Research Institute in adjunct faculty at
Washington State University
her human and pre-clinical research is
focused on pain management addiction and
harm reduction
Addie has published in top Act
Eddie has published in top academic
journals under the surname Wilson Poe
and she is passionate about the
interaction between cannabis and opioids
our conversation focused on a paper
Addie recently co-authored called the
nose nose Aroma but not THC mediates
subjective effects of smoked and
vaporized cannabis flour
as the title suggests the study found
that users subjective enjoyment of a
cannabis flower's Aroma was correlated
with that flower producing a pleasant
effect for the user or more simply put
if you like the smell
or more simply put if you like the way a
cannabis flower smells you're going to
like the way it makes you feel
during our conversation we discuss the
subjective
the subjectivity of cannabis aroma
whether the ability to predict a
positive experience through Aroma is
learned or intuitive
how closed container markets do a
disservice to Consumers
how the study found that the amount of
THC in a cultivar did not correlate with
positive user experience and what that
means for the industry
the difference between feeling high and
feeling good and the importance of
Tolerance breaks
before we get to my conversation with Dr
Addie Ray I want to thank this episode
sponsor Advanced Nutrients
founded in 1999 Advanced Nutrients was
the first to develop a complete nutrient
system that unlocks the true genetic
potential of the cannabis plant
since its Inception the brand has
introduced more than 50 Innovations to
the cultivation community and continues
to revolutionize the space through
proprietary scientific discoveries learn
more at advancenutrients.com
foreign
[Music]
thanks so much for joining us on the
podcast it's a pleasure to be here Ben
thanks
yeah I mean I'm really excited to talk
with you today about a paper that you
co-authored called the nose nose Aroma
but not THC mediates the subjective
effects of smoked and vaporized cannabis
flour
fascinating paper to me because it
really challenges this idea that THC
potency determines cannabis flower
quality it's something that's come up
many times on this podcast so I'm happy
to see some some data confirming this
um there's a lot of great information in
the paper I marked up my copy quite a
bit and I'm providing a link to the
paper in the show description so the
listeners can read it as well but before
we get too deep into it I wanted to ask
you why did you and your co-authors
decide to take on this study and what
questions were you looking to answer
highlight is that the study the paper is
actually a byproduct of the actual
purpose for the work because the purpose
for the work was a couple of weed cups
it was you know cannabis competitions
and the purpose there of course was to
identify objectively the best cannabis
in Oregon so truly using the most
rigorous scientific tools we could to
really identify high quality cannabis
and then reward those cultivators for
producing that cannabis so that was the
original intent behind all of the work
as a result of doing those cannabis
competitions here in Oregon
um we were able to you know come up with
this big Anonymous database which then
we could you know mine post hoc for all
of the insights that you see in the
paper
um so it was really important for my
teammates and I um and I'll highlight
them specifically stuff Barnhart
Jeremy Plum among many others it really
was a community effort to use the best
tool possible to Define quality cannabis
excellent so now you said this you
collected the state over over several
years or several events how did your
criteria for determining quality
cannabis change as you as you did this
she really sat down to think about what
are the components that we are trying to
analyze here right what questions are we
going to ask of our volunteers who are
sampling the Cannabis and you know
it it's kind of no-brainer stuff it's
really you know like how much did you
enjoy this we always knew that Aroma was
important so we asked how pleasant was
the aroma
and then we also asked questions about
the sort of large domains that cannabis
is well known for right like is it
energizing or sleepy does it make you
feel relaxed or tense you know really
you know not rocket science it's really
all the things that all of the reasons
that consumers are using cannabis to
begin with
um that's what we were looking at
um so that that's the human sort of data
collection end of things and then on the
other end too you know we wanted as much
information about the plant as we could
you know at that time so
widest panel of analytes in terms of
cannabinoids and terpenes
um and you know of course our
understanding of this plant and the
aromatic molecules that contribute to
its Aroma have evolved a lot since we
last collected data
um in you know 2019-2020
um but nevertheless it was really
important for us to have high fidelity
human information and High Fidelity
plant information and see just literally
it's a fishing Expedition what is the
data going to tell us so it's really
liberating in this that you know most of
my academic research is of course
hypothesis oriented so it was really
liberating to have a true Expedition and
tell a data-driven story allow the data
to tell us what's important about
cannabis
yeah I know and it sounds like so you're
collecting two different types of data
as you mentioned you know on The Human
Side what was your experience with this
and then you know on the lab side you
know what are the the percentages and
the numbers here so so I imagine you
tried to marry the two
um to try to find some patterns and that
and that's sort of what you're doing in
the paper here yes exactly and what you
don't see in the paper are all of the
results that are not so exciting so so
you know one of the things of course we
are super interested in is you know what
is this Entourage effect you know what
evidence do we have that a combination
of molecules is somehow contributing to
some domain of The Human Experience and
despite our best efforts to put it
through machine learning models and you
know apply all of these like really
rigorous techniques to the data it spat
out a couple of things one of which was
thca is important
well yeah we we kind of already knew
that so
you know um we didn't find you know any
one terpene for example that was you
know strongly associated with any one
particular domain of the of The Human
Experience
um so you know despite our best efforts
to look for those things and prove or
disprove those sort of urban legends
that are floating around out there you
know mere seeing being
um sedative for example our data didn't
support that
um so so yeah we we we weren't able to
really hone in on any one particular
molecule as being the driving factor in
the Cannabis experience other than
knowing that you know thca the the you
know decarboxylated version or the
carboxyl
um of THC
um we already knew that was important
contributes to the psychoactive
properties
right no and it's interesting that you
mentioned terpenes because you know
we talk about chirpings a lot and how
they're important and how they you know
differentiate the Cannabis cultivars but
really I mean you're not the first
person that I've talked to that said
that you know they looked for a
connection between terpenes and
experience or even you know therapeutic
applications but they're not really
finding it
um you know why do you think that is or
do you think that you know terpenes are
a bit of a a red herring here what's
what's going on yeah yeah I think that
the most likely what's going on and I
you know of course this is just one of
many possibilities but what's likely
going on is that things are a lot more
complicated than we would like them to
be
so we're looking for the easy answers
and
um it's probably not an easy answer
one of the cool opportunities that I had
in sort of digging through the
literature to prepare this manuscript
was getting really really deep into the
sensory sciences and and you know even
like looking really deep into fine
fragrances perfumes consumer fragrances
that kind of stuff and that body of
literature is you know very mature and
there's lots of cool artificial
intelligence models for Aroma you know
predictions and stuff like that
um but what I came to understand and
there is a citation in the paper was
that the presence of even a single
additional aromatic molecule totally
changes our perception of an aroma and
if that's true for just your olfactory
epithelium the inside your nose what
else is happening higher up all the way
up in your brain and especially you know
in the really sophisticated circuits in
our prefrontal cortex so if we know that
you know the presence of even one other
molecule can totally change our
experience of a product then that's
probably what's going on it's probably
just such a complicated and
um a situation that's so difficult to
replicate time after time that there's
you know we're we're really at the
limits of our technology right we simply
don't have the tools to process all of
the information better than our brains
already do which is to say this smells
good right
right and that was I mean I mean we've
kind of been beating around the bush
here but that was sort of the main
finding of your paper right is that you
know what smells good to the user is
usually predictive of what is going to
create a good experience for them
exactly exactly and that subjective
component I think is really important to
highlight you know we do show some data
in the paper where there is if we look
at the variability in people's responses
or you know their ratings for the
pleasantness of the aroma
um so there are some flowers where they
have a high you know score they're
really great smelling flowers and those
great smelling flowers there's a lot of
consensus people agree there's low
variability in terms of the aroma score
but the further you get away from like
the you know top 20 percent of great
smelling flowers the more polarizing
they are so you know on the far end
where we have some flowers with low
Aroma scores there's a huge degree of
variability some people love them and
some people don't
and so the analogy that I think about
all the time again coming back to
perfume because I think it's the the
most
comparison is that you know we can all
agree that this super expensive you know
like designer perfume at this specialty
perfume house we can all agree oh my God
this thing smells amazing it's like you
know Ambrosia
um whereas if we're walking through the
mall and there's someone's you know
spraying something cheap into the air
that one might be a little more
polarizing right there might be some of
us that would be like oh yeah I'd wear
that and others would be like no no no
don't get near me right so I think
that's a really nice comparison
um because it tells us that it really is
subjective that
um there's some degree of consensus if
you have a really great smelling flower
you know the breeder or the wholesaler
or a bud tender might be able to say
okay these three are the best smelling
ones
um but there is absolutely
um
objective component where a consumer
must be able to make a decision for
themselves based on their own sensory
perception of that flower
right and now I'm curious too
um and we could talk a bit about you
know how what the profile of the
different users are whether they're
daily users and things I know there's a
lot of information about that but do you
think that what's going on is that
people are smelling something familiar
you know it might be similar to a strain
that they've used in the past and
they're associating that with a positive
experience or is it just truly
um you know intuitive where like oh I
like this smell and you know it just so
happens that that's what their body
wants yeah I my my hypothesis and you
know I'm a neuroscientist and my my
field is definitely not the sensory
Sciences so maybe someone with that
my hypothesis is the latter that it's
just intuitive right like when you're
walking down the street that reaction
you have when you smell the you know
Falafel Cart on the sidewalk right that
reaction that you have is not something
that you're like oh that reminds me of
that one time that I was in New York
City you know for New Year's Eve
whatever you know like it's an intuitive
like it it's it strums the instrument
within your heart you know like you
don't have to think about it there's a
reaction there
um and sometimes it's like uh you know
like gross or sometimes it's really
appealing so I think that Aroma is
really interesting because all of the
olfactory processes and the evolution of
um being able to smell things in the
environment interpret those
environmental cues as either a cue to
approach or avoid something that's
really really deeply buried in our
medulla and and you know that's really
old circuitry that is conserved across
you know the phylogenetic tree so my
sense is that there is like low level
you know intuitive or or you know sort
of automatic kind of processing that
happens with Aroma that we don't
necessarily need to put much conscious
thought into
interesting so if instead of looking at
you know THC percentages or terpene
percentages when we're evaluating which
cannabis to buy we should really be
getting our nose in there and giving it
a smell absolutely that is I think the
biggest take-home message for all of The
Regulators in states where there are
closed container laws so in Oregon you
know I'm here in Portland and we have
the benefit of having you know deli
style
um
um dispensaries so you can literally
walk into any store and stick your nose
in an ounce it's great
um but that benefit doesn't occur in
California and in Washington
um and it's really in those closed
container markets where The Regulators
have done a serious disservice to the
consumers because they have robbed them
of the only information that we have to
make a really great decision about what
to buy
yeah and now is that in place for you
know sanitary reasons or is that the
thinking
the most likely answer is probably just
a law enforcement one right it's just a
matter of keeping things tightly under
control
um it's you know I I wasn't there when
they made those rags in Washington so I
can't say what those motivations were
um but I can say that you know it's it's
not you know those sort of package only
markets are problematic not only from
the perspective of you know being devoid
of Aroma but is excessive packaging also
which is like I'm sure an entirely
different podcast but but yeah it's
unnecessary
yeah and so going back to this whole
idea of you know sort of the the
quantitative results that we often see
on packaging or on websites um is not as
informative as as just smelling um one
of the some of the results from your
paper were showing that you know THC
potency was not correlated with
subjective appeal and you know the the
amount of terpenes present wasn't either
I was wondering if you could talk a bit
more about that I would be so delighted
to them as my favorite Topic in the
whole wide world all right let's do it
um so right now and there are very good
reasons for
THC is the primary marker of quality
cannabis right
and you know this has roots both in the
Legacy Market you know in the
prohibition days there are you know sort
of black market drug dynamics that
contribute to why people who produce
drugs want to make them as strong as
they can
so there's that Legacy that has carried
over into this regulated environment and
in this regulated environment there has
been a push toward more and more potent
products right demand for high THC
products has been high so then you know
the supply chain responds by producing
high THC products and so you have this
feed forward cycle where everyone is
producing where what they think the
costs what they think the customer wants
and the customer thinks they want THC
when in fact our paper demonstrates that
you know the amount of THC is really
irrelevant I I'm not at all you know our
data doesn't support and I don't think
that THC is irrelevant you know it's
very obvious that there is a
relationship between THC and
psychoactive effects that's what gets
you high
however there is not a linear
relationship between how much THC and
how much enjoyment there is so so that
brings up another topic which is this
distinction between getting high and
feeling good because you know there is a
therapeutic window there's a sweet spot
where you do need THC to feel something
but if you have too much THC the
negative effects outweigh the beneficial
effects so you know that there is an
assumption that more THC is better more
THC is high quality more THC is a better
value
um and there's this you know like ever
escalating push toward more and more THC
which is not an evidence-based approach
because this this data tells us that
yeah THC is going to get you high but
it's not necessarily going to make you
feel good
right no and I I always think it's
interesting that you know this push for
more and more potent cannabis more
higher percentages of THC
um I mean and if you look at alcohol I
mean that's just it's not the case you
know people aren't going to the liquor
store and buying Everclear or just
drinking straight ethanol like it's it's
more of an experience about the flavor
and you know everything else that comes
with it
um it's just interesting that cannabis
hasn't gotten there yet
exactly and and I like that the fact
that you use the word yet because I
think that we have an opportunity here
right this is a wake-up call that it's
time to diversify the spend the
dispensary Shelf
you know like right now the way that the
retail Marketplace looks it looks very
much like going into a bar that has 37
flavors of Everclear right and so if we
think about well what what does what
does the consumer actually want versus
what do they think they want so what
they actually want is probably diversity
they want to try a bunch of different
stuff because there are a bunch of
different kinds of experiences that are
possible with cannabis it's really
interesting that you know alcohol it
really is a great comparison because
we have a pretty
um
narrow band of responses to alcohol
everyone knows what it feels like if
you're over 21. everyone knows what it
feels like to have one drink or have a
little buzz or to be drunk or to be too
drunk right like those are all very
there's a lot of consensus around what
those things feel like but with cannabis
it's far less clear that what I'm
experiencing is what you're experiencing
and you know it's very common that you
might be at a party or something and
people are passing a j around and some
people are talkative and fine and keep
taking toke after toke and others are
very quiet and sitting on the couch by
themselves right so we know that even
even the literal same joint has
different effects in different people so
you know I think that this this paper
really demonstrates that we owe it to
our consumers to give them choices right
we want them to have ipas and you know
naturally naturally fermented skin
contact white wines and you know we also
need Commodities like Anheuser-Busch you
know whatever you know that we just need
to have a range of choices
um and that those choices a consumers
should be able to choose on the base
absolutely yo and you brought up a great
point when you were talking about how
you know the same joint can have
different effects on different people
and it it made me curious too going back
to your results here and people who were
rating cannabis for the pleasurable
effects were those pleasurable
effects actually subjective too meaning
did people
were they looking for an energetic High
versus a sleepy high like was there
differences there too that you sort of
had to layer in yeah that's a great
question so the the anchoring question
that we used for our volunteers was what
do you consider a good cannabis
experience right and so we gave them a
range of answers from I don't want to
feel anything at all I want to feel
totally normal to I want to be so high
that it's almost uncomfortable so they
have you know some choices in between
there and regardless of you know their
age or how frequently they consume
cannabis the vast majority of people
reported that they wanted a prominent
shift from their normal State of
Consciousness so regardless of people's
tolerance or or you know the products
they prefer or their experience with
cannabis or any other factors most
people are looking to feel
quite a bit different than their normal
daily life
so so that's that's the way that we sort
of typified you know what what the yeah
what the volunteers look like
and another thing that that stood out to
me when I was reading the paper was that
smaller amounts of cannabis consumed
actually had better subjective appeal
the answer to this it probably has
something to do with the fact that
people self titrate how much cannabis
they use so Carrie Cutler at Washington
State University is a wonderful like
mine she's shown this very elegantly by
having people smoke and take dabs over
Zoom calls and
um she shows that you know
people who are using higher more more
potent products they tend to take fewer
Puffs and hold it in less amount of time
so there seems to be you know this
effect where people especially because
you know this is a double-blind
evaluation so people don't know the the
strength of the products they're trying
and so
um probably what's happening is that you
know they'll pack a small bowl or you
know light the end of a joint and take
one puff and kind of see where they are
and then they stop because they're happy
where they are so it may be you know an
artifact in the data that you know the
vast majority of people just smoked very
small amounts of cannabis and of course
you know wherever the data is stacked
that's where you're going to find all of
those results
uh okay that makes sense
um uh another thing here the less
frequent cannabis users reported better
subjective uh scores yes this was really
interesting
um and I this is really a mystery to me
I don't I don't have a hypothesis for
why this might be you know in the
process of the peer review our referees
asked us well is this because of
Tolerance is it because these these
these no
um they're able to register the pleasant
effects of cannabis because they're not
using it as often
um and that could be contributing to
some extent but we also asked all of our
participants to take a 48-hour tolerance
break before they started their kits and
we also gave them at least 30 days to
complete you know all of the samples
between 8 and 10 seconds couples
um and it was just it's just you know we
might have had a handful of Judges who
you know were all we're already daily
users
one day after the other but you know
most of the people in the study like the
vast majority
um you know a spaced amount really
nicely and they adhered you know more
than 80 of the people adhered to the
tolerance breaks sort of guidance so I
don't necessarily think tolerance
entirely explains that phenomenon
um I think it might
you know if I had to like if I'm if
you're gonna put me on the spot to give
you an answer I would say it's maybe
just like
you know it's the idea that it's not a
party if it happens every day yeah it's
just more special if it is you know not
as often
um we our brains habituate to our
environments and our you know um our
situations and it just might not feel as
special or fun or cool if it happens
more frequent
yeah no and I think that the whole idea
of Tolerance too it's a bit of a
double-edged sword where if you if
you're taking breaks you might be more
sensitive to the positive aspects of
cannabis but you're also more sensitive
to the negative aspects too with the
paranoia anxiety or anything like that
Bingo exactly and this is actually
something that we actively work with
with our chronic pain patients so in my
other studies you know we work with
um you know people who are starting to
use cannabis to manage their Orthopedic
pain and it's a process of developing
enough tolerance to reap the medical
benefits of cannabis because of course
you know initially for for some of our
folks and this these are also you know a
lot of older folks with Orthopedic you
know issues arthritis and you know hip
replacements and things and um you know
growing up in the Nixon era of
prohibition I I you know it's no wonder
that they're hesitant
we specifically go through a sort of
ramp up the start low go slow kind of
mentality
um is the best way to get our patients
up to a level of you know THC
consumption that sufficiently eliminates
their pain but they've built up enough
of a sort of psychological tolerance to
it that they're in a comfortable
headspace
yeah and it it's funny you bring that up
I've been looking through
some videos from our press past kamed
conference getting ready for for the one
that's coming up and I was looking at a
presentation from Dr Dustin sulak that
was part of our medical practicum and
and he was talking about this you know
that therapeutic window and you know you
need to get up to a point where you're
feeling the effects
um but you don't want to necessarily
exceed that either or else you know you
can kind of get to a point of
diminishing returns and then you have to
actually you know take a step back or
lower the dose which is sort of
counter-intuitive
um so it's sort of interesting how you
need to really find that sweet spot I
absolutely you know Dustin and I are
very close colleagues we see you know
eye to eye on this issue and that idea
of the therapeutic window for our
patients is not exclusive to our
patients you know but for for the adult
use Market I tend to refer to it as the
sweet spot right you got to stay in your
sweet spot and if your tolerance has
gotten so high that you can't get up
into The Sweet Spot anymore then it's
time for a tolerance break and our
brains are remarkably responsive to
tolerance
you know like
um that I haven't seen quite enough
literature to satisfy me on on all of my
hypotheses around tolerance but um but
from all of the you know the limited
literature there is and all of the heaps
of anecdotal data that are out there
taking a tolerance break really works
excellent all right 80. um before I let
you go I wanted to give you a chance to
um plug any other resources related to
this that you think that our listeners
would like to read up more about or any
of your own social media or websites or
anything like that please let me know
and I'll put it in the show notes sure
on Instagram I'm at Dr period 80. Edie
um Dr period Adie
um so that's that's probably the the
easiest way to get a hold of me or to
find out you know what other work I'm
I'm producing
um and uh let's see I would say that in
general other things that I you know
think might be timely to highlight are
just the fact that
um you know right now we're speaking in
mid-December and there is a ton of
outdoor flower that's curing and
um that's gonna hit the dispensary
shelves you know probably early January
and outdoor flower in particular because
the outdoor environment is so you know
diverse and unpredictable that means the
chemistry in those outdoor flowers tends
to be more diverse also so
um if you're a cannabis consumer and
you're listening to this I would
encourage you to you know ask your bud
tender which smell the best and which
ones were grown outside and just
especially support your regenerative
Farms
excellent excellent well 80. thank you
again for joining me this was a great
great conversation and I hope we get to
do it again soon yeah I think
[Music]
hope you enjoyed my conversation with Dr
80 Ray check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode's sponsor Advanced
Nutrients our next episode drops January
18th that's two weeks from today in the
meantime please do check out the new and
improved canmanevents.com the team
really did an exceptional job updating
the website with all the information
about our kammed 23 event and of course
you can still find videos of all the
previous can Med presentations and
panels in the can bed archive you can
also find all the previous episodes of
the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this Innovative industry-leading
event I also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on Instagram Facebook Twitter and
Linkedin just search for Cannon events
and lastly please leave us a review on
Apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us on
the next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]
foreign