okay good evening
good day good morning who knows anymore
right we're in this cold dark room i
don't know
uh i'm gonna try to be funny but this is
actually a really serious subject and
something that's very near and dear to
my heart
i had the great pleasure of starting a
cannabis practice in 2014
and at that time
i had
some early adopters in the assisted
living community who
wanted to consider using cannabis for
their residents and
one of my very first patients was one of
my most successful and most profound
experiences
that i had
and for those of you who've heard me
talk before you'll probably remember
this story but
i met lucy when she was 89 years old
and she had been diagnosed with advanced
stage dementia and her daughter who was
her durable power of healthcare said i'd
really like to try to get my mom off of
these pain medications she was taking an
exorbitant amount of
antipsychotics gabapentin and opioids to
try to manage her pain and her pain
wasn't managed she'd suffered from
multiple sclerosis as well as migraines
for over 40 years
so we began working with her
and i did a very low dose 2.5 milligrams
of thc and cbd three times a day
and within a month we were able to wean
her off all of her medications that were
related to her pain
and she started to become more cognizant
she was more aware she was really
exhibiting signs that her dementia was
no longer an issue for her
and her daughter had actually never told
her that she was going to be using
cannabis she said mom there's a
supplement i want you to use and she had
the right to make that decision for her
mom
and so one day one of the med techs came
and knocked on the door to deliver lucy
her cannabis
and she said lucy i have your marijuana
and lucy was now at this time she had
turned 90 and she was about a 4 foot 11
petite french woman from france
and she said oh no
i don't do the marijuana
so um we were like okay i guess it's
time to tell lucy what's been helping
her
so we had a conversation with lucy she
was so successful in her
use of cannabis we actually were able to
get her diagnosis of dementia removed
from her medical record
and she continued to do well she's 94
years old
and
that's why i do what i do
so for those of you who don't know me or
don't recognize me that is me
pre-pandemic
my name is eloise thiessen i'm an adult
geriatric primary care nurse
practitioner prior to coming into
cannabis i've been in mostly oncology
and palliative care
the average age of my patient is 76 i've
worked now with over 7 500 patients who
want to use cannabis as a treatment
modality and i have a small niche of
dementia patients
97 or 90 of my patients have never used
it before so their cannabis naive
predominantly female they don't want to
smoke it they don't want to get high i
mean if they're not dementia related
they're usually coming to me for pain or
sleep
these are my disclosures
these are some of the learning outcomes
that we're going to talk about today
i am going to be starting a new job at
stanford next month in the outpatient
palliative care department and
they did hire me because of my cannabis
background so i'm really excited to be
able to bring this expertise
into uh into that community and
hopefully change hearts and minds but as
we all know i probably am being overly
idealistic
um but hopefully we'll get there
so dementia at a glance we know it's an
age-related it's an irreversible
condition and it results in
progressively
progressive cognitive decline that
impairs a person's ability to perform
activities of daily living
and the clinical manifestations can be
things like memory loss impaired
judgment depression mental deterioration
and they often will have what we call
neuropsychiatric symptoms that typically
will manifest in the later stages and
that's what i'm going to focus on today
is the work that i do with these
neuropsychiatric symptoms
dementia is now the seventh leading
cause of death and one of the major
causes of disability and dependency
among older people and in 2019 the
estimated costs related to men to
dementia was 1.3 trillion
u.s dollars and we expect this to reach
2.8 trillion us dollars by 2030.
it's funny i'm like trying to click my
laptop here so bear with me we have
different types of dementia
alzheimer's disease compromises 60
percent of cases and what i'm going to
talk a lot
i'm going to talk about alzheimer's and
dementia today
most of my patients in their chart are
diagnosed with alzheimer's even though
they haven't actually had imaging to
confirm that diagnosis
and we also see vascular dementia which
is often comes from
cerebral vascular disease
lewy bodies disease and parkinson's
frontotemporal lobal lobar degeneration
hippocampal sclerosis and mixed
pathologies those are the different
types of dementia we'll see
in 2021 65 and older people with
dementia will be about 58 million in the
united states only and we expect this to
reach 88 million by 2050.
and this year in 2022
65 and older with alzheimer's disease
yes
yeah no
still the wrong one
okay
we know that one in nine people over the
age of 65 have alzheimer's disease
and just to break that down about 27
percent are between 65 and 74.
um 37 are between 75 and 84 years old
and 35 are 85 and older
and by 2050 we expect to see 12.7
million people over the age of 65
diagnosed with alzheimer's disease so
it's only getting worse
there are seven different stages
according to the global deterioration
scale
and i just want to give some context
here because most of my patients come to
me in stage five through seven so stage
one is actually no dementia
or cognitive decline so i find that
fascinating um stage two is very mild so
this is usually age related right you
might be forgetting
a name or something like that you get to
stage three that's mild cognitive
decline and this is usually when other
people are noticing that you're having
some memory issues so you may be
performing poorly at work you may get
lost in certain locations
then we're going to get to stage four
this is often described as mild
dimension when i work with patients
who've gone through
you know a neurology
consultation they're usually described
in mild moderate moderate to severe and
severe they don't actually use these
stages
but we know in moderate you often you'll
see that they're starting to have a loss
of current events they're not as
knowledgeable about what's going on
around them maybe they're struggling
with their finances this is where you'll
start to see people have elder abuse
issues where you know they're having
people can take advantage of them with
scams
stage five is usually more moderate
severe cognitive decline and this is
where they're starting to need
assistance this is generally when they
end up in an assisted living community
or maybe the families are starting to
pay for them to have additional help at
home
and then when they get into stages six
and seven they're pretty severe
they're forgetting names of their spouse
at this point they may not recognize
them they may think it's their son or
daughter or other family member
they usually require assistance with
activities of daily living and they're
often incontinent
of bowel and bladder they usually need
help with eating so they might be doing
finger foods all right so in the stage
six and seven
again this is mostly where my patients
at sometimes i get them in that stage
five where they're just
you know needing a little bit of
assistance but not a lot and then of
course by stage seven they're pretty
severely um
demented and often can't even utter more
than a word or two
so what kind of options do we have for
these patients well in my opinion not
great ones we do have some fda approved
drugs that are
you know
supposed to be used for things
treatment of dementia but i just want to
make a point that none of these drugs
actually slow or stop the damage or
destruction of the neurons that cause
alzheimer's disease okay
but we know here that some of these may
actually temporarily improve cognitive
symptoms by increasing neurotransmitters
they may block certain receptors in the
brain from excessive stimulation and
then our newest one there and most
controversial one
claims to possibly slow the progression
of the disease but i do think the jury
is
out on that one
and just some interesting you know
research around well how effective are
these drugs will the acetylcholinase
inhibitors approved for memory
improvement
some of them have very low demonstration
of actually improving cognitive
cognition scores in fact 26 percent
that's our irrecept um and then 30 to 37
and many of my patients when they come
to me and they're stage six and seven of
dementia are still on these medications
so one of the things i like to get them
off as soon as possible so how do we
manage their symptoms
well not well
we use antipsychotics which come with a
black box warning and that black box
warning says well if you use these in a
patient who has dementia they have a
higher risk of death
we use antidepressants we use
anti-anxiety and hypnotic medications
but these are not fda approved so we
have no fda approved pharmaceuticals for
agitation or any of the neuropsychiatric
symptoms in dementia alzheimer's
patients so we'll see things again
agitation restlessness i see screaming
and yelling sleep disturbances sun
downing and wandering
and on very rare occasions i will see an
increase in sexual
um
behaviors as well and that's usually
i'll talk a little bit about that
can be interesting with thc
um common in all types of dementia we'll
see these neuropsychiatric symptoms
like i said they can manifest like
agitation anxiety
aggression depression these are usually
what are the most disruptive to the
assisted living communities the families
and the caregivers
they present significant physical risk
to the patients because they can
actually become violent right they're so
um anxious and agitated they can scratch
they can hit
they can be at risk for falling and
injuring themselves because they'll get
up and
move really quickly
often worse in the afternoon that sun
downing can happen anywhere between 1 pm
and 5 pm
it's poor quality of life and it's
really hard to watch your loved ones
suffer like that
and it's really hard to try to identify
what their needs are especially in
assisted living communities where the
staffing is so low
they don't get the attention that they
need
so first i'm going to talk about
dimension again
on tuesday i mentioned this can of keys
which facilitates access to public
science and aggregated critical data
points when you put in dementia there's
a very few studies actually looking at
dementia
so i want to talk just a little bit
about these studies and it'll be
interesting because when we look at
alzheimer's there's actually quite a bit
more because people ask me all the time
okay how did you figure out what to give
them eloise well there's a little bit of
data out there particularly looking at
synthetic thc
and this was a six week study that was
done in 2018 and it was a small study of
just 39 patients but they used synthetic
delta nine thc i believe it was
dernavanol
and then game of placebo for about six
weeks and they noted that the agitation
was significantly improved in these
patients who had the delta nine thc
complete compared to the placebo
it actually helped with other symptoms
as well shocking right
and this was done in 2014
it was a retrospective systematic chart
review of 40 patients who'd been
diagnosed with dementia again
small sample size but they were using
dronabinol
again found significant improvement in
agitation sleep and eating
this was a study done in 2017 to
determine that chronic low doses of
delta 9 thc restored cognitive function
in old mice
and actually reversed age-related
decline in cognitive performance of mice
aged 12 and 18 months what do you think
the number one
thing that i'll hear from other
clinicians when i want to consider
cannabis in the older adult what do you
think their stigma says
yeah you're going to make their memory
worse
[Laughter]
i'm like really that's our that's our
objective here
delta 9 thc we know binds with cb1
receptors and the restoration of cb1
signaling in older adults might be
effective strategy to treat age-related
cognitive impairments now i focus
predominantly on symptom management my
practice but i will show you a couple
studies about can we use cannabis to
prevent
dementia alzheimer's disease
this study done at harvard in 2016
looked
it was again a very small one but they
found that cognitive function improved
and 24 adults who smoked cannabis for
three months
of course they also reported better
sleep less depression and a significant
decrease in their use of medications
such as opioids
i really do want to use cannabinoids to
describe in my patients
when they're on polypharmacy
so this was a meta-analysis system a
systematic review performed they're
looking to determine the level of
evidence both qualitative and
quantitative to support the efficacy and
safety of using cannabinoids and as a
treatment for neuropsychiatric symptoms
it was actually hard for them to draw a
conclusion so they had nine publications
including data from six clinical trials
with 422 patient treatments psychoactive
cannabinoids or placebo
so they couldn't draw a conclusion
whether or not
the psychoactive cannabinoids were
effective in the treatment of
neuropsychiatric symptoms particularly
agitation and aggression
this is a pilot study done in geneva
only 10 females and actually dementia
does affect females more than males
about 60 to 40 percent
and i definitely see that in my practice
i have more women than
men with dementia
so in these 10 patients they were trying
to
treat their severe behavioral problems
they started out with an oral thc cbd
extract and you can see the progression
here between two two weeks to two months
they did do some dose escalations here
um and ended up with about a two to one
cbd to thc
i keep pushing this so if i fall over
just you know we'll have fun with it
they actually had a 40 reduction in the
cohen mansfield agitation inventory
score after two months with a
cbd two to one thc ratio
another systematic review of clinical
effectiveness and guidelines for medical
cannabis treatment and dementia this was
done in canada and they looked at 12
studies from 97 to 2019 so that included
six randomized controlled trials two
cohorts four case studies for a total of
178 patients 65 years and older and they
had administered cannabinoids including
dronabinol as well as plant derived
delta 9 thc and nabalone which is also
synthetic thc it's known as sesame
and their dosages range from 2.5 to 7.
these are low dosages right so i you
know when dr goldstein was up here
earlier talking about having
poor access to low thc products i have
the same issue
for my older adult patients my dementia
patients it's incredibly hard right now
because i as you'll see i start them on
two milligrams it's hard to find
products i can't do tinctures and i'll
talk about that in a minute why
four of the seven sorry four of the
twelve primary studies noted significant
improvement of the neuropsychiatric
symptoms in the cannabis group
and eight studies didn't find any
evidence to support cannabinoids in the
treatment of dementia so the question
for me here is are we looking at um
issues because there's a
full spectrum versus an isolate here you
know do we see better results and i'm
going to talk about what i see in my
practice
so looking at you know can cannabinoids
actually help in the treatment or
prevention of alzheimer's disease
there's some
pre-clinical research that's promising
we know that cannabinoids have been
shown to cause vasodilation of brain
blood vessels and increased cerebral
blood flow so there's the possibility of
using cannabinoids and alzheimer's
disease where cerebral flow
is decreased and could improve cerebral
perfusion
and there was a study that found cbd
reduced the infarct volume in animal
studies with focal or global cerebral
ischemia and the authors suggested that
cbd could potentially prevent vascular
dementia those patients are incredibly
hard to manage
um
and so are the fronto
temporal lobe dementia patients
so then we have cannabis and alzheimer's
and now look at the research
go back to my dementia slide it was
eight primary studies we have 68 primary
studies when it comes to alzheimer's
disease
so better research here
but again as i said most of my patients
are being diagnosed with alzheimer's
disease but don't necessarily have
the imaging to support that diagnosis so
we know that cbd can demonstrate
neuropath neuroprotective effects
similar to vitamin e and vitamin c so
similar to current pharmacological
options but without the toxicity
but we don't have any studies to
currently examine cannabis as a
treatment for alzheimer's disease in
humans
cbd can inhibit plaque buildup in the
brain and thc competitively binds with
acetylcholine or
acetylcholinesterase
i should have practiced and prevents
plaque buildup
and i need glasses in one study with 78
patients thc reduced nighttime agitation
so again this was gernabinol just at 2.5
milligrams it was all they were giving
of thc over four weeks very low dosages
and this is one of the more famous
studies that people have known about at
the salk institute where they determined
that thc promotes the removal of toxic
clumps of amyloid beta protein in the
brain which is thought to be contributed
to alzheimer's disease although i think
that this is
being reviewed right now as to whether
that's actually true
researchers stated that cannabinoids
might be neuroprotective against the
symptoms of alzheimer's by reducing
inflammation and amyloid beta
accumulation in nerve cells
and i do have a lot of people who come
to me when they
i'm working with their
their family member who want to consider
cannabinoids as a preventative and it's
really hard for me to to work with them
so i won't be focusing on any of that
because again the data is not really
there
and this is a study being done in
australia
and it's going to look at just 50
participants 65 and older with mild
dementia living in assisted living
communities and they're going to use a 3
to 2 thc to cbd oral spray so it'll be
good to see that when that data comes
out
so in my practice now
i've got about 76 patients in california
that have been
predominantly coming from the assisted
living communities again most of them
are 65 of them are female their average
age is 83 by the time they come to me
most of them are diagnosed with
alzheimer's disease about 92 percent
have a small amount of vascular dementia
frontal lobe and lewy body disease
mostly starting their treatment when
they're at stage six or remember they're
pretty dysfunctional at this point they
need a lot of assistance with adls
their typical behaviors are anxiety
agitation aggression obsessive
compulsive behaviors
they're very disruptive right they're in
these assisted living communities
they're yelling out they're walking into
other residents rooms they're yelling at
them and it's it just anxiety causes
more anxiety so sometimes it can just be
very very upsetting
most of them have tried about four
different types of pharmaceuticals to
manage their behaviors before they come
to cannabis and they're often coming to
me because they want to try something
quote unquote more natural something
that may not have as many side effects
the antipsychotics can be very
sedating
and often
zombifying for their loved ones
most the time they are
in an assisted living community about 75
percent those that are not an assisted
living community are trying to keep
their loved ones at home
by managing their behaviors
with cannabis versus pharmaceuticals
um so this is an 83 year old male who
came to me with vascular dementia stage
six he was living at home with his wife
his caregiver came in about four hours a
day he was verbally aggressive and
anxious although i never witnessed it
every time she brought him into my
office he was the nicest politest man
and she would look at me and she said
always i swear i'm not making this up i
said i know i believe you
you can see right here if you look at
his medications his dosages are
incredibly low for what we would
typically prescribe so she had
verbalized with me my father is
incredibly sensitive to medications
and i said okay and she said that's why
i'm terrified of putting him on any of
these antipsychotics i want to try
cannabis i said okay
so we started out with a 10 to 1 cbd
very very small improvements that we saw
and i thought okay
i like thc in these neuropsychiatric
symptoms so let's let's increase his thc
a little bit we'll try a four to one
tincture actually increase disagitation
um pretty quickly within the first day
so then i said okay let's take it the
other direction and go higher cbd less
thc
we did eight drops just once a day he
was a little less anxious but agitation
started to increase when we tried to
increase either the frequency or the
dose
so i wasn't able to increase the dose or
add any additional dosages due to his
increased symptoms but the daughter was
really
really keen on trying cannabis she said
is there anything else we can try and i
said well
since he seems to be sensitive to
medications why don't we try a product
that might bypass the liver so we
decided to try a cbd transdermal patch
and you know knowing that he had been
sensitive to medications i said okay
wait let's take this patch and cut it
into 10 strips we'll start with one
milligram
transdermal
it caused severe incontinence of his
bowel
he had quite a bit of diarrhea and
shakiness but his mood was improved
and she was like oh my god
if i can just deal with this you know
incontinence of of diarrhea i don't know
i think we're onto something and i'm
like oh my god
so i checked in with her another day and
she's like yeah it's pretty bad eloise
he's
constantly in a brief and i said okay
let's try a lower dose
so i took the one milligram sections and
had them cut into thirds
so 0.33 milligrams cbd every 72 hours
now the manufacturer recommends that you
put one patch on every eight to twelve
hours
he had significant mood improvement
throughout the day and his side effects
of the diarrhea and incontinence even
resolved that was his dose
incredible
so when my patients tell me that they're
sensitive to medications i believe them
this is a 72 year old female with
dementia she was residing in an assisted
living facility progressive symptoms of
mood swings anger yelling out at the
facility
they were trying to manage her symptoms
with gabapentin and quetiapine
they were helping but the husband didn't
want to increase the dose
so
i actually recommended thc for her
agitation and aggression and initially
the facility refused to allow the
resident to have cannabis as a treatment
so
after realizing you know that they
weren't going to allow for it
i said what about cbd hemp it's legal in
the state of california you're actually
a national
company and i work with other facilities
in other cities that allow me to
write recommendations for your patients
to have this medication dispensed and
she said
i'm the danville location
these are my rules and i went
no they're not
so i called the oms budsmen and talked
to them and said the neurologist has
signed off on it cbd hemp is legal it's
been descheduled and so we were actually
able to start cbd for her
because it's what the husband wanted
so we started with 10 milligrams daily
and increased to 30 milligrams daily
with good effect and we were able to
actually
stop any increased dosages of the other
medications he didn't want to take her
off her other medications you know i
really allow the patients and family
members to share in that decision
because sometimes
when we do describe their symptoms can
get worse and we have to play around
with the dosages and sometimes they're
just
happy that the quality of life is
improved
this was a 78 year old female who had
lewy body disease he was a retired
pediatrician and he was also residing in
an assisted living facility
he was one of the ones that would wander
into other residence rooms and he was
very
destructive
and disruptive he would actually break
things in the rooms and it would have
this domino effect and at the end of the
night you know it's like when you have a
kid that cries and it causes all the
other kids to cry
you know so they would actually have to
call the wife every night and she would
have to come down and calm him down that
was the solution
so he was getting quetiapine and
lorazepam as needed they weren't really
effective she was the only thing that
was effective and she was tired when i
went and met with them she just started
crying i cannot do this anymore eloise
um so i put him on a one-to-one cbd to
thc of just two and a half milligrams
each three times a day and within two
days the wife stopped getting phone
calls
she was actually able to have her own
quality of life his dose remained at
that for five years until he passed away
i never had to do any dose escalations
with him
and we successfully weaned him off
quetiapine and lorazepam
so you know when looking at using
cannabinoids for dementia patients these
are just some of my pearls here
for thc i usually start at about two
milligrams two to five depending on the
severity of their agitation whether or
not they've experienced any had
experience with cannabis before
and i often schedule it after lunch and
dinner to cover the sun downing time
usually they're okay in the morning
if it's cbd that i'm going to start with
it's usually between 10 and 25
milligrams starting dose and that's
usually if they're not candidates for
thc
um the the conversation i have a lot of
time because the the way that um the
phone calls go is hi eloise i'm calling
you about my mom i want to put her on
cbd like they're already telling me what
they want right i was like okay so then
i you know do the consultation and i'll
say well
you know your mom seems pretty miserable
and a little bit of thc might make her
laugh again and it she might be more
pleasant to be around and she might be a
little bit more con
conversational with you um she might eat
better she might sleep better
and they're like oh
well that doesn't sound so bad
you know i'm like yeah you know i tell
them all the time we know so much now
about thc and dosing that we can often
control their experience and really
avoid them from having adverse effects
my personal experience is that full
spectrum products do appear to work
better and they're less likely to need
dose increases and i can keep their dose
low
so on average my dementia patients do
well with around anywhere from four to
fifteen milligrams of thc daily divided
in about two to three doses and about 15
to 50 milligrams of cbd daily divided in
two to three doses
i don't do very many combinations or
ratios of cannabinoids
because what i've actually found is that
women respond best to low dose thc cbd
can actually increase their agitation
anxiety and aggression
i've seen it over and over again so i
just tend to go with thc in very low
dosages
it doesn't create a lot of side effects
the other
concern that a lot of times other
clinicians will have is they're afraid
it's going to increase their risk of
falls
i'm not saying that either
men with anxiety and dementia tend to
respond best to low to moderate levels
of cbd
sometimes like i said cbd may increase
agitation in particular in those who are
already taking quetiapine so i do try to
advocate to reduce or remove that
again with the quality of life the
describing really is depends on the
patient and family members wishes
but if they are having significant side
effects i do try to encourage them to
consider reductions and i usually wait
about
two to four weeks of putting them on a
regimen before making those changes
not only do i not see falls i don't see
drug-to-drug interactions like i said if
there is some increased agitation with
quetiapine we can usually modify
the dose of quetiapine or even the
cannabis if we need to and resolve that
pretty quickly
and family members and assisted living
community staff say that they see such
dramatic improvements in moods and less
resistance to care
and now they've become my strongest
advocates and talking to family members
about getting their
residents on some sort of cannabinoid
regimen
what are the challenges and barriers
well you've heard a lot today about
berries but not many practitioners are
willing to venture into cannabis
medicine so i'm sort of their unicorn
in the bay area for being able to offer
this to these
residents in the community
an order is required so somebody has to
write an order for them to be able to
dispense it
if they go into a skilled nursing
facility it often cannot be continued
it's still federally illegal
and in california we have to follow
title 22 for cannabis administration so
that means that labels are required on
the product just like it would be any
other controlled substance and this is
why i can't use tinctures
because they have to be able to count
the product at the end of the day to
make sure that if they had 25 thc
edibles and they administered three
doses that they have 22 at the end of
the day and they can't really do that
with tinctures which is
makes my
availability of products even smaller
because of that
and these are just some of my
recommendations for practice so again
consider an oral regimen if the patient
can tolerate oral administration
i'm not opposed to inhalation but it's
not really something that's available in
the communities that i work with
consider a transdermal patch if they do
have issues with
medication um you know if they are
sensitive to it consider a transdermal
patch
they are expensive so they can be
difficult for people to afford
consider low
thc start low and slow but but don't be
afraid of it it seems to work really
really well for a lot of these
patients and follow up based on the
severity of the symptoms often it takes
me
sometimes the i get it right right away
sometimes it takes me three or four
weeks
to get them on a regimen but often once
they're on a regimen they do well for
years without needing any dose changing
and it's not a great business model for
me because they don't come back you know
i mean they're not coming in a lot but
it's really satisfying as a clinician
and those are my references and i know
to whoever's up next i'm sorry we had
technical difficulties but um
i guess that means no time for questions
[Music]
[Applause]