thank you very much the organizers for
inviting me to all of you for listening
so I'm I'm a plant geneticist and like
John I find this plant really exciting
it's it's interesting to me to come here
I think this is a great group of people
with different interests different
skills different backgrounds and some
some of you and the audience are really
helping to build a solid foundation of
our understanding of how this plant
affects us starting with one enzyme I
mean sorry starting starting one
cannabinoid or maybe one terpene at a
time and and understanding how that
works with our own cb1 and cb2 receptors
and other aspects of our physiology to
create an effect other people are
starting with the plant side of things
and taking the whole messiness and
complexity that's in the plant material
or parts of that and seeing how that
affects people and using that as a
treatment and I think it's I think I
before I really get into what I the main
message that I want to say I think it's
really important to think think about
things starting from both directions I
think we know that the plant has a lot
of important effects on a lot of
different key traits key key pathways in
our own bodies but we don't really
understand how it works because of the
complexity of all of the different
terpenes and cannabinoids that that we
just heard about actually and on the
other side we know that there we know
the effects of some key molecules but if
it was as simple as one molecule
creating a lot of these effects Marinol
would be success and almost nobody uses
marinol right because it doesn't have
some of the same properties of the plant
material and we don't really understand
why so keep that in mind as
as I'm talking so um so just thinking
about how I got here when I started as a
professor a few years ago in Colorado a
lot of changes a lot of changes were
happening on the legal side and just as
we as we all know a lot of different
states are starting to experiment with
this and creating these state legal
markets where we can start to see what
people are going to basically we're
starting to see the effects of some of
these state markets and people are
starting to do some some science but the
science that's being done now really
dates back a lot you know cannabis
science is there's some there's mentions
of cannabis in the oldest medical texts
in both Asia and Europe so it's
something that's been recognized for a
long time that there's something
important about this plant and yet we
still don't really understand very much
how that's working and that's despite
really a lot of great work by people but
it's it's a complicated it's a
complicated system and today in the u.s.
anyway most of the science that's being
done on the real clinical side of things
has to go through the National Institute
on Drug Abuse which is the sole legal
provider of candidate of most kinds of
cannabis products for medical research
in the US so in nineteen sixty-eight
there's one source in Mississippi has
been really the where we're all
marijuana products for most kinds of
studies on human physiological or animal
effects are coming from really this one
source and most published studies used a
very limited pool of cannabis diversity
with only two or three percent THC
anyway very low levels of THC and also
very low levels of any other cannabinoid
also very anecdotally anyway very little
in the way of terpenes or other key
plant compounds NIDA is recognized
finally that this is maybe an issue and
they've been trying to increase some of
the THC levels and other cannabinoid
levels and diversity however I think
it's what I wanted to do as as part of
this is the thing about how how relevant
or how I guess
well how I'm how what's available from
NIDA compares to what's available in the
state markets and how relevant is that
we're happy when we try to compare
what's in these medical studies to what
people are saying anecdotally how do we
how do we make that connection and just
just to put things in perspective I
thought I'd look at how many different
papers talked about medical health
effects and the National Institute on
Drug Abuse suit derived some of their
findings either directly or indirectly
from information derived from these
strains and we're talking about
thousands of papers every year are at
least mentioning marijuana health
effects a National Institute on Drug
Abuse it's not necessarily definitive
but I'm just pointing out a lot of a lot
of people are using information derived
from this work to make some kinds of
claims scientific claims and mostly
mostly this this is focused on mostly
the THC and now CBD a little bit of work
on CB G and CBN but you know these are
basically the decarboxylated breakdown
products if some of the some of the and
they're more typically thought to be
more bioactive than the things that are
in the plant but basically a limited
number of cannabinoids people are
talking about we know something about
the genetics of you know if you have a
hemp strain you might have some
variation and how much CBD is there but
typically most of the cannabinoids are
going to be CBD very little THC whereas
marijuana strains are you be mostly THC
very little
CBD and and if you cross them you get a
whole mixture of different genetics so
each of these dots is a different
genetic variety that they have in this
in this case in these cases have
have you no novel cannabinoid profiles
different than either their parents and
that's really the basis of a lot of
modern cannabis breeding but really most
of the most of the work that's being
done is only looking at a very limited
part of the diversity of cannabinoids so
this is just this is just looking at
that it's tiny
these are all different cannabinoids
you'd find in the plant these are these
are you know just a small section of the
diversity and this is their biosynthesis
and then these are these are some
different breakdown products that that
can happen and you can see these are
these are some different terpenes and
you can see that they're derived from
some of the same precursors so related
biosynthetic pathways but but but this
is just a tiny portion of the of the of
the the chemical diversity that's in the
plant that's really being looked at but
but there's a reason for that of course
it's that these are some of the major
cannabinoids in there
I just want to mention some great work
that Ryan Lynch I did when he's in my
lab now he said this little genomics
doing great work there but basically
what I want you to get out of this
complicated slide is that there's some
genetic lineages this is based on genome
sequencing of a large number a large
proportion of the diversity of course
there's always more that you could wish
for to be included but we were able to
pull out hemp lineages as being distinct
from broadleaf drug types and narrow
leaf drug types are the things that have
a lot of THC in them and and then a lot
of things that are hybrids mixtures of
different genetic components so this is
just a this is called a genetic Network
showing some of the connections
representing the the major major genetic
lineages what really I want to get at is
that there are some in this case we were
able to identify three different genetic
lineages that were we're pretty clear
and if we look at the chemical diversity
we can see they differed CBD and THC a
right so there's some differences
between broadleaf and narrow leaf but
also
bigger differences between either of
them and and half in terms of how much
THC course hemp has very low THC and
much higher CBD this is just limited
sample of diversity but still I think
tells a somewhat of a clear story and if
we look at the more minor cannabinoids
we can see that those same three
lineages differ in some of so the
precursor molecule is just basically
very a lot how much is in the plant
material that's going to basically
depend more on the when you harvest it
and and how you grow it rather than any
genetic differences some of these
different minor cannabinoids actually do
differ at least in our sample differed
between the the major genetic lineages
and others didn't that's basically where
I'm going to where I'm going to leave it
at that is that there's there's a
there's there could be some key
diversity differences in some of the
more minor cannabinoids similarly with
the some of the terpenes again there's
some things that vary a lot within the
different lineages and are not
significant so the same letter means
they're not significantly different
the biggest difference at least in our
sample and the terpenes was was in
Mersin and several others have suggested
that might cause some of the differences
between some of the major genetic
lineages in terms of some of their their
effects could be due to mersin but noes
and I want to keep that just keep that
in mind that these terpenes and
terpenoids
they're mainly responsible for the odor
and flavor they have antimicrobial
properties some of them are already
known to interact with the cb1 or cb2
receptors and also do seem to interact
with the cannabinoids based on some
limited evidence to lead to alterations
in the psychological effect and the
science behind that is pretty limited
there's there's some but it's limited
but the main the main thing is if you go
in a dispensary you'll find a lot of
different strains that have very similar
levels of THC and yet have dramatic
differences in their effects and so it's
not just about THC it's about something
related to some of these other compounds
in their very
well might be some of these terpenes as
as it turns out but I wanted to compare
okay
so there's all this diversity out there
what kind of diversity is available for
federally legal research at universities
and how how does not a compare to what's
in the state markets and just to just to
show a few of the cannabinoids if we
look at CBD and I had to we had to
calculate CBD levels because the federal
government only releases CBD they don't
break it down at the CBD verses CBD a or
THC versus C THC a because they use GC
technology to measure their cannabinoids
and so what they report doesn't include
does include that information so we had
to we had to convert our values to
equivalent decarboxylated versions just
for those of you who care about that I
didn't I did I know there should be an a
after it but in this case the data we
have is on CBD from the federal
government and if we compare what what
what what's available you can see they
actually do a pretty good job for CBD in
terms of the range of different values
so each of these is represents a
different night of strain and their
reported levels of CBD and you can see
there's a fair amount of diversity on
average their CBD lines are lower in CBD
than what you'd get in state markets but
at least the range of diversity is there
if you look at THC levels you can see
it's much lower than anything that would
ever be sold by a reputable dispensary
anymore it's about a quarter as much as
you'd ever get in a in a dispensary in
most of the cases except for course it's
more similar to the THC levels in like
one to one or variable you know lines
that have a mixture of THC and CBD in
some of these dispensaries but on
average you know five to ten percent is
on the high end for what NIDA makes
available for research CBG is is not
that different between the federal and
federal materials and the
markets for at least the lines that have
CBG but they don't have anything that
they listed that has substantial THC V
which is a potentially a quite
interesting other cannabinoid but not
present in any of the nanomaterial
according their results and this is so
that's sort of the averages what about
the another of you another way of
looking at the diversities for lines I
have both CBD and THC in them at more
than one percent so so taking out the
lines that are just pure CBD or mainly
CBD or mainly th see what kind of
diversity does night I offer of things
that have more than that and you can see
it's only only a only low levels of
total cannabinoids and also only a
subset of the range of variation in CBD
to THC ratio is available in the lines
that they have listed compared to the
broader diversity available in the state
markets so um it's not necessarily
totally irrelevant but it only it only
tells us a part of the story of why
people are using cannabis products at
the in the state markets and also the
potential range of effects of those
cannabis products both good and bad it's
not is not able to be studied using this
kind of material if we if we go broader
and look at all of the total
cannabinoids it's basically the same
kind of story so basically this is
taking a whole broad range of
cannabinoids distilling it statistically
down into only two axes principal
component one principal component two
and what that does is this just tells
you it helps us visualize the diversity
of the chemical to the phytochemical
diversity available in some of these
different markets so just comparing
Oakland Sacramento and nighted we can
see that NIDA again only has a tiny
range of variation compared to what's
available in the state markets and these
are and you could see also a lot of the
state markets have have also these
outliers that are even more unusual
plant material whereas the night of
material has very little and
way of these extreme outliers and really
only covers a very small range of the
total total diversity the phytochemical
diversity that's present in the state
markets so just just to think about that
a little bit more you know we've we've
heard today about the effects of you
know individual cannabinoids or
groupings of cannabinoids and turf
beings and a lot of some of that is is
certainly done at the university level
but but a lot of what we hear about is I
guess a lot of I guess a lot of what you
read about in in the in the papers is is
going to be limited because NIDA
has very different levels of
cannabinoids they have roughly a quarter
of the THC levels in their teach see
lines they typically have lower CBD
levels then when you get a state market
but I would argue that it's not as
Extreme as the THC situation essentially
no measure - no measurable see HCV CBC
or other what we call what some people
term minor cannabinoids I should also
point out that they don't even report
terpene levels for their material that
they send out and so you can't request
material easily at least to have a
particular terpene content I think the
research using NIDA
marijuana is limited in terms of what
kind of terpene diversity is there there
are some things that I haven't shown you
from NIDA there are some can I have an
always that actually higher in NIDA
so what actually one in particular NIDA
has 11 to 23 times the cbn content so
what does that tell you yes oh oh bold
well it's also old so CBN is a natural
breakdown product of Delta 9 THC due to
oxidation or UV
other other other processes occur over
time leading to CBN to breakdown so one
possible explanation using nidus
information or not his website that I
got just a few days ago they say the
university designates a secure plot of
land where marijuana crops are grown
every few years based on current and
expected demand the manner marijuana has
grown harvested stored and made
available as bulk marijuana or other
purified elements of marijuana to use
for research every few years
ok maybe that explains why it has ten to
twenty eleven to twenty three times as
much of the breakdown products of
cannabinoids as anything you'd ever see
in a dispensary and it's not this is not
an essay this is not necessarily an
innocuous issue because we know all of
these cannabinoids are interacting with
each other to create the physiological
effects and the fact that the research
grade materials are so heavily degraded
that they don't have substantial
terpenes and have much higher rates of
the breakdown products limits our
ability to really really understand what
what's happening when people are using
very different material in the state
market so I would argue that you know
this issue NIDA having lower levels of
most cannabinoids a lower diversity of
cannabinoids and higher levels of the
breakdown products of THC CBD suggests I
would argue that's a major issue when
we're trying to understand the effects
of the marijuana that people are using
in the state markets and I would
advocate that something needs to change
such that ongoing and future research
can be improved in terms of its
relevance we need we need materials with
higher diversity of cannabinoids higher
levels of relevant products lower levels
of degradation products unless you're
interested specifically in studying
those degradation products and also
making sure that we have relevant levels
of the the key terpenes and terpenoids
compounds just to briefly thank people
before my time totally runs out daniela
Vergara constructed the bulk of the
statistical analysis along with student
Bidwell and my collaborator in the
psyche neuroscience department see you
ken hutchinson also the genetic analysis
that i mentioned in the beginning was
done by Ryan Lynch and funding from
several different sources and although
mainly mainly actually from from
donations and also I really should thank
steep hill for their expertise on the
chemists chemical side of things and
their their help with understanding and
generating a lot of this data so thank
you very much
[Applause]
you