um so we're going to talk about canabo
hyperemesis syndrome today which is one
of the few true indic
contraindications to using cannabis I do
have a conflict of interest in that uh
ketoscience has originated a screening
test uh for the genomics of this
disorder uh so I do have a vested
interest um so this is the paper that
came out of it and we're going to be
discussing this in detail subsequently
after some introductory material there's
a link there this is also open source so
you can access it on PubMed free or at
Ethan russ. org at the library
tab first what is this so this was a
real mystery it was first described in
2004 in Australia and eight patients but
the index patient first one that
manifested symptoms was cleared back in
1996 so you can imagine going eight
years with this mysterious illness that
nobody could treat um they nailed the
description because what they've said um
now uh 20 years ago is exactly the
description of the syndrome today which
is a combination of nausea vomiting
abdominal pain and hot water bathing
Behavior and this was among people who
had no knowledge of other people being
similarly affected so it wasn't a matter
of one person saying hey if you take a
hot shower you'll feel better so this is
associated with cycles of of nausea
vomiting abdominal pain um basically
abstinence from Cannabis or uh CB1
Agonist is the only effective treatment
but as we'll see halop par at all uh or
capsacin on the skin may be helpful for
an acute
attack prior to our study the biggest uh
case series was in 98 patients at the
Mayo Clinic uh there was a review in
2018 that
found citations about this disorder but
it's more sense uh probably the best
article on this
pathophysiology is devono in 2020 she
described a prodromal phase of nausea
and vomiting and anxiety and sweating
followed by the more classic hyperemesis
with all the accompanying symptoms and
then if a person abstains from Cannabis
uh then recovery uh there was a 2012
study uh that looked at the cost that
people had incurred between emergency
visits and diagnostic tests all for not
and that figure was 95,000 then so you
can imagine what it might be
now unfortunately there've been at least
two deaths directly attributable to this
so it wasn't cannabis that killed them
but the syndrome did because of
hyponatremia and accompanying uh
problems related to the
emesis um interestingly the standard
antiemetics the 5
ht3 antagonists like uh on Dan and
granisetron don't work here this is from
the devono article um and they had this
nice good diagram that I'm sure you
can't read um but uh again
describing possible
pathophysiology as we've heard before
canabo including THC can have basic dose
responses so everyone knows that a small
dose of THC is good for nause and
vomiting and chemotherapy but anyone can
vomit from Cannabis if their THC uh
intake is too high um additionally if
this is done on a chronic basis there's
a down regulation of the CB1 receptor
where T Works and under those conditions
TC can act as an antagonist and again
might induce vomiting a very prominent
aspect of this disorder is uh activation
of the hypopituitary
hypothalamopituitary axis
HPA and um she had pointed out that
there could be a genetic predisposition
but at that time that wasn't defined and
this is certainly something we wanted to
do you will hear from a lot of people
that this is due to pesticides or neem
exposure but that's totally
unsubstantiated um there was this
bizarre study in
2018 so uh This was done at bellw the
big uh public Hospital in New York City
um and among people who didn't present
with CHS they asked them about their
cannabis habits uh and whether they had
ever vomited and whether it was better
if uh they took a hot shower um so they
created their own definition of CHS they
estimated that 33% of heavy cannabis
users might have this if you extrapolate
that to the US population it would be
2.75 million people affected um another
agency estimated
350,000 I think that the truth is
somewhere in
between um an important point in this
study in
2013 there was this 30-year-old guy um
and he had a history of CHS based on the
symptoms he was a heavy cannabis user
but had a job where he had urine testing
so he stopped the Cannabis and this is
an unfortunate common scenario in favor
of using synthetic CB1 Agonist for which
they normally aren't they aren't going
to show on urine testing and he resumed
having CHS symptoms so he hadn't used
cannabis for 6 months they tested him
they did not see THC metabolites but did
see evidence of the synthetic
cannabinoids um when he quit everything
he cleared his symptoms in two weeks so
this shows that it is a problem with
Hyper stimulation over uh the long term
in the CB1
receptor now this similarly can happen
with Delta 8 synthetic that people are
making out of excess CBD is a way to
make money um it is weaker uh as an
Agonist as compared to Delta 9 but in
this uh case report this 38-year-old uh
woman um clearly uh had symptoms of CHS
related to delta8
gummies um and then this case that I
really question uh this is a
six-year-old who had uh seizures as a
result of an incilius
and had been on canaba as epid dialects
which is about 98% pure they're
vanishingly small amounts of THC in it
this patient had five episodes in six
months of vomiting lasting uh one to two
days uh they assumed it was
CHS um uh there was one more episode
after stopping and then there weren't
any and they decided that um
this was related to CBD I think that's
Highly Questionable we do not know if
someone took absolutely pure CBD whether
that would trigger it my suspicion is no
but everybody we've talked to so far has
relapsed uh and that's often because CBD
is rarely that pure uh particularly in
the current envir
environment um I got sick of hearing
that
um uh various other things were causing
CHS whether pesticides or nemes so I
wrote this editoral in
2021 um this guy had the crazy idea that
hop Laton vroid uh caused it despite the
fact that not only has this virus never
caused disease in humans no plant virus
has ever caused a disease in humans so
it was just a theory with nothing behind
it uh neem oil uh is an organic
pesticide you can search very carefully
in the literature and you'll barely find
any uh instances of toxicity from this
and the toxicity that is there is quite
distinct from CHS and that's true of its
most active ingredient is that a
reactant that is a very hairy molecule
you see here it's got an extremely high
boiling point of almost 800° C which is
about the temperature of a burning tip
of a joint so the idea that this might
be turned into something else that's
more toxic than as that tin itself is
really
farfetched um so another myth um and
this is just about pesticides pesticides
are a huge problem um where it's not
monitored properly uh in cannabis
Commerce however um you know the things
that they do uh like Organo phosphates
and um other agents that cause endocrine
disruption or potential carcinogens they
don't resemble the symptomatology of CHS
either now back to our
study um we hypothesize that this could
have a genetic cause and the reason for
thinking this is we we all know people
who use great volumes of cannabis and
have never had this problem whereas
others do um we thought that there might
be mutations on a variety of genes and
our top candidates were the CB1 Gene
cnr1 uh the trip V1 uh Gene that
responds to heat and capin that would
make sense uh or that it had something
to do with the the breakdown metabol IC
enzymes for cannabis particularly
THC so this could be done with genomic
testing um we had an extensive
questionnaire that was developed to make
sure that people had uh the diagnosis
that was active and that they had a
diagnosis already from someone we wanted
to make sure that people who hadn't been
misdiagnosed and didn't have symptoms so
they were eliminated uh this went
through an Institutional review board
and we Rec recruited over the C A year
585 patients there were
205 that had had a diagnosis of CHS and
had active symptoms they were um the
ultimate study group 99 of those agreed
to get a a genomic test kit but this is
where it got hairy only 28 returned them
and
unfortunately this was primarily due to
active um
dissuasion um from some people in the
CHS community that questioned our
motives um in doing this whole thing we
also had 54 controls that were high
volume canabus users that didn't have
the symptoms and 12 of those agreed to
testing
uh like it or not this is the largest
CHS study to date um this is the uh
methodology of it uh if you have
questions about it uh why don't you ask
Kevin mckernin because he'll understand
it and I
don't um so survey of the the summary of
the
survey there were 2005 CHS patients
again high frequency users 91% daily or
more uh primarily using high THC
preparations especially flour and an
average of 4 grams a day which is very
high intake these days um almost 16% had
had a diagnosis of canab cannabis
dependency or addiction and over half it
had withdrawal symptoms which is it's
not that were significant to them uh
which is not common either uh almost 90%
had symptoms improve after they stopped
but almost all had relapsed for the
controls the use patterns were quite
similar again they'd all been recent
users 70% daily or greater and smoking
high THC predominant material again an
average of four grams a day so we really
were comparing like to
like um in contrast to the CHS patients
less than 4% had ever been labeled as
being addicted or dependent and uh 34s
had never had withdrawal symptoms only
11% have been told to stop for any
health related reasons uh just a bunch
of comparisons from the survey a vast
majority smoked um again 100% of of the
controls were current cannabis
smokers um and um you can't can't see it
very well but on the right um that's a
graph of daily intake and the big spike
is at 4
grams um do you know the composition of
the Cannabis that you use and uh for the
vast majority it was the blue is uh Tec
predominant um is your use of cannabis
adult use um again the bluish purple
there um uh 6% purely medical and 38%
both um use patterns um I can't even
read the captions
um uh again treated for dependency or
addiction uh the ma majority of the CHS
patients and
um have you ever had to stop for a
health reason
um again the majority of the
patients um withdrawal 3/4 of the
controls had never had
withdrawal
um these were symptoms of withdrawal
anxiety um difficulty with sleep the
things that you would imagine in any
other
context
uh periodic nausea and vomiting and this
is how happen often it happened for many
people it was daily weekly Etc that
figure was Zero for
controls um hospitalizations for nausea
again the vast majority of the CHS
patients that figure was also zero for
the
controls um and abdominal pain same
thing everyone uh of the CHS patients
had uh severe abdominal pain and none of
the
controls uh how often often again
varying from daily to weekly or
episodically
um and let's just go ahead
here uh episodes are lasting anywhere
from days to months at a time it would
really depend on whether people were
continuing to use
cannabis uh did the condition improve
after cessation of cannabis usage uh the
vast majority
yes um after a period of abstinence did
the symptoms resume again a vast
majority that was true and how long it
took uh really was a function of
cannabis usage I can just say in general
that when people start back often they
do so gingerly and may not have a
problem the problem will occur with dose
escalation or at a point that they
develop tolerance um
again uh this one was interesting do you
have an opinion is the cause of
cannaboid hyperemesis syndrome couple of
people thought it might be genetic a
couple of people didn't think that they
believed in the diagnosis uh 6 % thought
it was related to neem or
pesticides um this is a chart on the
demographic comparison in both instances
there were more women than men I don't
think that's typical of the demographics
in the actual population it's just that
women are more patient to fill out a
long questionnaire and engage in a study
um and uh you see again a smoking habit
uh 86% daily consumers and CHS and 70%
in the control subjects the big
difference came in symptoms of abdominal
pain nausea Etc uh so high figures for
CHS and zero for uh the
controls this thing is hesitant now
again this may be hard to read but we
looked uh specifically at a number of
different genes
and we'll go into each of these in
detail but bottom line is there were
five genes where there were mutations in
the CHS patients that were statistically
significantly different than the
controls that didn't have
CHS uh the first hypothesized Gene was
cnr1 that encodes for the CB1 receptor
where THC works now in Prior studies
there have been Snips single nucle
nucleotide
polymorphisms that were associated with
cannabis usage but we didn't see that in
the CHS patients now this is an
important point of Distinction because
there is this thing called cyclic
vomiting syndrome that is distinct from
CHS sounds alike this is a form Frost of
migraine it often will begin in a child
who has episodes of vomiting for no
apparent reason has a family history of
mind Rin and only when they're older
teen or even adult will they develop
more classic hemicranial pain nausea
vomiting and um and sensitivity of the
eyes to light um so this test could form
a distinction between um CVS cyclic
vomiting syndrome where cannabis helps
uh and CHS where cannabis
hurts um
and there was unfortunately um
gastroenterology just uh published this
opinion piece that made me crazy uh
Bonnie sent it to me and she'll tell you
what my reaction was but they
conflated uh CHS with CVS saying they're
subsets of one another or something um
and they said it right here CHS is a
subtype of cyclic vomiting syndrome this
is a really dangerous and inaccurate
state statement um my letter to the
editor has been submitted we'll see if
they bother to print it okay
so one theory was wrong but still
helpful um we didn't know anything about
this one this wasn't something we
hypothesized but this is CT ketol methyl
transfer Gene that breaks down uh
dopamine so the um there was a mutation
on this Gene and 57% of the CHS patients
and only um uh very 10% of controls you
can see the P value is significant um
when there's a loss of function in this
Gene it leads to dopamine excess which
can lead to Compulsive Behavior like
gambling sex addiction or substance use
um this particular mutation has also
been associated with depression
rumination behavior and
alcoholism um so these are risk factors
for the same population and um we've
come to know a lot of patients who are
affected and they tend to have other
substance abuse problems it's also been
associated with impulsivity attention
deficit obsessive compulsive disorder
anxiety and psychosis so again risk
factors um one of the genes we did
hypothesize is being involved wasn't in
fact the case this is trip V1 for the um
that receptor um the this mutation was
in
71.5% of the CHS patients and only 30%
of controls trip V1 um does a lot of
different stuff it is it present in the
gut it's present in the
brain it mediates long-term depression
in the hippocampus it can controls
glutamate release in the solitary tract
that affects gut motility and
secretion um in a prior study no
mutations on this Gene were seen in
cannabis dependency but they may not
have been dealing with CHS patients um
this was a new mutation that wasn't
previously Le listed in the
databases uh but this really suggests a
linkage to mood and the gut phenomena of
CHS as well as the hot water bathing
because that will stimulate trip v b V1
also explains why capsacin on the skin
will help the other one that we
hypothesized was again metabolic enzymes
for
THC uh so
cyp2c9 as we heard from Bonnie yesterday
is the main uh enzyme that breaks down
uh
THC um and in this instance there was a
homo zy zygus mutation two two copies
that was seen in almost half of the CHS
patients and only 10% of
controls um so this breaks down a bunch
of other things including uh erodic acid
the precursor to
anandamide when it this enzyme is not
functioning properly it could lead to
THC accumulation and maybe kick it into
that range where it's protic rather than
anti getic it's also possible that
because the enzyme is screwy that it
could make abnormal metabolites that
could be
toxic um previously there was one case
report of a mutation on cyp uh c19 along
with two
2c9 on that patient had CHS also
dependency and a personality
disorder um next we we found another uh
dopamine Gene and this is the one that
codes for the D2 dopamine receptor
that's the target of most antipsychotic
drugs so 61% of the CHS patients had the
mutation and only 20% of the
controls stimulants of the drd2 are
protic and also affect gut M motility so
this fits well as well uh again
depression and anxiety go along with
this mutation also has been associated
with cigarette addiction uh Tourette
syndrome and chronic pain the fact that
we've got a two genes affecting dopamine
metabolism really helps explain the
symptoms of CHS and also the psychiatric
sequel that seem to accompany it um and
the last one was again something we
hadn't predicted the abca1 ATP bind
cassette
transporter again a homo zygous mutation
two copies in 68% of CHS and only 20% of
controls this is a gene affecting
cholesterol met and
phospholipid balance it's also
associated with apoe accumulation and a
beta deposition and Alzheimer disease so
having two copies of this would place
people at risk for a bunch of things
including dementia later in life um also
coronary artery disease and type two two
diabetes polymorphisms in a closely
related Gene were also associated with
cannabis
dependency so conclusions we found five
mutations with plausible ideologic roles
in the phenomenology of cannabinoid
hyperemesis syndrome that was
statistically significantly different
from high volume canab I AB users that
didn't have the the problems we feel
that this battery represents this
Greening test that could uh reduce costs
and uh fruitless searches uh for other
causes of this um I'll just read this
from the paper cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome can contemporaneously be
conceived of not as a functional
gastrointestinal disorder but rather as
a manifestation of gen environment
interaction in a rare genetic disease
unmasked by a toxic reaction to
excessive THC
exposure um these are links we have a
website what Dash is-
cs.com what is
chs.cc also a link to the test if you
would want to order this for someone and
and we have nine seconds thank you
[Applause]