I'm really happy to be here we have a
lot of clinical information going on in
California as you know cannabis has been
legal as a medical substance for 20
years I've been seeing patients for the
past 12 years and over the past five
years I would say the incidence of
cannabis use in the elderly has totally
skyrocketed when I started it was maybe
10% of my population and now it's more
like 50% in the age of 60 and above all
the way to my oldest patient is a
hundred and four years old so okay I
want to start by I don't have a video
but I do have a little story this is
patient Stuart who is 86 years old and
he wrote a little op-ed for our local
newspaper in Santa Cruz California where
he said for some years I've been dealing
with progressive numbness and fierce
pain and my feet a consequence of
peripheral neuropathy that began when I
had diabetes I had trouble sleeping more
than a few hours at night an old friend
suggested that I try some medical
marijuana that he and his wife were
using for sleep with excellent results
he gave me a small bottle of the drops
you will hear about the drops and the
result result was also dramatic and
immediate since the first night I tried
the drops the swelling in my ankles and
the peripheral neuropathy pain and my
feet disappeared and for the first time
in many years I sleep well every night
and for as long as I wish this
development truly stunned me to
neurologist and my competent caring
regular doctor had told me that the
neuropathy was progressive incurable and
untreatable I have no pain anywhere I'm
sleeping better and longer than I have
in years and feel a marvelous general
sense of well-being and energy without
the lingering consciousness of stress
all without having to make anything to
smoke anything or waste a lot of time
giggling
so I'm still seeing Stuart this is about
four years later and his peripheral
neuropathy has progressed and he has
started to use a different product for
sleep which is has a lot more THC in it
and he is still sleeping well in through
the night and the limitation on how his
peripheral neuropathy has progressed has
to do with building a tolerance to the
CBD and being unable to financially
afford the kind of dosing that he needs
to get to so he hasn't been able to
really follow my instructions as far as
how much he needs to take for example a
15 milligram dose of CBD three times a
day would probably keep his neuropathy
in check and he's only able to afford 10
milligrams once a day in this in case I
forget to say it later is the most
limiting and the most frustrating factor
of working with the elderly because many
are on fixed incomes and they simply
don't feel that they can afford the
medicine some of them truly can't afford
it and some of them are like you're
asking me to spend $200 a month on
medicine that's just too big a piece of
my pocket and I can't do it okay I'm not
gonna read this one you'll have copies
of all this this is a half hour talk
that I'm putting in 20 minutes but we
see here some very infamous drops which
are gonna be in a study that I'm gonna
be talking about this is Bobbi she's 82
she can dance again and you see her
arthritic hands they're holding the
drops okay so to begin with we do have
an informed consent sheet on my patient
intake questionnaire and one of the
things that I had on there where there
was the risks of THC cannabis which for
years like for 10 years that was what
was on the risk list and I'd have all
these older folks come in and they'd
start to receive it read about this
informed consent and risk listing and
they said well I don't want to come in
and do this this is like I'm scared I
don't want to
get dizzy I don't want to have memory
loss so I had to create an additional
section on the risks for CBD use which
most of them were going to be using and
as you can see I never saw a risk for
CBD use anywhere I made this up and I
can only come up with four items and you
know the change in mood or sensation is
usually a positive thing and here's a
good one though many patients do not
sleep well on CBD that's for another
talk so that's something to consider and
dry mouth and loose stools so that's
what they learn about before they come
in I don't have time to go through all
of these but we see that both THC and in
the next slide CBD have many available
therapeutic uses and the important ones
I want to point out here with the THC is
that it's analgesic and antiseptic we
don't necessarily see that as a primary
component of CBD use people may disagree
with me I get people that call me all
the time saying I want the pain medicine
that doesn't get you high I want the CBD
and if it's inflammatory pain then
indeed CBD helps but if you're working
with the central nervous system for
example you want to get off opiates I
have found that the CBD does not help
nearly as much as THC so there are uses
for THC that are important even in the
elderly and I'll show you how we bring
it in without causing psychoactive
effects and then of course the main
things with CBD are that they're
anti-anxiety antipsychotic is the most
important effect that I think is
important because you can use it in
combination with THC to actually get
some benefits of having THC in your
system while not getting you know
disoriented really important effect of
CBD among many others okay so what we do
when we consider using medicine in the
elderly at least is to start with the
concept of you can use a CBD rich
medicine
you won't have to worry about losing
your balance about being altered in your
sensation and a lot of the elderly
really like that they will eventually go
to a more THC rich medicine for sleep
but they like coming in with this idea
that they're not going to be stoned and
just some information about CBD it does
have this wide range of effects which I
showed in the last slide but it's
important to remember that as in all
cannabinoids it does have a dose
response curve that's biphasic so dosing
is very important in both CBD and THC
and you have to work with your patients
on follow-up visits for dosing or it
falls apart this is true of all aged
people and so in California the model is
is that you see patients once a year you
give them an approval they go away you
don't see them for a year but if you
really want to work with dosing you have
to see them like at least again after 1
to 3 months to help adjust to that naive
user to the to the user that has
developed a tolerance and you have to
adjust the dosing and you have to deal
with tolerance okay there are some risks
of using cannabis in the elderly this is
from the one article that I could find
in the Journal of American Geriatrics
that spoke about use of cannabis in the
elderly there are no articles there's
nothing written really that I can find
that has to do with any studies done of
people using cannabis in the elderly as
far as you know a published study
there's a lot of anecdotal evidence so
what they say in this article is that
older adults are vulnerable because of
age-related physiologic changes
comorbidity polypharmacy which increase
the likelihood of adverse drug effects
now this is what's interesting because
we're going to see that when we use
cannabis we can decrease the
polypharmacy
and we're going to decrease the
likely advent of drug effects so this is
an important reason why you do want to
use cannabis in the elderly is to
decrease their pharmaceutical usage and
of course lack of information about
safety and efficacy and this is really
true but you have to keep in mind that
most of the opinions that come out about
cannabis and its use in any patient
population is based on age-old ideas
that have to do with THC rich cannabis
which does have its value but that's not
what we're primarily using in the
elderly population okay there was this
having said there was no studies sorry
there was one study done in Israel about
the use of cannabis in a nursing home
and most of the residents there did
document dramatic physical results
weight gain reduction of pain and
tremors and help in mood and
communication skills this was done at
the hot area nursing home many of our
Israeli members here will remember this
and what I want to point out about this
study is that it was done with the raw
bud marijuana so it was either smoked or
vaporized and that's all that was
available at the time of this study we
are very fortunate in the United States
I don't know about every single state
but in California we have almost all the
different forms of cannabis available
the one that I find most useful for the
elderly are tinctures of those and I'll
come to that but generally alcohol
extracted full plant extract in a
dropper bottle because we can regulate
the dose by the drop and it gives us a
concentration range that's useful for
the elderly anywhere from maybe 2 or 5
milligrams of cannabinoids to 10 to 20
milligrams of cannabinoids that's
appropriate for an alcohol tincture okay
so because there wasn't any information
out and I have so many elderly patients
and fortunately many of them resided in
assisted living community it was easy to
gather just some day to get a
questionnaire and this is by no means a
study it's a survey but we did take a
survey of some other patients in a
senior community in my area to reiterate
what was said by the last speaker
there's a problem in skilled nursing
facilities anywhere where nurses have to
write an order we can't write orders for
cannabis this affects not only pediatric
patients impatience but elderly patients
in a skilled nursing facility so there
is a problem in getting the elderly to
be using some of these cannabis products
this particular community had assisted
living where they could choose to use
what they want and administer to
themselves but when and if ever they had
a condition that required a progress to
the skilled nursing facility component
this is not even hospitalization just
skilled nursing they had to come off of
their cannabis and all of the
polypharmacy reduction that we had
gained went out the window they were
back up on their three or four more
drugs and at the time that I did this
study about three years ago there was
not any way around it I wasn't the
primary physician at this skilled
nursing facility I would have been
willing to write an order but I couldn't
because I didn't have privileges there
the primary physician wasn't willing to
write an order risk his DEA license so
I'm happy to say that there are now one
or two physicians in the area that I
work that do come on staff at some of
these facilities that are willing to
write orders and they say patient may
continue cannabis therapy that's what
they say patient may continue cannabis
therapy and that's enough it's not
hospital but it's enough that the nurses
will allow the patient to come in with
their note for me which I say this is
what I recommend the patient use so
between those two pieces of paper
and they're getting their medicine so
that that's how we've done it and I
really think that nobody's trying to
shut any place down for a few older
patients continuing to use their herbal
medicine and so the the nursing home was
happy with it and the patient's happy
with it that's how we've gotten around
it
yeah yeah I'm gonna talk about that
thanks okay so moving on is going into
the study the survey I should say so the
participants in this survey all live in
a retirement community in California I
already talked about that this is
important all had out access to advice
from a team of professional so the the
primary physician on call at this
assisted living center was on board he
actually referred patients to me the
resident nurse manager became very
interested in cannabis and was a
facilitator so that these old folks
actually had someone to speak to on a
daily basis if they needed to help them
kind of navigate their way through using
cannabis for the first time and then
they have access to a cannabis
specialist myself and there is Karen the
nurse manager dispensing the drops will
come to them so the medicine was
administered by the patient's themselves
she might have taught them how to do it
at the beginning but they took it
themselves this was a survey the people
in the survey one to seven months at the
time of the report they'd been using
cannabis almost all the patients were
naive before they started at this time
in this part of California there was no
dispensary allowed there was no
dispensary do you know that the patients
could go to so we have delivery services
and there were two or three delivery
services involved in bringing the
patients their medicine so you'll see a
couple of different medicines here Oh
back well all the patients chose to use
it in a non inhaled matter
was the last sentence there so this is
the questionnaire you can read about
that later I want to get the results in
here so the kind of medicinal cannabis
that the patient's chose to use because
we did this as a retrospective survey so
we didn't tell them what to use topical
tinctures and edibles no one chose to
inhale at this time we had some problem
with finding out what was in the
medicine they used because not all the
materials were required to be lab tested
therefore not all were but many of them
were you'll see and not all the products
delivered to the elderly come from a
reputable delivery service nor do they
come from a reputable dispensary that
will even honor if you're lucky enough
to have a consultant tell you what they
want you to take they'll go to a
dispensary they'll be out of the product
that you want them to take and they'll
give them something else this happens
all the time it's a big risk I can't
tell you how many times I've had
patients call me and say I couldn't make
it home they gave me the wrong medicine
I took it before I left had to pull off
the road and call 9-1-1 at least three
times so we don't have any control of
that it's a really big problem we don't
have any control of what the patients
take all we can do is advise them okay
so this is just a review of the cannabis
used there were two different tincture
is one that's important is the glycerin
tincture as you can see it had a
concentration of about 3 to 4 milligrams
of cannabinoids per milliliter the
alcohol tincture more commonly has
anywhere in the range of 10 to 13
milligrams per milliliter the patients
ended up self titrating how much they
used which will be in the next slide
they used more of the glycerin tincture
less of the alcohol so the idea about
self titration and dosage really turns
out to be true other products that they
used were the cookies or the chocolates
these were taken before bed at the
suggestion of the delivery driver who
said well
if you want something for sleep use this
this mostly had THC it came as a shock
many of them were not prepared but since
it worked they continued to use it we
also had topicals and we had a couple of
folks using flowers boiled in tea and it
really helped their pain so presumably
they're getting th CA out of their
flowers boiled in tea okay then this is
just a review of the patient's ages here
on the left-hand column 78 to 97 what
their dose range ended up to be from
their various medicines and we can see
that we have something from about a half
a milligram up to forty two milligrams
that's the range that the patient's self
titrated into mostly focusing around ten
to fifteen milligrams and we can
conclude is that the patients do self
titrate to Anna prompt approximately you
know around the 10 to 20 milligram dose
range some more some less and the
problem with topicals is that they're
used to a medicine that this was not
given with direction like yet lasts 4 to
5 hours you have to use it three times a
day so they only used it once a day so
they really need direction on every
single thing ok the last of this study
is the different diagnoses that the
patients were seen for mostly centering
on peripheral neuropathy arthritis and
insomnia and you'll see on the right
hand slide is the change in medications
you can look at that later in almost
every case patients reduce their
medications or went off this was done by
themselves there was no doctor
supervising this this is just a report
at the survey of what they did and so
just some feedback about what the
patient said is that they wanted to
reduce their pharmaceuticals experience
less pain have better sleep in this
small group of patients presented here
these goals have been met with
levels of success most of all some
patients receive considerable reduction
in their other medication use and
overall what we learned is two years
later ten of the twelve patients were
still taking cannabis medicine one who
had discontinued resumed after she came
for a follow-up visit because she was
confused now 14 of the 24 residents used
this medicine and in the cases of
discontinuous it's due to lack of
education and inadequate follow-up
that's most important with elderly they
need follow-up they get confused they
forget they're not sure if they're
supposed to keep spending this money or
are they cured now that's really
important so I think I'm pretty much out
of time oh yeah here's the last slide
the biggest biggest response that we got
in this survey was we were afraid to use
it during the day so we had a lot of
people that had pain throughout the day
and only achieved remission of their
pain at night because they were afraid
but if they came back and they spoke to
me or they spoke to the nurse manager
she encouraged them to use it during the
day another patient came in complaining
of insomnia and back pain but he was so
afraid to use the medicine he stuck with
the topical only which of course is not
going to help him sleep
so that's some of the patient feedback
and Wow I spoke so fast I have one
minute left this is amazing so I can
tell you a little bit more about the
elderly that I treat now we have
patients that come in on their own their
families bring them in I have four or
five different communities you know
assisted living communities where the
patients are coming in a lot of patients
come in because their son or grandson or
some younger person is bringing them but
almost all of them are coming in because
of this held out miraculous hope that
they can use CBD or they can use them
the medical marijuana the one that
doesn't get you stoned and they have to
be educated that there are combinations
of CBD and th
seed that can be had that can help them
sleep for example this tincture that we
used was early days of teachers and it
was a two to one mix of cannabidiol to
THC so that 35% of THC actually this
strain canna tonic is pretty sedating it
actually did help them sleep so there
are ways that you can do with strain
selection and ratios that you can get
the benefits of THC into a non altering
medicine
last of all I promised to talk about
tolerance I'm on red oh I went the wrong
way yes they need to come back we need
to talk about taking a tolerance break
that'll have to be the subject of
another talk thank you
you