good morning
everybody uh first of all I'd like to
thank kmed for giving me this
opportunity to share with
you uh my talk on cannabis product
recalls so first of all I'd like to
share with you the learning objectives
you'll learn that product call
information availability and
quality is
varied reasons for product recalls have
been
numerous and many specific contaminants
have caused product
recalls I believe that
everyone uh knows a lot of this
information but I wanted to go over it
and this is the Cannabis Testing
regulations by state so first
the states that are have are orange they
have testing rules for both medical and
adult
use and there's one error there uh for
Alaska that should be orange then you
have the green States that's testing
rules for medical use
only then there's the green state that
has diagonal Stripes that's Kentucky and
it's not because they don't want to test
for medical cannabis is because they
just passed legislation and they haven't
adopted their first set of rules then we
have the the light gray States they have
the legal
cannabinoid programs in two remaining
States Idaho and
Nebraska um whereby cannabis as adult
use medical use and canabo programs are
illegal
next I wanted to give you an idea we
know that 38 states have legalized
programs so with that in
mind what we did is that we went into
the Cannabis regulatory sites well first
of all I'd like to acknowledge that the
original source of the recall data set
in its version 0.1 was provided by Jamie
to who is presently the director of The
Institute of
cannabis uh science and she she gave
this to me to
expand and
so the states depicted in Black in the
regulatory agency website we found
greater I mean some recalls in the
website one or more then the states that
are blue with the gray diagonal lines
we have they didn't have any recalls but
we
identified um news investigative news
reports that depicted recalls so you can
see examples of New
Mexico Missouri Illinois New York and
Maine and I believe there was a total of
nine recalls from news articles then we
have have the light
blue is no recalls and I'm not going to
make any conclusions in the sense
there's two possibilities one that the
cultivators processors product
manufacturers have such good practices
that they never failed a test
or there are recalls but it's not in the
regulatory website and of course all the
states depicted in white there's no
legalist can AB programs legalized
cannabis programs oh by the way I forgot
to mention that 20 States out of
the out of the legal states had recalls
in their
websites so I wanted to just take a step
back and talk about the FDA product
recalls that we're all familiar with
what is the purpose of FDA recalls in
the pharmaceutical and Food Industries
and that Safeguard Public Health ensure
consumer safety by swiftly
addressing
contamination or product mislabeling to
ensure consumer safety and drug
efficacy so here are some examples of
three food and pharmaceutical recalls so
all three of them come from this
year and so we have the top
it's a food recall and it's some
cashews and that it is microbial
contamination then this in in row two
and three are pharmaceutical products
where the first one was a potential lack
of sterility assurance and eye
ointment and the other one is a oral
suspension that a
medication for
let's see it's numus carani which is a
lung um a causitive agent for lung
infection uh for individuals that are
imal compromis such as HIV and AIDS or
they take massive amounts of steroids
which lower the immune uh
system and that and the contamination
was a bacterium
basilis
serus now now the methods that we we did
is that we had the source documents of
all to um of the recalls which
encountered at up to I mean 262 recalls
we reviewed each document we extracted
and inputed the additional information
the three examples would be the product
type the reason for the recall and
specific
contaminants uh or other issues so with
then we' com performed comparative
analysis and creative visualization of
the results which now I will show
you so we have 262
recalls in the 20 States up to March
2024 and there's been a lot of recalls
since then in the range of around 25
additional recalls but are not included
in this
analysis so in this pie chart the top
five states
and with their percentages depicted in
this pie chart is
Colorado Washington Michigan and Oregon
and I must say there's been a lot of
recalls coming out of the
DCC in California since our study and
then we have the remaining
States as shown in the pie
chart so then we did an analysis from
2016 to 2023
and you can see that in 20 in 21 and 22
it's about the same number of recalls
and all of a sudden in 23 it more than
doubled so I wanted to take a look at
what states stepped up so we have the
five states Arizona Colorado Michigan
Oregon and Washington stepped up which
accounted for greater than 90% of the
doubling in the recalls in
24 so recall
quality as compared to let's say FDA
recalls and so here are the examples
like in the movie The good bad and ugly
we have the good that's the state of
Colorado has very
detailed recall documents where the s
simple types are always
identified in almost all cases the
specific contaminants or other issues
are
identified and also all the different
products from all the different
dispensaries are identified in a massive
list so we have examples of a pesticide
flour trim concentrate and aused
products with a pesticide contamination
though actually this
mobinil was the pesticide that was most
identified and you and I looked at in
terms of possible human repercussions
it's a steroid demethylation inhibitor
and I understand that after ignition
cyanide is produced then we have the
flower shake and trim another recall and
we have microbial
contamination and one one of the
aspergillis human
pathogens uh in that state I
believe speciation is not required so it
could have been aspil flavis ASP
fumigatus Niger or
terius and there are over 20 clinical
case
studies identifying cases of
individuals with cannabis use and
getting aspergillosis or other
respiratory ailments so again it's a
third example flower shake and trim we
have metal contamination
Mercury uh which is the symptoms our
central nervous
system the bad and
ugly I didn't so what we have is in many
cases specific contaminant name was not
provided divided
so so in the state of
Washington many of the recall notices in
which a pesticide exceeded the action
limits the specific
pesticide was not named and in
Michigan whatever contaminate
contaminants exceeded the Action level
they also were not
identified so so the nomenclature for
recalls in the different 20 in the 20
different states of course is different
accordingly to regulatory agency and we
did our best the team to see the
commonalities and we bro we whittel it
down to 17 reasons for product
recalls the and in the Y AIS in the red
I just wanted to you know different iate
between recalls due to contamination
versus other issues but the top two
which accounted for greater than
65% of the
recalls was for pesticide contamination
and microbial
contamination U pesticide
contamination almost 40% and microbial
contamination almost
30% some of the recalls had multip
multiple microbials multiple pesticides
or a mixture of pesticides and
microbials and so forth and so
on oh and let's see going back and keep
your
eye uh on the bottom and that's always
not
provided so you can see the reasons for
product recalls they almost all the time
they gave a
reason so then you have the recall by
product
type and so the top two you can see that
plant material over 40% of the recalls
multiple products which included plant
material was getting into the range of
25% and almost 10% of the time the
sample type was not
provided so here comes the
pesticides there are 20 three pesticides
that were specifically identified in a
recall and I sincerely hope that The
Regulators for each jurisdiction
examines this list and review their own
list as a possible indication that if
it's not included in their list they
might want to include
it and
so the top one is the meltin which
counted
for over 20% and then you see the others
as they decrease and I put in red the 1
2 3 4 AOL compounds and these uh the
medications the primary
medications for aspergillosis are AOL
compounds and as a microbiologist there
is a possibility that we're
introducing pesticides
into the soil or the solid Matrix in
cannabis production that may be causing
the increase in AOL resistant aspila
strains in the
environment and then in pesticides there
were a lot of recalls over 30% in which
pesticide was not
named so for microbial
contamination the two
winners over 40% is total yeast mold and
the fort Aspirus
pathogens with a couple and salmonella
species and I just want to make the
statement as a microbiologist and a vast
majority of the states I believe over
60% of the jurisdictions require total
yeast and mold from action levels that
range from 10 to the
three per gram upwards to 10 to the 6th
per gram in
that I know there are differing opinions
out
there does one really get any
information as the sample submitter
whether the path whether the sample has
any
pathogens and then there weren't that
many recalls and metal
contamination 16 out of the 262
we see the big
four and there are some states that test
beyond the big
four and then there was just one recall
with ethanol that exceeded the Action
level and one with mot toxins but it
wasn't designated whether it was aoxin
or OK
toxin so the future dire
s is that there are
eight you know 18 remaining
states that there are no recalls and i'
like to
actually look into the possibility of
forming collaboration with the Institute
of cannabis
science to make
many you know Freedom of Information Act
requests to get recall information from
the remaining states where there are no
recalls in their agency websites update
the data set and repeat the comparative
analysis but ultimately all this data is
to
advocate for standard
information of all recalls to have a
much higher quality of the recalls and
to have transparency in all the
jurisdictions
so that we can protect the the people
and to ensure consumer safety and just
as a quick summary the
contaminants they they may pose a health
risk to
Consumers and that the pesticide
residues on cannabis
products um have the highest
percentage uh 30 almost 40% of total
recalls and the microbial test failures
is 29% of total
recalls and I'd like to acknowledge the
individuals that did all the work really
uh but we have
four uh tasks the data set Source I
already mentioned was from Jamie to at
icr uh the data set
expansion and um the analysis
and the results visualization In Summer
She's she's our Allstar she was
involved in everything and needy and I
help with the data set
expansion and
so anybody have any questions
[Applause]
you mentioned Colorado being the good is
that the best model that there is out
there is it comprehensive is that a good
model for a state like Texas for example
please welcome
Kevin who's moving we're our state's
moving forward with regulation of
cannabis slowly but surely um and so we
want to Institute best practices from
other states is Colorado the best model
for us to look at are there improvements
Colorado could make that we may want to
consider as well well thank I can say
that definitely Colorado is one of the
best
um you know we have a small staff and it
would have been really nice to line up a
subset of every state and really dig
in uh but I can say off the top that
Colorado is the best and Heather Krug
who is the from the
Colorado Public Health and environment
Department she's the regulatory branch
manager that oversees the the Cannabis
program but they also combin their
efforts with the reg the other
regulatory agency the
me but it's a great example and um to
look at and we can have offline
Communications to identify additional
States uh thank you very much