foreign
[Music]
Coffee Talk podcast where we talk with
the leading Minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
I am your host Ben amaralt I'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the can Med conference
all right here we are we're in November
already and you know what that means the
holidays are right around the corner and
with that comes a lot of things to do
people to buy for parties to plan
wouldn't it be nice if you could check
something off your to-do list right now
well you can you can register for can
med23 if you haven't already heard can
Med 23 will be taking place May 15th
through 17th at the Marriott Beach
Resort on Marco Island
this industry-leading event will feature
three full days of cannabis science
content from more than 30 presenters and
instructors representing our key Focus
areas of science medicine cultivation
and safety testing and new for cam
mid-23 we will also explore psilocybin
and psychedelic mushrooms
now due to the limited capacity of our
new location cam at 23 is an invitation
only event and we expect that it will
sell out so if you've already gotten
your invitation to cammed23 please
register and get that off your to-do
list and if you haven't head over to
cammedevents.com now and request your
invitation I hope to see you there
Our Guest today is Dr swathi Varanasi
Dr swathi is a bilingual pharmacist
specializing in integrative and
preventative health
Dr swathi has paved the way for other
Health Care Professionals to pursue
non-traditional career paths through
creating postdoctoral training programs
industry internships and online courses
focused on integrative medicine and
patient-centered shared decision making
during our conversation we discuss how
Dr swathi found cannabis medicine and
developed an interest in it how
pharmacists can help cannabis patients
with drug to drug interactions the lack
of Education about the endocannabinoid
system for pharmacists and other Health
Care Professionals
how difficult it can be for Health Care
Professionals to find trusted sources of
information around cannabis medicine
whether pharmacists should be accessible
in cannabis dispensaries and
cannabumetics the things we can do to
improve our endocannabinoid tone
before we get to my conversation with
swathi I want to thank this episode's
sponsor medicine Women Health
medicine women's team of Specialists
includes Medical Doctors naturopaths
medical cannabis experts nutritionists
and Alternative Health practitioners
these integrative teams evaluate health
issues and design targeted protocols to
promote personal healing medicine
women's protocols have successfully
alleviated symptoms of cancer autoimmune
diseases and neurological conditions as
well as providing overall health
Rejuvenation learn more at
medicinewomenhealth.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Dr swathi
Varanasi
[Music]
good morning swathi thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast thank you so
much for having me
all right I'm excited to talk with you
today because I believe you are the
first pharmacist that we've had on the
podcast and well I'm the first that's
amazing yeah and hopefully not the last
because I know that you have written and
spoken about the important role that
pharmacists play in helping patients
navigate their cannabis medicine Journey
but absolutely but before we dig into
that I was hoping you could tell us a
bit about how you got interested or got
started in cannabis medicine
yeah so growing up I was around
ayurvedic herbs and so I always was kind
of in this bridge between the
conventional and unconventional you know
and the the east meets west so was
always very interested in the
preventative side of healing and really
how we can work with prescriptions and
whether that's in conjunction
um if we add herbs if we add any other
healing modalities whether it be
nutrition or you know talking about
sleep hygiene or Homeopathy therapeutic
aromatherapy I was always interested in
how a healthcare professional could
guide a patient with all these different
modalities that could potentially work
for someone and so to me when I saw a
pharmacist in a pharmacy I saw them you
know standing between the prescriptions
and the supplements so going to pharmacy
school I really thought there would be a
wide array of information on all of this
but as some people probably know the
pharmacy curriculum is is very
clinically driven very clinically
focused and it's very you know very
specific about prescription medications
more than the other side of healing so I
was drawn to how can I be that
Healthcare professional that looks at
both sides that sees the value in both
sides and so that's how I found
Integrative Health and I found an
incredible Mentor
um out in LA and at the time I was going
to school in South Carolina and I grew
up in the Northeast so I really was just
on a whim I just messaged this appy
preceptor saying you know like what
you're doing is so inspirational I would
love to do a rotation so that's Dr Pam
tarlo I had a chance to do a rotation
with her and just a few two days into
the rotation realized wow like this is
absolutely where I fit in Pharmacy this
is what I've been searching for and so I
asked her if there was a way that I
could
move to LA after graduation and train
with her and so our conversations from
there kind of evolved and we got to the
point where we were like you know we
should start a postdoctoral residency
training program for pharmacists
interested in pursuing this like you
know unconventional path and so
um with her we created like the two of
us created this Integrative Health
pharmacy residency program and so I was
the first resident as well as the
co-founder so I was really able to craft
my entire experience and training around
what I really wanted to learn about and
I kept coming back to herbs I kept
coming back to cannabis and I was just
so fascinated by it and honestly I I
always say that like the nerdiest people
love cannabis and the endocannabinoid
system because it's this brand new
exciting thing to learn about that
unfortunately we don't get a lot of
information in our whether it's
undergraduate or postgraduate curriculum
so I found that just I just kept coming
back over and over being like wow
there's so much here there's so much
possibility in the way that cannabis or
other herbs all together can really heal
people so
um yeah I did a lot of work in cannabis
during my training and then after that
continued to do a lot of different
educational opportunities and different
education
programs whether they were you know
creating online courses or creating
other training programs for other people
so
um yeah I've done a wide array of things
but at the end of the day really what I
think is most important is
patient-centered shared decision making
so that's really putting the patient at
the center of every discussion and as an
Integrative Health pharmacist it's
really important to me to figure out
what the patient's treatment goals are
and then kind of crafting a perfect plan
that works for them and of course a plan
that's going to work to achieve their
overall treatment goals so it's it's
really like this um like conversation
and this like collaboration with the
patient and when you know if let's say a
patient comes to me and says I'm having
issues with insomnia I mean there's so
many different ways we can talk about
healing insomnia and I always say you
know
um sleep doesn't just happen at night
and so there's so many things we can do
during the day that can also help with
our quality and quantity of sleep
whether that's you know the utilization
of cannabinoids what are the what
whether that's talking about sleep
hygiene nutrition
um then a lot of the other modalities
that I mentioned beforehand too so it
really it comes down to what the patient
wants and then how I can help them with
my knowledge base being wide and
expansive of all these different
possibilities
excellent and I know that one of the
main roles that pharmacists can play is
helping patients navigate these drug to
drug interactions I was wondering if you
could speak a bit more about that
yeah that's definitely true and
definitely something that's really
important that that I wish more people
talked about and I wish there was more
focus in you know Medical Professional
curriculum on this that you know for
example with cannabis there are certain
drugs that if I see them on a patient
profile they're an automatic red flag to
me and I mean as incredible as cannabis
is there are other really great herbs
that don't have as many drug
interactions that maybe could be a
better fit for a patient depending on
their you know specific scenario and
what they want to achieve and so to me
you know there's some you know
anti-convulsant medications like
anti-seizure medications like clobazim
or valproic acid but those are big red
flags to me and you know there are some
other medications out there that you
know I might have caution with and
that's like a much longer list but those
are two definitely that are red flags
and then another one would be Warfarin
which you might have heard of where from
working literally interacts with
everything and so it's also one of those
medications if I see a patient I'm not
and I actually just got an email
yesterday
from a patient one of the things so I
co-founded a CBD Wellness brand and one
of the things that we offer
consultations and we have like an ass
doctor swappy part of the page where
anyone can message me a question and so
I received an email yesterday of someone
asking like oh can I incorporate CBD
into my regimen if so like what what
would you recommend and what dose would
you recommend and all that and so then I
had to get more information and the
customer responded back saying you know
this is my drug list that's the first
thing I asked you know people want to
incorporate cannabis or CBD or any herb
can I see your current drug list of the
medications supplements and herbs that
you're taking regularly and so this
person came back and Warfarin was on the
list and I unfortunately had to say you
know the Cannabis is not the right
choice for you unfortunately and always
the conversation comes down to benefit
versus risk and so if we can optimize
the benefit while decreasing the risk
that's always the goal when it comes to
incorporating anything new into a
regimen
absolutely and I think that's one of the
things we always have to keep in mind
with cannabis is
um you know there are some examples
where it's not necessarily a good fit I
mean I I know we like to think that it's
um it's an all upside sort of sort of
option for people because it's a natural
product and everything but you know like
like you just pointed out there are
certain people who are on certain
medications that it's just not going to
work for them
it's one of the myths that I said debunk
that just because it's a natural product
doesn't mean that it's safe for everyone
I mean like a lot of mushrooms are
poisonous and those are naturally
occurring as well so it doesn't
necessarily mean that everything in
nature is going to necessarily
um be like a safe option for everyone
right and and
there's usually some pushback from the
industry when when we point out that
there are you know some potential
dangers just because
you know
prohibition is still on the minds of
everyone and you know any sort of bad
news about cannabis is is taken
um
taken poorly but I think we need to have
an adult conversation about it and uh
just make sure people know that proceed
with caution in some in some instances
so
um I was wondering if you could talk a
bit more about how how patients can sort
of access pharmacists because I know
that you know a lot of people myself
included the the
rare times that we interact with
pharmacists is just when we pick up a
prescription from CVS and and they ask
if we have any questions and we
typically just say no and grab our
prescription but how how can we better
use pharmacists um not just in cannabis
but in general
yeah I mean pharmacists are the drug
experts so we're the ones that know the
the most of We're the the people that
should know most about you know what's
going on with the supplements and the
herbs and you know as much as that I
would love for that to be the case it's
not really the case all the time but I
really hope and I want to be a part of
building up a lot of this curriculum for
various Healthcare professionals where
if like for example a lot of Brands will
say go ask your doctor or like oh we
can't answer that go ask your doctor but
then the thing that worries me is that a
lot of the quote-unquote doctors or
providers or pharmacists don't know a
lot of this nitty-gritty detail to
really help and then you know when it
comes to that then the patient just
feels really lost and not heard and not
seen and that's the last thing we want
is a patient to not get the answers
they're looking for so a lot of the the
root of all of that really is this need
for education
and the need for
there to be access to this kind of
information that's evidence-based that's
scientifically driven I always joke that
like right now we're in this like sea of
misinformation right now with cannabis
where everyone is posting about it and I
mean anecdotes are great but we can't
base note scientific decision making on
anecdotes so we have to understand that
you know who are the experts who are The
Trusted sources of information and where
can we find it because once you know
more Healthcare Providers have access
they'll be able to really answer those
questions that pharmacists included and
I have to say out of all the questions I
received by email or via LinkedIn most
of them are from Pharmacists and they're
wanting to know how to answer these
questions because truth be told I mean
patients and customers are asking about
it and they don't want to say oh just
don't take it because that's you know
the go-to response a lot of the time for
providers is because you know they're
optimizing benefit versus risk and so to
them if they don't know that there could
be a potential benefit they just want to
decrease the risk so then their go-to
response would be like oh don't take it
and I've I'm seeing more and more people
messaging me asking you know like these
number of patients keep coming to me and
asking me about CBD and whether they can
use it for you know pain or to improve
their Sleep Quality this fat and the
other and they want to know how to
answer and they want to know that they
can be a trusted source of information
for their patient which honestly is very
inspiring that these Healthcare
Providers are out there interacting with
people daily and they want to be able to
provide that information so they're
looking online and trying to find people
that they can message that they trust to
get this info so
the fact that there are people messaging
about it really means that there is this
need for widespread education to help
providers that can thereby help the
patients
yeah and I imagine it must be difficult
too with with cannabis medicine in
particular because the endocannabinoid
system it's you know involved in almost
every system in the human body so you
have to imagine that there is going to
be some interaction with with any
medication that you're on right
right and so back to the education part
and you know maybe sort of some of the
lack of information part how much of
that is that there's just not enough
information out there about some of
these drug to drug interactions just
because I mean cannabis is so new and
the studies just haven't been done
so partially yes
um it's some of it is
more than any
like this there needs to be an overall
understanding of the way that cannabis
works in the body and like for example
the way it's metabolized in the body and
if we understand that you know CBD and
THC are metabolized by the Sip 450
system so this is an enzyme system in
the body that really does metabolize the
majority of medications on the market
medications meaning prescription options
on the market then that means that there
is a possibility that there could be
interactions and so even if there aren't
studies okay at this point there are
some but there are not an extensive
amount we need to just look at
how cannabis actually works in the body
and so if we understand how they're
metabolized AKA how they're broken down
in the body then we can really
understand okay then there could be
potential drug interactions if other
medications are metabolized by the same
exact enzymes and I mean this is not
unlike thinking about other drug
interactions so many drug interaction
conversations that you know that I've
had or that I've learned about in school
or in training or afterwards really
comes down to what enzymes are
metabolizing these substances and if
their metabolites by the same substance
it's possible one could get in the way
of the other and so at the end of the
day yes studies are great and studies
are the ideal you know benchmark but if
we have a general understanding of how
these things work in the body then then
we can turn to that before looking at
you know very specific pkpd studies for
example
right and now to help sort of patients
avoid some of these drug to drug
interactions like and I don't know what
the legalities are around this or
anything but you know if someone were to
be getting one of those red flag
medications from a pharmacy
can or should the pharmacist be asking
if they are using cannabis as a
supplement or
this would be my ideal situation yes I
think that
that's awesome I wish there was a way
that in any pharmacy it would even come
up as a flag like on the you know
pharmacist side certain medications will
pop up with like different flags and
warnings and I would love if that was an
option and that was integrated into
their system and then the other side of
that is actually you know kind of like
in the dispensary side and so there are
um some states that do have it mandated
that pharmacists be almost like a
pharmacist in charge of the dispensary
which I think is an incredible model and
I absolutely think that that's the right
way to go and granted these are a lot of
seats where it's not recreationally
legal it's more medically legal but
um there are some states really getting
it right and incorporating pharmacists
in every single you know initial patient
consult so like any patient who's new to
that dispensary would come with their
med list and be able to talk to a
pharmacist that would in theory be
trained on how these drug drug and Drug
herb interactions could play a role in
incorporating cannabis into their
regimen which I think is amazing so
pharmacists can play a role you know
from a dispensary side on this and then
also in like the pharmacy you know
conventional Pharmacy setting as well I
think that this is such a key place
where pharmacists could mitigate so much
risk or potential risk for people
interested in cannabis and I think that
this is you know because this is not a
Mainstay in most places this is why a
lot of people try one CBD product or one
cannabis product and then all of a
sudden are just like nope it doesn't
work I'm don't want to look at it ever
again and they kind of write it off
because you know for example maybe they
picked up a CBD oil that's supposed to
be taken under your tongue but they put
it on top of their tongue or they just
threw it in a smoothie and didn't feel
any difference so it's like it's so much
of this is yes based in education but
but also just the fact that there really
needs to be more widespread discussion
about it
yeah no I think that model of of having
a pharmacist available in the dispensary
yeah I agree with you that's that's
fantastic and in kind of building off
that point about people maybe not
knowing how to properly use the product
how difficult is it too that of finding
the right dose first cannabinoids and
then finding good product consistency as
well I mean this is this is so key so
um what you might have heard before is
people say start low
um go slow all of that you know which I
definitely agree with but I also like to
add at the end stay low because I think
that people maybe think that you know
just like a prescription until you go up
it will work better and that might be
true
um for some people
um but it might not necessarily be true
for everyone so I think that everyone
has to find their sweet spot and their
you know perfect milligram amount and
you'd be surprised some people it might
be really low for people who are you
know users every single day and then for
some people it might be really high who
are also users every day so it really
depends the person and I think that's a
bit of the struggle in the dosing world
for cannabis is because it's not
dependent on you know race or gender or
you know like to an extent it's
dependent on body composition but not
really at the end of the day
um and it's just really depends on the
person and their like trial and error
but I think that that's why Healthcare
professionals being involved in the
discussion is so important because if
there is someone in your corner guiding
you and helping you with saying okay
maybe you start with a quarter dropper
of your CBD oil the first day maybe you
take that for a few days you see how you
feel I always think it's really
important to keep like a CBD or cannabis
Journal so that once you're taking
certain doses then you can write it down
and
and then you can evaluate and see okay
how did this make me feel did this you
know was this enough to make me feel how
I want to feel
um and then after that you can you know
continually titrate the dose up if you
feel like that's appropriate but I mean
one of the things I love about natural
products and cannabis in particular is
that so many formulations allow for this
sense of patient you know empowerment in
their own treatment and they're able to
take as much as they feel like they need
that day after going through the
titration process of like okay maybe
this is not the right dose let me take a
little bit more and maybe some days you
wake up and you're like oh I need that
like extra 10 milligrams to make me you
know ready for the day or to help Focus
just a little bit more today so
um yeah I mean I I definitely think that
that's a part of it
yeah great
um and so yeah coming back to this whole
um lack of training or maybe lack of
knowledge among Healthcare professionals
um
first of all were you taught anything
about the endocannabinoid system in your
TR in your training and
um is that Trend changing our medical
school is beginning to offer more
courses on the ECS
so okay so when I was in school there
was
absolutely nothing in my curriculum
about this and honestly it was like
looking back on it now I'm just like wow
what about a lost opportunity to be able
to speak to students and even like new
practitioners about this stuff so when I
was in school no Brandon that was a
while ago
um but now I see that Trend changing and
even for example today I'm speaking um
at a pharmacy school about cannabis
medicine so um and it's a lot of what I
do now is I I lecture quite often
whether it's to you know a student group
like I lecture quite often at um
University of Southern California so I
live between LA and Toronto so I um
lecture there and then
um a lot of lecturing um during coven
went remote so I've had a chance to
um speak at a lot of other universities
like today I'm speaking at a university
in Ohio but it's of course virtual so
um that's really opened up a lot more
opportunity as well to realize that oh
you know we could and all these experts
but we don't need to necessarily fly
them in we can have them over webinar so
I see more and more schools interested
and more and more schools whether and
even if it's not just on cannabis on
like the idea of like Integrative Health
and integrative Wellness which I think
is really important because cannabis
plays an amazing role in that but it's
not everything when it comes to
Integrative Health like there's so many
other aspects and you know this feeds
into this topic that I love to
mathematics of all these like other
potential substances and activities that
can influence our endocannabinoid system
that are not just you know simply like
based on cannabinoids or cannabis so
there's a lot of other things we do in
our daily life for example that we don't
even think about that is actually
influencing our endocannabinoid system
every day
um one of my favorite examples is
exercise and so this is another one of
my like favorite myths to bust that when
everyone's talking about like the
endorphin high after working out right
so this came out like decades ago but um
there were a few researchers looking
into the different neurotransmitters
different neurochemicals that are
impacted with working out and so they
found that yes like all the way down the
biochemical Cascade that endorphins did
increase and then that really caught on
and there was a lot of marketing and you
know now everyone really talks about
working out as you know like the direct
benefit or rather one of the direct
benefits of working out is you know this
feeling of endorphins and this like
runner's time
um but actually if you look you know
earlier in the Cascade a lot of it has
to do with the release of anandamide and
anandamide is an endocannabinoid that we
you know synthesize on demand in our
body that interacts with the
endocannabinoid system and in particular
with CB1 receptor and so this receptor
is the same receptor that you know is
you know most closely associated with
the central nervous system function so
again like in the spinal cord in the
brain and also the one that THC binds
with and has a very high Affinity with
and so you know if anandamide is also
binding to the CB1 receptor it would
make sense that we get these feelings of
euphoria and this or this feeling of
almost being high from working out and
um so that's like one of my favorite
examples is that Canada Medics are all
around us and then things that we do all
the time
um but we just don't think about it and
then another you know another way that
it plays a role really is some like
spices and in the way that we cook
whether it's eating at home or eating
out and you know beta-carioxide is a
terpene that is found in a lot of you
know naturally occurring found in a lot
of different plants and spices like for
example black pepper and so beta
Caroline has been shown that it has an
affinity to the CB2 receptor and it's
really interesting because growing up my
mom would make every time I didn't feel
well she would make you know this like
lentil kind of porridge and it was
lovely and she would always put a lot of
black pepper in it because it was you
know something that she always had
growing up something that she continued
to do and she said you know black pepper
will help you and help go through your
immune system kind of the thing and
something that I always heard and then
now learning about the endocannabinoid
system and have so many things impact it
whether directly or indirectly knowing
that beauty care offline is an active
component and that it interacts with the
CB2 receptor that's most closely
associated with immune function and you
know optimizing immune function it
completely makes sense but almost from
like a scientific standpoint versus you
know something I heard so many times
growing up and then looking more into
herbs and things like black pepper it's
not just that it also interacts with of
course a lot of other systems and things
but it's it's incredible to think that
without even knowing it and without even
necessarily incorporating cannabinoids
or cannabis into our daily life we're
already improving what's called our
endocannabinoid tone and really that is
just the overall functionality of the
endocannabinoids so some and how
important that is because there's this
new phenomenon that some people are just
born with what's called endocannabinoid
deficiency and it's just the meaning
that you know endocannabinoid your
endocannabinoid system is not working at
its you know highest most optimal
function and so just thinking like okay
how can I optimize my system and maybe
for whatever reason if someone's on
Warfarin or on other drugs where maybe
incorporating cannabis is not the
sleepest choice for them there's a lot
of other things they can do and so
coming from an integrative perspective
love to talk about how we can make our
endocannabinoid system work best from a
cannabinoid perspective but also from
like a non-connected perspective
yeah great I'm glad you brought up
cannabis Medics because I I saw that you
had spoken about that at the Cannabis
science conference and that was a new
word for me I hadn't heard it before so
um it's really interesting and I'm glad
you brought that up
and I'm glad that you brought up that
anandamide is actually the compound that
gives you the the runner's high or the
Euphoria after you work out I actually
had a t-shirt made up that's just the
chemical structure of an animide that I
wear to the gym no one knows what it
means but I know what it means it's just
for me anyway so but you mentioned that
with the canaba memetics there are ways
to kind of improve our endocannabinoid
tone whether it be through exercise or
things that we're eating I'm curious
about the opposite though are there
certain maybe medications or lifestyle
choices that are people make that can
negatively affect their endocannabinoid
tone that that we should really avoid
this is a great question I don't think
anyone's ever really asked me this in
this way so
um if we think about the goal of the
overall endocannabinoid system really is
balance and homeostasis so the
endocannabinoid system you know is able
to synthesize these endocannabinoids on
demand whenever you know it senses that
things might be out of balance in our
overall body system or in like
particular organ systems or
neurotransmitter systems and it tries to
do what it can to rectify that what
really can get in the way is an excess
of unwanted inflammation and a lot of
what homeostasis has to do with is
really regulating the amount of
inflammation in the body and so this is
also something that I've started talking
about a little bit more recently
um but this term
anti-inflammatory and I see it
everywhere and it's just so important to
note that our body does need a little
bit of an inflammatory response our body
does need what I like to call a healthy
response to inflammation because you
know if there's pollutants or you know
other you know foreign substances things
that we don't want to enter our body or
that shouldn't be there then we do want
a way for our body to react and our
immune system to fight it off and so
we we don't want to you know an
anti-inflammatory effect but
cannabinoids as well as the
endocrabinoid system really help to
optimize our inflammatory response and
really make it healthy and the best it
can be and so a lot of what gets in the
way of you know increasing or improving
endocannabinoid tone and a lot of what
has to do with endocrabinoid deficiency
has to do with this increased
inflammation and it's really interesting
now because a lot of research is coming
out talking about chronic disease States
like you know whether they're you know
cardiovascular disease like heart
disease or pulmonary disease or
um even things like anxiety depression
um and all of these things really having
a root oh as well as diabetes has been
another big one
um about all these you know kind of
chronic disease states that we all deal
with them that so many of us rather deal
with on The Daily that that you know the
the root of a lot of these is
inflammation and this unwanted excess of
inflammation and so if we can work with
our endocabinoid system to help improve
endocannabinoid tone then you know this
would this would really help and also
stress has a lot to do with inflammation
and what type of stress we have in our
life whether that's you know inner
stress or like external stressors it
could be a lot of different things
um and so that's another thing that I
love to talk about too is like the role
of adaptogens in our life and adaptogens
are
herb substances activities that can
really help our improve our body's
response to stress and overall stressors
whether that's external or internal
stressors and a lot of that comes back
to the endocannabinoid system
it all comes back to the endocannabinoid
system a lot of it yes
all right swathi so winding down here
before I let you go I did want to give
you the opportunity to plug any social
media or any research or resources that
the audience can check out to learn more
about the things that we discussed yeah
absolutely absolutely so
um yeah please um check out my website
it's drslappy.com
I try to keep it as update as possible
with like recent you know speaking
engagements things that I
um different webinars things that I've
done to provide access from an
educational perspective I also keep
playlists going on my YouTube channel
um of different interviews and things
I've been a part of so you can be that
source of trusted information and or be
one of them rather
um in this really important Canada space
and so
um that would be something to check out
also I'm really proud of the the brand
that I co-founded our CBD Wellness brand
and name element Apothic so that's
e-l-e-m-e-n-t-a-p-o-t-h-e-c.com
um and yeah you're welcome to message me
through any of those platforms so we can
connect
excellent all right swathi thanks again
for joining us on the podcast and hope
to see you out at can Med sounds great
thank you so much
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Dr Swati Varanasi check out the links in
the show description to learn more about
the topics we discussed and thanks again
to this episode's sponsor medicine Women
Health
our next episode drops November 23rd
that's two weeks from today in the
meantime please do check out the new and
improved canmanevents.com the team
really did an exceptional job updating
the website with all the information
about our kammed 23 event and of course
you can still find videos of all the
previous can Med presentations and
panels and the can bed archive you can
also find all the previous episodes of
the podcast as well and while you're
there make sure you sign up for email
alerts to get all the notifications
around this Innovative industry-leading
event I also invite you to engage with
us on all our social media platforms
we're on Instagram Facebook Twitter and
Linkedin just search for Cannon events
and lastly please leave us a review on
Apple podcasts doing so really helps us
improve our rankings and reach more
listeners
all right that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to join us on
the next can Med Coffee Talk
[Music]
foreign