first of all I'd like to thank medicinal
genomics and cartage in organizing
probably one of the best cannabis
meetings that I have ever attended was
equally impressive last year as well
poverty laboratories is an ISO 17025
accredited laboratory serving the
medical cannabis space for the state of
Massachusetts so with that we work with
dispensaries we work with patients
caregivers researchers and so a lot of
the things that I'm going to talk about
today are actual things that we see day
to day and I'm trying to bring awareness
to contaminants because people who are
sourcing their material from unknown
vendors are bringing it to us for
testing and what we see is is in general
pretty horrific when we think about
contaminants I think about mother nature
versus human nature sure the plant might
have some components that might be
considered contaminants but really what
I'm most concerned about things that we
as humans introduce we tend to screw
things up when we touch things and
cannabis is no different so as far as
contaminants we need to look at how do
we cultivate to the plant how do we
process the plant oftentimes we're
introducing contaminants during that
process process we as a lot think it's
very important for producers to look at
a hazard analysis and critical control
point plan for any processing facility
and then how do we measure and report
contaminants and how do we regulate
there's people here from all across the
world and so a lot of my numbers that
are measure or basically state to state
differences but I'm sure if you expand
that to a global scale you'll just
expand those challenges if you look at
the different contaminants that are
required for testing by various states
you can see that there is no real
synchronicity between the different
states as far as what testing is
required it gets even more challenging
if you start looking yes they may test
for pesticides in these multiple states
but when you start looking at the limits
that you have to test for appropriate
limits of contamination it becomes very
challenging in our lab we use a variety
of analytical techniques to address all
the different phytochemical constituents
as well as contaminants I'm just going
to talk about a few focusing on the
contaminants that we use and look for in
our lab but before I do that I want to
talk a little bit
about units one of the one of my
favorite quotes through you get somebody
calling the lab and says do you guys do
the ppm test well I say well yes we do
and we also provide the ppb test but
it's really challenging sometimes when
people who don't have a science
background to understand what is the
difference between weight percent ppm
and ppb so when we're talking about
residual solvents we might be talking in
terms of parts per million but for heavy
metals we might be focused more on parts
per billion and then it gets even more
complicated a lot of regulators will
choose to use exposure limits and the
regulations
basically saying how much contaminant
can there be per kilogram of body weight
per week well in order for me as a
testing lab to understand what that
means from a pass/fail on a contaminant
level I have to know how much the person
weighs and how much they're gonna
consume each day or each week but a lot
of regulators don't understand all that
extra verbiage there and so they will
truncate it and just say well it makes
for CAG as ppm micrograms per kilogram
is ppb so it ends up in the regs being
numbers that are just extremely low and
inappropriate and then what we see
happening is when another state is
coming online they look at another state
they'll grab those regulations and so we
see these mistakes getting propagated
from one mistake to the next in the mean
time the first date corrects it but then
the second state never learned so it
leads to some really significant
challenges we also have a saying in our
lab that says letters and numbers mean
something I'm a chemist and so if you
look at these units here what this
actually means is that every kilogram of
soil can contain no more than four
hundred thousand kilograms of lead we
assured them that they meant a little m
there it took some time to convince them
that little m and Bigham did not mean
the same thing but these are some of the
challenges that we we address so I'm
going to talk primarily about pesticides
plant growth regulators heavy metals
microbiological contaminants and process
impurities when we think about
contaminants we have to consider the
route of administration because what is
of concern is going to be very dependent
on how
that product is going to be administered
whether orally sublingually etc you also
need to consider the matrix you know if
it's an edible product if it's an a
topical product is it in the acid form
THC a versus THC there's there can be
some different considerations that need
to be taken into account if you look at
pesticide that's probably one of the
worst ones and and Ryan talked a lot
about that with some really good data
and you see that from state to state
there's very significant differences in
terms of what the pesticides they can
use what the pesticides need to be
tested for what has what levels are
acceptable in the pesticide you can see
that just in a couple states you can see
a huge variance Nevada some of the
pesticides are from ten to ten thousand
parts per billion Massachusetts we
hardly have to test any pesticides and
these are the prohibited pesticides that
we're testing for but we have to test
them down to ten parts per billion which
makes it very challenging from an
analytical standpoint which needs I mean
need more expensive instrumentation
which ultimately that price goes up and
gets passed on to the consumer just as
an example in California there was a
report that they they saw pesticides in
about greater than 84 percent of their
samples so it is a real concern for us
if you look at some of the different
limits of acceptability by state you can
see that let's just look at Seif
Lutheran in Nevada the acceptable
contamination is four thousand parts per
billion
Oregon 1000 parts per billion and in
Massachusetts ten parts per billion so
which is the right answer we don't know
that and part of the challenges for
regulators is that there isn't a lot of
toxicological data on these pesticide
when it comes to inhalation in the first
place but inflation versus combustion so
it makes it very difficult for them to
pick regulations but when we're looking
for pesticides we're using a triple quad
mass spec so we're looking at multiple
transitions and fragmentation of the
pesticides and that's a way that we can
confirm that what we're actually seeing
is a pesticide and not an interference
this is an example of a flower sample
that we saw some contamination of my
club you know
butanol
there was significant concentration
there but after extraction that
concentration of pesticide went up to
over 5 ppm and that's a pretty
significant concentration but the
pesticides behave very similar to the
cannabinoids so if you're doing a
process that is going to concentrate and
enrich the cannabinoids you're also
going to be concentrating and enriching
the the pesticides as well that had a
serious impact for us on our extraction
equipment because after this extraction
we now have a contaminated piece of
equipment it took us several weeks to
clean that piece of equipment to get
that contamination out and after each
cleaning we did a cleaning validation
only to find out that we weren't
successful so we cleaned it again did
cleaning validation again so cleaning
validation is something that we're
trying to get across to the industry as
a very important tool that can be used
to ensure that you're not passing on
contamination through your processes
heavy metal toxicity cannabis is well
known to bioaccumulate the toxic heavy
metals from the soil and other
environmental sources most of the
toxicity data is relative to ingestion
rather than inhalation but we do know
that you can get inhalation through the
mainstream smoke from either smoking or
vaping cannabis products there's more
research needed to understand the
implications of what that means so that
the regulators have an idea of what can
they set assay is a safe level typical
sources for heavy metals include water
growing medium nutrients processing
equipment and hardware probably one of
the most common that we see is is from
the nutrients a lot of people say
they're using organic nutrients
therefore it should be free of heavy
metals but organic nutrients also can
frequently have heavy metal contaminants
these are just some limits from some
various states most states just referred
to the four heaviest mercury cadmium
arsenic and lead they are naturally
occurring elements so it's very
important to be able to distinguish
between ambient concentrations of these
metals as well as contamination levels
and you can see just that there's a huge
just like in the pesticides you see a
huge variance in what is an acceptable
level of contamination again whose
limits are most appropriate we just
don't know that yet and in terms of
testing in Massachusetts we have to test
every batch is that really necessary
once you have your your processes
established should you be required to
test every single batch or should you do
periodic testing after you've tested
your your water source your nutrients
your soils once you've confirmed that
what you're using is free from
contaminants should you have to be
continually testing that those are those
are questions that need answering we use
in Dec inductively coupled mass plasma
spectroscopy spectrometry for
measurement of heavy metals basically
where the samples whether it's a gummy
bear or brownie or flour is digested
with microwave assists in a concentrated
nitric acid and then it's basically
infused into a plasma source where it's
ionized and that we measure the mass one
of the things we talked to a lot of our
clients about is when you have a product
maybe you're using nutrients that have
heavy metals in it you can see that the
first sample the raw plant material
would fail the massachusett
specifications for concentration of
heavy metals extraction techniques can
often be used to remediate that that
contamination so a lot of these metals
are not soluble in typical extraction
solvents and by extracting the
cannabinoids out of there unlike the
pesticides in the pesticide you're going
to concentrate the pesticides the heavy
metals are typically left behind and so
it's a way of remediating heavy metal
contamination a couple other sources
that people don't think about and these
are really critical as you're processing
equipment this is a real example where
we actually saw shards of metal that
were probably two to four millimeters in
an extract and when we tested these four
heavy metal we saw iron chromium and
nickel basically stainless steel
probably whoever made this equipment had
it turned in some machine shop and they
didn't do a good job of fleshing out the
residual particulate matter and it ended
up in people's products another thing
that is a concern is these vape pens
where do most of these vape pens get
made almost all of them in China
hopefully there will be some US
manufacturers
but because of that these pens can look
identical from one vendor to the next
and you don't know what's inside we've
worked with some people in the past to
do some studies on the heating elements
and so what we actually have done is
hook up a smoking machine to these and
actually draw off the vapor we collect
that vapor on basically a cigarette
filter and analyze that for the heavy
metals and what we have seen is aluminum
copper nickel chromium these are all
elements that are frequently part of the
coil for these vape pens we do see that
some people are now moving to ceramic
coils which might be a much safer
alternative these are just some of these
there's actually the cigarette type
filter that we've used to collect the
heavy metals on residual solvents is
another one you know everybody's doing
some kind of extraction especially when
you start talking about preparation of
therapeutics for children you know
geriatrics you know just your average
person who wants a capsule or a tincture
you typically have to extract the
cannabinoid from the flower material it
makes it a lot easier to reproducibly
dose and so some kind of extraction is
typically used there's different
classifications for solvents which ones
are appropriate for use
certainly we try and stick to solvents
like ethanol that's probably our
favorite just because of the low
toxicity of it and because it's pretty
ubiquitous in our everyday life anyways
our hydrocarbon extractions acceptable
well to me that depends on what kind of
hydrocarbon you're using most states
recommend that you use 99% pure
butane to do an extraction well my
concern is what's in that 1% if you're
using 99.99% pure butane what's in that
point zero zero one percent until we
start looking at that contaminant in
that material I'm on the fence about
whether or not butane hydrocarbon
extractions are appropriate because I
don't know what that impurity is and I
can pretty much guarantee you that that
impurity is going to end up in your
product and then what limits are
appropriate in the last 3-4 months
Massachusetts went from a limit of
ppm for butane 212 over that same period
of time Colorado went for the same you
tane limits from 800 ppm to 5000 so 0.5
5000 ppm is 0.5% do you want to be
vaping something that's point five
percent butane do you want your family
members vaping something that's that
high no I don't think so but so what
limits are most appropriate I think that
one of the things Massachusetts has done
and it's very frustrating for us as an
analytical lab but Massachusetts chosen
very stringent guidelines with a thought
that as we have more data we can loosen
those up a little bit and I think that
is the right approach but hopefully
they'll move forward and loosen them up
some more the other thing that we talked
with a lot of our clients about is
cleaning solvents we very frequently
talked to people who are doing ice water
hash and we're seeing residual solvents
they said that's impossible I don't use
any solvents in my process I said well
what about when you're done what do you
do I said well we clean our equipment
with isopropanol I'm like well how do
you know that that isopropanol that
you're using is not the same isopropanol
I'm showing in your bubble hash which it
turns out after some studies we show
that these solvents that you use for
cleaning end up in your product if
you're not doing cleaning validation
cleaning validation is a whole field
unto itself
in the pharmaceutical industry everybody
knows what that is it's just part of the
the process of production it's something
that people need to be more aware of in
the cannabis processing industry but
here's just another slide just showing
some of the variability from state to
state we do see that there's a little
bit more synchronicity starting to form
at the residual solvents as they kind of
have chosen to standardize for the most
part on USP residual solvent standards
the USP does not have any standards for
butane or propane but for the other ones
they seem to be kind of settling in on
on some pretty similar values but this
is just an example that we saw this was
brought in from a client that had a
butane level of about 1300 ppm butane
and a lot of these people when you have
extracts that don't have butane there
they don't taste the same they they're
missing that taste I said well that's
the contaminant you're missing so and
then microbiological contaminants you
know I think a lot of the concern is
with the contaminants that we're
introducing and oftentimes the the
actual production processes will kill
MicroBot microbial contaminants so if
you're doing an ethanol extraction if
you're doing a decarboxylation
oftentimes these processes themselves
will destroy some microbiological
contaminants but well you also have to
be concerned about if you're making a
product that doesn't have heating
involved with it like you're making a
tincture that's based on a cannabinoid
acid where you don't want to heat it too
much you might have to think about some
other potential for microbiological
contaminants because that heating may
not kill some of you might be relying on
that heating step to kill microbial
contamination that is not going to be
there and so these really have to be
taken into account when states are
making regulations on the different
levels of contamination
there's many different ways to measure
microbiological contaminants certainly
the the plating techniques are probably
the most common we use a combination of
all of these actually where we're using
it's called the most probable number
enumeration but now we're seeing more
and more DNA based techniques and for
good reason and I'll explain in a minute
but DNA based techniques that can be
more specific to the the actual DNA of
the organism of interest most states
currently are using the American herbal
pharmacopoeia guidelines as a basis some
states have also added in mica toxin
testing but I put here the the typical
levels for contamination for flower and
one of the challenges of that when you
have people that are cultivating with
pesticides we're asking them not to use
pesticides and we need to give them
tools to use without pesticides so
there's beneficial insects but there's
also beneficial bacteria
there's beneficial fungi so these are
beneficial microbials that they can use
so that they don't have to
and pesticide so heavy the problem with
those recommendations that if they start
to use those beneficial microbes they're
going to start failing these because
these are not specific to the organism
but rather to a class and so as you
start to look at DNA based techniques
that have the specificity it becomes
much more appropriate a couple important
considerations certainly you have to
communicate with a state and local
regulatory agencies ISO accreditation
bodies have an enormous amount of
information our instrument vendors have
been phenomenal in terms of getting us
guidance and helping us with developing
methods they're currently about 10 or 11
different organizations that are trying
to establish testing methodologies for
the cannabis industry but the people who
are in the cannabis industry for the
most part are pretty tight-lipped they
don't want to share their methods and
that's not the scientific way the
scientific way you have to communicate
you have to validate in other labs you
have to share methodologies and work
together and so they still see that
there's more need for that communication
to develop those standardized testing
methodologies and then proficiency
testing proficiency testing is one of my
biggest challenges because we can't take
a sample of cannabis and send it to
every lab in the u.s. because of
crossing state lines
so it's very challenging to do a
proficiency testing program so for many
contaminants toxicity is cumulative the
cultivation product processing
activities need to consider the
different sources to minimize those
certainly a lot more work needs to be
done and understand the toxicity
especially when it comes to inhalation
combustion and inhalation those are
areas that really need more study and
regulatory consists considerations are
becoming more important they're always
evolving some of the numbers in my slide
may be off because literally the states
are revving them constantly and then
standardized methods and proficiency
testing are really going to help the
labs generate reliable data but
ultimately is that part of that whole
process we need to communicate better I
need to thank my colleagues at proverty
laboratories as well as a number of the
vendors who we've worked with over the
past three or four years who live just
as I said been very
a part of and helpful in our process is
getting up and running and with that I'd
like to thank you
you