welcome back to the canmed coffee talk
lounge here at canmed2022
i'm your host ben emerald host of the
canmed coffee talk podcast and i am
joined today by eloise thiessen eloise
thanks for joining us
um first of all how nice is it to be
back at an in-person event
and um in your opinion what are the main
takeaways that you get from an in-person
event like cam ed well it's great to be
back it's so good to see people and
reconnect my favorite part is getting to
actually
um have in-person conversations you know
there's something
missing in that virtual zoom world
sometimes you just can't connect with
people the same way you can in person so
lots of opportunities to ask questions
too and
talk about our experiences in a way that
you don't get to on zoom
right
and you know it's important to bring
that up because we do make the
presentations available on our youtube
channel and in our archive which is a
great resource but but you're right it's
those
networking opportunities those
conversations in between the talks that
you get the real value and of course the
hugs yeah hugs are nice
are there any presentations at this
year's event in particular that you're
interested or looking forward to oh
absolutely i'm definitely looking
forward to hearing from dr ethan russo
i'm looking forward to hearing from
dr bonnie goldstein as well i always
love
hearing dr dustin sulak because you get
a lot of that clinical
implications and how they practice real
world real life experience with patients
that you just get to take away great
nuggets yeah and they're a big part of
our practicum as are you
and i was in there a little bit earlier
and i saw during your welcome that you
you asked how many people in the
audience this was their first experience
doing medical cannabis training and
there were a lot of hands that went up i
would say about two-thirds yeah so
that's that's really promising it is
because we need more trained physicians
and nurses and nurse practitioners out
there too absolutely yeah very important
that your healthcare team starts to
understand the value
and the risks the benefits of cannabis
because as we know our patients are
using it um there's no turning back
train has left the station
absolutely and so
about that so your presentation in
addition to your time on the practicum
in addition to your being a panelist on
on a panel
it's all about managing alzheimer's and
dementia symptoms with cannabis
first i was wondering can you speak to
how common these symptoms are especially
in assisted living communities and what
makes them so difficult to manage oh
yeah i mean the neuropsychiatric
symptoms that we see in dementia happens
in the later stages of dementia so you
know early diagnosis you you may just
start to notice memory loss but these
symptoms of agitation anxiety
aggression really start to come as their
memories become even you know more void
so that at that point they're usually
not even recognizing their loved ones or
their family members so you can tell
that they're
just this constant state of anxiety it's
actually quite heartbreaking to see
and we don't have any fda approved
medications to manage these symptoms so
people are either using off-label
medications or they're looking to you
know try something
sort of outside of the box
like cannabis right and you know i saw
that in your abstract as well where you
said that there are no fda approved
medications
that's that's surprising given how
prevalent it is and why is that the case
i you know i wish i knew i mean it's for
me what is really interesting is to see
that the medications that we do use like
antipsychotics have this black box
warning which means there's a higher
risk of death associated with use in
dementia patients so even what we are
trying to use feels like the risk is way
bigger than any benefit
i think that you know more research
probably goes into trying to figure out
how to prevent
or slow down the cognitive decline
associated with dementia but not into
the actual managing of the behaviors
interesting okay and i guess that's a
good segue is there an opportunity or is
there potential to use cannabis as a
preventative medication there's
definitely some preclinical data to
suggest that it's a
neuroprotectant of course it reduces
inflammation
there was a small study looking at it
preventing the beta amyloid plaque
buildup although there's some debate now
whether or not beta-amyloid plaques are
actually contributing to alzheimer's
disease specifically so
i would like to see more research in
that area to see
if it can help with the anti-aging
process that of course can contribute to
dementia as we age
excellent and i know we mentioned that
there are no fda approved medications
now
what do you think the chances are of
getting an fda approved cannabis
medication for this well what's
interesting is
sativex which is not approved in the
united states has been
studied
for the use of neuropsychiatric symptoms
in dementia patients and so i think
there's an opportunity for that
one-to-one cbd thc
oral mucosal spray to be used to manage
i mean the the results have been
incredibly promising it's been helping
with sleep and agitation sometimes you
see a return to appetite you see
improved quality of life so i think
until we actually have
approval of something like that here in
the united states i mean
uh it's going to be a while but i hope
so yeah
no and it's great that you mentioned
sort of that
improving the quality of life aspect of
this and i know especially dealing with
geriatric patients like that's a that's
a major concern or not our major a major
goal i should say is improving that
quality of life and maybe speak to how
cannabis can help with that
yeah i think um it's actually the
conversation i love to have with the
family members because often when they
come to me they are
usually saying well i want to try cbd
for you know my
my mom or my dad's behaviors and you
know really thc
a lot of the data does support the thc
is going to be really effective and so
having that conversation with them
because they're a little scared of thc
about what does euphoria look like for
them you know so letting them know that
you know well maybe your dad's gonna
smile again
you know you might laugh at things find
things funny again and you know usually
they go you know that'd be really nice
to see my dad happy again he's but it's
very um anxiety producing for the family
members and caregivers to see how
distressed their loved one is so it
really does have this like positive
domino effect to just see them
making jokes again or engaging in
conversation the best they can
and now are you finding those
conversations are becoming easier to
have where you know seniors or families
are becoming more receptive to using
cannabis just because you know
whether it's the anecdotal evidence or
the actual evidence that's been coming
out seems to support it it does and it
also helps when in the assisted living
communities i have a lot of um champions
there both staff caregivers
other
families who have been you know having
their loved ones use it so you get a lot
of community support around it
and acceptance which has been really
nice and you know sometimes i have
patients who have such great success
that their spouse will actually go up to
the other family member and say let me
tell you a little secret i got my wife
on these gummies you know you should
consider it
absolutely and one thing i wanted to ask
you too is you know there's a growing
interest in psilocybin or psychedelic
mushrooms and you know even us at
medicinal genomics we're beginning to
explore that and see how we can sort of
help um move that along um
i'm curious is there any sort of
evidence or potential for using
psilocybin to help with these conditions
yeah i mean specifically in the
neuropsychiatric symptoms no but i think
there's great opportunity there you know
it's
you know with looking at you know
palliative care you know when people are
diagnosed with a terminal illness but
maybe they're going to live for years
like with dementia and alzheimer's
disease i think we really have a missed
opportunity of how do we help these
people still enjoy life you know where's
the pleasure for them whether that's
with you know psychedelics and
psilocybin or cannabinoids and euphoria
listening to music again you know having
those pleasurable moments i think
there's great opportunity and and we
know that we're seeing
psilocybin helpful for things like
mental health challenges and pain so i i
know there's there's room for it people
want to feel good right yeah there's
nothing wrong with it at all absolutely
okay so in wrapping up here i did want
to get your thoughts that you know given
that so much of the research that's
being done into medical cannabis is
being done by
private companies in a lot of ways just
because of the you know the realities of
prohibition how important is it for
those companies to come to events like
canmed and share those insights so that
you know
the the whole community community can
kind of benefit from that and we can
help these patients
oh yeah i think it's essential i mean
you know we need to be listening to each
other uh in terms of what everybody's
doing and you know again figuring out
how do we come together as a community
to to really help these patients
there's different unique perspectives
that people have that you may not really
again understand
unless you're coming to these events
networking having an opportunity to ask
these questions that you know maybe you
didn't even think of until you're in the
moment with those people and um
so i would really love to see the
industry come together more
absolutely yeah and it's great you
mentioned that the different
perspectives and that's one of the
things we like to focus on at canmed we
have the the wonderful healthcare
providers like you and bonnie and dustin
um but then we bring in the cultivators
and the lab safety testing and
everybody so so it there's so much to
learn when it comes to cannabis i can
see why it's intimidating for some
healthcare professionals because i never
understood the value of um
you know learning more about botany
but that has been eye-opening for me as
a clinician and the lab testing
um and the cultivation all of that i
couldn't do what i do unless i
understood all of those components
excellent we and we couldn't do what we
do without people like you so thank you
very much thank you for joining us and
thank you to our sponsors medicine women
health and the hemp coffee exchange for
sponsoring this great kmed coffee talk
lounge and we'll be back with more
you