now we've got the backdrop for our
bodies endocannabinoid system a
self-healing self-regulatory system this
concept of network pharmacology complex
interactions and hopefully letting go of
some of the need to understand all that
complexity in a reductionistic way but
feeling a little more comfortable
zooming out and understanding that the
future of medicine and the past may be
these complex botanical medicines used
appropriately and I really believe and
am seeing now that cannabis is the
gateway cannabis is leading medicine
back to greater comfort with a botanical
treatment greater comfort with multi
Constituent treatment and and complexity
levels of complexity that we don't fully
understand yet are comfortable enough
with because of the safety profile to
use in our patients so let's dig into
cannabis or actually specifically
cannabinoid pharmacology the following
lecture will address the terpenes and so
here we have the flower the compound
flower of cannabis sativa and if we zoom
in a little bit more we see the
trichomes these are resin glands present
on the little flowering structures and
this is where all the magic happens
these are factories of dozens hundreds
of compounds that have physiologic
activity and so just zooming in you know
the things that we're focused most on
would be the THC in the CBD and of
course as dr. Michelin pointed out this
morning very low levels of THC and CBD
are found in the raw cannabis flower
it's actually the THC a and the CBD a
the acidic forms and you can see that
little carboxylic acid moiety and the
molecules there and those were
considered the inactive forms of these
compounds for a long time and now
they're starting to gain some
recognition but of course raw
or very slightly heated preparations of
cannabis have been used in medicine for
a very long time so we're gonna dig in a
THC and CBD first and then we'll take a
tour of some of the other cannabinoid
compounds so THC is a partial agonist at
the cb1 and cb2 receptor much like
Ananda mind THC very closely mimics the
activity of our endocannabinoids and
probably the biggest difference is that
when someone is exposed to th see this
exogenous vital cannabinoid they end up
with a global cannabinoid effect right
it's going to be distributed into all
the tissues and affect them systemically
I'm just gonna try to get this a little
closer compared to compared to when our
bodies make an and amide it's done in a
very specific manner and it has very
short term activity but the effects of
THC analgesic antipruritic agonist at CB
1 excuse me bronchodilator a neuro
protective anti-inflammatory antiemetic
and then of course the psychoactive but
that's just to name a few really
anything that cb1 and cb2 can do THC can
do now that's probably the most
clinically relevant function of THC but
a lot of people aren't aware the THC is
extraordinarily active or promiscuous if
you would say at other targets we don't
know how relevant some of these targets
are but THC activates two other
g-protein couple receptors that are at
least peripherally involved in the
endocannabinoid system that's 18 and 55
P power gamma trip a one trip v two trip
III and Trippi before so notice the
absence of trip v1 which is the
capsaicin receptor but THC is active at
other receptors in this Vanna Lloyd
system and then THC has some receptor
inhibition activity as well again these
show up mostly in in-vitro work we don't
know how clinically relevant they are
but they probably some of them are in
some situations THC also has a lot of
effects actually enhancing or decreasing
the activity of various enzymes
throughout the body
again not really sure how clinically
relevant but I like to point out what we
don't know because I think that helps us
helps us prevent ourselves from assuming
we know everything there's a lot going
on with just THC THC is also inhibiting
or enhancing transporters of various
neuro trend yeah you will you can see
there adenosine dopamine noradrenaline
serotonin so the transport of these from
the synapse back into the cell can be
enhanced or inhibited by THC it's a lot
going on there with THC although it's
probably mostly this partial agonist
effect it's cb1 and cb2 now CBD is quite
different it has a lot of overlap with
THC in its clinical effects both can
help with pain both can help with
anxiety with inflammation and so forth
and it's interesting that CBD does not
directly act upon the main targets of
THC the cb1 and cb2 receptors it has
very low affinity for those receptors
and in fact it acts as a non-competitive
inverse agonist so a competitive agonist
or a full agonist is something that
would just completely block the activity
of either THC or the endocannabinoids at
this receptor we have a molecule that
does this called Ramana bent very useful
in research it was actually approved as
a drug given to people in Europe they
experienced severe side effects
including dysphoria depression and
suicide and so it was polled the goal
with Ramana Banta as a therapeutic agent
was to limit the munchies and actually
be an anti obesity drug but it limited a
lot more than the munchies CBD is very
different from that it doesn't block the
cb1 receptor as you can if you can see
in the bottom image there it's
interacting at an allosteric site so the
anandam ID the two AG the THC could
still bind to the receptor but the
signal that comes out of this receptor
is turned down so CBD is basically
turning down the volume of the activity
of these cb1 agonists and likely cb2 as
well even though that's not super clear
yet but that's not
exactly how CVD is that's not the only
way that CVD is working and I think a
lot of the benefits that we attribute to
CVD are not based on this negative
allosteric modulation of cb1 and cb2
they're based on these other targets
especially the 5-htt one a serotonin
receptor which is likely the mechanism
of CBDs anti-nausea properties and
probably some of its mood boosting
properties as well as some of its
ability to protect the central nervous
system after an insult because
interacting with that receptor can
improve vascular supply to damaged areas
the trip v1 through trip v4 and that
includes the trip v1 capsaicin receptor
which is a great target for pain
inflammation in some psychiatric illness
p-per gamma has been mentioned several
times today also the glycine receptor
which has implications for pain and then
CBD antagonizes a variety of receptors
we don't have to go through them all and
it inhibits the transporter reuptake of
various neurotransmitters and if you
notice the bottom one there anand amide
which is quite important so i'll CBD is
turning down the volume at cb1 and cb2
as well it's also enhancing the activity
of an animai by keeping it around in the
synapse by inhibiting its reuptake and
also weakly inhibiting foul which is the
enzyme that breaks down anonymized so
actually two different mechanisms of
increasing in an amide activity which
would then enhance cb1 signaling so CVD
is kind of working on cv one in two
different directions here and then CBD
also has activity in the mitochondria
which is interesting we didn't have time
to mention it this morning but the
mitochondria have cannabinoid receptors
as well and so much of medicine is now
starting to look at mitochondrial
function as a major player and
neurologic illness and chronic disease
and I think the cannabinoid system has
some things to offer us there but to tie
this all up with CBD we see these
antispasmodic a Ning Xia lytic an
antidepressant and so forth no
protective effects just a base
summary slide and my experience CBD
works the best in combination with THC
this is where it really shines as a
standalone agent a single molecule
pharmaceutical CBD absolutely has some
power but it really in the context of
some of the other aspects of the plant
in particular THC CBD works well why
because it antagonize --is some of the
side effects of THC while enhancing some
of the benefits of THC basically widens
the therapeutic window of THC when used
together in it even decreases the
appetite of effects of THC for those
worried about the munchies again we
don't need Romana bands to help us with
that but I will mention that that hasn't
this idea that CBD kind of limits the
high of THC is likely the case to some
extent but it doesn't show up that
clearly in all the literature there's
kind of mixed results so I just want to
paint a picture that's not black or
white this was a study that showed that
administering fairly generous doses of
CBD at 90 minutes before smoking fairly
weak cannabis cigarettes containing THC
night is supplied you can see it's like
5% THC
by weight it didn't it basically didn't
make people say that they were not high
it didn't work like that I don't know
based on this study if a oral dose of
CBD administer prior to THC smoking will
diminish the high you can see really no
difference in the results what it did
diminish though was the in the adverse
aspects of the psychoactive effects the
anxiety and the paranoia and the
uncomfortable feeling I suspect that a
lot of the UV phoria and the inXile Isis
and the other desirable psychoactive
properties of THC are able to shine
through even a very high dose of CBD
administered beforehand but when we look
at the really severe adverse effects of
THC like an acute psychotic experience
CBD actually does seem to limit that so
this is from
McCallum and Rousseau from a couple
years ago their paper on dosing which
was well done looking at kind of the the
threshold for toxic psychosis of marinol
which is just a pure THC drug was about
18 milligrams and it's shows it pretty
small here so I can't quite see it but
if I remember correctly a combination of
approximately one to one CBD and THC the
threshold for toxic psychosis was around
50 milligrams so half of that would be
25 so basically in the presence of an
equal quantity of CBD the threshold for
psychosis from THC went from 18 up to 25
and you can see that's widening the
therapeutic index someone could tolerate
more without experience this severe
experiencing 'no severe side effects so
these two do go very well together and I
think we have more to learn about
exactly how they interact and how they
work together but this this story is not
just about CBD and THC this plant is
just a treasure trove of phyto
constituents that have therapeutic
activities many cannabinoids terpenes
the acidic s-- and then also important
to remember as Kevin mentioned earlier
that plants figure this out a long time
ago since they can't run away from
predators how do they defend themselves
it's it's with these factories so the
trichomes are on the female reproductive
structures of cannabis the structures
that are going to be the most vulnerable
to damage from ultraviolet and other
accidents to pests molds invaders and so
these antimicrobial and antioxidant
properties that the plant is producing
these compounds to achieve in the plant
they are also conveyed to people who
take these as anti microbials and
antioxidants so moving along cbn just
some of the pharmacology it binds to CB
2 a little bit better than CB 1 in both
cases it's less potent to tea less
potent than THC but very similar to THC
now CBN is not produced by the plant per
se but it's an oxidative breakdown
product of THC so especially in regions
where there's a lot of humidity and you
would traditionally dry the cannabis
flowers out in the Sun that ultraviolet
light will convert some of the THC into
CBN and that gives the flower a bit of a
different quality mildly sedated
according to a report in 1976 I think a
lot of people in the cannabis field
assume that CBN is sedating and I think
for some people it is but there what
I've observed is a lot of inter
individual variability where CBN does
seem to help some people sleep and it
seems to wake some people up and there's
probably dozens of factors in there
including the oxidation of the other
components that nobody's looking at that
we're not really considering
anti-inflammatory properties and also
antibiotic properties including opponent
agent against mersa antibiotic
resistance not resistant to cbn and some
of the other cannabinoids as well so
moving on to CBG we have very low
activity at cb1 and cb2 it does activate
the trip v and the trip a receptors and
the alpha-2 adrenergic that's the
adrenal scepter like clonidine and
guanfacine so clonidine used for
treating blood pressure but also a very
valuable some paths oolitic guanfacine
which is and has less of the blood
pressure effects but used more for
attention deficit so perhaps CBG will
emerge is something that can help with
that by suppressing excessive
sympathetic activity do any of your
patients have excessive sympathetic
activity do any of you inhibits a
variety of receptors as well also
antineoplastic antimicrobial and anti
depressant effects and there may be some
evidence that CBC in the presence of th
so you can actually potentiate the THC
to some extent and I have had reports
that varieties that contain a little
more CBC than typical seem more
psychoactive but that's not due to the
CBC that's due to enhanced THC activity
then we have THC v which is a cb-one
antagonist at low doses but a cb1
agonist at higher doses could this plant
throw us at any more curveballs
hopefully yes but this is an interesting
one so at these low doses this could
also be an anti Munchie drug so to speak
because of this gentle antagonism
producing weight loss decreased body fat
and decreased leptin concentrations
increased energy expenditure at least in
mice has anticonvulsant properties
decreased edema and hyperalgesia in a
mouse model and also it lacks the
adverse effect liabilities of your
typical in inverse agonist like ramana
Bant it does not cause that dysphoria
and that dysregulation of the no
cannabinoid system as far as we know
moving on to some of the acidic ste HCA
is none psychoactive but I will say that
anytime there is any THC a present there
is always at least a tiny bit of THC
some of the earlier work on THC a was
very confounded because some researchers
found that it's got some cb1 stimulating
activity and some researchers found it
didn't and it was kind of confusing but
there's no such thing as a pure THC a
standard even the most pure will have a
small amount of THC in it that was shown
by McPartland a few years ago but not
psychoactive nevertheless a strong
inhibitor of tumor necrosis factor alpha
release which is a major inflammatory
component of a chronic disease
anti-cancer effects also it's at least
to some extent via the P PI receptors
and it has some inhibitory activity at
trip m8 activating trip a one-in trip
before and and some of these other
cation channels so that's
THCA in my practice i found it very
useful for treating arthritis it takes a
little bit longer for people to respond
to it because it's not an analgesic per
se it's an anti-inflammatory but usually
at the two or four week mark people are
starting to notice a difference and I
usually am recommending it via T because
there's not a lot of THC a products
available and I think can
he is a really great delivery method
moving on to CB da the CB da is much
more similar to CB d than th CA is to
THC if you look at the pharmacology of
THC a and THC they're very distinct CBD
a has a lot of overlap with CBD and it
seems to be more powerful it activates
the 5-htt 1a serotonin receptor but much
more strongly does not seem to act on
the CB 1 or cb2 receptors so as we
described before in many situations it's
valuable to get that negative allosteric
modulation of cb1 and cb2 in order to
make people tolerate their THC better
but that's not always what we're looking
for sometimes we want the full power of
THC to shine through yet we also want
some CBD like effects and the mix and in
my opinion that's where CBD a comes in
because it can convey many of CBDs
beneficial qualities at a much lower
dose without the negative allosteric
modulation of cb1 and cb2 so that's a
strategy to consider CBD a is also with
the only cannabinoid that's a strong
cox-2 inhibitor and again we don't know
if CBD a would share some of the
liabilities and side-effects of some of
the other cox-2 inhibition drugs and
when used at high doses I would be
cautious with some of the other problems
like gastrointestinal and cardiovascular
but the beautiful thing about it is we
don't need to use it in high doses so
here's a little data from 2013 in a
rodent model of nausea they're counting
something called gapes
because these rodents don't vomit they
they just gag and so you can count them
after administering a high dose of
lithium chloride which would make most
of us gag and see what the antiemetic
activity is and so I point out the
increased efficacy of THC a compared to
th see the this dosing here on the
bottom you can see it's milligrams per
kilogram so point zero five milligrams
per kilogram of tea
see a a tiny tiny dose even for humans
especially tiny for rodents suppress
their nausea ten times that dose of THC
a didn't make it any better but it
really was ten times that dose of THC
that was required to even show some
effect so there was no effect of THC Oh
point zero five it was 0.5 0.5 of THC
where you began to see the effect so 10x
the potency at least on THC a how did
these researchers know to look in these
very low dosing ranges of THC a I'm not
sure I'll tell just a quick story about
THC a because I've been looking at the
very low dosing range of it for a while
for about five years now with great
surprise still so back in 2013 as many
of you are aware Sanjay Gupta came out
with his first documentary weeds and
people were you know looking for CBD to
treat their seizures and their kids
especially and at the time we had just
started a cannabis analytic laboratory
in my clinical practice and I was very
excited when a patient came in and said
I got this bottle of CBD from the
dispensary and it's working my daughter
seizures are way down and I said well
yeah and I had heard that story a couple
times before but this was the first
chance I had to really find out what the
dosage was because back then there was
no labeling no testing we were the first
analytic lab in our state and so I
grabbed a bottle and we took a little
sample of it we ran it through the HPLC
and I was expecting to find out how much
CBD this kid was getting the answer was
zero
there was no CBD in that bottle there
was pretty much no THC in that bottle it
was a very weak glycerate of THC a that
was the only peak that was significant
in their THC a and the kid was getting
such a low dose I had a very hard time
believing that that was working for
seizures but but you know I'm not sure
about the placebo effect in cases like
this certainly parental report can be
influenced by things that the parent
hopes is working and so I didn't really
know what to make out of it except that
the dispensary was selling something
that
what they said it was it was some kind
of a cannabis oil that didn't get people
hi it must be CBD but it was actually
just a tea raw cannabis infusion into
glycerin anyways that happened a few
more times and I talked to a few people
around the world that we're seeing the
same thing before I believed it THC a
has an efficacy range way way down lower
than most people would expect in certain
situations then the authors who did that
last study looked at CBD a but notice
the scale is different now micrograms
per kilogram they went even lower on CBD
a and they found that a half of a
microgram per kilogram again that is so
small and rodents it's hard to even
describe maybe the equivalent in a human
would be brushing up against a cannabis
flower and letting some of that resin
get on your arm
and absorbed through the skin I mean
this is tiny tiny dosing reduced nausea
in a similar rodent nausea model and
here we just have the chart looking at
cox-1 and cox-2 in comparison with
indomethacin and diclofenac and you can
see the big signal and CBD a at the
bottom of the graph there now there has
been some anticonvulsant activity
reported around THC a way back in 1970
what was s in 1974 I think 1979 it was
at very high doses in rodents and again
as you'll learn from the rest of today
the cannabinoids are very dichotomous so
you know they they work in very high
doses they work in very low doses
there's bi-directional effects and
biphasic effects we're going to cover
all of that later but it again doesn't
surprise me that we see some activity
against seizures of very high doses and
at extraordinarily low doses now let's
talk about some of the pharmacokinetic
properties of THC and how our bodies
deal with this and we know surprisingly
little about the pharmacokinetics and
the metabolism of many of the other
cannabinoids but it's likely analogous
to THC where we have the absorption the
concentration into the body fluid we
have
metabolism in the liver and I'll show
you some of the metabolites in a future
slide and then we have excretion both
through the feces and through the urine
as well as through the skin and the hair
so bioavailability of THC as you can see
it ranges quite a bit this is an older
study that summarized some of the data
that was available but oral by oval
bioavailability is pretty low regardless
of what study you look at inhalation
gets a bit higher and then there were a
couple studies of recto by rectal
bioavailability which showed that Hemi
succinate preparation was much more
bioavailable than a regular suppository
and in general worked a little bit
better than oral but let's take a look
at some of these curves so on the left
and um and thank you for getting this up
here I appreciate it maybe in the future
there is a way to switch this up so that
it's a little bigger because the slides
appear quite small on this monitor but
you don't have to deal with it now so
looking looking on the left I believe we
have the oral you guys tell me where are
we on the Left chart is this
maybe yeah Wow we need some help here
has this sorry say it again
inhaling okay so oh right inhaling I can
see it now so with the inhaled cannabis
you can see the dotted line is the peak
of THC and that Peaks very very high
early on 15 minutes we give this peak
effect and then it drops rapidly we
don't see a lot of 11 hydroxy THC that's
the larger dashed line towards the
bottom because there's not that first
pass metabolism with inhaled but over
time what we see is the carboxy THC
which is an inactive metabolite and I'll
review those metabolites on the
following slide now as we go over to the
right we have a different scale on the
y-axis so I just want you to note that
look what happens when people take THC
by mouth the blood level of THC stays
way down do you see it way down there at
the bottom there's a decent level not
not decent I mean
slightly higher level of 11 hydroxy THC
which is an active metabolite and then
we have this large quantity of the
inactive metabolite so we have low oral
bioavailability and a lot of first pass
metabolism that really ends up making
very low levels of these active
constituents in the blood but what I'll
say is that the blood levels of these
compounds don't correlate directly with
the clinical effects and a really good
example of that is when people inhale
THC their peak blood level of THC occurs
at a different time than the peak
psychoactive experience when they're
peaking psychoactive lis their blood
level has already dropped and so you
could give someone that tiny little bump
of THC you see in the bottom of the
middle chart there and that might feel
stronger than what you're seeing over to
the left as far as a as far as a
psychoactive effect so it's it really
doesn't correlate directly and and it's
not just psychoactive it's analgesic and
anti-inflammatory HC it's very likely to
cause psychotic transient experience so
the metabolism of THC is mainly in the
liver but there's extra hepatic
metabolism as well and you can see just
as I've mentioned a few times here
there's an 11 hydroxy form that is an
active metabolite I think people assume
that it's more psychoactive it certainly
may be that way for some but I think
it's just qualitatively different people
that take cannabis more via an oral
mucosal route versus swallowing it would
be able to kind of describe some of the
difference between having more
first-pass and less first pass
metabolism and usually there's a
qualitative difference some people say
the first pass you know by swallowing it
they get more of a muscle relaxant
effect or maybe a more of a body effect
less of a cerebral effect
and some people say the exact opposite
so I'm not sure now here we have CBD
pharmacokinetics very high doses as you
can see unfortunately most of our
patients can't afford 6,000 milligrams
but I guess it's worth trying that in a
single dose just to see how safe it is
which is ridiculous it's that safe but
twice daily dosing it's still very high
levels for six days and evaluating the
effect of having it after a meal or on
an empty stomach and this was delivered
via the new drug epidemics and so first
of all the adverse effects diarrhea
nausea headache and somnolence time to
the maximum plasma concentration was
four to five hours it reached a steady
state after approximately two days with
very moderate accumulation and so
probably some of the time a steady dose
of CBD for even you know we could say
maybe three days then we've reached a
steady blood level and I think that's
important when we talk later about how
frequently to titrate a dose we wouldn't
want to titrate it one day after the
next we want to give that much time for
someone to achieve a steady level
half-life 10 to 17 hours no change in
their labs even with the super high
doses physical exam vital signs ECG or
body weight no consistent effect on
sleep or sleepiness this shows up a lot
in literature in my experience CBD seems
to help some people sleep it seems to
keep some people awake hard to predict
who's gonna be who and no clear evidence
of any drug withdrawal syndrome during
the trial
so quite safe and some of the
conclusions or takeaway points
twice-daily administration seems to make
sense
taken with a high-fat meal you can get 4
to 5 fold the oral absorption so that's
probably a good idea to recommend people
to take it after breakfast and after
lunch is usually what I'm doing again
because sometimes I'm cautious about
after dinner in case it keeps them awake
all adverse effects from mild or
moderate
and safety data is consistent with
what's currently established we'll skip
that little part on the side there so
here's some pharmacokinetics published
for the first time in the last year
about the acidic cannabinoids as you can
imagine I got very excited to see this
it confirmed what I was suspecting so
the acidic cannabinoids having a
carboxylic acid group on there they are
more hydrophilic right there they're a
little more water-soluble and maybe get
better distributed in the body so let's
take a look at what happened here first
we can see a comparison of THC and CBD
when taken in two forms one is a
decoction which is like a tea except
it's simmered for a prolonged period of
time while covered and the other is an
oil and you can see that these were
so-called bill enok preparations out of
Italy some of the studies out of Italy
are looking at the right things but I
feel like the rigor of their starting
materials and procedures can be a little
weak but I'm so glad they're looking at
THC a and and so you can see that there
was some variability especially in the
decoction quite a bit of variability and
actually what people were taking but
nevertheless some interesting results
here some more THC absorbed
excuse me more CBD absorbed than THC in
the decoction and then over here when we
start looking at the acidic s--
so that orange peak that's THC a if
you're looking for the THC peak as far
as what was absorbed you can see it's
just way way down there and yeah I could
do a better job of exploring explaining
if I could actually see it from up here
but what I think you'll notice is that a
lot greater absorption of THC a compared
to THC in both the oil and the decoction
and if you look at the top of this slide
you'll see that there were roughly equal
parts right so we're getting much better
absorption the other thing that's kind
of flipped on its head and that the
studies showed and it's a little hard to
see remember the oral dosing a
pharmaceutical grade THC we saw higher
levels of 11 hydroxy than we saw of the
parent compound THC that
back that's reversed in this so here we
have higher levels of THC than the 11
hydroxy and that's likely because the
presence of these other cannabinoids the
acidic cannabinoids is inhibiting some
of that first pass metabolism of THC
right and that's something that happens
a lot in complex botanical medicines is
that the variety of compounds with
Sherriff similar structures when they
get to the liver
they have pharmacokinetic effects on the
metabolism and can really change well
even before it gets the liver can change
the absorption and it can change the
metabolism and so it looks like having
some of these acidic cannabinoids can
decrease that conversion to 11 hydroxy
looking over here at CBD a again we see
some really pronounced absorption of CBD
a compared to CBD and this was just some
of the data so you can take a look at
the area under the curves and I did the
math for you and so it's looking like
THC a versus THC in the decoction was
absorbed 50 times better and 30 times
better out of an oil and more modest for
CBD but still a much higher absorption
for CBD a compared to CBD I'm just going
to wrap up here with a few more slides I
think this is a very important but
controversial topic and so I want you to
just be aware of the science that we
have behind it right now a good review
in the 2017 National Academies of
Sciences engineering medicine report
which looked at all the data on infants
that had been in children that have been
exposed to cannabinoids perinatally and
in prenatally and what they found was
that the only consistent finding was
smaller for gestational age this wasn't
dangerously small this was an ultra low
you know preterm and all that stuff but
it was smaller for gestational age which
was consistent with any exposure to
smoke
basically when someone's smoking they're
getting carbon monoxide they're getting
other chemical compounds that could
interfere with blood supply and other
factors in the fetus and cause a
slightly smaller baby we see it with
tobacco
as well and so these authors attributed
the small-for-gestational-age to the
smoke itself not to the cannabinoids and
and that's a very high-level summary
from the 2017 report there were actually
just three new studies that came out in
the last couple months looking at
cannabis and pregnancy and lactation and
their basic conclusion was that all the
rest of our data is really unreliable
because so much of it is based on
self-report and what one study came out
that looked at the difference between
self-report and urine toxicology screens
and as you can imagine there's a lot of
differences there for many good reasons
why moms aren't self reporting in
cannabis and why some are not sure and
in the current political environment
cannabinoids and lactation they are
present in breast milk once an early
study from 2013 estimated that the
neonate would be exposed to less than 1%
of the mothers exposure and that's per
kilogram of body weight so it is getting
into the breast milk but the exposure to
the infant is very small a subsequent
study found a little bit of a higher
result there 2.5% of the maternal dose
being delivered to the infant per
kilogram of body weight so unless mom's
taking a lot it's still very little
exposure to the infant but I'm not
saying that so that you assume very
little is irrelevant very very small
doses of cannabinoids can absolutely be
relevant I don't think we can say right
now if this is a good thing or a bad
thing because it probably depends on the
situation which is a complex family and
community situation that involves
factors like maternal stress and
maternal sleep and some of moms other
health issues and some of the babies
issues and the babies genetics that may
relate to the moms health issues and and
all sorts of factors here what we know
is that lots of kids have been exposed
to cannabis during pregnancy and
lactation and they don't develop
differently sometimes there's a little
acceleration or a little deceleration of
certain milestones prior to age five but
by the time they reach age five it's a
wash and so this this doesn't seem like
it's a
inherently dangerous for children to be
exposed to low levels and that is the
cannabinoid pharmacology talk thank you
[Applause]