[Music]
all right
in in looking at the results and we you
talked about dosing it seemed like there
was sort of a sweet spot range for the
dose that really got the best effect it
wasn't necessarily the highest dose that
got the best effect so I was wondering
if you could speak a bit to that sure I
mean this is we saw it across both
studies and Botanical drug extract and
in isolate and Tau model and not towel
model and then it's uh it's not really
surprising because we do expect just
about everything at a certain level to
have toxicity
um and and what we see actually CBG
appears to be less toxic in this model
than CBD milligram per milligram
um but but again you know you can
there's an ld50 for water so as you go
up eventually something's going to get
toxic
but I would also say in terms of
efficacy but this is
it's been a theory for some time about
this kind of inverted you or kind of
biphasic effects with cannabinoids I
think they're more profound with THC I
think there's a you know a narrow dose
window for THC uh we know that you know
low amounts uh or moderate amounts
increase appetite they may help with
anxiety they may help with sleep but
when you start giving really high doses
of THC you get massive paranoia nausea
and vomiting I mean it's not pretty
there are a bunch of hospitalizations
for people that you know didn't know how
much was in their brownie so you you
know as with
um these sorts of of physiological
effects you may see the same thing in
lifespan taking too much may be a
hindrance
um or or maybe neutral in terms of being
a benefit we still don't know kind of
where that sweet spot would be
especially as it relates to CBD and CBG
in humans
okay so can't necessarily apply the
dosage that was effective in C elegans
to humans like is there like a
conversion there that you could take
with in terms of what the dose would be
yeah there is a conversion um it's kind
of complicated how you do it in C
elegans there's two ways you could
actually look at the exposure you could
spin them down and look at their
exposure or you could use it as a
correlate with with other compounds that
have similar
lipophilicity so
um it is complicated but that 40
nanograms per ml or 40 nanograms of 40
micro molar excuse me
um is is certainly a physiologically
relevant amount and not the same as you
know if if I was doing work in a dish
right because
they're basically eating the medium so
that's concentration in the their food
essentially so
um not necessarily their exposure on the
cell level so when you see you know
cancer studies oftentimes we're applying
that and that would be the cell exposure
this is kind of the food exposure which
is relevant to their internal exposure
after metabolism
[Music]
thank you