this is a drug that was in common use
hundreds of years ago it was one of the
most prescribed drugs in 1900 it was in
the pharmacopoeia for for physicians so
it's already been approved who studied
the fact that we now have to reprove it
through the FDA which if you put aspirin
to the FDA today we wouldn't get through
is as is circular thinking
I'm Kevin mckernon I'm the CSO of
Corrigan life sciences and medicinal
genomics these are two companies that
are joined at the hip we look at
personalized medicine and patients so we
sequence patients their genomes to sort
out what types of defects they may have
or mutations in their genome that can be
properly treated and the same time we're
also focusing on medical cannabis safety
and so we look at the genetics of the
plants to try and help help bring some
more trust and security in that field
we are honored and extremely grateful to
have as our keynote speaker and our
scientific anchor and visionary for this
conference dr. rafael Mutulu I was
surprised very surprised to find out
that while we knew quite a lot about
morphine which had been isolated from
Optima many many decades previously in
the same is true for cocaine
the chemistry of cannabis was not well
known there was absolutely no interest
whatsoever nowadays it seems that
actually interest is going on more and
cannabidiol because of its therapeutic
activities and not being a top Singh and
not being psychoactive it can be
administered to patients at huge amounts
without any side effects the
endocannabinoid system is an extremely
important one and as a matter of fact
people from nih mentioned that it's
involved in essentially all human
diseases very very strong statement our
group showed to AG works against brain
damage so we have seen three or four of
these compounds working against brain
damage others have found that CBD does
that in mice but we have seen no work in
humans
with science gets politicized rational
discourse disappears and a feeling that
really has happened in this field we're
not addressing this in a rational
thoughtful way and but we can hundreds
of thousands of patients are already
using cannabis to treat symptoms but
it's really important to study it in a
controlled setting because we need to
understand what the potential risks are
of cannabis use in specific patient
populations and we need to understand
how the drug interacts with other drugs
the patient might we have tilray is one
of the only companies in the world
capable of producing GMP grade cannabis
and cannabis derived medications this is
possible because tiller is located in
Canada where federal regulations allow
the production of cannabis and also
cannabis extracts that can be used in
clinical research around the world
that's what we want to do is produce
scientifically sound methodologically
sound research that will hopefully
change policy and also provide
mainstream physicians with the tools
they need in order to treat patients
with cannabis derived extracts
my daily living was my hands shaking so
severe I couldn't stop it
I had suicidal thoughts constantly rage
to no end the only reason I'm here today
being able to do this is because of
canvas there is thank you
year ago today I stopped taking all
those pills and strictly using cannabis
I have not had a moment of thought to
suicide or the depression that I was
constantly under if an individual
decides to do what you're doing he's
being helped that's fine
but the physician or the physicians will
not do that I'm personally trying to vie
for clinical trials in football players
and that we have this brain disease that
leads to Alzheimer's and dementia and
all these horrific things we wanted to
find out whether the cannabinoid system
effect the damage then by concussion we
found that we could reduce by 50% the
damage that was done so here we have
strong data showing that a cannabis type
compound helps at the moment these
compounds have never never been given to
a human right not only for concussion
for anything this rage thing that comes
along with this brain disease is very
scary and when I found certain strains
of cannabis and have those feelings
anymore and being in Tennessee where I
was that it was difficult to get strains
it's like hey what do you got this week
we've been trying to put an end to that
by sequencing all the strains and making
a huge catalogue of every strain so you
can actually gently fingerprinted no all
right did it change on me if I'm just
curious your experience on that see when
I got to California I knew okay go get
my card let me go down and start trying
these strengths because I knew there was
something with it we're still really
early days tying genotypes
to patients but we're slowly building
this database of variants that we know
predict some level responsible CVD
eventually it's gonna go there do you
think you've been on using THC or CBD
long enough to get a sense of long-term
effects on for cannabis oh yeah and I
don't take Wow leave aspirin or vicodin
or anything anymore and people say
marijuana is a gateway drug I said you
know what a gateway drug is football
yeah the most exciting research we've
seen in addiction medicine is in CBD
reducing those dopes emerging addictive
desires and it's one of the most
promising drugs for ending addiction
that we've seen yet hemp is probably the
first agricultural plant that we ever
domesticated right around
thank you 37 we've ripped that from her
diet and added antibiotics we have
caffeine given to kids in orange soda in
school and your died as parents and
never been told about it many of these
kids are on ritalin methylphenidate okay
what does that do to brain
there's a host of things that we've
somehow said we're not gonna worry about
what that doesn't develop your mind but
we're gonna apply that that scrutiny to
THC there's there's no logic stuff and
when you see children with epilepsy
getting it and they're coming alive like
what's this third rail about Pediatrics
all about so I have a son with severe
epilepsy
it was untreated and it's a really
severe disease he was really suffering
and I met a dad at an epilepsy
conference who told me that marijuana
was helping his son who had severe
epilepsy
I looked up whether marijuana had any
compounds that might be anti convulsive
and I found some literature from the 70s
and 80s showing that in fact CBD is
pretty consistently anti convulsive 35
years ago we administered cannabidiol to
epileptic patients and we found those
eight patients that got the material
four of them didn't have epileptic
attacks during the period and we gave
them cannabidiol three had much less and
one was not affected so what we want to
do is make sure that everyone has access
right now in whatever way they can but
at the same time do the rigorous
research that's required and so what I'm
going to figure out is how we can move
the needle very quickly on policy will
also collect input of the data we need
clinical trials and unfortunately until
recently there were very few clinical
trials policy I think has really
interfered with the progress of science
the legal table has to do something we
need
the stigma has something to do with it
it shouldn't be that way kids that we
have here that their severe epilepsy
they look and on ones are the
pharmaceutical drugs they look as if
they're complete zombies if you put them
on CBD and something like they're now
awake and conscious and they're having
conversations with their parents really
high I don't think they're high I think
you're just restoring the a
neurotransmitter imbalances going on
there is enough data already published
which shows that yes it lowers the
number of epileptic attacks we did that
35 years ago in adult patients very
little has been done since my son has
been living with this disease for seven
years and I still talk to senators who
say we have to be careful we have to go
slowly and I don't think we can expect
patients to wait for years for
medication is already available to them
there's this thing called sudden
unexplained death with a velocity that
they just died Bank they're gone if you
don't have these things under control
and so it's one of those scenarios where
music I do the right thing so my goal
now chill ray is to make sure that we
develop these cannabis derived
treatments as quickly as possible it's
been black market for so long that we
don't have a good way to track this and
so that's what we're trying to do here
is to change that is to genetically
sequence all of these strains and then
tie those down to the cannabinoids
intervenes that they make and track that
throughout time if you don't have that
information and you start going down the
Epilepsy route without it you're gonna
go through all types of surgery and
invasive procedures or go through 20
different drugs before they figure this
out having the information advanced
sidesteps all of that it gets you on the
right drug instantly you should no
longer be about whether to providing
access right the debate should now be
about
to provide them access and I think I we
can do that collectively by
mainstreaming this medicine we were the
really lucky one there are two hundred
thousand kids out there who still don't
have access to pure cannabidiol you can
no longer allow a medicine that has been
proven to protect our brains to be kept
from us any longer especially thank you
to our sponsors clear a three pack here
if we can tie more science around the
plants so people don't just write it off
as you know a hippy stream it's
something that's actually been studied
we understand the planet better than any
plant in the world and then we'll start
to consider maybe those how do we
synthesize those on the planet get them
into compounds we trust in people
you
[Music]