[Music]
you
I mean one thing that can mat does so
well is it demonstrates that this field
is exciting there's a ton of research on
different aspects of the field it's it's
well funded and there's a lot of
scientific interest and that this is
real this isn't this isn't just
anecdotal data this this is real
scientific evidence and a lot of valid
interest rule relax everything's real
open it's really easy to get out and
speak to one-on-ones i I've already seen
more cannabis science here and I've been
in kind of a science for six years I've
seen more too concentrated here than
anywhere else for this is late first
hand med and I actually I'm so impressed
I haven't been asleep for three days
because all the information stimulating
I love this conferences which my second
hair here and it's always full of
information and it's really important to
their dissipate in this my friend we
have to be many minds involved to solve
really complicated problems if you have
to take a very distributed approach that
you push innovation to the edge of
networks and allow for the spider
permissionless innovation
you