[Music]
all right
and so it all comes back to this idea of
um I guess trying to keep impaired
drivers off the road and you know and it
seems that lawmakers or law enforcement
is really kind of fixated on on finding
a biomarker to kind of determine
cannabis impairment sort of like a blood
alcohol or breathalyzer
um
to your knowledge are there any
biomarkers that are reliable or that
were that were close on for determining
cannabis impairment or is that still a
bit of a Holy Grail
yeah like if you're talking biological
like in some kind of fluid biomarkers uh
at present no we just uh we don't really
have anything that's particularly good
so the most commonly looked at things uh
probably urine blood and oral fluid
urine
um is probably the worst of the lot we
know that
um THC and it's metabolize
um things persist in urine for a really
really long time particularly among
regular users you know comfortably over
a month
um blood is is not particularly good
either it can hang around in blood for
extended periods of time and this is
largely because THC
um so it's a lipophilic molecule meaning
that it likes to get into fat and sort
of stay there so it accumulates in
people's fat stores and then just sort
of slowly leaches into blood meaning
that it can be there for again weeks and
sometimes longer after use
all fluid is a tricky Matrix
um it sort of has some benefits I guess
in that it is the Matrix that THC leaves
most rapidly
um so if you take someone who only very
occasionally uses cannabis and a
minister an acute dose you'll probably
find that it persists in all fluid for a
few hours and then dissipates which is
kind of consistent with impairment but
there are a number of kind of
significant limitations aside from that
um for example the first being that uh
so the only way that THC can end up in
oral fluid is if it enters via direct
contact so you have to you know have a
smoked or you know ingested in some way
that it actually contacts the oral fluid
meaning that if you avoid that contact
say for example if the THC is
encapsulated
um You probably won't have any THC in
all fluid um which means it's not a
marker of impairment at all the other
factor is that there's been really
little research research looking at Oral
fluid THC concentrations in regular
cannabis uses and what seems to be the
case is that whether THC is present in
oral fluid and regular cannabis uses is
just a it's completely variable
sometimes it's there 12 hours later
sometimes it's not detected and it's
just a little bit all over the shop so
on the face of it there are some
advantages to that approach but when you
dig a Little Deeper it sort of falls
apart really quickly so yeah
um we don't currently have a
particularly good way of identifying
cannabis impaired drivers
[Music]