[Music]
no and in reading through your abstract
as well um it said that you found that
cannabis aphids and thps can acquire and
transmit hlvd as well can you talk a bit
more about the significance of that
Discovery yes so this was um it was not
surprising in fact what was surprising
is was was that in hops they found that
hops Aid did not transmit hop latent
vroid and this was published where my in
in our world I mean aphids as you can
see in my background you see how
prolific they are in the on him and um
they can pretty much and they've been
shown to transmit other viroids so it
was kind of surprising that they that
they didn't find it in Hops and so we
set up out to um test aphids and thrips
and the reason we pick those are they
are the most common Greenhouse P right
they love the green house environment
because it's hot humid this makes some
the populations grow uh faster they and
there's a year round supply of uh uh
host host plants for them within five
minutes both insects can acquire the the
vroid which is really interesting it is
in the flum and aphids feed in the flum
of the plant but it's also in the but
trips have much shorter mouth Parts
aphid's mouth parts are like mosquitoes
they're the mosquitoes of the Plant
World so they can go all the way down to
the flow and suck up the vroid uh thps
are not but they must be picking it up
from the they're cell content feeders
they're going to just suck up all the
cell content cytoplasm nucleus every all
of it so that so there are different
mechanisms by which they're
acquiring the viroid but both are doing
it super
quickly um and and so that was that's
great any any any insect could acquire
it but the proof of the concept was to
then test uh transmission and to do that
we then starve the insects to to make
sure all of the gut content is is out of
the insect it's not just in there
transiently
right and then we place those in effects
on healthy plants and sure enough both
of them can transmit I think um my um my
other Master student is uh re retesting
some things but retesting some assays
but it's between 10 to 25% transmission
and we sequence every single amplicon we
don't just rely on the band on the PCR
uh uh gel band every single one is um
sequent so not entirely surprised in the
other one that I'm very keen to test is
spidermites which is another huge
problem a huge Greenhouse pest um and we
also find it in outdoor hem um so couple
of other insects to test the other uh
interesting aspect is uh last year uh we
saw that hops can also infect other host
right some really important host host
plants like
tomatoes um and um cryan so we want to
see if these vectors cannabis AIDS or um
thps Can transmit it to other host
plants as well because it just takes um
a few minutes to acquire and seemingly a
few minutes to transmit too interesting
[Music]
a