hi guys thank you all for coming my name
is Jorden Tischler I'm a physician and
I'm here to talk to you guys a little
bit about pain management and
consequentially reducing opiates I'd
like to take a moment to thank you all
for coming I think one of the things
that I've gotten out of this conference
in spades today has been the vast number
of interested folks and the astounding
amount of research and development
that's being done and I think it really
warms my heart as a clinician and I
would also like to take a moment to
thank courtesan and medicinal genomics
for putting on this kind of an event
[Applause]
so I you know to take a few seconds just
to explain Who I am and why I'm here in
blathering at you I am a Harvard
physician I trained in internal medicine
at the Brigham Women's Hospital which I
think is that way from here but I'm a
little turned around and then spent the
last 15 years or so working as an
emergency physician for the VA and so as
you can imagine I became de facto a bit
of an expert on drug and alcohol at
least the acute presentation of that and
really came to see an awful lot of
damage done by by subjects both legal
and illegal and that got me to thinking
about cannabis is a safer kind of
medication to treat patients so my talk
today is going to be a little different
in that I'm actually going to focus
almost exclusively on clinical matters
rather than on research because that's
what I know so pain is a huge problem
I'm not sure why I'm staring at this
thing and there's a monitor here but
pain is the number one presenting
complaint nationally and pain is the
number one complaint that patients say
we don't address well so this is a huge
problem and I think one of the things
that stems from that that we have to
understand as clinicians and as
researchers is the problems that we're
seeing nationally and even globally with
opiate use are really a demand-side
problem right right now we have all of
these governmental missives that say we
should prescribe less and doctors you'll
be held more accountable and you need to
look at the PMP and all this stuff and
that's fine band-aids but really the
problem here is that we don't have a
particularly good way to meet the demand
in a safe and effective manner
so enter cannabis we need to understand
the scope of the problem as I said our
current approaches don't work that well
when you look at drug overdoses the
current statistics are they kill more
people than garz
guns cars and
Halling and interestingly we have this
opiate crisis that we're addressing with
major public health initiatives but some
of these things I think might well also
qualify when we break it down the
problem here is that we only have three
alternatives right there are three drug
classes that we can use to address pain
unless of course you look at the
Massachusetts DPH silly initiative where
they list in things like sliced inner
pearl which is a blood pressure
medication but really when it comes down
to it we're talking about Tylenol right
which is in a class by itself and we all
know what that is good for it's good for
some things but it also is not good for
other things and it has some attendant
risk there are nonsteroidal
anti-inflammatory medications like
ibuprofen right or Naprosyn which work
well for certain things and also come
with certain risks of GI bleeding or
renal failure and those sorts of things
and not appropriate for all
circumstances and then what's left
opiates that's it that's all we got
right so we're kind of stuck unless we
start to talk about cannabis and then
the question is alright well you know
what do we know about opiates well it
turns out that opiates have been with us
for so long that they haven't been
wonderfully well studied particularly
when it comes to chronic pain and so in
the last two three years we finally in
the setting of this declared crisis got
around to looking at these things it
turns out that opiates aren't that great
for chronic pain and they come with all
sorts of side effects you know from you
know the obvious addiction issues but
how about just constipation anybody
watch on television and there's now a
drug out that you can take so you don't
get constipated while you check your
opiates it's it reminds me of a
children's rhyme but this is what we
where we are right and opiates are
dangerous duh
okay I don't know about you but I've
known that forever I have had a long
reputation of being pretty stingy with
opiates and getting in a lot of trouble
in the early 2000s with my superiors
because you remember we had these groups
come in and talk about you know pains
the fifth vital sign and nobody
can come into the IDI without being
interviewed about their level of pain
and exit interviewed about whether they
were adequately a you know the pain was
adequately addressed and stuff and that
put a lot of pressure on us to write
more scripts and surprising not
surprisingly we did okay what we know
now is that when you look at the number
needed to harm it's only 3333 patients
one in 33 patients walking into your IDI
you write a prescription they're gonna
have trouble they're gonna either become
addicted or worse yet die so not such a
great idea let me call you about a
success story this is Theresa well
actually it isn't Theresa it's not her
name is not her photo but oops
we'll talk about go backwards please
excellent wonderful slide but anyway
let's talk about Theresa there she is
Theresa whom I met in my clinic about
two years ago maybe two and a half it
really wants to show you then the
cannabinoid system but we'll leave it
there and maybe it'll stay 42 years at
the time that I met her she's a
high-powered local attorney and she had
had the misfortune of having a car
accident and after the car accident she
developed two long-term consequences one
was she ended up with this weird seizure
pseudo seizure thing that was going on
and nobody could quite put their finger
on what that was all about and the other
thing not surprising that she had a lot
of musculoskeletal damage and so she was
in a lot of pain so by the time I met
her she was at her wits end she had
taken time from her high-powered job at
great cost to her financially as well as
emotionally and she was on a serious
handful of oxycodone percocet everyday
and tramadol which is a drug I really
disliked and she was being followed by
her primary care doctor and neurologist
and a pain specialist and none of them
knew what to do next with her nor did
they know how to get her off the opiates
because she was in so much pain but on
the other hand she was really suffering
from the side effects of
opiates as well then to make matters
worse this poor lady she had two young
teenage daughters the elder was an honor
student whose grades started to fall off
she ended up the daughter ended up
starting to use illegal substances and
the younger daughter developed an
anxiety disorder which then manifest
itself and in suicidality and ended up
having to be admitted to a local
pediatric psych office psychiatry
facility so life was not good when I met
this woman and what we were able to do
was to treat her pain and we treated her
pain with a mixture of cannabis through
various preparations and so I'm gonna
come back to this a bunch of times but I
like to think of these things in you
know the rubric that's were the analogy
to the way we use opiates and it's an
uncomfortable analogy because we're
trying to avoid opiates by the way we're
taught to think about these things is
that we use a long-acting form of opiate
to get baseline coverage and then we use
a short-acting form of opiate to deal
with breakthrough pain if there is any
on a daily basis and so when you think
about cannabis and we've certainly heard
lots and lots about different
preparations and ways to use what we
know is that anything that you take
orally gets metabolized by the liver and
has a much longer half-life it's also a
little bit erratic and it's onset so
that potential some problems and then
inhaled has a rapid onset in a
relatively short half-life so that that
works well in in that immediate sense
and over the next six months we were
able to titrate this to the point at
which she was no longer in pain she was
no longer in pain her mood came back she
was able to address family matters and
get her children the help that they
needed and ultimately the interesting
thing was even though her other
physicians were uncomfortable with the
idea of titrating down her opiates for
reasons that I couldn't understand even
after having multiple conversations with
them patient just did it herself she's
like look I feel okay I'm using the
cannabis so she slowly weaned off the
tram at all and the next came off the
percocet and at at 12 months she was
opiate free and
her family was back on track and I've
been following her since and she's had
some ups and downs but the the principal
is there and the success rate I think is
is pretty good so that's that's it in
sort of the nutshell the the success
story and I'm gonna now move on to this
slide about the endocannabinoids system
and really basically whizzed past it
because you guys have heard so much
about the endocannabinoids system in the
last two days that there's really not
much for me to say so we know that it's
a complex signaling pathway that it has
both receptor and non receptor mediated
ways of functioning and interestingly
enough this what I haven't heard a lot
of discussion so far is the ways in
which the endocannabinoids system
interact with our inflammatory system
around the prostaglandins and cytokines
that are also involved in pain
perception did you mention that
yesterday okay
so there are interesting bits about the
way the ECS works it it works both
peripherally and centrally there's all
kinds of really interesting data coming
out now about its peripheral function
this slide basically shows us that it's
they feet and negative feedback loops so
that when these neurotransmitters
stimulate the postsynaptic cell then we
get secretion of the endocannabinoids
typically in and amide which complex
then with cb1 and shut down the calcium
influx channels thus shutting off this
release of neurotransmitter but I think
you know that's fairly well understood
at this point but the interesting bit
about this is that we also get into
paracrine meaning secretion of
endocannabinoids from non neuronal
tissue that are involved in supporting
the neural tissue and then we also get
come on slide paracrine we'll come back
I'm really having trouble with those
slides today apparently so paracrine
function that affects inflammatory cells
that are also involved particularly in
tissue damage like histiocytes and
macrophages so there is a ton of
processing going on all
at all levels throughout this system
here in the central nervous system we
know that pain pain systems work both in
an a sending meaning it's going up to
your brain right but there's
interestingly a shutoff system where the
pain systems trigger down again to turn
off some of this and to prevent a
runaway cycle and we know that there are
there's more processing going on there
than we previously thought and that
there are these neurons in the spinal
column essentially here where the opioid
receptor works and that the cb1 receptor
is tightly complex to that new receptor
there and again is involved in signals
that then dampen this feedback loop is
this even worth mentioning nope okay
back to the practical stuff there are
many many ways that we can use cannabis
as we've heard so much about in the
clinical encounters I typically start by
talking about smoking
not because I recommend it I really
don't for obvious pulmonary health
issues but people understand what I wear
I'm starting alright a little mood music
so typically I will recommend that we
move on to vaporizing vaporizing avoids
products of combustion but it provides
an easy repeatable dosing framework
based on what I call puffs or you might
all call hits although I think that
slang is a little painted and it has the
following benefits its rapid onset right
you get effects from it within five to
ten minutes and also it doesn't last
that long which in many instances is
actually a benefit so we're talking
about pain today but in many instances
where I'm treating something that's more
like anxiety and depression it's nice to
have something that has kind of a medium
duration then we get into things that
you can take by mouth right and it turns
out when you look at some of the
bioavailability studies that
is one of the places where the stoners
got it right you know that when you take
cannabis in an oil form or as a solid
form or those sorts of things it's
really poorly absorbed you get about 30
percent absorption whereas if you take
it in a brownie you get about 60 percent
or one percent better it's still not
great bioavailability and that really
impacts how how we treat people and the
doses that they can take but we also
have to remember that patients are not
just whatever problem you're looking at
patients are complex organisms just like
you and me where we need to remember the
whole person right we're doing this in
part as holistic medicine and so I have
all these patients that come to me and
they are elderly and they're obese or
they have type 2 diabetes
yesterday last night no last week I saw
a young woman 31 years old had been a
type 1 diabetic since she was 18 months
she was telling me that her blood out a
1 C level which is a measure of her
glucose control is was 8.9 and that was
the best that she's ever seen and I just
marveled that because that's all not a
very good number so clearly and she came
to me for intractable facial pain
clearly I was not going to go tell her
take 2 brownies and call me in the
morning right so we have to work out
something else there I'm gonna skip a
lot of these other things I think you've
heard a lot about them except to mention
this guy I think that that oil based
vaporizer pens probably ought to burn in
hell because they are filled with all
kinds of nasty things like polyethylene
glycol or propylene glycol which are
dangerous and the last thing we want is
to treat somebody's pain and then have
them have a lung transplant because you
know we gave them popcorn low alright
what's next which one is right for you
this is a graphic pulled from the
internet apologies to its creator but
just the question is framing the wrong
discussion right the issue here is not
which one is right for you it's how do
we use these things properly
it's
not either/or it's complimentary right
again I've slipped into dr. speak here I
hope that if people under Pio means um
by mouth and so this is our long-acting
and then inhaled is a rapid onset
checking my time here and you know this
was where I wanted to mention my
diabetic patient but the point is I see
this time and again I see this
unfortunately we've heard from a few
speakers this this week about the
dispensaries misguiding people and i see
this a lot in my practice and one of the
areas where that comes up is that they
don't know medicine they don't know the
patient's problems so they may I may
send a patient into gets a capsules of
something and then they say well you
know the yeah sure here buy some
capsules but don't you want the
chocolate bars too they're so yummy and
then the patient goes home and their
blood sugar spikes and cetera et cetera
so we need to remember the whole patient
we've also heard a lot about dosing and
I think dosing is really crucial what we
know is that you start to get benefit as
you increase the dose and that's not
really a surprise but what is more of a
surprise is that you turn a corner at
some certain dose and at that point you
get much you don't really get any more
benefit but you certainly get more side
effect in risk right so these side
effects may be as minor as dry mouth
which is something I can attest you at
the moment not from cannabis but from
speaking but you also get things
particularly in the elderly like
orthostatic hypotension which can be can
lead to false and such like that as well
as obviously increasing tolerance over
time so there are reasons why we do not
want to push too far past this in my
practice what I have found is that a
dose around 10 to 15 milligrams
sometimes up to 20 and I've guessed this
is milligrams of THC component in whole
flower product or whole flower really
seems to be the sweet spot for almost
the entire population
what is interesting to me and this has
been mentioned by other speakers is that
there are really two populations that
come in there are the cannabis naive
folks I've never touched this stuff or I
or I used it you know in the 60s when I
was 20 and now I'm 75 and then there's
this other group which is sort of the
smaller group in my practice at this
point which are people who are coming to
me already using and wanting to either
become legit or they really have
realized that there's needs for best
practices for them and I find that that
group is comes in usually using way more
than I would recommend to them and then
that becomes a much more I think
difficult discussion to try and get them
to sort of Ratchet it back and when they
do if they are willing to play ball I
find they get much better benefit they
come back to me say doc Wow
I feel so much better and I'm taking so
much less and I'm saving money I'm like
yeah exactly I told you so this is the
goal and what's not the goal is this
grandma doing bong rips okay yep
so assuming that this actually yep oh
come back
alright well on here is how you reach me
if you want to ask me questions I'm more
than happy to go over any of this stuff
with you guys and somewhere up there was
supposed to be the list of references
all right
forward one references so if you want a
photograph that you can go that that
link and find all manner of stuff that
supports what I actually just talked
about thank you all for listening
you