[Music]
the can med podium is reserved
presenters who have performed novel
research in cannabis science medicine
cultivation or safety testing all
potential presenters must submit an
informative abstract that summarizes
their research including the study's
objective methods results and
conclusions our can met Advisory
Committee made of industry leaders in
the four focus areas reviews each of the
submissions for relevance quality data
and potential to inspire discussion
their feedback on the submitted
abstracts and their recommendations
helped shape the overall content of the
event why we do it the purpose of the
conference is to provide the can med
community with the latest most relevant
data in the four fields represented at
the conference our abstract approval
process eliminates the marketplace
atmosphere and business interest from
influencing presentations providing a
pure podium that is free from
self-promotion what types of abstracts
are typically accepted at kin med events
data-driven abstracts that cover novel
areas of research thought-provoking
abstracts that will inspire discussion
abstracts that are relevant to at least
one of the can med 2020 focus areas
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing we want to hear from
you submit your abstract at kin met
events comm today
[Music]
you