Kennedy was fantastic this year can med
conference is great because many
different doctors researchers scientists
people coming from all different parts
of the cannabis industry are coming
together and sharing knowledge
so I think it's it's really turned into
a forum that is credible but also
diverse can med is a great way to help
me educate myself on current trends and
topics and cannabis research
can man plays a huge role in advancing
not only my workplace but medical
cannabis as an entity but more
importantly I think a lot of us ended up
realizing that we're all heading in the
same direction we're doing it in
different ways but they're mutually
supportive and I don't think there could
be you you can't overvalue just having a
little bit of camaraderie and scientific
recognition among peers when there
really isn't a lot of that