[Music]
yeah and so I guess kind of to tie it
back all back to the uh the workshop
here so is that really sort of who
you're tailoring this this content for
is sort of the the small company who is
is starting up and is looking into some
of these novel compounds and they're
looking for funding they can come to the
workshop and kind of learn some best
practices to the best way to to get some
funding no actually it's meant to go
across the Spectrum it's meant to reach
out to biotech companies they meant to
reach out to Pharma companies they meant
to reach out to small companies it's
meant to reach out to PNG you know
companies that are not biotech or faral
Orient are out on the outside looking in
because what we've all been about GP
Golden Eagle partners has always been
about Ben is is help TR providing you
know trying to find the best capital for
the best companies whether it's inside
or outside of cannabis and that also
means to be the purveyor of objective
information to a lot of these companies
that are on the outside looking in that
don't understand the sector and frankly
we understand it better than a lot of
people and and Frankly Speaking whether
it's a big company or small company and
they want to get into cannabis the
smartest thing that they could do is
come to Golden Neagle partners and say
what should we do instead of trying to
go in there and throw a lot of money at
it and lose it because I can guarantee
you one thing that's for sure in
cannabis there's been a lot of money
lost by people that have been too
arrogant and with too little arrogance
and too much too too much arrogance and
too little humility it's a fact so if if
companies want to understand the
Cannabis sector better especially where
the science is going then yeah they
would be prudent to show up at the the
Cal markets
Workshop
[Music]
a