good morning everyone and thank you to
the mckernon for providing such an
incredible platform to share amazing
information this has been an incredible
event so far so my name is Deb Kim Ellis
I'm an anesthesiologist in pain medicine
specialist I'm also the medical director
of forward grow which is a medical
cannabis cultivation company in Maryland
we were awarded two stage one license to
cultivate cannabis in Maryland and we're
busy doing our build-out so that we can
be inspected and create medicine for the
patients in Maryland but my passion and
my love and what I do and I think what I
live for is that I am currently treating
over a hundred patients pro bono
actually I'm got medical guidance eart
with their treating physicians using
medical cannabis and when I do this we
define benchmarks we define goals
because everybody's goals and
everybody's benchmarks are different I
take that information and I share it in
conferences such as this medical Grand
Rounds healthcare professionals patients
and pretty much anybody that'll listen
to me so thank you for listening to me
today today we're going to discuss for
cancer patients for cancer patients and
each of them different but each of them
have some things that are similar in
addition to having cancer
the desperate desire for hope is that
they were all treated with a very low
dose cannabis oil extract some people
call it a micro dose and I'm going to
talk about with that definition being so
in the circles of in the context of
micro dose in the cannabis industry it
doesn't different than in science
industry mean 10 to the minus 6 it means
a very low dose because medical cannabis
I think comes from the recreational or
adult you size where people are using
very high doses or amounts and so we're
going to do a little bit of math here I
apologize so if we take a joint which I
hate that term and if it weighs about a
gram or a thousand milligrams and 24
is THD end up having about 200
milligrams in that in that dosage form
about 30 to 40 percent of it it goes up
in smoke literally and if they consume
the entire dosage it ends up being about
60 to 80 milligrams the low dose or
microdose cannabis that these patients
all took was literally less than 1 less
than 2 milligrams per ml and we'll go
into it a little bit more specifically
so this is their their their their
dosage form in 1 ml half of it is in the
tea in the acid form or the raw form
half of it is in the decarboxylated or
neutral form it has a ten to one ratio
of of the THC or THC a 2 CBD to CBD a it
also has a minor cannabinoids and some
terpenes in it as well and they take
varied amount of doses depending upon
what the condition is to treat and
there's a rationale behind it legrest at
all in 2006 published this chart which
was very nice and it shows the micro
moles of THC of all the cannabinoids and
it's acid in and neutral forms and what
it does to the IC 50 which is inhibitory
concentration where 50% of the cancer
cells don't grow and what does that mean
in English because I had no idea what a
micro mole means in life is that if you
use Avogadro's equation and I was absent
that day so I actually used the help of
a friend to convert micro moles to
milligrams and even at its highest doses
of THC it ends up being twelve point
five milligrams which I think we can all
agree is a lot less than the sixty to
eighty milligrams and I think the
thought is and what we probably heard
over the last day and a half so far is
that we want to keep the Med in medicine
the minimal effective dose you can
always titrate higher but we want to see
what we can do with the least amount so
we're going to talk about two to two
cases of patients with prostate cancer
so the first is a gentleman 72 years old
who came to me with recurrent prostate
cancer he was diagnosed in 2000
Levin he had a Gleason score of eight
clinical state of t2b and a PSA of seven
point two he was successfully treated
with hormone deprivation with lupron
injections he'd implant and radiation
therapy and his PSA dropped to 0.3 he
was doing great for about four years and
then his PSA started to rise again and
they monitored him over ten months and
in August his PSA level was seven point
eight and that's where he came to me end
up that his cat-scans thankfully in bone
scans were negative for metastases and
he wanted to do some help
get some help so in when he first saw me
he began the first of his three lupron
injections his PSA after a month was
still seven point eight we started a
program of low-dose cannabis well oil 1
milligram sublingually four times a day
we changed his diet and then he
continued this regimen for the second
and third loop ride injection and so I
just want to show you a chart that shows
on this level is PSA level that was our
benchmark and this is time in months so
this is his first month after his
recurrence where he got a lupron
injection alone and his PSA was seven
point two or seven point eight I'm sorry
second month alone he came to me we
continued his Lupron and gave him the
micro dose of cannabis oil sublingually
four times and after that a month we
redrew his PSA and it ended up being
four point eight third months continued
the same regimen with the Lupron
and the cannabis oil it dropped to 0.3
fourth months no more Lupron they only
get it three months in a row stayed
stable fifth month point two and
literally while I was standing in the
back getting ready to give this
presentation I just got a text from him
he got back from Italy with his wife and
his PSA remains consistent at point two
81 year-old man who is otherwise healthy
was diagnosed with had some back pain
issues workup revealed a metastatic
prostate cancer he was treated with heat
implants radiation therapy and the
Lupron injections and his markers were
escalating testosterone levels and they
wanted to do surgery to remove his
testicles to try to ablate the rising
testosterone that was fueling the cancer
so he came to me with the hope that
perhaps he could avoid surgery so here
we are testosterone is our is our marker
here it was as high as 1350 and over the
weeks we started at week zero to week
two in two weeks one ml five times a day
sublingually it dropped 500 points from
1350 to 850 his surgeon said that's
great we still think we need to have
surgery because give me two more weeks
in two weeks used to saw strong level
drop below like what would be even seen
in a normal level and it continues as
such to this day and there are studies
that show that this is not a surprising
result for these prostate cancer
patients including a study that shows
the androgen reducing effects of
cannabinoids so brain cancer to patients
so we have an eight-year-old girl with
acute lymphocytic leukemia
she failed multiple chemotherapy trials
and multiple radiation trials she had a
bone marrow transplant that lasted about
a year and then no longer was successful
and she was placed in hospice and her
mom and dad came to us wanting some hope
to see if we can help her out chief
complaints for the little girl's chronic
nausea lack of appetite severe headache
and lack of energy and upon evaluation
when we saw her she was very somnolent
non-communicative and her face was
swollen her eyes were swollen and
because she was on Hospice the medicines
that she was being treated with was
methadone and morphine
undivided doses actually so we talked
about goals and the goals for her was
that we hope that we would reduce her
opiates so they can she start eating and
actually live out her last days in life
being an active participant in her world
and so this is her MRI in February 2015
this is a lepton manual spread of her
cancer including her ventricles and so
improved quality of life
trying to help her with their pain and
transition off of opiates so it treated
her with one ml of the cannabis oil
extract four times a day and by the way
this stuff tastes like cannabis it's not
flavored it's not treated it has no
sugar component it tastes awful and this
little girl of eight years old sat and
watched her cartoons with this under her
tongue without a complaint which I found
incredible so the initial response was
that they started to slowly reduce her
narcotics and then replaced it
completely until she was off of all of
her opiates she became more active and
she had the appropriate demeanor of an
eight-year-old so for any of you who are
parents out there you would recognize
this as back talking not listening
refusing to take a bath and I think I
Rowling was involved and the mom the mom
recognized that this was not the normal
behavior of an eight-year-old who is
dying of cancer and she even though they
were on hospice insisted on another MRI
and so there was
and they're still you know some cancer
left am an angel sprayed here but you
can see the ventricles are cleared and
everything else was cleared this is just
a comparison and again this is no
surprise there are studies that show a
ll and of leukemia is being treated with
cannabinoids of all sorts either CBD THC
or a conjunction and in fact this last
case is a case study sing it out that
described a case very similar to the one
I just described who was put in Hospice
was treated with a whole plant extract
of cannabinoids sublingually she went
into remission and unfortunately in this
particular patient she died of a
perforated bowel but for our case she's
still alive
two years later same dose so history
here's a otherwise healthy 69 year old
man who presented to the emergency room
postictal he had a grand mal seizure and
he woke up in the ER not knowing was
going on he had an MRI that revealed a
tumor a biopsy diagnosed with a
glioblastoma his chief complaints were
lethargy inability to perform his
activities of daily living without
assistance and he was a big guy with six
foot four and his wife was it was a
small lady and she was really struggling
trying to just get him dressed in the
morning and and feeding him he had
cognitive changes he was a guy that
prior to the surgery was active he's
insurance salesmen he was on the
computer he rode his bike and interacted
with his kids all that changed the only
medicine that he was taking was the
tegretol for seizures and that was it
and that's his tumor and it's in a
really bad area that's basically in the
corpus close to him in the center of
his head so it was inoperable they did a
biopsy and the one drug that was
supposed to help with glioblastoma is
team adore it was tested not to be good
for him so he was supposed to see his
oncologist and gets it up for radiation
therapy but somehow he saw me first and
we started him on a low-dose cannabis
oil four times a day sublingually now he
complained he hated this stuff and
didn't want to do it but his wife
literally wrestled him down and made him
do it
and did the MARY POPPINS a spoonful of
sugar after it was done so he's done he
got a mint and he was happy with that I
guess until the goals were to improve
the quality of his life improve his
function and with the hope because
there's lots of stuff out there that
says that it can help with glioblastoma
is his wife desperately wanted to reduce
the tumor growth and in the first two
days he started feeding himself at the
end of the week he was on a computer and
somehow and I didn't order it somebody
ordered an MRI two weeks later and if
anybody knows how difficult it is to get
approval for any MRI I have no idea how
this happened but the radiology report
said evidence of central cystic
degeneration clearly responding to
radiation
but there was there was no radiation at
all given and here's a side-by-side
response now he did go for radiation
therapy they did treat him with timid or
even though it was not indicated I guess
they fit and far be it for me to make
these judgments I mean if I had this in
my head - or my loved one I think I
would throw everything at them he was
treated his last treatment was in
September and I'll show you what he
looks like now but again there are
studies that show that these things work
and so this was last week you still have
evidence of it but it didn't grow so I'm
not saying that we were curing this I'm
saying that we're managing it he's in
Florida he just rode a bicycle with his
wife they are celebrating an anniversary
I know they went to some spa I mean
they're living a better life quality
life than maybe many of us or anyway and
this is our green house that we're
building out it's one acre under glass
and I beat the clock so if anybody has
questions I'll be more than happy to to
to answer them now
funny look yep so it's a proprietary
extract of five different strains that
they want to combine so they get as many
of the terpenes in major and minor
cannabinoids it ends up being naturally
a ten to one ratio of the.2 CBD THC aid
PvdA
per ml some people get 4 ml today some
people get it depends on what we're
treating and how aggressive and what
they look like with their experiences
and we titrate it up I mean if that's
sort of the ultimate goal because I even
though with this ratio you're the
majority people don't feel any psycho
activity I treat patients it was
youngest to 92 and the 92 year old say
it just gives them a sense of relaxation
helps them sleep but no psycho activity
in the - do you know do you know the
terpenoid profile nobody has ever tested
it this stuff is out of California so
I'm lucky that we have this right and
then one more question in patients that
have had metastatic disease are you
seeing any of the metastatic tumors
shrinking as well so in the patients
with metastatic disease I see them
managed meaning that their pain is
reduced their tumors have an increased
or spread but I have not seen the Mets
disappear primary tumors yes but not a
success do you think do you think is
that the reason low dose is so effective
is that it mimics the low dose of our
endocannabinoids and it has a doesn't
affect our receptor no down-regulation
and that it keeps kind of the receptors
the way they without changing I mean
that's certainly a possibility right if
I had the answer or I would hopefully be
getting a Nobel Prize somehow but I mean
there's people here far more smarter
than I am but I think that you know my
thought is maybe it's helping us balance
ourselves allowing our immune system to
do what it's supposed to do I change
everybody's diet to give them the
maximum nutrition to provide a milieu so
that the endocannabinoid system can work
is as best as you can a conventional
knowledge tells us that the cannabinoid
acids don't cross the blood-brain
barrier but though they do cross
blood-brain barrier in pediatric
patients they clear-cut that it does
because it stops seizures is it is it
an indication that again cannabinoid
acids are actually you know or should I
say the the cannabinoid acids can
essentially be active active and not
necessarily the deactivated form and
they have to be activated by
decarboxylation so I never understood
the term activated or deactivated I
think cannabinoids and terpenoids tree
of this plant and the healthful benefits
that it can offer I think when people
use the terms activated I think it means
to allow it to become psychoactive and
so I'm wondering and I'll positive
question to everybody out here you know
is it is that with what everybody's
talking about it's trying to achieve a
cycle activity but I still think that
the acids provide a helpful benefit to
people when I've seen it in over on to
patients yes so that's a really great
question again we follow benchmarks so
for the the patient who's been nine
months with a PSA now still back down
2.2 we're going to start to slowly
reduce them because I know that his
benchmark is easy to follow for the
eight-year-old girl that is now 10 we're
keeping her on a steady-state dose
because I don't know any better and
right now she seems to be thriving that
way
oh no there's these are just the easy
ones I have lung cancer patients ovarian
cancer patients breast cancer patients
they have if if they follow the plan and
they listen and yes yes just can I ask
one more question have you tried higher
dose to see if you can eliminate tumor
completely so um I think somebody said
if all you'll have is a hammer
everything looks like a nail so sadly
because we're limited in opportunity for
consistency and profiling this is the
only medicine that I have access to
consistently and the beauty is I treat
my patients pro bono they get medicine
free of charge as well and so because of
that they're very open to trying it and
if it doesn't work then I do make
recommendations to go higher but then
our hands are tied as to what it is
because especially in legal states where
they're out west where there's not a lot
of testing it becomes very difficult to
figure out what exactly they're getting
and making sure they get it continually
but I would love to and that's why I'm
the medical director in Maryland because
that's my my passion is to make sure we
have consistency make sure we have
opportunities to scale up if we need
because everybody's different
not everybody needs high doses and not
everyone works with low dose thank you
everyone