hi
i'm oren davinsky from the nyu school of
medicine
and i'm here to present on the gw
pharmaceuticals epidialex trials
now these trials have occurred over the
course of several years
and have now included both open label
trials
and randomized phase three double-blind
i'm going to summarize mainly the data
from the open label trials
and then give a bit of data from the
newly released
drive a syndrome study which was a
double blind
randomized placebo-controlled trial so
to begin with
this second slide summarizes our open
label experience with cannabidiol or
epidialex
which was presented at the american
epilepsy society meeting
in december of 2015 in philadelphia
and i should start out by just saying
that epidiolex
is a commercial product produced by gw
pharma
which contains 99 cannabidiol
in an oil base this is cannabidiol is a
very
lipophilic molecule so it needs to be
dissolved
in an oil and that is the way it was
given to these children and young adults
so for this
first set of data that i'll be
presenting it is the
largest and most complete set and
included
313 children treated at 16
epilepsy centers over a little over a
two year period
these children and young adults included
261 individuals
who received the epidiolex for at least
three months of continuous therapy and
that's important because that's the
standard
time duration that we look for in the
fda trials
for both safety and efficacy in the
trials
that i'm presenting here on the open
label data there was a wide
range of patient ages between four
months and 41 years of age
with a mean age of 12 years old
the doses that were used varied widely
from a low of 2 milligrams per kilogram
to a maximal dose
in some sites that got approval from the
fda to go to higher doses
of up to 50 milligrams per kilogram per
day
but i should emphasize for the vast
majority of patients the maximal dose
was 25 milligrams per kilogram per day
or lower of the epidialex and for this
group of the
overall 313 patients
epilepsy diagnoses was unknown in 19
was drive a syndrome in 17
and was lenox gastow syndrome in
a few percent lower the median
convulsive
seizure frequency in patients
across this study was 48.8 percent
and in dravet syndrome patients 52.3
percent
in lennox gastow syndrome patients the
median reduction of
atonic seizures the most paradomatic and
signature seizure type for that syndrome
was 71.1 percent
now the big caveat with this study and
i'll repeat it again
is that it was an open label study the
physicians knew what they were
prescribing and giving to the patients
the parents and patients who were aware
of it
knew what they were getting they were
getting the actual labeled compound
in a jar that set up a dialects so they
everyone knew what was being given
and what was being received we had no
placebo
group in this and there was no blinding
so we have no idea from this
data set what the placebo response was
in this group of patients among all the
patients that we treated
and that we had the duration of time of
three months or longer
47 of them had a greater than 50
reduction in seizures as far as seizure
freedom
nine percent of patients overall and 13
of patients withdrav a syndrome did
obtain
seizure freedom during the study
now one of the things that emerged from
this open label experience
is that patients who are on clobazam and
then epidiolex or cannabidiol was added
to the therapy
we did see increases in sedation
and in select patients for whom we don't
have enough to say this definitively but
we've seen this dr elizabeth thiel
published this in epilepsia
dr dan friedman one of my colleagues
here at nyu published this as an
abstract and presented it the american
epilepsy society meeting a year before
is that when cannabidiol is added
to clobazam in a patient who's already
taken clobazam
we see elevations in the endes methyl
metabolite of clobozam
and that metabolite we believe is
biologically active
with regards to both efficacy
and toxicity so if a child or young
adult is on clobazam
and we add epidialex to that child's
regimen or young adult's regimen
we expect that in some cases we may
we likely may see an elevation in that
endes methyl metabolite
and that could lead to more tiredness
for example as a side effect
and potentially could lead to greater
effectiveness
of the cbd through this drug interaction
mechanism
there are some additional caveats about
this there are other drugs
that can also inhibit the metabolism
of this enzyme that converts
that degrades the endos methyl
metabolite
and so other drugs that may inhibit that
include
steropental which is also used in dravet
syndrome especially in european patients
but some american patients and
felba made as well so it may be patients
with dravet
who are on clobazam and stereopental
and potentially felt made as well we
don't have the data yet to confirm this
but we've seen instances where we have
not seen an elevation
in the endes methyl metabolite when
cannabidiol
is added to clobazam therapy and that
may simply be
because in those patients their
endesimal metabolite levels
are already quite high because of the
co-therapy with a drug
like steripental so that's an evolving
story
we need much more data to define it but
it is something to be aware of
in clinical practice and also in
research methodology
studies so in the presentation of the
data at the american epilepsy society
meeting we did look at those patients
who are on clove exam co-therapy
because we think that's an important
group to look at
and indeed there was a somewhat higher
rate of treatment response
a median reduction in the convulsive
seizure frequency
which for those who were already on
clobazen was 56.4 percent
versus 35 at week 12
for those who are not on clove exam
co-therapy
and as i said this we think may be in
large measure because
the cbd or cannabidiol induces an
elevation of that metabolite which is
biologically active
however clobizam co-therapy effect
did not seem to influence the efficacy
results in either the dravae
or lennox gasto syndrome groups and it
may be because some of these patients
were already on medications that induced
that were inhibited that conversion of
that metabolite
or other mechanisms so again larger data
sets will be needed and we hope
the randomized trials will shed light on
this as well with regards to the safety
of cannabidiol the open label studies
also provided some
some signals that we think were very
helpful among the adverse events
that were seen in at least 10 percent of
the
treated patients were somnolence in 23
fatigue in 17 diarrhea
23 decreased appetite
17 vomiting in 10 percent
and convulsions in 17
the convulsion is an interesting one in
that it's hard to know because we did
not
have placebo-controlled data
we don't know what the natural history
of the epilepsy is in this specific
patient group
and so we know for many of the children
and young adults who were entered
essentially all of them had very severe
treatment-resistant epilepsies and for
those of us of us in practice
we know these patients have bad days and
bad weeks and bad months and good days
and good weeks and good months
and for some of these patients what was
listed as a convulsion as a side effect
in many of the investigators views we
didn't list that as a side effect
because we thought that was the natural
history of the disorder
whereas other investigators felt that
any difference
from the baseline period should be
listed as an adverse event
so there's a lot of variability in how
different investigators interpreted
the same observations and again i don't
think any of us know what the right
answer is this is
clinical medicine and how we best
attribute things we see
to potential causes with regards to the
adverse events there were 14 patients or
4 percent of the overall study group
who had an adverse event leading to
discontinuation
and there were 36 patients or 12 percent
of those treated
who withdrew because of a lack of
efficacy
in addition 16 patients or 5 percent of
the cohort
reported serious adverse events that the
investigator
considered to be treatment related these
included
altered liver enzymes in four patients
all four of those were on valproic acid
status epilepticus or convulsion in four
patients and i discussed the challenges
of
understanding what their true
relationship is i don't think we can say
definitively
diarrhea in four patients weight loss in
four patients
and thrombocytopenia in one patient and
that patient
was also on co-therapy with valproate
now i'm going to turn in the next set of
slides to discussing the open label
experience
that was published in lancet neurology
in december of 2015.
this represents a smaller group of
patients
and a smaller number of centers and
this was the first set of data that was
really curated
and annotated that we could go through
very carefully
make sure it was highly accurate that
the methodologies were consistent
and so it was able to be combined for
publication
in a high impact journal this was 11
centers beginning
january of 2014 and going through 2015
214 patients with treatment resistant
epilepsy were enrolled and this
overlaps entirely with the other set of
data that i just presented
there were 162 patients who had at least
three months of continuous therapy for
which we could derive good safety and
efficacy
uh or i should say for here safety data
and 137
of whom we had sufficient data for the
efficacy analysis
the mean age in this group of patients
was 10.5 years with a range of 1
to 30 years they started typically at 2
to five milligrams per kilogram per day
and then were increased mainly to 25
migs per kilo per day
but in a few centers up to 50 megs per
kilo per day
and this flow diagram just shows the
group of patients who are enrolled some
were enrolled but did not have
12 weeks of follow-up after their first
dose of cannabidiol
11 stopped before that one due to an
allergy from the oil
one had elevated liver enzymes that
individual was on valproic acid
one had somnolence and you can see four
had worsening seizures and poor efficacy
and the family decided
instead of waiting they really just
wanted to exit the trial
so there were 162 left for the safety
and tolerability analysis and then we
excluded
25 of those from the efficacy analysis
for various predetermined criteria so at
the outset we said we'd be studying
children one year of age
and older there were several children
with progressive
disorders which were again an exclusion
criteria for the main protocol and they
were included for compassionate reasons
and then there were 21 patients who had
no convulsive or motor seizures
as we defined them in the methodology
for both the protocol and the lancet
neurology
paper and you can read that in the
methods and so they were excluded from
the efficacy analysis
because they didn't meet the criteria of
the seizure type that we wanted to count
and that left 137 for whom we did
analyze
so this is a breakdown of the groups by
sex and you can see it was fairly evenly
distributed
between males and females the number of
background drugs which ranged in
anti-epileptic drugs from one to seven
but averaged
three and again quite similar in the two
group
safety and efficacy analysis groups
vagus nerve stimulation was used in
about ten percent of patients ketogenic
diet and about eight or nine percent of
patients
and globosamcotherapy was present in
about half of our sample
and then you can see the range of
seizure types there were focal seizures
in
36 percent of patients there were tonic
seizures
41 percent of patients atonic seizures
and about 20
to 23 percent of patients tonic clonic
seizures
in the majority greater than 50 percent
of patients
and other motor seizures were identified
again in a majority of patients
the next slide goes over the diagnoses
of the patients
who were enrolled in the study that was
reported in lancet neurology
and this includes dravet syndrome in 20
percent
of the safety group and 23 percent of
the efficacy group
lennox gastow syndrome in 19 of the
safety group and 22 percent of the
efficacy group and then you can see
spread out a number of
other disorders from investigators who
categorize the diagnosis as minimal
brain dysfunction
cdkl5 tuberous sclerosis epilepsy with
myoclonic
absences febrile infection related
syndrome
odahara jevins and several others
so it was a wide range of patients but
dravet and lennox gusto were the two
most common
here is the side effect or adverse event
profile of the 162 patients that we
analyzed
and you can see on the top this is very
similar to what was reported before
somnolence decreased appetite diarrhea
fatigue
convulsion there were some patients with
increased appetite
were the main adverse events in more
than five percent of patients
with regards to the serious adverse
events status epilepticus was reported
in six percent of patients diarrhea and
two percent
uh decreased weight in one percent and
then a number of
uh serious adverse events in less than
one percent of patients
so i want to finish now with what i
think is the most exciting data to share
with you this was recently
released as a press release by gw
pharma and this is based on the phase
three
randomized placebo-controlled
double-blind trial
that involved a number of centers in
both the united states
and in europe and this was selectively
for patients
with dravet syndrome with the epilepsy
study consortium and ingrid sheffer
doing the screening to make sure all of
the patients
fit the clinical and diagnostic criteria
for draeva syndrome
there were 128 pediatric patients
enrolled
ages 2 to 18 years 61 of those patients
were in
randomized to receive epidialex or
cannabidiol
59 of them were randomized to placebo
and you can see the mean ages for the
groups are essentially identical at 9.7
or 9.8
years these patients had all
treatment-resistant
epilepsy they had an average of three
concomitant
anti-epileptic drugs and they averaged
having been treated
with more than four previous
anti-epileptic drugs none of them
in multiple combinations had controlled
their seizures
and the median baseline of convulsive
seizures
in this group of patients who were
randomized
was 13 per month so again a high seizure
frequency
for a very severe disorder with regards
to the safety overall
epidialex was well tolerated and these
data
closely parallel the open label
experience that we had
adverse events that were recorded in 10
percent or more of patients
included somnolence diarrhea
decreased appetite fatigue
pyrexia vomiting lethargy
upper respiratory tract infection and
convulsion
84 percent of all adverse events were
rated
by the investigator as being either mild
or moderate among the serious adverse
events
there were 10 in the epididylex treated
group and three
in the placebo group with regards
to discontinuation due to adverse events
epididylex patients eight of them
discontinued due to side effects
and in the placebo group one
discontinued
due to adverse events with regards to
the efficacy
which is really the the exciting data
because this is we had no idea what the
placebo rate
would be so it was a 14-week
treatment period for the patients who
were randomized
to the epidiolex or cbd therapy
there was a two week titration period in
which they went
from no drug to 20 milligrams per
kilogram per day
i do think in hindsight this was a
relatively
rapid taper and probably a lot of the
adverse events
could have been reduced or even
prevented had we have gone with a slower
titration period
but having said that there was a
two-week titration period people on
placebo were titrated to more placebo
during that time
people on epidiolex were titrated to
more epidialex
and then there was a 12-week period of
continuous treatment with the same dose
of either epidialex
or placebo the median reduction of
convulsive seizures which was our
primary
outcome measure over the 14 weeks
now the data would actually look better
if we just looked at the 12 weeks where
the patients were actually on
the target dose of epidiolex 20
milligrams per kilogram
but the data i will present is the
agreed
primary outcome measure with the fda
which was based on the entire 14 weeks
which includes the titration period and
for epidiolex the median reduction
convulsive seizures was 39 percent
and for placebo it was 13 and that was
significant
at a level of 0.01
we are very encouraged and excited by
these results we're very happy that the
placebo response rate
was relatively low which we think has
much to do
about careful selection of patients with
dravet
careful determination of the seizure
type that we would count
in which parents and caretakers could be
reliable
and consistent and we hope
that the second study which will be a
dosing study
of placebo versus 10 milligrams versus
20 milligrams
per kilogram per day will produce
similar results
and that hopefully this medication will
be available to children with drug a
syndrome
and can improve both their seizure
control
and their quality of life thank you