hey everyone uh I'm timl fever I'm
director of Discovery at nalo bio um
thanks to canmed uh for inviting me to
give a talk about some of the
investigative uh research we're
conducting on minor rare canabo in
pursuit of both neutraceutical or
therapeutic
development so I think it's obviously a
very exciting time in the canab oid
space um well certainly there's been no
shortage of research and interest in
developing cannaboid based Health
Products or Therapeutics um there's also
a lot we just don't know yet um and so
we've got this surge of interest in
canabo regulations are continuing to
evolve and research is is advancing and
coming out more and more and more but
there's still a lot for us to do um and
so we believe that the synthetic pathway
offers us an opportunity
so we can synthetically derive canabo
that currently cannot really be
extracted from any existing plant
genetics and so what we propose is
developing these synthetic Pathways
investigating them putting them out on
the
marketplace um and kind of establishing
the pathway for Botanical development
down the road so we're not saying this
is a separate Pathway to uh Botanical
development or that it's better in some
way it's just sort of Paving the way way
to justify the genetics on the plant
touching side of the business eventually
towards Botanical preparations that may
have better effects the Entourage effect
more um the the the sum is greater than
any of the individual
canono all right sorry let just changing
the notes on me here um and so while
we're characterizing these phyto canabo
uh for potential neutraceutical
applications uh we can also Leverage The
learnings from that data set into the
identification of potential scaffolds
for our therapeutic pipeline so at a
high level we tend to think of the
canabo uh as a nature-made
pharmaceutical pipeline that has a solid
promise but needs a little bit of
refinement through Medicinal Chemistry
to generate a hit so obviously as we
work on this approach we might find a
phyto canabo that stands up on its own
as well so we've built a computerated
drug design platform that's been trained
with critical existing information and
we refine it every time we collect data
and we recycle that information back in
uh so it's constantly getting better and
evolving and so with each cycle it
improves and the designs it spits out
given the parameters that we set
hopefully generate promising nces that
we can follow up
on so again this is just a highle
outline of how this commercial um and
therapeutic Endeavors are connected so
we start again with the canabo on the
left um we screen them computationally
and then follow up physically um and
then for those that have limited data uh
will'll undertake talks and efficacy
studies uh while optimizing our
synthetic approach to making them um and
protecting any IP that comes out of any
of that work um and if a phyto canabo
looks good through that entire process
we'll pursue
commercialization um and you can see now
moving to the right how the information
gathered on the phyto canabo uh can
inform our therapeutic program um so you
see that the early drug Discovery cycle
is very similar to the phyto canabo
cycle um again this is intentional we're
trying to drive efficiency and Synergy
across our platform um but you can see
that as we go farther into the drug
development pathway the assays start to
deviate to be a little bit more
traditional of a drug Discovery
program and again if we get lucky and we
identify a potential hit uh we move
towards pre-ind enabling work otherwise
we continue to revi revise and refine um
our ncees and again I just wanted to
provide this context of our program at
nalo uh before we jump into the work uh
that we did for this for this talk you
kind of have a have an idea and the
rationale for why we did what we
did um so for this first run through of
this approach uh we screened a number of
phytochemicals some obviously have been
more studied than others uh to get a
sense of how this process might work uh
tweaks we may need to make in this
approach going forward the predictive
validity of some of our models and then
just the overall value um and so given
the massive amount of data that we've
we've collected and and some of which
I'll show today I'm just going to try to
focus on CBC CBGB cbdv and Delta 8
thcv um I'll present the the data from
the other phytochemicals um and we'll
touch on some interesting findings here
and there but we'll focus on those
four so again as you saw in the approach
above what we're doing is is fairly
robust um we're Focus focused on
modeling and high throughput screening
initially to triage early and cheaply
kind of a staple of uh a drug Discovery
approach so we evaluated these canabo
across a range of assays and experiments
uh starting by validating docking models
at several orthosteric and alisic sites
and for today we'll touch on CB1 uh Mew
and
gpr19 uh we then screened all of these
phytochemicals in adme and
physicochemical
assays and some additional models uh we
looked at microsomal stability in human
rat and mouse cells uh mdck mdr1
permeability kinetic and thermodynamic
solubility uh finally log p and log D um
and then We examined the activity of the
canabo in several uh across several
Targets in radio Lian binding assays and
functional assays and again this
overlapped with some of our docking
targets where we wanted to compare the
validity of our docking model as well as
get a sense of um uh inv vitra activity
at some of the other targets we have not
yet modeled and last but not least we
then conducted a invivo c Elegance study
with nalif uh to explore potential acute
and subchronic toxicity uh as well as
impact on neuroactive function which can
be used as an indicator of neurod
degeneration or neuro protection
so first up uh for the adme results uh
the mdck mdr1 permeability assay I'm not
going to go into the the weeds of of a
lot of how these assays work or their
methods there's just so much data um
feel free to find me afterwards and we
can we can get into the nitty-gritty um
but basically uh understanding
intestinal absorption is key for oral
products and there's there's many
different ways to investigate this this
is just the assay we chose for this
first run um and it Sim ulates drug
entering the bloodstream uh from the
intestine by forming a monol layer and
examining the permeation efficiency from
apical to basolateral and vice versa so
this model can also be used to
effectively predict uh the potential for
a compound to cross the bloodb brain
barrier so on the left table uh with the
green highlighted bars you can see uh
both isomers of thcv Delta 8 and Delta 9
thcv as well as cbdv were showing to
have the most favorable favorable
directional
permeability or the transporter e flux
and so by extension these are most
likely to cross the blood brain barrier
um however I should mention that some of
these compounds uh weren't very easy to
work with in this model and so we went
back and forth with the cro um and some
of these were going to rerun as you can
see there's some Nas there's some blanks
so it's it's not perfect and we need to
keep working on on some of these um we
also screen these phytochemicals through
an open websource modeling program
called admet lab 3.0 uh which is which
is a great resource uh but we wanted to
see how our physical data uh aligned
with what was predicted and you can see
there are definitely some discrepancies
so for example again CBGB seem to score
very well in the model uh but not in the
invitro assay um so the model may be
able to kind of get around some of the
method development work or the chemical
complexities of cannabinoids in some of
these physical assays uh to get to
potentially a more realistic uh
prediction or score more
quickly uh obviously we're going to
continue to refine both our in vitro and
in silico models uh to to eventually get
to the point where we're so we're we're
uh confident enough in our predictive
validity that we can skip the physical
assays for the most
part so here uh this is human microsomal
stability data uh again the liver
represents uh the majority of the p450
metabolism and so understanding
microsomal stability is crucial for
understanding the basics of metabolism
uh by measuring clearance and in some
cases identifying the metabolites formed
um this a is available across a number
of different species uh which allows for
comparison as well as metabolism
profiles to be noted When developing
early PK studies for drug Discovery work
um in general most of the cannaboids are
metabolized pretty quickly indicating
rapid clearance or conversion and they
have a relatively short halflife uh
which typically is is not a favorable
attribute of Therapeutics um however can
flaven a and
cbcv both had uh better profiles uh in
the human liver microsomes than the
other canabo potentially indicating
better stability
and longer halflife um you can see again
the difference between CBC and cbcv here
where the only difference in their
structures just a carbon that's that's
the only difference um so besides this
work we're also pursuing structure
activity relationships of a number of
phyto canabo and hope that we might find
some similar predictive abilities so
between uh the the changes in uh elal
tail length and the impact of binding in
gpcrs does that also ring true for say
microsomal stability or permeability so
we're trying to put this whole story
together and hopefully build up a very
big uh a very robust predictive validity
uh or predictive platform uh where we
can screen even more and more phyto
canabo as well as ncees we
develop um one more thing that we're
trying to do this data just came in so I
wasn't able to add it we were able to
identify some of the metabolis of some
of these phyto canabo and phytochemicals
um and we're working on adding those
into this modeling as well which is very
helpful uh for a lot of these because
they haven't been reduced to practice
yet in in other words they're not
available for purchase to screen in a
physical assay so again if you have a
high predictive validity in your model
that's a very nice way to get it some of
that data quickly instead of waiting to
to synthesize material and then put it
into an assay
um this is not going to surprise anybody
in this room but uh canabo are not very
soluble for the most part um and so uh
they can be a challenge to formulate
with and so to that end we wanted to
establish Basics both around solubility
uh for formulation effort product
formats as well as how these phyto
canabo perform under physiological
conditions uh so in general CBGB and
cbdv were the most soluble both in the
kinetic thermodynamic solubility assays
and had the best log P scores um which
for lipophilic molecules as many
cannabinoids are uh is a good measure of
aquous Sol solubility and membrane
permeability uh so if you recall cbdv uh
showed decent permeability and CBG V was
predicted to have uh good permeability
but didn't uh follow up in the in the
physical
assay again all of this work with the
adme and the pcam um is to say that many
of these assays are are intricately
linked so if you improve one quality you
see Improvement in another if you see
delerious effects in one you may see
delerious effects in
another um you can also see once again
though that there's there's a lot of
potential to improve these molecules
towards a more drug-like molecule or a
therapeutic uh that we can use in our
pipeline so on to the docking models and
again this this is a whole talk in and
of itself and this is the work of my
colleague medy hagus um it is not my
work so I'm going to try my best to
represent it well but um basically he he
validated these docking models using
cryoem um of the proteins that were
available and then he trained the models
using as many compounds as available and
then screening false positives to try to
get an understanding of the predictive
validity of these um his goal is 70%
predictive accuracy uh where we're
moving towards 80% % uh as our standard
it takes him about a month to validate
each Target at each site um and the
availability of certain uh cryoem or
Crystal structures or Li existing data
on ligans really kind of dictates which
targets which sites we can go after in a
meaningful way towards having a
predictive model um so for example
aleric binding sites ion channels the
availability of data on CB2 Agonist kind
of limit the ability of some of those
models to be more predictive than others
um but again they're they're all rapidly
improving data is increasing every day
so we're very confident that over the
next few years um modeling uh the the
the uh the activity of phyto canabo and
chemicals in general um is just going to
keep improving and
improving and again so this is just kind
of an outline of how we did this for
gpr1 19 um so he trained up the model on
about 1,800 compounds with known
activity we're able to achieve about 74%
uh predictive accuracy when he reran the
known gpr19 Agonist mbx
2982 um and again we used a very similar
approach uh for the other targets and
sites um with the CB1 model being the
most robust in our hands he's been
working on that model for about four
years um so that one's up to about 8 4%
predictive accuracy where we just
started adding in the MU orthosteric and
alisic sites and so their predictive
validity is much lower but again every
time we collect data and put it back in
the models
improve and so here you can see the
predictive uh activity at these
different sites and targets based on
Med's models at at each one um and so on
the top half of this table you can see
the scores for the phytochemical again a
lower score indicates predictive better
activity um and on the bottom half of
the graph you can see in those
highlighted colors that correspond with
the Target and the site at the top kind
of controls if you want to think of them
that way or or lians that we know that
have a very specific activity typically
very strong activity at that given site
uh or Target uh so you can get a
reference point of where the
phytochemicals fall in line next to some
of those very strong strong uh lians
that we we also
modeled so to help verify these models
then what we did is we went out and we
we conducted some invitro bioassays so
we pursued a number of different radio
Lian binding and and functional assays
um so we tested percent inhibition for
radio Lian binding assays at CB1 and CB2
against cp55940 uh at Mew against uh
damgo and at 5 ht1a against 8 hydroxy
dpad uh we also then completed dose
effect curves for those four targets uh
in cyclicamp functional assays to derive
ic50s for Agonist and antagonist
activity um for trip V1 trip M8 and trip
A1 we used uh functional calcium flux
assays par par gamma we used a
luciferase functional assay uh and um uh
again across 10 concentrations but along
with the 5 ht1a uh functional data and
radio liant binding we didn't see much
meaningful activity in any of those uh
so I won't touch on those anymore for
the rest of the talk but again I think
for a few of the trip subfamilies we
need to go back and and look at those
individually uh because some of these uh
phos we we are pretty confident they
have some trip activity we may just have
not chosen the the right the right
family and the right sub family for
these
assays um again here's the here's the
invitro data we got back uh so on the
left you'll see the radio Lian binding
and the percent inhibition for uh CB1
and CB2 in the orange and uh green the
solid bars are at the one micromar the
uh checkered uh bars are for the 10 um
and then you see
in the purple um and the graph on the
right is the functional cyclic data for
those same targets um and so for the
most part our results match what's been
previously demonstrated um The Binding
effects are all concentration dependent
which is good um there are a few things
you know we would want to point out and
we want to follow up on uh so exam for
example again the difference between the
Delta 8 and Delta 9 thcv isomers is
something we're continuing to to
investigate and pursue um and it may
help to explain some of these
differences that we're going to see in
the in Vivo data in a few slides um so
we're very interested in in continuing
to figure out what the differences
between those two isomers may
be um we also plan to explore CB GV a
little bit further um as the antagonist
activity at CB1 uh is intriguing
compared uh again to the inv Vivo data
that we're about to touch on
uh so if we go back and we apply that
invitro data that we just collected onto
what Med's docking model predicted uh
you can see that for CB1 on the left
where as I mentioned he's been working
on that model for many years the
predictive validity is very high and the
physical data is almost right on top of
the predicted data um but what you can
see on the right as I mentioned is the
very new Mew docking scores that we just
added into our platform and you can see
the the predictive validity there is
much much lower but again every time we
screen we add in it will get better and
better and
better so on to the invivo data so we
partnered with Neema life um to look at
uh acute and subchronic toxicity as well
as well as neuroactivity uh in Sea
Elegance um and this model has become
increasingly popular po as a method for
high throughput in Vivo screening uh as
an alter as an alternative to initial
work using rodents um seans are a very
basic organism but they share critical
Properties or conserve biology that
allow for translational interpretation
into
mammals so again we are most interested
in just understanding the basic toxicity
as well as the neuronal activity uh
effects of these phyto canabo of
Interest so the neuroactivity data uh
can be used as an indicator of potential
neuroprotective properties of a test
substance so in general speed and
movement of the celegans or the worms
decline as the organism ages um however
the addition of some compounds will
result in maintenance of this Mobility
or speed as they age or in the case of
some some test substances will actually
increase Mobility um conversely
decreases in movement May indicate
neurod degeneration orx
toxicity uh so briefly uh worms are
loaded into this microfuidic chip which
is uh the the blue little device there
uh they live in there in a in a growth
medium that is um uh mixed with the test
substance so they they're constantly
living in that and then each day the
fluid is flushed and when it's flushed
it stimulates all of the worms there's
cameras over each of the chips it
records their activity and then activity
is scored using an AI
system um so some of the results uh over
the course of the nday dosing regimen no
really no toxicity was observed uh for
any of the cannabinoids so what you can
see in this graph is the percent
lethality on the Y AIS and then up all
of the the doses um and all of the phyto
canono along the X and just the percent
lethality is cut off at 8% so this is
there's nothing really significant about
any of this yes you can see some Trends
but they're very very very minor effects
um which was very uh which was very good
news for
us it was interesting to note however
that you'll see that
CBC the The Limited toxicity that we see
is actually uh going up as the dose
decreases um again not significant but
something we want to pay attention
to all right are you able to press play
on the
video all right so this is what the
videos look like and what the AI
software scores so this is for the
control worms they're not treated with
any compound so you can see Baseline
movement and then you'll see this flash
of white light and that's when the uh
liquid is being flushed there it goes
and so the AI then analyzes the activity
of the worms post flush um and this
allows for a very easy visual comparison
across the doses and the compounds um so
we're continuing to mine this massive
data set further to look at speed and
distance change from Baseline recovery
post stimulus Etc um and we're also
discussing looking at the actual
individual movements of each of the
worms themselves that have been
correlated in the past to Maman
behaviors for example if they're if
they're curving in a very specific way
or looping those can indicate things
like
stereotypy oh can you skip to the next
slide there you go and and then activate
this video for me thank you uh so this
again is the same thing we just saw with
the Control Data except this is uh worms
that were treated with 100 micromolar
delta8 thcv which was one of the most
stimulating uh Doses and biochemicals we
tested um so I know it's hard they're
not side by side uh we'll look at some
more data but trust me that these guys
are moving a lot faster um and if you
look towards the bottom left going up
towards the right there's one worm that
just screams across the entire the
entire uh frame very very quickly and
there were some other worms that also
exhibited that behavior which we want to
drill down into uh that seemed to be uh
linked to Delta 8 thcv more so than any
of the other uh compounds we
tested all right so this is a little bit
easier to see these are still images of
the paths of all the worms in red that
you can see at the very end of the
observation window post stimulus so you
can clearly see that the control and the
CBC data are somewhat similar in their
overall activity compared to the
increased activity or the density of the
red lines that you see with Delta h
thcv um and uh caffeine which is the
positive
control and again the the uh doses here
for CBC and Delta H thcv are 100
micromolar uh and the caffeine is five
micromolar
oops there we go uh so this is I just
talk briefly about a couple of the
individual phyto canabo uh so CBC was
pretty interesting uh in this model the
effects weren't dose dependent or
consistent so it could be that we were
off on the dose range we may need to go
back and look at it again um it is
interesting to note though that CBC was
the only phyto canabo that had
increasing toxicity as doses went down
not up as I mentioned earlier and again
not significant but certainly worth
following up as CBC does have some
published data indicating that it has
some neuroprotective effects um so I
think potentially for CBC we may have
just been too low and we were at a
threshold
dose the increased in activity we
observed with cbdv on the other hand is
unsurprising given given the nature uh
of previous research with cbdv and
neural protection um which may indicate
that by increasing the bioavailability
and subsequently permeability of cbdv
relatively low doses could be
advantageous across a variety of
neurodegenerative disease States or by
using Med cam to modify cbdv to be more
uh more soluble and stable while
retaining the activity that we're uh
we're looking
for CBGB again very interesting it
significantly increased activity at both
100 and 350 micromolar uh though they
were fairly equip potent and there was
no effect at 40 micromolar so the data
points Trend towards a potential dose
effect but again may need to go back add
another dose um to round out the curve
um and again CBGB as we noted earlier
does have that small Trend uh in the
toxicity data but not significant it's
just fairly interesting that one of the
most stimulating canabo also exhibited
some of the the toxicity we saw um and
CBGB we think it might confer some
neural protection uh through its
activity at the trip channels uh though
we need to explore this a little bit
further as I mentioned we didn't see any
meaningful activity of of C C bgv at
trip A1 trip V1 or trip M8 but again I
think we need to go back and look at a
few more of the uh subfamilies of those
ion
channels Delta 8 thcv uh had a dose
response relationship uh it was stronger
than any of the other cannabinoids and
on several days even outperformed the
positive control caffeine um so
interestingly only the 350 micromolar
dose of the Delta 9 THC CV uh isomer
significantly increased activity so we
saw a pretty big difference between
Delta 8 and Delta 9 in this assay um so
again we want to continue to explore the
difference between these isomers and
hope to better understand what's driving
certain effects over the
other so uh to sum up the invivo data
again none of the canabo produced any
significant signs of toxicity that we're
concerned about most seem to show
increases in neuroactivity which may be
linked to neuroprotective effects well
CBC and can Flav and a had some
inhibitory effects they weren't dose
dependent and likely just require some
basic followup on the doses we
selected so to bring this full circle so
in order to ensure this approach for our
overall program works um we used our our
in-house CAD system to generate designs
based on CBC and CBN towards our
validated targets and indications uh so
far we've designed over 300 we've
reduced 32 uh to
practice and of those 32 they have
predicted potential uh both in docking
scores as well as in adme and PCM
properties and so what we're hoping to
do is scale some of these up put them
into invivo assays later this year and
then continue to refine and build our
Med cem Library while also while also
building up more phyto canabo uh in our
uh initial screening process
process overall summary the modeled
activity was was fairly predictive the
adme and the pcam is in line with
previously published data for the most
part leaves lots of room for improvement
towards more drug-like molecules for a
therapeutic endpoint uh and the invivo
work coupled with the invitra activity
data shows several leads for us to
follow up on uh an interesting efficacy
studies to follow um and finally using
our model uh we were able to design CBC
C and CBN based scaffolds that are
already showing uh improvements over
those phyto
canabo thanks sorry I went over
[Applause]