[Music]
welcome to the CED Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
Amaral I'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics and proud member of
the team who puts on the C Med
conference a few housekeeping items
before we introduce this episode's guest
check out cam at events.com for all the
latest information about the camed 24
Innovation and investment Summit
happening this may in Marco Island
Florida camed 24 is an all-inclusive
event featuring worldclass content
fourstar accommodations ample networking
opportunities and meals and drinks
included be sure to sign up for email
Emil alerts at camand events.com so you
don't miss any announcements leading up
to this year's event if you plan to join
us in Florida I encourage you to buy
your tickets now space is limited this
year and rooms are filling up and if you
can't join us this year you can still
stay connected with the camed Community
by following us on social media we're on
Instagram Facebook X and Linkedin just
search for camet events you can also
enjoy free access to all the podcast
archive episodes as well as videos of
all the past canmed presentations in our
canmed video archive at canmed
events.com our guest this episode is Tim
Lefever Tim is the director of Discovery
at nalo bio he's an experienced director
with a demonstrated history of 20 plus
years of preclinical invivo research and
leading effective teams at organizations
such as canopy growth and Research
Triangle instit intitute he has authored
or co-authored numerous manuscripts and
presented research findings at a variety
of scientific conferences over the past
years at cam at 24 Tim will present
characterization of less studied
cannabis phytochemicals which
investigates the pharmacological
physiochemical and basic toxicological
characteristics of cannabis
phytochemicals during our conversation
we discuss
how Tim and his team choose which
phytochemicals to study what makes the
Varin canono particularly interesting
the difference between chemically
derived compounds and plant derived
compounds which phytochemicals show the
most promise for Therapeutics and
modifying phytochemicals to improve
their
effectiveness before we get to my
conversation with Tim I'd like to thank
this episode sponsor brains basule brain
bosal is a global leader in EU GMP
certified production of naturally
sourced active pharmaceutical
ingredients for the pharmaceutical and
neutraceutical
industries with a unique Suite of
licenses brains bosal is one of the only
natural plant-based phytochemical API
manufacturers in commercial production
today and is involved in academic and
clinical trials across the globe learn
more at brains basule
tocom okay and without any further Ado
please enjoy my conversation with Tim
[Music]
LEF good morning Tim thanks for joining
us on the podcast uh thanks for having
me Ben I'm excited to uh to talk to you
today and and excited for uh the
upcoming conference uh the canmed
conference in Florida in a couple weeks
yeah no it's it's coming soon we're
definitely excited and I'm excited to
talk with you today about the work that
you've done to investigate some of the
Lesser known compounds in cannabis but
before we kind of get into which
compounds and cannaboids you studied and
the results that you found I wanted to
ask what specifically you were
investigating um maybe more more so what
basic questions were you looking to
answer with this work sure sure so um as
as most folks in this space um are aware
um the the the cannabis plant is
incredibly complex there's a number of
different cannabinoids flavonoids
polyphenols um and well some of them are
are fairly well researched there's many
many others that have just a smattering
of information here and there um and so
uh what what we wanted to do was was
take a look at some of these less
studied a little bit more rare or
sometimes called minor canabo um and
just get some some basic information off
of them that can lead us in directions
where we can decide if we want to
potentially commercially pursue them for
health benefits or use them as a
scaffold in our drug development program
to use Medicinal Chemistry to optimize
them further for therapeutic
potential and so with with this work um
you know we chose we chose a number of
of canabo we looked at both the Delta 8
and the Delta 9 isomers of
thcv um as well as cbdv CBG v
cbcv um and CBC and can Flav vanet there
was there was a lot I had to think about
it for a second um
and again some of these have have much
more data in the literature than others
um and so the the basic information was
really around adme uh PK data um some
physical chemical properties uh of of
these cannabinoids um a little bit of
pharmacology work where we chose some
selected uh receptors or ion channels uh
probing for for their activity at those
um and again just to get a a basic sense
of where these stand so that we can
follow up with with more comprehensive
invo um biology studies where we can
really nail down efficacy and safety
right no and I was hoping you might help
me or help me and I guess the audience
to sort of Define a few of these terms
so you know looking through your
abstract in what you're investigating
with these different compounds um
there's pharmacology ology
physiochemistry and toxicology so I was
hoping you could kind of Define what are
those terms like what what are you
really looking at so maybe start with
pharmacology sure sure so so
pharmacology is is really just how a
chemical molecule or some some
entity interacts with with our system um
most often um by binding to and
activating or having some effect on a
receptor or again an ion Channel um lots
of lots of different ways you can you
can approach that but to boil it down
it's basically how does the chemical do
what it does in in the body um uh
physical chemistry is basically just the
chemical properties of the compound
right so you know everything from as
basic as its molecular weight to say
solubility so in various uh solvents or
um phosphate buffered saline how soluble
is this compound um which is related to
how much we could potentially mix or
dose um easily um which is it is which
is related to you know kind of the
ability to commercialize it um or again
identify um a characteristic that we
might be able to improve
upon um and toxicology is is pretty
straightforward obviously it's just
really how how safe are these and
there's there's many many many ways to
approach um assessing toxicology of um
uh of a chemical or or a molecule um in
this case we decided to go with a
celegans model um that we had some some
familiarity with uh in with some
previous work that we found to be a
really good early place to start that
gives us a good sign of both some acute
and subchronic toxicity um that we can
screen fairly rapidly compared compared
to a more traditional invivo rodent
model um but that again gives us an
early indication of this is one we need
to do some more work on or this is one H
right now we we just don't think it's
it's one we want to pursue okay great
thanks for that so in looking at this in
the compounds that you studied were
there any surprises or sort of results
that you weren't
expecting um yes and no um so there were
there were definitely a few things and
and this was again one of one of the
goals uh some of these we we looked at
purely from a a scientific interest uh
perspective um so for example the the
Delta 8 and the Delta 9 thcv isomers um
if you if you look across the
marketplace right now um a lot of the
thcv isolate products contain a ratio of
both isomer in in every direction and
permutation you can think of so we
wanted to understand a little bit more
um about each separately and you know
what are the the the pros and cons or
the benefits of having more Delta 8
versus delta 9 or vice versa um and so
while they really you know are are very
similar much in the same way that Delta
8 THC and Delta 9 THC only differ by the
location of the double bond on the
carbon right that that's molecular
that's the only difference um but when
we did some of our our binding and
functional assays we found that Delta 8
seemed to be a little bit stronger uh uh
antagonist at CB1 compared to Delta 9
thcv UM and then the exact opposite for
uh the CB2 receptor Delta 9 thcv was a
little bit stronger antagonist than
delta8 so again the the implications
there once you start to understand some
of this pharmacology you can either
specifically generate a ratio of the two
isomers to drive a tailored effect or
isolate and purify just one isomer um
and and get get the the most bang for
your buck if if you will okay so you
were investigating Delta 8 THC V and
Delta 9 THC v um and there are a lot of
V's when you're kind of rattling off all
the different compounds so um and I know
that's that's the Varin
um variety I don't know I don't know
what the term is there but so what
specifically was interesting about
varens that you know there are so many
of them in in this list well so so the
varens are are a little bit interesting
to us right and again that the
difference between um the varen and and
the nonin canabo acronyms that you're
you're familiar with is right again just
the number of carbons in the alkal tail
right um so the varens have have three
um so CBD V has three CBD has five right
and and so for for a while and I think
it still persists a little bit today
folks tend to look at the number of
carbons in that in that tail when they
talk about Agonist activity at CB1 um so
typically kind of an indicator of how
intoxic
um a canabo may be um we we don't pursue
anything intoxicating but in in this
case we see that the Varin are are
slightly more pharmacologically
promiscuous um and are a little bit more
like CBD in that regard they they don't
take a hammer to really any one
particular Target or receptor a site but
seem to kind of have this
General General like AC ity uh across
several systems that both contribute to
health benefits or or therapeutic uh
potential but also likely safety as we
see with
CBD interesting so in doing research for
for the conversation today I was
checking out your website at nalu bio
and there's a lot of talk about having
um chemistry derived compounds versus
hemp derive compounds so in doing this
work which were you using were you using
hemp derived or chemically derived so
these these were all synthetic
chemically derived um uh compounds um
which is which is our platform um at
nalu bio um so so we believe that the
synthetic uh synthetic mimics of of
phyto canabo that you can extract from
the plant or that are present in
processed cannabis material um um offer
offer some advantages and so that's why
we've we've decided to go down that
route um we understand that there's
there's a lot of negativity around the
word synthetic uh especially in this
space and and especially after um you
know the years of the the the K2 and
spice uh issues that that we all are
very well aware of um but we're hoping
that we can kind of get over that stigma
um and embrace the the what the
synthetic approach has to offer from a
uh both consistency standpoint from
batch to batch consistency which is
achievable with with with plant- derived
extracts for sure um but also that that
we're able to explore some of these more
minor or rare canabo that at this point
um the genetics don't exist uh or or
they're in process to make extracting
from the plant not very feasible uh or
not sustainable certainly from an
environmental
standpoint yeah yeah so what what kind
of levels are we talking about like some
of these compounds what is the typical
amount that the plant produces and what
were the levels that you were using in
your
investigation right right so i' I'd have
to look to to get really accurate
answers for you but most of these very
very small amounts I know um cbdv there
there are some varieties um from Africa
that that produce I think four or five%
maybe a little bit more um I I don't
know if GW has done some of that work as
well um but but very small amounts
nothing like like delta9 THC um or CBD
at this point although I will say that
um uh phos has uh recently put out a
press release that that they have um
achieved uh genetics for a very high um
uh Delta 9 thcv plant uh that they're
growing and and uh extracting from
so wonder if you can explain a little
bit about how are you kind of deriving
these chemically um is it similar I know
that for example with Delta 8 THC um
it's kind of using the CBD molecule and
and treating it with acid to sort of um
convert it into Delta 8 THC is it a
similar process that you're using now
where you're using a kind of canabo as a
base and then transforming it in some
cases yes um ultimately how we approach
the synthesis for for any cannabinoid is
tailored specifically to that to that
canabo so as we begin to explore what's
the best route we we look at various
input materials what's going to give us
um the best yield uh the best Purity um
and then as we we begin to hone in on on
What's That optimized synthesis we
further tweak it as we need to go from
you know bench scale up to say kilogram
scale synthesis work and there's there's
some more tweaks in there so um the the
very long answer is some rely on uh
other canabo as as input materials
others use um other input materials like
divinol or olivetol um which are very
common uh in this space um but each one
each one is different and
specific right and now of the
phytochemicals you studied which have
the most promise and and
why that's a very interesting question
so the with these basic studies it's
it's a little bit of a tease um so
you're you're you're just kind of
scratching the surface enough to get
very excited um about a few of them um
for for for a few different uh reasons
um and others you you kind of are left
scratching your head that you thought
going into it well I really thought we
might see something there um
so across the board more work is is
going to be done um but I can say that
that with the work we just completed um
in in my opinion based on the data we
have um I would think
CBG um and can flaven a are particularly
interesting um you know can flaven a has
has been published on uh a little bit
over the years uh it occurs you know
minute amount
uh in the plant which has hampered it to
some extent hampered its research to
some extent um but it has fairly
profound uh anti-inflammatory properties
um and as a a polyphenol it's it's
pretty interesting to explore that space
it's a little bit of a a departure from
from say the traditional canabo we talk
about um and in the case of CBG V this
is one again there's there's limited
information out there about it um but it
it set itself apart uh from from the
pack um on a couple of key adme metrics
like uh um like Half-Life and microsomal
stability um that looked a lot more like
what you see in typical Therapeutics uh
in the marketplace today which is was a
very nice surprise for us we we did not
expect that oh so explain that a little
bit more
so um what
specifically yeah so so with with CBGB
so we we did several different um
solubility
assays um as working with canabo a
common issue is that they're not very
soluble um and so we wanted to
understand where these where these fall
in relation to some standards um so we
did some kinetic solubility some
thermodynamic
solubility um and across all of these
what you see is that you can achieve the
highest con rtion with
cbv compared to all of the other
phytochemicals we we tested in those
assays um which which just basically
means it's it's more soluble um than
most which is a which is a very good
thing um and on
metabolics well just that you can it's
it's easier to to mix and get into
higher
concentrations um in say a beverage or
an o oil or a format where you can you
can
deliver you can deliver more of the
compound without it precipitating out or
you can maintain homogeneity of of your
finished good um so that when someone is
taking it you can you can potentially
deliver less compound and achieve the
same effect got it so it's less so sort
of its interaction with the body but
it's it's more of a manufacturing
problem that it's solving for it's going
to give you a more consistent
product it's a little bit of both
actually um and so so on the um on the
the microsomal stability and the and the
half-life work that that we did which is
basically you're looking at at how the
molecule is is moving across um uh
different microsomes in this case liver
microsomes um and so what again what we
saw is that CBG V had had the greatest
halflife so it more of it was sticking
around which speaks more again to its
metabolic profile but also that it was
it had a better transporter profile it
it was able to move more freely um than
some of these other canabo um which
again is is just it it caught us by
surprise and and certainly now uh gives
us gives us motivation to continue
following up with some uh some invivo
work right and I'm glad you brought up
that term because I wanted to talk about
sort of the difference between you know
inv Ro and invivo and I know you can't
really predict the future but when
moving from from inv vitro to invivo how
can sort of these um results or like you
said you get excited about a molecule
how can then when you translate that
into invivo how can that sort of how can
things
change it's
it's usually I i' say the the the
translatability from inv vitro to invivo
is pretty High um depending on depending
on the data you're using to to
inform the other right so if the invitro
data say is um is inv vitro biology data
about say the the pharmacology so the
binding and the functional assays we ran
um so if you if you get a good
understanding of this molecule has this
activity at at this receptor and this
receptor
mediates these effects or
interactions you can follow that up in
Vivo and and typically you can you can
see right so for example if you see um
CB1 agonism right you would say okay now
we're going to put this into an invivo
model and subsequently we'll see
analgesia right that's a common Delta 9
THC effect in in rodents um or any uh
CB1 Agonist with with really any decent
efficacy
right so when we're talking when you
were talking about CBG v um So based on
the pharmacology there like do you have
any idea like what sort of conditions
that might be helpful
for it's a little bit tricky on the on
the pharmacology side of things we have
to do a little bit more work there but
in um in some of the uh inv Vivo work
that we've done um that I hope to be
able to to have some more data to
present in a few weeks
um it seems to be uh very stimulating um
which is also interesting so we we're
seeing a dose effect there um which in
the model we used can sometimes be
predictive of uh neuroprotective effects
um which can come into play when you're
looking at say traumatic brain injury or
Alzheimer's um there's lots of different
ways to approach those and and they're
very complex studies but um I'm I'm I'm
pretty excited at the chance to to
explore CBG CBGB further um in in some
of these models and really start to
understand what we've got on our hands
interesting and now have you done work
to investigate sort of combining these
different compounds to see what the
effects are I mean I know that uh the
Entourage effect is uh is
real we haven't yet um so so our
Approach at this point is um really
trying to to screen these minor or rare
canabo you know through our platform um
and get an idea or or rank them really
by those that we
feel have have uh the data behind them
to pursue further for either a
commercial um pipeline or to use as a
scaffold for our therapeutic uh program
um but uh but at this point we we
haven't combined any we think we're
we're hoping that we're adding value by
adding to the knowledge we know about
these individual
cannabinoids um and well I I don't think
we'll we'll ever um be able to recreate
the chemical complexity um that leads to
the Entourage effect I think our goal is
is that if we understand enough about
these cannabinoids or or other
phytochemicals individually we can start
to thoughtfully put them together
uh with with other phyl chemicals or
with existing you know bioactive
neutraceuticals or health supplements to
to Really bolster specific effects um
well not having to worry about the the
Myriad of other other chemicals that may
be in the
product right no and that was something
that I noticed when I was looking at the
website as well was sort of this idea of
sort of combining uh the the compounds
the cannaboids with other vitamins or
probiotics itics proteins things like
that so is that that's something that
you you're
investigating yeah yeah so the the the
the commercial side of the businesses is
actively exploring um existing uh
combination supplements and how the
introduction or the addition of a canabo
or or more than one canabo may further
enhance their effectiveness so um we've
identified several that have a a very
solid um uh uh uh Clin clinical
literature space behind them you know
they're very solid as far as efficacy is
concerned from a safety profile they
look good um and so we're we're now
taking what we've learned about some
canabo and putting those in there and
eventually once we we start getting
these these manufactured uh the intent
is to do some some small uh clinical
trials or or focus groups to understand
their advocacy in humans excellent and
now which compounds um are you looking
to kind of move into the next phase of
uh of your
work definitely uh well definitely can
flaven a and CBGB um as I mentioned um
they it's a little early on those to to
be involved in the in the combination
products we're just talking about um but
but we definitely want to understand a
little bit more about those uh and and
as I said if if if there's potential for
them on their own that's that's one
thing um but the really interesting part
about this the nalo kind of ecosystem is
that we have this commercial side where
we're developing uh the synthetic
approaches for these phyto canabo mimics
but that also informs us on the
therapeutic side so our drug development
side where we can take what we know
about existing phyto canabo or
phytochemicals and do some of this work
that that we're talking about today and
then say you know what that has a lot of
therapeutic potential but it's not very
druglike it's not very soluble or it's
rapidly
metabolized um so how can we use
Medicinal Chemistry to modify that
molecule and improve upon those
characteristics while also either
retaining or improving the
pharmacological activity for the
indication or or the end point that that
we're looking at um so really it's it's
it's this like I say it's kind of this
feedback loop loop ecosystem we have
where no matter what data we're
collecting on either side of the
business we're learning more and more
and more about these different structure
activity relationships and how uh we can
take that knowledge to inform really
either side of our business so that's
interesting so for example when you were
talking before about CBG V and it's um
it being soluble and that being a good
characteristic are you sort of saying
that you can look at the structure of
that molecule and maybe apply some of
that to maybe another molecule that
isn't as soluble to try to give it that
um ability you you could
um typically what what we're trying to
do and what a lot of folks do with
structure activity relationships is is
by looking at the properties of a number
of of molecules so a large sample size
you start you can start to see patterns
emerge where then you can you can more
confidently say okay so making a
modification here seems to be critical
for x uh and so when you get large
enough data sets you can you can start
to tease those things apart and then
absolutely you can you can start to uh
tinker molecularly tinker um with with
purpose um and so we have a uh the the
first phase of anything we do um at nalo
is is our our insilico um uh platform so
so we have several different modeling
capabilities where we will put some of
these rare uh minor canabo we also use
it for novel chemical entities that we
we develop for the therapeutic side and
so we're we're able to model how these
might interact with different biological
systems from metabolism to PK as well as
their pharmacology so how they interact
with certain receptors in the brain and
so that's kind of our first pass and
when we see favorable results come out
of that work that's when we move into
the type of work we're talking about now
so we try to confirm that the data we've
we've modeled using you know PM work
adme work uh inv vitro studies um and so
that's step two and and if we we
continue to see favorable results we we
keep we keep investigating them until we
have a very very strong um profile and
rationale for commercialization or uh
therapeutic
work about how long does that whole
process take it it depends um it depends
on if if um if we have the target
validated from a from say molecular
docking perspective um
it's not too bad um if we have to
validate a new Target um that that can
take us you know a couple weeks maybe um
depending on the complexity and you know
depending on if we're looking at say the
orthosteric sites versus alisic sites um
what kind of training sets are already
available um but it's it's it's pretty
amazing uh how much this has evolved in
just the last few years um especially
with with machine learning and and AI um
it's it's evolving very very quickly and
becoming an incredibly useful tool um
that I think most biotechs and Pharma
companies are are becoming actively
reliant on um and it's certainly been
working very well for us um and again
any any data we collect you know
anything we collect um whether it's our
data or something we find in the
literature we can put that data back
into our system and it's going to
refine its its predictions going going
uh on so that we get more accuracy
better confidence in in what our models
are predicting and that's the ins
silicle work that you're talking
about so even beyond that so you have
the in silico in vitro inv Vivo and all
that how about that whole process how
long does that all take yeah so so on
the the commercial side so if we're just
trying to stand a rare say CBGB for
example if if we wanted to work that
through to the point we have enough
confidence to um to start exploring how
to how to synthesize it and optimize
that synthesis you know we could we
could maybe maybe six months to a year
before we really have a good
understanding maybe a little bit longer
um if we if we really wanted to explore
a couple different end points um on the
therap cutic side obviously that's a you
know the drug development uh pipeline is
is a much much much longer uh game um
and the stakes are a little bit a little
bit different right so um so if we were
to use again just CBGB for example um as
a scaffold and using our um computerated
drug
design you know to say generate you know
500 600 novel chemical entities based
off of CB bgv then running those through
say we get a few that that look okay we
may do another round of computerated
drug design or or Medicinal Chemistry to
further refine those uh those ncees into
potential hits that then we start to
again verify use physically in these
very basic um inv vitro assays um and
and as you know then from there it's
it's more refinement and more refinement
and more work and until eventually get a
a lead candidate um that that you really
want to push forward and and hope that
you get into first in human studies and
and clinical work but uh
that that you know probably a couple
years um you know at best right you
might get lucky but um but yeah we're
we're we're we're moving along at a
pretty good clip for our size um but
yeah that's if somebody figures out how
to speed that process up they'll they'll
make a lot of money right and so so the
goal is if I'm hearing you correctly is
to actually find a novel compound that
sort of mimics the action of the natural
compound and then commercialize that
correct or or we enhance that activity
right so we can we can explore ways to
um say change the you know we can try to
to make modifications and maybe say
um add bias to to these molecules or
which which signaling pathway they may
they may prefer over another knowing
that activating one pathway may have
common side effects that we want to
avoid um and so so that's that's just an
example of of one way that we can we can
keep working on this and and again get
to hopefully a a very safe an effective
therapeutic or or a library that we can
we can begin to use structure activity
relationship work to to really try to
find the key components that we can uh
exploit excellent all right Tim well
winding down here before I let you go I
wanted to give you an opportunity to
share any other resources that you think
folks might be interested in reading
more about if they're interested in this
topic um and also any information about
you and nalu bio that you'd like to
share uh please do so and I'll be happy
to put any links in the show description
so people can find it
easy yeah um I'm you know I think uh I
don't have any specific resources um you
can you can check out our website and
learn a little bit more about about what
we're trying to to do at nalo in our um
approach to to synthetic cannabinoids um
whether it be you know synthetic mimics
of phytos or um our therapeutic uh
pipeline um
um yeah I can't really I can't really
think of any other other resources to uh
to send folks to I will say that um uh
the majority of this data if not if not
all of it uh will will begin packaging
up and um we'll hopefully get get out in
a peer-reviewed publication here uh
before the end of the year um and and
hope to have many many other
Publications uh following excellent yeah
and in the meantime if uh you want to
have a conversation with Tim and the
folks at nalo bio make sure you come out
to canmed and uh and pick his
brain yeah yeah definitely looking
forward to it it's going to be a g to be
a great conference yes we are very much
looking forward to it as well all right
Tim well thanks again for the time um
and can't wait to see you down in
Florida thank you Ben
[Music]
hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Tim Lefever check out the links in the
show description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and thanks again to
this episode sponsor brains
basule in the meantime go to cam at
events.com to check out all the details
related to canmed 24 speakers poster
presenters networking events panels
workshops meals and more all the
information is there while you're at
camet events.com sign up for email
alerts so you don't miss any
announcements before the event if you
are planning to join us in Florida this
may register for your ticket package now
space is limited and tickets are going
fast I also invite you to follow us on
social media we are on LinkedIn
Instagram X and Facebook just search for
cim at events and lastly please rate
review And subscribe so you don't miss
an
episode all right that's it from us stay
safe stay healthy and be sure to join us
for the next C Coffee Talk
[Music]
oh