hello i would like to thank quartergen
for the great hospitality and the
wonderful conference of course
and all of the sponsors as well um
my name is mark lewis founded in april
in
2011 and that was the result of
trying to do at home r d piggybacked
upon service laboratories in california
um i'd always known that you know i had
a fond appreciation for plants so
i'd always loved flavor and aroma and
high oil content whether it was basil or
cannabis and when i tried to do r d in
2007 i had all these issues because
i couldn't get any type of consistent
results
from lab lab so
in 2011 napro set out to accomplish
several tasks
and do them as quickly as possible the
first thing we wanted to do was
create a robust and reliable validated
assay
to look at and screen all of the
relevant terpenes
and as well as some of the not so
relevant or unknown ones but we end up
testing for and validating for 17 and
11 cannabinoids then be able to
communicate that data in a meaningful
way not only to
patients but also to plant breeders
or physicians or just
the canna sewer you know someone who
wants to learn more about the plant
during that time we collected a bunch of
data from 2011
2015 looking at
essentially the whole chemo scape of
what was
popular medicine in california at the
time
once we had that data set we did a few
different analysis on it the first
analysis was to
really analyze these cultivars see what
metabolites were present
and see if any um patterns formed in a
potentially like classification system
based on secondary metabolites
the second analysis was to observe a
single genotype
over many many replicates in the exact
same environment
to see if what the real you know metrics
are for consistency and quality to
establish
quality metrics for certain clients
analysis three uh we wanted to compare
homozygous hybrid seed with
the asexual clonal propagation to see if
the rsds from plant to plant could be
minimized versus the rsds from
lot to lot for the single genotype
the reason this is important is because
as you learn as a chemist
all systems can be defined by the
summation of your inputs and outputs
so garbage in equals garbage out and
that's for us if
if the medicine were taken we don't know
what it is i mean you can't black box
that
or for a plant if you're giving it
stimulus
either environmental or chemical you
have to make sure you know what those
are
so that you don't get a the garbage
piece
in 2011 we were provided a unique
opportunity
someone had a series of controlled
environment
production facilities and 56 known
cultivars by common name these cultivars
have been
you know grown by these same cultivators
for decades so we knew that
blue dream was blue dream and og was og
and
of course i have quite an experience
with the plant as well so
our team was able to match common name
with the actual genotype that was being
produced um which kind of flew in the
face of
some previous scientists who said what's
in a name
and essentially
you know there is a name game out there
because the marketplace demands cookies
you have to have cookies so if you don't
have cookies it suddenly becomes cookies
when it moves across a state line
and the further you get across you know
the further the variation becomes
so the the thought here was well let's
figure this out
let's look at how cultivating in the
same environment over and over again
affects a single genotype
and and let's do this thing like like
real people
real scientists so i'm gonna go through
some of the data that we collected and
explain why it was good data
and and that's because we made took
painstaking efforts to ensure that
the lighting was the same the the
headspace above the light was the same
the rooms were the same dimension
the tables were the same the soil was
sourced from the same vendors
same techniques and and all that stuff
and napro oversaw
the entire project we collected climate
metrics over the course of the entire
lifespan of the plant
um making sure to produce control charts
something that people in the industry
often kind of have that starry deer eyed
look when you say so that if there were
out of bounds
situations you could eliminate that from
the data set as
a flaw similarly with the
nutrient metrics we monitored what went
into the soil system what went on the
leaves
and made sure that it was consistent and
the same across all batches
even if we were spiking humic acid on
day 40 it needed to be day 40 every time
and this is all part of the ge equals
your phenotype chemotype equation that's
shown there so what we try to do is
minimize that
delta e of part of the equation
and then that produced the phenotype and
we measured those metrics via
tape measure size of the bud height of
the flower
biomass um you know pretty
standard took pictures along the way so
that it looked nice when you went from
page to page i don't know what the
pictures do other than that
but the next piece was a little bit more
tricky we had to
actually collect the data from the
chemotype stuff right
so there wasn't any testing laboratory
out that was really doing terpenes at
the time everyone was just
dabbling in it a little bit so what we
sought out to do
was develop this methodology we paid to
make it open source
so anyone starting a laboratory anywhere
can
download this guideline from sample prep
to your analysis and you can get
reliable data for
the cost of an hplc and a gcfid
we answered a lot of tough questions
sample prep
extract stability i mean intraday some
of these matrices have
degradation of certain terpenoids and
formation of other ones so
let's be really careful it's all about
the rsd
so just take a look at our material in
data flow so you know that we
thought about it a little bit we looked
at a living plant we took the
morphological data combine it with the
environmental data
took a sample followed it through the
drying curing process
collected that data in this particular
show we're going to talk about the tier
1 assays we did which is a single
extraction in ethanol to create
samples we have to do one dilution for
the cannabinoids
as you know cannabinoids less than two
percent greater than 30 percent falls
outside the line of beer's law so
you have to do that dilution a lot of
people weren't doing dilutions in 2011
they were just shotgun blasting it
so we knew that there was rsds
associated on one side of the curve
or the other which could explain the the
um
conformational bias of the increasing
amount of thc found in flowers through
2000 to 2015 because there was 36
one it was crazy so then we put that in
a database
um create an analysis create our control
charts and then
it says mcf sheets that was a really old
name for what we call a phytofax report
a report that kind of
gives you a flash of what that cultivar
is
so to name a few of the 56 cultivars we
examined in this
there's everything from pinterest creek
old amsterdam classic train wreck
everything that you can imagine is on
there and those are
that's girl scout cookies on the left if
you're curious and candyland on the
right
i thought i'd make the presentation fun
by putting pictures of buds up there
because we haven't seen any yet
it's all been really heavy you know i
forgot my joke
oh my gosh thank you thank you thank you
you never remember
the rainbow at the very beginning
there's a greenhouse full of weed at the
end of it
it really was so the first thing we
looked at was total cannabinoid
concentration across the entire
population of 56
this is kind of the distribution here
you know we had we had a max of 36
or so percent cannabinoids in a min of
10 with you know
an average of around 20 which kind of
jives with what everyone's saying
of lot rsds you know average about 12
and we found that the highly sampled
cultivars had locked a lot rsds of 10 to
20 percent
which kind of you know arno has comp's
number of 15 percent falls right in the
middle there
um we've seen some things have more
variability
and some things have less and we just
started to wonder is that
do the things have less variability have
less of a
environmental impact maybe more stable
somehow with the environment
so when we went to look at terpenes
total terpene concentration range from
about half a percent to two and a half
percent
with a mean is about 1.5 percent and
this is
in indoor under artificial lights just
to be clear
a lot a lot rsds were increased
for the terpenes which kind of
symbolized that the
terpene biosynthetic pathways are more
influenced by epigenetic factors
and overall we found that cannabinoid
content was more stable than terpenoid
content between
locked a lot one of the
things that this brought up was well is
there a correlation between
high terpene production and high
cannabinoid production
and when we looked at that we saw that
there is indeed a correlation between
higher
essential oil production and higher
cannabinoid production however
the correlation factor is really low
that means that only about
15 percent of the factors influencing
the terpene content derive from the
cannabinoid content which means that 85
percent of that is coming from somewhere
else whether it's genetic or
environmental
we don't know the correlation is real
just really tiny
but what does that tell us about each
individual unique cultivar
and how someone can use this tool to be
able to treat specific ailments because
you know everyone says well what's
what's in a terpene
you know dustin uh started talking about
lineal wall
increasing efficacy mara talked about
the entourage effect
thanks to dr mitchulum for coining the
phrase
and it's it's like we have to look at
each individual terpene
so we created this really really oops i
skipped a slide forgot here's the
whole spectrum of plants from the low
concentration of thc to high
low terpenes to high and they're in four
letter codes so it doesn't tell you a
whole lot i'm just showing you the
spread
but the individual terpenes themselves
would colored with
color coordinated so that they would be
intuitive
but also informative and create what we
call a phytoprint
it's essentially the fingerprint of a
particular plant
we started this with basil and this
slide actually had basil where the um
the the the buds are now and
sometimes i think about if we could grow
a bud that big
how that might be pretty incredible
um especially after drying could you
imagine how big it would be on the plant
it's crazy um but this is this is nice
so
essentially terpinoline is red osamine
is orange limonene is yellow pinene's
green
mircine is purple and a little lavender
so they're all intuitive
you can create collateral that you know
color matches and it shows
different types of effects that these
things do
but more importantly you can look at
different cultivars and compare them
and you have a couple examples here
but essentially if you if you look at
the major
terpenes that are produced by the plant
they really class off pretty quickly
either you have one major terpene two or
three
it's more rare to have four or five or
six all equal amounts so
if you look at bubba kush east coast
sarah diesel and crypto they both have
high amounts of limonene and
caryophylline however
you can see the mir scene in the lineal
wall disappears in crypto which
those subtle minor differences are how
you differentiate the subtleties between
each cultivar
across the bottom you have classic perps
blue dream 2
and it's just 2 because there are
multiple cups of blue dream
which i'm sure quarterfin knows about
and then old amsterdam
just a different purple class we call
this purple class because
before we put science behind it we used
our indigenous knowledge
all the purples tended to be mere scene
dominant but we just call them purples
because they're purple and then it
turned out that it
worked out in our color scheme thank god
problematic if it didn't
but you can see the subtle differences
here in the pinene and the caryophylline
between the different cultivars and
that's how you really differentiate each
cultivar
but they're all really within these
three cultivars are across two classes
um if we look at some archetypes and
these are uh
you know there's a terpenoline dominant
that's associated with like your train
wreck
limonene dominant this particular is an
og
that's a og legend mir scene dominant
that's purple anything that was cbd
prior to
2014 was pretty much all mere scene
dominant
osamine dominant this is a hawaiian
plant
i mean some of these things produce like
two percent of a single
terpenoid pinene dominance beta
cariophylline dominance
and terpenes are important because beta
carotene actually is a cb2
agonist so if you're only testing for
cannabinoids and you're giving your
child a preparation you should be very
cognizant to the fact that
when you concentrate this co2 anything
you lose your monoterps but you usually
get a
ton of the karyophylenes whether it's
alpha or beta
they're there they're present so you
should be aware of that and if you
hybridize two of these like the pinene
group and the myrsine group you'll get
something that
kind of looks in between the two or a
combination of the two
this is interesting because you know you
create custom medicines this way right
and if you could just buy seed that was
the medicine you wanted instead of uh
what would you call the lottery you know
you don't know what you're going to get
it's like a box of chocolates
so when we do a dendogram of this
chemical data
you get a nice breakup of hierarchy
we call it the terpene superclass system
it's just based on metabolites so
if pinein is in the major terpene world
and those cultivars fall in that family
branch
limonene caryophyllene as such
mercinosamina terpenoline
interestingly limonene and keraflain are
seem to be quite coupled and osamine and
myrcene quite coupled in the plant
so lots of neat trends you see here but
just
showing some stuff and from that bore
the classification system where we
wanted to do away with indic and sativa
because we we don't really care about
20 years ago or 100 000 years ago we
care about right now and what it's going
to tell our patients so
if you use a simple alpha system here to
outline what the top three terpenes are
in this case it's limonene caryophyllene
and myrcin for lcm
one means it's a type one plant and g
means that cannabidiolic acid is the
second most abundant cannabinoid
then you have a quick cartridge of
five-digit item code that would work in
a qr system
for inventorying at dispensaries and
totally removes the common name game
[Music]
this led to having to do a pca analysis
on the data points to make sure that our
classification system would hold water
and as you can see it did the ellipses
are really great
clustering for different chemo types if
you
notice the the purple here the blue
dreams
there's also kins gdp thrown in here and
there's actually three cuts of blue
dream
then you have headband and several
different og's you have purple train
wreck and classic train wreck and then
so it's not just the same genotype
well it may be based on the world but we
know that the train wreck ones aren't
because one was purple and one was not
so
um the point is is that this this
the system works however some genotypes
have too much lot to lot variability
and over the course of say 40 or 80 runs
you you have this plant that slides from
one or two different classes right
in this case we're looking at o.g kush
another great picture of a wonderful
flower
it's an mcl one t-class as we designate
it internally that's mercin karaokeline
limonene
these things have two percent chirps
always and greater than 25
cannabinoids it's truly a beast ogs are
marked by equal amounts of limonene
karyophylline and myrsine
quite regularly but if you look at these
this phytoprint over say a dozen or so
runs you have a separation of a couple
different classes here where
sometimes the limonene is dominant
sometimes the the keratophyllene is
dominant
and then you have this mirror scene
dominance across here
all of this is highly contingent upon
environment and time of harvest of
course
and post-harvest conditioning so
you can have terpenes degrade to other
things so the point here is that quality
control and laboratory integration with
production
is absolutely essential and the idea of
having
third-party laboratory services that you
send samples to is kind of like
ah to me because it doesn't make sense
unless you're just making pure extracts
and then you're still
waiting in a holding pattern for your
results and
not even guaranteed if they're correct
and if you have to send it to three
different laboratories oh my gosh and
then how do you pick which one do you
average them
i don't think so so complicated
especially
i mean this is the same genotype same
environment over and over
if we look at a control chart here for
total terpene content and total
cannabinoid content
with we ran a little experiment just
trying to check out i'm trying to speed
up here
check out the difference between organic
practices plus biostimulants
which biostimulants are that biome thing
that kevin was talking about at the
beginning
well if we take away the biostimulants
and just do organic practices we have
we see a significant decrease in both
terpenes production
and cannabinoid production the producers
didn't like that very much so we had to
quickly change that's why there's only a
few data sets there and then we went to
conventional
agriculture salts moved assaults away
from organic practices
and brought the biostimulant back and we
got a boost in thc compared to the
baseline
and a decrease in terpenes so it was
very interesting for us to
as it confirmed what the grower said all
along they had to do it this way to get
the oiliest tastiest
products but at the same time there's a
neat way to boost your thc by switching
the salts
this variability in cannabis brings up
the quality question
the industry seriously lacks qaqc
most producers don't even have
established quality metrics
i mean it's like you have to have size
of a if it's a flower you have to have
size
shape color all these things most people
don't consider
the only seed on the market you can buy
that's true breeding
currently is cannabis seed and it may
not even be in most cases
unlike corn you can't just buy a disease
resistant og
or a bi-colored kush so
but people are making advances and one
of our
clients wanted to make a type 2 train
wreck because
this particular person had anxiety and
she felt that jack rare really made her
you know feel calm and she wanted a type
2 version this
a train wreck is really a txx1g class
which means it's trapinaline dominant
type one with canon hydraulic acid is
the second most abundant cannabinoid
that's a picture of the classic train
wreck right there
very very specific morphology
when you look at total cannabinoid
concentration across all the individuals
in the class it's really nice and
homozygous all at about one to two
i was going to say that we do everything
exactly backwards
we'll start from the plant you start
from the human the humans say cbd to thc
and the plant breeders say thc to cbd
so such is life but if you look at the
terpenes
it's beautiful they're all in the same
class
in this particular uh data set there was
like 70 individuals but
i didn't want to clutter to the screen
with fido prints
the point is is that things are changing
in the world of propagation
and we should start thinking about this
because the
rsds from plant to plant here were less
than the rsds of a single cultivar from
lot a lot
this begs up the question of indica
versus sativa again
i don't know i think it might be better
used as an effects gauge than a
genealogical nomenclature in the current
system of medicine not taxonomy
[Music]
so end on a set of sample reports i was
talking about before
where you have the top terpenes
color-coded at the top and the bottom to
give you a feeling of the plant
total cannabinoids terps and moisture
content along with the class
a picture of the flowers that you can
visually identify the product tested
with the product on the shelf
we have suggested entourage effects that
are based on
algorithms and patient panels
done over the course of 2011 to 2015
a little flavor spider graph just a
really cool way to do it
warm tones are typically more
stimulating cool tones are typically
more sedating so it's a
very intuitive system so that's how you
have it
thanks
you