hi everybody thanks so much for being
here today thanks for for John for his
his talk which is very enlightening and
I look forward to following up with with
some details on some of the things that
we've been up to in British Columbia as
well as with my colleagues Cindy or sir
and Aaron Hilliard from digi paths labs
in Las Vegas essentially you'll notice
that there's a there's gonna be a lot of
parallels there with with John's talk so
I think we've seen these illustrations
of the plant morphology and I like to
refer to to cannabis as essentially a
single species with multiple gene pools
and as we all know and what we've talked
about a lot today is the fact that the
influence of cannabis and humans and
vice versa has been nearly
disproportionate in nature in the sense
that what you can see here on this
current map is what I would say is the
origin of different morphologies of
cannabis without referring to to
anything more than just a morphology and
the size of the leaves so you see a
narrow leaf hemp nlh kind of in europe
they're the broadleaf drug type and the
narrow leaf drug type which those would
be the indica sativa of the recreational
or the medical market and then the
broadleaf hemp which is more thought of
as being the Chinese hemp so essentially
these would be the you know kind of a
primer of where the plants emerged and
evolved and essentially as we know it's
moved around the world and there's
hybrids between most likely all of those
gene pools at this point broad leaf and
narrow leaf hemp have hybrids and
obviously I think when we refer to drug
tag cannabis these days we're really
referring to a large hybrid gene pool of
both broadleaf drug type and narrow leaf
drug type so afgan occur and kind of
South Asia origin with some of the
autoflowering traits and possibly
specifically autoflowering traits
originating from northern latitudes so
typically European hemp that was
intrigued rest
but in essence you know what we see is
that we have a natural process of moving
a plant around the world and then we
have the impact of artificial selection
like humans have had on any other crop
and here's a here's of paper from Ernie
small who essentially illustrates what
this means and so we have on the one
side the fiber cultivars and then we
have more than narcotic cultivars and
the concept here is that there was
divergent selection selective pressures
by the people that were essentially
collect with these plants and then
selected them for very different reasons
whether you know let's say broad
categories of drug cultivars vs. ham
cultivars this relates to this is the
same paper or not a paper by a very
small as well but this relates to the
question everybody asked hey let's get
you know is it good to do commodity
cannabinoids from ham grown outdoors or
are we better off focusing on you know
growing indoor in a controlled
environment a dropped drug track
cannabis so essentially what you see
here and what this table shows is that
there is a significant difference in
between the size of trichomes in drug
type cannabis versus fiber type cannabis
over hand versus marijuana there is here
essentially almost a you know one point
six time largest size of trichomes in in
drug cannabis so essentially you can see
that this plant was purpose bred for
resin production so essentially having
larger trichomes maybe more numerous
trichomes is also one of the key
features there and essentially for me at
this point in time I think that's the
large difference between Hampton and
cannabis is really the you know that's
why we cap at 5% when we're talking hemp
that hasn't been integrated with that
key trait of resin production I'm not
going to go over the the solid paper
because obviously it was just covered
but what I did do here is is essentially
delve a little bit deeper into that that
concept of the divergence between these
two gene pools in particularly European
hemp and drug type cannabis and this is
work done recently published at the end
of 2017 by a group that I did my
undergrad thesis and my master's thesis
at the University of Lausanne in
Switzerland where I'm
from so essentially my my master's
advisor Dahomey Gouda and one of my my
committee members were the lead
investigators on this study and the
interesting part about this study is
that they used the type of genetic
markers called single sequence repeat or
microsatellites and the interesting part
with those is that those markers are
typically thought to not be under the
effect of selection so they are
typically thought of being neutral so it
means that it's it's basically immune to
the effect of people moving stuff around
and essentially moreso breeding for
specific purposes so neutral areas of
the genome they don't code for genes but
they might be associated with genes so I
think it makes more sense to use neutral
markers when we're trying to decipher
the evolutionary history of a particular
you know a particular structure that
we're observing and in this case here we
do see as you can see here from the the
green plot on the right there every
single one of these bars is an
individual plant so there's a 1234
plants sampled here out of 48
populations and I think this is probably
the first population level study on
cannabis sativa where we have you know
thousands of individuals and thousands
of populations
so essentially red and green separates
that these two gene pools between HAMP
and and drug type cannabis and then you
see that there is essentially you know a
clear pattern of structure but there's
there's not not much more that we can
see from this image so thankfully to do
these authors they they essentially
shared their data so I downloaded the
data from from the +1 website and
repeated those analyses and added some
essentially labels to it but also going
beyond that seeing a particular
structure where we have on the top right
essentially the monoecious varieties of
European hemp and and as we as we go
kind of from the the blue colored to the
yellow colored we're now going towards
dioecious hams
so essentially mono ashes have been a
hermaphrodite
variety as opposed to dioecious gonna be
more what we're what what's coming for
us to understand that we have both a
male and a female plant and it's
interesting to see and it makes sense
there that obviously the dioecious hamp
a cluster closer to to the narrow leaf
drug type and then we see essentially
divergence towards the broadleaf indica
afghan occur whatever we want to call it
but it really is quite interesting that
we can we can tease apart a pattern here
from you know a larger a larger pool of
samples than what had been seen
previously using you know single
nucleotide polymorphism which are you
know possibly both functional or under
selection and also neutral so I want to
talk more about snips John mentioned
them essentially this is what they look
like here it's a single pair difference
on a sequence it's one of the most
common some one of the common sources of
polymer polymorphisms so essentially the
source of variation that's the most
commonly found it is typically thought
to arise from a mistake in replication
from one basically from one cell cycle
to the next and it's also one of the
means of you know generating diversity
so using mutagens and things like that
but nature does it all on its own it
doesn't necessarily require us and
typically we see an average frequency of
about one snip for every thousand base
pairs and when we're talking about the
cannabis genome we see that that's
actually there's actually quite a bit
more snips so large amount of diversity
about one snip every 100 base pairs in
cannabis so essentially what I want to
talk about here and this is an example
from one of the licensed producers in
Canada that I I knew their horticultural
director and they came he came to me and
said something very interesting happened
in in one of our strains that we bought
from the BC bud depo which is probably
not the most recognized seed source but
essentially they have a variety called
shiatsu cush which they claim is from
Japan which it's not but it's typically
a high THC variety and then here in this
case as you can see something happened
in the production line that
caused one plant to express CBG inequal
almost an equal concentration to to THC
acid so it doesn't have to be a mutation
it could be something else if it be an
insertion of a transportable element
right inside of an active THC a synthase
gene but it's really quite interesting
how one of the reasons why they pick
this up is because they have to they
have to QA QC test their products and
when you when the when the one sample
test comes back with a high c BG they
don't believe that it's happening so
they resend the same plant and they see
that actually something happened to one
of the clones and I'm happy to see that
they're actually producing it as a plant
and offering and you know as medicine to
people that that would be interested in
having access to different minor
cannabinoids so these things can happen
you know if a mutation can happen in a
you know small AC MPR greenhouse or
a grow house in Whistler Canada you know
it it's definitely happening in those
fields out there all the time we're just
not looking for it because of the scales
were growing at so this is something
that I that I did is essentially using
data from from medicinal genomics and I
you know part of the reason why I'm here
is because of the philosophy of sharing
this type of information with people to
be able to you know there's a lot of
information we can't all you know go
through it and decipher it so here's an
example and I've got the NRC logo up
here and that's a little bit of a wave
to you John page because as you see the
USO 31 and the phenol as samples there
came from them so this is all in silico
data downloaded from the internet and
again thanks to medicinal genomics and
in john's group for sharing that data
essentially what I do is is use
statistical approaches to be able to now
you know decipher genomics and make it a
little bit more approachable and maybe
fast-track some of these developments as
we're talking about marker assisted
selection so here you see that the
clustering like we said we've got fin
all out there hemp and then we have the
drug type cannabis that have some kind
of a structure but again this is done
with 28 accessions and starting with a
hundred and
180,000 dataset 180,000 snips so what I
did is in silico I managed to use
statistical analyses like discriminant
analysis the principal component to
reduce this 180,000 snip dataset to a
set of 42 that in silico on the computer
provided the exact same pattern and
here's something that I did also way
back in a day a 3d PCA that then was
used by some other groups that are
presenting their data in you know in a
fashion like this but it's the same
principle here we see that there is a
clustering going on but again you know a
very basic structure that we see so
here's what I set out to do with it with
another follow-up study in 2017 was
essentially compared to indica sativa
paradigm so what I took data from the
internet on terpene expression and then
what I did there is that I forced the
software to say ok on the Left here I'm
going to say indica sativa hybrid how do
they differentiate themselves that you
can see they're all overlapping and I
tested a couple of options including
some of what the name Pro Research had
done which they said I think it was
limonene caryophyllene and mersin so I
did that and I did another essentially
clustering possibility which was mersin
turpentine and limonene as you can see
this was kind of what was the best a
cluster that I showed and essentially
what I did from that is I took the
genetic data constrained it based on
these three classes and was able to have
a data set that that almost perfectly
clustered these groups into their
relevant groups here this is more of a
proof of concept but essentially this
data is available on the internet I have
these 21 markers that are available for
people to download and play with and
again this is really just digested
information from from canopy dia so the
study with with terpenes and digi paths
really kind of came as a follow up to
that and you know going from you know 70
something samples do now about 5,000
samples and this is all terpene data so
you see all of the variables there
limonene blah blah and you see how
essentially the software can
clustered these groups into into three
different groups and this is just drug
time cannabis but typically you know
Amer seen better Curie often in dominant
and red atropine and lean dominant group
and an alignment in dominant group with
obviously some other terpenes in there
but we get a really consistent
clustering of these three groups based
on their on their chemo chemo chemo
tipic data so what I did is the same
kind of concept using fancy statistics
to to simplify and and really actually
generate synthetic variables called
principal components and and here what
you can see is out of those five
thousand individuals seventy samples
that were a sequence essentially with a
similar genotyping by sequencing
approach by medicinal genomics and you
see that there is there still that
cluster still holds essentially and
there's still some there's some overlap
there and this it's not a perfect fit
but essentially from that data set I was
able to to generate 48 sets of primers
that I wanted to validate from the in
silico on the computer studies to now
being able to say we can do this in the
lab in a repeatable fashion so
interestingly out of 48 markers we
really only had about 23 that were
validated so nine of them just never
even amplified so I think it's based on
the large amount of snips in the priming
areas of the primers we found that
sixteen that showed polymorphism on on
in silico data were actually monomorphic
even between hemp and cannabis and three
minutes essentially that out of that 18
of them were associated with terpene
expression as well and here's just an
idea of the assignment where we compare
the the genome GBS or 10,000 snips
against 18 snips you can see that the
the statistical assignment to the
different groups is very very close you
know with essentially a thousand times
less markers and this is also being
confirmed by some other groups
essentially this is a study out of New
Mexico that shows the same kind of
clustering in Mersin terpene and lean
and limonene and this is something that
i validated with the licensed producer
in british columbia that i work with
called the flower corporation where
essentially now we've taken we
see HAMP here clustering by itself and
those are ex 59 and finola samples a
Mersin dominant group what we see here
is the little cloud the green cloud
that's actually a piney and dominant
accession that has pining and mersin but
piney is quite a bit higher and and you
can see at the bottom the pink is is ham
samples and so they're not all
distributed in one part but they you can
identify them very easily with this with
this approach I'm not sure what this is
I don't see it but this is interesting
I'm showing the same data here and what
it shows is the the markers that are
associated with the clustering is on the
top left there is hemp and we see my toe
so it's a mitochondrial marker that's
always fixed in hemp and then sw6 which
is actually a cheese synthase marker
that I developed that enable you to
irrefutably identify hemp so CBD hemp
versus CBD drug type cannabis anyways
and then the same when you look at HAMP
there's different phenotypes in the
fields that are also associated with you
know the height and also the the
fragrance of the plants and then again
you know the last thing that that I did
is essentially take these small set of
markers so actually just 23 of them and
I took all the data from canopy dia when
I wanted to see how how you know if
we're able to identify strains and again
here identified a few of them but one of
the well you know one of the the data
that that they show is a glute
clustering and a lot of the blue dream
accessions and the same of the Durbin
poison so it's just nice to see that you
know this actually translate across
across the board and thank you so much
everybody for the attention not much
time for questions