[Music]
welcome to the canb Coffee Talk podcast
where we talk with the leading Minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing I am your host Ben
ameral I'm the senior marketing manager
at medicinal genomics and proud member
of the team that puts on on the C
Conference so we are back from our
summer break I hope you didn't miss us
too much we are also working hard on
finalizing the details for our canmed 25
event which will be announced very soon
so if you haven't yet please go to
canmed events.com now and sign up for
email alerts so you can get that
announcement once it's made we are also
putting the finishing touches on the
canmed 24 video presentations and we'll
be adding those to the canmed archive
very soon as well so if you're on the
email list you'll get that notification
as
well my guest today is Zach ricardi he
is a cannabis specialist working with
biosafe systems which is a company that
produces environmentally sustainable
products to protect crops water and
people Zach regularly puts puts out
content on social media under the name
Zack the gro guy where he shares his
extensive knowledge of production and
plant Health that he has aced over the
years working with all types of
Growers Zach also authored the book
clean growing integrated Pest Management
for cannabis Growers The Ultimate Guide
to clean crops and safe cultivation
practices that protect Growers and
consumers during our our conversation we
discuss what is IPM and why is it
important to cannabis Growers how Zach
got involved with IPM for
cannabis how cannabis Growers can
Implement IPM into their
operations common pests and pathogens
that cannabis Growers are battling
common mistakes cannabis Growers make
when it comes to IPM and
more before we get to my conversation
with Zach I'd like to thank this episode
sponsor sponsor Advanced
Nutrients founded in 1999 Advanced
Nutrients was the first to develop a
complete nutrient system that unlocks
the true genetic potential of the
cannabis plant since its Inception the
brand has introduced more than 50
Innovations to the cultivation community
and continues to revolutionize the space
through proprietary scientific
discoveries learn more at Advanced
nutrients.com
okay and without any further Ado please
enjoy my conversation with Zach
[Music]
ricardi good morning Zach thanks so much
for joining us on the podcast thank you
Ben I really appreciate you having me on
here and uh shout out to Medical
genomics for putting us on all right
appreciate that yeah I'm excited to talk
with you today about integrated Pest
Management for cannabis cultivation it's
a topic that you've literally wrote the
book on um we'll talk about that I'm
sure um but how I became familiar with
you is um I was actually sitting at the
cultivation workshop at CED 24 which was
just um few weeks ago or in May and IPM
came up during the panel conf
conversation and one of the panelists I
don't recall who it was um but mentioned
you in your book clean growing
integrated Pest Management for cannabis
Growers The Ultimate Guide to clean
crops and safe cultivation practices
that protect Growers and consumers uh
mentioned that specifically and said
that you know you are the person to talk
to and you are you are the guy when it
comes to IPM so I quickly jotted that
name down and made sure to reach out to
you to get you on the podcast so I'm so
happy that you're here today um um so
maybe just to just to get us started
kind of set the scene tell us a bit
about your background how you got into
uh cannabis IPM and why it's uh
important so I kind of fell into
cannabis IPM almost out of necessity um
I've been in love with cannabis my
entire life and grew up in Colorado when
I turned 18 I uh basically moved out to
California to kind of Chase the you know
cannabis cultivator dream and operated
under SB for 20 and prop 215 in the
state of California for a while I was
able to kind of get on with the
gardening unlimiting crew who were the
guys that you know were basically
selling the supplies and that really
kind of kindled my passion for the you
know why not just uh you know the what
uh there's a lot of cannabis Growers
that follow charts but they never ask
why are we doing this and you know I
just kind of wanted to take that deeper
delve um originally being from Colorado
when our industry here started to you
know Snowball and blow up I had a lot of
people telling me that I needed to come
home and so I actually ran a smaller
hydroponic store in Golden Colorado for
I want to say about 2 years I ran it
from the day that it opened to the day
that it moved to Boulder um when the
owner decided that they were going to
relocate it was time for us to just kind
of separate paths and so I actually
painted bikes for Harley-Davidson for a
little while before I got on with a
company called ACW Supply here in Denver
Colorado um they are gold or uh
Colorado's oldest wholesale grower
Supply they've been around since 1893
three and being a counter guy there
really kind of jumpstarted my
IPM uh path I guess we could say because
I uh I was able to talk to many
different aspects of growers in a single
day and this is when cannabis was really
starting to snowball in Colorado but
being the counter guy I would talk to a
you know potato grower a poinsetta
grower and a hemp grower and a canabus
grower all in the same day and they all
had the same issue and so I was kind of
able to you know conglomerate that
knowledge and make suggestions across
different you know fields of horiculture
and say well you know this sector is
trying this this sector is trying this
and uh then Colorado came out with what
is called the approved list which is
basically a list of pesticides
fungicides bacteria sides that are safe
to put on a consumable crop like
cannabis and being in the very early
days being involved in seeing what that
list was looking like I was able to put
together a very comprehensive approach
for cannabis growers in a commercial
environment to rotate their chemistries
effectively so that they are able to
maximize their productivity and manh
hours because there's a lot of stuff on
these lists that's kind of misleading or
confusing and so being able to you know
again Emirate that Knowledge from large
scale Growers and be able to break down
an acre to you know a 4 by8 table really
help me out in terms of being able to
make some of this stuff understandable
for the industry and you know there was
a a long time ago there was this
mentality in cannabis where if you got
certain ailments you just chop down and
start over well you know traditional
Growers don't have that luxury and being
able to see that and say like you know a
cucumber grower can't clean out their
greenhouse because they got powdery
mildew and start from scratch they would
go bankrupt they have to have something
that could eliminate this powdery mildew
especially if they're organic certified
so there has to be a solution out there
we just hadn't found it yet and you know
being able to work with some of the
largest grows in the United States at
this point I feel that the biosafe sop
it does have some ins ciliary products
on there because I always say you know
I'd never hire an electrician to put in
a toilet for me we have the foundation
covered very very well and depending on
the unique scenario there are some ins
ciliary products from I don't
necessarily want to call them
competitors I will say other producers
of similar you know Organic pesticides
fungicides insecticides um they fit into
the program very well so that the grower
can be successful any one company that's
telling you that they have all the
answers is just trying to take your
money uh I think one of the reasons I
was probably brought up on this panel is
because I want Growers to be successful
I will often recommend things to
complement our program that biosafe
doesn't manufacture and that's because I
want you to be able to eliminate this
issue and also have that feather in your
cap so to speak uh because if this comes
up again you know what to do to come
full circle those Growers that their
mentality was to just chop down and
start over well the next time this
happens now you've lost two
crops right so now is your solution more
of a kind of reactive I have a problem I
need to address it is it or is it
preventative is it both I I always uh
you know preach preventative over
Curative but there are scenarios where
you know things find their way in and so
um in the book clean growing I do have
preventative measures as well as
Curative measures and the idea is that
Growers just get used to the idea of IPM
unfortunately it's kind of been the
redheaded stepchild of the industry and
it doesn't really matter until it
matters and then that's the only thing
that matters because Growers freak out
and they start spending a bunch of money
trying to eliminate issues that will
compromise the quality of their end
product where you know the the best plan
would be to have something in place
ahead of time stuff still Finds Its way
through ACS fail Lights Go Out people
quit you know there's insc silary stuff
that we always have to deal with beyond
what the plants are doing but you know
just like we have to water these plants
we also have to spray them and be that
intermediary because we've created a
perfect environment for these plants
we've also created a perfect environment
for pests because there's no natural
predation in these facilities and so a
rud AED a spider might a thrip Finds Its
way in that growth curve is exponential
unless we're spraying because they're
just going to grow unchecked so just
like we need to water these plants we
need to make sure that we have a program
in place to where we are that
intermediary to go after anything that
could find its way into the garden and
again you know recommending some other
company stuff with cannabis I really
only like to spray up until about week
three of flour unless it's absolutely
necessary at that point we can deploy
bcas which are our biological control
agents such as our beneficial insects or
nematodes basically using mother nature
to combat whatever else we could find in
that Garden um it allows Growers to
actually have a successful approach in
that aspect because they know what
they're targeting at that point if
you've been spraying these plants from
propagation all the way up until about
week three and you're in that
environment you know what kind of pest
you're dealing with so for example if
we're dealing with two dotted
spidermites you know that you need Pima
and californicus to be able to eliminate
that issue being in that garden and
spraying isn't just trying to eliminate
it it's also scouting it's prepping it's
note taking it's allowing you to
basically set up that next week for the
most amount of success that you can
possibly have and by you know basically
spraying up until that week three cut
off week three roughly it's it's when we
transition from stretching into setting
so there are some varieties it might be
a little later there are some varieties
it might be a little sooner but
basically we want to make sure that
we're addressing that wide array of
stuff that could find its way in because
while BCA work very very well Ben
they're specialized again plumbers put
in toilets electricians put in circuits
not all beneficial insects are going to
go after everything so when you see
people deploy ladybugs and they say they
have spider mes that's great that you
introduced a bunch of ladybugs and they
may eat some of those spider mites but
it's not a specialized food source for
that you know insect and so you're kind
of wasting money at that point by being
in the garden and having these notes and
knowing what happened last week you can
tell your approach next week so that you
are going to have the most success you
possibly can excellent all right before
we get too deep into it I'm hoping can
you explain or Define what is integrated
Pest
Management integrated Pest Management to
me is all things growing it's not just a
position that one person is assigned at
the Garden it's literally on the entire
team while there's one person that's
probably doing the sprays and doing the
logs and you know doing the heavy
lifting IPM is on everyone if we've got
a lazy team of trimmers and they go into
a dirty environment and then they go
into veg well then we just contaminated
veg so we have to educate the entire you
know Workforce that's at a facility at a
grow at a garden the IPM is on everybody
we have to move consciously we have to
think about what we're doing and we have
to try to eliminate cross-contamination
wherever possible you know we always go
to our cleanest areas first if we have
you know potential issues I always am a
you know proponent of using irrigation
marker Flags so that you can tell
everybody on the team that there's an
issue that you've spotted without having
to verbally say anything to anybody you
know anybody that walks into that room
if they see a red flag sticking out of a
pot whatever your facility deem the red
flag notates to they'll look at that and
say hey I need to avoid that area until
I'm done in this room that way I'm not
contaminating everything you know IPM is
is a cultural practice of cleanliness
across the board and it is a
preventative as well as Curative
approach to eliminate issues that could
you know possibly facilitate themselves
in a horiculture
environment and how does that differ
from like traditional pest control
methods really the only difference
between cannabis IPM and what we'll call
traditional IPM is the types of
chemistries that are used and the
longevity of said chemistries because
cannabis is a consumable most of the
stuff that is going to be sprayed on
cannabis is going to be uh what they
call grass or generally regarded as safe
um you're not going to see the longlived
systemic pesticides that they'll use on
ornamentals because they're poisonous um
I'm sure you know you've been around for
a long enough period of time everybody's
heard of Eagle 20 Eagle 20 is a
chemistry that is used in traditional
horiculture and it's not necessarily the
Boogeyman in that aspect because people
aren't combusting it Michel butol or
Eagle 20 really becomes dangerous once
it's lit on fire you create uh Benzene
and hydrocarbon once it's combusted and
so for a cannabis crop it's not a good
fit but if you were to spray it on your
leafy greens your Tomatoes whatever
because those are on the label it goes
through your digestive tract and it's
unchanged it doesn't have that carboxy
group basically it's it's like with thca
and Delta 9 you know how when you light
thca on fire it becomes you know Delta 9
UM same premise so you know having some
of these chemistries that are in
traditional Horticulture they're not
necessarily as safe and they don't have
the residuals so cannabis Growers have
to be a little bit more diligent and
educated in terms of what the spray that
they're doing right now is going to do
and how that next spray they're going to
do is going to either complement or
contradict what they just did for
example you would never want to spray a
biological inoculant and then spray a
sanitizer but if you did it in the
adverse and you sprayed a sanitizer and
then a biological inoculant the
inoculant will actually perform better
because you're putting it onto a clean
tissue environment where it can colonize
and spread much easier than if you were
to try to put it onto a dir environment
and then follow up with a sanitizer a
couple days later and kill all those
Sports so a lot of it is just the
rotation of certain chemistries and you
know making sure that you're using as
different a mode of action as we
possibly can we don't necessarily have
that same Iraq group classification that
traditional horiculture has where it
says this the IRA group three it does
this this and this this Ira group four
it does this this and this a lot of the
pesticides and fungicides that cannabis
Growers have are going to be contact or
very shortlived and so no knowing how to
play those off of one another so that
the grower has the most success allows
them to basically stack an IPM regimen
to where again every spray is compliment
in the one that preceded
it great so now integrated Pest
Management now do you include like plant
pathogens within that sort of definition
there so you know your hop and vroid and
um fusarium pythium all those sort of
things pest can be anything from you
know a single celled organism you know
viroids are very very small 25 to 50
nanometers in size all the way up to you
know bang aphids that are you know the
size of a a BB almost there's uh a whole
different schw of stuff that can attack
the plants and basically you know Pest
Management is going to be you being the
intermediary for everything from you
know the stuff you see to the stuff you
can't and so how how unique is sort of
the the program to each facility can is
there sort of a general uh protocol that
they should be following or is it very
specific so in the the book I I have
what I kind of call the recipe for bread
which is just the basic outline of the
rotation of a growth regulate style
chemistry which is more than likely
going to be Aid duratin in cannabis what
I like to call The Heavy Hitters which
are going to be your MCO insecticides
like your Bavaria basana your bur Alura
your assaria fosa uh your metah harium
chemistries and then on Fridays just so
we can keep the pressure on the button
so to speak and depending on the
scenario that's when we would use either
like a sulfur a citric acid or possibly
an insecticidal soap and so each
scenario is is a little bit different
but it allows the grower to basically
tailor their approach to best fit what
they're dealing with at that point in
time and because the base of the program
really doesn't change a whole lot it
allows them to be able to make minute
changes while still staying on you know
the same basic premise so that you know
your guys aren't saying like oh we did
this this last week and now we're over
here doing something completely
different you know there's there's a few
minute changes that occur but the nice
thing about it is that it's broad enough
that it can address most of the issues
that we're trying to do and again if
we're doing this as a preventative then
we don't have to get into that
necessarily specialized section of it
where it's like okay we're dealing with
russet mites specifically or we're
dealing with rude aphids and that's when
we make little changes but you know for
a general just overview sop of just
trying to keep things clean it it's
pretty Universal
right so no I'm glad you said that so
because I know I mean in in researching
kind of IPM there's all these articles
that kind of talk about the the
different tenants of it and it can be
anywhere from four to six to whatever
but I know that one of the the main ones
is the whole idea of identification in
modur in which is sort of like what you
had talked about before so what are um
some of the signs that um Growers should
be looking for to in order to sort of
identify a problem before it you know
Ball's out of control you know um one
thing that I always try to have Growers
do is Empower their staff because a
grower is only one person and there in
any given facility there's thousands of
plants possibly but you have people that
are looking at those plants every single
day Empower your staff to come to you
they don't need to be an expert
necessarily but they know when
something's not right if that plant
looks different than it did yesterday
have them come tell you and then you can
figure it out you know it's it's one of
those things that if you don't allow
your staff like I don't want you to have
your staff think that they're making a
mistake you know what I'm saying like a
lot of times people will not go and tell
the head grower that something's a Miss
because they don't want it to come back
on them like oh well then you did this
type of thing Empower your people to say
like if there is anything that's off
let's figure it out you know if this
plant looks different than it did
yesterday if it's got purple stems if
it's got stippling on the leaves if the
you know turgidity is gone and the
leaves are starting to curl down if
they're starting to curl up like
anything that just looks a miss
your how do I put it like you don't
necessarily have to have a team of
Master Growers you just got to have a
team of diligent people and as long as
there's one person on staff that you
know can say like okay there's an issue
let me go see it like most facilities
have one maintenance guy that fixes AC's
it's not on everybody to do it so if you
have one guy that's responsible for
plant health and pathogen mitigation
when somebody finds something he can say
hey I got to go tell Ben what I just
found and you know it could be that they
topped it funny it could be that it's
hlv it could be that there's an actual
issue going on beyond that you know but
having the ability and that
communication between your team is
Paramount uh because those are the guys
that are in the trenches so to speak and
you know you got to empower your team to
let you know what's going on because
again the head grower is only in one
spot at one time and having the ability
to have a team that can relay real world
information to you uh you know very
quickly helps a lot that flag system
that I was mentioning a little bit that
really helps a lot because a head grower
can stick his head in a room and count
Flags in 30 seconds and that's a great
way to you know also track progress if
we had 10 red flags last week and this
week we're down to five then what we're
doing is working you know we need to
continue on that process that we have
implemented if we were at 15 red flags
this week and last week we only had 10
then we need to switch it up because
it's getting worse and so it's it you
know communication is I think the most
important part of integrated Pest
Management to
me yeah the communication definitely
seems important and like you said it's
it's a culture right and um so how
common is that the culture in in
cannabis cultivation like is it is it
becoming more of a thing I see more and
more operations becoming more and more
regimented in terms of how they do
things and whether it's state
regulations that have kind of
facilitated that change or people just
realizing that they have to run leaner
because the market isn't what it was um
having the ability to educate staff and
you know get them all on the same page
and Empower people I think is the way
that the successful grows are going if
you punish your employees for trying to
do their best they're not going to want
to work for
you right right all right I want to talk
to you about some of like what are some
of the common pests or problems that
cannabis Growers just always seem to be
dealing with I would say the uh four
most common things that I run into
traveling the country are going to be
thrips rude AIDS hop and vroid and
powdery mildew thrips can be kind of a
problem because a lot of times folks
will only attack one life cycle stage of
this infestation thrips actually have a
point where they live in the canopy and
they have a point where they live in the
strata of your media and so if you're
not treating both you're going to see
these es and flows where they're gone
for two weeks they come back they're
gone for two weeks they come back and so
you know educating Growers that doing a
sprunch application with thrips really
does allow them to get ahead of it uh
rude aphids are extremely hard to get
rid of just because they're incredibly
Adept at what people have been throwing
at them um um what I've found to be the
most effective method to attack root
AIDS is to actually do an irrigation
cycle before you do any drenches or
sprays they run away from that moisture
of the first irrigation cycle of the day
if we can get those pots wet and get
them complacent to the fact that that
moisture is there they're less apt to
try to run away and so whatever we're
putting out via a drench sprunch or
spray is going to have much better
likelihood of actually coming in contact
with them because they're not just
trying to run from it um pop and vroid
is something that uh
a lot of Growers have it but they don't
know they have it until they have it and
again this comes back to that cultural
practices thing and you know kind of
falls on everybody and just the
communication that vroid can be
transferred via dirty matter it can be
transferred mechanically so it grow goes
from one plant to another doesn't wash
his hands it can be spread by tools it
can be spread by runoff it can be spread
by insects is a very prevalent pathogen
and a lot of folks don't take it as
seriously as they should there are some
grows that have completely realized that
it can decimate their business and they
will test their moms before they take
Cuts every single Round And they're
they're doing everything they need to
and then there are Growers that still
use a single cup of clonex and dip every
single cut in that same hormone and it's
like if if there's any contamination you
guys just spread it across the board so
you know honestly I feel like the the
viroids and pathogens are going to be
the hardest thing for the Cannabis
industry to address because you don't
know that you have them and until you
have them and once you have them we can
go into remission so to speak we can you
know get it to a point where the plant
can still finish but those genetics are
contaminated at that point and to keep
them on board would be to you know
facilitate the downfall of everything
else that you have in your stable
because again that can transfer so many
different ways and so easily and the
thing that a lot of grower the latent
portion of this virid if your plants are
healthy you're not going to see what it
can do right away but over time the
plant Health starts to go down it's
almost like cancer or you know the the
patient isn't necessarily bedridden when
they're first diagnosed but the longer
they are alive that line goes like this
and the sicker they become and you know
to compromise an entire business with
hlv is just it's very scary because it
will compromise your Harvest your THC
percentages blumm it your bag appeal
goes down and the medicinal value of the
plant is just not there anymore you know
you're basically growing hemp at that
point like you're compliant with the
farm bill
almost um the uh I'm sorry the no I I
never thought of it that way the uh the
last you know most common pathogen that
I see is powder Milo just because it is
very prevalent it's easy to pop up it's
not the end of the world a lot of times
Growers won't do everything they need to
do to eliminate said issue but uh it is
something that can be gotten rid of
Fairly easily um first thing I always
tell people is make sure your
environment's on point if you can't set
your temp to 60 and your de to 10 and
then hit those numbers your environment
isn't where it needs to be you know
there there are folks that say oh I can
get it to where it needs to be and if if
you can't hit those parameters it's not
and so the first thing Growers have to
do is make sure that their HVAC is up to
point their you know air conditioning is
up to point their deu is where it needs
to be and if they're still experiencing
powdery Meo that's when we say okay
let's look at what we can spray to you
know basically kind of hinder this thing
in its tracks and we've got some really
cool options for cannabis Growers that
have uh you know very safe application
uh methods and you know zero residual
aspects in terms of dangerous stuff um
and you know it just allows them to
basically get on that schedule of like
okay it's it's flip we got to spray oxy
fos and zerol or you know it's Wednesday
we got to hit a a Mico
insecticide and you know to touch on
what you kind of said earlier in my
program Monday Wednesday Friday for
preventative is spray days Tuesday and
Thursday is plant work and scouting and
then once we get uh from you know
basically Curative into preventative I'm
sorry I said that wrong I said
preventative but I meant Curative um
once we get into the preventative mode
we actually flip it and Monday Wednesday
Friday we're doing scouting Tuesday
Thursday we're doing our sprays um but
the idea is that you're in there looking
at the plants as much as you're spraying
or defoliating or doing anything else
because we have to evaluate our progress
and you know keep a lot of logs if if we
don't write down what we're doing in a
month we won't remember what we did we
don't know if we did anything right or
not you know grows are very cyclical in
terms of what happened last June likely
is going to happen this June and so if
you can go back to your log last year
and say we had thrips on the 14th
when it got really hot and then you look
at your calendar and you say okay it's
going to get up to you know 102 or
whatever I'm anticipating thrips you
could put out your ambelas cucumeris you
know beneficial insects and later flour
and then do your sprays and your veg and
your prop and your early flour and
combat the you know thrips before they
ever even get
established right no I wanted to go back
to when you were talking about the
pathogens and you know it sounded like
one of the main challenges with that is
you don't really know you have it until
it's too late so in in that sense do you
sort of advocate for you know uh regular
testing um full disclosure uh medicinal
genomics we we develop qpcr aades for HL
and vroid cerium pythium a lot of the
plant pathogens that uh folks use and
you know we're trying to spread the word
to Growers that you know should make
that part of their program to to do
testing is that something that you would
agree with definitely every other aspect
of horiculture that is uh traditional
does tissue testing if you go to a
tomato grower Greenhouse they're doing
it once a week they don't know how to
adjust their feeds if they don't know
what the plant's uptaking and what it's
not and you know it that's nutritional
analysis but being able to have this
pathogen testing is Paramount if you
have a dirty genetic and you put you
know 2,000 clones into production that's
a loss because that 2,000 clones with
the where where the market is now you're
going to spend more money labor and time
then you're going to be able to recoup
off of that crop at that point if you
can even sell it because it's not going
to come out looking like it should um
I'm an advocate of you know having a
test allows us to make educated
decisions if we don't know what we're
dealing with then we're just throwing
stuff at the wall to see what sticks
every time you cut clones if you bring
in something new you know even quarterly
test your your stable just to make sure
everything is where it's supposed to be
but anything that comes in brand new
should always be quarantined and tested
and then those you know plants should
have clones cut off of them and as long
as those clones off of the plants you
brought in look okay then we can put it
into production but I that's a mistake
I've seen time and time again where
Growers are excited to get some hype
genetic they put into production right
away and then they're like you know
I just infected half of my stable with
XYZ right no and now going back to the
pests um another thing that I sort of
saw in my research too is this sort of
this idea of setting thresholds so is
there like a certain amount of pest
that's sort of like okay as long as we
can manage it and you know keep it down
or I mean in a perfect world brother the
the perfect number would be zero but
this is farming and we're in a fluid
environment where you've got people
coming in and out of the facility all
day long you know depending on the type
of facility if it's a greenhouse every
time you open your louvers to ventilate
the greenhouse we've potentially
introduced contamination and so the the
m and IPM stands for management you're
never going to completely be ahead of
everything you will always have
something to do the next day because
nature never quits you know it will
always try to find its way in or you
know do its best to stifle what it is
we're trying to do and so you know the
acceptable level is low pressure but you
know don't get complacent and say oh we
we've got mites but they're not that bad
you know we've got mites but we're
treating them as the right approach once
you get complacent with something that's
when other issues start to snowball and
so low pressure isn't unaccept able but
you know make sure that you're doing
your best to get that to as close to no
pressure as you can and again because
it's farming if we wipe one issue out
Ben something else is going to pop up
tomorrow that's just the nature of the
Beast yeah yeahh all right so winding
down here I'm curious you know are there
some common mistakes that Growers make
when they're implementing IPM that they
could avoid the most common mistake that
I see is that Growers don't necessarily
look at active ingredients they're just
looking at brand names and so you know
you know one time I went to a facility
here in Denver and the grower had
clarified hydrophobic extract of neem
oil as a duratin and Ne oil and those
are all basically the exact same thing
just different versions of the exact
same product and he was wondering why he
wasn't having success with his issue and
it's like well brother you're using
three versions of the same stuff you
know being able to differentiate between
actives really allows Growers to get
those different modes of action and you
know making sure that uh they are phing
their sprays at the end of it is
something that I've seen some Growers
neglect to do like they'll pH their
reservoirs every time but they won't pH
their sprays for whatever reason I feel
like that sometimes is
a a whoopsy and uh the other thing that
I I see a lot of Growers do man and this
is not knocking anybody but you know
water quality isn't necessarily the best
in some places of the country so Growers
will spray with Aro water and uh Aro as
you know is acidic comes out of the
machine at 7 but you let it sit for 24
hours it's going to be a pH of something
like 5'5 and then they add something
like citric acid to it it's going to be
a pH of something like three you spray a
pH to three on your plants man you're
going to see some phyto and burn some
stuff and so uh what I typically
recommend to Growers is if you've got
really dirty water and you cannot spray
with tap take some of your base NPK
spike it to about3 EC get a little bit
of that bicarbonate content from that
fertilizer back into that water column
and that way if you do have to buffer it
or add something else to it it's not
going to have the DraStic swings that it
would without that bicarbon in content
anytime Growers are spraying zerol I
tell them if you're use an R spike it
to. 3 EC and they add the zerol and nine
out of 10 times it'll fall between 55
and
62 which is for a f year
app um so looking ahead uh are there any
advancements or innovations that you're
excited about when it comes to
IPM uh definitely you know the the realm
of mro insecticides is continuing to
expand uh the nature against nature
really is my favorite approach Mother
Nature has been doing this a lot longer
than we have and you know she's got
checks and balances for everything so
being able to utilize more natural
products and get further away from
petrochemicals and you know stuff that
harms pollinators and hurts the
environment really is going to I think
allow Pest Management to be looked at as
not necessarily this big Boogeyman like
anytime you hear the word insecticide
pesticide people always think Monsanto
Round Up cancer and it's like there's to
farm on scale you have to be able to be
that intermediary but we don't
necessarily have to use those
chemistries that poison the planet you
know biosafe are montras to try to leave
the planet better than we found it man
and you know we're able to address a lot
of these issues that these gnarly
chemicals address we do it without
hurting the environment and so I in the
future I'm just excited to see more of
these really cancerous you know gnarly
chemistries be replaced by stuff that
works that is safer for the planet and
for people excellent all right and
Before I Let You Go um are there any
other resources besides your book which
I will put a link to in the show notes
so people can uh can find that on Amazon
but are there other resources papers or
anything like that that you could
recommend uh that if people are
interested in learning more about uh
what do you do um we definitely have uh
you know really good uh Instagram page
if you go on to the igtv tab uh when the
P pandemic first started I used to do
these things called Fireside Chats where
I would just talk about a different
aspect of cultivation it has everything
from trimming to curing to you know
russet mites and rude aphids like
anything and everything I could think of
talking about I did um so anybody that
wants to watch free videos all the stuff
that's in the book is also on those
videos It's just sometimes you don't
have eight hours to come through videos
to find the answer you're looking for um
and then I really recommend that anybody
that's serious about the industry get
onto a website called MMJ daily uh
there's a on the horiculture side it's
called HED daily but MMJ daily is a
cannabis specific daily newsletter that
gets sent to your nbox and it talks
about Cannabis News from all over the
world so you can see what the
Netherlands are doing you can see what
Israel is doing see what South Africa is
doing you can see what Germany is doing
you can see what Canada is doing you can
see what we're doing and it just it
keeps you really bre of you know the
what's going on in cannabis as a whole
and you know gives you that kind of
thousand yard view of the industry and
you know allows you to know what's
coming before it comes you know they a
lot of times they'll talk about
legislation that's potential and you
know you'll know about something six
months before it's talked about on MSNBC
or something excellent
excellent all right Zach well thanks
again for doing this uh I think it was
great and um hopefully we can see you
out at canmed once uh once we announce
the details for that love to see you
there heck yeah brother keep me posted
thank you so much for having us on and
uh enjoy your weekend okay all right
we'll do
[Music]