thank you for getting up and offering
your questions please go ahead thank you
what about pharmacogenetics we all
respond differently
I started cannabis cannabinoid
pharmacogenetic company but recognizes
science just isn't there yet and yet
there's a few companies that are
swearing that they have it what do you
know what's your opinion so one of the
comments I have is I had a chance one of
my patients did do one of those kind of
cannabinoid genetic tests and the thing
that bothered me about it was that on
the paperwork that came back it reported
that she her child was at a high
likelihood of becoming cannabis
dependent and that really bothered me
because she got she was like oh now he's
going to be addicted and all this and
there's really no evidence of that and
again medical use we're not talking
about addiction independence we're
talking about an endocannabinoid
dysfunction and we're trying to treat
that so if you do one of those tests be
very careful with what results you get
and make sure that you remember that
just because you may have a snip or a
gene it does not necessarily correlate
to what your experience is going to be
with cannabis so I had talked to that
company and said you need to remove that
off of the test because again it's kind
of like saying oh you're 85 and you're
starting cannabis and you did this test
now you're gonna turn into a person
who's addicted to cannabis and is
extremely unlikely so I just want to
make sure that people interpret those
results carefully I just want to point
out that while our genetics can point us
in directions and give us a few clues
about what might be the case there's
this huge realm of epigenetics which are
the factors that turn on and off the
genes and affect what happens when those
proteins are expressed and that there's
just so much complexity I
I like the idea that people are trying
to tie up these levels of complexity
into systems that may eventually give us
usable data but I think as you mentioned
we're pretty far from that right now
just a really quick comment on the
epigenetics and it's largely affected by
lifestyle so it comes back to the idea
of of physiological context what exactly
is happening in the system what is it
bombarded by what kind of conditions has
it been under that's gonna largely
affect your response to whatever it is
whatever stimulant we're talking about
whether it be cannabinoids or a
pharmaceutical or you know any other
compound yep
awesome day guys thanks for everything
in your leadership and mentorship
through the years I'm from Florida my
name is dr. Barry Gordon Bonnie you said
something that was so interesting to me
that is California advanced out of their
medical into the legal adult responsible
use stage that actually the medical
products were harder to get right and
that's one of the things that we're
seeing in Florida right now we're in
that middle zone where we're still
medical but we know we're going towards
legal adult responsible use who do you
think are the best people to impact to
the extent of making sure that we
maintain the medical program in Florida
to the excellence that we have now the
ratio products the tinctures the
suppositories things of that nature
because what I found is that in many of
the states as they go legal adult
responsible use the medical programs get
left behind
second question now that it's legal in
California have you ever given any
consideration towards slipping a little
sublingual five milligram mint or
something into the sublingual space
while you're actually examining your
elderly patient for the first time so
that in that in that half hour in that
half hour visit with family and patient
that they can actually experience that
first time so you know so to speak
intoxication of cannabis right so okay
so the first question is to who do you
address you have to go to your
government you have to
and it might behoove you to go as a
group the society cannabis clinicians is
a great group to use as a resource you
don't want to repeat what happened here
in California I mean we were the grand
social experiment it got passed by
Californians and nobody the state didn't
want to do anything politicians didn't
want anything doctors called in law
enforcement to go after the doctors in
the in the beginning it was terrible so
what really wasn't done very well and
what ended up happening here in
California is that we had a mandate to
regulate medical and then legalization
became on the ballot and that passed and
it just so turned out that both needed
to be kind of completed programs by
January 2018 so our government said well
we're not going to do it separately that
will cost too much money so we need to
do it together and I still think it
should be separated so if there's a way
to sever separate it out it Colorado
model so to speak which has the
Department of Revenue control record
that's exactly right
so taxes on medical patients in
California can run anywhere from 20 to
35 percent what else is taxed that high
that's medicine you don't pay that on
your prozac you don't pay that on your
blood-pressure medication you don't pay
taxes on your medication so I don't
understand why and and I think it just
goes back to the fact that our
government still looks at this as a
medical cannabis as a hoax despite all
this time and all these reports and that
oh yes select oh this patient it might
help and that little child it might help
but they don't really realize because
they just don't live in the world that
that we live in here
your second question I'm not allowed to
dispense cannabis in my office so I
cannot medicate my patients however they
did have a patient that came in with
lung cancer she was terribly nauseous
she could barely keep her head up she
actually put her head on my desk and
then we had our go lie on the bed and
her adult son said I have a bag full of
stuff I bought that I have no idea what
it is but can I give something to my mom
we gate we there was a little vaporizer
and there was again before all the vape
nonsense that's going on now and we
broke it open and we gave her a puff he
gave her a cuff in the office I did not
and
within minutes she had color back in her
face she hadn't said any you know when
you're so nauseous you can't talk
she started talking she was smiling she
walked out of my office so happy so
there I probably first rally didn't
might be allowed to give somebody
medicines right for this medicine again
we have to get it off the schedule yeah
to me when it becomes legal you know to
a certain extent it would be interesting
if you could do that for the first time
in the office hi I'm Susan Sklar I'm
local here in Long Beach in Southern
California I have two clinical questions
one is patient with autoimmune hepatitis
and fibrosis and there's been talk about
some of the can of cannabis products
doing something about fibrosis in the
liver and the second one is I treat
patients women with a condition called
burning mouth syndrome
that's a neuropathic pain condition they
do very well on hormone restoration
about probably about 80% of them but
then there are 20% that don't and so I'm
just wondering I've heard a lot of talk
about neuropathic pain and pain
syndromes which products would I
recommend to those women thank you so
the answer to the first question I'm not
sure when we did our little stretch
break I kind of covered the liver stuff
maybe you stepped out but the synopsis
is lean heavier on CBD which is anti
fibrotic and if you want a non-invasive
way to track liver fibrosis in response
to an intervention you can use the hepa
score or even the FIB for fib - 4 which
is a calculation based on a CBC and CMP
that accurately correlates with a liver
biopsy results in terms of fibrosis so
you can track it and then as far as
neuropathic pain I mean the best
evidence that we have comes from the new
pics of moles trials a one to one ratio
is a pretty good place to start I will
say that in cases where oral mucosal
dosing doesn't work sometimes inhalation
does
oh hi thank you so much for this and I
hope there's a lot of doctors here I'm
from Carmel California I've been doing
consulting for seniors since 2012 and in
their home and my question is this or
it's an actually a statement and on how
you all feel
you know since seniors a lot of them are
deficient in their endocannabinoid
system and wouldn't it seem right for
them to maybe start cannabis like we
started now so we're not deficient in
our endocannabinoid system it's just a
question because more I'm learning you
just want to take it you know to prevent
there was a prophylactic perhaps and
then my other quick question was seniors
because they're not making tinctures
with alcohol it was a little bit it
burned them to do the sublingual
starting out so now that there's more
oils the coconut oil and olive oils etc
how are they absorb some sublingually
are they as well absorbed do we know all
right okay so the first question that
you asked about preventive so we don't
really have studies but when you see all
the literature I agree with you why not
why wouldn't you there was something I
came across when I was doing the
literature review where one of the
researchers who looks at
neurodegenerative illness wrote in his
article I've been looking for something
to help prevent neuro degenerative
diseases and the only thing I've come
across is cannabinoids so that's the
answer to that question thank you yeah
you bring up a really good point it
comes back to context physiological
context so you want to lay a really
strong foundation right and one of the
things that we tend to forget I think in
the cannabis field is that
endocannabinoids are made out of fatty
acids and so the quality of your diet is
gonna
have a very significant impact on your
endogenous endocannabinoids how much
endocannabinoids have got then it's not
just to AG in anand amide now they're
made out of arachidonic acid and they're
in the 80s and the 90s people were
showing flow charts that show that
arachidonic acid went to pge2
which of course is inflammatory except
in the gut where it's protective if you
so nature paths were telling people that
they shouldn't eat chicken because it's
one of the richest meats and arachidonic
acid well okay that's all well and good
but remember any compound in the body
uses a double-edged sword it's got two
directions that can go or multiple
directions actually and so in this case
we're a katana Casa de de is actually
beneficial as well so there's a rakha
donek acid and then there's the oleic
acid the allele derivatives that are
endo cannabinoids and even DHA and EPA
potentially have got some sort of
endocannabinoid effect on tone so if
we're eating well and so remember this
if your endo cannabinoid deficient it's
not about taking cannabis it's about
let's see well play up regulate our
physiological system by playing and
having a euphoric experience and not
just cannabis induced but life induced
and those things in themselves will make
a huge difference in terms of the
baseline of the endocannabinoid system
then certainly if we need cannabis or
some other compound that makes sense
yeah I don't think that there's much
pharmacokinetic data on the sublingual
absorption of oil except for what I
showed you that Italian study but I
think it varies widely based on the
terpene content in that oil there's some
that you can absolutely feel in a minute
or less after that hitting your oral
mucosa and something that might take a
while and in terpenes are known
permeation enhancers hi thank you all
three for a very informative day I'm
Ryan Zack and I'm a physician in
Massachusetts I have two questions one
I'd love to hear your experience with
cancer patients
that come in asking about our so I mean
do you have a strategy with them for my
patients I try not to take their hope
away but I try to you know suggest
multiple strains and several dots or
whatnot so I'd love to hear your take on
that and if you had any experience with
success because I mean the the original
story is based on a basal cell which
doesn't never made any sense to me in
the first place and then the other one
is topicals do what do you have you had
any experience with systemic success
with patients that use topical
preparations or is it mostly from
localized areas you mentioned trigger
points eczema or you know skin
conditions or more local conditions I'm
happy to answer the cancer question so
we see a wide variety of presentations
and requests right I want to use
cannabis exclusively I want to use it in
kanne kanne combination with
conventional treatment that's kind of
one major fork in the road and when I
look at people that are wanting to use
it exclusively I very often find a
patient that is unaware of their
prognosis and the treatment course what
that would look like if they went
through conventional treatment and
there's a lot of death anxiety in that
patient population so that's my first
target actually is addressing the death
anxiety and getting better information
so that we can then make a real decision
and so that I lean with the low-dose
cannabis and I paint the picture of what
we're gonna introduce you to this get
you feeling really good maybe follow
some cancer markers you know if there's
non-invasive markers and things that
don't require an expensive skin a lot of
people aren't aware of things like
neutrophil the lymphocyte ratio is very
easy to follow HSC RP yeah you know ESR
there's a lot of markers that can tell
you what direction the cancer is going
monocyte levels so you know we follow
that and then we have the real
conversation at the first follow-up
visit which is are we going to shift
gears here into the super high-dose
approach which I don't really have a lot
of evidence will help you now Mike in my
clinical experience I have cases that
have absolutely responded to cannabis
mono therapy at low and moderate doses
one that I'm following right now
testicular cancer
that produces HCG so it's very easy to
follow and no other treatment in the
history of this case beyond cannabis
about 40 milligrams total daily and
those levels are down and the patient's
doing fine
so while most of the anecdotes you hear
about are related to these like 500 to
2,000 milligram doses as far as a
response I don't think that's always
recommen my cases that we've seen do
great are those that combine everything
right they use cannabis they
intelligently choose what fits for them
personally best from conventional
treatment they paint the picture of hey
I'm sitting in the infusion room
everyone else is turning green and
looking sick and I'm feeling great
you know it's that that's usually what I
see but I think so many people just
don't know what they're dealing with and
come in with a lot of anxieties so it's
a good place to start I'm gonna leave
the topical to you but I'm just gonna
comment on the cancer so again because I
take care of children if they're in my
office and they have cancer it's usually
because they are at the end of the line
and it's unfortunate you know you as an
adult have a right to choose your
treatment but pediatric patients do not
if you choose not to have your child
treated with chemo and they have cancer
they will take your child away from you
and subject them to the chemo and
radiation I have had numerous who came
to me with end-stage what stage four
there is no stage 5 right metastatic
cancers where we have actually achieved
remission I have a Wilms tumor patient
who had a kidney removed and then she
three months later relapsed pulmonary
relapsed and we have her she's now like
I don't know almost five years out and
that was with high-dose cannabinoids
added to chemo about she was on I think
nine out of twenty eight plan chemos she
was already cancer-free so they decided
to discontinue the rest of the treatment
and she's done very well she has
continued on cannabinoid treatments her
mom says she's going to be on it for
life
we and we usually recommend that you
should not stop there is a case dr.
Jeffrey hergenrother who's a cannabis
physician in Northern California had a
patient who was nine and a half years
free from glioblastoma multiforme II and
stopped using cannabis and he relapsed
so remember it's not just you you can't
see the little stem cells the cancer
stem cells that are floating around I
have one case of a stage four boy with
stage four osteosarcoma who had over 20
or 30 tumors in his chest who became
cancer free on very high doses of CBD
THC it was a Hail Mary I'll just share
that with you combination with chemo
that wasn't working we added in high
dose CBD and th so you might say
high-dose 500 milligrams of each that
was in 2015 he is still alive and
cancer-free 500 milligrams daily daily
yes and the 500 milligrams of t8 3
divided and tid so about a hundred and
sixty-five milligrams of each THC two
separate products and he did take it in
the RSO formulation sublingually and he
is he just he came to me at 16 wasn't
supposed to make it to 17 and he turn he
just turned 20 so that's a great report
however not you know we don't get that
with everybody he was on gemcitabine and
Taxotere there is a record in the
literature of mice with pancreatic cell
Xena graphs that have gems that when
they take gemcitabine and cannabinoids
there's a synergistic effect so for him
I wanted I wanted to do that but by the
way I'll just share with you I had a
young lady come in 14 years old with
stage 4 osteosarcoma with visible tumors
coming out of her legs and her father
misheard my dosing and when I said 500
per day he thought I said 500 per dose
but I will tell you already
everything is shrinking and it's been
maybe eight weeks now well when they
emailed me so she has hurt her she had a
lung tumor that was inoperable that was
12 centimeters it's down to 8 the two
leg large tumors are no longer lighting
up on the nuclear scans
and she came off oxygen off opiates got
up and started walking around so there
are sometimes cases I'll be honest with
you these are somebody this is
somebody's child that's in my office and
the last thing that I'm gonna do is harm
them but cannabis and high doses is not
going to harm a child we can always stop
it so I figure especially because so
many cases come in so late why wouldn't
you try I'll throw in a little on the
cancer side too one of them one of the
first gigs I had in the in the cannabis
industry was helping a company up scale
scale up who basically did a lot of
cancer treatments and they were rather
inflexible in their protocol but they
were using about a gram a day and I was
great great to hear Dustin here say that
and Bonnie that you don't need
necessarily a gram a day but if you're
using a gram a day to treat cancer you
got to know that that's chemo like
you're gonna be sick you're gonna be
wiped out a Cox inhibitor by the whale
help with some of the side effects but
like you're gonna need somebody to take
care of you so I saw people have
remarkable recoveries in 12 to 24 weeks
I also saw people die because they this
company insisted that they couldn't use
anything else any other drugs which is
not an intelligent way to go what was
the topical topical is just what kind of
have you seen any systemic benefits from
topicals than local so there's a
physician in on the East Coast named dr.
Deborah Kym Ellis who is actually got
some interesting case studies on using
topicals for cancer which makes you
think about dosing because certainly if
if the effects of the topicals are to
reduce the cancer if it's a direct
effect then that's pretty low dose you
can just can't absorb that much
cannabinoid through your skin so it's
definitely interesting is something that
should be checked out I do know a case
actually in my land in Southern Oregon
where a guy was using really tiny doses
of THC I think it was under 20
milligrams a day and had stopped a liver
cancer
and had when I was four years into his
treatment it was it had been a Stage
four
so there's lots of anecdotal stuff out
there there's some direct clinical
experience here there's definitely
something to think about but I think
topical check out Deborah Kim Ellis I
think she's got a website what's that
she's in Maryland thank you and I think
she's got a topical company No one last
thing is the report that I talked about
from GW pharmaceutical where they
combined team Adar with CBD and THC
those are not high doses they used low
doses in that report hi so I just wanted
to ask about applications of of cannabis
for acute pain I know of course it seems
to suit well for chronic pain but with
acute pain my understanding is that it
can magnify that can you speak to like
what kind of protocol and dosage you may
suggest for acute pain if it is at all a
good match for that so topical cannabis
is an excellent first aid remedy for
acute pain even in the naive user I
think it's great on beestings and other
things like that this really needs to be
framed in some ways as a first aid kind
of a home remedy but systemic use in a
naive user THC can absolutely exacerbate
acute pain less likely to do so in
someone that is an experienced THC user
and I don't think there's much data on
CBD for acute pain and I haven't seen it
used that way very much thank you thank
you
hi Derek Johnson physician from Park
City Utah thank you all for sharing your
knowledge with us today we touched
briefly on perinatal exposure and based
on the current literature I'm just
curious as to how you all are counseling
your patients who are either pregnant
and using or new moms who are either
using or interested in using
sure so you know number one is really
document this clearly and copy the OB
team with your chart notes and a letter
and everything but you know the way I
think about it is in a couple different
categories so there's the women that are
doing really well using cannabis to
treat a chronic condition that then
become pregnant right and in that
situation we have to weigh the risks and
benefits of removing this current
treatment what the alternatives might be
and what their risk is for mom and baby
and you know I I think these categories
have kind of been done away with but we
might consider cannabis like a category
C medication or maybe somewhere in
between B and C when it comes to
pregnancy so you know one example we
could talk about which is probably more
the two most common would be chronic
pain and PTSD right so if a mom is doing
really well treating her chronic pain
and PTSD she becomes pregnant and then
we want to remove the cannabis what are
our other options
well how about NSAIDs in Tylenol not
great you know for pain
how about opioids in pregnancy not great
neonatal abstinence syndrome right
cannabis does not cause na yes let's
look at PTSD more mild treatment might
be SSRIs those do cause any neonatal
abstinence syndrome and they're not very
effective so then what are we left with
the benzodiazepines and other inXile it
exciting the risk benefit ratio favors
the cannabis over the benzodiazepines so
that's that's how you kind of work it in
the assessment and really spell it out
that there's already a level of efficacy
and what we're going to do is make sure
that it's there's no combustion so mom's
not inhaling smoke we're using the
lowest effective dose we're avoiding
tolerance building which means we're
avoiding causing a dysregulation of the
endocannabinoid system and we're gonna
follow this mom and monitor her and then
be extraordinarily vigilant when it
comes to the perinatal period because
you do not want an interruption of
bonding and initiation of breastfeeding
which will happen when Child Protective
Services gets involved because some
nurse is concerned about THC in the
urine drug screen so I very vigilant
around that time make sure it's in the
birth plan that THC is not going to be
tested for in the urine because the
results are clinically irrelevant just
do
test that's that's I mean it requires a
lot of work in communication but you can
do it successfully so then the other
case is someone with morning sickness
and no we're not going to just say oh
you've got my own morning sickness why
don't you try cannabis it's more like
why don't you try ginger right and try
changing your diet but when it's
hyperemesis gravidarum that's refractory
to antiemetics and we're considering a
PICC line which is the more favorable
risk benefit ratio cannabis or the PICC
line I mean it's it's not rocket science
but it requires a lot of work and
advocacy and education
I'm just gonna share with you I had to
take care of a woman who had bipolar
she's been my patient for probably ten
years and she came in pregnant and she
said to me I'm terrified of talking to
my OB about using cannabis so we
actually called the OB right there and
then during the appointment and the OB
was actually quite lovely about it and
what they said was that now that they
know what they're gonna do is counsel
her and they felt that it was important
to tell her that they would prefer that
she didn't use this but that they were
not going to drug test her at the time
that the baby was delivered because we
had made this phone call and because it
was now documented and because there was
a reason for her to be using medical
reason and she was medically approved it
wasn't the same as someone who was not a
medical patient so I think that was very
helpful the communication is huge and I
think we're out of questions and right
on time thank you all for sticking
around for the whole day amazing let's
see before you get up and leave I want
to make sure everyone's had a chance to
sign has anyone not signed in for the
CME looks like I haven't actually so if
that clipboards silly or what we need to
sign it and any other housekeeping
things done oK we've got dinner here in
an hour so grab your stuff and get some
fresh air thank you again