good morning everybody thank you for
being here
and i would like to say
thank you to medicinal genomics for
bringing us all together
i know that the pandemic has been a
little wonky actually the whole world
has gone wonky on us lately
and i would like to thank our panelists
for being here today in making this
journey
so we are in a wonky world and i would
invite you to think about our colleagues
friends and family who are undergoing
some challenges in eastern europe these
days so
when you have time later in the day just
take a moment pause and
and give them some thought
they don't have the opportunity that we
all have right now today
and
my heart goes out to them
so regulating cannabis is not
straightforward and it is most
definitely not consistent across north
america and definitely not within the
united states
as individual states are slowly and i do
mean slowly and independently legalizing
cannabis it's often defined as hemp
marijuana
cannabis all of this other stuff
mentioned to somebody yesterday that
cannabis is still in its infancy stage
we haven't even identified our
vocabulary yet
um
[Music]
all of the regulating bodies and other
interested parties have one goal in mind
and that is to ensure consumer safety
that's the one central thought and one
central objective to all of the parties
working together
and without getting into the history of
the legalizations
or the lessons learned or the lessons
not learned thus far
on the pathways forward i am delighted
to introduce you today today's panel
that represents regulations and
mostly around laboratory testing
and a snapshot into the science that's
been diligently working towards
catching up to regulations
as well as representation from the
national safety council
which is a non-profit agency
centralized on consumer safety how many
of you here have heard of the national
safety council
not too many people
hold that thought and um you're gonna
hear more about that later so i'm
delighted to meet
to introduce you to today's panelists
the first one here is k doyle
she is the director of u.s public policy
and legal counsel for jazz
pharmaceuticals prior to her tenure at
jazz kay was one of the inaugural
cannabis control commissioners for the
commonwealth of massachusetts and she
was charged with implementing the
programs for adult use
and medicinal use of cannabis and she's
living to talk about it
kay also
served as the primary council for the
medical use marijuana program food
protection program and tobacco control
program for massachusetts department of
public health she has also taught
marijuana policy and law as an adjunct
professor for the new england school of
law and prior to a public servant
surface k practice land use and civil
rights law litigating in state and
federal trial appellate courts including
the u.s supreme court
right next to uk is katie miller who
represents the national safety council
as the senior program manager and of the
impairment practice she brings 15 years
of experience in public safety program
planning and project management public
policy creation and communications
traffic safety focus on impaired driving
occupant protection and community
outreach and education
as i mentioned many of you folks here
are not familiar with nsc so very
quickly it was established in 1923 to
advocate for workplace and roadway
safety
in 2021 nsc members
initiated research into a cannabis
impairment division through
the division of alcohol and drugs
cannabis division but you'll hear more
on that from katie
next to katie is jenny wong who is the
assistant branch chief of the california
department of cannabis control she has
worked in the health and safety field
for 13 years with specialized experience
in food safety drinking water safety
and environmental compliance following
her career as a health inspector for the
la county public health department she
expanded her purview to manage the
environmental health environmental
compliance and occupational safety
programs for the ucla office of
environment health and safety she now
brings her experience to support the
licensed cannabis industry by building
compliance
structures for the cultivation and
manufacturing licensees across the state
she's also living to talk about it
heather krug
is the state cannabis science program
manager for the colorado department of
public health and environment
she has served in this role since 2014
the program includes three sections
the cannabis laboratory certification
sections performs audits of colorado
retail medical marijuana testing
facilities and hemp testing labs for
compliance and suitability for
certification under state regs she's
also responsible for the cannabis
reference laboratory which develops
methods and tests
cannabis products for compliance and
public health investigations heather
also oversees
the marijuana health monitoring and
research section which monitors
marijuana use patterns and health
impacts across the state
the section evaluates and summarizes
existing in emerging scientific evidence
about potential effects of marijuana use
and administers two research grant
programs using the data information
generated by the program heather advised
the state cannabis policy and regulatory
decisions and she holds bachelor science
degree in biomedical science and a
master of science degree in forensic
toxicology
and finally at the end certainly not
least is dr shurim holm who is the
director of regulatory affairs at
medicinal genomics
and they are marketing genetics-based
cannabis tests and breeding technologies
sherm's received his phd in microbiology
at the university of california at davis
in a
postdoc training in molecular genetics
his primary responsibility at medicinal
genomics is to make recommendations to
regulatory officials that are tasked
with either drafting and or modifying
cannabis hemp and psychedelic mushroom
required microbial testing regs to
ensure safe products for patients and
consumers
previously he was at the department of
new jersey department of health and
public health and environmental labs
where he led teams that started the
cannabis testing lab the cannabis
microbial testing unit and created a
compendium of allstate
medical cannabis required testing
regulations database
so that's our panel and as for me among
other hats i serve as the science
advisor to the cannabis
analytical science program which is the
cannabis division of aoec international
which is an independent nonprofit
non-governmental science organizations
that's been
vetting and publishing testing standards
for more than 130 years and the casp is
very exciting and on behalf of the aoac
team we welcome the input and engagement
of scientists laboratories and
governmental agencies several of whom
are on the panel today
and
we're going to start with the panel
discussion with some questions and then
open the floor to questions from the
audience
and i invite your engagement and look
forward to some dynamic discussions
so when we think about where are we
today and what are we doing i have a
question for jenny
what regulatory checkpoints exist to
protect consumer safety
hi good morning everyone
um
on behalf of the uh speaking for the
department of cannabis control in
california
we've built in a lot of the
like safety and regulatory checkpoints
into our auditing and inspection program
for our licensed facilities i oversee
the inspection program for the
cultivation
facilities throughout the state as well
as the la and central california
manufacturing licensees
so we look at things like like you would
imagine for
an audit or a health and safety
inspection
we look for things like master
manufacturing protocols other good
manufacturing practices sops solvent
purity and food safety whenever
when the facility is
creating edibles so we look at various
health and safety checkpoints in that
way our team of environmental scientists
goes uh does a really detailed audit
because you know knowing that um a large
portion of you know the public
that consumes these products you know
our patients and may have compromised
immune systems so we keep that in mind
when we're doing when we're doing these
really detailed um inspections at the
cultivation sites we look for pesticides
to make sure that the
pesticides are on an approved list and
they're not you know
banned pesticides or anything like that
and and that the list that they've
declared at licensure matches what we
find on site
so there's a lot of different regulatory
checkpoints there
if we if and when we find deficiencies
depending on the severity
we use a progressive discipline
process you know working closely with
licensees unless it's an immediate
danger to
life and health
if it's a contaminated product we can
initiate a recall process which happened
recently we had our first mandatory
recall
and you know we work really closely with
our licensees who acted really swiftly
um with us to to recall the uh the
products
um if it's uh
if it's something that's an immediate
danger to
like occupational safety for example
like an
unregistered uh extraction unit that may
be a combustion risk we work with fire
department to rent that red tag that
that piece particular piece of equipment
make sure it's not being used
and that's more on the you know serious
uh violation side if it's um or minor
moderate like
they didn't post their license you know
um in a visible area of course it's just
uh it's just a matter of notif uh just a
notification to the licensee saying you
need to post your license great thank
you very much jenny i appreciate that
sounds like you guys are busy out there
in dcc
um heather question for you
we have two we have representation from
two different states california and
colorado can you tell us what camera is
and what are the objectives of that
organization sure
a camera is the cannabis regulators
association and um currently camera has
about 40 different member states i think
so essentially every state that has
legalized cannabis in some form
primarily medical or adult youth but
agencies that have hemp programs are
also represented within canberra
and what's nice about camera is the the
primary regulatory body is usually the
the main member but if your state
chooses to have full membership in
camera any of your state agencies that
touch cannabis in any way can
join in the discussion so even things
like our department of education
or department of public safety that you
know just as law enforcement they can
all be members of the organization to
share information
and canada's main goal really is to
be a source for regulators to
discuss uh best practices to discuss
lessons learned
and to to share
i guess our experiences with each other
in trying to regulate cannabis so that
in the end one of the primary you know
goals there is that can rule will be a
forum to promote standardization and
harmonization in regulations um across
the country
um obviously there are challenges with
that um as each state undergoes their
own law making processes and regulatory
development processes uh which is why we
do probably see so much disparity in
state regs but camera is this recently
organized group um that is really hoping
to to bring some of that harmonization
it also intends to serve as a group that
can help educate others so again that
could be educating federal lawmakers so
as we look at you know possible federal
legalization
state lessons can be shared with the
feds
um
and and also to be kind of you know
partners with industry to again share
information both ways and learn how and
understand how the regulations really
affect the industry um there are
certainly goals that as this is all um
developed that public health and safety
and consumer safety
equity and all
and other things are really at the
forefront of the work of camera
thank you very much and it's so nice to
hear that that states are beginning to
form and union not unionized but
harmonize and centralize so thank you
very much um and i'm assuming that
colorado and california
are both part of the organization
awesome that's great and
katie
um
what prompted the national science i'm
sorry the national um
safety
council's involvement with cannabis
sir so the national safety council like
susan mentioned is 120 year old
organization focused on
workforce safety
both in the workplace and on the road
and so as canada's legalization began
affecting employers we
have about 53 000 membership member
organizations and we issued a survey to
them kind of asking what are your
concerns about employees and
your organizations as is cannabis
affecting
workplace safety and how are you
addressing it
so what we heard from them was that they
needed help they needed education and
they needed resources in order to
educate their employees and develop
really evidence-based policy
and so we partnered
with a few different organizations to
develop a project to look at how states
are regulating
regulating products and hope to come out
with the resource this year
really to do what heather was talking
about and really just provide education
as others are legalizing and
regulating cannabis to learn the best
practices and lessons learned from other
states and organizations
thank you very much so there you have it
nsc and i'm expecting that we're going
to have a lot more interaction from nfc
moving forward
and this will be terrific so this is a
really quick snapshot into where we are
and and how we
and and where we're hoping to go
um but now how do we
how did we get here
so let me ask you kay um
what were your challenges when you were
when you were facing state regulators
trying to develop a comprehensive
testing requirements
thank you it's a great question um and i
am talking here today
as a former cannabis regulator rather
than on behalf of my current employer so
i should make that clear but um can you
speak into them thank you
reminding me that i'm short
thank you
so when we were working with the
department of public health in
massachusetts in 2015
we were trying to develop a
comprehensive testing regulation and
typically
uh to be honest
when we were trying to develop
any kind of regulations govern governing
cannabis
we would look to the west and we would
look to the examples that were set by
colorado and california so it's very
nice to be on
uh the panel with representatives of
those two great states today but with
regard to trying to do comprehensive
testing regulations in that particular
year they were just themselves getting
into it at that time so what we were
faced with was a lack of federal
resources to look at because cannabis
was illegal and still is at the federal
level but also a lack of
prior
comprehensive regulations in the more
mature markets and the problem that we
had
in addition to the fact that we didn't
have anything to copy from is that when
you are looking at policy makers who are
addressing cannabis regulations not only
then but today their resumes look more
like mine than they look like the uh
more scientifically oriented members of
this panel or indeed the members of this
audience so we are challenged not only
in the fact that we didn't have
resources to draw on but we ourselves
were not conversant with the
matter that we were trying to regulate
so it was
extremely difficult we needed to draw on
experts within the government itself but
then also
request help from the outside
organizations and one of the things i
would encourage
folks in the audience today is to get
involved
as much as you can understanding that
your time is limited
states need to hear exactly what heather
was referring to earlier how the
regulations are affecting industry and
if you're seeing a problem
please do try and explain what it is so
that regulators can try to adjust it
it's very difficult when the
stakeholders in a particular environment
are not communicating with each other
and instead are siloed
it's not a productive way to proceed so
to the extent you can please provide
comment and explain to regulators where
you believe that something needs to be
addressed rather than
confining your comment to publications
that we may not read
i think that would be incredibly helpful
until such time as
camera and other organizations like it
with the help of national safety council
managed to achieve a more uniform
standardized environment
i think communication between the
different stakeholders in this
environment needs to increase otherwise
we are going to be left with this
patchwork
that we currently have in the different
states
thank you
and okay i'm just going to follow up on
one one more thing with you on that
and that is as a regulator from the
commission perspective
i have heard in the past about muhammad
and the mountain
can you tell me what might be implied by
that
that was what i was referring to with
regard to making sure you're
communicating with the folks that are
regulating your environment especially
when you're dealing with new and
emerging markets
in colorado california and massachusetts
at this point in
our market development we likely have
scientific staff that can advise us and
help us but when you're starting out
like i did with not only the medical
program but the adult use program you
may not have access to that kind of
resources in the timeline that you are
given either by the legislature or by
the citizens in a ballot initiative to
get your program up and running so it is
very important for the stakeholders to
come to the regulators don't wait for
them to come to you please
get your thoughts on paper or
you know by way of testimony in front of
the regulators so they can understand
where you're coming from
thank you very much and sure you are um
a stakeholder right an industry
stakeholder here
and what successes or challenges or both
have you had in the cannabis regulatory
space
i would like to first of all tell you
a story
of how
difficult it was for me to make a
decision to to
to pivot from being a public servant
to being an industry stakeholder is that
i had
bumped into
at a conference a commissioner from a
particular state in a regulatory body
and i had some ideas or recommendations
or amend
amendments to their microbial testing
rules and that i said to this individual
that there were plenty
of individuals
or industry stakeholders in her state
that could advise
for amendments of the rules and she just
looked at me and she said
you know i don't listen to them
but i'm glad that i'm with medicinal
genomics the last
year now
and the challenges that i face
is that there's no federal legalization
and so therefore there's
sets of required microbial testing rules
and so one by one
i review
the test microbial testing rules i
identify
areas where we feel
to make recommendations to amend rules
based on scientific
principles
and the
and then
the second challenge is to open a
dialogue
a true dialogue
between
our organization
and the
regulatory body
officials concerning our recommendations
concerning the successes
to be very honest with you
for five months
submitted public comment to various
regulatory bodies in multiple states
and all i heard was
then something happened in november
and various dialogues have been opened
we've been able to dialogue with them
a particular example
in one particular state that i read the
allowable methods the issues the
challenges are allowable methods what
analytes to test
and the action levels
so one particular state i read
the action excuse me the allowable
methods
are
usp1111 and 2025 and i do understand
that at this
the start of this
you know cannabis you know industry
there were no standards and methods
and so
this is why this was
adopted
and so
but it also said plating only
and i have five decades of experience
all the way from plating systems through
qpcr
and to
sequencing and therefore
i communicated
that to them with a recommendation to be
open to the aoac
standards and methods
that have been certified and then
the director of that agency contacted us
and we've had been having open dialogue
concerning everything about their
their rules and that they are amending
the rules and
and
this is an example of one of
you know our successes and are multiple
states
and we've had success in terms of
opening the dialogue
thank you and and you brought up aoac
and actually for all of the panelists
here well most of the panelists here you
all have some involvement with the aoec
casp
sure what prompted you to get involved
with with aoac
i'm glad you asked that you asked me
that question susan i was absolutely not
aware
of aoec cast program i am glad that an
industry friend of mine alerted me
to the existence of this program because
i knew immediately it was necessary
standards and methods
so i reviewed the first year's progress
report
and to be honest i was aghast
at
the plan or the three targets
for the next year
the second year
so
with an open heart i simply communicated
to aoac officials that i wish to just
simply have a dialogue and to share
my understanding of the
microbial testing
well the entire testing space
but specifically microbial testing
space
and they agreed to the dialogue and i
simply explained
who i was and what i
my experience
i gave them my recommendations
and
that was it
and to my shock they invited me to be a
member of all four committees because of
the breadth of knowledge that i had
accumulated at the department of health
and i simply says well
one is enough and being a microbiologist
i joined
the working uh the microbial working
group and in the last two years we've
been able
to have standards and subsequently
methods for the detection of the four
pathogenic strains of aspergillus
as well as for sugar toxin producing e
coli and salmonella
and in the clinical literature
for salmonella and the four aspergillus
pathogens there are clinical
cases reported of persons
utilizing cannabis or medical cannabis
that have
had illnesses and also death
thank you for that
heather you're very involved with aoac
casp as well
um
i want to ask you to ask answering
questions about that but as you know
that organization is focused on
establishing standard test methods how
do you think that might affect
regulations or in in colorado or on
behalf of camera or any place else sure
sure
well i think um
you know i think one of the reasons we
got involved with casp was because we
have seen directly the need for
more standardization and test methods
across laboratories i truly think part
of the issue that we see
in variability in test results between
labs is because there are so many
different methodologies and
inconsistencies and methods being used
i do want to say though
when i when i'm talking about utilizing
more standard methods in cannabis
testing i am not necessarily advocating
that every lab should use the exact same
method
again i don't think that we want to
stifle innovation we don't want to
stifle growth in the science we want to
ensure that people are able to
do the best testing that they can to use
good science and cannabis is complicated
it itself is a complex matrix
and then we have all these different
product types and so one test may not
apply to everything
so when i say that i think the
development of standard test methods is
really important again i think that
means
development of methods that have been
put through a level of rigor that is
perhaps more than an individual lab can
do on their own so what aoac does is you
know they put out an smpr different
method developers can submit methods
they have to be proven to meet the
requirements of the smpr by an expert
review panel
and the method can be published for
first action and then before its final
action it has to go through multi-lab
studies to again be shown to be fit for
purpose and to be really reliable as a
method and i think having those types of
methods developed again will overall
benefit the the general science and the
cannabis industry
and i think as those things are
developed and regulators can look to
that process again of a really robust
science then it gives regulators the
ability to say like you know maybe maybe
i hope again i hope regulators don't say
you may only do this one thing
but um i hope that regulars will say
this has been proven if you you either
need to you know do this this thing that
has been proven or you have to at least
demonstrate that your process or your
method is equivalent or better
and so that's really why i think things
like aoac casp are really important in
the in the science space of cannabis
so i guess this will go back to both
heather you you heather as well as jenny
would you see these standards as being
um
supporting the regulatory efforts in
your respective states
i'll just i'll be brief and let jenny
talk but yeah absolutely again i think
um
you know it's again it's not
if anybody's ever participated in
legislative or regulatory development
what any individual person um who is
involved with these things thinks may be
best it doesn't always mean it works out
that way in the regulatory or
legislative process
but again if we want to make
evidence-based policy decisions if we
want to make things based in science we
have to have these standards and these
processes to look to if we don't have
them then how are we going to make those
decisions so again it doesn't always
mean that we're going to
always make the right choices in
regulations or policy but again having
the resource and the data and the facts
is extremely helpful thank you jenny do
you have anything to
add actually don't have purview over um
the laboratory side so i'm just going to
echo what heather said i agree it's it
may be not um
the same exact standards for for every
method but if it's been tested and shown
that it's rigorous enough absolutely
great thank you and jenny by the way i
understand that the california structure
recently changed from the bcc to the dcc
can you very briefly talk talk to us
about the differences and what prompted
that change
yeah actually
prior to july 12th there were three uh
licensing agencies for cannabis in
california there was the bcc the bureau
of cannabis control which oversaw
distribution and retail licenses
cal cannabis which was under the cdfa
the california department of food and
agriculture which oversaw cultivation
and my legacy agency was cdph and i was
from the manufacturing manufactured
cannabis safety branch and we oversaw
the manufacturers um come july 12th we
consolidated agencies into the uh into
the main department of cannabis controls
a new agency and that was really to
offer a better you know regulatory
structure for our licensed market um to
streamline efforts you know to combine
resources so that we could be more
efficient and more effective as a
regulatory agency in california
excellent thank you so much that helps
helps me understand
what what's going on
so it's always a dynamic
industry isn't it
katie question for you and that is
how do we elevate safety as a priority
as cannabis regulations evolve
yeah well i think one of the key here i
i've heard everyone say it is engaging
science in in the policy decision making
process right engaging those individuals
who are
doing the research and validating the
methods
in the regulatory process or encouraging
them to be engaged
at the national safety council we did
that for example when we
embarked on product testing regulation
research we
gathered a scientific advisory board of
you know toxicologists and
microbiologists and others who were
involved in the research because we are
not researchers
and although we hope to come together
and have a resource that others can look
to for best practices we know that that
that knowledge cannot only just come
from us
um and then look to the data you know
there are
there's lots of great research happening
in the field and i think that as
policies are developed on the state
level and on the federal level as well
we have to utilize the data that's
available and look at the states who
have
learned lessons and elevated safety in
their own regulatory situation
and
you know emulate those in others
i think that training is another area
that we need to prioritize and that's
worker safety training that is
training for individuals to recognize
impairment
and there are
just a lot of areas that workforce
training public health training is
needed as we regulate cannabis thank you
very much
and kay as a former regulator what are
some of the practices or
maybe even best practices that you might
recommend to regulators who are
implementing new systems or
or reinventing their systems
sure
um well i think we
raised some of them already on the panel
and
particularly the independence of the
laboratories not having ownership in
common with the people that they are
testing or the entities that they are
testing
um
engaging with the scientific community
and being open to the kind of dialogue
that sherman was discussing earlier and
also interacting with canro which
had what was starting to
become
what it is now today back in 2015 but it
was very much at a seed level
and i think these organizations as well
as aoac are
critical to
regulators such as myself who do not
have a scientific background to
understand what is being told to them
and to try and find a balance and create
regulations that make sense
prior to a centralized regulatory
authority by a science-based agency
thank you and
most people who know me
know that i am
not shy about saying that some
regulations although very well intended
are not necessarily always that
practical and founded in
pure empirical science
so
it sounds like we're still on the
pathway forward and we're using many
resources
to to get there
so taking that rational approach looking
at science and and moving forward i
think is great and as as we've all been
talking about it's a very dynamic system
um
so
i'm just kind of going to throw this out
to everybody we still have about another
20 minutes left in our session and i
have more
i have more questions to fire off at our
panelists but at this point do you have
any questions that you would like to
raise please step up to the microphone
now we'll really test them right
yeah good morning and thank you for
being here i
had a question from a laboratory's
perspective by the time we actually test
something it's too late to do anything
about
product quality
i'm interested in where you see
laboratories fitting into haptic
gmp gap and
any ancillary testing that
we could be providing that would
ensure product safety and compliance
would you like to direct that to anyone
in particular or just open it up to
anybody yeah uh
well uh specifically on uh haptic and uh
gmp
okay
would any of you folks what could
laboratories contribute to uh
well when we talk about laboratory
testing can i ask you to qualify that
for me do you mean third-party
independent testing to comply with
requirements or
third-party independent testing but uh
any
any uh testing that would be done as
part of the haptic plan or gmp or gap
plan should be done by an independent
laboratory
so the compliance testing is different
from gmp correct
okay just as long as we're all on that
same page
anything in addition that laboratories
could do to
assure that okay
uh if i missed the last thing you just
said let me know because i couldn't
quite hear you but um i think so i think
most states allow for
the third party labs to do r d testing
for the uh licensees and i think that's
a big part of it in our current sort of
scheme is that
you know
whether it's
you as a laboratory educating your
clients on the importance of actually
testing things while they're in progress
versus just only doing that required
test at the end
right if we think about what gmp really
is and how that you know would typically
go people would really be looking a lot
more at their inputs than i think what
typically happens in the cannabis
industry
again as regulators like our concern
right is that final product so um you
know typically and it varies from state
to state where you're required to test
but again our our goal is that that
final product is as compliant and as
safe as possible for the consumer
but again if you as a manufacturer
really want to understand your
manufacturing process if you really want
to ensure that by the time you reach
your final product stage that you do
have a quality product that you will
pass your testing i don't know how you
do that without doing some in-process
testing again you might want to test
your inputs that you purchase from other
vendors you may want to test midstream
in your production process exactly what
is important to you is up to your
business process again there was a risk
analysis discussion earlier this morning
like risk assessment is really important
and i think um i think unfortunately a
lot of cannabis industry doesn't really
understand that because all they all
they really know is the regs say i have
to test my end product
but so i think there's a lot of
education to be done and you as a lab
can help explain that to them what your
testing services can can offer to them
in that regard because even though you
know when we look at more
standard gmp and other industry that
often involves in-house testing right a
lot of facilities will have their own
labs
well for one labs are very expensive so
a lot of cannabis companies currently
don't have them and even if they have
the option to if they weren't required
to use a third-party lab they may not
want to invest in that expense
and again you guys the labs are truly
the experts in the science so
you know why not utilize your services
and your expertise rather than trying to
build that in-house so i hope that helps
with some of your questions but i think
there's a lot of education understanding
that still needs to be done in that
regard
thank you and i think we have a question
on here to decide hello uh thank you all
for the work you do and everybody on the
panel um like to just ask this question
to the panel so
speaking of plating based methods we
recently also had a large recall in
michigan
what is the regulatory approach for
auditing products in
colorado and california to confirm
refute previously recalled products with
safety concerns
um how do we approach this with plating
methods that have such lack of
reproducibility internally and amongst
other labs as well
sounds like a question for sure
yes i monitor
the
recalls
in the various states
and so i've seen
an increase in the frequency of
recalls for
cannabis products that have
you know that are tested to be beyond uh
the action levels for
total yeast and mold
for asthma jealous
and there are other contaminants i focus
on the microbial
the one thing you mentioned plating
systems and this is very problematic
in the sense that let's just take the
example of
you know total yeast and mold
is that
first of all
cannabinoid there's in the literature
there's con the cannabinoids have been
shown
to have
antibiotic activity so when
i say that word to myself i think
bacterial but if you also go into the
literature there are certain antibiotics
that
besides
affecting the growth of bacteria also
affect the growth
of total yeast and mold
that's been shown in a paper that we
recently published where in the plating
system of drbc which has chloramphenicol
and an additional antibiotic actually
decreased
the
growth of aspergillus by fivefold
on this plating system
secondly
there's endophytes you're not measuring
all the total yeast and molds that's
been shown also in the literature
and
that's why we are a proponent you know
of qpcr testing
so i'm wondering if this might be an
opportunity where jenny might talk about
in california anyway how do you handle
when the the
i'm sure this never happens anywhere but
there's a discrepancy or there's a
deficiency during an investigation or
something on the coa
doesn't quite line up how it would never
happen in reality right so it's all
hypothetical
how do you handle that in california
yeah yeah i don't have uh direct purview
over the lab side but we did have a
recent recall that that did
that we did execute at dcc
um if the if there is a deficiency in
um lab results generally licensees are
very helpful and move very swiftly to
help us in a voluntary recall
if
if a coa doesn't pass they also have the
option of remediation
which is
sending it back to a manufacturer to
either repackage it or
correct it for any kind of uh for any
kind of deficiency that could mean again
repackaging
or
uh drying if the lr activity was too
high
um remediating for molds or for
heavy metals or or pesticides or
something if possible generally the
edibles are more
difficult to remediate if it's if it's
unless it's packaging
and so those are kind of deficiencies on
the coa testing side again the
deficiencies that come out of a
compliance inspection of a facility we
work through a like you know we work
closely with licensee to correct them
depending on the risk
thank you very much and i believe we
have a question over here yes thank you
um i have two questions
the first one
is
what is going on with any kind of
standards writing
or application either proposed or
generic i know that astm had their d37
committee and was looking into i was on
that committee for a while i found it
very slow moving actually thorough but
still moving but they're certainly a
respected organization i don't know
where they're at but it would seem to me
that at least some kind of
standards
from which agents state agencies could
or or private sector could comply uh
either voluntarily or
uh with some modifications are well
needed in the industry for everything
from
labeling um packaging dosing what have
you
my second question is if you don't mind
i'll take that liberty um you may not be
the right panel for it but i imagine
you'll have something to say anyway
because most people do what in the world
is going on with the fda and cbd or
three and a half years since the farm
bill was passed there's a tremendous
remains tremendous confusion what i like
to call the rubik's cube between laws
and regulations and industry
knowledge as a lawyer i i it's hard
enough to advise people what to do with
this industry and uh to do it safely and
correctly without violating well too
many laws but um uh to try to explain
yes hemp is a legal product but no you
can't sell cbd if it's an adjustable
because the fda hasn't gotten around to
it so with those liberties i look
forward to your comments
if it's okay i'll take the first the
first question there
with respect to standards
so as we know the regulations came out
before the standards came out right so
standards organizations aoec ascm many
of them have been running really fast to
try to catch up to regulations and we're
kind of like doing this right now
and education has become a very strong
part of that whole process
so
i also was very involved with ascm in
fact i was a founding member of d37
um but i'm no longer involved with astm
there are only so many volunteer
activities i can i can handle
so i put my energy into aoac and it's a
very robust process um as heather
mentioned earlier it's not a popularity
contest it's not a we need a method oh
i'll write one great it's great it
sounds great let's vote it in it's now a
standard it's a very very very rigorous
process that that it goes through
so standard methods already exist we
have first action
methods for cannabinoids in
plant material and bever in
concentrates and oils we have methods
for heavy metals we have methods for
beverages coming out so we do have those
methods many of them are from
private organizations urofins
was if you're familiar with europeans
is
responsible for the very first potency
or cannabinoid method that's out there
so they do exist they are catching up
but they're put through
a lot of rigor before they become
standard test methods they have to go
through a vetted expert review panel
where you can't just sign up and say
yeah i want to vote on a method you
actually have to have
qualifications to be on that committee
and review it so they are catching up
and our panelists here are part of that
and
you know on the on the other side of
that saying oh hi
you know you feel like a limp noodle
after you've submitted a method and it's
gone through that erp and medicinal
genomics has gone through it um
on behalf of the product testing side of
it as well
so a number about a year or so ago a
number of uh products were
put through the ringers of hell
for product standardization for total
yeast and mold
medicinal genomics was one of them so
it's not an easy process to get through
but right now organizations like aoac
are working very hard
as the advisor for that particular
program we have scientists from around
the world we have working groups that
number in the hundreds and on you know
try managing a phone call with 100
people on the line from
seven or eight different countries all
coalescing on one scientific method it's
not an easy process but we're all
working together recognizing that the
regulatory landscape is ever so changing
and trying to keep up with that and also
trying to
educate regulators on the empirical
science side of that so all of that is
moving forward now
as for the other question
i'm not on that panel i don't have to
answer that question i'm going to leave
that to our friends here
have at it well i don't know as as none
of us are actually working at the fda we
obviously can't answer that question
with any degree of confidence or
knowledge
but
we do know that the fda is
taking some enforcement action in fact
did so just this week regarding uh
companies not only that are selling cbd
but also uh for the first time delta
eight uh and making claims that the fda
deemed appropriate so
they are taking some action uh but i
think as everyone in this room is aware
have not yet issued any sort of
nationwide regulations we certainly
think look forward to the day that that
does occur
but unfortunately it has not yet i think
the fda is in the best position to do
that
in a way that it puts public health and
public safety at the forefront
thank you very much thank you thank you
next question
thank you guys a great panel wow that's
mike's
um i had a couple questions
i think i'll drop this one first one
do you guys on the panel see
any possible
way to regulate the enormous amount of
waste that's being produced for instance
in california
it has to be packaged products huge
amounts of waste the lab produces when
they have to you know open up all these
products not just paper or cardboard but
the batteries themselves we have to find
you know ways to recycle that is there
any thought on ever kind of regulating
that
or finding a way around it environmental
concerns you know yesterday we had a
panel around it and um it's of concern
that's my first question
that is something that has been uh that
has been discussed including you know
the tags that are used um for track and
trace you know that they're but i i've
heard that there are companies now that
are looking to recycle them once the
rfid or chip
rfid chip is removed from the tags
um it is a concern um i think i would
have to check in with cal recycle to
better answer your question so if we can
connect um off
after the panel i can i can try to find
out the answer for you
fantastic thank you so much um i'm
really hoping you know it's great to see
you all together that there'll be some
kind of uh future collaboration among
the states to sort of
simplify and standardize and i think
susan answered my other question which
was really around
uh do you foresee adopting you know cass
or some other compendium method and
giving the industry especially
laboratories opportunity to either adopt
that or at least be prepared and i asked
this in light of you know january 1st
right um
there's about what seven months left
will there be opportunity for that or
will it be
you know okay now adopt this in the next
30 days
it's not uncommon for other industries
to defer to an aoac or usp method
in fact you can go to the fda website
for some testing where the fda will
defer to an aoec method for example or
an astm method for example so
i personally foresee that happening in
the future if there comes a time when
the fda or other federal regulatory body
steps in
that they may very likely defer
laboratories to a specific
compendium method
but who's you know no mind readers here
i don't have a crystal ball but judging
from other industries i wouldn't be
surprised if that were the case
thank you
hello again
current california law allows for an rpd
of 30
in potency analysis
uh plus or minus i'm curious if uh with
the adoption of
standardized methods if that would be
tightened
a laboratory can
be off by 30 percent and their
analysis still be valid
if that's still the case with a
standardized method nothing's going to
change
can so i'm sorry it's just a little the
monitors are weird to hear but you said
california labs are allowed to be off of
their california regulations have been
rdp of thirty percent plus or minus
thirty three percent so again is that
there's two there's a difference there
though and again um is the laboratory
allowed to be off by thirty percent or
is the
label uh number allowed to be within
thirty percent of the laboratory's uh
test result the the results of the
laboratory can vary
plus or minus 30 percent well be within
regulation
so the question is is there going to be
a tightening of that criteria
in
with the adoption of standardized
methods
i would hope so
yeah go ahead susan so the aoac is is
non-partisan it's non-governmental right
it's it's for the public
it's not for anything private
um so when the method performance
requirements are published and and
there's a solicitation for methods we
make every effort to keep it as broad as
possible
as long as it's scientifically sound
um up to this point casp has been
focusing on meeting regulatory
requirements
because the industry is desperate for
those test methods to meet regulatory
requirements but we all recognize that a
lot of those requirements
are not necessarily
founded empirically um so it's a very
difficult balance in developing those
standard methods now if we're not
chasing a regulation and we establish
the performance requirements of a method
then life is good right now it's up to
the state to either require
a lab to meet our requirements the
standard requirements or not but we aoac
methods do not dictate to the state
but the state does have the ability to
dictate
back down to the standard method
um so that that process
questions the question really pertains
to the development of standard methods
and whether or not that would be a
consideration i hope so but you know
there are so many things that i wish for
in this industry in the testing industry
um and my hope is that the regulatory
bodies that kay and others have so
profoundly mentioned today have not
necessarily based on the scientific
foundation
but now we have an institution like casp
that's available in providing that
education so my hope is that in time
those regulations will become more in
line with
better
or more sound science and i know i'm not
answering your question very directly
i'm trying to be
i have my own opinion
but i'm trying to be
cognizant and respective of all the
regulatory environment thank you
my turn
that's not too loud
so
going back to uh
the cannabis controls are the regulatory
limits for some of the category one uh
pesticides and the uh
from the cannabis control group for here
in california
um has there been discussion about
perhaps making those more scientifically
valid because to say
not detected is your lower limit is
i
don't know
the statistics aren't there so
i don't know if there's any movement on
trying to make that more
more of a normal
value i'm not saying that right but
the way it is now to say that if you
detect anything at all even though it's
below your limit of detection you have
to call that bad
it violates science so what do you think
i'll look at me so i'll try to i can try
to i'm not i'm not from california so i
can't really say um what the regulators
are possibly going to do in terms of
defining that but i i think your
concern is very valid um
for one lab shouldn't be reporting a
detection below their limit of detection
as a result because again it's below the
limit of detection and theory you can't
see it
and you certainly can't see it with any
accuracy
but two
a
saying that the limit of detection is
the action limit
it also i think is problematic because
different laboratories are going to have
different detection limits based upon
their individual methodology so
you may
take the same sample to two different
labs and pass that one and fill it the
other when it's based upon the limit of
detection and it doesn't actually mean
either lab is wrong so i think that's
also very you know challenging then to
um
to understand as a
the customer submitting the result or
the sample for results but also it will
further drive our problems with lab
shopping where again labs may be tempted
to
make an artificially high limit of
detection so that they can pass more
samples that shouldn't actually be
passing
but
we could probably spend another hour or
two talking about the challenges with
pesticides and trying to come up with
action levels for cannabis given that
the
you know the epa has not established
tolerance limits for pesticides on on
cannabis and so
i completely understand why california
has defined
those category one pesticides as a not
detect
but again as we just talked about
there's a lot of challenges with that so
i think i think regulators across the
country are grappling with how to
require testing and establish action
limits for pesticides in in cannabis
we're having an ongoing working group in
colorado and frankly we've been talking
about pesticides for years we're looking
at it right now again and it's just a
it's a really complicated debate to try
to figure out how to do this when we
don't have the data that we would
normally have
for something that you know would
normally be a federally defined
number so
we are i am so sorry to say out of time
and i can
we are one minute over but if you are a
game maybe we can field one more
question
or we can
say thank you very much to our panelists
and i thank you
on behalf of all of us here up on the
stage for your participation and
engagement
if you have any questions catch us when
we step down or when they step down and
enjoy the rest of the of the day take
care