[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast where we talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the km ed 2020 conference in
Pasadena California this september 20th
through 22nd I am your host Ben emerald
I'm the marketing manager of medicinal
genomics and a proud member of the can
med 2020 team head over to can med
events dot-com to check out our phase
one schedule which includes presentation
topics from 20 of our invited speakers
and abstract presenters we will continue
to add to that lineup throughout the
summer so be sure to sign up for email
alerts so you don't miss any
announcements if you sign up on our
podcast page kamut events comm slash
coffee talk you will also be entered
into a drawing to win two tickets to our
can med 2020 VIP dinner on this episode
we talk with our kin med 2020
cultivation keynote presenter Seth
Crawford of oregon CBD seth and the team
at oregon CBD specialize in turning out
new exciting and unique industrial hemp
varieties designed for maximum yield and
large-scale production there early
adoption of disruptive testing
technology in large-scale breeding
techniques allowed oregon CBD to produce
a number of industry firsts including
the first high cannabinoid content
autoflowering CBD plant and the first
pure CBG CBC CBD v CB GV &amp; cv cv
field-ready varieties his presentation
at cam at 2018 was an instant hit and as
I mentioned in our conversation
Seth was mobbed with questions from
attendees immediately following it I
know because I was trying to get an
interview with him and had to wait for
the crowd to clear we dig into some of
the details of that cam med 2018
presentation particularly the process
his team uses to develop unique stable
hemp seed varieties
Seth shares his thoughts on where the
hemp industry is headed as well as some
of the challenges the industry is facing
this season I also noticed when I listen
back to the recording that Seth dropped
several references to the year 2021
which could offer some hints into what
the keynote presentation he has planned
for km at 2020 which happens to be
titled cannabis 2021 the golden age of
discovery we are excited to have Seth as
a keynote at kin med 2020 this year and
we are excited to see you there as well
go to kmn events dot-com now to see our
ticket pricing options and get your
ticket today we are currently offering
early bird pricing through August 1st we
are also offering a 100% refund to
ticket holders should can med 2020 need
to be postponed due to kovin 19 rest
assured that we are working closely with
the Pasadena Convention Center to make
sure that we can provide a safe
environment for our staff and attendees
and as of this recording the event is
still on but just in case we have
updated that refund policy go to our
website for more details
that's cam at events comm slash kovat 19
I also wanted to thank this episode
sponsor advance nutrients founded in
1999 advanced nutrients was the first to
develop a complete nutrient system that
unlocks the true genetic potential of
the cannabis plant since its inception
the brand has introduced more than 50
innovations to the cultivation community
and continues to revolutionize the space
through proprietary scientific
discoveries their most recent innovation
advanced hemp is the first all-in-one
fertilizer that is backed by 20 years of
science and specifically formulated to
assist growers who are looking for
higher yield CBD counts for more
information visit advanced nutrients
calm and finally we're proud to say that
this episode of the can med coffee talk
podcast is fueled by the hemp and coffee
exchange the hemp and coffee exchange is
a grassroots Tampa based Coffee Roasting
Company
progressively sustainable consumables
combining two of the most genetically
diverse plants on the planet hemp and
coffee hemp coffee is a healthy
delicious natural product rich in trace
minerals and nutrients providing
sustained energy without the crash of
regular coffee for more information
check out hemp coffee exchange calm and
use the promo code drink hemp to get 10%
off your purchase okay without any
further ado please enjoy my conversation
with Seth Crawford applause MCTV
[Music]
hey Seth thanks for joining us on the
podcast thanks for having me man I
really appreciate it of course and let
me say the team's really excited to have
you as our keynote presenter for the
cultivation focus area for cam at twenty
twenty year presentation at cam at
twenty eighteen was a standout for sure
and I might have a question or two about
that as I'm a novice when it comes to
plant breeding but I'm still very
interested in it and if others are
interested and I imagine you are if
you're listening but I encourage you to
listen to them
Seth's kimba 2018 presentation I'll put
a link in our show description so you
can check that out but if I remember
correctly and you could tell me but I I
think you were mobbed after the talk
with people asking questions and maybe
handing you business cards which is
always a good sign so we knew we had to
have you back as a keynote and that we
were sure that you'd have new data to
present so I'm wondering we're dying to
know what is it here looking to present
at cam in 2020 this year most definitely
mobbed it was fantastic to get that kind
of response from folks I think in a lot
of ways what what we're doing up here in
Oregon and I there's other folks around
the world that are engaged in this in in
similar levels is us but what we're
doing is really dramatically different
from from previous cannabis breeders and
the things that we've been lucky enough
to uncover both on a phenotype and chemo
type and now even genotype level is just
distinct right it's different from from
what's available and we're continuing to
push that forward so this year we're
really excited to be able to talk about
some of the breeding projects that we're
working on obviously both the collection
of the few phenotype data chemo type
data genotype data we're gonna give you
a little bit of an update on our
collaboration with Oregon State
University and how that's going there's
a number of very interesting fronts
there we're going to look at some larger
population genomic studies that were
engaged in both remember when when Kevin
was on talking about his presentation
the euro fin snip chip we're
participating in that with some of our
some of our f2 varieties along with some
some competing approaches that are
really looking at identifying structural
variants that are present in the
cannabis genome and specifically
structural variants between individuals
within the population is that seems to
be where a lot of the the most
interesting interesting examples pop up
in terms of new new genotypes that
express new chemo types and new
phenotypes that are much much more
acclimated for specific types of
production so we're really excited to be
able to share the findings so obviously
we're still in the process of gathering
all that information but we think that
it's going to be a significant
revolutionary shift and the way that
cannabis is produced based on a lot of
the results that that US and others are
collaborating on finding excellent now
are you still very much at this stage
looking for
you said variations is it in regards to
you know cannabinoid expression terpenes
and sort of potency sort of things or
are you looking also at you know actual
plant structure or drought resistance
and things like that all of the above
yeah it again any good breeding program
you know you really have to narrow in on
things that are really really critical
for specific projects so I would say
that the answer to that depends on the
project that we're working on but we do
have some some awesome trials going on
with OSU over the summer we've got 10 12
different states as of this afternoon
that are engaged in a multi-state land
grant University variety trial to be
able to assess what kind of
differences emerge in different
ecosystems whether it's from flower
timing to disease resistance to water
usage number of other trials going on
here in the western United States
specifically focusing on water
consumption that stuff's all really
interesting but I think some of the the
biggest breakthroughs that we're going
to be looking at for 2021 are really
coming down to chemical chemical data
and chemical changes in the plants as
you're probably well aware that the USDA
has made it fairly difficult for
industrial hemp farmers to continue to
grow large fields of cannabinoid rich
plants specifically CBD plants in part
due to the underlying genetic
predisposition of the CBD a synthase to
produce some residual THC but we have
actually figured out a way to basically
get around that and we've got some
wonderful wonderful plants that are very
very rich in cannabinoids CBD a CBD VA
CBCA and have great olfactory
characteristics as well so these are
these are plants that have wonderful
terpenes and other compounds that are
responsible for making the plant smell I
think this is going to be something that
everybody comes to understand a little
bit better in 2021 but yeah we're really
excited about these these new chemo
types and being able to get them into
farmers hands to allow them to continue
successfully producing low-cost
cannabinoids for the public and now
oregon CBD is specifically focused on
hemp correct yeah I mean here I and I
saw the in your list of questions that
this was going to come up and I'm my PhD
is in sociology so I'm gonna just step
back and say any dichotomy any sort of
external definition that we place on the
cannabis plant is a social construct
first and foremost there's more more
similarities between a plant that has a
THC ace and face that's active in a
plant that has a CBD a synthase that's
active outside of those genes yes those
two those
those two synthases end up determining
what's legal in in most countries in the
world however it doesn't necessarily
demarcate an actual difference between
plants so everything's cannabis we got
into the industrial hemp space just
because it didn't have the same plant
count restrictions that the the THC
production space had and we knew if we
wanted to actually breed plants the way
that you you need to to move this crop
forward you're gonna have to have really
really large numbers access to an actual
bank account relationships with
universities and other other
institutions and that was that was
really the way to move forward so when
you say that the way that you're doing
breeding is different than kind of
traditional breeding that's going on in
the cannabis space is that what you mean
that you're able to do it at this large
scale and and kind of do it the proper
way yeah and when we say proper way not
just scale so obviously with any type of
information that the larger your sample
size is the more accurate your your
under lighting data is in our case we
were really bucking the trend and this
is that it's present in the THC breeding
side and I won't say that all THC
breeders are doing this but because it's
illegal and it's essentially still an
underground activity even for the folks
that are operating in state legal
production programs there's always you
know the the overhang of federal
interference which means that you can't
run huge huge numbers and you have to
focus on some very specific
characteristics you also don't have the
you know that the freedom to do five
generations of inbreeding with a
specific variety before you out cross it
to create your your field-ready versions
so in that in the THC side of things a
lot of times you see people that are
taking Sour Diesel and crossing it with
purple kush and the resulting plant is
purple diesel or sour cush or you know
whatever it happens to be but in reality
you know that the offspring of those two
plants well you're gonna end up with you
know maybe one out of twenty phenotypes
it's just amazing and great for
production you know and you can clone
that and then grow your small canopy on
the THC side from a breeding perspective
you just created
an absolute mess of genes it's it's a
it's it's not going to produce a uniform
crop we call it a poly hybrid pollen
shucking is the term used by people that
are that are doing the actual line
breeding and line breeding is difficult
you know it takes years to do you know
the average development cycle for one of
our varieties is about three years and
that includes you know from the time
that you actually identify your standout
in a in a population to embracing it in
isolation tents self pollinating
repeatedly for generations and testing
each one of those generations to figure
out which plants have the traits that
you're looking for both from a chemical
being a typical and now genotypes as
well making sure that you're getting
what you want and then once you've
identified ten to twenty standouts you
know four or five generations into that
process you then outcross and perform
field trials and those field trials are
where you actually get to see which of
your inbred population which of your
inbred plants ends up producing the best
field production populations so we end
up you know in a situation like that we
may think we have twenty amazing plants
but in reality we narrow it down to one
or two that ends up becoming a
production plant we throw away 99.9
percent of what we start with and that's
a that's a different situation I think
most of the folks in the the THC world
are accustomed to that's gonna be
heartbreaking in a way you know
sometimes progress requires death it's
that the plant Raiders on staff we are
it's it's so funny we all obviously
deeply deeply love plant life in
particular but at the same time we know
what our goals are it's sad to cut
plants down but it's also to a certain
extent of relief you know you're you're
you're taking the unknown out of the
field for a farmer and replacing it with
something that you know is going to be a
stellar performer so it's you know yes
it's sad but at the same time there's a
bit of joy knowing that your actual
making the gene pool better and are they
just completely scrapped is there any
way stacks and stacks and stacks of
plants stacks of plants yeah no they're
gone they're done we obviously we stored
there we store DNA to go back and figure
out you know hey what was what was wrong
with this particular phenotype genotype
genotype etc but no we we literally just
we compost them okay now I want to step
back a bit because you're kind of
talking about your process of you know
taking a creating a new variety and
you've had a a great slide about
this in your presentation in 2018 but
I'll fully admit I got a little lost so
I don't know if you've gotta help me so
so you start with your to parrot lines
and you get your F ones take me through
there from there because there are some
terms like bat crossing and cell thing
that I'm just not familiar with but I'd
really like to try to kind of understand
the process here yeah yeah most
definitely and and on that slide what
what I was basically starting off with
were two very diverse parent plants and
what it would take to actually go
through and identify segregation and
your resulting population the the more
common approach is to take two plants
that you think are distantly related and
in breed each one of those lines
repeatedly over and over and over until
you get to the point where you have a
highly homozygous plant it's basically
it's homozygous a most critical low sigh
in a way that leads to predictable
phenotypes and chemo types so let me
stop you there
so you have the two plants you cross
them you have a generation after that
you're saying that you're after just a
second let's say you find a let's say
you find a plant that has a great
chemical profile regardless of where it
came from
the next step in that process is to self
pollinate that plant so that plant is
gonna get inbred and then you're gonna
pull the seeds off of that plant
and you're gonna grow them out and do
exactly the same thing identify the ones
that have the characteristics that
you're looking for
self-pollinate those collect the seeds
and basically start the process all over
okay to self pollinate you're not
actually crossing it with or you know
crossing it with a sibling or anything
it's it's also through self pollination
that's the quickest way to achieve
homozygosity so what you just described
as say--let you know you say you've got
a great chemical result in the initial
plant that you have another way to do
that is to take one of your self
pollinated seeds and then back cross it
to that original mom that had the right
chemical profile we we tend to stray
away from that in part because of what I
was describing before the fact that most
of the cannabis varieties that are
publicly available are very very
heterozygous so they're they're uh
they're a total mess and that self
pollination ends up leading to less
variation and a tighter likelihood much
higher likelihood that you're going to
get what you are actually looking for so
to take that and then back cross
sometimes that works to lock in the
trait that you're looking for but more
likely than not with the current
population of cannabis its present in
the world
you're going to end up with a just a
bigger mess okay so where'd we stop
there so we're in the f2 where do you
that's where the magic happens to be
honest that's in your in your s2
population or your f2 s to is best
because then you're not crossing
siblings and it's a it's a strict self
pollination regime you're gonna find
plants that are they have the maximum
amount of diversity that's present in in
cannabis in the f2 population you're
gonna see tall plants you're going to
see short plants you're gonna see plants
with giant calyxes small galaxies you'll
see a diversity of olfactory compounds
that are giving them distinct smells and
so just that I don't mean to cut you off
but just to review so this is the the
product of that original cross between
the two distinct
and then that self upon self-pollinated
that's creating the FTS that are have a
lot of different varieties do I have
that right you can do it that way yeah
you can definitely do it that way I
guess what I was getting at is do you
from it yeah from a developmental
standpoint if you've got a plant that
has the chemicals that you want
generally what you're describing right
now is give you a good example we've
we've been working on
Varun's CBD v th c v CB CB etc for about
four years now and once we had finally
found some plants that had very high
concentrations of the Varens it turns
out that they have really poor structure
not great smell horrible flowering time
like they're they're plants that you
would just throw away normally but it
does have that specific ability to
produce Davern ellic acid so we take
that plant and we cross it to a plant
that has all of the other
characteristics that we want but is
missing the different alloc acid
component and in that f1 then we go
through and we look for the plants that
have the highest concentration that have
the best structure etc and then go
through exactly what you just described
yeah guys okay great
alright so sorry I didn't mean to cut
you off no no it's it's kind of I mean
you know this is the downside of audio
if we had some video on here I'd throw
some slides in for you it would make a
lot of sense but right alright so you're
in the FTAs and you're seeing all this
different variation so well then I
imagine that you find the best
performers and then what repeat that
process again exactly yeah you in breed
those and basically we like to repeat as
long as we possibly can one of the
issues that we run into is cannabis it's
an obligate out crosser it really likes
to out cross to other other plants
rather than to itself and in a lot of
cases these plants become sterile fairly
quickly
and that in and of itself is a is a
inherited trait and it's something that
we select against at first in our
populations but yeah you basically just
do
as much as you possibly can with the
goal if I mean we've heard this a lot
lately this this notion of flattening
the curve quote-unquote taking a large
you know what would end up being a large
distribution of people and in our case
traits and spreading it out so what
we're trying to do with cannabis by
inbreeding it is to reduce the amount of
variability that's present that's the
curve that we're trying to flatten
you're trying to create something that
doesn't have variation so that when you
do out cross it you're going to have
something that breeds true for very
particular characteristics great so yeah
so explain to be outcrossing so you're
doing all this
this inbreeding to stabilize and then
you say that you do an out crossing what
what exactly does that mean
that means you're you're actually making
the f1 seed so your true hybrid seed
that will go into a field for farmers
that's like it's the you've done all
your homework and now you're doing the
presentation it's out in the world for
everybody to see yeah they basically
just planting it in the field yeah and
and what what's required to make that f1
are two independently developed highly
inbred lines and like I was saying
before you may have like you know you
may have twenty plants in one of those
lines it's all seemed great but when you
cross them to make your F ones maybe
they don't perform as well as and this
is always the case there's one or two
plants that just outcross exactly the
way that you want them to and perform
better than all of their siblings so
yeah two independent lines to create
your one line that actually goes out to
farmers all right well that's very
helpful thank you for that so you guys
are constantly doing this coming up with
new varieties what are some of the new
and interesting ones you've come up with
or that you're the new and interesting
varieties that you're excited about what
are they the big ones for twenty
twenty-one are all compliant so the USDA
gave us this insane when I was Congress
but USDA is enforcing it this
scientifically inaccurate zero point
three total THC concentration limit
there's a lot of questions in the in the
industrial hemp farming sector you know
does that mean 28 days before harvest is
I mean 14 days before harvest doesn't
mean the day of harvest does it mean
final products etc that's been really
difficult for for folks who are on the
traditional CBD side of breeding to
accomplish we're really really excited
in addition to our pure CPG these are
type 4 plants that we've been working on
and been in various stages of field
trials and public release since 28 2016
2017 in addition to those we now have
type 3 plans these are high CBD plants
that even on the day of harvest and even
after you've trimmed them and they're in
a you know in a store or for sale online
they are compliant 100% compliant with
that 0.3 total THC requirement in
addition to having a number of different
unique compounds that I think are going
to be really useful for people and
enjoyable I think on the on the
consumption side as well excellent and
how has the season been for you you you
mentioned the the farm bill how is that
sort of how has that shaped your season
I'd hurry up and don't do anything is
kind of it's kind of been the mantra
we've been waiting for the FDA to issue
some guidance I know a lot of the
manufacturers of CBD products have been
waiting for some guidance from the FDA
and that has had a very depressive
effect on the entire industry looks like
there was some overproduction in 2019
you know we were we were basically being
yelled at by farmers across the country
for not being able to supply enough
seeds for them so we built out of an
infrastructure capable of producing
enough seed to supply the entire country
and then the market shrank by about
seventy five percent this year so we're
fine it has definitely been trying and I
know that farmers are in a similar
circumstance as well mostly because
they're sitting on product from from
last year and basically just waiting for
the federal government to give the green
light to to have it out in the
marketplace
I think that's going to continue for a
little while we do know that that
Congress is willing to act to be able to
tell the FDA hey it's time to move
forward with with cannabinoids which i
think is a very exciting very exciting
moment it's been a long time coming but
it's gonna open the door up for other
compounds as well so not just CBD but
but the whole pantheon of cannabinoids
including THC to be able to get into
both the food supply and to be
legitimate as something that people can
consume now one of the things you
mentioned in your presentation it came
at twenty eighteen that stuck out to me
because I am a craft beer enthusiast was
these cannabinoid free varieties that
could maybe be used in beer with the
terpenes and everything is almost a
substitute for hops how is that going
really well really well they're they're
really neat plants in addition to being
useful for beer flavoring which to be
perfectly honest you could do with with
other other cannabis plants that have
cannabinoids in them as well but this
just happens to get around a lot of the
regulatory hoops they're they're really
they're really cool they also are able
to produce some some other interesting
compounds that go along with the the
terpenes and the other olfactory
components that would be very very
useful for basically anti-inflammatories
so it's something that we're really
excited about getting out working on
improving them for disease resistance
and getting them out into the
marketplace the one thing that I would
say though at this point is that the the
hop industry is is fairly small compared
to the cannabis industry so it's it's
definitely a niche market but it's
something that we're excited about just
from both a craft brewing standpoint and
then the the Union bring bringing
bringing hops and in cannabis back
together in some really important ways
yeah and I know that you had mentioned
that hop farming doesn't seem fun
that they're just you know 20-foot tall
binds and you have to replant you know
20% of all of your your hops every year
from downy mildew infections and that
kind of problem it's it's hard and very
labor-intensive to be able to get the
components from a hop that are a lot
easier to do it's a cannabis plant and
you don't have the issues of you know
long-term disease pressure popping up in
your field so it's less pesticides less
reinvestment every year for the farmer
and to be perfectly honest cannabis is
capable at this point of producing more
of the compounds that people want from
Hobbs then the hops are themselves
I know another thing that you guys have
been working on is sort of auto flower
varieties or early flowering lines sort
of what's the difference between those
two terms and then I guess a follow-up
to that is will photo period crops kind
of be a thing of the past I think true
photo period crops well should I should
hesitate on this they have a place but
you have to understand the underlying
genes that are responsible for flower
timing and to be able to identify the
variants that will get you where you
want to go in specific places so photo
period plants will have a future but
it's it's more about gene stacking and
being able to use those to get you into
a period where harvest is going to be
preferential so a place like Tennessee
or Kentucky for example they have a very
wet August in September and then
everything just kind of dries out in
early October again with climate change
this is obviously going to fluctuate a
little bit but for folks like that you
want to have a the ability to harvest
early and then also harvest late to
maximize the useful usefulness of your
space so I think there is always going
to be a place for photo period plants to
step back the difference between a auto
flower and a photo period plant is
one is considered a neutral let's the
auto flower it'll it'll flower under 24
hours of light the photo period plant is
flowering based on relative day length
so what we found so we created the first
in North America the first autoflowering
CBD plant in 2016 and created the first
Auto flower photo period hybrids in 2016
as well did a bunch of field trials in
late 2016 and then again in 2017 to
demonstrate the efficacy of combining
these two distinct germ plasm lines and
what we found was was really interesting
and driven home in 2018 even more so
when you take these hybrids containing a
out of an auto flower gene and a photo
period gene when you take these hybrids
anywhere in the country they all react
to photo period changes in exactly the
same way at exactly the same time
there's some slight variations depending
on which photo period gene you have but
what it looks like is that these early
flowering hybrids you can clone them you
can you can maintain them but they they
go into flower roughly two weeks after
the peak of summer so early July across
the country all of these these plants go
into flower and what it looks like based
on the literature is that this is uh
basically creating a little bit more
sensitivity to a shift in red light
spectrum so the plants pick up on that
and go into flower so some some pretty
good examples in the literature about
mechanisms and other model organisms
using these same genes but we just
happen to pick up on it and be able to
use this in our hybridization process to
be able to create these F ones that are
predictable in flower timing across the
country and that's a huge advantage to
farmers you know what folks figured out
after the first couple years is that if
you have a plant line that was developed
in Colorado and flowers consistently and
you know it's done by early October if
you take that to a different photo
period regime like Florida or Vermont or
Oregon the plants respond in a in a very
different way and you'll end up you know
not finishing until December in Oregon
so being able to have that predictable
flowering time is a huge benefit to
farmers and one of those great examples
of where more knowledge that gets
generated by everybody who's engaged in
this process in the cannabis space ends
up leading to much better much better
products and better outcomes for farmers
and again this is particularly useful
for outdoor cultivation which the
correct me if I'm wrong is much more
common in the hemp space than the
cannabis space and why is that a cost of
production it's free sunlight free free
soil for the most part the cost of
production outside is much much lower
than in the indoor space and it's long
to be perfectly honest the only reason
why indoor cannabis is still grown
outside of producing seed for
large-scale farmers on the THC side it's
only because of prohibition as soon as
you drop that that requirement and you
know strange requirements like you know
12-foot tall fences or an enclosed space
and those sorts of things the total cost
to produce outside just makes it much
much more likely that people will be
engaging in that type of production
behavior now so it organ CBD you guys
seem particularly focused on you know
resinous big buds producing cannabinoids
and terpenoids for you know whether it
be supplements or pharmaceutical
applications are you guys interested at
all in maybe going after the other
markets of you know using hemp as a
fabric a plastic a fuel building
material anything like that yeah very
much so although you know the the main
the main take-home message on this is
that other countries because they had
legalized industrial hemp ahead of the
United States I think they're a little
further along and in terms of their
breeding programs for things like fiber
or seed I think I think that we have the
tools to be able to catch up relatively
quickly and some of the things that
we're really excited about for 2021 is
being able to introduce new varieties
that can
do those things particularly on the seed
side for for a consuming seed as a
protein source as a basically as a
nutritional supplement in and of itself
as a food and then also being able to
grow your cannabinoid rich crop right
next to that and being able to safely do
that without having any seeding yeah
that was one thing I wanted to ask you
about because I if I remember correctly
your you had an Instagram post sort of
about being being good neighbors and
being careful not to grow male hemp
outside so I was wondering if you could
kind of talk about some of the dangers
that come with with that yeah if your if
your crop gets seated you're gonna lose
30% of your overall cannabinoid content
you're gonna lose 50% of the weight of
your crop just because the plant is
putting all of its energy into seed
production rather than cannabinoid or
floral tissue production hugely hugely
problematic it makes the production of
certified seed outside also very
difficult number of different issues
that come along with it that farmers
really you know at the end of the day
they're just trying to grow a crop
that's going to make them money and it's
going to benefit people and it's it's
something extra that they shouldn't
necessarily have to worry about we are
very confident that in 2021 we're going
to be able to release seed lines that
make that concern obsolete we've figured
out a way to get around that and the
results we're so excited about this the
result is I think going to push forward
the envelope of what people even
consider possible with cannabis it's the
early results that we're seeing in our
experiments are the most resinous the
most pleasant smelling most vigorous
plants that we've ever experienced and
we've been growing cannabis for pretty
close to 20 years now just amazing
evolutionary jumps forward and we're
really excited to be able to talk about
this
in depth at can med 20/20 well that's a
great place to stop if I ever heard one
but before I let you go I want to give
you a chance to plug your website or
social media or anything where can
people learn more about you and Oregon
CBD yeah our website is Oregon CBD seeds
calm and we are on Instagram and
Facebook as Oregon's CBD were 41 strong
scientists plant propagators folks that
are taking care of greenhouses we've got
a great company family owned and
operated and we're just really excited
to be providing farmers with quality
seeds that they can depend on excellent
like I said where we're more than happy
to have you and we're happy to work with
oregon CBD where as you know a family
operation over here as well and i think
we kind of see ourselves as sort of cut
from the same cloth in the regard that
we both try to do what we can with good
science and good old-fashioned hard work
so again happy to have you as part of
kim at 2020 and we'll see you out and
pasadena this fall sounds great thanks
for having me Ben
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed my conversation with
Seth Crawford I always learned so much
talking check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed and please also
check out oregon CBD seeds calm the
oregon CBD team has added some great
content resources lately and they're
definitely worth a read next episode we
welcome Brianna Cassidy of CDX analytics
Brianna is the lab director at CVX a
full-service cannabis testing lab in my
hometown of Salem Massachusetts we
discussed the challenges that come with
testing cannabis flower including
sampling bias and the lack of
standardized methods Brianna also shares
her approach for evaluating new testing
technologies a topic she will explore in
more detail at chem med 2020 that
episode will drop June 24th - week from
this episode in the meantime please go
to CAD med events comm slash coffee talk
and sign up for email updates that will
enter you into a drawing to win two
tickets to our kin med 2020 B IP dinner
and keep you up to date with all things
can med 2020 if social media is your
thing you can find us on Facebook
Instagram Twitter and LinkedIn just
search for kin net events and lastly if
you are listening on a podcast app go
ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device and if you want to leave
us a five star review that'd be great
too alright that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to come back
for the next episode of kin med coffee
Talk
[Music]