[Music]
uh
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science medicine cultivation
and safety testing
i am your host ben ameralt i am the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and a proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
every year head over to kim at events
dot com now to learn all about
our canmed 2021 event that will take
place
april 12th through 14th at the pasadena
convention center
in pasadena california and get your
tickets today at our special
early bird rate while you're at
kments.com please be sure to sign up for
email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry leading event
and the best place to do that is on our
podcast page
which you can find in the main menu
under the media tab
or you can go there directly by going to
canmedevents.com
coffeetalk there is a sign up form on
that page
and if you complete it you will be
entered into a drawing to win
two cam ed 2021 vip dinner tickets
while you're on that page you can also
listen to all 13
canmed coffee talk podcast episodes
in our archive our 14th guest on the
canmed coffee talk podcast
is jordan zager co-founder and ceo of
dewey scientific
jordan is an expert in cannabis genetics
and
natural product biosynthesis having
authored multiple research papers
in the fields of trichome development
and metabolism
mathematical modeling of biochemical
pathways
and functional genomics jordan's canmed
2021 presentation
will explore the biochemical processes
the cannabis plant uses to create
cannabinoids
and how each cultivar's unique genetics
plays a role
topics we hit on the conversation
include the problems cannabis and hemp
growers are trying to solve via genetics
how lighting in temperature
influences gene expression in cannabis
plants
and the cannabinoids and terpenes they
produce the potential for minor
cannabinoids to become more dominant in
future cultivars
and just how far behind cannabis
genomics research is
when compared to other crops before we
get to that conversation
i do want to thank this episode's
sponsor the scientist magazine
the scientist is a seriously refreshing
source of life science research news
and a forum for in-depth exploration of
issues
important to both scientists and the
science curious public
we tell life science stories that
researchers and science enthusiasts
want while delivering indispensable
information
on discovery policy publishing
careers ethics and more visit
the scientist.com to learn more
and finally i want to thank the hemp in
coffee exchange
for providing the hemp infused caffeine
boost that keeps this podcast going
if you don't know hemp coffee is a
healthy delicious
natural product rich in trace minerals
and nutrients
providing sustained energy without the
crash of regular coffee
for more information check out
hempcoffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
off your purchase okay as promised
here's my conversation with jordan zager
of dewey scientific
[Music]
hey jordan thanks for joining us here on
the on the podcast how are you doing
today
i'm doing pretty good thanks for having
me excellent and we're
we're really excited to have you this
year at canmed 2020. now is this going
to be the first candid that you attended
this will be my first candid that's
right um and i hadn't even heard about
it
until you know last year i was at a
conference
um where kevin gave a talk kevin
mckiernan your cso
um and it was promoting it pretty hard i
looked into it and yeah it definitely
looked like a conference that uh
i'd be interested in going to the future
and
what do i know you guys asked me to
present so i'm very pleased to join
canva this year
yeah we're excited um especially since
your your focus is very similar to ours
so you're
very much investigating the genomics and
the genetics of the cannabis plant and
why i'm really excited to talk to you is
because you're actually applying that
genomic information and
actually applying it to the plant you
know us here at medicinal genomics
we're sequencing the plant finding all
sorts of interesting markers and
interesting insights into the plant but
we don't we don't grow here
so we don't really get to apply it so
i'm always interested to talk to folks
who are actually
working with the plants um
i don't know if you want to give a
little insight into what you guys are
doing there
at dewey scientific yeah so dewey
scientific
um first and foremost we are a
biotechnology company focused on
bettering the cannabis industry
and we're doing that through a couple of
of ways the first is through our
scientific service offerings so what we
do there is we sort of offer
cultivators or other breeders
um a science team you know if you look
at some of the bigger companies they're
starting to swallow up
um scientists but not every cannabis
company can afford to do that so we sort
of
uh offer you know we have a traveling
team of scientists that will
will uh come to you and collect the data
we need and then do all the data
analysis here and sort of
make sense of you know the overwhelming
amount of data that genomics can provide
and the second aspect of what we're
doing is we have uh an in-house breeding
program
with um with one of our very close
partners actually so dewey scientific
we don't grow the plants ourselves we
just have very close partners that do um
and for them you know we have a
quantitative geneticist part of our team
actually our co-founder and uh
vp of research paul mahalov he
he's our breeder and he you know can
really
make sense of you know a vcf file while
not everybody really
necessarily know what that means um it's
it's you know the variants that are
present in a genome so he
he's has a lot of experiences with using
that kind of data
and applying it to breeding for specific
traits
excellent so when a client engages with
your team
what are they really looking to
accomplish or do they even know
um yeah i think for the most part they
do know what they're looking for
accomplish
to accomplish they just don't
necessarily have to get there
so for example we've worked with some
some cultivators in the hemp space
and last year we we helped them identify
when they should be harvesting
you know if you wait too long all of a
sudden your compliant half crop
is no longer compliant um and you have
to destroy
your summer's worth of labor um and you
know that
unfortunately that that was the reality
last year for many growers so
just knowing knowing the plants are
growing at a better level
can really make the difference for
farmers and that's that's what we've
been helping people do
yeah and that's an interesting point you
make because there were there were tons
of articles that came out
the end of last year with a lot of hemp
farmers who
suddenly discovered that what they were
growing wasn't technically hemp because
it was it was testing hop or thc so do
you offer some services to
to hemp cultivators who are maybe just
starting it to get into this to make
sure that
what they're actually planting is going
to be what they expect it to be at the
end
yeah that's that's an area that we're
looking to get in
um this year we're working with a couple
partners out in the yakima valley area
of washington state
um helping them choose the genetics that
they will be growing this year
um and you know more than anything uh
it's it's just sort of doing the leg
work uh and doing the background check
on where the seats coming from or where
the clones coming from
is this a fly by night clone provider
like we saw
so many last year or do these guys have
legitimate coas backing up what they're
claiming to have
being sold yeah and unfortunately that
seems to be such a
such a trend in the cannabis industry as
these fly-by-nights
uh companies not just clone providers or
seed providers but
i mean we see it in our end too um so
it's it's nice to see
folks like you out there kind of helping
to
to weed that out for lack of a better
term um
so that's great so yeah i and i guess
the segue to that is
i mean there are other companies out
there that are offering similar services
um to what you guys are so kind of what
sets you apart
so yeah we like to take a slightly
different approach than most
folks we actually take an rna-based
approach towards genomics
we prefer this approach because you can
answer many questions with a single data
set
um you know because this plant has so
many
there's so much genetic diversity in
what's out there right now relying on a
single reference genome
um can be a little problematic so we we
prefer to take a de novo
transcriptome approach um and so when we
take that you know we can still get
all the necessary structural genome
genomic structural information we need
we can identify snips across the the
expressed genome if you will which is
the transcriptome
and then we can look at you know we not
only gain insight into which genes are
present but we
get insight into how
hard those genes are turned on or turned
off
and this is particularly important when
it comes to cannabinoid or terpenoid
biosynthesis
so it just gives you a comprehensive
view of what's going on in your growing
plants
interesting and that kind of brings me
to one of the things i want to bring up
to you is this whole idea of nature
versus nurture
you know you can have all this genetic
potential in a cultivar but you know
what environment you put it in
is gonna you know determine what
actually gets expressed so now you're
taking an rna-based approach does that
sort of
help sort of weed that out as far as
what's actually being expressed and what
phenotype you're actually going to see
yeah absolutely so that's that's uh one
area of emphasis we're looking to expand
on is
how are the varieties that you purchased
or the varieties that you
uh bred how are they actually performing
in your
grow area whether you know you're a hemp
farmer on 50 acres or you're a
adult use cannabis producer in a
warehouse
you know we can sort of look at the
genetic performance of your variety
in action that's excellent and now do
you have any
any sort of data on that are certain
grow mediums or certain
light sources able to um
well i guess lack of a better term
express genes more than others
yeah i wouldn't say we've seen much
difference with grow mediums
nor is that really something that we've
really monitored
but lighting has a huge influence
temperature hasn't has a huge influence
so you know if we're talking about
cannabinoid synthases it's really
important um
to know the the temperature and the
light influence
um on that the plants are receiving you
know a change in
temperature or ph can change the
function of a cannabinoid
synthase and when it comes to terpenoid
synthases
these are our genes that are
highly regulated by light
you know and the type of light that they
get so you know you could you could have
one variety growing
in a say a grow room uh all with high
pressure sodium bulbs
and you move that over to a grow room
that has leds
well you're changing the light influence
and you're more likely than not
changing the terpene profile and sort of
changing the
the chemotype of that plant so it just
can lead to inconsistencies in what
farmers think they're growing and what
they think they're going to end up
producing
now is that strain specific are are
certain strains more
sensitive to that than others um not
that we've seen
um just terpene expression um
in in all plants is just very
sensitive to to light um
especially the expression of those genes
so what's the preferred light source um
you know we haven't done quite enough
work yet to determine that
um but i think it's it's uh
it's more of looking at
the the germplasm collection you have
and
and seeing how it's performing in your
your grow setup and whether it's attempt
or adult use
okay and you mentioned earlier that you
know cannabis being
so genetically diverse and i always
wonder
you know do we fully understand the full
genetic potential of cannabis like
through efforts like yours and continued
breeding could we end up
kind of seeing cultivars that are
radically different than what's out
there now
yeah i absolutely think we can see
varieties in cultivars
or rice that aren't out there right now
you know because the majority of this
crop was
was grown in backyards and basements and
deep in the woods
for so long you know
we're just a ways off uh compared to
other other crops
um and so to you know fully understand
the genetic potential
i think um you know a concerted effort
needs to be made into
stabilizing these genetics because you
know
when you are well sort of what we did
we do a scientific but we the the
cannabis community as a whole was we we
sort of drove evolution in certain
directions
based on what certain people were
selecting for in various regions
of the country
right and so have you done any research
or analysis into sort of land race
type strains to see you know without the
the breeder's hand sort of what cannabis
can become
yeah so we've sort of um we've looked at
a
couple of land race varieties one of
which was featured in our
our plant physiology publication last
year
um it was a variety called mama thai and
reportedly this was a variety came
straight from thailand
it was grown in a light deprivation hoop
house most of the plants in there were
about five feet tall
but this this mama tie was about eight
feet tall
um and then when we looked at the the
chemo print or the chemotype of the
plant the metabolic fingerprint
um you know it did vary quite a bit from
the other varieties it was a lot more
heavy on sesquiterpenes
what the implications are that are i'm
not really sure yet
but it was notably different from the
things that had been
you know grown or bred for uh
over here in the u.s interesting
and now we are i mean we all know that
you know thc and cbd are sort of the
dominant cannabinoids that we see in the
in the cultivars that are out there now
could and that the other cannabinoids
are very much present at
at small kind of trace levels but is
there an opportunity to kind of
flip that script and and kind of see
these minor cannabinoids take a bigger
percentage
i i think so you know i think one area
of interest right now are the variants
um you know so they they just have a
different fatty acid precursor
towards cannabinoid biosynthesis
thcv and cbdb
you know i don't think that was really
on anyone's radar in you know
much much past the last five years um so
i think as as breeders start to
go down that route i mean these are
these are stemming from um
you know they're not cannabinoid
synthases that are responsible for this
difference
um it's it's upstream in the
you know areas of fatty acid
biosynthesis
so i think it's going to be interesting
to see but i do think you know some of
the
more minor cannabinoids are going to uh
rise in prevalence
in the coming years right um
any predictions as far as what's the
what's going to be the new hot
cannabinoid
oh man i don't know i think um in terms
of new
i think folks need to be
careful with what is being described as
new
or or where it's found or if it's
even actually produced by the plant and
not an artifact of
sample prep or
just a faulty hplc run or something like
that
i don't want to make any predictions on
what the markets are going to
prefer in the future but i do think that
as as we learn more about the different
cannabinoids
and maybe start to tie those in with
some some clinical studies
about the pharmaco uh kinetics of these
cannabinoids um i think that's
ultimately what's going to drive what's
hot is
what's coming out of the medical
research yeah
and i guess to bring that all back to to
what we're doing here at canmed i think
that's a
a great reason why folks like yourself
and cultivators and
and others in the industry could really
get a lot out of out of coming to the
conferences that
we're going to have a lot of the the
latest research
into applying cannabinoids for different
medical conditions so if there is some
breaking research
um on a new minor cannabinoid you'll be
the first to know about it so
it's a good thing you decided to join us
this year
i'm glad i did um and so i want to go
back to
you said that you know the cannabis
plant is so far behind
other plants in terms of understanding
the genomics
i mean if you were to make an analogy
how how far behind
are we really you know if
let's make a comparison to american
legacy crops like soy or corn or wheat
you know they've they've been
playing with um you know the the
genomics of these these crops have been
known for let's say 30 years
um prior to
when cannabis actually started to get
some some you know molecular
type of work done on it um you know the
genomes of the
these plants obviously haven't worked
sequence 30 years ago but they were
sequenced you know
closer to 20 years ago whereas the first
cannabis variety
was sequenced uh about nine years ago
um with a lot more coming up in the last
few years
but with all of those crops they've been
genetically stabilized you know you
a farmer goes and buys pounds of wheat
seed well they expect that
field to grow uniformly there's not
going to be differences in
in height or uh you know club length
um within their batch of seeds whereas
you know with cannabis we just
aren't quite there with the genetic
stabilization so
it just makes it harder to understand
the genomics of cannabis because of the
the diversity and the lack of
stabilization that's occurred
well that's interesting and so is
the fact that cannabis is so diverse
just because
there hasn't been such a stabilization
effort or is it something that's
that's unique to the plant um i don't
think it's something that's unique to
the plant
but i do think that well
i think one reason that that
stabilization has not really occurred is
that the plant suffers from
inbreeding depression which is you know
a very real threat
towards you know making a stabilized
variety
but it's it's been overcome in the past
with other deployed
deployed crops but
inbreeding depression i'm not i'm not
familiar with that so that's
that's yeah so it's it's if you uh you
know in breed within a family
um it's most popularly seen or known
i should say it's not really seen
anymore uh with humans you know
um lineages of royal families from
europe you know there was
evidence of well um cousins were made
cousins uncles were marrying their
nieces things like that
um led to genetic disorders and genetic
effects
in the their progeny or their their
children
and you see the same thing with cannabis
and it takes a couple of generations
but you know once you're at the the
point of you know four or five
generations of inbreeding the plant
starts to display
um problems and growth uh in development
so
to overcome that in cannabis i mean it's
it's really a numbers game
not every single inbred plant is gonna
have these these issues
so it's a matter of doing it enough
within the same family to identify
those that are not suffering from
inbreeding depression
wow that's interesting so one of my
questions i was going to ask you is
i guess to start i mean a lot of
commercial cannabis cultivation now
is done through cloning clonal
propagation
do you ever expect we'll get to a place
where we could
have stable enough seeds that um
that seed propagation would become the
norm
it sounds like that would be a challenge
with this inbreeding depression now
um you know i think we're starting to
see it on the hemp side of things
a lot more producers are going from seed
than from clone
and yeah i absolutely think we'll get to
a point where commercial cannabis are
growing from seed
you know if you're going from from clone
ultimately it comes down to the bottom
line
but you know it's it's my point of view
that um
seed is a much more automatable process
than than clones you know um
and so there are a lot of hurdles that
need to be cleared
but you know i think it's all about
genetic stabilization and ensuring that
your crop will grow with uniformity and
you can rely on
your expected results of that crop you
know that
these plants are going to grow in
uniform they're all going to have very
similar
chemotype profiles and that they they
are all going to have
relatively similar yield numbers
and they're all going to be female for
the most part too right yeah i mean
that's
that was you know a big topic in 2019
when people were buying what they
thought were feminized seeds
turns out they weren't um their crops
got pollinated and
you know you see a tenfold reduction in
cannabinoid production
um and you know i think this year those
uh farmers who learned a lesson last
year they're
absolutely going to look specifically
for feminized seeds from a
reputable source
you know i think the adult use industry
will get there but because of the the
fragmentation we've seen from state to
state
um clones are going to remain prevalent
for the time being
all right so so we talked about what
cannabinoids
that breeders and growers might be
interested in selecting for but
are there other genetic markers that you
think could make a
huge impact on cannabis cultivation
yeah i think you know if we we go back
to cannabinoids really quickly it's um
you know a lot of these cannabinoids
synthases are leaky
um so if we can better characterize
those and develop markers
um around those regions of the gene that
may lead to a leaky synthase
versus a non-leaky synthase i think that
will go a long way
but outside of cannabinoids you know i
do believe the the metabolic pathways
um that are responsible for other
bioactive compounds that cannabis
produces like the terpenes like the
flavonoids
you know if we can uh design genetic
markers
based on on the production of those
compounds you know that will
ultimately initially help the the
medical field
so so breeders can produce varieties
that are more predictable
in their their overall chemotype not
just cannabinoids but
in these other bioactive compounds that
might
might be playing a role in the uh
the medical properties medicinal
properties of cannabis
excellent and this will probably be a
great segue into the topic that you're
going to be presenting on at canmed
which is
gene networks underlying cannabinoid and
terpenoid accumulation
in cannabis so i was wondering can you
give us a little
a little preview of what the folks can
expect yeah
yeah so this my talk is is largely based
around
a paper that we had published in
may of 2019 with the same title as the
talk
but basically um it you know comes down
to that
chemical profiling is currently employed
and it's a
is a fairly powerful tool in
differentiating one strain from the next
but you know if you add genotyping
information uh whether that be
you know a static genetic level or at a
transcriptome level
it's just going to increase the
resolution of differentiating one strain
from the next and then that ultimately
helps
um you know clinical researchers if if
uh with their work you know
is it a certain compound that is uh you
know
leading to an effect is it is it five
compounds is it
uh dozens of compounds that are leading
to an effect
um and really you know with it with this
with this research
um we took an approach that's been used
um in many a number of crops you know
including alfalfa corn and wheat
and it's been been successful
but really you know it just sort of puts
everything into a functional context
you know what what what are the
functions that are active in the plant
as it's
as it's growing and ultimately before
it's harvested
excellent no and one of the things you
mentioned there that that reminded me
was
when you're talking about sort of the
the different combination of
cannabinoids could be used for a
specific treatment
um david miri spoke at last year's
canmed and he was talking about the
research that he's doing in his lab in
israel which is just fascinating
and they were they were finding that um
it was a combination of
three cannabinoids that they were using
to to treat this specific type of cancer
and it was when those three were present
that they would see the effect
if you took away any one of them or i
believe if i remember correctly even
added an additional one it did not work
so it's pretty fascinating this whole
idea of the entourage effect how that
actually is is being applied
yeah absolutely and you know i think us
on the plant side of things
um we just need to be uh
more responsible with with what we're
putting out there
and just so you know users can have a
better idea of what they're
they're consuming um and ultimate and
you know beyond that what researchers
are
actually testing um for you know whether
it's cancer or alzheimer's or epilepsy
um these types of
clinical trials can only benefit from a
more precise understanding of what that
plant is capable of and what it is
actively producing excellent and now you
mentioned that you
had published a paper on the on that
same topic the one you're going to be
discussing at cam
where can folks find that yeah so that's
that's available um at plant
physiology.org
um it is an open source paper so you
don't have to worry about a uh
a pay to read firewall that is common in
academic papers
but yeah it's available at
plantphysiology.org
excellent excellent um and then you want
to tell the folks where they can
find out more about dewey scientific and
yeah more about you absolutely if you're
interested in doing scientific
dewey scientific.com um deweyside.com
we'll get you there as well
we are active on uh twitter linkedin and
instagram
um and yeah we're always always happy to
answer questions and help
cultivators know more about their growth
and ultimately improve the economics of
their
facilities all right excellent well
thank you jordan again for taking the
time to talk to us today
we'll be in touch and we will definitely
see you out in pasadena
all right thanks man i appreciate the
[Music]
time
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
jordan zager
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and please also check out our sponsors
the scientist magazine
and the hemp coffee exchange our next
episode will drop
october 14th in the meantime please go
to canmanevents.com
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you into a drawing to
win two tickets to our canmed 2021 vip
dinner
and keep you up to date on all things
canmed2021
give us a follow on social media too we
are on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for cam at events
and lastly if you're listening via a
podcast app
you can subscribe to our feed so that
new episodes automatically download to
your device
and if you like what you hear please
leave us a 5 star review
alright that's it from us stay safe stay
healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of can med coffee talk
[Music]
you