[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast where we talk with the leading
minds in cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
who will be taking part
at the canmed 2021 event this
april 12th through 14th at the pasadena
convention center
in pasadena california i am your host
ben amrald i'm the marketing manager at
medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
every year head over to canmedevents.com
to learn all about the camed 2021 event
and get your tickets at our special
early bird rate
while you're at kim at events.com be
sure to sign up for email alerts
to stay up to date with all the news
surrounding this industry-leading event
we still have our safety keynote panel
discussions and additional oral
presenters to announce
along with some other surprises and
here's a special tip
if you sign up using the form on our
podcast page
can events dot com slash coffee talk you
will be entered to win two tickets to
the canmed
vip dinner you will also find all the
previous episodes of the canmed coffee
talk podcast there as well
so it's a good page to check out this
episode's guest is plant pathology
expert dr
zamir punja of simon fraser university's
department
of biological sciences zamir's research
investigates the causes and management
of plant diseases
on cannabis and hemp including fusarium
penicillium
powdery mildew botrytis as well as other
new and emerging plant pathogens
his kmed 2018 presentation featured
several amazing images
zamir's team captured using an electron
microscope
the image of powdery mildew mycelia
wrapped around a cannabis trichome
is one i won't soon forget be sure to
check out the link to that video in the
show description
in addition to his work on plant
diseases zamir's team has used their
electron microscope to investigate the
structure
of cannabis trichomes and will present
those findings at cam ed 2021
i expect we will see even more amazing
images during that presentation
in fact zamir gave us a few sneak peek
preview images
that i've included in the show
description
topics discussed on the podcast include
how diseases
infect and affect cannabis plants
which cultivation methods are more prone
to infection
how to breed for pathogen resistance
which pathogens pose a risk to consumers
and how each of the four observed
cannabis trichome structures differ
and what each might be responsible for
before we get to my conversation
with samir i want to thank this
episode's sponsor the growers network
growers network is committed to
providing the highest quality cannabis
content
education and resources be sure to check
out their canna crib series
your behind-the-scenes look at some of
the most sophisticated
and technologically advanced growers in
the world
visit them at youtube.com growers
network
and finally this episode of the canmed
coffee talk podcast
is fueled by the hemp and coffee
exchange
hemp coffee is a healthy delicious
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing
sustained energy without the crash of
regular coffee
for more information check out hemp
coffee exchange dot com
and use the promo code drink hemp to get
10 off your purchase
okay without any further ado please
enjoy my conversation with dr zamir
punja
[Music]
good afternoon samir thanks for joining
us
oh thanks ben it's a pleasure to be here
and talk to you
absolutely and i'm really excited to
talk with you today because
i know you've done a lot of research
into plant pathogens
excuse me plant pathogens and diseases
that affect the cannabis plant
and coincidentally our team here at
medicinal genomics has developed
some qpcr dna based tests that can
identify some of the very same species
you've worked on so although i'm
familiar with some of the species and
i've read about how they can
affect the cannabis plant we don't get
to work with any actual plants here
in our lab like you do so i'm really
interested in getting your
perspective it's really fascinating to
me
so um with that i think maybe a great
place to start is with fusarium because
i know that your team
recently published uh two two papers on
that fungi
so um i was wondering can you tell us a
bit about fusarium and how it affects
the cannabis plant
yeah thanks so we started working on
these various diseases about
four years ago and the first thing we
did was conduct
surveys of a range of different
producers out here in
in primarily in british columbia
although we did get a chance to get some
samples from back east in ontario
and the first disease that popped out uh
the one that was the most visible was
fiserium
and on the plants on flowering plants
fusarium will show up as
sort of a yellowing of the lower leaves
which is then followed by
in many cases wilting and eventually if
the disease progresses
it it'll kill the plants so in many
other crops it's referred to as
physiorum yellows
but what we saw in cannabis was more or
less a root infection
and a crown infection and so when you
see a plant that's yellowing that's that
that's wilting
if you examine the the roots they're
going to be brown uh some of them
may be rotted off and then if you look
at the crown you'll see sort of a
pinkish orange
maybe even a dark brown discoloration
that would indicate that it is
it is a fusarium so you see on on those
flowering plants but even more
importantly we found it on vegetatively
propagated cuttings so
you know a lot of growers obviously
start their plants from cuttings and
and in fusarium we saw a lot of damping
off
and so in other words rather than the
cuttings going ahead and rooting
they were starting to literally fall
over uh
and they rotted and that came as a
surprise to us and so when we isolated
from there we found a lot of fusarium
and going back to your earlier point the
main species is fusarium oxysporum
which is the the fusarium that causes a
lot of wilt in in many other plants like
tomatoes and
and basil and lettuce um in addition we
found
solana solana is the one that sort of
causes more of the damping off and there
and the root rot and then the third
species that we found just recently this
past
year was fusarium polypherotum and that
one actually moves up the plant it
actually
causes the crown infection but then you
start seeing discoloration
pretty much all the way to the top and
so
those three species you can sort of tell
by looking whether it's a crown
infection a root infection or whether
it's progressing up the plant but
i think as you mentioned the diagnostic
the pcr diagnostic tests are going to be
the most accurate
in telling which of those three species
are actually present
uh in a crop now you mentioned that
in flowering it can kind of present as
having yellowing leaves um
are there signs and symptoms that can be
visible
sort of before that flowering stage
the the only symptom i would say is a
stunting so in other words your plants
haven't grown to the same height that
they should have
they they don't look like they're you
know really happy maybe they you think
it might be a fertilizer problem
uh it ends up that it's actually
physarium that's infected the roots and
potentially started infecting the crown
interesting and you're saying that you
know cuttings can obviously take the
if a mother plant is infected can kind
of take it into the cuttings
would the mother plants really be
showing any signs and symptoms
or is that sort of is that sort of the
problem
so that that's where the problem
actually started the mother plants tend
to not show any symptoms
and so we think that fusarium originated
i don't know many years ago even before
we started sampling
four years ago from mother plants or
disease plants that were maybe passed
along
from one grower to another or from from
one friend to another
unknowingly that they already had some
fusarium probably in the roots or maybe
in the crown
and then those mothers are grown up and
if they're really diseased you will get
the mothers dying
they will collapse and obviously then
you know it's time to get rid of them
but if you don't don't see those
symptoms and you take cuts from them
you have the you run the risk of
actually transmitting fusarium into the
next crop
and i suppose and you can correct me if
i'm wrong but if if you did have a
an otherwise healthy mother plant that
develops the
infection later on in life you wouldn't
really see that
that stunting on the initial growing
phase
is that fair to say yes correct
um and and you know it's it's hard to
tell when a mother is is
well too old if i can say that we tend
to recommend
mother plants be tossed out after six
months to a year
and not keep them for four or five years
as some some producers might be doing
at that stage i think you might start
seeing symptoms of yellowing and
and stunting in which case you know it's
time to get rid of them
right and i know that it's it's not
uncommon for
a flowering plant to sort of you know
have some yellowing leaves as
it sort of directs more nutrients into
creating buds and things like that so
is there more of a a telltale sign of
you know what's
kind of typical yellowing versus a
fusarium infection
yeah so most of the the most of the
infections that we do see
that are quite severe would probably be
within the first two weeks of flower
that's when the plant is producing you
know trying to get a lot of its its
energy into the flowering phase
and it puts a lot of stress on those on
that particular plant
and that's when you start seeing the
yellowing and the wilting
and in many cases those plants actually
die before they get into full flower
so when you've got a plant that's in
full flower and it may be showing a
little bit of yellowing here and there
that could just be nutrition or
environmental stress or something else
if it's fusarium it's probably going to
go down within the first three weeks of
flower
wow and now is there anything you can do
once once you've identified a fusion
infection
yeah so the first place to start is with
the cuttings um
if you know your mom your mother plants
are clean or there's a way to test those
we actually haven't
haven't developed the testing method yet
to test the mothers to see if they're
carrying fusarium and
part of it is you know the plants are
large and and we don't know what part to
actually sample for the for the analysis
but if you're you know if you know the
the history of the mother plant
and you're you're you know it's a good
source and it's clean
um the first place to test would be the
cuttings so cuttings start
dying they're not rooting well it could
be fusarium
present there um we're looking at a
number of biological control agents
that are registered so for example
trichoderma
gliocladium there's products out there
that
are quite effective in keeping the
fusarium on the cuttings at bay
provided they're added early so in other
words once the cuts are made
the cuts could either be dipped in
fusarium or sorry in
in the trichoderma or the the
gliocladium
or you can apply a drench before the
cuttings are actually rooted to actually
prevent the infection from getting in
and now so how big or widespread is um
is the fusamur fusarium problem is it
something that's pretty common
in cannabis cultivation
yeah so it's interesting uh the short
answer to that is the more we look the
more we find
um i think i would i would have to say
out of the 12 or 15
commercial producers i've sampled every
one of them had
uh either very very trace amounts of
fusarium to
fusarium in about 30 of their plants so
i i think it's it's there uh it's had a
chance to sort of move around
and depending on the the variety or the
strain depending on the growing
conditions
it may or may not be a major problem or
end up it could end up being a major
problem
um in some grower growth facilities
yeah and you bring up an interesting
point so do
environmental conditions kind of play a
role in this i know that
you know for example with powdery mildew
um
you know if humidity is really high that
tends to
to breed more powdery mildew where if
you have sort of your levels in check
it's
it's less of an issue is there a similar
kind of trigger
environmental trigger for cerium
um so fusarium it you know it grows over
a pretty wide range
anyway from 20 to 30 degrees celsius or
you're looking at 75 to 90
90 degrees fahrenheit i would say
overall that as it gets warmer
as you start hitting the the seven the
90 to 95 degree
range uh physiom can be quite a bit
worse
than it would be at lower temperatures
it also seems to like
moisture and of course that's kind of
hard to avoid because we tend to you
know really water the plants and make
sure the cuts
are well watered freezer and will grow
and actually it'll spread
with water so you can have spores moving
from
let's say a propagation room where
you've got cuttings uh into an
adjoining room if the water is being
recirculated you can actually get fuseum
spores moving from one location to
another
wow and i know you you mentioned that
there could be some treatments that you
do to the cuttings after you take them
from the mother to sort of maybe
prevent an infection but so say you
already are a few weeks into
uh flowering and you're seeing those
signs and it looks
it doesn't look good is it a lost cause
at that point or is there anything you
can do to sort of salvage that plant
yeah i know i would go in and pull those
plants out particularly the ones that
are yellowing and starting to weld
there's always a concern that as the
fusarium develops on the roots
and the crowns it's going to produce a
lot of spores
uh and and if you've got plants let's
say sitting on the same table or in the
same growing area
you could have spread as i mentioned in
the water
but interesting enough it also moves in
the air so if you've got
fans moving spores back and forth you
could actually be moving
uh inoculum from that disease plant or
disease plants into other areas in the
growing room so
my recommendation plants look bad
they're yellowing
grab them take them out bag them and and
toss them
well that's interesting so does that
mean that like spores could
even infect maybe if there were some
plants that were further
further in their development they have
full flowers could it actually infect
the flowers themselves
okay so yeah so that's a good news bad
news story the good news is that
uh if the spores do move around they
will not infect
uh plants uh at flower or even at a
younger stage this fusarium seems to
like to get in early
so it'll get in with the cuttings it
might get in that in the vegetative
stage
but once you've sort of passed that uh
the plants seem to be
able to withstand the the um the
infection level so
if the plants have made it through at a
certain stage you're probably not going
to worry about freezer and moving around
too much from plant to plant
but we have found that if spores are
produced let's say there's a plant dying
and it's producing spores at the base at
the crown those spores once they get up
into the air
can actually infect flowers of a
neighboring plant so if you've got
plants a little bit further down
those spores can actually get up into
the flower head and establish themselves
uh in in the flower if the humidity is
right you know
if it's if it's really humid and if it's
hot
and so we've seen what we call fusarium
flower flower rot or fiserium bud rot
which in many ways looks a lot like
botrytis
but it's only when you isolate and
recover that you actually find out it's
not botrytis and it's actually fusarium
wow and now would that pose
any health harm or health risk to
consumers if uh flour was infected with
that
yeah so yeah so
and you're probably familiar with
fusarium head blight and cereals and
fusarium and corn
we know uh many of these species things
like physiomoxisporum can
produce mycotoxins and there is a risk
that that if you had severe infections
by fusarium
in the flowers that that could cause
certain mycotoxins to accumulate
because we've only just published those
two papers in the last month or so
i think the regulatory agencies and and
i think in general
the community hasn't quite recognized
that there is a potential for
uh physiorum species to infect the
flower again
it's not something that i would i would
necessarily raise a flag and say you
know this is the end of the
the cultivation of cannabis i think it's
a it's it's
it's there i think we're gonna find a
little bit of it i would say
maybe one percent of the flower could
have fusarium but
it's something that i think we need to
be aware of and certainly
um there should be screening methods for
detecting some of the specific
microtoxins produced by fusarium
yeah that's i mean that's really
interesting because i
i went back and i and i re-watched your
your lecture from canada 2018 where you
were talking about
a lot about fusarium and some of the
other pathogens that can affect cannabis
and the thing that stood out to me is
that you were mentioning that
penicillium which is another species
that can affect the plant um is sort of
a similar thing where it can
produce mycotoxins in the um in the
flower
and i know that you know regulatory
agencies aren't specifically looking for
um penicillium or fusarium um
they'd be kind of covered under the
total yeast and mold umbrella
but much like with with aspergillus
i mean unless you're specifically
looking for that it can sort of
get underneath that that total threshold
and
you know maybe actually be
posing a risk to consumers so that's a
little um a little concerning and maybe
something that regulatory agencies need
to take another look at
do you agree
yeah so uh you know you guys at
medicinal genomics were the first to
actually show that
some of these uh penicillium species
like penicillium citronym
and and others are potential microtoxin
producers i mean
this was was work that was published
three or four years ago by kevin and so
on
and his group and that sort of alerted
me to the fact that we should be
testing our our cannabis flower for for
penicillium as well
and sure enough we we found penicillium
it's
you know penicillium is everywhere uh
it's found uh in
in soil it's found on plant material
that's starting to
to decompose it's found in compost
it's found in people's homes like it's
not something that you necessarily can
can kind of eliminate from the growing
environment
but what tends to happen is when you've
got a lot of it building up so let's say
you've got
some plant material that's decaying and
producing a lot of spores or the floors
aren't necessarily kept very clean
or um the filtering system or uv
system isn't collecting all the spores
those penicillium spores land
on the flowers and they can stay there
and
after a while they can start growing and
producing more spores
which in turn can then maybe lead to
certain mycotoxins that are produced by
by the penicillium species so i know
penicillium is
is a big component of the overall yeast
and mole count
but as you mentioned all they do is
count numbers right so once you get you
you're under a certain limit you're good
to go but uh they could potentially be
mycotoxins building up in there
yeah no that's and and you
mentioned sort of if you have plant
material collecting and it
reminded me of that slide that you had
showed
of a plate that you had left out in a
trim room and just seeing the uh
the sheer amount of molds and things
that grew on that
um that was that was pretty
pretty shocking to see i i was shocked
when i when i saw that and
just to clarify there in the trim room
you know those those flowers and those
stems are really being agitated
um they're either going through some
mechanical de-stemming
process and that that physical
breakage of that plant material i think
is releasing a lot of spores
and they sort of they're sort of like
think of the cloud effect those clouds
are sort of moving up into the air so
when we put those plates out
when the spores landed back down onto
the plates and we had them out for about
an hour
they were just covered in penicillium
spores so
you know we're finding flowers that are
that are dried hang dried
and are not agitated to the same extent
as as buds that are pushed through
mechanical
um de-stemmers and and trimmers
um those that mechanical agitation is
causing more spores to build up on
product
than if you actually hang hand-dried
those those those stems
yeah and i have to imagine that if
you're a um if you're an employee there
you're you're breathing all that in
unless you're unless you're wearing a
mask and i'm not sure if they are
um i would think that if you're not
that's
something that you definitely want to
consider
yeah and that's the first recommendation
we made is is let's get those workers to
wear
um uh you know either n95 type mask so
masks that would have respiratory
abilities to take those spores out so
that their lungs are not exposed to
and it's not just the spores it's the
dust as well
right yeah masks they're they're
becoming
more and more common so i i wouldn't be
surprised if
folks adopted that for sure
and another thing that stood out from
that presentation was um you
actually looked at whether um
certain mediums were actually
contaminated and you were finding that
um
some uh coco coir that you had had
looked at was
was coming in contaminated that was that
was surprising to see as well
yeah and so you know uh you know again
the coca-cola is nothing more than
a plant material mostly fibrous plant
material that's
that's you know taken out of the cocoa
husk and and dried and
in some cases it's it's it's sterilized
and then it's sort of packaged in
in large bulks and shipped over from
overseas countries so
there's always a chance that microbes
and mold and other things can be carried
over
nothing you know nothing in particular
other than the penicillium and the
aspergilluses and so
on but once you place that cocoa in a
moist environment so you're wetting it
up and you're adding fertilizer
and you're using it as a growing
substrate that allows the
the residual spores that are in there to
start with to all of a sudden start
multiplying
and so what we were seeing is that when
you had those coco substrates um
spores were were being produced that we
were catching on these petri dishes that
we were laying out
and the concern was similar to the
fiserium concern
is that once they get up into the air
they could then land on these flowers
that are maturing or getting ready to be
harvested and then you're picking up the
spores that
that were building up as a result of the
substrate that you were using to grow
the plants in
right and that's not to say that
you know all all microbes are bad right
so there are
certainly beneficial microbes that that
may be present in
sort of an organic uh medium like that
as well right yeah and and so we've
actually sampled recently a lot of
organic
substrates and and as you mentioned the
organic growers tend to use soil
and soil is good uh in the sense that it
has a
much better buffering capacity against
pathogens than
let's say hydroponics or rockwool so
the on the positive side we're seeing
less disease develop
in in roots and crowns of plants that
are grown in soil
because you've got so much of that
buffering capacity
but we're finding more microbes in the
air in an organic production system
again going back to this idea that
soil has a lot of beneficials and other
microbes in there
more of them are getting into the air
then you would find perhaps in a
hydroponic or or
a system that uses is used as rock wool
the the concern the irony here is that
even these beneficial microbes let's say
coming out of organic systems
if they do land on these flowers they
would be rated again as a general
quality forming unit
it may actually cause a lot of the
product to fail and
and you know as a general rule and this
is just sort of a broad statement
a lot of the organic organic growers are
having problems passing their product
more so than than the guys that are
using hydroponic or rockwool
because of that background level of
microbes some of which are beneficial
getting onto the flower and causing the
plant the product to be rejected because
we don't discriminate right now between
the good and the bad
right and that's something that we see
on our end too because obviously we're
we're involved in kind of testing the
end product to make sure it doesn't have
that that contamination um
and yeah we we see cultivators that are
using
you know trichoderma as you mentioned
earlier and other these other beneficial
microbes that
you know might be testing hot for some
of these total count tests so
um i think it's great the work that
you're doing and others are doing to
sort of identify
what are these harmful pathogens that
are out there and
we can develop some species specific
type testing to make sure that
it's clean of that and sort of let the
beneficial stuff
go through obviously within reason
um yeah
yeah and i think the problem is it adds
an extra burden
on the on the companies that are testing
um because it's so much easier to just
say oh yeah ten to the four or ten to
the three
conforming units when you have to start
distinguishing between them
uh you need the pcr based type assays
that you guys are developing to say
okay it's a trichoderma or it's a
penicillium or it's an aspergillus or
it's something
in between and i think that's going to
be really important
and so i imagine that sort of the the
goal would be eventually to maybe
breed some varieties that have
resistance to some of these pathogens
whether it be fusarium or powdery mildew
or things like that
and in general how long does it take to
to sort of do that first of all and then
second do we even really have a full
picture of all the pathogens that can
potentially infect the plant
yeah so um with cannabis i think
breeding for resistance is quite doable
and a couple of reasons for that firstly
there's so much
genetic diversity that i think it's not
so much can we can we find it
it's how are we going to find it i think
the first step is going to be developing
methods for screening
so whether you're screening for fusarium
or if you're screening for powdery
mildew resistance
we have to have some really good methods
developed that are actually
already developed in other crops so you
know in tomato again and
in cotton or basil they've already
developed methods for screening for
fusion and powdery mildew resistance so
we need to adapt those methods for
for cannabis and then go out and do a
major collection
and maybe collect about 100 of these
different strains or genotypes
and then run these these methods through
and try to identify
um let's say five or ten that show some
level of resistance to either fusarium
or poverty mildew
and then i think it's a matter of making
crosses so you induce
some male flowers collect the pollen you
know make the crosses like most breeders
most growers would collect that seed and
then
run the test again in the next
generation to find those plants that
that may have picked up the resistance
so i think you know after three or four
rounds of this testing we could identify
potentially certain strains of genotypes
that have resistance
yeah and then second part of that
question do we even really have
a full picture of the
full breath of pathogens that can affect
cannabis
yeah so you know i go out to i go out to
the license growers uh
about once a week usually i go out on
wednesday so that's my cannabis day
and yeah i'm not and it's i'm not
surprised where
uh we stumble across new diseases and
i'm not going to say there's like
hundreds of them i would say we're
probably found maybe 10 or 15
and that's not to say that that's the
maximum number of diseases were found
there's going to be more so you talk to
the hemp growers in the u.s they're
always finding new diseases there's
diseases coming from a different crop
there's diseases coming
from a different area there may be
diseases coming from
a wind storm or rainstorm that brings
you know spores in from nearby areas
at some point we are going to max out
we'll probably have a full list of
diseases that are out there
but you know i think we've got the major
ones the major ones being powdery mildew
botrytis fusarium pythium
a number of leaf spotting diseases that
are found back east
and then of course a couple of virus
diseases that we haven't quite um
worked on yet so i think we're the list
is getting closer to being
completed at least i hope it is
yeah add it to the list of things in the
cannabis industry that we don't quite
have figured out yet
um yeah and i did want to shift gears a
little bit because
i know that um your presentation at this
year's canmed
um isn't actually about plant pathogens
it's actually about um
the development of cannabis trichomes
um so i want to give you an opportunity
to talk a bit about that
and give us a little bit of a preview of
what that's going to be about
okay i i'm sorry this this didn't work
out for you guys this year to have the
conference in
in pasadena but um hopefully next year
when kovid gets a little bit
easier to deal with yeah i was going to
talk about some of the work we've done
with
with trichome development and trichome
analysis
so what we've done is is you know
there's a standard
large piece of equipment called a
scanning electron microscope
and what that allows you to do is
actually magnify
the bracts and the other tissues
surrounding a cannabis flower
where you can you can magnify let's say
ten thousand times
and really get in there and start
looking at these these uh developing
trichomes
and we've found well we found two or
three really interesting things
um the first would be that we found four
uh different trichome types and maybe
i'll come back to that in a minute
there's
there's at least four different types
the ones that we're all familiar with of
course
are the stocked glandular trichomes
those are the ones that
that produce most of the cannabinoids
so we found the different types we also
found that there appears to be
changes in numbers in those four as the
plant matures
and so again as you probably would
expect more of the glandular
stock trichomes are are being seen as
the flowers tend to mature
because the other ones they're the sort
of the horsepower behind
producing all the cannabinoids and then
the other thing we
we did see is some differences between
varieties or between genotypes and so
the excitement there is that if you
could correlate
those different trichome types or
different trichome numbers
to final thc cbd and other cannabinoid
ratios
then that would be a really powerful way
to say okay i'm going to use
well maybe not a scanning microscope but
i'm going to use a way
to magnify those those flowers and look
at them and see
how many trichome types do i have and
how many total numbers of trichomes do i
have
and is that going to be a way for me to
tell whether i've got 12
thc or 20 thc or not so that's sort of
where we're going with this study is
is trying to correlate what we're seeing
visually with
some biochemical analysis of those
flowers
so that's interesting is it possible
that the different
trichome types could actually be
producing different
cannabinoids so that's a really
interesting question and
and um so so let me just tell you sort
of what those four
types are the the first type is is sort
of the hair like projections this the
staccalits as we call them
which really don't produce any
cannabinoids at all they have a
protective function they're the ones
that you know these humongous hair-like
structures that if i was an insect and i
i stumbled into them it's going to be
game over for me so
those definitely have a protective role
and then as i mentioned
the stock glandular trichomes the ones
that produce most of the the
cannabinoids
and then there's a there's a shorter
form of those uh which are the
what we call the sessile glandular and
the sessile are pretty much
um the same as the the the glandular
except
they have way lower levels of
cannabinoids in other words they're
they're immature form of the the stock
glandular
uh so that's that's sort of the second
type uh the third type is
what we call bulbas and the bulbas are
tiny
they're so small that that you could
never see them with even with a
magnifying glass you really have to have
a high power microscope to see those and
so i don't know what those are doing
in terms of their function are they
producing cannabinoids are they
producing terpenes maybe i don't know
and then the fourth type is what we call
the peltate
and those are um sort of like half moon
shaped in the microscope they're half
moon shaped
they're like saucers upside down saucers
sitting on the surface of a leaf
they don't have a stalk they're pretty
large you can see them
and again i don't know what the function
of those are it may be terpenes and
maybe cannabinoids
that's really interesting um and then i
thought reading through the abstract it
looked like you had looked at two
different types
or two different cultivars
is it possible that if you were to
survey more you might even find
other types of trichomes
yeah it's possible so we picked those
two because they differed quite a bit in
the in the thc content so one was like
10 percent and
and the other was like around 18. uh and
and i think we saw
that in the 18 percent the higher thc
cbd type strains they were
larger numbers of trichomes and the
stalks from those trichomes were
much longer in other words they they
were the type of
strain that you looked at with that with
a hand lens and you you could see the
trichomes really clearly
and you could differentiate whether or
not they were so the milky type or
whether they were the
sort of the amber colored uh type so
at least for those trichomes we think
there's a correlation between the
final thc content and trichome numbers
excellent well i look forward to seeing
those pictures if they're anything like
the
the photos that you presented at kmid
2018 with the
the close-up of powdery mildew and
things like that and
infecting the plant that's it's pretty
amazing stuff to look at i i encourage
anyone to
go back and view the video of um of
zamir's
presentation at 2018 because it was uh
it was certainly a hit
yeah i i tell you ben these these
pictures are are way better i mean i i
was
i'm really really excited next year to
try to present those because i
i look at them every once in a while and
i i think i'm like i'm i'm in outer
space i'm sitting on the moon somewhere
and these huge projectiles because
they're massive in the microscope
they're scanning
they're huge and they're amazing they're
just an amazing sight
well i'm looking forward to it i think
it's a good
i think that's a great place to stop um
thanks again zamir for for taking the
time to to talk with us
and i look forward to seeing you out in
pasadena this spring
thanks a lot ben and i appreciate all
the work you guys are doing and hosting
all these
these kind of med conferences they're
they're a great way to meet people the
great way to socialize and i'm sorry we
couldn't have done it this year
it'll just be bigger and better next
year
okay thanks a lot
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
dr samir punja
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and thanks again to our sponsors the
growers network and the hemp coffee
exchange
our next episode will drop september
16th
in the meantime please go to
cammanevents.com
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you into that drawing
for two tickets to our canmed2021 vip
dinner
and also keep you up to date with all
things canmed2021
if social media is more your thing you
can find us on facebook
instagram twitter and linkedin just
search for cam
ed events and lastly if you are
listening via a podcast app
go ahead and hit the subscribe button so
new episodes will automatically download
to your device
and if you'd like to leave us a five
star review we'd really appreciate that
as well
alright that's it from us until next
time
stay safe stay healthy and be sure to
come back for the next episode
of can med coffee talk
[Music]
you