[Music]
welcome to the can med coffee talk
podcast will be talked with the leading
minds in cannabis science medicine
cultivation and safety testing who will
be part of the kam med 2020 conference
in Pasadena California
this September 20th through 22nd on this
episode we talk with our kin med 2020
medicine keynote presenter dr. Bonnie
goldstein of canna centers bonnie is a
kin med staple in fact she has either
presented at or attended every can med
event going back to our very first at
Harvard Medical School she has also been
a very important part of the km advisory
board where she helps to shape the
content of the conference each year
bonnie has treated thousands of patients
with cannabis medicine and as I learned
from our conversation her patients range
in age from just a few weeks to 90 plus
we talked a lot about how she goes about
evaluating patients determining
formulations and dosing these patients
in our conversation we are excited to
have Bonnie as a keynote at cam at 2020
this year but that will not be the only
way she's contributing bonnie is also
leading a full day medical practicum
along with dr. Dustin Sulak dr. Kevin
Spellman and Eloise Thiessen who is a
board-certified NP this is a great
opportunity for healthcare professionals
to learn about the latest research into
cannabinoid therapies and also tap into
the deep clinical experience the
instructors have to offer when you
consider that most medical schools don't
teach the endocannabinoid system courses
like this are really the only way
healthcare providers can learn about how
to properly administer cannabinoid
therapies attendees will walk away with
practical information about the
different types of extractions and
products that are on the market and
optimal dosing learn more at cam at
events comm slash practicum the
practicum kicks off this year's can med
2020 on September 20th and will be
followed by two full days of oral and
poster presentations about the latest
research into cannabis science medicine
cult of
and safety testing go to cam med events
dot-com now to see the latest collection
of presenters and purchase your ticket
to the event if you are hearing this
before May 20th you're in luck you can
purchase a full conference pass for just
four hundred and twenty dollars which is
more than half off the full price you
don't want to miss out on this deal head
over to cam n events dot-com now now I
know what you're thinking what if the
event is postponed due to Cove in
nineteen
rest assured that we are working closely
with the Pasadena Convention Center to
make sure we can provide a safe
environment for our staff and attendees
as of this recording the event is still
on but just in case we have updated our
refund policy to provide a 100% refund
to any ticket holders in the event that
we do reschedule and the new dates cause
a conflict check out on our website for
details before we get to my conversation
with Bonnie I want to thank this episode
sponsor the American cannabis Nurses
Association the ACN a is a national
organization dedicated to expanding the
knowledge base of endocannabinoid
therapeutics among nurses their mission
is to advance excellence in cannabis
nursing practice through advocacy
collaboration education research and
policy development
learn more at cannabis nurses org okay
and without any further ado here's my
conversation with dr. Bonnie goldstein
[Music]
good afternoon Bonnie thanks for joining
us thanks for having me first again I
want to thank you for taking the time to
join us today and what must be a hectic
time for you and your patients how has
this pandemic affected your practice
it's a great question so we've changed
from in-person appointments to all now
via telemedicine or telephone because we
certainly don't want to put anybody
who's sick at risk or even healthy
people at risk so we're we're following
socially social distancing and lockdown
I'm encouraging all my patients to try
as much as they count to limit their
exposure as you know I take care of many
sick children who have epilepsy autism
cancer all kinds of serious conditions
and certainly coronavirus would not be
something that would be a good thing for
them to get at this point so I'm hoping
everybody is staying home and just
hanging in there absolutely and has it
been more difficult to access cannabis
and get their medicine apart from people
just being fearful of going out and
having exposure it really has not been
California has deemed cannabis medicine
as essential and it is essential I have
children if they miss a dose of oil who
will have a terrible seizure and
potentially end up in the hospital and
potentially it could be deadly so this
is not you know haphazard you know here
in their use of cannabis this is
medicine for so many of my patients and
so many Californians as well as in other
states and it's unfortunate that there
are people out there who think that this
is not necessary medicine but there are
people who just obviously are still
unenlightened as far as I can tell yeah
but fortunately in California and here
in mass
she sits where we're located too it's
great the cannabis has been deemed as
essential is that something you would
have expected when you first begin
treating your patients with cannabis
well yes because remember I'm on the
medical side I see people who are
usually in my office as a last resort
they've saw it every type of treatment
and they don't know why cannabis would
help them they don't know the science
behind it but they show up and ask you
know I really want to use this because
somebody told me it might help or I want
to try it or can you tell me more about
it
and so I knew about the medicinal
properties because you know my
experience but also reading the
scientific literature and following the
research that is ongoing and you know
it's a statement a lot of because
there's not enough research there's tons
of research you just have to read it and
learn about it and you know look or
there's three-day conferences about all
the research it's just there's a lot of
research and what we are missing is the
ability in the United States to do human
clinical trials but they are being done
elsewhere and they are certainly showing
that even if we don't get to the primary
endpoint that we might be seeking
meaning oh you know everybody has pain
relief or whatever we are certainly
seeing that it is safe and well
tolerated and there's really no
increased danger with cannabis in fact
one of the things I tell people is over
and over again if you just go into the
scientific literature and just read the
clinical trials in humans what you will
see is it says well tolerated very
minimal side effects and unless they go
very very high dose and of course with
very high doses of anything you may push
into the world of side-effects but
usually with cannabis medicine you don't
need very high doses but anyway that
going back to this essential medicine
part of it it's an interesting thing
they're calling it an essential medicine
but yet California where I practice is
charging medical patients ridiculous
taxes
on their essential medicine so we now
have a little bit of a conflict and
maybe this can be something that we can
use after the pandemic kind of settles
down and we have a handle on it to
potentially protect medical patients
using cannabis from the tax burden
because you know if you think about
somebody who's ill they're not working
they might be on a fixed income and then
it's out of pocket certainly not covered
by insurance and then the state is
taxing them on top by the way the big
point here is that you do not pay taxes
on your other medications like your
pharmaceuticals those are not taxed so
why they're taxing medical patients is
beyond me and I feel that it's very
disingenuous to call it essential
medicine and then slap a whole bunch of
taxes on it yeah absolutely I would
think that that would be an opportunity
to get that changed to say that yeah
you're deeming it essential in the time
of a pandemic how about you deem it as
essential after the fact and removed
that tax I think I think that would be a
great thing a great change to come out
of all of this we're gonna work on it
excellent so I did want to talk about
the types of patients that you see in
your practice what are some of the
conditions and you mentioned that your
your treating children what are some of
the typical ages who's typically coming
to see you so in terms of age group you
know my youngest patient is six months
old or sorry six weeks old when he
presented he had a genetic syndrome that
caused terrible seizures and even the
physician taking care of the patient was
on board with cannabis because he had
seen this syndrome before and knew that
the medications that are currently
available for seizures in that
particular instance were not very
effective and then my oldest patient
almost about a hundred I have colleagues
who have patients who are even older
than that 100 and 305 so in terms of age
you know we all have into an
endocannabinoid system so it really
doesn't matter how old you are there's
no real contraindication in terms of age
to use cannabis mostly I you know I do
specialize in Pediatrics because that
was my background
a pediatric trained physician and I did
pediatric emergency medicine for many
years so I'm comfortable with sick
children and and helping kids who have
complex medical conditions in children
I'd say the most common conditions are
treatment-resistant epilepsy autism
cancer GI disorders like Crohn's disease
ulcerative colitis autoimmune disease a
lot of genetic syndromes that have
either medical or behavioral components
to them so really it runs the gamut in
Pediatrics and then in adults you know
obviously there's a lot of conditions
that we see but they're the top three
are paying chronic pain anxiety
depression and then also insomnia and
remember those three often run together
if you have chronic pain you're probably
not sleeping great and you have some
anxiety and depression right if you have
anxiety and depression sometimes you
have other medical conditions where pain
plays a big role and then sleep is huge
I mean so many people struggling with
sleep the sleep industry is multi
billion dollars in the United States
between pharmaceuticals and other other
treatments and I do find that about 90%
or even a little bit more than that of
patients that will try cannabis report
and improvement and sleep well okay a
few things I wanted to unpack with that
the first being that I didn't realize
you had such a wide range of Ages that
you were treating it makes me curious
how does endocannabinoid function change
with age is there sort of a time where
it where it falls off in older folks
yeah great question so in children they
have an immature like everything about a
child's body and nervous system and
brain is immature right I mean they're
babies and they're then they're growing
and school-aged and then into teenage
years and they're constantly changing me
think about someone
born yesterday and 18 years from now
completely different humans so it's
important to understand that the
endocannabinoid system is present at the
beginning of life and through fetal
growth and then as there during infancy
and so on and it goes through changes
and the levels of endocannabinoids
andrás and the cannabinoid receptors are
all changing and are somewhat different
we find it's very counterintuitive but
it appears from some research that
children are less sensitive to the
effects of THC than adults and you would
think oh my gosh they're little they
would be more sensitive but they're not
they're they seem to be less sensitive
to the intoxicating effects and that's
because they're endocannabinoid system
is quite immature and they have probably
less density of cannabinoid type 1
receptors where THC interacts and causes
the intoxicating effects and then as
people age their endocannabinoid system
it's been shown starts to for lack of a
better word atrophy and it you know and
somebody we think about somebody who's
old how their muscles kind of their
muscle mass goes down we know brain
starts to shrink as you get older and
very similar their endocannabinoid
system starts to deteriorate I mean
that's maybe a strong word for it but it
does start to succumb to the aging
process and certainly what we know are
endocannabinoid system to do is to play
a very well described protective role
and so as somebody ages I really believe
that they should have support and
augmentation of their endocannabinoid
system through using cannabinoids to
help continue the protective process as
they get older well that's interesting
about children being less sensitive to
THC is that the same with other
cannabinoids like CBD well remember THC
is the one that works directly at the
has THC has multiple targets let's
say in the body but it's the one that
binds directly to the cannabinoid
receptor giving the well-known effects
CBD has some action within the
endocannabinoid system but it has many
many actions what we call non
cannabinoid system mechanisms of action
so it targets many other receptors and
many other locations enzymes
transporters in the body so ID 1 I don't
know that it's been researched in terms
of sensitivity to CBD but in a way you
almost would not necessarily be able to
know because you don't always see
immediate effects from CBD right you can
give it and somebody says oh I don't
feel anything but meanwhile it's doing
something you know it's
anti-inflammatory antioxidant neuro
protective
anti epilepsy but they may say well I
don't feel it meaning the same as most
people who take THC will tell you oh I
feel it right so it may be difficult to
assess but I do find that young children
who let's say going through cancer
treatment or going through who have
epilepsy when we give them THC that
might a dose that might intoxicate an
adult they you know we stay in very
close touch with the parents I always
tell them there's what I call the
sealing dose and the sealing dose of THC
is the dose at which you feel
intoxicated and even though a child may
not be able to describe that I will tell
you parents know their children very
well and they'll call me and say my
child's eyes are a little red he looked
a little glassy seems kind of mellow
okay
we've probably hit the ceiling dose and
it's surprising though in these young
children just what that dose is because
many of my adult patients may not even
be able to get to that dose because
their ceiling dose is so much lower so
not everybody and again there's always
outliers we must understand that
everybody's endocannabinoid system is
different to genetically programmed and
determined and how we react to
cannabinoids is very individual there's
similarities of course but you know what
I'm talking about with children is we
can't just you know look and people will
say oh well what about all the overdoses
that you know all these hospitals may
see well because if you leave your
edible that has a hundred milligrams
laying around of course a child if they
ate a hundred milligrams are going to be
intoxicated I'm talking about low
medicinal doses yeah so let's get into
dosing in first I wanted to ask you
where do you sort of come down on the
the debate or the divide between sort of
whole plant medicine versus like
isolated compounds well look as
scientists and researchers we must know
what isolated compounds do so I want to
know what does CBD do as what what is
CBD responsible for so before you can
make any treatment plan for somebody you
have to know what these how these
compounds work and so it's important
that people understand that yes in
research we use isolated compounds to
understand the mechanisms of action and
the therapeutic benefits or detriments
of phyto cannabinoids but there are is a
nice body of research that shows that
these compounds clearly work together
enhancing each other but also minimizing
some of the potential unwanted effects
for instance CBD can buffer a little you
know some of the high from THC almost
what we call antagonists they have
opposite effects at the receptor and so
knowing that we can use that to up to
our benefit so what's important hang on
one second sorry so what's important to
understand about that is that even
though a study might show isolated CBD
did X Y &amp; Z in the study if we use whole
plant which I will share with you I
always encourage whole plant why would I
remove medicinal compounds from
somebody's plant and everybody would say
oh it's medicine you should control it
and all of that well yeah
there's a lot of companies now that have
very consistent medicine batch to batch
if I test the bottles batch to batch I
see they're very similar and I can use
those as medicine because I'm following
the patients closely and I see what the
medicine is doing for them and you have
to know what each cannabinoid can do and
then you have to be able to understand
what happens when they kind of work
together and one of the things that I
had to kind of come around to as a
scientist was that there is always gonna
be some small level of unknown when
you're using whole plant that somebody
might be sensitive to something else
that's in the bottle but if it doesn't
fit them or suit them we sometimes try
different things and then we try to
narrow in on maybe this did work for you
and this didn't work for you what does
this bottle have that this bottle
doesn't have right so you try to be
scientific about it and try to narrow it
down but studies show that whole plant
seems to have higher efficacy than
isolated compounds no I liked that
response very very diplomatic that you
know we know that that we get a lot of
benefit out of the whole plant but there
still is very much a need to be studying
the isolated compounds so I think that
is a nice balance between the two so but
I'm curious when and just in your
approach in in treating patients is
there a certain sort of blend of
cannabinoids and terpenoids how do you
sort of go about that so that's a loaded
question because like oh I get a lot of
families or people that ask me which
what's the best CBD what's the best
medicine and the answer is the best
medicine is the one that works for you
and it may be different for you than it
is for me even though we have the same
condition and that's because what we're
trying to do is take a plant that has
over 500 different compounds I II a very
complex product of mother nature and I'm
trying to
Matchett - you're extremely complex
physiology and particular let's say team
of our chemical variety of plant ie
strain which I try not to use that word
because it's not really accurate the
word is keema var chemical variety of
plant that works for your arthritis may
not work for my arthritis why Bowl
because again your DNA is different from
my DNA your response your absorption the
way you metabolize the way you excrete
chemicals from your body is very
different from the way that I do
if you've ever talked to someone who has
been successful using cannabis they'll
tell you I had to try a number of
products to really narrow down on what
worked for me Park let's take
Parkinson's disease so Parkinson's is a
neurodegenerative disorder and the
beginning of Parkinson's the course of
illness is different than the middle
than the end so when somebody says to me
what do you use for Parkinson's well you
know where is the person in their course
right are they just diagnosed are they
ten years in or they twenty years in
what are their most symptoms that
they're trying to address how old are
they do the can they tolerate THC do
they not want THC in their in their mix
there's a so much to determining what
works for somebody and that's why you
can't necessarily just walk into a
dispensary and say oh I have X disease
what should I take and then somebody
hands you and says oh use this you might
get lucky and it works hey great but if
it doesn't work you have must understand
that this is not cookie cutter it's not
one-size-fits-all I get all the time
what ratio should my child be on for
epilepsy that there is no
one-size-fits-all for that it's
absolutely ridiculous to think that this
complex plan and your complex physiology
is gonna be you know as they say
one-size-fits-all it just does not work
that way yeah I imagine that's got to be
difficult
are there certain certain traits certain
markers that you commonly see that
know that oh I imagine that this person
might benefit from Luna loool or any of
the particular terpenes or or
cannabinoids that you've just sort of
gathered in your experience yes so let's
say take a child with autism for
instance so we know autism is a
condition where the brain is
overly excited what we call neuro
excitation same thing with epilepsy the
brain is overly excited and what's
happening is you're getting
neurotransmitters right the chemical
messengers in your brain are sending
messages that aren't always adaptive and
and correct and so we're trying to tell
those neurotransmitters you know dial it
down I use the analogy like someone who
many of the kids with autism are just a
lot of parents will acknowledge this
like I call it it's a it's a Ferrari
flying down the freeway with no brakes
okay and we don't want to stop the
Ferrari what we want is the Ferrari to
go speed limit right we want to just
balance and obviously neuro excitation
is out of balance it's the out of
balance message if your bear is chasing
you yes you want your brain to be
overexcited fight-or-flight but not in
just everyday function so many of those
kids have been shown to respond to the
calming terpenes like lynn Elul the
anti-inflammatory terpenes like beta
carry off one there's a terpene pine een
which can help with focus and
concentration and learning and some
people find that to be very helpful for
their child with autism again ultimately
what we're trying to do is take this
really large amount of products that are
out there and narrow them down to fit
that specific person that we're treating
but we can start with using our
knowledge about these compounds to say
hey let's start here and by the way this
is what doctors are doing all the time
if you came in to my office let's say if
I was a regular doctor practicing
medicine I have a handful of tools in my
toolbox ie the pharmaceuticals and using
my knowledge my clinical
experience the research and kind of
trying to make the best educated guess
that I can make let me pick this drug
and tell you to take it right and
sometimes I'm gonna get lucky and it's
gonna be the perfect match and the
perfect fit and you're gonna say wow my
doctor was great she knew exactly what
to give to me and sometimes by the way
which has happened to me
you take one dose and say there is no
way in hell I'm taking another dose of
that and you call your doctor and say oh
my gosh you know like I'm thinking I
need to go to the ER after I took that
pill I've been on the end of that once
in my life and that once was enough
and I remember calling the doctor and
the doctor on call was not my doctor he
said gee I wonder why he started with
that one which did not instill any
confidence of course but at the same
time you're you're making the best guess
you can until somebody takes something
you just do not know how they're gonna
respond
the beauty of cannabis is that you're
not going to be harmed you might now if
it's got a lot of THC and you have an
unpleasant like you know THC overdose
experience where you get too intoxicated
and you get paranoid and anxious and you
freak out a little you still won't die
from that so it's okay and you're
probably not going to end up in an ER if
you get some reassurance that you're
gonna be fine and it's gonna wear off
but the reality is is cannabis is
extremely safe too
trial and error and for many of my
patients the reason I'm able to help
them is they're willing to hang in there
with me as we methodically approach a
trial and error way of doing this
because again look there was a study out
of Israel that took 60 kids with severe
behavioral issues as part of their
autism and 50% of them responded
basically 50% responded to a 20 to 1
ratio CBD to THC well what about the
other 50% you know that's a crapshoot
right the other the other 50% about half
of them little slightly more than half
responded to adding in a little more THC
so often that's the approaches let's
start with this and then we can add
something in if your child looks like
it's not gonna your child's not going to
be the one that's in that responder
category so anybody using counter
we're serious illness has to kind of
accept the fact and I tell everybody you
must be patient you must understand that
probably for the first three to six
months you're gonna be doing trial and
error that is just part of it and you
may get very lucky and the first product
out of the bet out of the gate helps you
that's terrific
but sometimes that's not how it works
and so hanging in there and just getting
some good advice and trialing things is
pretty much standard it's par for the
course
now what about delivery method I hear
you saying bottles a lot is a lot of
oils and tint shoes that you're
recommending I am and one of the reasons
is because you can really control the
dosing right so if you buy an edible
let's say right and let's say the edible
has got 10 milligrams and you cut it
into let's say a little piece of I don't
know a chocolate and you cut it into
four pieces you can go as low as two
point five milligrams and then maybe you
could cut that piece again in half and
get a low dose but with oils I can
measure out a half a milligram of THC
which can be medicinal for some people
you want to be able to titrate what we
call titrate dosing to be able to start
with very tiny doses and go up if cap
let's say you bought THC capsules and
they only come in 25 milligrams but
you're a dose you figured out somehow
that your dose is 15 milligrams well the
capsule comes is 25 how are you taking
15 so I find that initial in especially
initially again if if we don't get the
if we can get the dose right then we can
look at what products allow for that
dosing so obviously inhaling is not
something that we do a lot with
pediatric patients there are some
parents using like a type of vaporizer
where it has a bag and then you can put
a little mask over the child's face so
for some kids who have severe rage and
aggression as part of their syndrome or
as part of autism or whatever it is they
have they are using that vape in those
cases they're not really medicating by
that because the other thing with
children is that children grow and you
have to be able to increase the dose
based on their weight and as they you
don't want them to outgrow the dose
that's very typical for any medicine
attrex most most medicines are based on
weight in the pediatric world for adults
though I find that having liquids that
you can titrate you know a quarter of a
dropper to a half a dropper for instance
0.25 milligrams to 0.5 0.5 s too much
and 0.25 s not enough you can use a
little syringe to measure out 0.3 or 0.4
it just allows you to kind of really
narrow in on dosing does everybody need
that no just some people need that not
everybody needs it but I do like
tinctures for that particular reason the
other thing that tinctures is that you
can hide the flavor in food you can
actually buy empty capsules and make
your own capsules so that if you can't
find that the dose you're looking for
you can make your own so it just allows
for a lot of it's very easy to work with
however edibles are great you know
vaporizers sure I'm all in board with
those I also encourage people to use
topicals so there is no again no
delivery method that is better than any
other I just think as a physician who's
trying to dial in dosing for people and
to find that sweet spot especially in a
you know population of children who are
growing and changing who sometimes you
know they're nonverbal and you don't
know what's going on you want to be able
to make changes simply great and we're
coming up on the end here but I did want
to ask you do you have any idea how many
physicians out there are like you well
not like you because there's no one like
you know but but position but pediatric
clinicians who are actually treating
children with cannabis are there a lot
of a lot of them out there and how does
one find one right so unfortunately no
there are a lot of cannabis doctors that
will treat children who may not have had
specific training with pediatrics and I
do think that because cannabis is so
safe that you're they're not going to
harm anybody but whether or not they
understand the nuances
treating a child you know after working
with children for so many years there's
definitely some nuances there it's not
it's not just a small adult that's for
sure but I think there's probably less
than ten of us in the whole country that
are specifically pediatric trained I
know of a handful on the East Coast or a
few on the East Coast I know of a doctor
in Florida I think there's a couple in
Colorado and of course there may be
others and not to discount them but you
know there's really not very many of us
and I think part of it is that it's
still considered controversial I
recently gave Grand Rounds at a local
Children's Hospital and the doctor who
introduced me said you know this is very
controversial and I thought I've been
doing this for so long and so to me it's
not controversial at all we you children
have an endocannabinoid system we have
some understanding that there's
dysregulation or deficiency within that
endocannabinoid system for for sure with
epilepsy autism maybe with ADHD that
research is is being done in other
countries and you would never leave a
child with a deficiency of any other
necessary chemical in their body like
you would like what do we call insulin
deficiency like type 1 diabetes is an
insulin deficiency and what do we give
those people we give them insulin if you
have no thyroid deficiency you have
what's called hypothyroidism so we now
know that children with autism based on
two studies one out of Stanford
University and one out of Israel show
that children with autism have low
levels of their natural what we call
endocannabinoid their inner cannabis
compounds which serve a protective role
of regulating the brain chemistry and
here now we have a population of kids
who have dysregulated behaviors that's
their brain chemistry not balanced
why wouldn't we fix the imbalance right
now I'm not saying more research isn't
needed but you know I've treated so many
patients when parents say my child can
go back to school my child's the
aggression is gone we are no longer
living in fear of our ten-year-old
that's huge and when we look at downside
I will I always say I point to the
patients ask the parents they will tell
you whether or not they're seeing side
effects and all that kind of thing so to
me it's not controversial and to me this
is again just another tool in the
toolbox and we are smart enough to
understand this we're smart enough to do
the research right now we should
continue to move forward so we
understand more we should not you know
there's why and many people say why is
there a ban on research look ultimately
it comes down to money
the only reason cannabis is being kept
as a Schedule one is because it can
replace lots of pharmaceuticals and you
know that doesn't help the
pharmaceutical company so my my point
being that what is everybody afraid of
let's just do the research so we can
finally know so when somebody comes to
me and says is cannabis gonna help my
child with this rare syndrome wouldn't
it be nice if I could tell them whether
or not they should spend their money on
this mm-hmm well I didn't realize the
number of pediatric clinicians using
cannabis was so low so what is your
advice to parents who maybe have a child
they think could benefit from cannabis
but don't have access to to one of those
where do they start well so some of us
do educational consults where we're just
educating the parent or kind of where to
begin there are some resources online
there's a website that's it's a
nonprofit that I work with them on their
advisory board called the whole plan
access for autism
it's WPA for a.com
there's project CBD org that's a
nonprofit that people can turn to to try
to find a referral or you know find a
doctor that's cannabis friendly there
luckily we're moving in the right
direction and they're more doctors that
are learning about this and are starting
to incorporate it into their practice so
at least we're moving in the right
direction but you may have to seek out
somebody who's able to do a telemedicine
consultation if you can't find somebody
in your state and of course you should
always just take a look online and see
if you can make sure what your state
allows for so that you're not getting
into trouble making sure that you are
following the rules because certainly we
don't want anybody's child getting taken
away for trying cannabis or using
cannabis when their state laws don't
allow it again we should have a federal
leadership on this but right now we it's
state-by-state but you're allowed to
give your child so right well thank you
for those resources I'll definitely put
some links in the show notes so people
can check those out so I know we're
coming up on the end here and I did want
to talk about can Med of course what's
kind of what brought us here and correct
me if I'm wrong but you've been at all
of the kid meds right you've been with
us each year I have since the beginning
that's great and we're so happy to have
you as a keynote presenter at this
year's event I was wondering if you
might want to give us a little preview
of what you're going to be presenting on
I think I'm just sharing you know my
findings and kind of going over what the
latest research is in terms of
pediatrics and how patients my patients
are responding to various cannabinoids
everybody's focused on THC and CBD and
certainly I focus on those two but
there's other cannabinoids that we are
using CBG THC a CBD a and now just
coming out on the market in California
our THC v tetrahydrocannabinol you can
óbuda varam which all have again their
own medicinal properties and it's
important for people to understand that
there is not just one way or one ratio
or one product there's many different
compounds that we can
and use therapeutically to address
illness and again this goes back to
right if you're not a big responder to
just CBD THC combination is there
something else that the plant offers
that you can try and you know for every
patient of mine that does well on CBD or
THC there's those that don't even take
those cannabinoids and they're using
other cannabinoids so I think I'll be
talking about that I haven't written I
haven't gotten the talk together yet so
I you know sometimes it takes you to
other places and certainly what's
fascinating too is that between now a
preliminary search and so you know
sometimes I'm literally putting together
something a week before that is new and
this is a very exciting time to be in
this industry yeah absolutely
and as as the person on the team who
usually has to put the put the slides
together and get everything ready for
the production team you're not the only
one who waits inside you try to get it
in early but sometimes these wonderful
cases or good results or even a
groundbreaking research that that just
gets published and you'd want to include
it because you want to keep people and
you want to be cutting edge and leading
edge you don't want to you know in this
in this crazy world of cannabis
you know I joke around that like one
year is equal to like seven dog years
right because there's so much that you
think so many things change and again
it's such an active area research all
around the world that you have to really
stay on top of it in order to be able to
be on to be have the latest and greatest
yeah absolutely and that's why we love
having this event every year so we can
we can get the latest and greatest and
get everyone together to share their
information and we love having you a
part of it so before we go is there any
other any other information you want to
share in terms of how people can either
get in touch with you or follow what
you're doing whether it be website
social media sure so we have a Facebook
page it's canna Centers
you can look for Kanna - centers and
then I have an Instagram which is Bonnie
goldstein MD and I don't over post but I
try to put things on Facebook that are
good articles that I come across in the
scientific literature that I think
should get out there you know there's
this finding that it takes 17 years for
article of scientific information to
trickle down to doctors which is like
blows my mind because but remember if
you're a busy practice you're taking
care of patients you're taking care of
your business and you're you're you know
you're deep in it's very hard to keep up
with the research so I try really hard
to make sure I post articles that are
again some of the latest information
that can be helpful to people and it's
meaningful to people and then on
Instagram I just often share stories of
my patients or you know reposts of
patients who are getting success because
people we we are fighting also
propaganda and fear of cannabis and what
people need to realize is that under
medical supervision cannabis is
extremely safe I joke around that I'm a
chicken inside I am I am a very
conservative doctor overall and for me
to be able to feel comfortable with
cannabis I will tell you it is extremely
safe my elderly parents take cannabis
for their conditions and I would never
let them take anything that I would
think that would harm them and I
certainly wouldn't recommend cannabis to
children if it wasn't safe so I just
think people need to realize that this
kind of party line we were dealt with
you know we were handed a long time ago
that oh it's dangerous and it kills
brain cells and it's gonna do all these
terrible things it's just baloney I
think that's a great way to close it out
thanks again for joining us Bonnie we'll
see you in the fall
soon
[Music]
I hope you enjoy my conversation with
Bonnie goldstein it's always such
pleasure to get to talk with her check
out the links in the show description to
learn more about the topics we discussed
and also please check out the canna
Center's website next week we're
shifting gears a bit as we welcome any
Afiya from canna safe labs ne is the lab
director at canna safe one of the
largest testing labs in California we
discussed the importance of safety
testing challenges that come with
navigating regulations the recent vaping
crisis and more that episode will drop
May 27th - week sfrom this episode in
the meantime please go to can Med events
comm / coffee talk and sign up for email
updates that will enter you into a
drawing to win two tickets to our can
med 2020 B IP dinner and keep you up to
date with all things can med 2020 if
social media is your thing you can find
us on Facebook Instagram Twitter and
LinkedIn just search for can Med events
and lastly if you are listening on a
podcast app go ahead and hit the
subscribe button so that new episodes
automatically download to your device
and if you want to leave us a five-star
review that'd be great too alright
that's it from us stay safe stay healthy
and be sure to come back for the next
episode of KM ed coffee talk