[Music]
welcome to the canmed coffee talk
podcast
where we talk with the leading minds in
cannabis science
medicine cultivation and safety testing
i am your host ben amert i'm the
marketing manager at medicinal genomics
and proud member of the team that puts
on the canmed conference
every year all right let's address the
elephant in the room
if you've signed up for email alerts
then you should have received an email
yesterday
with an important update for canmed2020
if you have not signed up for email
alerts then please go to kments.com
coffeetalk and do so now
the news is that our team has made the
difficult decision to postpone this
year's event
to the spring of next year can med 2021
will take place april 12th through 14th
at the pasadena convention center in
pasadena california
if you're a faithful listener of the
podcast you have heard me say that we
were closely monitoring the covid19
situation in california
and working with the pasadena convention
center and local leaders to make sure we
can provide a
safe environment for our staff and
attendees
our team felt moving the event to april
2021 would be the best way for us to
provide
a safe environment for everyone we are
offering a one hundred percent refund to
current ticket holders should they have
a conflict with the new dates
go to cannemedevents.com coven19
for more information the good news is
the cam med coffee talk podcast will
continue
with new episodes every other wednesday
we look forward to continuing the canmed
conversation
through this medium as well as on social
media and
on our website we will be announcing our
safety keynote presenter an
expanded phase 2 schedule in new
speakers
as well as multiple panel discussions
throughout the rest of this year
and into 2021 so please sign up for
email alerts if you haven't already
that link again is kmedevent.com
covid19 and also follow us on instagram
facebook twitter and linkedin just
search
for can med events now with that out of
the way
let me tell you about today's guest
keith allen
keith is the director of bioinformatics
at front range
biosciences where he is tasked with
exploring the cannabis genome to find
genetic markers
that can be selected in breeding
projects his current focus
is on cannabinoid and terpene production
but as we discuss in our conversation
there are a number of different traits
cannabis and hemp breeders
will want to select for in the future
including yield
drought resistance pathogen resistance
flowering time
hardiness for the outdoor environment
and more
the opportunity for improving the
cannabis and hemp
plant is only restricted by our
understanding of the genome
which keith readily admits is still in
its infancy
keith will be presenting on gene
families and gene networks
underlying oil production and cannabis
trichomes
at canmed 2021 this spring
so please do consider picking up your
ticket for the event now
before we get to my conversation with
keith i want to thank this episode
sponsor
the growers network growers network is
committed to providing the highest
quality cannabis
content education and resources
be sure to check out their canna crib
series your behind
the scenes look at some of the most
sophisticated technologically advanced
grows in the world
visit them at youtube.com growers
network
and finally this episode of the canmed
coffee talk podcast
is fueled by the hemp and coffee
exchange
hemp coffee is a healthy delicious
natural product
rich in trace minerals and nutrients
providing sustained energy
without the crash of regular coffee for
more information
check out hemp coffeeexchange.com
and use the promo code drinkhemp to get
10 percent off your purchase okay
without any further ado please enjoy my
conversation with keith
allen from front range biosciences
[Music]
good afternoon keith thanks for thanks
for joining us today
good afternoon no problem excellent um
and thank you so
much for agreeing to be a part of can
med 2020 i know the team here
at medicinal genomics has been an
admirer of your work for
for quite a few years so we're really
excited to have you presenting this year
yeah i'm excited to be a part of it this
has been on my radar for a while
now have you ever have you ever attended
canfed before would this be your first
this will be my first excellent
excellent and
we already have you secured in a
speaking slot i was wondering if you
could talk a little bit about
what you're intending to present to
everyone
so what i'm going to be talking about
started out as being about gene
networks underlying oil profile
and cannabis trichomes and it turns out
i got a little bit distracted on the way
to getting there
and so what i'm going to talk about is
really the gene
families so before i could get to
networks of genes i need to understand
what the genes are
and i ran into some kind of
a lot more complexity and a lot more
interesting detail in terms of
what's going on under the hood in terms
of the way
trichomes are organizing the work that
they're doing
creating all of these compounds that you
know make that make the plant so uh
so interesting so when you say you were
originally going to
talk about gene networks and now talking
about gene families
what's the difference so gene networks
you're talking about the way
genes interact with each other either in
a regulatory
system you've got you know genes are
responsible transcription factors for
example that are responsible for turning
on
a particular set of genes or you've got
other genes that that regulate
what's going on in different ways either
by turning something up or
destroying it or whatever so that's one
kind of gene network
the other kind of gene network is um
a biosynthetic network cannabinoids are
pretty big molecules
and the way cells handling making a
molecule like that is by assembling it
from
smaller parts very standard parts
that it just makes a part of what we
call core metabolism
so there's a there's a sequence as a
pathway of genes
that's involved in taking these very
standard plugged together
parts and building very very specific um
large molecules like like the
cannabinoids
it's almost like an assembly line it is
a bit like a
like an assembly line only this one
this one every step is robotic but there
seems to be about five different robots
that
could be working each step and we don't
know that all the robots are the same or
have the same priorities
okay so that's gene network so what's a
gene family
so a gene family you take a particular
kind well
so here's a great example the
cannabinoid synthases
are members of a large and very
evolutionarily
ancient gene family called the berberine
bridge
enzymes they're we call them a family
because
it's clear that there was way back
in the deep past before the fungi
split off from the plants there was an
enzyme
and all of these enzymes
and they've diversified now to do a lot
of different things but they're all
related in terms of their history their
lineage back to this original
uh this original enzyme so in
cannabis the berberine bridge family
contains on the order of about 20 genes
that we would recognize as cannabinoid
synthases or
you know very very likely to be
cannabinoid synthesis
and then there's a bunch more of these
enzymes some which are
pretty well expressed in trichomes that
we don't know what they do all we know
is that it's probably a fairly you know
a molecule that's in the range of the
same size um
as as a cannabinoid so that would be an
example of a gene family
it's fascinating and one of the things i
hear so much in
in talking to kevin here medicinal
genomics and other folks are kind of in
this
in this space is we don't know how much
how much do we know about the cannabis
genome
not very much every time
every time you know i peel back a layer
of the onion
it's like you know i mean it's it's a
little bit like one of those
those russian doll things except instead
of taking it off and there's a smaller
doll
inside you take it off and there's 50
smaller dolls
and they're all a little bit different
from each other so everything about
this genome is unlike
other genomes i've worked with i've
slowed down a little bit i'm thinking
about the maze genome it's is
maybe maybe close to the same level of
crazy
but basically
this has been a very an intensely
neglected
crop for a very long time so you compare
what we know about
the cannabis genome to what we know
about you know tomato
corn corn soybean you know
for pizza sweet potato um where there's
you know entire academic careers have
been sunk into
studying you know these other crops and
you come over to cannabis
and you're really really
starting with you know stone knives and
bear claws in terms of
the amount that we know we do have
various genomes that are finished
to various rates of quality we do
have an initial run at
um at annotating these genomes which is
basically just going through and saying
here's a gene here's a repeat element
and whatnot
and we're just at the beginning of
starting to get
a sense for
how much the genome varies from plant to
plant
from cult or article to our within
cannabis um and
and this is really my focus getting into
specific gene families like you know the
um the family of genes that um
create the early precursors in the
pathway to the to the cannabinoids or
the terpene synthesis
for example how much variation do we see
in these from cultivar to cultivar in
terms of
just whole blocks of these genes being
missing and we're seeing that
you know new ones we haven't seen you
know
showing up as we as we as we sequence
new cultivars
and also changes within the genes
themselves you know i can reliably say
you know
this is the you know the thc synthase or
or whatever
but every plant i look at the gene is
just a little bit different
so the the amount of variation
in this genome particularly
within the parts of the genome that are
relevant to the kind of breeding we want
to do
um amount of variation is amazing
uh that much we know right now so on the
one hand
from the standpoint of trying to study
this genome
um it's frustrating because it's i
you know i can't just write a simple
document that says the cannabis genome
is this
um on the other hand
it's really exciting because every time
you turn around there's there's
something new
and probably most importantly
from a breeding standpoint breeding is
about
making you're mixing up you have you
have this line and this line and this
one has these characteristics you like
and this one has
these other characteristics you like you
want to create
a stable hybrid between them that has
all the things
that you want so it's about making
combinations of different genetic
elements
so if you take a step back and look at
this variation
rate thing it means the number of
potential
combinations or another way to look at
that is the number of possible breeding
targets
that we can we can get to with this
with this plant is incredible
if you compare that to something like
soybean
where the amount of genetic variation
within
you know the breeding stock that we we
have available to us
extremely limited um
what you can do with that genome because
it's just very little it's a very what
we call a bottlenecked
uh genetic population
cannabis is absolutely the opposite
extreme and let's see to actually answer
your question
we are just at the beginning of
understanding how much variation happens
wow that's fascinating so and so how
much of that
genetic variation in cannabis is just
because it has been sort of
on the fringes and hasn't had as much
intense study as say
a soybean or is it is it something that
was always part of the plan
or is it kind of due to circumstance
so um that's
kind of really not surprising that's
kind of a complex question
one of the things um so if you look at
corn for example there's an ancestral
species
called teosinte and
teosinte actually still exists you can
grow this stuff you wouldn't be able to
there's a way to eat it that has to do
with like soaking in lie
stuff like that you know but there was a
set
of like a half a dozen mutations that
happened in
tiacente that turned it into something
kind of looked like
you know modern field corn um
and so then we've been breeding on that
all these years and you
drive across iowa and boy i'm here to
tell you
modern what we're growing in iowa right
now it doesn't look
anything like what what you know the
inca and maya civilizations
um discovered yeah yeah what is that on
the
range of a thousand years um ago
so that's an example where we've got
the product of you know a millennium of
selection
and and now targeted breeding
and we've got the wild relative in
cannabis it seems like all we have
is you know we don't have
really really good what you would call
land races or
or or wild relatives that everybody
agrees yeah this is what it looked like
before
human selection everything i mean we
have been doing selection
in this in this uh species really
since the egyptians you know so it's a
very very large number of
generations uh plant generations have
taken place
while we've been selecting on this so
we've got kind of this crazy
mismatch of you know we've been
selecting on this genome and
and you know we we we end up with
something that is basically kind of a
ways from
from you know what the natural genome
would look like the other thing that's
going
on is there's been a lot of
you know it wasn't random in terms of
what you know individual breeders were
doing but if you kind of like back
up and look at the whole effect it's
essentially kind of like
random all of this mixing of you know
southeast asian strains and you know
it's strange found
found from various places around the
world to create new varieties
so we have that aspect of it as well is
that there's
basically everything you pick up right
now is
a hybrid meaning you know it's
this is a diploid organism means it's
got two copies of the chromosome
and those two copies are very
dissimilar um to each other
so if you i try to you know like breed
this thing
you know in my f1 population all the
seeds are going to be different
so that's another aspect where we're
very far behind
you know the species where
you know i mean corn we
i don't know how long missouri 17 and
you know
these these old inbreds that have been
reliable
and understood and studied for
50 years and we're kind of away from
that
in cannabis right but i would think the
potential to
to breed a new and interesting strain of
corn
that's got to be pretty hard to do
correct
it it is to get to um uh
to get to something that's really
fundamentally different i mean what
what modern breeding and corn is doing
so it's it's moving to
very much more sophisticated
mathematical models for looking at the
inter at the relationship between
observable genetic markers and
output traits um but basically
we're on this this part of the curve
right now
where uh for corn we're increasing your
yield by about one and a half percent
a year well you know it still looks like
the same plant
but one and a half percent more than you
got last year
and that's been a very reliable um
trend at about that rate since about
or so we don't know we're going to hit
this guy would be a theoretical maximum
someplace but cannabis
will be very different um from that
because
we're really we're just so early in
breeding we don't
know you know
there could be we could flail around
and and fail to find you know much
that's particularly useful
i don't think that's going to be the
outcome on on the other hand at the
other extreme
we could end up really hitting pay dirt
on
some new combinations that we haven't
you know we
we haven't known to try yet
so it's maze breeding
is in many ways boring and reliable
it's you know general motors it's just
kind of
plugging along cannabis breeding is
going to be
a lot more
exciting in terms of what are the kinds
of things that
that that we get out of it i guess the
other thing to say there
is that in maze um
there's there's two main traits that
that all the big breeding companies are
they are
are focused on right now one is yield
period and the second is drought
tolerance or
yield under under drought um
nitrogen use efficiency or uptake
efficiency is
is another one that's for further down
on the list
you move over to cannabis and
you know yield is going to be really
important
but it's a it's a very complicated trait
um to breed with drought tolerance is
going to be important
but i think that in the short term
the kinds of things we're going to be
looking at is creating
stable reliable lines that give you a
very specific oil profile
under a given growth regime
that's what the market is the most
looking for
um right now the end user
market and that's also going to be
what i i think we're going to be best
position
to be able to to to breed for um
in in the short term so you're saying a
consistent cannabinoid terpene profile
um from generation to generation that's
sort of the first
hill to to tackle yeah that's that's the
first one that we're going to be able to
go
after now if you talk to
growers i mean there's a lot of growers
out there who say man
i've got i got this one variety and
i can sell every gram of the stuff that
i can grow
and i can sell it a big premium but i
can't afford to grow it because yield
the overall yield is so low you know
what can be done um about this and
there will be things to do there but
any time you you know so overall yield
we don't even know how many genes are
involved in that
and so it's it's much more
complicated to design a breeding program
that you know and it may be the you know
it's probably going to end up modeled
very closely on on what's currently be
done been done in mays
and it'll just be gradual incremental
increases in yield
um year by year yeah i mean and that's
fascinating when you said that
you know corn yield is increasing by one
percent
a year and has been since 1950 so yeah
i can only imagine you know 70 years
from now what cannabis is going to look
like
yeah yes
it's fascinating so
in terms of cannabinoids in terpenes i
got to imagine that's
intensely complicated as well just
because
i mean modern testing labs can't even
test for all the terpenes that the
the plant is creating so
so where do you start there
um so
the the terpenes are very difficult
for a number of reasons you know as
as a breeding target as a you know
anyway you want to want to go at it um
one of the big challenges with the
terpenes is
they're volatile i mean they just they
just
you know evaporate and you know if
if if you take your you know you you got
a whole bunch of fresh bud
and your curing protocol is to put it in
basically a low temperature oven for a
day or two and just drive all the water
out
it's gonna be nice and dry and you're
gonna lose almost all
you know of your terpenes out of there
if you so
there's all these variable variables
before your sample
even gets to the extraction step in your
testing lab
um that impact
you know at the terpenes they all boil
at different at different points
you know the monoterpenes are boiling in
the like 150 degrees celsius range but
the sesquiterpenes are larger and you're
more like 225 or so but they all
but what that means is different
molecules
are being depleted out of your sample at
different rates
so you know if you're looking at the
ratio
between the ratio of mercene to
caryophyllene for example
it's going to change depending on how
you cure the plant
and how old the sample is
so it's kind of a nightmare scenario for
a breeding program
where you would need to be going in and
periodically
checking do i have exactly the terping
you know profile that i want um it's
just
it's inherently difficult just because
you know this this kind of experimental
variability
is is both built in the other aspect of
this
is that um this is a particular area of
chromatography where you've got very
complicated mixes people are dealing
with
different matrices that you know they
have to you know do
do the extraction from um
and it's there's a lot of stuff that
that makes it difficult to do
to do these measurements really well um
you know steep hills seem to do a
particularly good job of it but
you know your mileage is going to vary
because this stuff is
not easy and we haven't standardized
to like a global set of
best practices um that everybody would
adhere to
yeah absolutely um when i when i speak
with with folks in the
lab testing side which is one of the
focus areas of canmed
that's one of the things they come back
to all the time is the need for
a standard to sort of get consistent
results from lab to lab so
hopefully hopefully we'll see that soon
yeah
um one of the things you sort of touched
on and it's not
an exact correlation but i did want to
bring up to you this whole idea of
nature versus nurture
as well where you know the genes are
only going to do
so much it it a lot's going to depend on
the environment you place it in the type
of lights that you're providing
so i'm wondering if you could comment a
bit on that and is there
sort of is there variation even between
strains where some are more sensitive to
sort of those
changes or is it universal
a little bit of all of those of course
yeah so for for a given genetic
background
you have you grow up this stuff and
you know either it's completely
genetically pure
well we don't have that so you know you
do cuttings
um we already know you know so you do
and
you grow them indoors and outdoors you
grow them under
you know high pressure sodium and you
know you know
led light you grow them outdoors in
five different fields or you walk a
field outdoors and just look at
if you've got a lot of variation in the
field and
most of the time when i'm out in a field
it's rare to find a field that is really
100 homogeneous in terms of
soil type the amount of water that uh
that the plants are available to them
and
you know the various things that you're
not shading from
wind for example so
a given genetic background is going to
give you
basically like a set of performance
characteristics it does
this under these lights and this under
these other lights and
this range of things when grown outdoors
the one thing you know for sure is it's
going to be really different outdoors
than it is in the greenhouse but to come
back to that last part of your question
that's something that's going to vary
from strain to strain
some strains i don't i don't know
it's some strains are going to be really
good
indoors and they're just going to be
crap outdoors
or the opposite you're going to have
other strains
that are really a lot less sensitive
to environmental changes
than others and it's just it all comes
down basically to a complex interplay
of the set of gene networks
working in in each particular
in each particular plant one of the
you know you know if from a data
analysis perspective what you would most
like to have rather than say you know
here's the plan and it performs like
this what you would have
is a complete breakdown here it is in
five different growth environments and a
half a dozen
replications of each one so you know
within
each growth environment how much does it
vary and
how much does it vary between growth
environments
the cost of doing something like that
starts to get
fabulous very very quickly so
you have to work with less data than
that yeah
and now is that something that could
eventually be sort of bred into the
plant is to kind of have
i guess more robustness so they're not
so sensitive to those variations like
you mentioned out in the field
yeah yeah yeah once but
targeted breeding like that you need to
know
basically what are the exact genes or at
least
what are the you know chunks of the
genome sometimes you can do a mapping
and it just says
well it's this part of you know
chromosome 8
is is what's giving us this behavior but
you need to have you need to know
something like that and then once you
have that you can devise a molecular
marker and you can follow it
um through your crosses and breed for
you know in this case you know
robustness to environmental change
so there's a prior step first gotcha
one of the things you mentioned was you
know that a lot of
commercial commercial cultivation right
now is done with cuttings
and i imagine the goal is to eventually
get to stabilizing seeds
for for propagation so how how far away
do you think we are from that
so there are there are some lines
on the hemp side um
that are relatively homogeneous
um homozygous is a is the exact term
um but
you know for if we do it the traditional
uh by the traditional method um which is
uh years of what's called back crossing
targeted
um back crossing or you're you're
monitoring
um you know am i
fixing meaning making this homogeneous
in in the genome am i fixing all the
positive
um gene variants the alleles
and not what you want to avoid is fixing
negative alleles which is you know
because what you're creating is an
inbred line
the danger with inbreds is you can be
you
fix deleterious genes in there so the
magic of
making good inbreds is being able to
follow knowing enough about the genome
that you can breed something that that's
that that's inbred
and doesn't have you know serious
ability deleterious
um alleles in there so the
traditional the old-fashioned way to do
that takes
years um you know
depending on who you talk to you're
gonna get different numbers
on on how long it would take but
if you were just to do say
you know a half dozen back crosses
you're going to be a fair amount of the
way there
and you could do that probably in
you know two or three years
but to get to really good homogeneity
it's going to take longer than that
now on the other hand
there is a trick
called double haploids where you start
with a haploid cell like for example a
pollen
grain and you trick it
it's a chemical trick that you can do
and
regenerate a diploid plant from it that
is now
what you've done is you you you forced
it to
go through a doubling without creating
two cells
and bang now you've suddenly got
um a line that is exactly homozygous
at every at every position um
that's called double haploid technology
and it
doesn't exist yet in cannabis um
we don't technically know if it's
possible
in cannabis um yet
at syngenta we got it going in maze
and it was a nuisance but we had it
running then we we tried
and we had very good experts working on
we tried to get it going in tomato
and just failed abjectly we ended up
licensing from
another company in the netherlands that
had gotten it working
so cannabis may be you know it's
it's going to be really hard to get it
working it could be really easy or it
could be impossible
but with double haploids
that would revolutionize a lot of things
in the industry very quickly
so you're actually taking pollen and
having it essentially breed with itself
basically it's fascinating
so i would be remiss if i didn't ask you
um about your position at front range
biosciences
um what's your role there what are what
are the things that you're working on
so um i am the the director of
bioinformatics
uh you know we're a little startup so
it's a that's a
a fancy term for for basically i'm you
know the
uh doing the main amount of the the
bioinformatics work which is
mainly focused on gene discovery
um you know developing the catalog
of the genes that um that we'll care
about
for um for our breeding purposes
and so what is your focus currently
so i've been focused uh
on um the terpene family
and right now i'm working on
um the the cannabinoid uh family both
the
the what we call the terminal synthases
that make the individual
um cannabinoids um and
the upstream um parts of the of
the pathway there's a number of other
things that
you know along the way you know we're
we're going to get to um you know
disease resistance obviously is one that
you know there's a critical need for um
in cannabis but um
you know basically i mean right now i'm
really focused on the cannabinoid
pathway
excellent and any any cannabinoids
in particular is it sort of a
combination of the
the tried and true thc cbd are there
sort of other lesser cannabinoids that
you're interested in
yeah we're mostly interested in
the lesser cannabinoids in the uh so
so front range is focused on
cbd dominant legally hemp varieties
and so you know one of the things that
everybody in the field is very concerned
with is
not having your plants go hot that
0.3 thc
um so understanding what are the genes
that are involved
in creating this extraneous um thc a lot
of times you're seeing this
in in varieties where the thc synthase
gene
looks like it should be stone dead so
there are other sources of thc
so understanding understanding those
but then also there's a lot of interest
in the other um cannabinoids and
and for very good reason i mean if if
you only know one thing about
pharmaceutical chemistry it's that if
you've got a family of related molecules
and you know that
two or three of them are really super
interesting you better go look at the
rest of them
so cannabi chromium is one of the more
easy to find
but but also cbg um
strains the varan uh
cannabis cannabinoid and
thcv and
there's a number of these you know
lesser cannabinoids
that you know we're looking for plants
that make reasonable amounts of them
but there's a lot of there's a lot of
perfectly good-looking
synthase genes that are actually
expressed
in you know in flowers not at the same
rate um
as as the you know as the cbd and thc
synthesis
but you know they're these are real
healthy genes and we'd like to know
you know what do these things do
excellent so you're very much focused on
creating
you know high-yield resinous buds for
terpene cannabinoid
production any interest in sort of uh
looking into hemp as a as a textile or
for other uses beyond sort of the
pharmaceutical or nutraceutical uh
aspects yeah yeah definitely definitely
um there's
so the um there's various sides to like
you know
the economic our argument in terms of
you know what's
is it profitable um for the
you know for the farmer versus other
things that they could they could be
doing
um and uh
you know so that that kind of drives
like where are the most important
market segments for us to be looking at
but you know hemp as a
fiber um
you know it's got you know this long
list of really substantial advantages
and
if nothing else creating varieties where
you get
say both things going on at the same
time you've got
you know very good oil production and
very good
um fiber production
you know that's something that that that
we've talked about
um i think it's maybe more likely that
it's going to continue to be
two very different um kinds of varieties
but
you know the short answer the question
is yeah that's
you know that's obviously another one
that's that's
you know the the other is is uh
use of the as the of the seeds as a
protein source
um absolutely you know so
well that's it's very fascinating stuff
keith um
where can people learn more where can
people learn more about uh
about your work in about front range
biosciences
well that's well let's see you can go to
the front range biosciences website
um uh for my terpene work um i've got a
paper out
uh in in plus one um
you know uh you could go to canmed i
understand i'll be giving a talk
yes please yeah and uh and i'm
i'm starting to kind of
shape out the profiles of uh of another
paper that will be
focused on uh the cannabinoid pathway
excellent when can we when can we expect
to see that
oh i'm not going to make any kind of
guess on that
within the year all right excellent
we'll be sure to uh
share that with everyone and uh hey
hopefully it'll be there in time for
canmad we can get a
you can get a glimpse into it so
thanks again keith for taking the time
to talk to us today and
we'll see you in pasadena this fall
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed my conversation with
keith allen
check out the links in the show
description to learn more about the
topics we discussed
and please also check out the front
range biosciences website
our next episode will drop august 5th
in the meantime please go to kim at
coffeetalk and sign up for email updates
that will enter you into a drawing to
win two tickets to our canmed 2021
vip dinner and also keep you up to date
with all things
kim in 2021 if social media is your
thing
you can find us on facebook instagram
twitter and
linkedin just search for can med events
and lastly if you are listening via a
podcast app
go ahead and hit the subscribe button so
that new episodes automatically download
to your device
and please also leave us a 5 star review
alright that's it from us stay safe
stay healthy and be sure to come back
for the next episode
of can med coffee talk
you